<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By A. Theodore Tuttle</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by A. Theodore Tuttle.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/A.%20Theodore%20Tuttle.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by A. Theodore Tuttle.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1971 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Message of the Restoration</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, you have joined this meeting to listen to the Tabernacle Choir sing its singularly beautiful music, to worship on this Sabbath day, and to learn something more about The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. In th</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03006_000_4030" doc-version="2" hash="tknhTw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="FKmcYqfzH0WGab9ZwcuX9A" hash="ldxeLA">The Message of the Restoration</h1><p class="authorName" guid="81d9550b-e85c-44db-bd64-f6aff95bc1a0" pid="fOeYNtpw5EeLHnwBx5zPhg" hash="uG5ddw">A. Theodore Tuttle</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="f3b4a4e1-03eb-4916-ae72-11662f9c4e08">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27d8.jpg" alt="President A. Theodore Tuttle" guid="c7f89584-5e5b-41b6-90b2-2f0cb828170f" pid="BcY8bln1o0y4-tmdsRVUyw" hash="uF_y9g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p1" guid="7201d3f0-c0b8-40d3-ac15-8aeb1df35bdd" pid="j5HLinvpFkurv1bJpb3z9g" hash="sf1iNw">My dear brothers and sisters, you have joined this meeting to listen to the Tabernacle Choir sing its singularly beautiful music, to worship on this Sabbath day, and to learn something more about The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. In the next few minutes I would like to explain the message of this church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p2" guid="457b3af0-4be9-4e0b-9471-f682b9d579fa" pid="PMb8VBCPSEGsQV9pGqbxSQ" hash="Q4meiQ">It is the message of the restored gospel. I speak of the restoration, for The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is the restored church. In organization and power, it is as the Savior established it when he walked the earth. The Church of Jesus Christ of “Latter-day Saints” distinguishes it from the Church of Jesus Christ of former-day saints. It has been established in what the Lord has called “the dispensation of the fulness of times” or the last gospel dispensation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p3" guid="39662a99-31e3-404a-90b0-66ad7d92a897" pid="-HBD8LVlo0e-NMbPlu_ALg" hash="KQDdoA">The cornerstone of our message is the divine sonship of Christ. He was the Son of God, the Eternal Father, from whom he inherited immortality, or the power to live. He was the son of Mary, from whom he inherited mortality, or the power to die. Hence, he could say: “No man taketh … [my life] from me, but I lay it down of myself. … This commandment have I received of my Father.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/10.18" class="scriptureRef">John 10:18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p4" guid="6049c73a-5938-4ac9-ba34-a13f5d72a5ca" pid="vTHyrSZwI0GoZuEiFR7h6w" hash="YUdvZQ">As the Son of God, he had power to atone for the sins of all mankind. He broke the bonds of death, initiated the resurrection, and became the first fruits thereof. In another seven days, on Easter morning, the Christian world will celebrate the resurrection of our Savior. He arose from the grave, took up his earthly body, and, the scriptures say, “he shewed himself alive after his passion by many infallible proofs, being seen of them forty days, and speaking of the things pertaining to the kingdom of God: …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p5" guid="7a11ecd3-8eba-4b14-96e4-6d48e5a06526" pid="fepZcrS9h0ek2WwsgtraDw" hash="Qlfr9A">“And when he had spoken these things, while they beheld, he was taken up; and …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p6" guid="8fb21879-e92c-4ae1-8e67-d7840a9beaa2" pid="3RjI7zLyjUCrz4DMaCdk8A" hash="3c_5hw">“… two men stood by them in white apparel;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p7" guid="178ce0ad-3ad9-4ee4-ab3e-77ed7143532d" pid="lRjaYDwUG0aJDGcyasbNaw" hash="QnO8Kg">“Which also said, Ye men of Galilee, why stand ye gazing up into heaven? this same Jesus, which is taken up from you into heaven, <span class="emphasis">shall so come in like manner </span>as ye have see him go into heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/1.3,9-11" class="scriptureRef">Acts 1:3, 9–11</a>. Italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p8" guid="d18e5f40-1b84-448e-b422-df29eec38620" pid="pb4YnvXAl0OMSsAu5a9SSQ" hash="kPVasA">Salvation is in Christ; that is, in and through him, his atonement and his resurrection, we can be saved by obedience to the principles and ordinances of his gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p9" guid="db4caa02-1b61-424d-9983-83da07aadc74" pid="bEAZ2A6R2keoVfkwcmMl2g" hash="1mpmrQ">Jesus Christ is the central figure of all the world. He came in the meridian of time as had been predicted. Old Testament prophets prophesied of his coming. The Lord promised Adam that a Messiah would come. In fact, the law of sacrifice was given to Adam and his posterity. It was symbolic of the death of the Lamb of God. This sacrifice was dramatically explained by Moses in the Feast of the Passover. A lamb, a male of the first year, without blemish, was to be slain. Its blood was to be shed, but no bones were to be broken. This ordinance was to turn men’s hearts and minds <span class="emphasis">toward </span>the day when the Lamb of God himself would be sacrificed for the sins of men. The sacrifice which the Father gave of his Only Begotten Son ended sacrifice by the shedding of blood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p10" guid="c8b04b20-2705-40d8-8265-15e08177fd91" pid="IFEBh8nGO0y6ffboIhwa7A" hash="kYM9rw">In its place and to point our minds <span class="emphasis">back </span>to the atoning sacrifice, the Savior instituted the ordinance of the sacrament:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p11" guid="06cb905e-08a3-48a4-a55a-8069136b1666" pid="RICiLh05wkyD_acJHlmFFw" hash="lmliEw">“… the Lord Jesus … took bread:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p12" guid="545c802f-3687-4e16-91c7-7d7b9b07a1e4" pid="ClMmin68j0SgMjIgezYP5g" hash="v3YOCA">“And when he had given thanks, he brake it, and said, Take, eat: this is my body, which is broken for you: this do in remembrance of me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p13" guid="7ca421df-b0a0-48a5-ae7f-927f69755ba8" pid="hPqy5z4jjUOy5WtMFETkMA" hash="_N-2MA">“After the same manner also he took the cup, when he had supped, saying, This cup is the new testament in my blood: this do ye, as oft as ye drink it, in remembrance of me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p14" guid="3e77b25b-0ee4-478e-8128-5e1caf9ad393" pid="u_rv_wwrrUmGPutKsRC5aQ" hash="mA_ENw">“For as often as ye eat this bread, and drink this cup, ye do shew the Lord’s death till he come.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/11.23-26" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 11:23–26</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p15" guid="ff6b2ed1-bec0-4aa1-9b7f-f40113341250" pid="Cavtbm_3hUmDgUDsjVMP3w" hash="BnQQVw">We declare the divine Sonship of Christ. We know he lives today. We know he shall come the second time, as was prophesied.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p16" guid="f8cd6838-ffd7-4a1b-91f2-19be912931c9" pid="4w7DW9JB5E-KWM3d1TDxGA" hash="gSTxOQ">After the Savior had called the twelve apostles and established his Church, it was not many years until, as prophesied, the Church gradually fell into apostasy. The priesthood authority to administer the ordinances was lost. The Church dwindled in unbelief. Political power usurped what was left of the organization, and complete apostasy occurred. Just as this falling away was prophesied, so also was the time of restoration—or “the times of restitution of all things.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/3.21" class="scriptureRef">Acts 3:21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p17" guid="b70ca30d-228a-4783-8d1a-6b31c4bb61c2" pid="rCNvZ7RHBECKxvZTrtxSEA" hash="2W9UGg">In the spring of 1820 a boy not yet fifteen, whose “mind was called up to serious reflection,” pondered the question which, if any, church was true. He followed the scriptural injunction to “ask of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.5" class="scriptureRef">James 1:5</a>.) He records:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p18" guid="b39401a0-4461-4be1-9d9f-1c8308499a46" pid="5eA-1kvpkUaGPCXtfAee0w" hash="D94Siw">“… I saw a pillar of light exactly over my head, above the brightness of the sun, which descended gradually until it fell upon me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p19" guid="61422e39-28e2-4ecb-b3ce-464ba2cfc840" pid="3xS2xDIYoUWzmHEHaTuZHQ" hash="jQObPA">“… When the light rested upon me I saw two Personages, whose brightness and glory defy all description, standing above me in the air. One of them spake unto me, calling me by name and said, pointing to the other—<span class="emphasis">This is My Beloved Son. Hear Him!</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.16-17" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:16–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p20" guid="4922f0e8-d0d5-4f62-9742-6efae888fb21" pid="-ee5GtZJ906fzRk4994C1A" hash="zp9mtQ">This marvelous vision, the personal appearance of both the Father and the Son, clarified once and for all the <span class="emphasis">fact </span>of their existence. The fact that they lived. The fact that they are separate, distinct beings. And the fact that they love us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p21" guid="85c9790f-3977-4457-88cb-75d5355cb2ce" pid="69crwJAQr0Gyvg9TESzCKA" hash="6bgC8Q">Subsequent to this vision, heavenly messengers bestowed additional powers and blessings to Joseph Smith. He prophesied. He taught gospel principles. He translated. He brought forth books of scripture—both ancient and modern. He built temples and cities. He was a revealer of the knowledge of Christ. He was the authorized servant of God. He fulfilled every requirement to complete the profile of a prophet. In due time Joseph received the “keys of the kingdom.” With this apostolic power he reestablished the true church in its fullness and power. The Lord said to him: “… this generation shall have my word through you.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/5.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 5:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p22" guid="e9d724b5-9410-4ca2-a46e-543200e0d210" pid="cIYSQmfQIkakNImLW4ez4Q" hash="qWdH5g">There is no greater prophet in any dispensation than Joseph Smith. He translated the Book of Mormon from ancient plates. Its purpose is to be another witness that Jesus is the Christ. Concerning this book, the Lord declared: “And he has translated the book, even that part which I have commanded him, and as your Lord and your God liveth it is true.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/17.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 17:6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p23" guid="5e4f5079-e882-4bc4-8f9c-de86afd0dd76" pid="iZZJQ5eK-UeijBQhT6elKg" hash="uWE8yA">We know that it is not a popular thing to teach that a backwoods boy from Vermont, reared in New England and trained on the frontier, was a prophet. But, popular or not, it is a fact! <span class="emphasis">Joseph Smith was a prophet, and all of the calumny and aspersion to the contrary cannot controvert that fact. </span>Anyone who has concern for the welfare of his eternal soul should give attention to this message. Every man who has lived since the days of Joseph Smith is subject to accepting him as a prophet of God in order to enter into our Heavenly Father’s presence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p24" guid="488f7aa6-6e5a-42f4-8121-56ba661ad2e5" pid="afm4aXYoJEqcdszq5bpMGQ" hash="hj3y0A">If you do not know of the divine calling of Joseph Smith, perhaps it is because you have not considered it. Of those who consider the Book of Mormon and the message he restored, more than two hundred people daily receive the witness that he was indeed a prophet of God. He suffered martyrdom. He sealed his testimony with his blood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p25" guid="54e15a26-1f68-47bb-a61a-e12d64ffb942" pid="w1gDzCfaVEmK8Tg3DQXBgA" hash="A9mI6A">We declare that The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is true and that there is today a living prophet at its head.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p26" guid="1ede3bf9-433d-4be2-8d2a-c004113671e2" pid="o1UMz6wuZ0-a9hsqlQXHcw" hash="u2omhA">The Lord himself has said it is “the only true and living church upon the face of the whole earth, with which I, the Lord, am well pleased. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.30" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:30</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p27" guid="d7721678-b36e-4598-8063-860e2ca8630b" pid="ppvMAuAEEEqx5hX9FWQqEQ" hash="Gjyndw">Our present prophet has been chosen by the Lord to direct his affairs and be his mouthpiece. At ninety-five he is moving a bit beyond middle age! But then, the Lord has never specified how old or young a prophet should be. Nor has he said how short or tall. He has not required that he be possessed of any particular academic degrees. But he has made it abundantly clear that he must be “called of God” and empowered by <span class="emphasis">him. </span>It is to be so called and ordained that qualifies President Joseph Fielding Smith. He is like other men, it is true. He will chuckle at a pleasantry. If you prick him he will bleed. His great tender heart will cause him to weep at another’s sorrow. He is subject to sickness and pain. But there is one thing different about President Joseph Fielding Smith—you see, he is the prophet of God. I know this man. I love him. He has lived a life of rigorous service in which there was always intense opposition from the evil one. He has withstood all of that. The Lord has honored him by this great call to be his prophet. I love the stalwart counselors at his side. I love the Twelve. I love all my brethren.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration.p28" guid="0a202c15-6583-4a47-8e5c-85099d9c7950" pid="9-cD2nhW7UWFHguyA9uTVw" hash="kxgYAA">Now, what is the destiny of this church? It will go forward. It cannot fail. It will grow until it fills the whole earth. With Christ at its head, in constant communication with the leaders of this church, we are destined to carry out the work God has assigned it. This church will carry the gospel message to all of our Father’s children. It will save the living and the dead. This church will be maligned. It will be attacked. Many will doubt. Some will apostatize. However, it will bring the righteous and honest in heart into its fold and set their feet on the way to exaltation. Some think it strange today that so many Christian churches are empty. They wonder why this church progresses and grows. To us it is understandable. We know that an apostasy occurred in ancient days. We know that there has been a restoration of the true gospel in our day. We know that The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints has been organized with power and authority and with a living prophet to head it. We know its great destiny, and we are willing to live in order to achieve it. We know Christ is our head. We believe in the final, inevitable triumph of truth expressed in the gospel of Jesus Christ. We know we shall succeed. We invite all men of goodwill to join us in achieving this great destiny. In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/04/the-message-of-the-restoration</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1971-general-conference/1971-04-4030-elder-a-theodore-tuttle-64k-eng.mp3" length="6685429" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1971 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Things That Matter Most</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Some years ago, I read an editorial in the entitled “The Mechanical Rabbit.” I quote:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03012_000_4040" doc-version="2" hash="VmX-5Q"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="GnUlNh_DkkeNaWr7qiIHFA" hash="-KuGnQ">The Things That Matter Most</h1><p class="authorName" guid="81d9550b-e85c-44db-bd64-f6aff95bc1a0" pid="W4Lq9jrdZkC3jG_iIzu9Xw" hash="uG5ddw">A. Theodore Tuttle</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="0c715ca8-6a98-4a14-aa54-3ccd9de313db">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27d8.jpg" alt="Conference photo" guid="22813403-d1ad-443e-9003-76c5f265e333" pid="1fKhq2ubKkWbNKGaCN6R0g" hash="uF_y9g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p1" guid="24940279-990b-4ae5-8fef-5942d71dbd10" pid="1OwtlnqUZ0uQOteDs1l4gQ" hash="jjhGXg">Some years ago, I read an editorial in the <span class="emphasis">Deseret News </span>entitled “The Mechanical Rabbit.” I quote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p2" guid="59d56643-9073-4cbf-8aa9-b452f46ec0ae" pid="EE0rkObtOkyclQbIRVRyjA" hash="47Jjsw">“Most of our readers must have smiled the other day when they read of the greyhounds in Britain <span class="emphasis">who don’t know a rabbit when they see one. </span>So long had they chased a mechanical rabbit around the racetrack, that when a <span class="emphasis">real rabbit </span>bounded across the track, the dogs didn’t give it a second look.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p3" guid="66dcfc50-3ad0-4a21-a4e5-d20862e189e0" pid="vvWjnIoWEkKsI4hU-PSY0Q" hash="3Rj8JA">“Stupid, eh? But sad too, this perverting of the natural instincts. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p4" guid="2c758014-bfa3-4290-bd2f-209b175c29a4" pid="US5j2tkYXUCYPkpWxEa4vw" hash="zzSIlA">“We chase mechanical rabbits, too.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p5" guid="897b3b21-108f-49d0-a260-69bf49f13e33" pid="ApqQyiPS_02ngwsDuDSU_A" hash="TE9rtA">“We chase <span class="emphasis">paychecks, </span>and don’t give a second look to the glint of the rising sun on a snow-topped peak.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p6" guid="ca0a0623-60d5-4c21-8685-42180b20a145" pid="_QLzdoLJukCyn9E3NfeyPw" hash="-SirZQ">“We chase our way through the <span class="emphasis">appointments </span>of a crowded desk calendar, and fail to take time to chat with the next-door neighbor or to drop in on a sick friend.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p7" guid="c9a39f69-c17c-4174-8f8d-fd37df083bd7" pid="pciXbKgAR06Z0cH45l0haw" hash="0CSsqg">“We chase <span class="emphasis">social pleasures </span>on a glittering noisy treadmill—and ignore the privilege of a quiet hour telling bedtime stories to an innocent-eyed child.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p8" guid="fb7f414a-b42e-450a-87c4-fd33fc66ba11" pid="57vxeYuWx0iB7uGlfAV_bQ" hash="OfNqFA">“We chase <span class="emphasis">prestige </span>and <span class="emphasis">wealth, </span>and don’t recognize the real opportunities for joy that cross our paths. …”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p9" guid="0cd8740c-b64d-4bcc-80ee-142dfd5dedab" pid="kvFxLnGOuES0W-0E6_U6ag" hash="Sq0Vbw">Wordsworth said words appropriate to this condition: “The world is too much with us: late and soon, Getting and spending, we lay waste our powers.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p10" guid="4b1d4233-f69a-4af4-98d0-86ea0d5dcd8d" pid="rAGPLN4pMUWXbxKXxPzYhQ" hash="QhZmzg">“Race on, you poor, blind over-civilized hounds. You’ll never catch your rabbit until you learn to recognize a genuine one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p11" guid="4275022d-cb7c-41b2-8159-ec1f306bd96e" pid="xkFInZEUH0-l30b5NR5OMA" hash="Q5y36w">“But, you’ll have company in your race; the company of unnumbered men who’ll never catch the joy they chase until they, too, learn to recognize a genuine one.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p12" guid="d3cbf35b-a280-4eb7-9534-7b89d8baa48c" pid="G9aEfTl7_ESqrInfpwH9yw" hash="pd6aPg">This points up our challenge: See “that the things that matter most … are not at the mercy of things that matter least.” (Ashley Montague.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p13" guid="8941e9a0-574a-423a-b227-bae34a49c2ac" pid="NxHbaeWWA0yPd_iEd2OLgg" hash="KtXJNQ">Someone rephrased this thought: “Too often we are involved in the thick of thin things.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p14" guid="121966e2-a09c-4ae9-aca2-a0321d6a4314" pid="9s0ZFO_Tk0ykvC1AemNOxw" hash="7rqCoQ">In modern revelation the Lord said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p15" guid="aead8588-4cde-4f6a-80c5-f93b17234b87" pid="bs-Y1Y16t0ikKz4YzJb--Q" hash="byoPIA">“Behold, there are many called, but few are chosen. And why are they not chosen?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p16" guid="7eb92699-afd3-4ccc-9f2b-5bbd2bbae4ea" pid="Dhh0j6HVk0uxIgNGpSV9wg" hash="1rzqmA">“Because their hearts are set so much upon the things of this world, and aspire to the honors of men. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.34-35" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:34–35</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p17" guid="cab9fdd8-17d7-4e0c-b7a8-76a553517255" pid="gy3gZSdVOU-eTGr-twfvPA" hash="ZuFxoQ">Here is instruction to straighten out our values.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p18" guid="f62d539e-0cfe-438d-a655-5e5b60d83354" pid="YlBzbgF730G4nqww28SFnA" hash="8VvLzg">Note again the admonition: “their hearts are set <span class="emphasis">so much </span>upon the things of <span class="emphasis">this world”</span>—not on the things of the spirit. And they “aspire to the honors of <span class="emphasis">men,” </span>rather than seeking approval of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p19" guid="34a550b0-a76b-4dca-a559-e2cb26ec97fd" pid="RqtfTMMe40-jJavJMoIfWA" hash="y56DEg">Have we sought “so much” for material things while missing, even ignoring, the things of God? The beauty of nature at this or any other season goes unseen and unappreciated.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p20" guid="3f7d0e40-9edc-4304-a498-8c3d667a4e8e" pid="LQvl99tqhUGyL-OGNPC_tg" hash="k0Fnzg">Our lives are ruled by a schedule and appointments while the Christian acts of kindness wait—ofttimes in vain.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p21" guid="75c7148a-5b4c-4cb3-b16f-a285b2f3482f" pid="JOYvNJWd70CjIjPh-6I21A" hash="5dbETg">Our most flagrant violations, perhaps, occur in our own homes. We chase worldly pleasures and neglect our own innocent children. When did you tell stories to your children? Or go fishing or hunting with your son? Or help him earn a merit badge? Have you counseled with them concerning their personal achievement program?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p22" guid="55a9e4da-1f95-42f6-8c07-56aabd626dbd" pid="4BtNm-jtCkiBTUkuEyFPiA" hash="l2V1qQ">The trials through which today’s young people are passing—ease and luxury—may be the most severe test of any age. Brothers and sisters, stay close to your own! Guide them safely! These are perilous times. Give increased attention. Give increased effort.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p23" guid="e5c719e9-44e2-49bf-bf57-a4e82c5e5af0" pid="g8i9BEEQqkCpBADRVLGtMQ" hash="QJLeug">The responsibility rests on the family to solve our social problems. Youth search for security. They search for answers to be found only in a good home. No national or international treaty can bring peace. Not in legislative halls nor judicial courts will our problems be solved. From the hearthstones of the homes will come the answers to our problems. On the principles taught by the Savior, happiness and peace will come to families. In the home youth will receive strength to find happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p24" guid="c715f51e-7dd4-45db-a902-c447101d94eb" pid="_UXbQnhhkE2avnzJ3dmO8g" hash="j_tCYg">The world is full of foolish schemes. They contravene and hinder the purposes of the Lord. Some seek to change the God-given roles of the sexes. Some invite mothers to leave the home to work. Others entice fathers to find recreation away from their families. These questionable practices weaken the home!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p25" guid="51b3b565-b1bd-4db9-b68a-e973e44f2e26" pid="OY1ea2OaNUSct5Ysnrw_Ug" hash="3BLoKw">Some fathers provide a good house, clothing, cars, and food, and forget what real fatherhood is. Fatherhood is a relationship of love and understanding. It is strength and manliness and honor. It is power and action. It is counsel and instruction. Fatherhood is to be one with your own. It is authority and example.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p26" guid="0935eac1-44d4-4e99-b986-17c1e3d0e84d" pid="ECsPK8v21UKJLq2ffsWkcw" hash="S0THvw">Elder Packer has counseled: “Most fathers concentrate on material security for their children. Security stored up for this lifetime with the world’s situation as it is, could, and probably will, vanish. To really secure one’s children, give them the memory of a happy home life. This is a pattern, a blueprint for them to follow, an image for them to create, an ideal for them to realize.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p27" guid="1ebe7793-fe64-4845-95a5-6192a36d1534" pid="qb7enrX3KE-bHKYDpgmkRw" hash="dImEqA">Create a wholesome atmosphere in your home. Let seeking minds find adequate family support for growth and development.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p28" guid="5b65f579-c738-406e-93f2-37509d792a90" pid="mfHE-iEYPUWDOq6nojoXeA" hash="qmZtiQ">Mothers sometimes turn to the business world for their own selfish purposes—sometimes due to necessity. Again the home is weakened. Face the fact that true fatherhood and true motherhood are fast disappearing. The failure of fathers and mothers to assume their rightful responsibilities actually creates the disturbed conditions we face. As Latter-day Saints, we must resist the thrust of the world against our homes. Repentance is in order for many of us. We <span class="emphasis">must </span>put our values in proper perspective. Put time and attention and means on the things that matter most. Few, in their more sober moments of reflection, do not know where true values rest. It takes a reminder, however, to keep them properly in focus.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p29" guid="2df8ee39-8495-4bbf-ad61-997e1340a029" pid="ZRlIgnJ3A0-clhKKlexLbQ" hash="-_fCLQ">King Benjamin counseled parents not to “suffer your children that they go hungry, or naked; neither … that they transgress the laws of God, and fight and quarrel one with another, and serve the devil. … But … teach them to walk in the ways of truth and soberness; … teach them to love one another, and to serve one another.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.14-15" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:14–15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p30" guid="c8c85678-563c-42ae-9dff-06fdeea33632" pid="MwzCLVgpzkqQDqMxJhFUxQ" hash="1zkUEA">The Lord placed upon parents the responsibility to teach their children. This means more than to teach them verbally. There are better, basic ways to communicate values to our children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p31" guid="359c4519-1b08-4c3b-9449-e45767190d8e" pid="xYLfWIE0OUyRWTL8Ly4p_Q" hash="Ny4W_w">For instance, in a society that tolerates divorce as the inevitable result of 50 percent of its marriages, there is great difficulty transmitting the principle of family solidarity. Children from broken homes seldom carry the idea that the family is an adequate problem-solving organization. Children whose entertainment comes largely from television find their needs for involvement in life frequently frustrated. Where a doctor who stops at the scene of an accident may be sued for administering aid, it is difficult to transmit to children the idea of service and responsibility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p32" guid="445514ec-8426-4802-a7ad-f6c04c77ee6c" pid="8Mw20FILbU2w0JPxeUWv0w" hash="XikulA">In a home where the accumulation of worldly goods has become so important that the father works inordinately at providing financial security at the expense of spending time with his children and sharing his counsel and encouragement; and in a home, likewise, where the mother forsakes her children in order to get more “things,” it is a poor place to teach the worth of a human being in terms of love and sacrifice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p33" guid="1e414ab2-5bf4-40bf-a974-627c3794ac92" pid="4lUMwfJfD0eW6teFcfzppw" hash="-3womA">The Lord has said: “I have commanded you to bring up your children in light and truth.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.40" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:40</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p34" guid="f9569c6c-3a97-4355-aff5-1c9018ddba21" pid="dqT6XfPZ4kG7jFFzhnRI9Q" hash="k-6B5w">Dr. [Paul] Popenoe said, “Our youth are not products of their own lives, but of what their parents give them. If we can get parents to set a good example, we will take away the greatest stumbling block between generations.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p35" guid="ba421ea9-96a6-4d69-9d58-dd6c073da8ea" pid="XJAKGkIi5kiJQ3_o_bTGDA" hash="wDEWew">The Lord said: “Train up a child in the way he should go: and when he is old, he will not depart from it.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/22.6" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 22:6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p36" guid="11ebd4be-3e88-4b54-a784-ee78689932b8" pid="ZZ5CztiNJU64iiLaVUYflA" hash="xfBmiQ">We must learn, before it is too late, the truth spoken by Elder Richard L. Evans: “There never was a tonic that would cure more social ailments than a healthy, happy home. There never was a greater source of social stability than an affectionate and understanding family. There never was a better way of helping children to happiness than the close confidence of wise and loving and responsible parents.” (<span class="emphasis">From Within These Walls </span>[New York: Harper &amp; Bros., 1959], p. 191.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most.p37" guid="a094dbf1-6d99-4e09-8ca0-73748a1411a9" pid="dZji82qujUCLTrl-enrShQ" hash="kMg9OQ">I was reared in a home of wise, loving, and responsible parents. I was reared in a home where a sweet mother was always awake when I came home, like Brother Dunn’s parents. There was always an opportunity to report and to talk. These sessions are some of my choicest memories. In that home was nurtured the testimony that I bear you today. I know that God lives; that Jesus is the Christ, our Savior and our Redeemer. I know that Joseph Smith was a prophet of God. I know that President Joseph Fielding Smith is a living prophet today, with the keys of the kingdom. I know that if we will follow the counsel we have been given in this conference, our homes will be better, our service more effective, and our joy more full. In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/10/the-things-that-matter-most</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1971-general-conference/1971-10-4050-elder-a-theodore-tuttle-64k-eng.mp3" length="12350454" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Priesthood—Its Power and Vitality</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality?lang=eng</link>
      <description>A major recurring theme of this conference, including the seminar of the Regional Representatives of the Twelve, mentioned either directly or indirectly by nearly every speaker, has been the importance and necessity of the priesthood. I want to addre</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03020_000_7030" doc-version="2" hash="vMFTeQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="nT-S41Zf_k-1dEQ7r14j6g" hash="bY0thw">Priesthood—</h1><p class="subtitle" pid="gZM6NykP3kSFY5VTNnMgmw" hash="443Vhg">Its Power and Vitality</p><p class="authorName" guid="81d9550b-e85c-44db-bd64-f6aff95bc1a0" pid="Eva8H1TWq0iGNPKiq3ZzBw" hash="uG5ddw">A. Theodore Tuttle</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="61107fb8-d567-4048-b84d-0d58878d7e32">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27d8.jpg" alt="President A. Theodore Tuttle" guid="faf9dc9e-3f6c-44d9-8cbd-bae47521b7bc" pid="tIu4NX__bUa9uiCiYNx-dg" hash="uF_y9g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p1" guid="619818a5-8e06-4002-aec4-81031408aafc" pid="cYlzynTvvkuf1p-V2rbM9g" hash="Y_ng_A">A major recurring theme of this conference, including the seminar of the Regional Representatives of the Twelve, mentioned either directly or indirectly by nearly every speaker, has been the importance and necessity of the priesthood. I want to address my remarks to this subject. The vitality and power of the priesthood on the earth today are greater than at any other period in the world’s history.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p2" guid="abd8a73a-8f16-421c-a8b7-39c4e301332f" pid="WYZUVLFow0SxLv7hxqyYaA" hash="tgtlAQ">On March 28, 1835, in Kirtland, Ohio, in a meeting with the Council of the Twelve, the Prophet Joseph received a singularly important revelation on priesthood:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p3" guid="eda47565-d4c4-4310-a9f4-10dc8670f838" pid="M79Pyt6QZkuGxxUxJ7W3hQ" hash="ldEFwA">“There are, in the church, two priesthoods, namely, the Melchizedek and Aaronic. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p4" guid="e9f4e0d2-8b55-410f-9b3f-0c55540286c2" pid="Y0mzktF9M0ebrxyG_eSQgA" hash="upI-xQ">“Why the first is called the Melchizedek Priesthood is because Melchizedek was such a great high priest.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p5" guid="2975bc37-1907-4e44-b0a6-3613df4cf6fc" pid="D-hftvJurUG6m55pw8DDHQ" hash="bJnBBA">“Before his day it was called <span class="emphasis">the Holy Priesthood, after the Order of the Son of God.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p6" guid="cdd978f8-c249-44f1-acb2-dc82cac2465d" pid="nXBnq2Hp5UiX2qsAWBMtHg" hash="oQ28kA">“All other authorities or offices in the church are appendages to this priesthood.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.1-3,5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:1–3, 5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p7" guid="5bc70f52-0fdc-4b2c-b791-c745a27a3357" pid="Eqfnq6IRJEOTTGUbZtP6ZQ" hash="wwEZaw">It is vital that we understand this foregoing thought. President Joseph F. Smith said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p8" guid="e76f1b73-e344-4143-81c7-0516dd1bf1fb" pid="CYlBKu-vxESOasTloN6amw" hash="lFkF9w">“There is no office growing out of this Priesthood that is or can be greater than the Priesthood itself. It is from the Priesthood that the office derives its authority and power. No office gives authority to the Priesthood. No office adds to the power of the Priesthood. But, all offices in the Church derive their power, their virtue, their authority, from the Priesthood. If our brethren would get this principle thoroughly established in their minds, there would be less misunderstanding in relation to the functions of government in the Church than there is.” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Doctrine </span>[Deseret Book Co., 1939], p. 148.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p9" guid="5b70ae02-c598-4dc0-8beb-e2a9aa3d3fd6" pid="LQvgHFQti0OIdnuqh6lypw" hash="DXLAWw">There are three presiding quorums in the Church chosen from the body of the priesthood:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p10" guid="78262733-9c2a-4acd-a91d-92b0a6d9eea0" pid="mIIYtw77PkmC9u1Woogzzg" hash="VU5lzA">“Of necessity there are presidents, or presiding officers growing out of … those who are ordained to the several offices in these two priesthoods.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p11" guid="ad77f764-6a2c-450e-b35f-8fd43ac57a42" pid="lLiHJj-egkynY2uel409iw" hash="W7LJuQ">“Of the Melchizedek Priesthood, three Presiding High Priests, chosen by the body, appointed and ordained to that office, and upheld by the confidence, faith, and prayer of the church, form a quorum of the Presidency of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p12" guid="1c028b4b-afe0-4bc0-a962-079b9b766461" pid="bDE6WyhZsUG0Mh5GYJmavw" hash="sJGwYg">“The twelve traveling councilors are called to be the Twelve Apostles, or special witnesses of the name of Christ in all the world— …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p13" guid="f140699f-8856-4c6d-accd-708a24f7d316" pid="bLDRx7laiEmuWN17bDUOAg" hash="pOV9Kg">“And they form a quorum, equal in authority and power to the three presidents previously mentioned.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p14" guid="cc28592c-5456-4602-a99a-f70de8ca8981" pid="zBPfeMZzKEyvGNqM10eX1A" hash="d-UXng">“The Seventy are to act in the name of the Lord, under the direction of the Twelve … in building up the church and regulating all the affairs of the same in all nations. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.21-24,34" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:21–24, 34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p15" guid="773c7670-9d09-4a3e-969c-722a7a9c89b2" pid="fVP2hcpzwUy_A36TRZlm3w" hash="Jwpcfg">What is the priesthood? President John Taylor said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p16" guid="0ae528b8-6f91-43d5-aa2f-a8cd7ba87878" pid="_R-b7rKsekKkSrYCdWL_OQ" hash="TMzCAQ">“… it is the government of God, whether on earth or in the heavens, for it is by that power, agency, or principle that all things are governed on earth or in the heavens, and by that power that all things are upheld and sustained. It governs all things—it directs all things—it sustains all things—and has to do with all things that God and truth are associated with. It is the power of God delegated to intelligences in the heavens and to men on the earth. …” (<span class="emphasis">The Gospel Kingdom </span>[Bookcraft, 1943], p. 129.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p17" guid="95a919c8-9b13-4e12-a2e5-726cf648f5d5" pid="SgH1qB4E1EONlVuZG5Jgsg" hash="ibyKJw">In order to gain exaltation a man must obtain, then magnify, the holy priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p18" guid="c70c1a99-cafe-41fa-a6f3-6f69ec25936d" pid="M6cBSYra0U-k2tvUtQxhzA" hash="fV64hQ">“For whoso is faithful unto the obtaining these two priesthoods of which I have spoken, and the magnifying their calling, are sanctified by the Spirit unto the renewing of their bodies.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p19" guid="8eebe6c2-97cf-45ee-8f98-c49d23ebec74" pid="8GSrInuW5U-3DkEj0c509g" hash="Vu-okQ">“They become … the elect of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p20" guid="7e4b8895-bc39-4093-9542-0426742cbbd7" pid="0jN3OkvUlUOUSXH-4hdAtg" hash="TlCcfw">“And … therefore all that my Father hath shall be given unto him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p21" guid="b2f5cd19-56ba-47b9-8098-995096a1a715" pid="CyM3mguklESvTYwSS0JfLw" hash="vbZVhw">“And this is according to the oath and covenant which belongeth to the priesthood.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.33-34,38-39" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:33–34, 38–39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p22" guid="1cc8dbcf-4722-4ed4-8703-2ca57727a5eb" pid="sY0h5lqwBUyPusUbyV6uJg" hash="a9Goww">But we must remember that it is on condition of magnifying the priesthood we obtain. There is great energy being expended and much emphasis given to the operation and administration of this priesthood in the Church today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p23" guid="2f69fef2-9b52-421f-b4ff-dd6703bce382" pid="QArjR-h0GUGLm81h4fXBCA" hash="pOvpvA">“Therefore, let every man stand in his own office, and labor in his own calling; … that the system may be kept perfect.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.109-110" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:109–110</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p24" guid="3e6ca38f-ff7a-497d-be5b-734d8bab4308" pid="sjJd02DPXEqzhsc00tk9Ug" hash="NUJyBw">Standing in their responsibility, the high priests in the Church today have the overall priesthood responsibility to do genealogical research and perform temple ordinances. Through the priesthood they are to see to it that everyone in the Church, in proper time and order, saves his kindred dead. This means that all members are to—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p25" guid="fc102716-228c-4259-a760-778ec272233e" pid="eQV0wO6n-EGCOKtKU7U3eA" hash="OdU-Fw">1. have their personal book of remembrance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p26" guid="0c6cc9c1-a184-4b1f-bcb2-f92f1c220bfa" pid="0SCdzw2CWkeQCllOtT8x0w" hash="eK_0WA">2. complete research on at least their four generations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p27" guid="ec280246-0cf4-4da0-bab2-f593f4f7a9f4" pid="WbXf65P-gkK9FZfxBGsZgQ" hash="0r2LHw">3. live worthy to obtain a temple recommend.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p28" guid="ca5bdb1d-8f49-4a26-82e7-2dd917b22e1f" pid="qSCrs6ye5Eiildo6kJEqJw" hash="7GoZZQ">4. attend to temple ordinances for the dead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p29" guid="0d5e6551-1af0-4a74-a50e-0524066435b7" pid="T1N7UKD89ECocphhh3mYsw" hash="vOhpig">The seventy are to stand in their own office and labor in their own calling, which is priesthood missionary work. The seventy, as missionaries, are specialists in teaching. As members, our strength is in finding and fellowshiping. United we form a productive team to carry the message of the restoration to all of our Father’s children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p30" guid="44a4dd19-6a45-4c91-9da0-fac4f5588639" pid="oyRwPa4FfEu0jaxKGxXqFg" hash="1f5yHQ">Elders standing in their office and calling have a place in welfare work. However, they share a major responsibility for the perfecting of the Saints through priesthood home teaching. The president of the elders quorum has the unique calling to administer the gospel to more people in the ward than anyone else except the bishop. Priesthood home teachers are to—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p31" guid="a4521c91-0eec-4c52-8460-82539b0a0242" pid="gwSJfaGBRUKwsATi1L4mrw" hash="6opO7w">“… visit the house of each member, and exhort them to pray vocally and in secret and attend to all family duties.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p32" guid="3262646d-ea4c-43a0-adc2-0e39839a5e85" pid="OTjWTfzhDUCmfpAtUoUqTg" hash="YHuywg">“… watch over the church always, and be with and strengthen them;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p33" guid="8890c0ab-9457-485d-83cb-901761be348f" pid="uVSwA9aVLUGPR7UV0mbQUQ" hash="Ax4FXQ">“… see that there is no iniquity in the church, neither hardness with each other, neither lying, backbiting, nor evil speaking;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p34" guid="f92218ed-d67a-4592-bbef-c30882226d2a" pid="TEmC4YN1e0uLPm-kbx5AUg" hash="96Zmfg">“And see that the church meet together often, and also see that all the members do their duty.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.47,53-55" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:47, 53–55</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p35" guid="cae9e830-405d-46f4-b741-eb7fa797c6f2" pid="79DCezFh7EuHBlKSbrV5Mw" hash="LFL3aA">Each one of these specific duties is designed by the Lord to strengthen the home. You will notice that the word <span class="emphasis">teach </span>is mentioned only indirectly in this scriptural instruction. Perhaps if we as home teachers could catch the whole vision of what our duty is, then the teaching would eventually be done by the ones the Lord ordained to give instruction in the home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p36" guid="de27db13-3cbc-4577-90d5-9fc37bce1fd0" pid="74BUcHydu0q3fUMEvf4Dng" hash="L3Wgag">Though priesthood home teaching has not yet come into the dignity of its calling, we may yet come to understand that it is one of the loftiest concepts of service in the Church. One thing is certain: it is service that saves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p37" guid="07d708e0-7023-48f4-9963-7d8ff11b7caa" pid="bLFfRrwMC0uUJAwtbKt0fQ" hash="E33_wg">The priesthood in the Church is a mighty bulwark against the advance of evil. There is no power on earth that can withstand the thrust of the adversary except a body of righteous men who honor their priesthood in their homes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p38" guid="7beec0ac-141f-44e1-9dbd-01269642463f" pid="GvoIFW2G-kCAgMEZ_4c0xQ" hash="Hg9b2Q">The young men of the Aaronic Priesthood have not been neglected. The Lord in his wisdom has seen fit to call you young men early in your lives to service in the kingdom. Sometimes, because you do not understand the program of the Church, you think that the Church is neglecting the vital issues. In the vernacular, you “want a piece of the action.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p39" guid="c00d9794-5913-414c-b15e-d4aa5ffb979e" pid="3ONLY7KHbUetdHv3UGxd6A" hash="4IDWMA">In this church there is a call to youth and there is plenty to do, if you will but follow the counsel of your leaders. It is not intended that you just “take the bit in your mouth” and run. A wise saying aptly applies: “The hand that holds the reins is not the power that pulls the load.” The vigor and energy of youth united with the wisdom of mature men make a great team. That is the way the Lord has designed the Aaronic and Melchizedek Priesthoods to work together.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p40" guid="c59e4ac5-3c72-47b9-9862-f82e7826b1b8" pid="SlIIbEoTVUu-xiraqR9QhA" hash="IKIejw">Why do we call upon you to live in purity? So that you will be fit servants to make your contribution to the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p41" guid="6d2967e5-3be0-46fa-b650-4dfc0f75ae65" pid="tErRPf9pbUqOJ98dbImOnQ" hash="xb1yFg">Sixty-six years ago President Joseph F. Smith said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p42" guid="5bdf38fb-42ed-4d42-b8c0-3b27e7fbaba7" pid="RxSa10lbWUGICym2HqVqEg" hash="1zuWhw">“We expect to see the day, if we live long enough (and if some of us don’t live long enough to see it, there are others who will), when every council of the Priesthood in the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints will understand its duty; will assume its own responsibility, will magnify its calling, and fill its place in the Church, to the uttermost, according to the intelligence and ability possessed by it. When that day shall come, there will not be so much necessity for work which is now being done by the auxiliary organizations, because it will be done by the regular quorums of the Priesthood. The Lord designed and comprehended it from the beginning, and He made provision in the Church whereby every need may be met and satisfied through the regular organizations of the Priesthood.” (<span class="emphasis">Conference Report, </span>April 1906, p. 3.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p43" guid="2151323c-36d3-4cd0-8655-a8e4db8aa6e7" pid="EyW53sXL2U6wg2GHUzVZrA" hash="rFiB_w">We are just beginning to see the day when the strongest men in each office of the priesthood are to be called to priesthood leadership.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p44" guid="0213669a-3e01-4850-8426-897e98f67e89" pid="o_wP7c6WcUu1EZ4MQ8LAfg" hash="dN1eDw">We call upon those of you who are now prospective elders to rise to your potential. Become the spiritual leaders in your home. Take upon yourselves the mantle of this responsibility. Perform the service that will save and exalt you and your loved ones in the kingdom of God. This is no ordinary call to serve, nor is this a frantic appeal. It is a solemn warning to get your personal life in order; to regulate the affairs of your family; to reach out to serve your fellowmen and bless the lives of others through this divine power.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p45" guid="ef1c2565-d54c-4458-ae00-47db811335e7" pid="fXiOrwijxUW9zpigJrJ0Fw" hash="_hxUPg">This church with its inspired leadership is already battling the adversary. The struggle in which we are engaged is not some distant day in the future. It is now! If we do not see this clearly, it is because we do not understand the signals that come from the Brethren today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p46" guid="eb0e5c5b-685c-4845-9353-fddf371ac646" pid="HZCaCnVFKkuzKg4rWHmg0Q" hash="XI6M7g">After listening to conference for three days, the message of this conference is clear. It is to arise, assume your priesthood responsibility, and carry off the work of the Lord. This has not been a common conference. Nor is it just “the best conference ever.” We have heard a clarion call to repent, to begin now to magnify this great power which is vouchsafed in this church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p47" guid="5985ef27-8e81-4020-925e-ec3d4933c9e5" pid="R4VKqSGSr020vQIIUDGsKg" hash="m4Tgpw">Oh, my brethren, I plead with you to rise up. Shake off the shackles of indolence and sloth and go forward.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p48" guid="5509d2ed-d6e1-4207-96f0-ae3b0fd6b516" pid="pI4oT0QaVEivHNWPPebFtQ" hash="JJVYbA">In the encouraging words of the Prophet Joseph: “Brethren, shall we not go on in so great a cause? Go forward and not backward. Courage, brethren; and on, on to the victory! …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/128.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 128:22</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p49" guid="52a8de11-9024-4f9a-9cd8-aea97857e82c" pid="W_7NLJcmekqXGLY_9mFsrg" hash="huPExg">I want to testify that Jesus is the Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality.p50" guid="99ff6e58-227a-4d38-a698-4a1a0e55f16e" pid="Z0ryxdpV1UWMQRoSgG_deQ" hash="a0NhfQ">I testify that he is the great High Priest forever. I testify that God the Father and his Son Jesus Christ did appear to the Prophet Joseph Smith and instituted anew in this day the church of Jesus Christ, empowering him with God’s power. I testify that these men hold the keys of the holy priesthood, that there is power and inspiration in what these Brethren say. There is no other group of men in all the world like these men. They have not come to position through a political party, nor have they won a popularity contest. They have been called by prophecy and by the laying on of hands. Things will be well with us and ours to the extent that we listen to and follow their inspired counsel. In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/04/priesthood-its-power-and-vitality</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1972-general-conference/1972-04-7030-elder-a-theodore-tuttle-64k-eng.mp3" length="7193140" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Altar, Tent, Well</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well?lang=eng</link>
      <description>“And [Isaac] builded an altar there, and called upon the name of the Lord, and pitched his tent there: and there Isaac’s servants digged a well.” (.)</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03027_000_3030" doc-version="2" hash="j4xh7A"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="MiYrYYEQokaTB_ho518sKg" hash="d0VE4g">Altar, Tent, Well</h1><p class="authorName" guid="81d9550b-e85c-44db-bd64-f6aff95bc1a0" pid="yBCRyZcCkU6jtuSShL7cuA" hash="uG5ddw">A. Theodore Tuttle</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="16a1ddfe-bc97-406c-9d16-fdfaca2ed2ef">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p1" guid="3a5faccf-9b3c-46f5-9a60-94d746a6e30e" pid="l_StV3kdHkac6F3il26A_A" hash="Z6fH4g">“And [Isaac] builded an altar there, and called upon the name of the Lord, and pitched his tent there: and there Isaac’s servants digged a well.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/26.25" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 26:25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p2" guid="a9174c28-a1f2-4e03-a164-2c9c86b34eea" pid="QXBchU0x9UC3yFlDWiIenw" hash="__2F9g">
        <span class="emphasis">Altar, tent,</span> and <span class="emphasis">well.</span> Isaac did not become an Abraham or a Jacob. He did not reach the heights of Abraham, called the “father of the faithful.” Nor was he as impressive as his son Israel, father of the twelve tribes. Yet Isaac is loved and revered. He worshiped God, cared for his home, and pursued his work. He is remembered simply as a man of peace. The eloquent simplicity of his life and his unique ability to lend importance to the commonplace made him great.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p3" guid="2a0eb57a-d1c0-4aff-80f3-379e99a0a387" pid="GBRxIdA-ikqNrHRUoGcpSA" hash="leC6xw">Altar, tent, and well: his worship, his home, his work. These basic things of life signified his relationship to God, his family, and his fellowmen. Every person on earth is touched by these three.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p4" guid="40e54ae3-dc03-4e53-835d-fc0cd48e9f72" pid="-YhUj3pLRESyiKCYhZQQUQ" hash="_W1k8w">Isaac worshiped at an altar of stone. He sought there answers to life’s questions: Where did I come from? Why am I here? Where am I going?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p5" guid="d5678309-f193-4774-a32d-6ce5f336d101" pid="xwUQx103bkqMemyIDGzqCQ" hash="46ZVpQ">These questions every man asks. These questions continue with us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p6" guid="a3630222-27bb-4ee0-b240-7780fdb80873" pid="ChWNI-JaYkW-GNHNWNE-PA" hash="xThH-g">Biblical scriptures alone cannot answer these questions. Revealed religion, however, gives clear and solid answers. The fullness of the restored gospel declares: We lived with our Heavenly Father in a celestial home before this world began. We learned, progressed, and grew. We yearned to come to this life where we could receive a physical body. After resurrection, we shall return to our Father’s presence, united in an eternal family. All this, through obedience to the principles and ordinances of the restored gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p7" guid="50de5a0e-956c-481f-b3fe-6c69aa9e2b56" pid="MyQQb8-u9EGznALp5sYWcg" hash="xicpnw">We know by revelation that our Father lives. Jesus is his Firstborn in the spirit world: the Only Begotten in the flesh. He is the Christ, our Savior and Redeemer. His work and his glory is “to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p8" guid="328d0e3b-56c5-4b8a-bab0-37ef1d7a4cd8" pid="W_mqYN6sdUmLkcu8kf-CVg" hash="dj95AA">We know he lives, for he has appeared to men in our day to establish this latter-day work. There are living prophets and apostles on the earth today, called by God and ordained to carry out his divine purposes. His only true and living church is The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. His chosen prophet is President Harold B. Lee. Thank the Lord for modern revelation that gives solid answers to life’s important questions—in which we find peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p9" guid="202d82e0-f576-4aef-b1a0-4ac6d46122d5" pid="_z8-KIx9c0yDGQ0xV3tMzg" hash="A6GmBQ">To know the word and works of God, Isaac knelt in his day at his altar. His tent, a home for himself and family, was sacred to him, as our homes are to us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p10" guid="0d47d45c-00b3-476e-bdab-15e81dddc4d1" pid="nKe_U6bTz0GJ060M163oDg" hash="yq76Qg">To Latter-day Saints, the home is a holy place, patterned after the celestial home whence we came. The priesthood-led home is the loftiest spiritual unit we know.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p11" guid="7ab629a7-4f9b-4132-babb-fc28138dab03" pid="E7TVyWescEmU7VbtMWbbKQ" hash="QB-_eg">The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is a family church. In its missionary work we seek to bring families into the Church. We teach the principles and perform ordinances that unite the family for eternity. Indeed, we may say that a prime purpose of this church is to perfect and exalt the family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p12" guid="9e4c4c33-3154-4194-a9af-08ee216207d5" pid="HYaCC4L5YE-BG_F98xbOvg" hash="FAP3yg">There is widespread misunderstanding today concerning the role of father and mother and children. The Prophet Joseph Smith explained that the destiny of the family is to live together as a family unit in the celestial glory. To understand their proper roles, one must understand the eternal nature of man’s life—his premortal existence, life’s purpose now, and his future destiny. Our religion comprehends this and more.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p13" guid="96c45ab8-4f6e-4988-86e1-d23682b330dd" pid="bJ-MZxHNrkCpDMurGrJL8g" hash="DGjoNg">The man is the head of the home. He is to preside and administer its affairs “by persuasion, by long-suffering, by gentleness and meekness, and by love unfeigned; by kindness and pure knowledge.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.41-42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:41–42</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p14" guid="d796daee-ad65-4036-a01d-1f3e2e4a5e54" pid="cCmBjlYg_k6iUj1D1bVJQA" hash="OsafhQ">The woman is the heart of the home. “And the Lord God said, It is not good that the man should be alone; I will make him an help meet for him.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/2.18" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 2:18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p15" guid="1f73369e-64b0-4058-93de-ecd4e2e52c5b" pid="uq7HSAWRyECQBTgs9u5PoA" hash="mSLSzw">“And they twain shall be one flesh. …” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/10.8" class="scriptureRef">Mark 10:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p16" guid="e492fba0-cf9c-463a-8c24-806669a95e93" pid="xZIZdIuTukGIOQzzaYixjw" hash="B1hNOw">President J. Reuben Clark, Jr., one of the Lord’s noble servants, defined woman’s role in eternal perspective. Speaking of Eve, he speaks of all women:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p17" guid="14352198-39d2-4943-905a-a6a4e41b6fb3" pid="_96j8prf4EalWiA9fB6lWQ" hash="TUCkog">“So came Eve, an helpmeet to the priesthood mission of Adam—Eve, the last created being in the … world. … Adam took her in her purity, … radiant and divinely fair, into the Garden he had dressed and kept for her, into the bridal home he had built, into the Garden that from then till now has been the symbol of heaven on earth, there to begin together their earthly life, that was finally to bring opportunity … to the untold myriads of spirits then waiting for the mortal tabernacles these two were to make it possible for them to possess.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p18" guid="860b6d11-7bda-4dae-a4cb-3bdbca1da6b3" pid="B566qpJjCUyWLv1qLD4PUw" hash="Lp0z4A">“… So Eve came … to be a creator of bodies … that God’s design and the great plan might meet fruition.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p19" guid="d09cbdce-93c7-4275-bf4f-f1e5e4f2a309" pid="WAlf63ynDkmgy8VaGAks7w" hash="PvslSA">“This was her calling. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p20" guid="fa8dc413-7d1d-4761-b150-4a050fbae1e9" pid="69gvPHREPkOKC0sL5X_86A" hash="pVdF_g">“From that day, … the greatest glory of true womanhood has been motherhood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p21" guid="3715a42c-7fe8-4381-9b50-2733a2ec0121" pid="foWX7Bek7UuZKCbZ91FpFA" hash="jhUQwQ">“What a miracle is motherhood; how nearly infinite is mother. She fashions in her womb the most complex structure known to man. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p22" guid="90c1eb48-936e-43f4-948d-4e108eaaef7c" pid="OXW-edq9TkKSUWVN-83EcQ" hash="v9eEIg">“This is wife’s and mother’s task and opportunity; and did she fail … then the great plan would fail and God’s purposes would come to naught. … This must never change. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p23" guid="d3b8d712-0335-4c4c-9700-64f16234d11d" pid="iPBV4RMXgUa2VEgOjO6T9Q" hash="XG4j3Q">“But the full glory of motherhood is not yet reached when her child comes forth into this world of trial. … She feeds not only, but clothes it. She cares for it by day and watches over it by night. … She gently leads its faltering steps, till it walks alone. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p24" guid="622b4bde-9646-4a91-b64f-623bc58dfcb5" pid="TAYPlG2OLk6olh8b_SKt9A" hash="nRVNdA">“Thus to the full stature of manhood and womanhood, mother guides, … instructs, directs … the soul for which she built the earthly home, in its march onward to exaltation. God gives the soul its destiny, but mother leads it along the way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p25" guid="f9eb1a55-b655-46df-857e-05735f50c278" pid="owbK5XXhzk6xkrPxZdXD-A" hash="ODcTtw">“When the souls shall return to the presence of the Father of all, the worthy mothers will be there to welcome their worthy children. …” (<span class="emphasis">Immortality and Eternal Life </span>[Melchizedek Priesthood Course of Study, 1969–70], vol. 2, pp. 24–28.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p26" guid="b6ebfad5-f19d-47ea-b9df-8222cbf82877" pid="4FMhNBlFMUyaqH0Xb7TcJg" hash="T0knXg">Wives and mothers do what men cannot do. Men will bow in reverence and in love before mothers who perform this great, this marvelous service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p27" guid="8639c33c-c8ec-4410-991f-4a3452136ed2" pid="Vv2DckRAEEulehN820ZiJg" hash="wpKBaw">Contrast this view of woman with the current prattle that demeans motherhood and her exalted role; that even condones abortion and its attendant evils; that sets aside the role God gave to her. It would be hard to imagine a more exalted role of woman and her place in the eternal plan than is held and taught in The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. We invite you to consider this carefully, for it comes from God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p28" guid="2bfcae09-d108-4d76-adb7-d43f1a2835cb" pid="gy4ecMSXrkegjzHKb1GrHA" hash="xLfv9Q">Parental responsibility cannot go unheeded, nor can it be shifted to day-care centers, nor to the schoolroom, nor even to the Church. Family responsibility comes by divine decree. Parents may violate this decree only at the peril of their eternal salvation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p29" guid="3839440b-7106-4364-bf06-89794de2cee8" pid="6tkcCqVcfkegY90wjhoJJA" hash="OA12SA">Only out of this purposeful, divine relationship of parent and child grows eternal joy and fulfillment. President Harold B. Lee has said, “The most important work you will ever do for the church will be within the walls of your own home.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p30" guid="11d906e2-760a-4673-b733-5447c5fa58fe" pid="EK8fLtynq06-M2wSe8uUOQ" hash="0x517g">To the child, God said at the great day of law-giving at Sinai: “Honour thy father and thy mother: that thy days may be long upon the land which the Lord thy God giveth thee.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.12" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p31" guid="49fb2f06-1386-4ebd-acd2-0495fc38814a" pid="7y2rXZR5jk6fiJxJuTww9g" hash="5giSBA">Kneeling at his altar, mindful of his family in his tent, Isaac found most of his working hours consumed in watching over wells he had caused to be digged. His flocks were nourished by them. His simple dependence upon the water and the soil and the forage that grew is little different in our day, for man must work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p32" guid="07249bc3-0c99-4cdd-a6e3-609acaaba599" pid="93klhMzUTEaZdxrdixfwpg" hash="0lXxdQ">The revelations say that “every man who is obliged to provide for his own family, let him provide. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/75.28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 75:28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p33" guid="4d6f1d42-2d84-4536-b684-a2b11b0afc95" pid="GjxxzjxTK0uBYjsySe76sw" hash="Yz-NSw">In the beginning the Lord decreed, “In the sweat of thy face shalt thou eat bread. …” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/3.19" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 3:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p34" guid="3c2e4d58-cd58-4981-bdd1-bcf47d1cdcc6" pid="ZBvz4rI1Qk-OdfJuOFkFiQ" hash="vFjOJQ">Ever since the restoration in 1830, The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints has encouraged thrift and fostered work as the ruling principle among its members.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p35" guid="fe0ce351-e2ca-47d3-8508-f270c6639bcf" pid="oLzduyVBmkWavjT-CjFLxg" hash="kB46lw">Few evils has the Lord denounced in our day with more vehemence than idleness:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p36" guid="2bf22bde-d82b-4fc7-a5b7-80a5a2ec05ad" pid="9T58xSt_E0eUt5W5DJaL2g" hash="r0Athw">“Thou shalt not be idle, for he that is idle shall not eat the bread nor wear the garments of the laborer. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:42</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p37" guid="c52767d0-b1c3-4ed4-88cf-35e463ec99ee" pid="DRsQa_fCVEqDFCntRcpsuw" hash="9CYAjw">“… the idler shall be had in remembrance before the Lord. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.30" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:30</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p38" guid="cf6bf44e-f981-412a-8d69-78333ef3d6d2" pid="ZEZXmjVxBEKBrtMRuVs44g" hash="jWcZ_Q">“… And the idler shall not have place in the church, except he repent and mend his ways.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/75.29" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 75:29</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p39" guid="8782df3a-7a6c-4acc-a1b4-5e4384b1b431" pid="BDV7FIoAnEKHExw_zzSy9A" hash="_JODaw">Let a man choose an occupation in balance with the other two elements of the triumvirate of which I have spoken. Learn to give an honest day’s work for an honest day’s pay. In the farm or shop or office, let that man know that work is not an end in itself, but a means to a noble end.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p40" guid="09ff2da9-8f74-4669-a6ff-85105ca54e46" pid="U4ibgIcEOE2yxhyecAt1UA" hash="an9TuA">How little things have changed since Isaac’s day—the things that really matter. There is the same God of Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob, the same family roles to fill, the same need to work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p41" guid="e31e3fcb-5382-4b05-9678-71d64b0ce677" pid="K7fgNY4YPk-07T-7wi2DDw" hash="UVzXZw">Altar, tent, and well: these things are essential. Placed in proper perspective by God’s revealed word, they provide at once our greatest challenge and achievement.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well.p42" guid="29336fd8-83b8-4c95-84bf-125161b027fb" pid="08rrn8uDV0uRrd82ywDZJA" hash="m8kL1g">Our Heavenly Father, wilt thou help us thy children to see eternity in these things and act accordingly. In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/10/altar-tent-well</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1972-general-conference/1972-10-3030-elder-a-theodore-tuttle-64k-eng.mp3" length="5769698" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1972 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is a Living Prophet?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Lord closed section 1 in the Doctrine and Covenants, with these words: “What I the Lord have spoken, I have spoken, and I excuse not myself; and though the heavens and the earth pass away, my word shall not pass away, but shall all be fulfilled, </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03033_000_1020" doc-version="2" hash="H7dz2A"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="3LpEFigEoECNzreS4WSewA" hash="GNuMNA">What Is a Living Prophet?</h1><p class="authorName" guid="81d9550b-e85c-44db-bd64-f6aff95bc1a0" pid="BcO3H1Y-jU-HkyQwdIeKSQ" hash="uG5ddw">A. Theodore Tuttle</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="221502cd-21be-4bbd-95a3-8247651d63e4">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p1" guid="189dc901-2d47-4c64-b3b9-0398f6d893d6" pid="qe52TlOVNEy41qgxFlW2vw" hash="jcMllg">The Lord closed section 1 in the Doctrine and Covenants, with these words: “What I the Lord have spoken, I have spoken, and I excuse not myself; and though the heavens and the earth pass away, my word shall not pass away, but shall all be fulfilled, whether by mine own voice or by the voice of my servants, it is the same.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:38</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p2" guid="5026156f-9302-467a-92e9-02c4b58abbc2" pid="e83XK39gz0qipVW6-Z4Hpg" hash="zUIOPw">We have just heard the voice of his servant, and it is the same! President Lee has done what all prophets in all ages have done. He has testified that God, our Father, lives; that Jesus Christ is our Savior and Redeemer, the head of this church. He has testified that Joseph Smith was the prophet of the restoration. Like all the prophets before him, he has declared that the way to peace is found only in the gospel of Jesus Christ; that only by keeping God’s commandments, as revealed through the living prophets, can we find eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p3" guid="4ee291b1-67ac-4a7b-ad21-9da8a3085491" pid="x-f5t3XrnUStJfKTUIbxbw" hash="h82tZw">What is a living prophet? His age? He may be young or old. He need not wear a tunic nor carry a shepherd’s staff. His physical features are not important. A prophet need not have advanced educational degrees nor come from any special social class. He may be rich or poor. He needs no credentials from men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p4" guid="d1d25509-4dac-464e-92ab-94fc4f19e208" pid="BcBmJrp5n0WkV9LPBYTwYw" hash="7tHZLQ">What is it, then, that qualifies a man to be a prophet?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p5" guid="c30a6aa7-a28b-41c9-8b00-92b4aba05206" pid="YC5U9p9VTk2C8ByFvZLVxw" hash="MIKllg">Foremost, God must choose <span class="emphasis">him </span>as his prophet! This is entirely different than for man to choose God. The Savior, speaking to his apostles, said, “Ye have not chosen me, but I have chosen you, and ordained you, that ye should go and bring forth fruit. …” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/15.16" class="scriptureRef">John 15:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p6" guid="5ee513dc-de49-4d68-880b-fac168847028" pid="sDzN3drTzkSK_npN9GImdw" hash="Dttp4Q">“We believe that a man must be called of God, by prophecy, and by the laying on of hands, by those who are in authority to preach the Gospel and administer in the ordinances thereof.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/a-of-f/1.5" class="scriptureRef">A of F 1:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p7" guid="e00b46c0-d536-4071-af89-2af9475eede4" pid="eNRZQ_XfM0-ObvxF2SSt8w" hash="Fush5A">A prophet, then, is the authorized representative of the Lord. While the world may not recognize him, the important requirement is that God speaks through him. A prophet is a teacher. He receives revelations from the Lord. These may be new truths or explanations of truths already received.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p8" guid="7b693ab5-686d-4239-b83b-4265e911562a" pid="fAUMPlThV0GJyTbG35HXBQ" hash="JBaCpw">It is an easy thing to believe in the dead prophets. Many people do. For some mysterious reason there is an aura of credibility about them. It is not so with the prophet who lives among us, who must meet life’s everyday challenges. But it is a great thing to believe in the living prophets. Our salvation is contingent upon our belief in a living prophet and adherence to his word. He alone has the right to revelation for the whole Church. His words, above those of any other man, ought to be esteemed and considered by the Church as well as by the world. One day this truth will be understood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p9" guid="fd9d8f30-dad6-4474-aad5-ed4dd261a170" pid="pbUVz2tljkeQy2oBaJvF_A" hash="nOpe0g">Someone has said, “That person is not truly converted until he sees the power of God resting upon the leaders of this church, and until it goes down into his heart like fire.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p10" guid="779461eb-358e-4927-a9f7-bd17258d5ad9" pid="p513yfXiw0OqKLg-aJL1eA" hash="l0oRog">Some may wonder at such power and authority being vested in one man. “Could he not lead us astray?” they ask. President Wilford Woodruff once said, “I say to Israel, the Lord will never permit me or any other man who stands as president of this Church to lead you astray. It is not in the program. It is not in the mind of God. If I were to attempt that the Lord would remove me out of my place, and so he will any other man who attempts to lead the children of men astray from the oracles of God and from their duty.” (<span class="emphasis">Discourses of Wilford Woodruff </span>[Bookcraft, 1946], pp. 212–13.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p11" guid="b372ee61-bc71-4b12-8bf3-446cff034172" pid="D1lAdc3mhE6DP8_M5WnVmQ" hash="enrZqQ">President Henry D. Moyle has said, “The older I get and the closer contact I have with the President of the Church, the more I realize that the greatest of all scripture which we have in the world today is current scripture. What the mouthpiece of God says to his children is scripture. It is his word and his will and his law made manifest through scripture, and I love it more than all other.” (BYU tri-stake fireside, January 1963.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p12" guid="0e7b2a0e-c0dc-4c4a-a160-968cb28313bb" pid="AILgiUKTj0mQn5BbMyHVMQ" hash="MQKrlw">The Lord has given this promise to his servants: “And whatsoever they shall speak when moved upon by the Holy Ghost shall be scripture, shall be the will of the Lord, shall be the mind of the Lord, shall be the word of the Lord, shall be the voice of the Lord, and the power of God unto salvation.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p13" guid="1c22172e-e376-4344-bd76-6fc35437e061" pid="rwQsSe6bHEWSAc8y7G0jHQ" hash="SR7tIg">President John Taylor said, “We require a living tree—a living fountain—living intelligence, proceeding from the living priesthood in heaven, through the living priesthood on earth. … And from the time that Adam first received a communication from God, to the time that John, on the Isle of Patmos, received his communication, or Joseph Smith had the heavens opened to him, it always required <span class="emphasis">new revelations, </span>adapted to the peculiar circumstances in which the churches or individuals were placed. Adam’s revelation did not instruct Noah to build his ark; nor did Noah’s revelation tell Lot to forsake Sodom; nor did either of these speak of the departure of the children of Israel from Egypt. These all had revelations for themselves, and so had Isaiah, Jeremiah, Ezekiel, Jesus, Peter, Paul, John, and Joseph. And so must we, or we shall make a shipwreck.” (<span class="emphasis">The Gospel Kingdom, </span>[Deseret Book Co., 1944], p. 34.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p14" guid="173f9e5b-2e4b-4ca1-85a2-d3586e8b9be1" pid="jRvtw7Cgfkqg26uxCpXZCA" hash="7530yQ">Orson Pratt has said, “The very moment that we set aside the living oracles we set aside the revelations of God. Why? Because the revelations of God command us plainly that we shall harken to the living oracles. Hence, if we undertake to follow the written word, and at the same time do not give heed to the living oracles of God, the written word will condemn us. …” (<span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses, </span>vol. 7, p. 373.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p15" guid="8353f5ed-0c0b-4dca-a274-0fdc195dc436" pid="5HL7w1VOEUqY8c74V_w0IQ" hash="6GBhXg">It is the right and responsibility of the prophets to counsel the Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p16" guid="523d5c22-202e-4512-9afc-5e4775922e92" pid="xhc4NmJor0iA3C2oeGGPBw" hash="hcA97g">President Wilford Woodruff said, “We, as a people, should not treat lightly this counsel, for I will tell you in the name of the Lord—and I have watched it from the time I became a member of this Church—there is no man who undertakes to run counter to the counsel of the legally authorized leader of this people that ever prospers. … you will find that all persons who take a stand against this counsel will never prosper. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p17" guid="6ad9d049-5163-4d09-9b00-1694666974fb" pid="RvY1G3BwJEyWA43jQODmkQ" hash="qXR96A">“… We have been governed by counsel instead of commandment in many things, which has been a blessing to the saints. …” (<span class="emphasis">JD,</span> vol. 14, pp. 33, 36.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p18" guid="f2945b67-8c57-44a9-aa06-3bb92837fce6" pid="2bIQU44bPk60ewybSlsb4w" hash="XYZ0mA">President Stephen L Richards comments on counsel: “… a moment’s reflection will convince you of the rather serious regard in which we hold counsel. While it is true that we characterize infraction of the law as sin, and we do not apply quite that drastic a terminology to failure to follow counsel, yet in the Church, under the priesthood, counsel always is given for the primary purpose of having the law observed, so that it does occupy a place of standing and importance, almost comparable to that law of the gospel.” (<span class="emphasis">BYU Speeches, </span>February 26, 1957.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p19" guid="6211dbab-9371-4708-842d-6e3710461668" pid="YFtGgwTMvkaqdjp_uWyAWg" hash="SFtmxA">President J. Reuben Clark, Jr., pinpointed today’s need: “What we need today is not more prophets. We have the prophets. But what we need is more people with listening ears. That is the great need of our generation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p20" guid="2ca0233d-0360-4d47-8c38-96141873fd4c" pid="83QE0XF6_UyeaH-IPNI7wQ" hash="SfJECg">“There are those who insist that unless the Prophet of the Lord declares, ‘Thus saith the Lord,’ the message may not be taken as revelation. This is a false testing standard. For while many of our modern revelations as contained in the Doctrine and Covenants do contain these words, there are many that do not.” (<span class="emphasis">Church News, </span>July 31, 1954.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p21" guid="32d20dd7-f1c7-4ea7-a6e3-2425f32f244d" pid="2M3_26rElkWeYs-dLx57vQ" hash="u6q3YQ">President Marion G. Romney clarified the responsibility of those who hear the witness of a servant of God: “We who are his present witnesses are but discharging our responsibility when we bring these testimonies of the prophets and our own testimonies … to your attention.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p22" guid="088796b8-da9d-4edb-b69b-8336fc1f747a" pid="rZytIs3y0kWCycbFqQyKug" hash="7wytZA">“To the extent we do bring them to your attention, the responsibility passes from us to you to determine the credibility of the witnesses and their testimonies. Let no man underestimate the importance of his decision concerning this matter.” (<span class="emphasis">Improvement Era, </span>December 1967, p. 100.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p23" guid="b13dc0d1-b667-4fc4-b518-c335f5d69e47" pid="hugKlbUMBkeVTj7K7kCBwQ" hash="fEMszg">It is a privilege to follow the President of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p24" guid="41994fc2-c772-45d1-9525-0094de7c2247" pid="V0EQqnTUOEuscMCzYy4jGQ" hash="8Mq0_g">There will be other General Authorities and prophets and apostles who will counsel us during this conference. May we listen and hear the voice of the Lord, for—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p25" guid="dbab0eae-72b1-47ec-be77-6165b0c98fc5" pid="GvOPOkBRe0GLKXACMXqDKA" hash="-l10vQ">“What I the Lord have spoken, I have spoken, and I excuse not myself; and though the heavens and the earth pass away, my word shall not pass away, but shall all be fulfilled, whether by mine own voice or by the voice of my servants, it is the same.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p26" guid="32d0480f-8a09-46dd-8c6f-84943917984b" pid="H3sJOvxfW0CROD7uhvRefg" hash="DKvLDw">“For behold, and lo, the Lord is God, and the Spirit beareth record, and the record is true, and the truth abideth forever and ever.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.38-39" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:38–39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet.p27" guid="d2ffc32a-8fc6-4127-97b2-ccb3821e9169" pid="yFLYg37ZAkafiBl14mEutQ" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1973/04/what-is-a-living-prophet</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1973-general-conference/1973-04-1020-elder-a-theodore-tuttle-64k-eng.mp3" length="5662529" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 1973 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Fathers</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers?lang=eng</link>
      <description>There is genuine concern over the diminishing role of the father in the home. His influence is fading. Presiding responsibilities formerly assumed are left either to the mother or to agencies outside the home. This diminishing role is at the root of </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03040_000_4050" doc-version="2" hash="zQe1cg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="u7y7Qb1sjkqPhOuzALFv3w" hash="o7-n_Q">The Role of Fathers</h1><p class="authorName" guid="81d9550b-e85c-44db-bd64-f6aff95bc1a0" pid="MlD0KWULMEGg0jOfn8X1Zw" hash="uG5ddw">A. Theodore Tuttle</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="efad48fc-b179-4e77-9a92-ce360234daf1">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p1" guid="6a77fbeb-7107-4a5c-96e2-64fd2a70bb71" pid="m-Y9118ZtEi0V3M6QZ-qpg" hash="Rapvig">There is genuine concern over the diminishing role of the father in the home. His influence is fading. Presiding responsibilities formerly assumed are left either to the mother or to agencies outside the home. This diminishing role is at the root of a multitude of our problems. Numerous things go awry when the scriptural family organization is upset!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p2" guid="d2f94121-8fe4-4f8c-8f9f-eb1439449e8f" pid="UqKg9KPY50C3FQDILXpzxA" hash="M-a74g">The father is the patriarch in the home. This means that the father is the presiding authority. This does not mean that he should be dictatorial. Modern scriptures set forth qualifications for all who preside:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p3" guid="c5c1898e-04be-46ec-84fd-626da24cd3ea" pid="ZfRTnlelvUyJtZucBn6gwA" hash="vHVTCw">“No power or influence can or ought to be maintained by virtue of the priesthood, only by persuasion, by long-suffering, by gentleness and meekness, and by love unfeigned. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.41" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:41</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p4" guid="b0224616-cc2d-47e6-b744-6025e9360f41" pid="MqPOT_CfA0e7Ng7M93uVOw" hash="8TJAjw">In reality, each family is a dominion within itself. Father heads that government. In the beginning it was the only government on the earth and was passed down from Adam to his descendants. Properly organized in the Church, the father is the patriarch of an eternal family unit. Heaven, to us, will be simply an extension of an ideal home. As the presiding priesthood officer, the father fills an irreplaceable role.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p5" guid="cc65b34b-d0ee-4074-8eb3-ad0a1d4bc701" pid="nUThXAeRs0OLkg3-QbPo2Q" hash="d2H8SA">A worthy father who holds the Melchizedek Priesthood should be encouraged to name and bless his children. He should administer to the sick in his home. The father may baptize, confirm, and ordain his children, at the invitation of his file leader in the Church. He may give a father’s blessing. President Joseph Fielding Smith has said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p6" guid="649ab887-cf4a-4c7b-8288-4751ecc01322" pid="vppyNXw2Mk2M_DmHK1ERMQ" hash="nfbvGg">“<span class="emphasis">A faithful father who holds the Melchizedek Priesthood may bless his own children, and that would be a patriarchal (father’s) blessing. </span>Such blessing could be recorded in the family records, but it would not be preserved in the archives of the Church. … in addition, children may receive a blessing by an <span class="emphasis">ordained patriarch. </span>A father blessing his own child could, if he received the inspiration to do so, declare the lineage of the child. As the Patriarch of his home, a father is also a revelator to his family … and, … in this sense stands in line to receive the revelations from the Lord for the good and blessing of that family.” (<span class="emphasis">Doctrines of Salvation, </span>3:172.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p7" guid="96ebec50-0418-421b-98a4-787c352982e6" pid="IbDRLLCJpkuGmFiiziOivQ" hash="nOWCug">The father exercises his spiritual leadership in the home by calling his family to prayer each morning and evening. Weekly family home evening, likewise, is called and presided over by the father, though all others participate.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p8" guid="67073e86-5ab7-4a07-9cbf-4991246681d6" pid="c-IsNvAB7kaD4cosdg5G2A" hash="bQhJow">The father is the protector of the home. He guards it against the intrusion of evil from without. Formerly he protected his home with weapons and shuttered windows. Today the task is more complex. Barred doors and windows protect only against the intrusion of a corporeal creature. It is not an easy thing to protect one’s family against intrusions of evil into the minds and spirits of family members. These influences can and do flow freely into the home. Satan can subtly beguile the children of men in ways we have already mentioned in this conference. He need not break down the door.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p9" guid="e86e69af-ba2b-4f00-9e95-6e6c960db666" pid="H0i5OkVaEU2CKsR8HhGHxw" hash="xu_3OQ">Fathers, you will have to live close to the Lord. Develop a sensitivity to the impressions of the Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p10" guid="54a03d0a-460a-4928-af36-8934ac51507c" pid="WSG7EUlFGUKIMGdEr8FI8g" hash="hhjzRw">There is yet another intrusion into the home that needs to be mentioned. It is an unwise father who carries to his family his daily business cares. They disturb the peace existing there. He should leave his worries at the office and enter his home with the spirit of peace in his heart and with the love of God burning within him. If there is friction, his presence should soothe it. If there is turmoil, he should resolve it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p11" guid="f4994ab7-fb22-4c33-baf2-44892fe14edf" pid="ENflv1Q3eEiw5e-lLUSqkA" hash="QImVQQ">I have a friend, a businessman in this city, who does special ordinance work in the temple. One day I passed him on the street and asked where he was going. “I’m going to the temple. Inside those thick walls, in the quiet serenity of that lovely building,” he said, “I find peace.” Then he added, “There is only one other place in the world where I can find peace—in my own home.” What a compliment to his wife! What a compliment to his children! What a credit to him. This should be the ideal for all fathers—to so live that we can find peace in our homes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p12" guid="876f776d-c2f7-4534-b1d2-f3a00d1c2d26" pid="jmQJD6resUmAJLIIUeuidg" hash="TWXJRg">Fathers, draw close to your children. Learn to communicate. Learn to listen. This means giving a father’s most valuable commodity—time! Only good results occur when a father interviews his sons and daughters regularly. He can know their problems and their hopes. He can align himself with them as their unconditional friend. To the extent we become friends with our children in unconditional love, to that extent we become like our Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p13" guid="f7e023d4-a6a8-42d1-ba7f-d1459d862489" pid="WVOxqgURZ0qRkk-J7p3UFw" hash="rt0cKw">The story is told of an elementary teacher who had students write essays in hopes that it would motivate the fathers to attend a PTA meeting. The fathers came in $4,000 cars and $400 cars—bank president, laborer, clerk, salesman, meter reader, baker, etc.—“every man with a definite estimate of himself in terms of money, skill, and righteousness or looks. … The children’s essays were read at random.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p14" guid="9da92a64-ce97-4a61-8c81-0e0710451dc9" pid="9BAfiQg0VkmqeuY0p5PbMQ" hash="yY92eg">“‘I like my daddy, … he built my doll house, took me coasting, taught me to shoot, helps with my schoolwork, takes me to the park, gave me a pig to fatten and sell.’ Scores of the essays could be reduced in essence to: ‘I like my daddy. He plays with me.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p15" guid="296bbc21-962b-4d26-abe7-9796805dfa34" pid="ZYaUv-MvNke7KAt8F4J8ew" hash="Kt90GQ">“Not one child mentioned his family house, car, neighborhood, food, or clothing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p16" guid="7bc03c14-9c7f-48e0-956c-6a7044c6cfd9" pid="h9WPEblfEUa6DB23HaygWQ" hash="leFHJw">“The fathers went into the meeting from many walks of life; they came out in two classes: companions to their children or strangers to their children.” (“The Savior, the Priesthood, and You,” Melchizedek Priesthood quorums’ course of study for 1973–74, p. 226.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p17" guid="87724da1-8f6a-40c6-85b9-7c596392a6c6" pid="ES6l1YGtTEe04tSF_Lqy7A" hash="0Ho3-g">God help us to be real companions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p18" guid="216006f3-5824-4836-b642-da34707ae5ec" pid="jeFzKiFbvEiX20iW_dJROA" hash="lOkN1Q">A father is a teacher. The Lord has commanded sons and daughters to honor their parents and to give heed to their counsel. The words that open that great volume of scripture, the Book of Mormon, ought to be our guide as fathers: “… having been born of goodly parents, therefore I was taught somewhat in all the learning of my father.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/1.1" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 1:1</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p19" guid="7f560e38-ce87-4ed0-b992-db68ea1b5931" pid="-q4d8yNJRkS0tpBtzJyc3Q" hash="v7IUnQ">Enos, likewise, credited his father for his teachings: “… knowing my father that he was a just man—for he taught me in his language, and also the nurture and admonition of the Lord—and blessed be the name of my God for it. …” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/enos/1.1" class="scriptureRef">Enos 1:1</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p20" guid="8db819c4-789c-4be8-921f-6030d155406d" pid="WO66NLM0YkywYjmQGMfyqQ" hash="AJ4N1A">Have you fathers noticed that the present Melchizedek Priesthood lessons are like father-training lessons? I cite an example:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p21" guid="41bb0ee2-bac4-4e4c-8f67-1fa1491ca898" pid="CthXCN4gRk66RcHn0zqD7A" hash="we076A">“One father and son have an agreement that the son will be in at a specified time. Before the parents retire they set the alarm for that time with the understanding that the son is to turn the alarm off before it rings when he comes home. If it does go off, the son knows that his parents will be waiting for him and further, he will not have the privilege of going out for two weeks. Follow-through on the agreement between them is the key that creates better understanding.” (“The Savior, the Priesthood, and You,” Melchizedek Priesthood quorums’ course of study for 1973–74, p. 237.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p22" guid="05d07861-f8d1-485a-adf4-d14f7139a959" pid="P5T3gEMogE-Lb8f37D3cbA" hash="smqX-Q">Someone has said: “There is no need of searching out your genealogy if you do not know where your children were last night.” Many inspiring suggestions enliven this practical course of study for fathers. I heartily commend this course to strengthen fathers for better spiritual leadership.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p23" guid="887446c0-bbf2-4897-b6a2-7498e85bd626" pid="i1sf569iWk2tV_0jICLCGQ" hash="yAG6aA">Discipline is part of the process of governing children. The Lord has told us how:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p24" guid="c1f8db9e-2236-4107-894b-77aaead5ee13" pid="kyO9NRjlhEeFFyaF7UXKkg" hash="XWkMww">“Reproving betimes with sharpness, when moved upon by the Holy Ghost; and then showing forth afterwards an increase of love toward him whom thou hast reproved, lest he esteem thee to be his enemy.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.43" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:43</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p25" guid="1229fdc9-223a-421d-99ac-f47fffac046e" pid="_WD3ql_xBE6-4pCmKC9gQg" hash="Yw3_ZQ">There has been no better statement of a father-child relationship. When a father wisely corrects his son, it proves his love. Only the unwise foolishly indulge their sons and withhold proper discipline.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p26" guid="7686ad4c-d4f7-4718-bebd-2772233e9a3b" pid="znuhprakqUytTJvWCThqlQ" hash="kShLdg">And finally, the father is to be an example of the highest Christian virtues. To walk uprightly in the admonition of the Lord requires not only patience and forebearance, but an exercise in constant practice of all the Christian virtues by each family member. Perhaps the Lord knew this when he instituted the family. A man needs the responsibility of a wife and family. He needs the responsibility of being an example of righteousness. There is wisdom in this requirement. This kind of gentle persuasion is needed to keep a father “on course” and gently guide him toward perfection.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p27" guid="55a277f4-d725-4ea1-bd9c-5daaa3e9caaa" pid="WaCoOUyXtESYI5R26jEUpw" hash="VYQRvA">In the family relationship, we find our best laboratory in which to practice celestial living. While this task is fraught with much challenge and some adversity, it is, nevertheless, blessed with that supreme joy that can come only to a father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p28" guid="6088cb96-682c-4869-93ad-a76e181b8162" pid="Cdl9M33x0UuL-e9SxC5VHA" hash="tfpb4g">It should have great meaning that of all the titles of respect and honor and admiration that could be given him, that God himself, he who is the highest of all, chose to be addressed simply as “Father.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p29" guid="3e6bcc3f-bf67-4142-9bc3-f7cc7e82b825" pid="9HGGmGu0ikeguECLsVYoow" hash="w_qZng">I am grateful indeed to see the emphasis given by the Church leaders today on the place and position of fathers. There has never been a time in the history of the Church when the importance and place of the Melchizedek Priesthood quorums have been emphasized more and where the activity of fathers has been stressed so much. I know that this is inspired direction by our leaders today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers.p30" guid="8e05dc08-d44d-4c8e-99a2-bb0dd8738df6" pid="wEtNY8fsb0ajGmM8P579xw" hash="2rdm7A">I know that God lives. I know that Jesus is the Christ. I know that he guides this Church through a living prophet on the earth today, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1973/10/the-role-of-fathers</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1973-general-conference/1973-10-4060-elder-a-theodore-tuttle-64k-eng.mp3" length="6355675" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1973 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Mission Preparation</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Young men, I want to counsel you about your future missions. I was once a boy like you. That may seem like a long time ago to you, but to me it’s but a moment. I have passed through every day of every year that you have lived thus far—and much, much </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03050_000_029" doc-version="2" hash="8CdRYw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="m7ytTV-LbUerwkWvF7yVMw" hash="H5sV9g">Your Mission Preparation</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="PFvVBi6Sbkya5nxTamrMxQ" hash="uG5ddw">A. Theodore Tuttle</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27d8.jpg" alt="President A. Theodore Tuttle" pid="9fiwn9AyKEKK2bWM8nlVMA" hash="uF_y9g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p1" pid="DaU-jD2MGkeRPwPYP6hBeg" hash="ANFzkg">Young men, I want to counsel you about your future missions. I was once a boy like you. That may seem like a long time ago to you, but to me it’s but a moment. I have passed through every day of every year that you have lived thus far—and much, much more. I am also a father and I have had much experience with young people during my lifetime.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p2" pid="g2ydICmDx0qIw4VZgmdiBw" hash="XfA9fw">When the prophet of God declares that now is the time to lengthen our stride and to increase our missionary force, now <span class="emphasis">is</span> the time!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p3" pid="8jpzdWxzXEudSPHxUUwLnw" hash="trQp5w">I talked with a young man about a mission. He said, “I don’t want to go.” I asked, “What has that got to do with it? We need you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p4" pid="AkvXjVJ0PUeh3FODsr63bw" hash="d-qKmg">President Kimball has said we don’t have <span class="emphasis">half enough</span> missionaries. Can’t you see that it doesn’t matter whether you want to go or not? You’re needed! Do you know what it means to be needed? The bonds of brotherhood are forged deep and strong in the mission field. You will develop a love for a companion with whom you kneel in daily prayer. You will learn to love the people where you serve, no matter what nationality or condition. And they will love you. They will love you because you brought them the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p5" pid="iM4UN2Mv6UO6iSp0Zx4Ndw" hash="I_R50g">Converts always remember those who taught them. I’ve heard many converts speak almost reverently of “our missionaries.” Imagine having people pray for you. Do you understand what that means? This will always be a purifying and refining influence in your life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p6" pid="SKtD5Va5GkOC2TjcyM5-Nw" hash="Lzafwg">Many people out there are praying for the truth. You are the one who can bring it to them best. At present only 18,000 of you are serving. There are nearly 60,000, 19 through 25, who have not. We need more, many more. Missionary service is not preempted by any other thing. Marriage does not take precedence. Your work does not have priority. Your education is interrupted to fill this calling. College-related activities may be timed to satisfy both school and mission requirements. Some of you may be physically handicapped. There may yet be opportunity to serve in fitting ways locally.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p7" pid="pcPr9UQ0wUuzV2VSEYg_OA" hash="jjRbPw">Your moral worthiness is a prime consideration. We want no flabbiness of character when spiritual strength is required. Study! Get some colored pencils. Keep them with your Book of Mormon. Underline verses important to you. Another tool of missionary work is an additional language. Study one. We should “become acquainted with … languages, tongues, and people.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/90.15" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 90:15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p8" pid="wCE2Kyr_Eky6xKDSPaoZVA" hash="oc91Ng">Learn to pray constantly. Kneel down morning and evening. Get on good terms with the Lord. Like the young man who said: “Whenever I pass the church, I always stop to visit; so when I’m finally carried in, the Lord won’t ask, ‘Who is it?’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p9" pid="lwccrdc97kmysVGqELQSTA" hash="cT4r2g">Remember, young men get hungry whether they are missionaries or not, but especially if they <span class="emphasis">are</span> missionaries. Learn to fry an egg and cook spaghetti. Learn to wash a dish and sew on a button. This isn’t only “girl’s work.” You don’t have that kind of companion in the mission field. If you can’t do it, your companion probably can’t either, and, of course, we don’t want to send your mother along.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p10" pid="cUiUoglYxUWk_askeKO4UQ" hash="X66AJg">Some missionary quarters are not too tidy. That’s because you didn’t learn early to pick up, hang up, fold up, and put away. You could start now, of course, but go slowly or you’ll startle your mother. Shine your shoes. Press your pants. Learn how to wash and starch and iron the cuffs and collars on your shirts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p11" pid="eu8ynj44tkCl50M1PTt-2A" hash="PP3Cag">Fads come and go. Gratefully, we are moving out of the period of the sloppy, hippy-type attire. Take pride in your dress. You might just as well learn now to keep the dress and grooming standards of the Church. If you would cut your hair a little shorter now, it wouldn’t be such a shock later. It not only improves your outward appearance; it actually does something to you inside. In your attempt to follow the styles and be casual, do not offend good taste. When we go to worship the Lord, we ought to be dressed in our finest, cleanest, and best. Some of your fathers could take a tip about this too, but that’s another sermon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p12" pid="P6Wul1pPPk6UwObvxm3VTg" hash="7IQZ3Q">Where will you go on your mission? If you are normal, and we hope you are—in fact that’s one of the requirements—you’ll want to go to some exotic place in a faraway land. Or you’ll want to go where your father went. That’s normal too. There are some young men in this Church who think there is only one true mission—that’s where their fathers served. Have you ever noticed your father when his old mission field is mentioned? He always gets that wistful look, brightens up, and has to take his glasses off and wipe something out of his eye. Every man deserves that warm glow that comes from mere reflection on those marvelous missionary days. So, like others before, you will go where you are called.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p13" pid="ab9TfEg840OuqyBr3Kh-5Q" hash="XdBhSA">Did you know that your bishop must send the president of the Church a report concerning your driving record? He notes any accidents or violations or suspension of your driver’s license. Remember this and keep your record clean.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p14" pid="hSIqy_Vz2Uq737-YKT1pAQ" hash="6q8egA">Young man, it now costs about $130 (U.S.) per month for a mission. By the time you are ready to go it may be even higher. That means you will need between three and four thousand dollars to complete your mission. Some of you don’t have enough. You’ll have to get it. The Lord will help you and your family. You must start early. Counsel with your father. Get a job. Work hard. Save your money. Too many boys play too much, watch TV, and are idle. Open an account where you save by mail. I caution you: Do not squander your missionary funds for a bike, then a scooter, then a car or stereo, and records, etc. Do not rationalize that this is an “investment” which can be transferred into ready cash just before you go. Self-denial and purposeful saving may well be the greatest blessing to come from your missionary service. After you have done everything possible, some of you may need to see your bishop. He may have some helpful suggestions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p15" pid="nScyUB0rQU20-I83njVQJg" hash="PjOo1w">You will be two years older when you return from your mission. Tonight you may think that won’t matter much. I can assure you of one thing, however—there will be some significant changes. To delay courtship and marriage is wise. You might change partners in the process. Many do—both by <span class="emphasis">his</span> choice and <span class="emphasis">hers.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p16" pid="YsaIA16p0kqGkxbHionRqQ" hash="uv5cuA">While a mission does not guarantee a happy and successful marriage, it stabilizes many things in your life that affect your marriage. Growing to maturity in the mission field brings a better marriage partner to both sides of the altar.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p17" pid="OZKuwZ9gbUKMJebIq3IP3A" hash="cjuZdQ">Now, young man, I warn you. Beware of the girl who places a low premium on missionary service. Beware of the girl who teases and tempts, who discourages your mission. You had better be careful. Is this the kind of girl you want for your eternal companion? You would do well to end this relationship.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p18" pid="Cuc0KLDlj0mYwGJWtlk-Nw" hash="kSx9og">You are not too young to gain a testimony and bear it. In a stake conference we called on a young lady to speak. She had just returned from the Hill Cumorah pageant. She bore a fervent testimony. After she finished we called on 17-year-old Gary. He looked surprised when his name was called. He unwound his full six feet and came to the pulpit. His first words were, “I don’t know why the president called on me; I don’t even have a testimony” (referring, evidently, to the testimony borne by the young lady). For several minutes he spoke about seminary, he expressed gratitude for his family, then said: “I know the gospel is true, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p19" pid="YsvF8Nk9H0i9rIJntUoEWw" hash="ZtGNbg">Testimonies come through the gift and power of the Holy Ghost. We gain testimony as we bear testimony. Take opportunity to do so whenever it is appropriate. If you desire a testimony and seek for it, you will receive it. You will have opportunity to bear your witness to thousands. This will have more effect on people than any other thing you do. That’s why you are called—to testify that Jesus is the Christ, that Joseph was a prophet, that this Church is true—with a living prophet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p20" pid="F83tDo2b00OiYLaupuXzOQ" hash="l29MZA">There are many thousands here who are not the captain of the football team, the valedictorian, and the student body president, all in one. Socially, you feel inept. Your grades are not all that good. You are wondering if <span class="emphasis">you</span> can qualify to serve a mission. Young man, fix firmly on your heart a desire to serve the Lord and to declare the gospel: “For I know that he granteth unto men according to their desire, whether it be unto death or unto life.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/29.4" class="scriptureRef">Alma 29:4</a>.) I know this promise is true. The Lord loves you. He needs you. You may not have all of the qualities you would like to have. You have great potential. Some of you have made mistakes. Some have troublesome personal habits. Talk to the Lord about them tonight. If you are greatly troubled, talk to your father. You may even need to see your bishop. Get things straightened out now.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p21" pid="2G9TwOwJ50ObspqfK56qxQ" hash="dc4sbg">The greatest missionaries in the Church have been humble men—men who have paid the price of honest toil, men who lived close to the Lord and relied on him. You too can be numbered among the great. Decide tonight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p22" pid="vI41TAPlhUu-NASFRXQy_A" hash="3FAYXA">Imagine standing in the baptismal font with <span class="emphasis">your</span> convert, raising your right arm to the square, and saying these words: “Having been commissioned of Jesus Christ, I baptize you in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.73" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:73</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p23" pid="fih7aauJmECuZiML4jd5Jg" hash="oj2C7A">You may make the winning touchdown, cross the finish line first, swish down the mountain on perfect powder, drive “a beauty” to the left-field stands, or pitch a no-hitter. You may do and thrill to many things. But you will experience few feelings equal to the quiet, even tearful moment when you record in your diary: “Today we baptized Mr. and Mrs. Brown and all their children. They are a fantastic family!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation.p24" pid="X3bCF04F80CKzZ23pUz6ow" hash="YQaaWA">I know that God lives. I know that Jesus is the Christ. I know that Joseph Smith was a prophet. I know that President Spencer W. Kimball is the living prophet on the earth today, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/10/your-mission-preparation</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1974-general-conference/1974-10-5020-president-a-theodore-tuttle-64k-eng.mp3" length="7029101" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 1974 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Come Drink the Living Water</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water?lang=eng</link>
      <description>There is a large relief sculpture on the wall of the church I attended as a boy. It depicts the Savior and the woman of Samaria at Jacob’s well. As a little boy, I pondered on the tree, the well, the Savior, the woman, the city in the distance, and t</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03057_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="dVZHIw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="p3mUiFul_kKOSMQRD2ZfXg" hash="xNvjXw">Come Drink the Living Water</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="QDEvg1X5MUi1Z27FZLegoQ" hash="uG5ddw">A. Theodore Tuttle</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27d8.jpg" alt="Elder A. Theodore Tuttle" pid="M1D-ZAn9cUOzQ8JhNeVglg" hash="uF_y9g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p1" pid="WZxwDuiIjUWe_PP9GsGWxw" hash="XAtVTw">There is a large relief sculpture on the wall of the church I attended as a boy. It depicts the Savior and the woman of Samaria at Jacob’s well. As a little boy, I pondered on the tree, the well, the Savior, the woman, the city in the distance, and the approach of the disciples. As I grew older, I learned more about the account as recorded in John. In later years I have reflected on the message the Savior taught the woman of Samaria.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p2" pid="RxSZIm4X50-6go7FjNIuVA" hash="XrJY9Q">“Jesus saith unto her, Give me to drink.” The woman was amazed that he would talk to her. The Master said: “If thou knewest the gift of God, and who it is that saith to thee, Give me to drink; thou wouldest have asked of him, and he would have given thee living water.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/4.7,9-10" class="scriptureRef">John 4:7, 9–10</a>.) It is evident that she was talking about well water and he was talking about “living water.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p3" pid="FdSm9-fZHEuaeOLvmyWBog" hash="miGtbA">This difficulty of understanding about water recalls the story of a sailing ship that had become disabled in a storm. It drifted aimlessly for many days. The crew and passengers became famished and parched from lack of food and water. Finally another ship came into view. They signaled frantically for water. The other ship replied, “Let down your buckets where you are.” This communication made no sense at all, for they supposed they were far out to sea in typical ocean water. Again the famished ones requested water. Again the signal came, “Let down your buckets where you are.” They could not know that they had drifted into the mouth of a great river and that the water beneath them was fresh and could save their lives. The water of life lay just beneath them, yet they were dying for lack of this knowledge.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p4" pid="WxWuPMPgJEKtcNj8S5u9Gg" hash="eLxmZQ">Like those passengers, multitudes of people are thirsting for “living water,” and they know not where to find it. Like the people on the other ship, we are signaling that we have found the “living water.” It has brought us the abundant life. It has made us happy, healthy, and serene. We who enjoy the abundant life want to share this happiness. You, too, may want to drink of this “living water.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p5" pid="t4RpQphiF0e8gob8zujf3w" hash="laCYNQ">A friend of mine told me this experience: A financially successful man came home from work one day and said, “Dear, there has got to be more to life than just getting up, going to work, making money, watching TV, eating and sleeping, and then doing it all over again! We have all the money we need. Why doesn’t this satisfy us? Somehow we are missing the purpose of life. What is our dilemma? Could it be possible that it is religion we are missing?” In the conversation that followed, his wife mentioned the Mormons. After serious investigation they soon found satisfying answers to their questions and joined the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p6" pid="QGVZ5QwqAke2kndvh74B0A" hash="arm9Dw">You ought to know that the greatest problem in The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is the problem of growth. The Church needs to complete a building nearly every day in order to keep up with the growth. Although the Church has been maligned and scoffed at over the years, today it is becoming recognized as the one church whose members enjoy the abundant life spoken of by the Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p7" pid="QEOCKPn5J0Wc4h2lpGDnGA" hash="f2-GXw">In the next few minutes I would like to explain why this message appeals to people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p8" pid="S05zM_MI30uITQfG1uoY2A" hash="Bve9Dw">This message appeals to men because in the Church you are the head of your family. Your proper role is provider, spiritual leader, father. In the Church, the priesthood is available. For instance, you may baptize your children, bless you wife when she is ill, perform other church ordinances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p9" pid="UpM6iStREEWg97FmzUCDpw" hash="aG4-6g">When you join the Church, you are generally called to positions of service as an officer or teacher. You are able to give talks in church or visit other families and see to their temporal and spiritual needs. You soon discover that everything about the Church strengthens your family. You will enjoy a weekly family home evening. You will find strength and peace in daily family prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p10" pid="cyimK0JtRkC4pxXzYutzNA" hash="jddUkw">This message appeals to men because in the Church you become a better man. You are better physically because you keep the Word of Wisdom and avoid those things harmful to your body. You are better spiritually because your goals are clarified. You learn more about your relationship with your Heavenly Father. You are motivated to be a more understanding father, a more faithful husband. You will find that the Church fills every need and fosters every virtue of manhood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p11" pid="4JHohVwAskqbVF9EQOy39g" hash="ff3m6Q">The Church appeals to you women because you find your true identity as a woman and a person. You are glorified in your unique role as a wife and mother. Whether you are married or single, you will be a member of the oldest and largest women’s organization in the world. You will continue to learn in fields of special interest to women: cultural refinement, spiritual living, social relations, and homemaking. The feminine virtues of a woman are strengthened by the Church. Your companionship with your husband can be eternal, as also your relationship to your family. You will have an outlet for your special talents of compassionate service in satisfying ways that develop and fulfill your womanly virtues.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p12" pid="bxQP7wtw1Um3QrjEn3Yghg" hash="h1Jh0Q">And now to you young people. In the Church you will find that you won’t sit in the bleachers and watch. You will be on the team. You will play basketball and softball, baseball and tennis, checkers and Ping-Pong, volleyball and golf. There is much to do. You will be able to help with service projects. You will give talks, be in plays, sing in choruses, compose skits. You are the leaders, advised by adults. You young men get to be missionaries and declare the gospel of Jesus Christ someplace in the world for two years at your own expense. You young ladies get to give them up while they serve. Somehow all this works out well and makes better marriage partners of both.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p13" pid="SbXJqwBik0mj2vOnlYE_Vg" hash="ERFn9g">In a lonely world, brotherhood in the Church really means something. Everyone needs to be loved. Everyone needs to be needed. Everyone has some kind of talent and wants to use it. Somehow in the magic of this marvelous organization you can find your place and make your contribution. When you serve, you find purpose to life. The Church hath need of every member. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.110" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:110</a>.) You need not be alone. We are a busy and active people and love to serve each other. Whether you are young or old, married or single, you are needed in the Church. You get involved in wholesome activities that build and strengthen friendships.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p14" pid="DgCIEl1gnk-gYCFl4lkuWg" hash="fUUC3w">People live longer nowadays. There are more older people. You who are older are not left without something to do. We need the power and energy of youth. We also need the wisdom of age. Classes need both teacher and students. You never cease to learn in the Church. We need you. Many people work in the temple each day. The temple environment is next to heaven itself, and you associate among the best.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p15" pid="vZ7MD6aYXEel4ZO3MQgscQ" hash="SU6psg">Despite medical marvels, ill health and early death still rob men not only of life but of the zest for life. We are a healthy people. I quote briefly from a recent report in the <span class="emphasis">Washington, D.C. Post:</span> “Mormons neither drink nor smoke, and they stress clean living. They also die of cancer at half the rate of other Californians. This is not surprising, since many cancers—especially cancer of the lungs, one of the biggest killers—have been linked to tobacco and alcohol.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p16" pid="lM2C-G7qTU6KHXuFxmsIgQ" hash="7hUc8g">“Moreover, among Mormons in Utah, the annual cancer rate is approximately 2 Mormons for every 3 non-Mormons.” (“Lower Cancer Toll Is Found for Mormons in Calif. Study,” Nov. 18, 1974.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p17" pid="np1ncfFRQ0uj8b-U77IEpw" hash="tOWCeg">Dr. Harry Schwartz, professor of the College of Physicians and Surgeons, has said, “Statistics show Utah is the healthiest state in the 48, if not the entire union. If you believe the statistics, any sensible person would pack up and move to Utah.” He suggested three areas which might be looked into as part of the explanation—the Mormon dietary laws, genetics, and the lack of poverty. (<span class="emphasis">Salt Lake Tribune,</span> Sept. 21, 1974.) Our health record is unusual.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p18" pid="7QIkDWJhDE2ZDFxfPTkJqg" hash="_LGKcA">We believe and obey a revelation from God. It says “wine or strong drink … is not good. … Tobacco is not for the body, … hot drinks (meaning tea and coffee) are not for the body.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/89.5-9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 89:5–9</a>.) Obedience to this law qualifies us to receive the promised blessings: we shall receive health, wisdom, strength, and protection. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/89.18-21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 89:18–21</a>.) We do not worry. We have an inner peace and quietude. Even knowing the calamities we may face, we know we will have the promised blessings and protection of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p19" pid="dKyF2kecPkmWOqOVuau4Fw" hash="kL7teQ">The Church appeals to people—because it is true! All of the other reasons are secondary to this one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p20" pid="lEbh2myKPEeW-bPhPpXpaQ" hash="FybGxA">The Church was founded by God the Eternal Father and his Son Jesus Christ through a personal visitation to the earth. They called Joseph Smith to be a prophet. The Church contains the fulness of the gospel. All the principles and ordinances that pertain to the abundant life are here. The Church is built upon the foundation of apostles and prophets. The priesthood authority rests with the Church. The restoration and rise of the Church in the latter days fulfills scriptural prophecy. The other scriptures—the Book of Mormon, the Doctrine and Covenants, and the Pearl of Great Price clarify and sustain the Bible. They testify that Jesus is the Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p21" pid="xpuenN11cUaxAlF1VwthbQ" hash="7shrrw">In the latter-day scriptures the Lord speaks of “the only true and living church upon the face of the whole earth, with which I, the Lord, am well pleased.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.30" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:30</a>.) There is much difference between a dead and living church. While one may have the form and shape, the ritual and dimension, the living church has life. A living prophet leads the Church today. There is a vibrant, living movement to it, a captivating spirit about it, a glory to it that lifts and builds and helps and blesses the lives of all it touches. The Church will move forward to its divine destiny with or without you, because it is true. Everything else in the Church is built upon the foundation of truth. That is why the Church grows so rapidly. That is why the message appeals to families. That is why, in the lonely world, brotherhood means so much. That is why we have a feeling of calm assurance, purpose, and peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p22" pid="ctmCDvZUhUaDXwGsmWF7EQ" hash="7QCeAA">Every member is entitled to a personal testimony that these things of which I have spoken are true.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water.p23" pid="4qjvbJlmDEiQKgw1BlRI8A" hash="Bs9Jpg">We have tasted of the living water, for we know the source. Like those on the rescue ship, we signal to you, “Let down your buckets where you are.” Like the passengers on the ill-fated ship, it may seem strange to you to learn that salvation has been so near to you all the time. Listen to the message. Try to understand it. Honestly test the truth of our message. You may drink freely of the waters of life found in the living Church. We invite all men to come and share our joy and truth and peace. I bear my solemn testimony that it is found in the Church, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/04/come-drink-the-living-water</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1975-general-conference/1975-04-6040-elder-a-theodore-tuttle-64k-eng.mp3" length="7135502" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 1975 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Prophet’s Faith</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We miss Milton R. Hunter today. He was a great and able servant and a loyal friend. On behalf of President S. Dilworth Young and the First Council of the Seventy, I extend a hearty welcome to Elder Gene Cook as a member of the First Council. He comes</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03063_000_010" doc-version="3" hash="ZkAAEg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="Zk88jD-LW0OJRL0KAHYjPw" hash="heB0yQ">A Prophet’s Faith</h1><p class="authorName" pid="mwRnGbEcVUmMC9HJb4PRGg" hash="uG5ddw">A. Theodore Tuttle</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27d8.jpg" alt="Elder A. Theodore Tuttle" pid="wAUk13pyCkaX1KhdVariaQ" hash="uF_y9g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p1" pid="Gcui132g2UuSvAEm8VofrA" hash="7GVzew">We miss Milton R. Hunter today. He was a great and able servant and a loyal friend. On behalf of President S. Dilworth Young and the First Council of the Seventy, I extend a hearty welcome to Elder Gene Cook as a member of the First Council. He comes well qualified, well trained, and with tremendous capacity. He loves the Lord; he knows the work and is completely dedicated. We are delighted, as we feel all of you are, with the announcement to organize the First Quorum of the Seventy. We welcome wholeheartedly the first three members of this quorum: Elder Charles Didier, Elder William Bradford, and Elder George Lee. These men are stalwarts, men of proven ability. They are great missionaries, and we look forward to the privilege of working with them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p2" pid="O3M6rtw9ckKkjgIjJ0s_qw" hash="JUA6Fg">There is great power in faith. “Faith is the moving cause of all action. …” (Joseph Smith, <span class="emphasis">Lectures on Faith,</span> p. 8.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p3" pid="nJZWBJ6w2kO-vHb7tKFGYQ" hash="PcK9Jw">The Prophet Joseph said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p4" pid="sKoOp0HYCkOIRd2cmr3Nsg" hash="QfdvXw">“It was by faith that the worlds were framed. God spake, chaos heard, and worlds came into order by reason of the faith there was in Him. So with man also; he spake by faith in the name of God, and the sun stood still, [and] the moon obeyed, mountains removed, prisons fell.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p5" pid="FPrFp9tawk6WVH0g50nD-A" hash="-Fz8Nw">“Had it not been for the faith which was in men, they might have spoken to the sun, the moon, the mountains, prisons … in vain!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p6" pid="Av0t2kQwWUaI3ZfMfEFhhg" hash="N-FO1Q">“Faith, then, is the first great governing principle which has power, dominion, and authority over all things; … Without it there is no power, and with out power there could be no creation nor existence!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p7" pid="AfxtV9DWDkaSnTnpz0Uyfw" hash="b6OJxw">“When a man works by faith he works by mental exertion instead of physical force. It is by words, instead of exerting his physical powers, with which every being works when he works by faith.” (<span class="emphasis">Lectures on Faith,</span> pp. 9–10, 61.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p8" pid="rZF9xJQ9Mk-583_NMaJ3sA" hash="uDdvrw">I believe there are basically two kinds of faith. The kind of which I have spoken—faith that God lives and rules in the heavens—sustains us in life’s challenges. It enables us to endure without yielding, and bear the trials common to us all. This faith has characterized the lives of this people all through their history. It is a great legacy to inherit and to bequeath.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p9" pid="y8Jz7P8eakC7w8JgdYSRZg" hash="EI1xtQ">There is another kind of faith: more powerful, less known, infrequently observed. This faith in God compounds our ability to accomplish our righteous desires. It is the creative, and generative kind of faith. This is the faith save for the exercise of which things would not happen. This is the great causative force in human lives. This is the faith that moves mountains.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p10" pid="I_34Hscay0SBbWB2B_vzTQ" hash="t59cbA">The scriptures teach that certain powers of heaven are governed by the faith of mortal men. The Lord’s ability to help us succeed is limited only by our faith in him. “For if there be no faith among the children of men God can do no miracle among them; wherefore, he showed not himself [unto them] until after their faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p11" pid="NrRVTB2Krkielm8YYm94lg" hash="PPwRGA">“Neither at any time hath any wrought miracles until after their faith; wherefore they first believed in the Son of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.12,18" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:12, 18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p12" pid="_Nix3QKoBUKed7RPgFfC9A" hash="0-M5Mw">Just as faith without works is dead, likewise, works without faith are dead. We can cause righteous desires to come to pass, for in the words of our Master, “According to your faith be it unto you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/9.29" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 9:29</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p13" pid="Exl2k2iahUG9RIHARenXpw" hash="XAp7SA">In the last eighteen months, I’ve watched this kind of faith <span class="emphasis">cause</span> things to happen. It began with a prophet. He spoke. His words put spiritual forces into action that heretofore had been dormant. People acted. They repented. They changed. Events changed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p14" pid="Uofh3gAti0Sk0_XhdUjBHA" hash="b3yuGg">A prophet not only prophesies of things that will happen. A prophet, by the exercise of faith, causes things to happen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p15" pid="ia4U6j0U5kiQX1ZHsc8X0w" hash="VCfLCA">Let me tell you what has happened since the prophet spoke.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p16" pid="PxMpWHTyVkmvheUl7F4ISw" hash="pzZ42g">He asked for more missionaries—and more came! They came from areas of the world where they have never come from before—and in greater numbers. At first they came by ones and twos, then by scores, then hundreds, now by thousands. Hearts are touched. Lives are changed. Youth responds. Sacrifice increases. Parents weep for joy. A prophet is made glad.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p17" pid="cGNwoLAJf0OHTrsPs4T4oQ" hash="MoDtVQ">Usually people don’t listen to statistics, but these are impressive. Eighteen months ago in Brazil they had only forty local Brazilian missionaries. Today they have over one hundred. Elsewhere in South America, Mexico, Asia, the islands of the sea, Europe, and other areas of the world, there is similar response.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p18" pid="LsJMElyW0Uisp5YHr-VV7A" hash="ka-VfA">Eighteen months ago, in all the missions of the world combined, there were 17,600 missionaries. At that time our projections indicated that we might possibly have as many as 19,000 by this year’s end. Already we have more than 21,000! By year’s end we will have more than 22,000.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p19" pid="QtFGqrausEu30tlquF8CCQ" hash="7Gdmxg">Let me tell what really happens when missionaries serve.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p20" pid="X54ICMVvnEOhkEB8B53uXQ" hash="qId_rQ">We had a neighbor boy who regularly passed our place headed for the mailbox, impatiently awaiting his letter of call. It seemed unusually long in coming after his recommendation was sent in. I observed this scene the day his letter came. He opened it at the mailbox, called his friend over, and they rejoiced together. Then he figuratively bounced down the lane to share the good news with his family. A few minutes later his sixteen-year-old sister came strolling by, headed home. I merely mentioned in a greeting that her brother had received his mission call. She instantly changed her pace and ran all the way home to join in the excitement of her brother’s call. Think of the anticipation, the joy, that gladdens hundreds of homes and hundreds of hearts each week—for this is a family call.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p21" pid="FL3FWawtx0GpCbw0vn6dYA" hash="9_TaMw">Not only does this service bless the homes from which missionaries come, it blesses lives where missionaries go. One young lady who worked among the Indian people wrote: “The Navajo are a great people. Words can’t express my love for them. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p22" pid="9-iVqfqU4EWL-Hs_DknzrA" hash="dR6hwQ">“The Navajo people accepted me, a white girl, as one of their own. They called me their white daughter. I had a hard time with the language, but I could teach by reading the lessons. I was very fortunate to have Navajo companions who could explain in detail. We could communicate with love. I learned that love is the greatest language to know. This people loved me and I loved them. We spoke with smiles, laughter, and sometimes tears. They were patient with my broken Navajo and helped me when I couldn’t think of a word. I left with a testimony in my heart and a feeling that cannot be described in words. …”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p23" pid="aH02R33bGECdPSFCbaI9-g" hash="Qkgj9w">She concludes with, “In December I met a returned missionary. We fell in love and have been married in the temple.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p24" pid="BDuuGzS74UWvHGmseffT0w" hash="0w5klA">While we lived in South America, our eldest son reached the age to fill a mission. He was the first missionary to leave our little branch composed mainly of converts. The closing prayer at his farewell was offered by one of the new converts. He expressed this thought: “Heavenly Father, we have seen missionaries come. They have blessed our lives. Now we see that we must send missionaries. Help us to rear our sons to serve.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p25" pid="n7mjBJR3DkO5zNmHKsIlag" hash="O77ivg">That prayer of faith was answered. When that man’s son was nineteen, he was called to go to Italy. I received this note about him from the president of the branch where he labored.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p26" pid="HTyz28bwkkqTxIEimMeWSQ" hash="PkJCTg">“We have known Elder LaBuonora since he arrived six months ago. … In the short time he has been here he has baptized nine people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p27" pid="1QJ-hUTrp0KzS0SDOyQSaw" hash="0FWOtA">“Because you knew him before, I share a little experience. We were visiting one of our sick members in the hospital. … In the ward of about twenty people, there was a three-year-old boy whose mother had abandoned him when he was born. He has had no one to love him. The child was playing in his crib and needed his nose wiped. So Elder LaBuonora wiped his nose with the tenderness of a real father, held him in his arms for a minute, kissed him, and put him gently back in bed. The expression on the child’s face was a mixture of surprise and security. We believe this young man is the greatest missionary we have seen. What a blessing he is to our mission and branch.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p28" pid="y_nu2QfUpECWHyorbHqF4Q" hash="KVrJ5g">It is a further evidence of faith to note that President LaBuonora, the father who prayed that they could rear their sons to serve, has since sent his second son into the mission field.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p29" pid="dHbd5P7CXkWt0pb_PA2Dlw" hash="6L69Nw">On a recent flight, a young lady missionary sat by Sister Tuttle and me. She didn’t know us when she sat down and started a conversation. When she discovered who I was, she exclaimed disappointedly, “Oh, darn, I can’t give you a Book of Mormon. I wanted to share three before I reach New Zealand.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p30" pid="-LUINt34EE2KKQVY4hrXpg" hash="fsdktw">Brothers and sisters, we face another challenge: to become missionaries. We have not been as successful in doing this as we have been in providing missionaries. This is an opportunity for all of us to exercise this second kind of faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p31" pid="cMMoxm5q4UOF8HkjCJ-ceQ" hash="3VWR1g">We need to set personal and family goals. Make the achievement of these goals a matter of earnest prayer. Exercise our faith in God, and cause success to come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p32" pid="qAVCIUyZDEmd6e-2SQ3X5w" hash="8_RJwg">Eighteen months ago President Kimball said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p33" pid="RswUZewxVUuhPEGiRR9OKQ" hash="h77rnQ">“In our stake and district missionary work, … we have hardly scratched the surface. … I believe the time has come when we must … change our sights and raise our goals. …” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Oct. 1974, p. 14.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p34" pid="E5sC3BPe8Uao8JR1nyW-Zw" hash="21VKtQ">Stake missionary work is a great sleeping giant but it is beginning to stir. We now expect all stake presidents to give greater attention to this work, to do three things: (1) develop stake goals and (2) see that your seventies are organized correctly and functioning properly in order to (3) assist every family to share the gospel with another. In this work every member must lengthen his stride, as our leader has done—a fact so beautifully attested to this morning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p35" pid="TYfdOiQf6kKqYsx5uBxdPw" hash="CVmStA">There is a place for everyone in the Church to serve as a missionary—either at home or abroad, for people on this side of the veil or on the other.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p36" pid="cQRMU6PQ6kuG5OSql4MKsw" hash="8o9P1g">Eighteen months ago one man expressed his faith that missionary work could be improved, become more efficient, and more productive. At that time it seemed impossible. Immediately, however, his counselors joined their faith with his faith and it was trebled. Then the Twelve joined with them and Church leaders and many members have compounded that faith again and again. Faith called forth faith and a mighty work moves forward.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p37" pid="KSIP0TOAbUK_Hb7PqG6SIw" hash="A8OgyA">Our salvation and the salvation of all of our Father’s children will be determined by our obedience to the counsel of the living prophet. May we arise and exercise greater faith in God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith.p38" pid="CI-m4CH_oku5pPCM2aT_Lw" hash="hZMA0Q">I bear witness that this work is true and that President Kimball is a living prophet. In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/10/a-prophets-faith</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1975-general-conference/1975-10-2030-elder-a-theodore-tuttle-64k-eng.mp3" length="11472322" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extending Missionary Service</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I am grateful to the Brethren of the First Presidency for the call extended me to serve in the First Council. I pledge my best efforts to fulfill this call honorably.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service" dup-mag="false" dup-conf="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03076_000_011" doc-version="2" hash="qwlUZw">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="WmV46OYZiEivjq2AnMiYgw" hash="DFezEQ">Extending Missionary Service</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="SM0rPE4jKkGD_Wr8BDR9Rw" hash="uG5ddw">A. Theodore Tuttle</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.t1">
			<img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27d8.jpg" alt="Elder A. Theodore Tuttle" pid="26wH1dSE1UWYY-VMceZzOw" hash="uF_y9g" />
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p1" pid="whFSVE8p-UayCTGCTs8LcQ" hash="nfrJ1Q">I am grateful to the Brethren of the First Presidency for the call extended me to serve in the First Council. I pledge my best efforts to fulfill this call honorably.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p2" pid="VtyMsWdL4EWuAw52eSwQ2g" hash="eoUrxQ">Our beloved president formerly supervised South America. As I have traveled in this area, scores of members have asked me to express their love to you, President Kimball. I am happy to bring you their <span class="emphasis">“saludos y gran amor.”</span>
			</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p3" pid="iVa5G3Tv70CRKCf6ji2I6w" hash="pBdC5Q">In these lands there are hundreds of young men striving to fulfill President Kimball’s request to serve full-time missions. Meager funds, scarce resources, hard life, and devastating inflation make this extremely difficult. Jobs are available, but pay is low. Where a young man has no family resources on which to draw, it would require many <span class="emphasis">years</span> to earn sufficient to finance himself completely.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p4" pid="iwKWLGUfzk2Uq2_-bvUK_g" hash="cVLvPg">Other difficulties compound the challenge: some young men are a financial support to their family. Merely losing a breadwinner in order to fill a mission constitutes a tremendous sacrifice on the part of the whole family. Sometimes the young person is the only Church member and lacks parental support.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p5" pid="6HGLNtkWskG_SwWGu_GqfA" hash="u7w03A">Of course, some families can and do support their sons. Remember, however, that the Church is new in these lands. In five of the eight missions where I serve, the Church is less than twelve years old. In the other three it is less than twenty, with the major growth occurring recently.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p6" pid="FltmYqyX4kibB_g0TbjnGg" hash="96FBqA">Indeed, the Church is new to all families who have recently joined. They have not yet developed Latter-day Saint traditions. They have not had years to look forward to and prepare for missions.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p7" pid="EuYnmEX3ZkqcK9cm7_o1OA" hash="vw2uvg">In future years we can and will become better prepared. And yet, it is Church policy not to call anyone to serve a mission who has not made substantial personal and family sacrifice. We have literally hundreds of young men who through great sacrifice can procure only part of the funds necessary to finance their missions. Still, these fine young people present themselves to their leaders with a seriousness of purpose. They are ready to serve with deep spirituality and testimony, ready with their native language—a greater blessing than most of you can appreciate—ready with everything we require except sufficient money.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p8" pid="3lEPb4fkOkmNdjgUinxyJg" hash="dmvJhA">In the Church we do not send bills. There are times, however, when it would be appropriate to make known a special need. You no doubt would want to know, therefore, that the First Presidency has established a Church missionary fund. Presently it is being methodically depleted. Since we do not normally appeal for money over the pulpit, I wouldn’t do that. Now that I have carefully avoided asking for funds, you should nevertheless be advised that if you were to put something in the mail for the missionary fund, it certainly would not be refused.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p9" pid="Av2c7HjicUWVd8deUCj1tQ" hash="fA4jFA">Let me tell you of some young people I know who have tried to provide for their missions, to whom you might provide additional help. A mother approached a mission president with this plea: “Could I get my son on a mission somehow? He’s my only hope! Unfortunately, his father is unable to provide well for the family. We have eight children. Our income is very meager. We eat only two meals a day. But this is a good boy. He wants to serve a mission. If we are very, very careful, we can provide a few pesos per month. Isn’t there some way he could serve a mission?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p10" pid="5Qjlads7E02TqmX-zUSd4w" hash="jIMRXw">Another young man lived on the outskirts of a large metropolitan area. There were no lights or water in the thin-walled, modest structure that served both as a home and a small shop. After his family’s conversion he attended seminary and developed an insatiable desire to learn. With great effort he entered the university, working part-time to buy books as well as to help support the family. When the desire to go on a mission became overwhelming, he had to double his efforts to save money for his mission. So he carried his books under one arm and his bag of wash rags, wax, and sponges in the other. Between classes he would go out and wash cars, then return for another class. The Lord blessed him with work. He multiplied his income until his leaders felt he had made the necessary sacrifice to help sustain himself.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p11" pid="idBUtNFLc0SvPezpt-r9WA" hash="q7zl7Q">There are scores of others, each one a lesson to all in the principle of obedience and sacrifice. A young lady with a great desire to fill a mission was counseled to buy ingredients, make cookies, and sell them at school during lunchtime. She did so. Then she bought more flour, baked more cookies, and continued this process for weeks, making a small amount of money each day to help toward her mission.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p12" pid="TtOkBGRpHkC4iapRHwyIuQ" hash="3MhA9Q">Are there not thousands of you listening today who are ready to match these two precious years of a young man’s life with sufficient additional funds from your abundance so that he can have the privilege of service? In this way, could you not become “nursing fathers and mothers” to these children of promise?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p13" pid="t-Obt65RI0u2jpVkX5ublA" hash="hOnILw">I call this matter to your attention for two reasons: First, time is of the essence! We need to get moving with the things of real import. The world <span class="emphasis">must</span> hear the gospel. Paul asks: “How shall they believe in him of whom they have not heard? and how shall they hear without a preacher? And how shall they preach, except they be sent?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/10.14-15" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 10:14–15</a>.) And I ask, how shall they be sent today without sufficient means?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p14" pid="qT9pETiWiUaPdL8kHJIjxQ" hash="DjSzXw">The second reason is the Lord counsels rather specifically about the wise use of property. “Seek ye first the kingdom of God, and his righteousness; and all these things shall be added unto you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.33" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 6:33</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p15" pid="oE5aFXecGE2-aZ0xw8jbNw" hash="-VNbTw">Jacob counsels:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p16" pid="_b7RZycXdUOqw51wBuofcA" hash="fbXD9A">“Think of your brethren like unto yourselves, and be familiar with all and free with your substance, that they may be rich like unto you.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p17" pid="gmh8GfISZ0CeNSuFn4-Kgw" hash="lmOLVQ">“But before ye seek for riches, seek ye for the kingdom of God.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p18" pid="nzjInvtyDUqr_V02V2Tzmw" hash="SWpEbQ">“And after ye have obtained a hope in Christ ye shall obtain riches … to clothe the naked, and to feed the hungry, and to liberate the captive, and administer relief to the sick and the afflicted.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/2.17-19" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 2:17–19</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p19" pid="pjqDbR2HxUuw_KX7WRn-nA" hash="DjbUYg">How blessed we would be if we could pattern our conduct after the Nephites described by Alma:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p20" pid="-EAgzcV2-0yJWNuA1hJglQ" hash="XhgOiQ">“And thus, in their prosperous circumstances, they did not send away any who were naked, or that were hungry, or that were athirst, or that were sick, or that had not been nourished; and they did not set their hearts upon riches; therefore they were liberal to all, both old and young, both bond and free, both male and female, whether out of the church or in the church.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/1.30" class="scriptureRef">Alma 1:30</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p21" pid="EX8xQDH2L06G8VUWenYJNw" hash="tDtg4Q">In our day the Lord has warned us sternly, “And again, I command thee that thou <span class="emphasis">shalt not covet thine own</span> property, but impart it freely.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/19.26" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 19:26</a>, italics added.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service.p22" pid="qKSaUxe6RE2xus_v6NNCww" hash="2w8idA">My brethren, we have been too casual about these matters in the past. There is work to do. We need your help to do it. The word is <span class="emphasis">urgency</span> and the time is <span class="emphasis">now.</span> Many of you have the power to open doors of opportunity for the service of others. May you see this opportunity as a means to wisely use the property with which the Lord has blessed you to help His work and to save your souls. I know many of you already contribute. I know He will keep His promises to you if you will keep your promises to serve. I testify that God lives. Jesus is the Christ. This is His church. This is His earth—and all things in it. We are but stewards over His goods. May we delight to share them, and may we realize the promise that “he who doeth the works of righteousness shall receive his reward, even peace in this world, and eternal life in the world to come.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:23</a>.) In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/10/extending-missionary-service</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1976-general-conference/1976-10-2020-elder-a-theodore-tuttle-64k-eng.mp3" length="4652313" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 1976 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Service Saves</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The last time I spoke from this pulpit I explained a special need to help local missionaries from some of the missions in South America. In most of these countries the annual income averages less than 10 percent of what it is here. I explained that t</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03089_000_022" doc-version="2" hash="V4bcYQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="Ewu_c7h4u0-ikpXwQ9XJtw" hash="wiSFug">Service Saves</h1><p class="authorName" pid="XBF0B7mJNUGcslT36DIs1A" hash="uG5ddw">A. Theodore Tuttle</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27d8.jpg" alt="Elder A. Theodore Tuttle" pid="yaFX5Q-ixUOmtCRRSJFVaQ" hash="uF_y9g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p1" pid="UE2TBxPJGk69fZae-sr-Ug" hash="U-zDmA">The last time I spoke from this pulpit I explained a special need to help local missionaries from some of the missions in South America. In most of these countries the annual income averages less than 10 percent of what it is here. I explained that these young people had already sacrificed much, and that they would need additional financial help from those of us who could easily share. I didn’t really appeal for funds. I outlined a need.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p2" pid="IVNSD3CLUkqXTiJmF5LbOg" hash="y4h5Sw">This is my first opportunity to express thanks to so many for helping these missionaries—even without being asked! I can’t imagine what would have happened if we had actually asked for help! One lady wrote, “You so carefully avoided asking for funds that you also avoided telling us where to send them.” I should repent of that. I’m really hesitant—but you all know where Church headquarters are!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p3" pid="_RiLAqPn-ECUApogb6WFhw" hash="aFN_cw">Some letters came to me personally. They are as heartwarming as the stories of need. One lady sent a generous first monthly check and had her niece write: “Some question my ability to help so much on my small income. But I want to do my part; and if I do, the Lord will take care of me.” She was ninety-nine, disabled, and blind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p4" pid="AG8Jlb6eE0Kk9EnMo29NSg" hash="-YSnBw">A nickel and four pennies were taped to a card over the printed signature of a five-year-old whose mother wrote his message: “I love Heavenly Father. I’m giving part of my allowance to a missionary.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p5" pid="yVI-l87Rrki7mayT2G2WFA" hash="P1O22w">A youngster, fifteen, said, “I didn’t think two dollars would matter much. But my dad said if everyone in the Church sent two dollars, it would be over six million—and that’s not too bad!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p6" pid="tVLnc-TCjkm5Ue3JiHL6Mg" hash="UCDZ3w">Another wrote: “As a father of eight sons, I know how disappointing it would be for me if any of my sons was unable to serve a mission because of lack of finances. Enclosed is some help.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p7" pid="iDTxe--nN0axjv1UfPInPA" hash="8swCIw">An elderly couple, remembering their temple vows, said: “We have sent seven of our own children. We know it takes more money now than then.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p8" pid="i7yl7kHApE2gkK_M4IgOQw" hash="-mFKcQ">A mother wrote, “After October conference, in family council, we decided to <span class="emphasis">earn</span> some money not to spend it for Christmas, but to send it to missionaries. The boys, ages five and six, gathered cans for refunds, stacked wood, raked leaves, vacuumed the car, and swept the garage. Two-year-old Becky stacked wood and set the table. Mom gave piano lessons. Daddy cracked his piggy bank of eight years. One boy lost a tooth, and Daddy paid him a quarter for it. He promptly loosened and removed two more for an additional fifty cents! We are sending our total earnings ($81.85). It’s been a pleasure.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p9" pid="EBl6wA_q-0GGMyiJMjteIg" hash="GKqSew">The shortest letter read, “Per your instructions last general conference. Sincerely. …”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p10" pid="MlECQVqGTk2Bv6aBQtHDyg" hash="vDc8eg">Aside from some concern about possible toothless youngsters, I commend you all. Thank you, brothers and sisters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p11" pid="0XyZXp8hvEGEEXteJnWypA" hash="l6iCmg">Gratefully, the need still exists. In fact, it’s growing daily. Last year we experienced a 37 percent increase in the number of local missionaries serving.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p12" pid="z5SO8G9_70ewLRgcpDrDkw" hash="US1Kmg">We have another and different need in the fast-developing areas, as well as in most of the missions. Last year more than 140,000 converts joined the Church. With so many converts the little branches grow rapidly. New leaders are called to positions of service early. They are able but inexperienced in Church procedures and administration. These new leaders, as well as older ones, need to be taught how to organize the Church correctly and cause it to function properly. Who is available to teach these principles? Regional Representatives? Yes. Their visits are limited, however, and they cover wide areas. Mission presidents? Yes, but they are greatly burdened with large and ofttimes difficult areas to cover; and in reality, they have little time in which to do it. Mature couples with a background of Church service? Yes. But where do we get them? Why, the Church is full of them!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p13" pid="aefrXgTCJk-Jtnn8mB3uRQ" hash="Ri55ng">Would you like to serve? Such a call will delay your retirement, take you off the golf course, and take you away from your mobile home. It will place you face to face with real challenges that require deep spirituality, earnest prayer, and the exercise of great faith. If you would like to serve, contact your priesthood leaders to see if you are worthy and able. They are the ones who determine your worthiness to receive a missionary call from the Prophet. Our priesthood leaders will be very careful about whom they recommend. They will carefully review all information submitted and give special attention to your medical record to see if there are any physical or emotional problems that would interfere with full-time missionary work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p14" pid="GEluSgJHEkyfTqFY6S6-uA" hash="V_x3Wg">Your children must be grown and married. Good health is essential. In spite of your desire and means to go, it may not be possible due to poor health. I must be very frank about this matter and caution you: Missionary work is not a sentimental journey. While the work will be accommodated somewhat to your needs, it will nevertheless be <span class="emphasis">work!</span> You will miss births, deaths, weddings, and other family events. You will live in less comfort than you are accustomed to. It will be the most challenging, disappointing, discouraging, and difficult time of your life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p15" pid="eruJY5nRDk2ZqBcZHOCAWA" hash="yvemkw">Nevertheless, I have heard the testimonies of couples who are presently serving; and in spite of the inconveniences, I can promise you one thing: supreme joy—the joy that comes from diligent labor and selfless service. Ammon knew this kind of joy. In the Book of Mormon we read: “And this is the account of Ammon and his brethren, their journeyings in the land of Nephi, their sufferings in the land, their sorrows, and their afflictions, and their incomprehensible joy.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/28.8" class="scriptureRef">Alma 28:8</a>.) You, too, may experience a joy and exultation known in no other way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p16" pid="6RoVzAzzA0adP2K3yrb4Qw" hash="HwLdEA">Most people who need your help speak another language. You will be enabled to learn a new language, however, through a system adapted to your situation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p17" pid="vDdSJVJDYUKLwx6RuER-yQ" hash="joNfWQ">The nature of your service will not be exactly like the young missionaries. The emphasis now is for experienced couples to teach leadership principles (which you already know) to inexperienced leaders. Normally you will not preside in a branch or district, but you will help those who do to improve their abilities and to cause the Church to function properly. You will also teach principles of personal and family preparedness. You might work as a specialist in health, agriculture, or vocational services. You will share the gospel through proselyting as well. The length of service is usually eighteen months. However, you may serve a six- or twelve-month mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p18" pid="f5OCCue8J027r1c6dr8-iA" hash="BYqJIw">The areas where you are needed vary sufficiently to meet the needs of most couples. It will require $400 to $500 per month. In many cases this cost provides the opportunity for children to now help their parents fill <span class="emphasis">their</span> missions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p19" pid="TOuFaQhgvUSXtKU1Ynv4cg" hash="35M9Pg">Perhaps some of you couples listening today may look at one another and say, “Dear, why shouldn’t we see if we qualify?” Some of you who desire to serve may not be members of the Church. We would welcome you, too. There are, however, one or two preliminary steps you need to take prior to being recommended. If you should see our young missionaries about, or if you know members of the Church, please ask about their message. It will open the door to marvelous opportunities in the service of the Master, as well as open the door to eternal life for you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p20" pid="5BQQOreVx0uSf4vKWdvEgg" hash="rXe95Q">Our Savior taught that service saves: “For behold the field is white already to harvest; and lo, <span class="emphasis">he</span> that thrusteth in his sickle with his might, the same layeth up in store that <span class="emphasis">he</span> perisheth not, but bringeth salvation to <span class="emphasis">his</span> soul.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/4.4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 4:4</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p21" pid="QyubzaZ9mUK3FYsl9IwtNw" hash="3gl-_Q">“And if it so be that you should labor all your days in crying repentance unto this people and bring, save it be one soul unto me, how great shall be <span class="emphasis">your</span> joy with <span class="emphasis">him</span> in the kingdom of my Father!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p22" pid="YyALt-vteE2YUxySd-8lyw" hash="QGZ-lg">“And now, if your joy will be great with one soul that you have brought unto me into the kingdom of my Father, how great will be <span class="emphasis">your</span> joy if you should bring many souls unto me!” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.15-16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:15–16</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves.p23" pid="4iQKw9Mslka5VU4fsjuX2A" hash="ofi46w">I know that we are in the service of the Master. I know that Jesus is the Christ, that he lives and directs his work through his living prophet, President Spencer W. Kimball. To this I testify in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1977/10/service-saves</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1977-general-conference/1977-10-4030-elder-a-theodore-tuttle-64k-eng.mp3" length="5535210" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 1977 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welfare Services Begins with You</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you?lang=eng</link>
      <description>One day in South America we had the interesting experience of seeing in a hot jungle area a small brownish gray animal hanging upside down in a tree. It had rather long front paws and short back legs. Its movements were so slow that it was hard to kn</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03096_000_042" doc-version="2" hash="aFJJ_A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="kJqyQ_aCI0ufud9MKzC8dg" hash="nAJcPw">Welfare Services Begins with You</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="SwrdvMTVM0Ghyh0hZ9CYuA" hash="uG5ddw">A. Theodore Tuttle</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27d8.jpg" alt="Elder A. Theodore Tuttle" pid="NiBUXJ7JEEGISZKu_FxLgg" hash="uF_y9g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p1" pid="Ouz1aUaEXkiHiz0PvG63xA" hash="O5ALig">One day in South America we had the interesting experience of seeing in a hot jungle area a small brownish gray animal hanging upside down in a tree. It had rather long front paws and short back legs. Its movements were so slow that it was hard to know whether it was alive or dead. We were told that it was a sloth. I was intrigued because reference to the sloth appears in scripture. The Lord used it with disdain, referring to those who were slow to act.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p2" pid="bURrR6i15kSDVkFXuuR1VQ" hash="0dqSTA">When the welfare program was begun in the 1930s, it aimed to eliminate the curse of idleness, reestablish self-respect, and help people to help themselves. The basic principles of the Lord’s economic system had earlier been revealed to the Prophet Joseph. Nearly everything that has happened since then has been to prepare us for the time when this program would be needed to a far greater extent. In the intervening years, many great principles have been declared. I shall review these briefly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p3" pid="EeSuGNxMWUiQswETs-w4-A" hash="G75QcQ">President Grant declared: “The Church needs blessings, and the only way we can receive … them … is by keeping the laws on which these blessings are predicated. The fundamental law pertaining to the <span class="emphasis">welfare</span> of our people is fast offering. The reason we want to stress the paying of fast offerings is because we need blessings that come from paying fast offerings.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p4" pid="JFKbVx4a80WEGAzwkebhnQ" hash="Pw2Khg">President Clark counseled: “Live within your means. Get out of debt. Keep out of debt. Lay by for a rainy day which has always come and will come again. Practice and increase your habits of thrift, industry, economy, frugality.” (In <span class="emphasis">Conference Report,</span> Oct. 1937, p. 107.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p5" pid="4MAkgIDv9kyeAywqjbH0sA" hash="8ChdPA">“Let every head of every household see to it that he has on hand enough food and clothing, and, where possible, fuel also, for at least a year ahead. … Let every man who has a garden spot, garden it; every man who owns a farm, farm it.” (In <span class="emphasis">Conference Report,</span> Apr. 1937, p. 26.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p6" pid="ZvIPB2ewyEK7VmuS_75Bog" hash="trAmAg">“Cash is not food, it is not clothing, it is not coal, it is not shelter; and we have got to the place where no matter how much cash we have, we cannot secure those things in the quantities which we may need. … All that you can be certain you will have is that which you produce.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p7" pid="RpTaZcWwXUGQp8JgiT7W_w" hash="3n-E6g">“We must purge our hearts of the love of ease; we must put out from our lives the curse of idleness. God declared that mortal man should earn his bread by the sweat of his brow. That is the law of this world.” (In <span class="emphasis">Conference Report,</span> Apr. 1937, p. 26.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p8" pid="892-g4v0ZkGfBrwhQuhcZQ" hash="VRtBQg">“Many of us are not yet willing to bring ourselves under control and to quit spending not only all of our savings, but also all we are making, and in addition, running in debt on installment buying.” (In <span class="emphasis">Conference Report,</span> Apr. 1948, p. 117.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p9" pid="5NQspX2N90SPoBhwcrXSMA" hash="Zhu3Vw">You sisters will be pleased to hear again his counsel: “If there is any Bishop in this Church who thinks he can get along without his Relief Society, he does not yet know his job. And if he is getting along without his Relief Society, he is not doing his job.” (In Conference Report, Apr. 1948, p. 177.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p10" pid="klxqm_V9SE6lI6xpLhMc5Q" hash="1wVSxQ">(May I state parenthetically that the displays in the Relief Society building of ideas for home storage, suggestions for meeting emergencies, etc., should be visited by all who attend the conference.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p11" pid="4BoTQG5pc0anDX1MqlxHcg" hash="oIpPuw">President Harold B. Lee said, “Priesthood plus womanhood together bring exaltation! Priesthood plus womanhood is necessary in welfare. Without this teamwork, never in the world would we accomplish what we are doing in the welfare program.” (Harold B. Lee, address delivered at Welfare Agricultural meeting, 2 Oct. 1971.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p12" pid="bzh7v9emL06TOPg-NV8bdQ" hash="8sHD6A">President Lee also taught: “Keep in mind that the Church welfare program must begin with you personally and individually. It must begin with every member of the Church. … You have to act for yourself and be a participant before the welfare program is active in your household. Moving out from there, then, to quorums, to united teamwork … tremendous results can come.” (Harold B. Lee, address delivered at Welfare Agricultural meeting, 5 Apr. 1969.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p13" pid="0NrKQbwCskKyafNdtlSHOw" hash="aFrDMQ">“May the Lord help us to understand these fundamentals, and guide us to that destiny which … is … to attain, a full consecration, wherein we consecrate our lives, all that we have and are … for the upbuilding of the kingdom. Then only can we develop the faith necessary to an exaltation in the celestial kingdom.” (Harold B. Lee, address delivered at Welfare Agricultural meeting, 5 Oct. 1968.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p14" pid="lIdjYqdkhEue_MGUbStcFQ" hash="FPcafg">President Romney has said, “Both history and prophecy—and, I may add, common sense—bear witness to the fact that no civilization can long endure which follows the course charted by bemused manipulators and now being implemented as government welfare programs all around the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p15" pid="7KW6FcQ7WEawrO0cgGV_xA" hash="un0oQQ">“Babylon shall be destroyed, and great shall be the fall thereof. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p16" pid="4KZNNDsink-Zod5sSUeSEw" hash="Vi9VnQ">“But do not be discouraged. Zion will not go down with her, because Zion shall be built on the principles of love of God and fellowman, work, and earnest labor, as God has directed. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p17" pid="jYcrnGePQ0S4q_SNwUW6HQ" hash="IAVO1A">“As we prepare for the building of Zion, we must not and we shall not abandon the basic principles upon which our Church Welfare Services are founded: <span class="emphasis">Love</span>—love of God and neighbor—and <span class="emphasis">work,</span> or labor.” (In <span class="emphasis">Conference Report,</span> Apr. 1976, p. 169.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p18" pid="UTD7O2VJr0yJhtxA13LBwQ" hash="4Hxelg">Elsewhere he states, “Almost from the beginning of my service in Church welfare I have had the conviction that what we are doing in this welfare work is preliminary to the reestablishment of the law of consecration and stewardship as required under the united order. If we could always remember the goal toward which we are working, we would never lose our bearings in this great work.” (In <span class="emphasis">Conference Report,</span> Apr. 1977, p. 118.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p19" pid="t0E-eksxV0WH5PVl-SUKcQ" hash="CG4N9A">Now, brethren, listen to Alma’s landmark counsel for leaders: “And he commanded them [the leaders] that they should teach nothing save it were the things which he had taught, and which had been spoken by the mouth of the holy prophets.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.19" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:19</a>.) We are under that same obligation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p20" pid="OexUxiRDqU-kb8pJPY8RGQ" hash="T_8YHw">President Tanner said that President Romney was the best informed and greatest authority in the Church today on welfare programs. In the last few years President Romney has restated and expounded the fundamental principles of the welfare program. The major addresses of the welfare sessions have been reported in the conference editions of the <span class="emphasis">Ensign</span> magazine for the last five conferences.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p21" pid="EwkuDTlvVkOgfYHkudJrvA" hash="Arqtcg">The preventive aspects of the welfare program can and must be accomplished by you quorum leaders learning, teaching, and implementing these principles. Besides the preventive work, there is the work of rehabilitation. The individual who is in need of sustenant help should be built back into a self-supporting member of the Church. This is the work of the priesthood quorums as Elder Hinckley illustrated so beautifully six months ago. The quorum must help its weakened members.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p22" pid="WYM-9jPgt0upJMU12Kn4PQ" hash="ASxlIA">Likewise, on you Aaronic Priesthood quorum leaders—including the bishopric, of course—falls the responsibility to teach welfare principles to over half a million young men and women.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p23" pid="Qgw3JhTCOkK_F3Z8OiPXBQ" hash="vyyK0g">Often we hear youth say: “What is there to <span class="emphasis">do?</span>” In addition to the collection of fast offerings by the deacons, some of the finest opportunities lie in the area of Welfare Services. Brethren, build into your programs the excellent activities suggested in the <span class="emphasis">Aaronic Priesthood Quorum Guidebook</span> and <span class="emphasis">The Activity Book.</span> Here is a sampling of the useful and interesting ways in which youth can participate in home storage and Welfare Services activities: store and preserve food and water, store firewood and make newspaper logs, prepare an inventory of family possessions, plant a garden, build a compost pile and make an outdoor storage pit, prune fruit trees, make shopping comparisons, learn about proper diet, cook game fish or meat, clean a house, repair an electrical cord, replace a water faucet, paint the interior and exterior of a house, and enjoy a festival of homemaking skills.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p24" pid="eDAQ6mVqVUGJNgk1Euif1Q" hash="ZK4nww">Each of these ideas has other suggested projects that are both fun and useful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p25" pid="XDU5bq4uTEevvnT0xHSIVQ" hash="WH30Mg">Brothers and sisters, I have reviewed briefly these principles. They are true. You can live them. Now I give a word of caution, even warning. The word <span class="emphasis">sloth</span> or <span class="emphasis">slothfulness</span> appears in scripture twenty-five times, generally to condemn those who were slow to act. As we watched that sloth hanging in the tree, it reached out ever so slowly to pull off a leaf, then slower still brought it back and put it into its mouth. As we watched it we could understand the words <span class="emphasis">impatient, irritated, exasperated.</span> The Savior’s reference to the sloth and slothfulness illustrates His displeasure and impatience with the person who is slow to act, who is slothful. Brethren and sisters, our generation has been counseled patiently for more than forty years. It is no longer optional to learn and teach and implement these principles. It is crucial!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you.p26" pid="Frv29WkGkkKiaOCZErkDiw" hash="bSOk_A">This work is divine. It will yet save and exalt us. That exaltation will come by living this law. May we in unity rise to this challenge and do it, I humbly pray in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1978/04/welfare-services-begins-with-you</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1978-general-conference/1978-04-6040-elder-a-theodore-tuttle-64k-eng.mp3" length="4803234" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 1978 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Therefore I Was Taught</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We have an International Mission in the Church, over which Elder Carlos Asay presides. It cares for all the members of the Church who live outside the boundaries of regularly established stakes and missions. This includes the families who live in far</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03115_000_012" doc-version="2" hash="H9lE4A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="F-Lj1C7WfEqx4fQ96WrhuA" hash="X8du8Q">Therefore I Was Taught</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="0mpZBoMt8Emzld-hDRoR8A" hash="uG5ddw">A. Theodore Tuttle</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27d8.jpg" alt="Elder A. Theodore Tuttle" pid="xNH3mbNahEadtU3ut-p-Cw" hash="uF_y9g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p1" pid="lg1L8DNDoE-J2bcSeB1mcg" hash="4icHIA">We have an International Mission in the Church, over which Elder Carlos Asay presides. It cares for all the members of the Church who live outside the boundaries of regularly established stakes and missions. This includes the families who live in far-distant countries away from the centers of the Church. These families generally are on assignment with the government or with the military, or work for international corporations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p2" pid="gJEJmNVv-Eum7IPdQ99ksQ" hash="05xd8w">Typical of these is a family down in the Indian Ocean on the island of Réunion. There is a family of eight living in Benghazi, Libya. Another family of five lives in Karachi, Pakistan. For these and many other families there is no organized unit of the Church. They have to teach their own children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p3" pid="D1l1ookWAk6RWOA0YuDCjw" hash="E7c-RQ">Many of these families regularly conduct “church” services. Actually they are “home” services for their family. The mother may gather her small children about her and hold Primary. In this case she serves as the president of the Primary, the counselor, the teacher—and always the janitor. If the family has priesthood-age sons, all the regular priesthood offices somehow merge into one—the father—as he teaches them their duties and ministers to his family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p4" pid="VE1ypfq9eU-H_FKpDLbF7Q" hash="BvMn7w">Actually, where the Church is fully organized, priesthood and auxiliary leaders are striving to have all parents teach their children anyway.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p5" pid="nSAHEsr5eUCXuP2CKvdNdw" hash="EwAN3w">Often these distant families receive only a few basic materials from the Church. We now have available an excellent basic lesson manual for the men and boys and one for the mothers and daughters, a manual for small children, and a very fine basic manual, <span class="emphasis">Gospel Principles.</span> Generally these families receive the Church periodicals and have access to the family home evening manual, and, most important, the standard works of the Church. Activities are planned and centered around their families. In spite of limited materials, if the <span class="emphasis">parents</span> teach their children the gospel, these homes may be as blessed as any in the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p6" pid="MC1EW42uDUm19t50Fw7WTg" hash="nsU-PA">The things that are essential to these homes are essential in every home. In fact, living away from the organized Church <span class="emphasis">might</span> even be a blessing, because family members draw closer together and because they cannot delegate to the Church things that a father and mother should do wherever they live in the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p7" pid="ys-ArrpyMk2m3tpJjV5Pdw" hash="iA2Z0A">The Lord organized the family unit in the beginning. He intended that the home be the center of learning—that the father and mother be teachers. He has given counsel that applies whether the family lives within or without the boundaries of an organized unit of the Church. I cite but a few of the scores of verses:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p8" pid="BdsEEEQSRU-xDx_A426GsQ" hash="rN6E2Q">“And they shall also teach their children to pray, and to walk uprightly before the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:28</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p9" pid="NafgBPrbHEyOerf4WhlKRg" hash="VNdlFg">“The glory of God is intelligence, or, in other words, light and truth. … I have commanded you to bring up your children in light and truth” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.36,40" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:36, 40</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p10" pid="ItF8c7WgNUulUpSutP_KKg" hash="_J2p6Q">“But ye will teach them to walk in the ways of truth and soberness; ye will teach them to love one another, and to serve one another” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.15" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:15</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p11" pid="jS8rErD0bkCGpUXUm8mEuQ" hash="uluIDA">“Train up a child in the way he should go: and when he is old, he will not depart from it” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/22.6" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 22:6</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p12" pid="qgVDDgUTskWDID-SdzfL_A" hash="TJTtIw">The Lord fixed families to give parents more influence on children than all other agencies combined. There is safety in this arrangement. It provides <span class="emphasis">parents</span> the privilege, the awesome privilege, of molding the life and character of a child, even though outside agencies have influence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p13" pid="Kr4NabP_9kqtIq9bMQfDZQ" hash="5Vtugw">Parenthood imposes a singular responsibility. Not only must parents put good things into the minds of children, we must keep bad things out. That is why we have been cautioned against the unrestricted invasion of our homes by the media. While some agencies that have influence on our children are good, some are not. Parental vigilance should be constant. Safeguard your children against those who seek to destroy them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p14" pid="6AOgEs8sBEKz5OOGDi86tA" hash="aa4CiQ">How would you pass the test, parents, if your family was isolated from the Church and <span class="emphasis">you</span> had to supply all religious training? Have you become so dependent on others that you do little or nothing at home? Tell me, how much of the <span class="emphasis">gospel</span> would your children know, if all they knew is what they had been taught at home? Ponder that. I repeat, how much of the gospel would <span class="emphasis">your</span> children know if all they knew is what they had been taught at home? Remember, the Church exists <span class="emphasis">to help the home.</span> Parents, the divine charge to teach has never been changed. Do not abdicate your duty.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p15" pid="shMv_FjWjUGTW-eWZRPffA" hash="814A3w">We have been counseled to become self-reliant and independent temporally. It is as important spiritually! Suppose conditions changed. Suppose you could not receive all the services to which you have become accustomed. Suppose that much more responsibility were placed on your shoulders to care for the spiritual welfare of your family. Surely you cannot study the scriptures without knowing that perilous times are coming. Will you be unaffected?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p16" pid="8bt7dIln7km4QPKJ_2tGPw" hash="2FXEtA">Prepare now! Take steps now to strengthen your family. Spend time together. Establish and maintain family traditions that build happy memories. Maintain a discipline with fair rules and regulations. Express unconditional love to one another through word and act. Develop within each one self-esteem and self-respect by loving and believing in him and having him belong. Provide security that children need. These are the values of which life is made. Establish these, and then we won’t need to worry about the frills that too often concern us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p17" pid="SNXXVzt8WEqAiB2RsTGu5g" hash="WWto3A">As prophetic events unfold, one thing is certain: we will need to be more self-reliant. We will all need to teach more within the walls of our own homes. In the Book of Mormon we find some models:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p18" pid="MYz8de0jDUC5moL2spDsxw" hash="T9vI1g">“I, Nephi, having been born of goodly parents, therefore I was taught somewhat in all the learning of my father” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/1.1" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 1:1</a>). No doubt Nephi was taught the things of the Spirit—his writings reveal that. He probably was taught practical matters as well, for he was a very resourceful man. Today that son is fortunate whose father teaches him somewhat in <span class="emphasis">all</span> his learning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p19" pid="5gxZkjjwlUST7dIKJujWKQ" hash="PnnEaA">Enos, son of Jacob, was another who esteemed his father:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p20" pid="xljgZotG1kStoXCabT-amA" hash="bj9Iag">“I, Enos, knowing my father that he was a just man—for he taught me … in the nurture and admonition of the Lord—and blessed be the name of my God for it. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p21" pid="6nSFOKsjnUOBBa-QsLSumg" hash="TjEVGg">“Behold, I went to hunt beasts in the forests; and the words which I had often heard my father speak concerning eternal life, and the joy of the saints, sunk deep into my heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p22" pid="BWwNuusg7EyqdazDrZw-Dw" hash="lHlktQ">“And my soul hungered; and I kneeled down before my Maker, and I cried unto him in mighty prayer and supplication for mine own soul” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/enos/1.1,3-4" class="scriptureRef">Enos 1:1, 3–4</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p23" pid="OYjmRtEUb0KJiMGV1UEGlQ" hash="v-r_Qg">His life of service pivoted on this great spiritual experience. This experience occurred because of the words of his father. These are great models. They are good examples of the power of parental teaching. One thing is essential. Parents and children must spend time together.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught.p24" pid="jUVafeVwWkuZYboAw7gNjQ" hash="PSFJ1g">Some few of us may receive public acclaim for our deeds. Most of us will live out our lives in comparative anonymity. This need not matter. Serve your fellowman. Love and teach your children. Then one day we will merit a tribute from them, which in the eternal plan will mean more than fame or wealth: “I … [was] born of goodly parents, therefore I was taught.” In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3046.jpg" alt="First Presidency, 7 Oct 1876" pid="j3D8mxv3UE-1DQ12UIum5Q" hash="KMXOuw" />
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1979/10/therefore-i-was-taught</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1979-general-conference/1979-10-2050-elder-a-theodore-turtle-64k-eng.mp3" length="5083559" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1979 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eternal Links that Bind</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Brethren, something has happened to me. For twenty-two years I have been a General Authority. I have traveled the world over in my ministry. Over the course of these years, I have had marvelous experiences and have met many wonderful people. I have p</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03122_000_018" doc-version="2" hash="AsWABw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="YIREcGiyKU-Us9BHcezqFA" hash="JH2oiQ">Eternal Links that Bind</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="BxJt3tAxp0KALmguTx7XLg" hash="uG5ddw">A. Theodore Tuttle</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27d8.jpg" alt="Elder A. Theodore Tuttle" pid="Mpu0QLEpWUKGCc0Xo60-XA" hash="uF_y9g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p1" pid="vTGc_a_BH0uDnnaBz5pDww" hash="xUL8Sg">Brethren, something has happened to me. For twenty-two years I have been a General Authority. I have traveled the world over in my ministry. Over the course of these years, I have had marvelous experiences and have met many wonderful people. I have participated in sacred meetings. The choice association with my brethren has taught and inspired me. Now something has happened—I have been called to serve in a temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p2" pid="an-mBM8ei0OKKx-yLAr9Tw" hash="hq-Avg">I want to bear witness—and my witness is true—that the work for the redemption of the living and the dead is divine. It is a keystone of our religion. The work performed in temples stays the judgments of God from smiting the earth with a curse. It is not unusual, therefore, that the Prophet Joseph would say, “The greatest responsibility in this world that God has laid upon us [as individuals] is to seek after our dead” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith,</span> sel. Joseph Fielding Smith, Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Company, 1938, p. 356).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p3" pid="E3JWHThFAkicOE8xu5k3Rg" hash="N6EMwA">The Prophet Joseph taught that you and I are to become saviors on Mount Zion. We are to gather, build temples, seek after our dead, and perform all the vital ordinances. This work welds eternal links that bind us to each other and to our fathers. We are exalted as family units.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p4" pid="lRguTuF13EmU90DoVGSKzA" hash="ufXiCw">The Prophet Joseph said, “It is necessary … that a … welding together of dispensations … should take place … from the days of Adam even to the present time” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/128.18" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 128:18</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p5" pid="i0HY03EjF0CHn6xeQ4h3JQ" hash="gMdiIA">Then go, brethren. Be sealed to your wife and your sons and daughters. Be sealed to your fathers as far back as you can. Temples are built to perform these sacred ordinances. It is sad that in some of our larger centers temple work is presently lagging. Leaders, strengthen temple work! The Prophet Joseph warned, “Those Saints who neglect it in behalf of their deceased relatives, do it at the peril of their own salvation” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings,</span> p. 193).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p6" pid="PhRtRWin_E6RYGH5BvjaWA" hash="ROTThA">Yet in his anxiety the Prophet once observed, “But there has been a great difficulty in getting anything into the heads of this generation. It has been like splitting hemlock knots with a corndodger for a wedge, and a pumpkin for a beetle. Even the Saints are slow to understand” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings,</span> p. 331).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p7" pid="QzkrdkdVikWA89zx9FrZPA" hash="MQVnTw">Our performance manifests that we are giving neither sufficient time nor attention to temple work. Genealogical research needs more vigor. Submittal of the four-generation sheets must be hastened. This program was announced thirteen years ago. Since that time nearly half the present members of the Church have either been born or baptized. We ask you leaders, Where are the four-generation sheets from all these new members? As a matter of fact, where are yours? Will you see that this work is done, brethren? This is an inspired program.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p8" pid="rREqQlIgME-GOHhv32vA-Q" hash="ncbfPg">Once you complete your four generations, you are not finished. Continue to search out all of your ancestral lines. The four-generation project becomes a platform for launching further research. In fact, this is one place where you move forward by reaching backward! “It is our duty,” counseled Elder John A. Widtsoe, “to secure as complete genealogies as possible, to discover our fathers and mothers back to the last generation, to connect, if it may be possible, with Adam, our first father upon the earth—a duty which we cannot escape” (“Genealogical Activities in Europe,” <span class="emphasis">Utah Genealogical and Historical Magazine,</span> July 1931, p. 104).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p9" pid="_N1oCbIOCUKa2yULfcASoA" hash="VkQuDQ">There are great promises to those who do this. All who diligently search realize that help comes—often from the other side of the veil. You see, they are organized and working there at least as well as we are here!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p10" pid="zAVWvHgRFki046maToUG0A" hash="qnEgiw">Elder Melvin J. Ballard testified that “the spirit and influence of your dead will guide those who are interested in finding those records. If there is <span class="emphasis">anywhere</span> on the earth <span class="emphasis">anything</span> concerning them, you will find it” (Bryant S. Hinckley, <span class="emphasis">Sermons and Missionary Services of Melvin Joseph Ballard,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Company, 1949, p. 230; italics added). And Elder Widtsoe said, “I have the feeling … that those who give themselves with all their might and main to this work receive help from the other side, and not merely in gathering genealogies. Whoever seeks to help those on the other side receives help in return in all the affairs of life” (“Genealogical Activities,” p. 104).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p11" pid="4EqvqLvyxUqmMhBZlCkT9g" hash="00_NaQ">I testify that this is true.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p12" pid="h7ZNyo5PhkW3xh40GMGe2g" hash="xdmyXg">This testimony is echoed by thousands of humble Latter-day Saints whose labors bear witness of this truth! Elisha’s words have been vindicated: “Fear not: for they that be with us are more than they that be with [the enemy]” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/2-kgs/6.16" class="scriptureRef">2 Kgs. 6:16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p13" pid="sixNo79EQkOKEbD_OxjK_Q" hash="JzHm8w">We have introduced the name-extraction program in many areas in order that the work might progress better. Brethren, assist this work wherever possible.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p14" pid="jBmzfaoDskOYi_3sMaoGLQ" hash="2KN_Hg">Young men and young women must not be left out of the joys of this special work. Deacons, do you have a Book of Remembrance? What about you teachers and priests? Have you started your own life story? Are you collecting pictures, certificates, and spiritual experiences to add interest? Assisting your parents in the search for your relatives often develops real pride in your heritage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p15" pid="TonOr5e-eUOlFgQ7z_tIZg" hash="67YSaA">You may have heard of the young man who got involved in this work. He was sent to the department store to buy some genealogical supplies. He asked the first clerk he saw, “Do you have any family group sheets?” Perplexed, the young lady replied, “Well we have twin-size sheets, double, and queen size, but I’m not sure whether we have family group sheets!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p16" pid="-xLoKpj5hE24wLnItO-m_w" hash="LWCaOA">To all who may want to help in preserving family history, we issue an invitation now to come to the World Conference on Records this coming August. This conference is designed to assist all of us to do redemptive work for the dead in a better way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p17" pid="IM-92GWDA06A5npVo_HNLw" hash="QYGZTQ">You leaders in the stakes, wards, and quorums, assume the additional duty to see that every man in your priesthood quorum fulfills his responsibility with respect to his dead. I quote from President Marion G. Romney concerning the significance of holy covenants: “We are individually responsible and will be held accountable for the way in which we <span class="emphasis">ourselves</span> keep the covenants we enter into, and we shall also <span class="emphasis">be accountable for the breaking of covenants by others for whom we are responsible insofar as such breaking is the result of our failure to teach them</span>” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1975, p. 73; italics added). Ponder that thought!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p18" pid="-G1MnqgDfUKJb1LeS7zjKg" hash="3z_0bw">Brethren, the great priesthood leaders of past dispensations look to us to move this work. All the righteous men and women who ever lived look to us! We are their <span class="emphasis">only</span> hope for salvation. We hold the key to their prison doors. We must set them free! How can we any longer ignore their right to salvation? President Brigham Young said, “When I think upon this subject, I want the tongues of seven thunders to wake up the people” (<span class="emphasis">Discourses of Brigham Young,</span> sel. John A. Widtsoe, Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Company, 1941, p. 404).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p19" pid="QXKnRvcWVE-5AzJcL05OzA" hash="iFBULg">It was this supernal work—redemption of the living and the dead—of which the Prophet Joseph spoke when he said, “Brethren, shall we not go on in so great a cause? Go forward and not backward. Courage, brethren; and on, on to the victory! … Let the dead speak forth anthems of eternal praise to the King Immanuel, … for the prisoners shall go free” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/128.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 128:22</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind.p20" pid="xeoVDC3J4068KFmxswMFBQ" hash="jdkJPg">O God, please grant that the spirit of Elijah may fall upon the vast body of priesthood in thy Church, to cause thy great work to move forward. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1980/04/eternal-links-that-bind</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1980-general-conference/1980-04-3030-elder-a-theodore-tuttle-64k-eng.mp3" length="5181469" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 1980 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The First and the Last Words</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words?lang=eng</link>
      <description>If we were to speak of the very center of spiritual strength in the Church, surely it must be the sacred ordinances of the temple of the Lord.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03148_000_028" doc-version="2" hash="DnNPww">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="7eDmGwwDYkmnjquQ5xudIw" hash="ga3VNw">The First and the Last Words</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="oR1aDIIzFkCZxhvE8dfrIg" hash="uG5ddw">A. Theodore Tuttle</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27d8.jpg" alt="Elder A. Theodore Tuttle" pid="sm9mJk0CFU6CZl7gnGCjEA" hash="uF_y9g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p1" pid="Yyfoi9yOh02qlAtzw9mpEw" hash="KqRbGQ">If we were to speak of the very center of spiritual strength in the Church, surely it must be the sacred ordinances of the temple of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p2" pid="zcpsOQsXRk2SZ6IvCgw5wA" hash="s43Fpg">It is not generally known that almost the first words of the Lord to the Prophet Joseph—the intent of the gathering and building up of the Church—and almost the last words of the Lord to the Prophet pertained to temple work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p3" pid="Ics75PIiJk6WC6zOtQJYdg" hash="LoatOA">After the wondrous First Vision of the Prophet in the spring of 1820, three and a half years passed. The next divine manifestation he had was when the angel Moroni appeared to him. He told Joseph about the Book of Mormon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p4" pid="aOie6zPqO02U3Ml6e8dtDg" hash="UIqJcQ">Because of the preeminence of this message, most people do not realize that Moroni brought another momentous message! First he quoted, with some variation, the prophecy of Malachi:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p5" pid="tz1xguz-7kOhO7bCHENOQA" hash="Yh471Q">“Behold, I will reveal unto you the <span class="emphasis">Priesthood,</span> by the hand of Elijah the prophet, before the coming of the great and dreadful day of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p6" pid="11A5kw2Rw0WGS6SvKJAudQ" hash="OUxrkQ">“And he shall plant in the hearts of the children the <span class="emphasis">promises</span> made to the fathers, and the hearts of the children shall turn to their fathers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p7" pid="Ljk0q35-E0yd_CfZLo3kwQ" hash="AVUtEQ">“If it were not so, the whole earth would be utterly wasted at his coming.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/2.1-3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 2:1–3</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.36-39" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:36–39</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p8" pid="UBkRkMUOAEy4pSXQ5bIgyg" hash="09LP7A">Moroni also quoted from Isaiah, Acts, Joel, and “many other passages of scripture.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.41" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:41</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p9" pid="fGJRiv2YxU6_qtkgztgpaA" hash="cN_K8g">The prophecy of Malachi concerning Elijah was treated differently from all other scriptures quoted by Moroni. It was considered of such unique importance that it now appears as section 2 in the Doctrine and Covenants.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p10" pid="Xe3lCXbK8k-zJypChKAMQw" hash="lg77gA">Moroni’s message signaled to the Prophet that Elijah soon would appear. The foreordained events pertaining to temple work began to unroll like a scroll. Less than a year and a half after the organization of the Church, the Prophet dedicated the site for the temple in Jackson County, Missouri (August 1831). But the Saints were prevented from building it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p11" pid="Hbk_y8sHlUSwXGPxKCQKCw" hash="6VkDZw">Then followed a score of significant events pertaining to the building of the house of the Lord. (See chart at end of talk.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p12" pid="GLvtAdtpGUaFBmhNPn5V4g" hash="vm06bg">The first temple completed was Kirtland—built under great difficulties. The dedication of this temple was accompanied by the visitation of angels and fire resting upon the temple. Some saw visions and experienced other glorious manifestations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p13" pid="SYwiwrOqx0OBLpNOV41j0A" hash="176oHw">On the third of April, 1836, one week after the dedication of the Kirtland Temple, the monumental event occurred! The Savior appeared and accepted the temple. Moses and Elias also came. Then, Malachi’s prophecy was fulfilled—for Elijah the prophet stood before them and said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p14" pid="RWwMiQNs4UioDHlVHENnSw" hash="ML3wPQ">“Behold, the time has <span class="emphasis">fully</span> come, which was spoken of by the mouth of Malachi—testifying that he [Elijah] should be sent, before the great and dreadful day of the Lord come—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p15" pid="AwFa4lgwwk6lqZNAHIOjiw" hash="AyDnfQ">“To turn the hearts of the fathers to the children, and the children to the fathers, lest the whole earth be smitten with a curse—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p16" pid="5tHZ-kldF0-DqWp74V1hvA" hash="NZ5UBQ">“Therefore, the keys of this dispensation are committed into your hands; and by this ye may know that the great and dreadful day of the Lord is near, even at the doors.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/110.14-16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 110:14–16</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p17" pid="rZdtL71QsEaYrTSuOt1TAw" hash="z6r2MA">That event occurred 146 years ago yesterday, on the day that the Jews were celebrating their traditional ritual. For more than two millennia the Jews have looked for the coming of Elijah. Even today, in connection with the feast of the Passover, they will reenact the scene as they have done for centuries: they will set a place at their table, reserve an empty chair, open the door, raise their cups, and rise as if to greet Elijah.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p18" pid="qo3mXB22xUGkipZt_JpjkQ" hash="k22Aag">Elijah has returned! Thanks be to God! He bestowed his keys! Work could now commence in the temples to weld eternal links between husbands and wives, between parents and children, through the sealing power of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p19" pid="Ui5IUnrlH0mcpld_3MBc8Q" hash="ERxjsA">It is essential to obtain the sealing power of the holy priesthood so that whatsoever an authorized officiator shall bind on earth shall be bound in heaven and whatsoever he shall loose on earth shall be loosed in heaven. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/127.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 127:7</a>.) For in the sacred ordinances and through this sacred power come glory and honor and eternal life. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/128.11-12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 128:11–12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p20" pid="w7TyR5IxMUewCwuZwgKPZw" hash="PrHobg">It is by this power that husband and wife are sealed in a never-ending bond of marriage. It is by this power that a welding link is forged between children and parents. This is the holy power that is exercised in the temple. It is the power that validates all ordinances in the Church. This is the consummate authority in the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p21" pid="gVq0fiiQdEqTPBBUFlVy9g" hash="RnGcNQ">Without the authority and use of that power, in all ages of the world, none of our Heavenly Father’s children can enter His presence or ever become like Him! And if this were not so, the whole purpose of existence would be useless. That is why the Lord said “the whole earth would be utterly wasted at his coming.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/2.3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 2:3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p22" pid="h5Y30y0tWUOh4FzXVfyKrA" hash="0BW4SA">Almost the last words of the Lord to the Prophet, so far as we can tell, also pertained to temple work. The Lord commanded the Prophet to build a temple in Nauvoo. The Saints set about to do it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p23" pid="n8vFlxK-C0uHz_bn6Ht2QA" hash="2o_qYw">Prior to its completion, the Lord revealed His sacred ordinances, “things which have been kept hid from before the foundation of the world, things that pertain to the dispensation of the fulness of times.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/124.41" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 124:41</a>.) The order of performing baptism for the dead was revealed. Also the Lord required that witnesses verify the performance of ordinances, “that in all your recordings it may be recorded in heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/127.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 127:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p24" pid="eO3P275WjE-fVRNBpId7OQ" hash="vEDLcQ">Finally, the members of the Twelve Apostles were endowed and the sealing authority conveyed to them, thereafter never to be lost. They could now carry on the fulness of the gospel. These crucial things the Lord revealed to the Prophet Joseph only months before his martyrdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p25" pid="6qHA4CYEdkmdYlVV2T-lHw" hash="oeUMkw">From this brief account of significant events in the life of the Prophet, it becomes apparent that his first and foremost duty was to build temples and restore the sealing power to perform sacred and eternal ordinances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p26" pid="qB9yWqCHmEK838HLlSL5eg" hash="-35aYg">All the prophets since his time have likewise shown a concern for this work. During President Kimball’s presidency more temples have been constructed than in any other time. We are now truly taking temples <span class="emphasis">to</span> the people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p27" pid="xUztKXHKL0Why3pBTRzOxw" hash="ptZJ2g">And now, brothers and sisters, I want to testify concerning this sacred work. I know that it is true. The principles are eternal. The ordinances are divine—they are eternal—framed before the world was. You and I are responsible to carry on this work. The Lord has no one else to do it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p28" pid="ze1sUvdcUUKDKXhtO1voqA" hash="BrjxrQ">Surely this is not an onerous burden! It is a privilege. A temple recommend is one of the highest accolades we may receive. To use it regularly permits us to participate in the choicest gifts within the keeping of the Church. Those who attend feel a special spirit there. Peace comes. I know that their service there assists a departed one to gain exaltation. And I know that they in turn qualify for blessings from the other side of the veil. And I know that blessings will follow you home from the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p29" pid="ERZ249rcrUKOAWD4JSkwpw" hash="JdxGCw">God lives. Jesus is the Christ. This is the consummate work of the kingdom. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="lFz1_EGOZUezuKNg4n1kGw" hash="qzaOQw">Partial List of Events Related to Temple Work, 1831–1843</h3>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p30" pid="6IYVud9FTUaB-NRX0jOdpg" hash="TlfC9Q">20 July 1831</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p31" pid="35ZUleW1vEGTipTVKWF9gQ" hash="ymd4xQ">Temple at Independence, Missouri, announced. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/57.1-3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 57:1–3</a>.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p32" pid="HJg2mt02dEqHDkU9HKQKkw" hash="kHRjow">1 Aug. 1831</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p33" pid="znTy7xQUQUOR3HAhhANTUw" hash="7yXzTw">Missouri and temple site directed to be dedicated. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.57" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:57</a>.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p34" pid="xyUQrW7DRE-iayVfTa0evg" hash="vBVtTQ">3 Aug. 1831</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p35" pid="d1CbZhbc_068gxZRrrkjOQ" hash="QrSo_A">The Prophet dedicates temple site in Jackson County, Missouri. (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church, </span>1:199.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p36" pid="scMhTDx6RUil-TeAYbO4Nw" hash="dzJI8g">1831</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p37" pid="2GmsxR82x0ipG6w8D_35YA" hash="2vI1nw">Doctrines and principles of the new and everlasting covenant revealed, but not recorded until 12 July 1843. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/132.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 132</a>.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p38" pid="V2xE5wCu7kScXutDIoJyqA" hash="AxflPQ">22 Sept. 1832</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p39" pid="66tswikF-EuMYCCeHmewPg" hash="8hsdHw">New Jerusalem and temple prophesied. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.1-5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:1–5</a>.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p40" pid="IR4Dxlw9NU2F7N5Mwf2kGQ" hash="Jj-Vng">27 Dec. 1832</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p41" pid="mwrDsUKsykOcWasl08diEQ" hash="VwXEDw">Saints commanded to establish a “house of God” (temple). (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.119" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:119</a>.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p42" pid="_gwifdK_PUGWnHUVTWby1Q" hash="-9slOA">1 June 1833</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p43" pid="hF4VvuknyUSlr9sjs2SaxQ" hash="j8vm_Q">Saints in Missouri again commanded to build a temple, in which they will be endowed with power. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/95.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 95</a>.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p44" pid="zlecvpUs3kWLOKXOz7WBbA" hash="_joSGg">23 July 1833</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p45" pid="qY-eTzAYfUqDvnn89l48XQ" hash="ftXTsw">Cornerstones of Kirtland Temple laid. (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church, </span>1:400.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p46" pid="HKwocmuxkU6wGQqRbc2S0w" hash="2yPeTg">2 Aug. 1833</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p47" pid="z7ictImMVEGlO95Sz9JbJA" hash="EMayTg">Further revelation on temple in Missouri, which is to be built after “the pattern.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/97.10-17" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 97:10–17</a>.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p48" pid="6yYYsXID4EqiH4943K5VAg" hash="eSCmTg">21 Jan. 1836</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p49" pid="sGuqmrTMtECZgNBHe2cihA" hash="tr4_SA">Doctrine of salvation for the dead revealed. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/137.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 137</a>.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p50" pid="vFo9xrcEVESTmAiivSVkNA" hash="STRgKw">27 Mar. 1836</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p51" pid="28uf67VCYkOCBPJvKFkZSA" hash="1blV0A">Dedicatory prayer for Kirtland Temple recorded. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/109.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 109</a>.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p52" pid="oturG91sRUW42Xzpg5OziQ" hash="brY8sw">3 Apr. 1836</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p53" pid="noICCL3k9UK6v2ZZIP_exA" hash="M_k1Mw">Elijah comes, sealing keys restored. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/110.13-16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 110:13–16</a>.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p54" pid="Sv78vw4cckyIf_yL4B6ESQ" hash="iG52hQ">26 Apr. 1838</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p55" pid="IV1w91vQVEua9nL4xS_1hA" hash="PWYXVg">Saints commanded to build a temple at Far West. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/115.7-16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 115:7–16</a>.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p56" pid="vD2E0Oc2okKEeb3FvaWJRQ" hash="QJYPlQ">8 July 1838</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p57" pid="IrJSUa7Gjkm-jm2TLCfOrw" hash="_D2AHQ">Tithes directed to be used for building temples. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/119.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 119</a>.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p58" pid="Amy9HaBUdEqLgTbRwvaupA" hash="Fu2sGg">26 Apr. 1839</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p59" pid="X31X1TTUTkKTAk2aNLSfxA" hash="kJoHng">Cornerstones of Far West Temple laid. (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church, </span>3:336–37.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p60" pid="B8R3dMwXwkSbpMM-5WiNig" hash="aC1l-g">19 Jan. 1841</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p61" pid="S5BYXCRlb0yrr_3MyktQmg" hash="1ft1uQ">Saints commanded to build Nauvoo Temple. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/124.25-45" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 124:25–45</a>.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p62" pid="XR-d68A_S0mwbdz8TcFsqw" hash="-ziV7A">1 Sept. 1842</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p63" pid="ZWmRJkQ5xEauiNWrTMiGYg" hash="YABR9w">Saints instructed to keep a record of ordinances. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/127.5-9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 127:5–9</a>.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p64" pid="954HanTAXEueqeG5J0LZig" hash="WK3xcg">6 Sept. 1842</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p65" pid="DNzdhMOyRkGbEfBfpG0t5w" hash="G87Kqg">Saints instructed to have witnesses at ordinances; various doctrines and principles explained. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/128.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 128</a>.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p66" pid="taaBxJgr8Uu2YZKVAnGjhw" hash="FEkh1g">16–17 May 1843</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words.p67" pid="Pz76Bj16PE6gxmEjOF0geg" hash="T0SNZw">Doctrine of Sealing expounded. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/131.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 131</a>.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1982/04/the-first-and-the-last-words</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1982-general-conference/1982-04-5030-elder-a-theodore-tuttle-64k-eng.mp3" length="4992332" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1982 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covenants, Ordinances, and Service</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I have served in past years as both a mission president and as a temple president. I have watched the young people as they have come to the missions in South America and come to the temple for their endowments and sealings.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03174_000_012" doc-version="2" hash="w3fFOA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="HtOCEJjmT0iLaBuD4rvytg" hash="hAV8VQ">Covenants, Ordinances, and Service</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="3hiEqDn12keOboeIluvRyg" hash="uG5ddw">A. Theodore Tuttle</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27d8.jpg" alt="Elder A. Theodore Tuttle" pid="-Bj1z2uisEOkcSXqLlQMeA" hash="uF_y9g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p1" pid="WIssCXzDKEeOvkt8MBaGRA" hash="a0NUww">I have served in past years as both a mission president and as a temple president. I have watched the young people as they have come to the missions in South America and come to the temple for their endowments and sealings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p2" pid="wU-PDk-O4EigNPV1C0_vBg" hash="iboAvg">I have seen those who were well prepared, and those who were not so well prepared for these blessings. But, most of all, I watched anxiously for those who were not prepared—those who did not come at all—and wondered why.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p3" pid="vfbSH7yQGUSUR1BpPpAE4A" hash="oBp4VQ">A few of them were from families where every effort had been made to prepare them for missionary service and for the blessings of the temple. Most of them, however, were from homes where they did not receive what was required to qualify them and to give them a desire to serve.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p4" pid="q9VJDuDpS0yy3CHQnGDA7A" hash="PBybIw">In order to prepare youth for missionary service and for the temple blessings, parents must have more in mind than schooling. They must have more in mind than preparing for a career. They must have more in mind, really, than just to be a missionary—as though attendance was all that was required.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p5" pid="DnLO9YTT2E2tTf7AAndhHg" hash="vW0IyQ">There are three words which must be kept in mind: <span class="emphasis">covenants, ordinances,</span> and <span class="emphasis">service.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p6" pid="gbTytlXzRkGraxAe-2i4QA" hash="TuXeKg">The training for covenants, for ordinances, and for service <span class="emphasis">belongs in the home.</span> If these are paramount in the minds of the parents, the youth will be prepared. And they will not, because of this, miss any essential training for their careers.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="YMQy3GxgvkGk3BuacVOJkg" hash="ys9ybA">A New Challenge</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p7" pid="Zu3jUdSaU0me3-i7SKenxg" hash="_RxH5g">Fathers and mothers are under divine instruction to take care of their parental responsibilities. The things we have done in past years are not now sufficient to protect our children in these critical times. It has long been taught in this Church that the day will come when no one will be able to stand without an individual testimony of the divinity of this work. That day is here. We are seeing some who lack testimonies turn away from the truth and become prey to error. While we mourn their loss, sorrow will come to those who, by failure to put true principles solidly into place, or by creating doubts in the faith of the weak, or openly teaching falsehoods, caused them to stray. Too many of our youth fail to receive their covenants and ordinances and give service. The onslaught of wickedness against our homes is at once more subtle and more brazen than it has ever been. It is taking its toll among our families. It will be difficult to escape these influences.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p8" pid="CZ6Fd9Y6IEGgUgjza7ELoQ" hash="H2t2og">However, if we act more wisely, we will be safe. “If ye are prepared ye shall not fear.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.30" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:30</a>.) The solution is simple. The results are certain. <span class="emphasis">No longer can we expect the Church to assume the major role in teaching our children—parents have this prime responsibility.</span> Parents will be held fully accountable by the Lord to teach their children the principles and ordinances of the gospel and inspire them to serve. The Church, of course, will support parents through home teachers, visiting teachers, classes, counseling, and other assistance. No single parent in this Church needs to feel abandoned in carrying out the duties imposed by the Lord.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p9" pid="Vt5zYrR1YkaPY90KPe34LQ" hash="wgbFkg">Recent studies by the Church have identified some things that parents can do to achieve our goals. Elder Dean Larsen reported the results:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p10" pid="FVdrT1m0U02P-ucEXfxC9w" hash="G6dNgw">“The factor that has by far the greatest effect on the private, religious life of our youth and upon their achievement of the desired outcomes is <span class="emphasis">home religious observance.</span> If a young person lives in a home situation where there is <span class="emphasis">regular family prayer, regular family study of the gospel and the scriptures,</span> and <span class="emphasis">agreement on basic values,</span> the likelihood of going on a mission and being married in the temple is greatly enhanced. This home and family influence is much more significant than that exercised by peer groups or by programmed participation. In fact, the influence of the home, whether it be positive or negative, is overwhelming.” (Regional Representatives’ seminar, 1 April 1983.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p11" pid="i39SW03qQUmK2Hf8QTfmNA" hash="ns6vsw">Did you notice that the three key elements are regular family prayer, regular family study of the gospel from the scriptures, and agreement on basic values between parents and children? These are the things, more than anything else, that will lead to a proper understanding of covenants, ordinances, and service.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="s4rw0cmIl0CwPGJVh3N98g" hash="aE-65Q">Family Prayer</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p12" pid="eLEPQWNjqUKPsG3j4R4qQg" hash="gdT9EQ">Parents, we must start each day by kneeling in family prayer. Children need to pray and gain knowledge for <span class="emphasis">themselves</span> from the Holy Ghost. Nephi said, “For if ye would hearken unto the Spirit which teacheth a man to pray ye would know that ye must pray; for the evil spirit teacheth not a man to pray.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/32.8" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 32:8</a>.)</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="Kf7MIQN9H0mqVeYrBsEQEQ" hash="OOoI2g">Scripture Study</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p13" pid="BchSrF8yPUOOdMhgkXU8YA" hash="fJubwQ">Our opportunity to study the scriptures as a family has been strengthened by the consolidated meeting schedule. A good part of the Sabbath can very appropriately be used for both personal and family scripture study.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p14" pid="CauNnmiJD0SSaWTBDV5jOw" hash="apupPQ">Few things sponsor spiritual growth more than studying from the scriptures. The Savior said, “He that hath the scriptures, let him search them, and see. …” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/10.14" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 10:14</a>.) The Lord has promised that if you will search, you shall see marvelous spiritual truths that will persuade you to turn to Christ as your great exemplar. You will be strengthened in your desire to make covenants with the Lord, to receive the ordinances, and to serve. Alma taught a great principle when he said to Helaman, “My son, … see that ye look to God and live.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.47" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:47</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p15" pid="In3_xwnubkarKemQSbQ6XA" hash="P9tzlw">Parents, when you desire to really teach, what do you do? Should we not do as the Savior did? He used questions. He quoted the scriptures, used parables, told stories, and he testified. He drew on everyday experiences to teach spiritual truths, using all kinds of occasions for teaching. He created an environment for learning—drawing out instead of pouring on.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p16" pid="vkPV3GvbnEiyJCzbja6gZw" hash="98Wzkw">I know a man who teaches his children at mealtimes. He has a habit of asking two or three gospel questions. He says he can always get the attention of his teenagers when he says, “I have a dollar question for you.”</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="pH2L08bWPkKQCcTKTpL25w" hash="K5TQRQ">Agreement on Basic Values</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p17" pid="MtybNPY1qE-iq2Oo25vLcg" hash="dnZeOw">As we seek to teach by the Spirit, we set a high priority on the importance of covenants, ordinances, and service.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p18" pid="UzclEyKSl0qHqsAMbP7KdA" hash="JBN5Xw">A covenant is a mutual exchange of enforceable promises. “I, the Lord, am bound when ye do what I say; but when ye do not what I say, ye have no promise.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/82.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 82:10</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p19" pid="LPvBlICiYkCq9_HdwHu-Uw" hash="lLFieg">Gospel covenants are made between God and man. The terms are stipulated by the Lord. Gospel covenants have been given to us by revelation. He has given us those covenants and ordinances that are essential to bring us back into his presence.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p20" pid="7wBNL7JSgUCVqjhVOTrtIw" hash="sNsrNA">Baptism by immersion for the remission of sins is an essential covenant to make with the Lord. Faith and repentance precede this ordinance. Confirmation and the gift of the Holy Ghost follow baptism. Acceptance of these first principles and ordinances may obtain for us a remission of our sins and assure our salvation. In the ordinance of the sacrament, we regularly renew this and other covenants, and by complying with our part of the covenant, we receive the Spirit of the Lord to be with us.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p21" pid="4FBh1ETxFkaLkjG-DqI9Bw" hash="qjGDhg">The holy priesthood is likewise received by covenant. In essence, priesthood is power—to serve. Additional covenants are made with the Lord when we receive our endowment and when we are sealed in the temple. These are the covenants of exaltation. Teach your children that only by receiving these ordinances and making these covenants can they be exalted and become like our Heavenly Father. As we endure in faith to the end and serve and love our fellowmen, we can develop the virtues and qualities necessary to qualify us to live with the Lord.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p22" pid="T2iEyh7SmUCnLhkoLSUA_w" hash="pKL-PQ">Service, then, becomes one of the highest virtues. The Savior is our example of unselfish service. Service is a divinely appointed duty. King Benjamin taught that service to others is the same as service to our God. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.17" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2:17</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p23" pid="ucoICGupzEusiCWlH-MFPQ" hash="B33uVA">Parents, if you will keep in mind that you are preparing your sons and daughters to make covenants, receive ordinances, and render service, you will do things differently. You will have different priorities. You will teach with clearer vision and more productive effort. Missions and temples will see youth coming, not only in greater numbers, but also better qualified for these blessings. And they will embark early on a lifetime of service.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p24" pid="P1Zk_eXyOEeCjdXlXpy4Lw" hash="xzkl4g">And when your children do these things, they shall be lifted up at the last day, and shall arise and call you blessed—because you led them to eternal life.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service.p25" pid="m1ICkoLIpUG0klpu6N284A" hash="SL5N-w">When we as parents have a genuine <span class="emphasis">desire</span> to teach the gospel to our children, the Lord will give us entrance into their hearts. Then may we know that as we enter there we stand on holy ground. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1984/04/covenants-ordinances-and-service</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1984-general-conference/1984-04-2040-elder-a-theodore-tuttle-64k-eng.mp3" length="5437207" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 1984 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing Faith</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My beloved brothers and sisters, I would be ungrateful if I did not thank the many of you who have prayed for my well-being over the past few months. Medical science is marvelous, but above and beyond that, it takes special blessings from our Heavenl</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03206_000_028" doc-version="2" hash="SwCt6g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="h8Lg-59rHUWvWBE_h37cnA" hash="N69ECQ">Developing Faith</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="08qoBNWNFkCaelXS5RUlAg" hash="uG5ddw">A. Theodore Tuttle</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27d8.jpg" alt="Elder A. Theodore Tuttle" pid="i9rYRivV80iOpG79a4Hg_Q" hash="uF_y9g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p1" pid="9s2HFzrCD0GxgGX0wg2_Hg" hash="VeXdsg">My beloved brothers and sisters, I would be ungrateful if I did not thank the many of you who have prayed for my well-being over the past few months. Medical science is marvelous, but above and beyond that, it takes special blessings from our Heavenly Father for healing to occur. I appreciate your prayers in my behalf.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p2" pid="08L6k8maFkuz8r5fl7iB2A" hash="7wQD7A">I was told of a conversation by a Primary teacher, who related what transpired in his class. He was teaching the eleven-year-olds. He asked the question, “Suppose the Lord asked you to build a spaceship big enough to take you and your family and provisions off this planet? Could you do it?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p3" pid="w5ld0L-aE0axSncpDZK18g" hash="qsxdyg">Steve spoke up and said, “Yes.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p4" pid="MfLuPsXTwEiB472PKc2usw" hash="gPspWw">And the teacher said, “Have you ever built a spaceship?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p5" pid="0IwAat81gkWD_brOYPIM8Q" hash="5U6CmQ">“No.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p6" pid="q6p2sRmUYEeaIY_Nr2ih7g" hash="gJ2RsA">“Have you ever built a model spaceship?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p7" pid="cq6KmMRjpE650ok9ujn06A" hash="5U6CmQ1">“No.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p8" pid="tW0RmbaY50eaUcKCICEMSg" hash="byyTpg">“Have you ever seen one?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p9" pid="vBCrk5WUME2Sxbo9XplfAA" hash="7kHLBQ">Steve said, “Yes, on TV.” But then he declared, “You said the Lord <span class="emphasis">told</span> me to build it. If the Lord told me to build it, I could do it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p10" pid="nxXU1Wb9c0iMJhXjHafQKQ" hash="A6PJjw">I wonder how many of us as adults have that kind of faith. I would like to read in the Book of Mormon a great example of this kind of faith. I go to the seventeenth chapter of 1 Nephi:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p11" pid="481B4B77tUOIRehEqVL9qg" hash="wdYZ6Q">“And it came to pass that the Lord spake unto me [Nephi], saying: Thou shalt construct a ship, after the manner which I shall show thee, that I may carry thy people across these waters” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.8" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p12" pid="xbgYcyHdMEGju2GxUmO3nQ" hash="JYWtCQ">Listen to the answer of this great Nephi:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p13" pid="9py90uQdtUSG9hA8c-HUpw" hash="g5Il_A">“And I said: Lord, whither shall I go that I may find ore to molten, that I may make tools to construct the ship after the manner which thou hast shown unto me?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.9" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:9</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p14" pid="CRW6gSJP2k-UrmdDmwN6lA" hash="wtas5A">And when his brothers realized that he was actually going to set about to build a ship, they said: “Why, you’re a fool. You don’t know how to construct a ship” (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.17" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:17</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p15" pid="TrMcY6lFTEm0gz9jAuJTtg" hash="acRtOw">And then Nephi set about to teach them a great lesson.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p16" pid="t9_4pQGjzUy9sK-o3JTbmw" hash="c-Ov2g">How do you <span class="emphasis">develop</span> faith?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p17" pid="dNb8uXPYB0KZSbIOKZRFVA" hash="Ity9jA">Let’s learn a great lesson from what transpired with Nephi. He started to recount the things that had happened that they all knew were a part of their heritage. He went back to the coming of the children of Israel out of Egypt. He said: “You know what happened. There they were right against the Red Sea with the Egyptians coming, and the Lord saved them” (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.26-27" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:26–27</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p18" pid="u9qzk7hu7E-kaNEhYqI6FQ" hash="1Gq75Q">Then he goes on and talks about how they received manna in the wilderness, how they received water from a rock, how the Lord led them by a pillar of cloud in the daytime and a light at night, and how when they crossed the Jordan, it stopped when the feet of the priests touched the water (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.28-30,32" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:28–30, 32</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/13.21" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 13:21</a>, <a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/3.15-17" class="scriptureRef">Josh. 3:15–17</a>). And then Nephi tells how the Lord scattered the people; and then how, when they came among the flying serpents, Moses fashioned a brazen serpent, raised it, and all they had to do was look at that serpent, and they would be healed. The account says that many perished because they wouldn’t even look (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.32,41" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:32, 41</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/ot/num/21.8-9" class="scriptureRef">Num. 21:8–9</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p19" pid="wEzyyYkYbke7RIE7FNKuUg" hash="dZ-s_w">He was trying to do what you and I as parents need to do with our families today—to develop faith in the Lord. And the way to do it is to recount the examples of faith that have happened in our history and in our heritage and with our people. That’s the value of history. It contains accounts of faith of our own blood and ancestry and of our own people and our children. As has already been said in this conference, we cannot go one generation without losing faith if we do not do this. And to rear a generation of faith for what we must do in these days, you and I simply must develop and increase faith in the Lord Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p20" pid="lGALvPAVX0OYYcTECETOYw" hash="0fGQIA">There’s another principle: that is, that faith precedes the miracle. This lesson is found in Ether, chapter 12. You’ll recall that Moroni was abridging the records of the twenty-four plates, and this is what he records:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p21" pid="HtImIarbc0y4duhE7PYpQQ" hash="7AGH1w">“And it came to pass that Ether did prophesy great and marvelous things unto the people, which they did not believe, because they saw them not” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.5" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p22" pid="Hl496rj6gUiJ4fpHP5Mg3g" hash="8tDXwA">They couldn’t see them; they wouldn’t believe them. They needed to be taught that <span class="emphasis">believing</span> is seeing. And then Moroni interpolates here:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p23" pid="kO_4h2eig0yJyVrJ2SZfxA" hash="RlXWLg">“And now, I, Moroni, would speak somewhat concerning these things; I would show unto the world that faith is things which are hoped for and not seen; wherefore, dispute not because ye see not, for ye receive no witness until <span class="emphasis">after</span> the trial of your faith” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.6" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:6</a>; italics added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p24" pid="e15Q9mJyzk2Y5GFiGRg5Yg" hash="hOYU3A">We need to learn that. We can’t have just faith. We cannot have the miracle until <span class="emphasis">after</span> the exercise of faith. Moroni sets forth on the next page or so instances of those miracles that have occurred after the trial of the faith of the people. We need to learn that principle as well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p25" pid="dyEMl-cNKkC9zJ4c3jwBNQ" hash="_37zaQ">I recall that when I was twenty years old, I went for an interview with the bishop to go on a mission. When I returned, my mother, all smiles, said, “Well, Ted, what did the bishop say?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p26" pid="irKYW3IaZ0aawrao--6zkQ" hash="KK6ajg">“He said I couldn’t go.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p27" pid="1wSUgojopEmPtB5TPXT-ug" hash="yQ8CKw">“Why not?” my mother asked.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p28" pid="KfIswbx9uUmzMdIap69_Gw" hash="m9O11w">And I said, “Because we don’t have enough money.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p29" pid="GTYgP-3mVk6UkzgUy7NFpw" hash="3RDxjA">“If my father could leave two children and another to be born shortly after he left, you can go.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p30" pid="ohHDY6ZgckyelYIAmjkGeA" hash="Hk6iEw">I said, “I know that, but the bishop doesn’t.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p31" pid="J319ITEh4kKetbWDhYhZjQ" hash="XNGgoQ">Parenthetically, I might say that he was doing his job right. He asked me if I had any money. I told him I had a few hundred dollars that I had earned that summer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p32" pid="1AAUqCoHFUu26X81juwLjA" hash="TB-sIg">He said, “Then what?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p33" pid="vqMr1fMpPkiUqkn8z5aQpg" hash="2SoFOQ">I said, “My dad would send it to me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p34" pid="cajreBSr00-UZCsUY1lBFg" hash="2ivxDQ">He said, “Does your dad have it?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p35" pid="zdVkum2peUCVt5qyvW055w" hash="w4KfcA">I said, “No,” and he didn’t. We had lost our sheep herd during the Depression. My father was a livestock dealer buying lambs and wool on commission, and that was a very uncertain income.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p36" pid="avWpc5y3f0uonG6bpC5Xgg" hash="AD6Z6w">The bishop said, “The Brethren have had some serious experiences, and so you cannot go unless you can guarantee that you’ll have sufficient money.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p37" pid="EiYdOnRmsUK8AcHaQu9IXA" hash="cCEKiA">I accepted that, and that’s what I told my mother.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p38" pid="QkFpevgxwEm-eNP0v49nIg" hash="GMZIOQ">That night we waited for Dad to come home and then held a family council. We concluded that we didn’t then have enough money—and that we wouldn’t, so far as we could see, anytime in the future. We decided to ask our neighbor, Tom Anderson, a rather wealthy man, if he would help. When we explained our situation, he said, “You tell the bishop that I will ‘back you.’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p39" pid="yP9WUYiKBEWKYBYw0EeKKA" hash="CgpOMw">Before the bishop opened his business the next morning, I was there waiting to tell him that Tom Anderson said he would back me. The bishop said, “That’s all I need to know.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p40" pid="5j0JPB4CpU6QLuc_s_vXmQ" hash="F4vfOw">The interesting thing was that we never did have to call on Brother Anderson. My folks would send that check and with it a note, “This is for this month, and we’ll have the next month’s, too.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p41" pid="jMTO8m8oO0KkAdJTzHI4TA" hash="_0UTXg">I am a product of a household of faith. I learned faith in my home. I was taught it. It was drilled into me. I need that faith now as much as I ever did.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p42" pid="ZZZg1o3_-Eq114IYvYLETg" hash="Que0gA">I think we all do. We’re not going to survive in this world, temporally or spiritually, without increased faith in the Lord—and I don’t mean a positive mental attitude—I mean downright solid faith in the Lord Jesus Christ. That is the one thing that gives vitality and power to otherwise rather weak individuals.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p43" pid="J6XeU2wG-kyj6KYDspqb9g" hash="pLi1DQ">I bear you my humble witness that I know that God lives. I know that he lives, that he is our Father, that he loves us. I bear witness that Jesus is the Christ, our Savior and our Redeemer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith.p44" pid="p3GlJJ7te0K0YNy8qpvgbg" hash="LgrpGQ">I understand better what that means now. I am grateful for his atonement in our behalf and for knowing something about our relationship to him and to our Heavenly Father and about the meaning and purpose of the gospel of Jesus Christ. I am grateful for Joseph Smith. I know he was a prophet, and I know that President Ezra Taft Benson is a living prophet today. I bear that witness in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1986/10/developing-faith</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1986-general-conference/1986-10-5030-elder-a-theodore-tuttle-64k-eng.mp3" length="6509197" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 1986 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
