<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Adney Y. Komatsu</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Adney Y. Komatsu.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Adney%20Y.%20Komatsu.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Adney Y. Komatsu.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>My Mother Gained a Better Son</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In humility, I would like to bear you my testimony of the truthfulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ and my conversion to the Church.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03057_000_043" doc-version="2" hash="Y_xFZw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="6v4lsWk-kEqMBs4CtHWhRg" hash="JRzzHA">My Mother Gained a Better Son</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="VG5C0d1m3EKbfxDqIYa9sw" hash="LuJyCw">Adney Y. Komatsu</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2bcc.jpg" alt="Elder Adney Y. Komatsu" pid="t-v5zR7SNES7dMBxjHEzdA" hash="0lr9pw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son.p1" pid="edgYKtQQpU6L0ZgEFMsiLg" hash="VgTdOA">In humility, I would like to bear you my testimony of the truthfulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ and my conversion to the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son.p2" pid="pFK4CyfaSESm5_WyLQD8Ew" hash="Q_pcKw">A little over 34 years ago, when yet a high school student, I was first contacted by the missionaries—who invited me to attend MIA and join their basketball team. Not knowing anything about the Church, but being very interested in basketball, I attended MIA. Later I attended Sunday School, then sacrament meeting.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son.p3" pid="Ew1qfERLfUSGKKE7sAIY-Q" hash="qaMyPg">After a year of attendance and studying the gospel with the missionaries, and having read the story of Joseph Smith’s first vision, I accepted the invitation to be baptized into the Church. That evening, I returned home, having committed myself to baptism, to ask my widowed mother for permission to be baptized.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son.p4" pid="woBx6wumCUmfLEWMnbsgYw" hash="F-5dzw">Suddenly I saw tears in her eyes. I asked her why was she shedding tears. And she answered, saying, “These are not tears of joy, but of sadness”—for she had just lost another son. In her widowhood she had lost a son—my brother—and so she said she had just lost another son to a Christian church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son.p5" pid="CZzggcssMUaU7Udm25gHPw" hash="4yo_fg">She later explained that at my father’s deathbed she had promised and covenanted with him to raise the children honorably in the Buddhist faith. I quickly assured my mother that in the year that I had been associating with the missionaries, I had always been lifted up and had learned nothing but good things from them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son.p6" pid="4KFkivA8ok-0yS7FT54nKA" hash="e36EAQ">I promised her that if she would permit me to be baptized and later found that through my behavior I had caused her any embarrassment—or committed some shameful or dishonorable act—then all she had to do was ask me to stop going to church, and I would, without question, obey her will.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son.p7" pid="VclbvmTUFUKQ_g2WptwzTw" hash="BzPZsQ">However, on the other hand, if I became a better person—more attentive to her needs as a widow, more kind toward the demands of home, brothers, and sisters—then, I said, “Would you permit me to continue to go to church? Because I know that this is the place where I can gain an education for an eternal life.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son.p8" pid="FqkCxQ0tT0GOZIdkpcYPPA" hash="1NeY9A">It is my testimony today that I never had to leave the Church nor cause my mother any concern about my behavior. As I lived the gospel principles taught by the missionaries, and as I studied the principles myself, I had the assurance from my Father in heaven that my future outcome would be one that I would never have to worry about.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son.p9" pid="MSThWfRa9UixTCIclw5RCw" hash="bGipeA">I have always tried since baptism to put the principles of the gospel in practice. I have always especially loved this scripture that I came across in Matthew: “But seek ye first the kingdom of God, and his righteousness; and all these things shall be added unto you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.33" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 6:33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son.p10" pid="QZWchvo2fk6S1aRT7kYOTA" hash="XqabUA">I have tried in all of my years of membership in the Church to never refuse the Church whenever a call came to me. I have surely been blessed by the Lord as I have lived the gospel principles, and I have come to appreciate the sacred priesthood that I hold.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son.p11" pid="hu4ujRx28kCPgRM6wifB_w" hash="MSnVHQ">I am grateful today for the missionaries—like those that are covering the world today—who came to Hawaii to teach the gospel principles and the many members of the Church there that I have associated with who have taught me gospel principles, as well as leadership principles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son.p12" pid="pOIT97T6ekGmwSKmJ7O9SQ" hash="8-UCRA">I am grateful to my dear wife and our children, for we have had a blessed life together living in a Mormon home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son.p13" pid="mJZFJIjAUEyKRo52anHyZw" hash="Vf6Wng">I bear you my testimony humbly this day that I know God lives. He hears and answers our prayers, and Jesus is the Christ, the Only Begotten of the Father and the Savior of the world. Joseph Smith was indeed an instrument in the hands of the Lord, commissioned to begin the restoration of the gospel of Jesus Christ in its fullness for the salvation of all mankind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son.p14" pid="lUNpwlx7Wk2bAEmAHnwIjQ" hash="7Rc7zQ">All the presidents of the Church that followed Joseph Smith—they were all called of God, and even today, President Spencer W. Kimball is our living prophet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son.p15" pid="CtZLBvKLAky4phaTMTb1fQ" hash="t5WCow">I bear you this witness humbly in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/04/my-mother-gained-a-better-son</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1975-general-conference/1975-04-7030-elder-adney-y-komatsu-64k-eng.mp3" length="2670809" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faith and Works in the Far East</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, and friends: In humility I stand before you and thank my Father in heaven for this opportunity and blessing of being in attendance at this semiannual conference. I have enjoyed the wonderful spirit of the conference and </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03063_000_037" doc-version="3" hash="kVAYpg">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="zA5RnojXvUa0l5BPdK2aXw" hash="SiNnTg">Faith and Works in the Far East</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="tqlTUst8v0KMVLncPzjNpg" hash="LuJyCw">Adney Y. Komatsu</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.t1">
			<img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2bcc.jpg" alt="Elder Adney Y. Komats" pid="ABI9bkmoBUyhWuS1qK--Rw" hash="0lr9pw" />
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p1" pid="J5oxj0ygVEy6ucwZyE0i8w" hash="EpCp5w">My dear brothers and sisters, and friends: In humility I stand before you and thank my Father in heaven for this opportunity and blessing of being in attendance at this semiannual conference. I have enjoyed the wonderful spirit of the conference and the many instructions and the advice given by our prophet, President Spencer W. Kimball and all the General Authorities of the Church. I hope and pray that the Spirit of the Lord may guide and direct me to say those things that will add to the spirit of this conference.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p2" pid="0-mN4M8ZZEaGEBHLq7qSrg" hash="tsJVhA">In the New Testament we read the words of John: “For God so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son, that whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.16" class="scriptureRef">John 3:16</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p3" pid="8OYHHq4qx06B-lqJlqB6dg" hash="aXQg6w">Our Father in heaven, because of the great love that he has for his children on this earth, gave us the opportunity to experience an earthly life and prepared a way that we may return to his presence after this earthly experience through the Savior, Jesus Christ.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p4" pid="4b6A7cH0Hk-WlRqnECSz6Q" hash="P35CfA">The Savior said during his ministry: “I am the resurrection, and the life: he that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live: And whosoever liveth and believeth in me shall never die.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/11.25-26" class="scriptureRef">John 11:25–26</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p5" pid="2QIBQ_KxkESCW96oXNLcBw" hash="lnR_wA">The Savior further said: “He that believeth on me, believeth not on me, but on him that sent me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/12.44" class="scriptureRef">John 12:44</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p6" pid="48V4CcUPW0Gb1-PwD0QQjQ" hash="_q-JaQ">We, who are members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, as well as many of the Christian world today, understand and believe that there is a God, and that Jesus is the Christ, the Son of the living God, and the Savior of the world.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p7" pid="JHkP7aJVi0CFLlVOs13ZKA" hash="G-codg">Yet, in the Far East among the many Asian countries today where we find the great majority of the population of the world living, this simple truth is not understood and accepted as God’s plan for his children on earth.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p8" pid="5lfEblRfJkqknKwByYCQfQ" hash="4VxROw">However, the work of the Lord is progressing among the Asian people. Ten years ago there were three missions in the Far East; today there are fifteen missions and five stakes.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p9" pid="N0BrCflXVU6pA5kc9r5GzQ" hash="EgsVtw">In the recent area general conferences held in Japan, the Philippines, Taiwan, Hong Kong, and Korea, it was a great and wonderful experience to see the tears of joy of the members of the Church as they listened to President Spencer W. Kimball, our prophet, and other General Authorities.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p10" pid="4PScPhSXUUCd7QMO7RjZ4Q" hash="XoBDww">It was reported that approximately 45,000 members and nonmembers attended the area general conferences in these countries. For many members and nonmembers of the Church, this was their first experience of hearing a living prophet of God.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p11" pid="r3rcRsH1EU2ZDtWNC790rg" hash="1Q4Jdg">In Tokyo, when President Kimball made a proposal for the building of a temple, there was a spontaneous applause of joy and happiness by the congregation; then a quiet appreciation of tears followed while they raised their hands to sustain the proposal. Likewise, in all the other countries where an area general conference was held, the members of the Church were happy to sustain the proposal made by the prophet for the first temple to be built in Asia.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p12" pid="hOuJGcovSkimeF-I8IL19w" hash="K8X2Gw">It was a great and wonderful experience to see President Kimball counsel and advise the members of the Church in Asia and see their faces full of appreciation and love for the guidance and direction they received.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p13" pid="BGm6p-6vM0mm0_sZEdgF2Q" hash="RZyJMQ">President Kimball encouraged the members of the Church in the different countries to live the gospel of Jesus Christ and keep the commandments of the Lord. He reminded them of the importance and need for more genealogy work and emphasized the importance of temple marriage. This great blessing will be available to the members of the Church in a few short years when the temple is built; and for some it will be only a few hours away from their homes, while for others it will take a longer journey, but not as far as Hawaii where the majority of the members are now going. President Kimball also stressed the importance of the family and the raising of young men who will be worthy to serve missions.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p14" pid="koWH-NCRgkG2nuMo9sdrSw" hash="-a44zw">Because of the large population in the Asian countries, and if we are to bring the gospel message to the many people there, we must lengthen our stride in missionary work and adhere to the counsel and advice of President Kimball by preparing our local young men to assist in this great work. It will take the efforts of every member of the Church in Asia, and we must follow President McKay’s appeal that “every member be a missionary” in his daily life.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p15" pid="3v-E-BfHrEm2XmVRN3l-VQ" hash="0Vj0vA">For many members of the Church, the area general conferences were miracles, for they had never dreamed that the day would come when they could listen to a prophet speak in person, nor attend area general conferences under their difficult and trying conditions and circumstances.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p16" pid="W0fVG_HosU6GEwwVnN2tFQ" hash="-plQDQ">I am reminded of a statement made by a Book of Mormon prophet when he said:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p17" pid="yQCRJsV6Xk2FpmnwUpwwlA" hash="Qh5BRw">“And now, I, Moroni, would speak somewhat concerning these things; I would show unto the world that faith is things which are hoped for and not seen; wherefore, dispute not because ye see not, for ye receive no witness until after the trial of your faith. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p18" pid="OmlalOPCYkioUN8dtNrhuA" hash="1F4nVw">“For if there be no faith among the children of men God can do no miracle among them; wherefore, he showed not himself until after their faith. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p19" pid="ZX2KTjfn5EyF3JvIX6ZYfg" hash="bBjpwQ">“And neither at any time hath any wrought miracles until after their faith; wherefore they first believed in the Son of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.6,12,18" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:6, 12, 18</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p20" pid="f7VLUFGMnEmS8hSQVbPMSw" hash="8wBfaQ">Surely the many members of the Church in the different countries exercised faith to receive the great blessings of area general conferences.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p21" pid="cJ30fjYonkWdaBSuUy3Clg" hash="MkGRmg">There were many faith-promoting experiences witnessed by the members of the Church as they prepared for the area general conference in their respective countries. All these experiences helped to increase their faith and strengthen their testimonies.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p22" pid="pjNEaCtMaESfDjjcGpltVg" hash="r6R-6w">May I share with you an experience that took place on the island of Okinawa in the Servicemen’s District? As the local Okinawan members were excitedly preparing to go to Tokyo, which is nearly 900 miles away, for the area general conference, the young people of the Servicemen’s Branch found out that an active young Okinawan family was not planning to go with the rest of the branch. When approached and asked why he was not going to conference, this faithful brother hesitantly replied that he just could not afford to take his wife and children at this time; it was out of the question.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p23" pid="mbyLQUwtaE6nzKPvPuB0Pw" hash="jkCORg">The young people of the Servicemen’s Branch immediately met and planned a cookie sale project to raise funds necessary to send this family to conference. The young people baked cookies in their parents’ homes; later when they were busily engaged in selling these cookies, they were pleasantly surprised when they approached the servicemen to purchase their cookies, explaining the purpose of their project. Without hesitation the servicemen all bought cookies and donated money in excess of the purchase price, so that the young people could reach their goal. The happy result was that this young Okinawan family was able to go to Tokyo to conference with the rest of their branch, because of the help they received.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p24" pid="2nFc4JNchkO5cRGsJr0qJA" hash="0ejFDQ">The young people of the Servicemen’s Branch all learned a great lesson in giving and loving; they learned through experience that persons who really care for others and who give some of their time, talents, and belongings for the good of others are the ones who really receive the fullest blessings of life.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p25" pid="meY0yKnNRk-nS8pe9birhQ" hash="g9qoag">The Prophet Joseph Smith tells us that love begets love in this way: “It is a time-honored adage that love begets love. Let us pour forth love—show forth our kindness unto all mankind, and the Lord will reward us with everlasting increase; cast our bread upon the waters and we shall receive it after many days, increased to a hundredfold. Friendship is like Brother Turley in his blacksmith shop welding iron to iron; it unites the human family with its happy influences.” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith,</span> p. 316.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p26" pid="keLFXHt3r0OzWPvr8Nqm3Q" hash="m1Kjjg">Surely the many members of the Church in Asia who participated in the preparation for the different area conferences learned this great lesson of giving and loving. They also received the blessings of the Lord as they sang in choruses, danced in the cultural programs, or served on the many committees in the different countries.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p27" pid="qnzSmFHAQ02Wt4W4HOlmRA" hash="0ODcJQ">To give our time and self for the good of others is more important than giving material things in life. This most important part of the gospel is the very foundation of God’s commandments, for he said: “Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, with all thy might, mind, and strength; and in the name of Jesus Christ thou shalt serve him.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p28" pid="QQpC4uZ7m0a0tO6tt1t9NA" hash="ST0AKw">“Thou shalt love thy neighbor as thyself.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.5-6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:5–6</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p29" pid="d9OEw1zEIUqVGFWICxyBGg" hash="ZSkwPQ">This means, brothers and sisters and friends, that one does things for and with his neighbors. He visits the sick and the needy. He buoys up the discouraged and gives encouragement at every turn, while seeking the happiness of others.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p30" pid="YXYaUiK-y0-8ANtnrTfgXg" hash="bEIqmg">Robert Louis Stevenson said, “If we would have friends we should be rich in admiration and free from envy; rejoice greatly in the good of others; love with such generosity of heart that your love becomes a dear possession in absence or unkindness.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p31" pid="q8zRFZzivUi1rM3kPsDCtQ" hash="8EagSQ">When we actively participate in Church activities, and give of ourselves in home teaching, visiting teaching, or fellowshipping a newly converted family or a less active person, we are showing our love for our fellowman. The Savior said, “This is my commandment, That ye love one another, as I have loved you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/15.12" class="scriptureRef">John 15:12</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p32" pid="b18a4OvFLUybcdNRCuqTyQ" hash="Pgs4Xg">I bear you my testimony, brothers and sisters, that I know that the gospel is true. I know that God lives and that he hears and answers our prayers, and that Jesus is the Christ, the Only Begotten of the Father, the Son of the living God, and the Savior of the world. Joseph Smith was the prophet called by God in these last days to restore the gospel in its fulness.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east.p33" pid="7HmRFrX0SEW1uGqLu3f6nA" hash="uSIDSQ">And I bear you this humble testimony that I know that President Spencer W. Kimball today is a prophet of God on this earth, guiding and directing the Lord’s work here upon this earth. I bear you this testimony humbly, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/10/faith-and-works-in-the-far-east</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1975-general-conference/1975-10-6030-elder-adney-y-komatsu-64k-eng.mp3" length="5318571" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 1975 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Blessing of Building a Temple</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters and friends: It is glorious to be here with you in this great conference and feel the Spirit of the Lord made manifest through the many inspired words spoken by the Brethren. My testimony has been strengthened; my heart h</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03070_000_045" doc-version="2" hash="AO_D5A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="9_6ZMlUc_06rmocRabFzzQ" hash="2gNTkw">The Blessing of Building a Temple</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="uSZyNL2Z6keI7Rqs61hNoQ" hash="LuJyCw">Adney Y. Komatsu</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2bcc.jpg" alt="Elder Adney Y. Komatsu" pid="jp-PJF2hBE-amzYIYTPQ6g" hash="0lr9pw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p1" pid="JTtAI2fwsU-5v48LnBQ32w" hash="oFKZVw">My dear brothers and sisters and friends: It is glorious to be here with you in this great conference and feel the Spirit of the Lord made manifest through the many inspired words spoken by the Brethren. My testimony has been strengthened; my heart has been touched by the spoken words. I humbly bear you my testimony that I know that this is the Lord’s church, led by a living prophet of God, President Spencer W. Kimball.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p2" pid="B52WWawx8US2x2elVbTXmg" hash="oYAGrg">President Kimball has repeatedly admonished us of the necessity for more missionaries to bring the gospel message to the peoples of the world. He has reminded us that every worthy young man should go on a mission. Today we are experiencing an increase in convert baptisms as more dedicated young men and women answer their calls to serve as missionaries for the Lord. The Church is growing very rapidly in many parts of the world because of the leadership and direction we receive from a living prophet of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p3" pid="u40Uttan40GtZubhRigsHw" hash="eLWYYw">President Kimball also has announced through inspiration and revelation the need for more temples; and last year three areas in the world were designated to receive this great blessing of a new house of the Lord, namely, São Paulo, Brazil; Tokyo, Japan; and Seattle, Washington.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p4" pid="Li_PZOK4GUSZtRnd4c0pVg" hash="D8TN3A">As the gospel of Jesus Christ was restored in these last days, temple building and temple ordinances were restored through the Prophet Joseph Smith. Soon after the Church was organized on April 6, 1830, the Lord commanded the Saints to build a temple; and from 1833 to 1836, with fewer than two thousand members in the Church, the Prophet Joseph Smith and the Saints commenced to build a temple in Kirtland, Ohio.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p5" pid="GRP7u2KtGUeZEzeaAbSzYg" hash="J_ZX0g">The Saints at that time did not have many worldly possessions, but with great personal sacrifice they gave all they had to build the house of the Lord. Their sacrifices were many, but compared with the great blessing that followed, they were only small offerings unto the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p6" pid="d4ARjjDhSEi9yK3xQy10Nw" hash="47dcHg">For on April 3, 1836, after the completion of the temple, on the occasion of a Sabbath day meeting and after solemn and silent prayer, the Prophet Joseph Smith and Oliver Cowdery received a great manifestation. A vision was opened to them with a personal manifestation from the Lord Jesus Christ of his acceptance of the temple. They were also visited by three great prophets holding the keys and authority of their callings, each committing into the hands of Joseph and Oliver his authority and calling as the restoration of the gospel in its fullness began.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p7" pid="Rwi762BI60Gr_-Vkp2pKLw" hash="SC6fhA">Today I am sure the Saints in the areas where temples will be built are also sacrificing and living by faith to fulfill their obligations and assignments. In Japan and in the other areas of the Orient, members have committed themselves to the building of the temple as well as to the building of stake centers and chapels.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p8" pid="rdU7uMweBE-JXfUdtoIyAg" hash="fD8z0g">Recently a young father bore his testimony regarding his contribution to the temple fund. His challenge by his bishop was to accept a suggested assessment for the contribution to the temple fund. This amount totaled nearly all he had saved through the years to build his own home. After discussing this with his wife and his children, they decided to give to the Lord all they had in their savings account for the building of the temple in Tokyo, and they gave up their dream of a new home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p9" pid="dAMxBYAmM0ixEWk6RSdxnA" hash="lPu5Jw">One day, not too long after making this contribution to the bishop, the man’s superiors called him into the office and unexpectedly gave him a promotion in the company, with a large increase in his salary, and also with the promotion came an allowance for a new home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p10" pid="Hz-DS3Uh4kG8dCN3ea1QGQ" hash="p0C3Nw">I am sure there are many other faith-promoting experiences among the members of the Church as they dedicate their lives to the needs of the building of the kingdom of God on this earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p11" pid="XeJ3by2Go0CYwvXlI264Ww" hash="c8VlAg">It is gratifying to see the dedication and faithfulness of the members. Surely the Lord God will bless and honor those who meet their obligations and sacrifice their time, talents, and means in helping to build the kingdom of God on this earth. By latter-day revelation the Lord promises those who are faithful, “For thus saith the Lord—I, the Lord, am merciful and gracious unto those who fear me, and delight to honor those who serve me in righteousness and in truth unto the end.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p12" pid="daVUa8egiUS-Kkb152xlUA" hash="Ijln8Q">“Great shall be their reward and eternal shall be their glory.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.5-6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:5–6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p13" pid="P1guxEDPlUSgz4aFv8JCgw" hash="rfAbyw">One of the three great prophets appearing to the Prophet Joseph Smith and Oliver Cowdery in the Kirtland Temple was Elijah the prophet, who was taken to heaven without tasting death. As he committed the keys of this dispensation into their hands he said, “Behold, the time has fully come, which was spoken of by the mouth of Malachi—testifying that he [Elijah] should be sent, before the great and dreadful day of the Lord come—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p14" pid="gfDNK-WprUCsQ-usy_03_g" hash="LfMuCA">“To turn the hearts of the fathers to the children, and the children to the fathers, lest the whole earth be smitten with a curse.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/110.14-15" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 110:14–15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p15" pid="X5-qV2RV3UasUZDRAXcqgg" hash="RBV8Cg">May I share with you this afternoon an experience that happened to a young couple who were members of the Church in Japan. They wished to be married, and as is the custom in Japan, they sought permission from their nonmember parents for the marriage to be performed. The boy’s parents refused to give permission. With concern and disappointment, the young couple prayerfully sought ways to fill their lives with meaningful Church activities and trusted that permission would be forthcoming later.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p16" pid="mmhtouzYbUSSpqmlT8bn8A" hash="1HpLyw">At this time Church members were planning a trip to the Hawaii Temple, and much emphasis was made and was being placed on the importance of genealogical research. So the couple joined with others in seeking out their ancestors and in planning to have the temple work done for them. The girl searched diligently through shrines, cemeteries, and government record offices, and was able to gather seventy-seven names. The boy’s uncle, who was a respected and influential member of the family, heard of this and was deeply impressed with and interested in her work. He noted the intense devotion of the girl to honoring her ancestors and suggested that such a young lady would be a good wife for his nephew. Permission was granted for the young people to be married, and the marriage was performed. Later they were sealed in the Hawaii Temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p17" pid="29cQUHkvPUuM9UWxH_9D1Q" hash="A3Y3sQ">It is a Japanese tradition that families gather together for special holidays in January and August. As this young couple joined their family members on these special occasions, they displayed their book of remembrance, and much interest was generated in their work and in the reasons for it. They discussed with those relatives assembled their ancestral lines and the importance of completing the genealogical research. It was difficult for their nonmember families to understand the reasons for a Christian church teaching principles such as “ancestral worship,” for this was a Buddhist teaching and tradition.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p18" pid="KJgegog5RUmh5IsLTXNMUQ" hash="36cueA">Today many young men and women are completing their family group sheets and are teaching the gospel of Jesus Christ to their parents and their relatives by this method. Through genealogical research and through doing temple work for their progenitors, and especially with a temple now becoming available in Tokyo, members can so live that the gospel will yet be embraced by many more in the Orient. This great work has just begun.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple.p19" pid="GIy7q1noCUaAKR1k_KTj2Q" hash="ghBD6A">I bear you my witness that the gospel of Jesus Christ is the way of salvation for the living and the dead and that God hears and answers our prayers. He will inspire and assist us to gather up the records of our progenitors, and he will open the way that we may bring joy and salvation into the lives of those who blessed us with this life. I bear you my humble testimony that I know that Joseph Smith was an instrument in the hands of the Lord to restore the gospel in these last days and we have a living prophet in President Spencer W. Kimball, who is guiding and directing The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. To this I testify, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/04/the-blessing-of-building-a-temple</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1976-general-conference/1976-04-7050-elder-adney-y-komatsu-64k-eng.mp3" length="9240115" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1976 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“After Much Tribulation Come the Blessings”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Thirteen years ago, as a mission president in Japan, I received a call from a young serviceman’s wife who needed to see me. Her husband, an air force pilot, had just been shot down and had died in combat over Vietnam. As she was ushered into my offic</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03115_000_026" doc-version="2" hash="XobSPg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="HqHxfwIja0moNqY9vXFfCg" hash="NQe3WA">“After Much Tribulation Come the Blessings”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="osu-1MSuPk6075ekjphTpg" hash="LuJyCw">Adney Y. Komatsu</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2bcc.jpg" alt="Elder Adney Y. Komatsu" pid="3-VaZ-QJUECdihw7SClG1w" hash="0lr9pw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p1" pid="2eV7vlkzKUyFrFB9OarXGg" hash="jZwcsA">Thirteen years ago, as a mission president in Japan, I received a call from a young serviceman’s wife who needed to see me. Her husband, an air force pilot, had just been shot down and had died in combat over Vietnam. As she was ushered into my office, I saw her hugging a large picture. We sat down to talk and she showed me the picture of her husband, a handsome pilot with his helmet in his hands, standing proudly beside his jet fighter plane.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p2" pid="Fiv04KPkVEm68JWqd2hj4Q" hash="VG-stw">She sobbingly said how much she loved him and couldn’t believe that he was gone. She continued by saying that she was a convert of nearly two years. She had met her husband while in college, and it was he who had introduced her to the gospel. Later she was baptized, and they were sealed in the temple for time and all eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p3" pid="zNguzls9a0eNW9iYp3vPHw" hash="7m_3FQ">Her life with him had been beautiful and everything a person could ask for. She had looked toward the future with great joy and anticipation. But now, all too soon, it had come to a sudden, crashing halt.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p4" pid="7aEZD9HZ2E-nsCowuXTiyA" hash="VqR4rg">She had a great adjustment to make in her life and wanted assurance that all would be well. What would your counsel be to her?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p5" pid="rfC8ZRrJNEWUAfTFaYzn4w" hash="Z92oQg">The Lord has said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p6" pid="KO3ToVVU3UGzREOQ7FrRGg" hash="yz3kyA">“For verily I say unto you, blessed is he that keepeth my commandments, whether in life or in death; and he that is faithful in tribulation, the reward of the same is greater in the kingdom of heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p7" pid="rKbme6Sm0UaI23BWGzh6YA" hash="NrA0vA">“Ye cannot behold with your natural eyes, for the present time, the design of your God concerning those things which shall … follow after much tribulation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p8" pid="y6lbMPwYQk23XtFUGUf50g" hash="Bk0DWw">“For after much tribulation come the blessings” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.2-4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:2–4</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p9" pid="5a9cdOhHHUyOn56sK9tLVw" hash="Ih9m4Q">As we pass through this mortal probation, we accrue many experiences. It is in these experiences that we are often beset with problems, challenges, adversities, afflictions, trials, and tribulations. The Lord said to the Prophet Joseph Smith, after a period of great afflictions, “Know thou, my son, that all these things shall give thee experience, and shall be for thy good” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/122.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 122:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p10" pid="-nUcog6Ax06q41uotKxhxg" hash="jOP_KQ">The early members and leaders of the Church suffered many afflictions, challenges, and trials. Many gave their very lives for their belief and testimony of the gospel. In the long journey over the pioneer trails, many children and adults were buried in graves along the way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p11" pid="fCyTcNgEB0WrsXiM81s_mg" hash="RqWM7A">We have the promise of the Lord who said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p12" pid="vfJCxpkT5kqPH5guMX4wBw" hash="XRMpdw">“And it shall come to pass that those that die in me shall not taste of death, for it shall be sweet unto them;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p13" pid="ixFETobU4UKNcRS4vAAXHQ" hash="vQQOiA">“And they that die not in me, wo unto them, for their death is bitter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p14" pid="Pn6BI02SMkC1cGzEvV3ovA" hash="OSRtuQ">“Thou shalt live together in love, insomuch that thou shalt weep for the loss of them that die, and more especially for those that have not hope of a glorious resurrection” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.46-47,45" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:46–47, 45</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p15" pid="CT8BeoZpz0qR8G3BJQxa5A" hash="w5XPRw">Recently I attended a funeral service for a faithful member of the Church on the remote island of Vava’u in Tonga. This good brother had been loved by the people of his village, and he had the respect of nonmembers as well as Church members.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p16" pid="ei5vMRk43kyoaayfbI_VKQ" hash="Gy4TEQ">As the funeral procession left his home and proceeded to the grave site, the whole village followed and finally gathered on a knoll overlooking a peaceful bay. The people clustered around the grave site while the bishop and those participating stood facing the family. I couldn’t help but notice that while many were overcome with sadness and wept during the service, the widow sat peacefully by her beloved husband.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p17" pid="NpRZN_2QbUmQsmJB50pehQ" hash="XLo9pg">I knew that she had the knowledge of the resurrection and plan of salvation. I later learned that she and her husband had journeyed to the New Zealand Temple and had been sealed together for time and all eternity. In her life, this was not a total calamity but rather a part of God’s plan. There was about her an air of peace and appreciation for the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p18" pid="Cz8Fw-aAF0iPebFOS3gcDg" hash="cznaEw">President Kimball stated: “The Lord has not promised us freedom from adversity or affliction. Instead, he has given us the avenue of communication known as prayer, whereby we might humble ourselves and seek his help and divine guidance, so that we could establish a house of prayer.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p19" pid="K5_Rv0wrhkmriqwtcVLrMw" hash="SBci3Q">President Kimball also said: “They who reach down into the depths of life where, in the stillness, the voice of God has been heard, have the stabilizing power which carries them poised and serene through the hurricane of difficulties” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1979, p. 6).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p20" pid="fvTkEstpnUmw_8RqBFe-Iw" hash="gai2Ew">President Harold B. Lee stated in general conference in 1965: “Just as a flood-lighted temple is more beautiful in a severe storm or in a heavy fog, so the gospel of Jesus Christ is more glorious in times of inward storm and of personal sorrow and tormenting conflict” (in Conference Report, Apr. 1965, p. 16).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p21" pid="8Wn0hkaMmE-3j4DrC2ixIg" hash="-1tb1A">May I share another experience with you? A few years ago in Japan, a stake was being organized from a mission district. In the course of an interview, the district president stated that he would shortly be moving to another city where he had accepted a promotion with his company to become the manager of their largest branch. But the Lord wanted this man to serve as the new stake president. He was called before the General Authority who inquired whether his superiors would reconsider the promotion and allow him to remain in the city where he might be able to serve his church in this very important position.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p22" pid="7QkVGp8ORkmRVZRHe9oGCA" hash="0gnyBA">Immediately the district president stated that he had given his word to his superiors who had already made changes in all of the branches in the company, except in the branch that he was to supervise. He had asked for a delay of his assignment until after the organization of the stake.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p23" pid="W1sbVSFIp0ymqUMukxME5w" hash="xTQfmg">Notwithstanding this explanation, the General Authority asked the district president if he would be kind enough to contact his superiors with this request and then notify him of the results.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p24" pid="4uC07xw6yECq3Ooldi0_1w" hash="dyNFdA">Late that night I received a call from the district president. His employer had been understandably dismayed by his request to remain in the city and reconsider the promotion. The company president asked him to seriously think again about his request and then to call him back in five minutes. In that short interval of time, he would be forced to make a decision that would affect the rest of his life. At that moment he called to ask my advice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p25" pid="CWNravFS5keKY7u77G3zNQ" hash="RrbWOQ">My reply to him was that the Lord had sent one of his Apostles to organize a stake of Zion in Japan. If he had to give his answer to the Lord himself, would it be any different? He thanked me, then called his employer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p26" pid="TJGtVr-v_EiMBGLqAocGww" hash="crXjyw">Early the next morning, he came to the mission home and was officially called as the new stake president. When the General Authority inquired about his status with the company, the district president responded that his promotion was canceled and that he would have to accept whatever they decided to give him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p27" pid="4sTmoAuRCEiJ9Fkoz3g4VA" hash="ExQsLg">Before he left, the General Authority blessed this man and stated that although he would go through a period of trials and tribulations at work, the time would come when he would be called upon by his employer to help make great and important decisions for his company, because he had made a decision to serve the Lord rather than to accept personal gain.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p28" pid="6HtzxVM9jUCLvYvnFHDaEg" hash="R36RPQ">A few years later, this man—still a stake president—became the assistant to the president of his company, fulfilling the promise made by an Apostle of the Lord. How great is our reward as we faithfully endure our afflictions and sufferings of this life!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p29" pid="47-rrAxlA0C_NgkyOOXU3w" hash="JhG10A">We are promised, as the Prophet Joseph was promised, “Thine adversity and thine afflictions shall be but a small moment;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p30" pid="KZj4aLMv-0aeQ0rp_EThLw" hash="n21SVQ">“And then, if thou endure it well, God shall exalt thee on high; thou shalt triumph over all thy foes” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.7-8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:7–8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p31" pid="Yc6pLbO3pUeBS8c4aiohhw" hash="y7lSRg">Orson F. Whitney said: “No pain that we suffer, no trial that we experience is wasted. It ministers to our education, to the development of such qualities as patience, faith, fortitude and humility. All that we suffer and all that we endure, especially when we endure it patiently, builds up our characters, purifies our hearts, expands our souls, and makes us more tender and charitable, more worthy to be called the children of God … and it is through sorrow and suffering, toil and tribulation, that we gain the education that we come here to acquire and which will make us more like our Father and Mother in heaven” (cited in Spencer W. Kimball, <span class="emphasis">Faith Precedes the Miracle,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1972, p. 98).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p32" pid="ATupD4Ui8kSzkww7TiGHyQ" hash="vQF_SA">President Kimball said: “Suffering can make saints of people as they learn patience, long-suffering, and self-mastery. The sufferings of our Savior were part of his education.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p33" pid="v6gsF3lpFk6p-OPDvmWdXw" hash="3iZetA">“‘Though he were a Son, yet learned he obedience by the things which he suffered;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p34" pid="i8HcwQsGKka00t671O8EYA" hash="L5ufBg">“‘And being made perfect, he became the author of eternal salvation unto all them that obey him.’ (<a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/5.8-9" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 5:8–9</a>.)” (<span class="emphasis">Faith Precedes the Miracle,</span> p. 98).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings.p35" pid="a-jkuu7YmUCVz4wa8pd4zw" hash="iLa7Hw">May we endure our trials and sufferings well. May we look to the Lord with faith in his righteous judgment is my prayer, and I ask it humbly in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-305e.jpg" alt="The First Presidency on 6 April 1933" pid="qm9sX3WuQUSUXbVObLxRiA" hash="iMWNHw" />
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1979/10/after-much-tribulation-come-the-blessings</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1979-general-conference/1979-10-5020-elder-adney-y-komatsu-64k-eng.mp3" length="4866745" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 1979 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Light of the Gospel</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Some years ago an assignment took me to one of the islands of the South Seas to dedicate a newly completed chapel. That evening, as I approached the building with some of the local leaders, we were surprised to notice that the building was completely</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03141_000_011" doc-version="2" hash="LT2Erg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="KJciftU6I0avjIbr9urvEg" hash="wWuk3g">The Light of the Gospel</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="H8OC8MO3B0GWgGQpnrCHrw" hash="LuJyCw">Adney Y. Komatsu</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2bcc.jpg" alt="Elder Adney Y. Komatsu" pid="r3Eigdj6hU-BRYBA5acXgQ" hash="0lr9pw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p1" pid="uED-g-9cM0CMaUUZZlFhBA" hash="k9TRdA">Some years ago an assignment took me to one of the islands of the South Seas to dedicate a newly completed chapel. That evening, as I approached the building with some of the local leaders, we were surprised to notice that the building was completely dark.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p2" pid="c2gg7y_fHkCiBad9hOs98g" hash="3zkSkA">As we entered the building and saw all the members sitting in the chapel, we inquired about the absence of lighting. The bishop informed us that earlier in the afternoon the building supervisor had inspected the building to make sure all was in readiness for the dedication. But now, as the time approached to begin the services, for some reason there were no lights, even though lights were aglow in nearby homes. All possibilities for correcting the problem were checked without success, and so the local leaders and I decided to proceed with the dedicatory services.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p3" pid="ASqZiYVp0kuLgWoxecqafQ" hash="wZsjzg">As the program proceeded, illuminated only by a kerosene lantern in front of the chapel, I felt sure that this would be the first dedication performed in darkness in the history of the Church!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p4" pid="owD6ptM1cE-gp51JjVsITg" hash="YP48kQ">I’m sure all those good brothers and sisters in the congregation joined me with a silent prayer in their hearts to ask the Lord to bless us with light so that the chapel could be dedicated.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p5" pid="rUwD2FJEOk-KLmeyR9je6A" hash="Zy4mow">One by one the speakers spoke—in the dark. The choir sang beautiful anthems—in the dark. As the concluding speaker, I, too, gave my talk in the dark. Then, as I asked the congregation to unite with me for the dedicatory prayer, the lights in the chapel suddenly flickered on. How grateful we were to the Lord for this special blessing! I was overcome with emotion and felt meek and humble that we had been so blessed, but the illumination of the chapel could not compare with the light of love in our hearts for this great blessing in answer to our prayers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p6" pid="5He73ktd0EG3N4mNAXr9Qw" hash="s-3VSA">It brought to mind the words of the prophet Moroni:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p7" pid="gTf3BuUOTEW9xgk9fNr6Cw" hash="Qh5BRw">“And now, I, Moroni, would speak somewhat concerning these things; I would show unto the world that faith is things which are hoped for and not seen; wherefore, dispute not because ye see not, for ye receive no witness until after the trial of your faith. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p8" pid="P8os470sFkCfbBartVvv-Q" hash="YpEJVQ">“For if there be no faith among the children of men God can do no miracle among them; wherefore, he showed not himself until after their faith.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.6,12" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:6, 12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p9" pid="mgtMoyQHC0-5a7ut7C3i0Q" hash="-7qwnQ">Yes, the Lord blessed us, even as our faith was tested and as we prayed with hope.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p10" pid="VZAC5f76KUCSHPqGgMpH9w" hash="UuwKhg">There are others among us who search for light in their lives. One such young man had broken many of the laws of the land and had been punished by a prison sentence. He even escaped from prison, only to be caught and reincarcerated a short time later. His was truly a life of darkness and misery, but through the constant efforts of a caring bishop, this young man decided to change his ways and return to Christ. With a meek and lowly heart he began to repent, and the Spirit of the Holy Ghost touched his heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p11" pid="z1YolWYbD020C35hFMNKOQ" hash="VDoRzw">As he prepared to leave prison after serving his term, there to greet him at the gate were his bishop, who had worked with him all those years, and he brought with him his father, mother, brothers, and sisters, who received him with open arms and great rejoicing. What a deep appreciation this young man had for his bishop and his family, who had stood by him even though he had caused them much embarrassment and many sleepless nights with his wayward activities. But their faith never wavered, and indeed a miracle was wrought. Today, this young man serves as the elders quorum president of his ward.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p12" pid="uxFjSf8_iEGNXoAVgAIoVg" hash="uiNFXA">What great force changed the life of this young man from one of spiritual darkness to one of truth and light? It was the pure love of Christ, which the bishop portrayed as he worked with him. And this pure love of Christ is charity. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.47" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:47</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p13" pid="SCqPIF8qE0aqL_EEjO3X9g" hash="mb195w">The prophet Nephi said: “Wherefore, the Lord God hath given a commandment that all men should have charity, which charity is love. And except they should have charity they were nothing. Wherefore, if they should have charity they would not suffer the laborer in Zion to perish.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/26.30" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 26:30</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p14" pid="-1todtkFoUS_AsWkEbPRyQ" hash="rh-MGA">We must also remember the faith and courage of this young man’s family as they endured many trials and heartaches and then greeted him with open arms at the end of the ordeal. The prophet Moroni reminds us:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p15" pid="VCIDS999Mk6w266If4MBEw" hash="WmXoBQ">“Behold, it was the faith of Nephi and Lehi that wrought the change upon the Lamanites, that they were baptized with fire and with the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p16" pid="BQaYih9V3Eawz-2Zhnr1Xw" hash="tM8bwQ">“Behold, it was the faith of Ammon and his brethren which wrought so great a miracle among the Lamanites.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p17" pid="0U-Yg1FlX0aM1aGYjMtv7g" hash="5BkH5A">“Yea, and even all they who wrought miracles wrought them by faith, even those who were before Christ and also those who were after. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p18" pid="ojPN4d9UNUODdN-fla6JFw" hash="rEr10g">“And neither at any time hath any wrought miracles until after their faith; wherefore they first believed in the Son of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.14-16,18" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:14–16, 18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p19" pid="fnwrLJ98ukiHuhuLEUJWxg" hash="1HvpAg">The prophet Mormon also preached that “it is by faith that miracles are wrought. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p20" pid="7IqwgfsQy0KyuEoV7dE6vg" hash="5IR79A">“For no man can be saved, according to the words of Christ, save they shall have faith in his name. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p21" pid="X7L6r3_PU0iPxpNjkqiRUA" hash="9-uQGg">“Wherefore, if a man have faith he must needs have hope; for without faith there cannot be any hope.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p22" pid="5bFO4mcHYEOGqFeJoT69WA" hash="yxRwDg">“And again, behold I say unto you that he cannot have faith and hope, save he shall be meek, and lowly of heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p23" pid="NeFe_96-uU61v4Mv3WusPQ" hash="B3Gbww">“… and if a man be meek and lowly in heart, and confesses by the power of the Holy Ghost that Jesus is the Christ, he must needs have charity.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.37-38,42-44" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:37–38, 42–44</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p24" pid="4BjrStJCXkyXhS7LlUEyDA" hash="wf2f6g">We are reminded today of the importance of charity through the Apostle Paul’s epistle to the Corinthians:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p25" pid="L-Qn35CO_EO1OH0MPQ38DQ" hash="VIO79Q">“Though I speak with the tongues of men and of angels, and have not charity, I am become as sounding brass, or a tinkling cymbal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p26" pid="Mr5kAscxfUaeVfkxu99Ceg" hash="9kafxw">“And though I have the gift of prophecy, and understand all mysteries, and all knowledge; and though I have all faith, so that I could remove mountains, and have not charity, I am nothing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p27" pid="bES3MVP3p0GDIzS5PRTuVg" hash="F5VNLg">“And though I bestow all my goods to feed the poor, and though I give my body to be burned, and have not charity, it profiteth me nothing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p28" pid="pA-HxfGtFkyfQuJRoPUXow" hash="W32NZQ">“Charity suffereth long, and is kind; charity envieth not; charity vaunteth not itself, is not puffed up,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p29" pid="Xa5PIOIAnE2cf5KPDkMvzQ" hash="XpwV8A">“Doth not behave itself unseemly, seeketh not her own, is not easily provoked, thinketh no evil;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p30" pid="RsJNaeubikOEHpa7khzjaA" hash="UkB12A">“Rejoiceth not in iniquity, but rejoiceth in the truth;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p31" pid="ZGMADIOD20iNERU1xRZYFQ" hash="CQVhaw">“Beareth all things, believeth all things, hopeth all things, endureth all things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p32" pid="jPY9hvT9h0CAxYy4yUNfCg" hash="HrOYfA">“Charity never faileth.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/13.1-8" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 13:1–8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p33" pid="5b67_w8PkUCH073lRm74VA" hash="l1fMpA">In the Church we have many opportunities to perform charitable acts. Some of the greatest acts of charity begin with an outstretched hand of friendship. One great example was related by an elderly brother in a ward conference meeting.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p34" pid="hS-LS4TFs0yInL37TAMrMg" hash="OGP-FQ">This good brother was the Sunday School president and was called upon to bear his testimony. During twelve years of his life of inactivity he had been tossed to and fro with life’s problems and had become filled with deep despair. When life seemed its blackest, hands of fellowship and friendship were extended, first by home teachers, then by the bishop, then by members of the ward. As he returned to activity in the Church and felt the warm spirit of the members extended to him without judgment or reservation, he knew that the gospel of Jesus Christ was true and that there is always room for a repentant soul. The Lord forgives; his true followers also forgive. The hand of friendship is outstretched; the sinner repents; the circle of charity is complete.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p35" pid="RkuALhsReEqbiUYZBucGoA" hash="TKGmfA">The prophet Mormon also taught:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p36" pid="JFZWuXvE5069OnsDZgZ0ng" hash="N5T3iA">“Wherefore, my beloved brethren, if ye have not charity, ye are nothing, for charity never faileth. Wherefore, cleave unto charity, which is the greatest of all, for all things must fail—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p37" pid="-45MUxaYVUCw1NNtd1ufSQ" hash="on5J7A">“But charity is the pure love of Christ, and it endureth forever; and whoso is found possessed of it at the last day, it shall be well with him.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.46-47" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:46–47</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p38" pid="Ezijc7qpF066I2wyk3ZBdg" hash="QDwvUw">As we faithfully render our stewardships in the Church, as we remember that our actions speak the feelings of our hearts, and as we extend our love to our Savior who waits to receive us into his kingdom, may we do so with hope and with love and with charity. His invitation to the generations of mankind rings forth in this hymn, “Come unto Jesus”:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="ijVjIL7F8kmZHbXx2hohtw" hash="hJtd2w">
            <span class="emphasis">Come unto Jesus; Ye heavy laden,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="XfRn0gxYoES1CTREPINIyw" hash="5Nrpzg">
            <span class="emphasis">Careworn and fainting, by sin oppressed;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="JBogtdgDAUWO5xbYGyrrsQ" hash="6GQ94w">
            <span class="emphasis">He’ll safely guide you unto that haven</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="4EmDV1_nmkGa_Lp5fIjdkw" hash="ChPA5A">
            <span class="emphasis">Where all who trust him may rest.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="sgKDhWxxFkeP0Mt-em2pqg" hash="uVSFaA">
            <span class="emphasis">Come unto Jesus; He’ll ever heed you,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="MfBBprMq_EOewU72JRrunA" hash="FLzPUw">
            <span class="emphasis">Though in the darkness you’ve gone astray;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="cJGFGsmTCkGyjIjSLwC2bA" hash="G6uvqg">
            <span class="emphasis">His love will find you, and gently lead you</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="YhwTavAIjUKEzrHoGX_KKA" hash="ZG-yUw">
            <span class="emphasis">From darkest night into day.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="Y196RDgiYUqJkSEgl9kQ1g" hash="3RRaLw">
            <span class="emphasis">Come unto Jesus; He’ll surely hear you</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="3tYPR2QRY0qvV5xctHVEYQ" hash="_Ecxqw">
            <span class="emphasis">If you in meekness plead for his love;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="oYRKSjmNu02iAuWOpVtC4A" hash="StXXgA">
            <span class="emphasis">Oh, know you not that angels are near you</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="e7zre7NH-EO7vs7YDGuLvA" hash="xcTTow">
            <span class="emphasis">From the bright mansions above.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="q9cTvQjNyE6icLduKJDFZA" hash="MKk3qw">
            <span class="emphasis">Come unto Jesus from ev’ry nation,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="kHNxnaRmQEKBL6g7mwiSLw" hash="itI5pA">
            <span class="emphasis">From ev’ry land and isle of the sea;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="fJRolGleGU-A__L2Srqo4w" hash="KZIMPg">
            <span class="emphasis">Unto the high and lowly in station,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="HA9eBQpQ5ka-WIKFxO2MyQ" hash="6GdT9g">
            <span class="emphasis">Ever he calls, “Come to me.”</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel.p39" pid="ypSdbeyqfk69eUwLkxHMQw" hash="zZx_sA">My dear brothers and sisters, I bear humble testimony that I know that Jesus is the Christ, the Savior of the world, and if we heed his beckoning to come unto him, surely we will be blessed with all the blessings he has in store for the faithful and the righteous. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1981/10/the-light-of-the-gospel</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1981-general-conference/1981-10-2030-elder-adney-y-komatsu-64k-eng.mp3" length="5132306" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 1981 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The House of the Lord</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In recent months we have seen the completion and dedication of several temples in the Church—one in Atlanta, Georgia; one in Apia, Samoa; one in Nuku’alofa, Tonga; and another in Santiago, Chile. Others are now in the planning and construction stages</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03167_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="P_c-Qg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="o-XPgch5QkqHC4GyQq6SPg" hash="JRUv6w">The House of the Lord</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="1GuD22pmB0O1BdIUpb53Pg" hash="LuJyCw">Adney Y. Komatsu</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2bcc.jpg" alt="Elder Adney Y. Komatsu" pid="gl6tuGAW5E2KfVakOGlKeQ" hash="0lr9pw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p1" pid="g3JUKTWmWUOtSMkd88QQHg" hash="RufbXQ">In recent months we have seen the completion and dedication of several temples in the Church—one in Atlanta, Georgia; one in Apia, Samoa; one in Nuku’alofa, Tonga; and another in Santiago, Chile. Others are now in the planning and construction stages, and of course many are in operation in various parts of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p2" pid="c6aDUYOGnkWiQFfD6nph6Q" hash="WvlJqA">I am grateful for the special calling that I have at the present time to serve as the president of the Tokyo Temple. It is a joy and a privilege to visit with the Saints who come to that holy edifice to partake of the blessings there.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p3" pid="0Z3SC1YbcEyfnc1B_84BEQ" hash="ZyJZyQ">Why does the Church build and maintain temples?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p4" pid="PutVzdC4VEa_pc7QCqD1yQ" hash="XAwonw">This question was asked by the contractor for the Tokyo Temple when he was engaged to begin that construction about five years ago. He noted that the Buddhist and Shinto religions in Japan build many shrines and temples, but this was the first time he had heard of a Christian church building a temple. Christian religions are noted for building beautiful chapels and cathedrals, but he had never heard of a Christian temple before. Of the many churches that profess Christianity, The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is the only one that builds temples.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p5" pid="PTpQ3UIm_kiezEVYIE0zaw" hash="8U7lEw">The contractor was told that the temple would be a sacred building, a holy house, where the glorious work of salvation for the living and the dead would be carried out, where baptisms for the dead and other ordinances would be performed to bring about the joining of wife to husband, children to parents, for the living as well as the dead, and where families would be sealed together for time and for all eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p6" pid="vFLbOOnPGkeR0Lu6Yfyy9A" hash="EQIoig">The direction to the Prophet Joseph Smith was clear when he received this revelation on August 2, 1833, only three years after the Church was organized, instructing that a temple should be built:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p7" pid="6jHJz-zYAk2aoPcwLBknVQ" hash="JkKBtw">“Verily I say unto you, that it is my will that a house should be built unto me in the land of Zion, like unto the pattern which I have given you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p8" pid="t3iDPFZrbkq0XpNlgGuV_A" hash="nbNs6w">“Yea, let it be built speedily, by the tithing of my people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p9" pid="8s1ouA_LYESJSe7n6z3uhA" hash="-E46_w">“Behold, this is the tithing and the sacrifice which I, the Lord, require at their hands, that there may be a house built unto me for the salvation of Zion—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p10" pid="PJkuZlit40yTsWRM3Y4HsA" hash="QAgtqA">“For a place of thanksgiving for all saints, and for a place of instruction for all those who are called to the work of the ministry in all their several callings and offices;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p11" pid="UhD8GOrMy0-X9q9v4meJow" hash="LQ9O6w">“That they may be perfected in the understanding of their ministry, in theory, in principle, and in doctrine, in all things pertaining to the kingdom of God on the earth, the keys of which kingdom have been conferred upon you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p12" pid="bp4ei0-XTU-8MeQOaIrAqw" hash="9eDqEw">“And inasmuch as my people build a house unto me in the name of the Lord, and do not suffer any unclean thing to come into it, that it be not defiled, my glory shall rest upon it;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p13" pid="kuFXgBNFmkWW8MMqRIhWhA" hash="trSc0g">“Yea, and my presence shall be there, for I will come into it, and all the pure in heart that shall come into it shall see God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p14" pid="oq6GOz84Tk2Cb7YH7udTuw" hash="6-Gbcw">“But if it be defiled I will not come into it, and my glory shall not be there; for I will not come into unholy temples.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/97.10-17" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 97:10–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p15" pid="NJ1Sq-yZ5Eeb9bxQlwAqVg" hash="Wd3gfw">There were very few members of the Church at this time, but they all greatly sacrificed, and the Kirtland Temple was completed and dedicated. The Lord appeared in glory and accepted the temple. Moses, Elias, and Elijah also appeared, each to commit his keys and dispensations. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/110.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 110</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p16" pid="tkTMxFfY4UKcxODLdl4n1g" hash="nnHE2A">However, before the temple work could really begin in the Kirtland Temple, the Saints had to flee the attacks of mobs. The temple fell into the hands of wicked men, and, as was stated in the revelation, when it became defiled, it was disowned by the Lord. Efforts were made by the Saints to build a temple in Missouri, but again they were forced to flee for their lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p17" pid="7p3z2X3h1kK-6A561fepZQ" hash="qiqWdQ">Again, after nearly five years, the Prophet Joseph Smith received the following revelation:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p18" pid="avD4aGPdZUW5gYe02YIJvg" hash="07sJ3Q">“For there is not a place found on earth that he may come to and restore again that which was lost unto you, or which he hath taken away, even the fulness of the priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p19" pid="1y0Kh81DO0Ga6IiZbfvoxw" hash="x71wBg">“For a baptismal font there is not upon the face of the earth, that they, my saints, may be baptized for those who are dead—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p20" pid="iFQn8EZsMk6XOnGH1kJn2w" hash="ccs3BA">“For this ordinance belongeth to my house, and cannot be acceptable to me, only in the days of your poverty, wherein ye are not able to build a house unto me. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p21" pid="-ZSL5smhZkih49y0k6YYUQ" hash="R2T-Sg">“And verily I say unto you, let this house be built unto my name, that I may reveal mine ordinances therein unto my people;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p22" pid="92Xw7mn-UkO3QJGsiihNUA" hash="8PKLNw">“For I deign to reveal unto my church things which have been kept hid from before the foundation of the world, things that pertain to the dispensation of the fulness of times.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/124.28-30,40-41" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 124:28–30, 40–41</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p23" pid="wfBcHWknRUaE1TJ2J5Ga3w" hash="wDXUXw">In this revelation, which is recorded in section 124 of the Doctrine and Covenants, reference is made to “the fulness of the priesthood.” What is the meaning of that and how is it obtained? The Prophet Joseph Smith taught: “If a man gets a fullness of the priesthood of God he has to get it in the same way that Jesus Christ obtained it, and that was by keeping all the commandments and obeying all the ordinances of the house of the Lord.” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith,</span> sel. Joseph Fielding Smith, Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1938, p. 308.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p24" pid="MG0grMogdEib45uo4QYVJg" hash="pNsB-A">President Joseph Fielding Smith further taught: “If you want salvation in the fullest, that is exaltation in the kingdom of God, so that you may become his sons and his daughters, you have got to go to the temple of the Lord and receive these holy ordinances which belong to that house, which cannot be had elsewhere. <span class="emphasis">No man shall receive the fulness of eternity, of exaltation, alone; no woman shall receive that blessing alone; but man and wife, when they receive the sealing power in the temple of the Lord, … shall pass on to exaltation, and shall continue and become like the Lord.</span> And that is the destiny of men; that is what the Lord desires for his children.” (<span class="emphasis">Doctrines of Salvation,</span> comp. Bruce R. McConkie, 3 vols., Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1954–56, 2:44.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p25" pid="-HrIfRumJEGsfv2ND1WdRQ" hash="G5G9IQ">It is clear, then, that unless we go to the temple of the Lord and receive all the ordinances and obey the commandments, we cannot receive a fulness of priesthood blessings and neither can we receive exaltation. These are wonderful blessings that have been made available to us through temple work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p26" pid="WpL8wkgtWEiAXNdU07-Ufg" hash="eRidfw">I have been a member of the Church most of my life. I was baptized when I was seventeen and was ordained to the Melchizedek Priesthood at age twenty-one. While still a young man, I served in many assignments and had many good experiences in the Church that helped me to learn many concepts that were helpful to me in building my faith and testimony. But I never felt that I had completed my <span class="emphasis">full</span> membership in the Church until I took my bride to the temple and received the new and everlasting covenant and the blessings and understanding of the work performed there.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p27" pid="L10w1rEhNESrb5v8CBQAOQ" hash="MQxUPA">I was the first member of my family to be baptized into the Church and thus have the responsibility to perform vicariously the temple work for my ancestors who did not have the opportunity to hear the gospel during their time on this earth. I also have had the responsibility to teach my children the gospel and to instill in their hearts and minds the importance of temple work. My wife and I have four children, the oldest of whom is married and has two children—our grandchildren, who are very special to us. Our children were born under the covenant, and our grandchildren have also been born under the covenant. The greatest gift I might give to my children or grandchildren in this life, or the most valuable legacy I might leave them, would be a testimony of the truthfulness of the gospel and the importance of genealogy and temple work, which binds us all together down through the generations in love and in happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p28" pid="IdigUuU0NUWkmwaFwh055A" hash="5DTc0A">There are many people in the world who travel great distances at great personal sacrifice to go to the temple. I know our Heavenly Father is aware of their righteous desires and blesses them abundantly for their efforts. Recently a group came to the Tokyo Temple from Okinawa—nine hundred miles by plane—among them a young couple who had come to be married. It had required all the money they could possibly save to pay for their transportation, and there was nothing left for a wedding celebration or honeymoon. When those who accompanied the couple realized their plight, they dug deep into their own pockets and contributed what little they had so the couple could have money for a delightful one-day honeymoon in Tokyo. Not only did the young couple enjoy the blessings of the temple, but they also enjoyed and appreciated the generosity and kindness of their brothers and sisters. Surely Paul’s teachings to the Ephesian Saints apply, when he said, “Now therefore ye are no more strangers and foreigners, but fellowcitizens with the saints, and of the household of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/2.19" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 2:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p29" pid="RUu0gkZdpEGMmglKU7YGiA" hash="IEwHjQ">I have a firm and abiding testimony of the importance of this work and the blessings it can bring into our lives. I express gratitude for this testimony and for the small part I now enjoy in teaching genealogy and temple work. May we all be blessed to receive the fulness of the blessings of the House of the Lord, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1983/10/the-house-of-the-lord</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1983-general-conference/1983-10-2050-elder-adney-y-komatsu-64k-eng.mp3" length="4927892" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 1983 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking to the Savior</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, as we approach the Easter season, our minds and thoughts turn to the Lord Jesus Christ, His crucifixion, resurrection, and atoning sacrifice for the sins of the world.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03213_000_029" doc-version="2" hash="PJ3UhA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="UVai612R2E2PaU4IPeNvvw" hash="3F25QQ">Looking to the Savior</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Dpe9mSsi1kaP7vJgfvli5Q" hash="LuJyCw">Adney Y. Komatsu</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2378.jpg" alt="Elder Adney Y. Komatsu" pid="KvQR0TQmwEitFHIUeuEzcw" hash="S3GJDQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p1" pid="Xyl78E4xUkmiA2aIv7sVxA" hash="nJPtAA">My dear brothers and sisters, as we approach the Easter season, our minds and thoughts turn to the Lord Jesus Christ, His crucifixion, resurrection, and atoning sacrifice for the sins of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p2" pid="yoM3VakPQU2BmoFtoDipcQ" hash="Xnw_IA">John the Baptist, who was commissioned to be the forerunner of the Savior in his day, declared that our Father in Heaven had not forgotten His children on this earth. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p3" pid="2iPsXx08FUmRZAMrkLZE0Q" hash="Wi5kOg">“The Father loveth the Son, and hath given all things into his hand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p4" pid="aQAh-FFNdEq-N270OwQ6Dw" hash="Ltncgg">“He that believeth on the Son hath everlasting life: and he that believeth not the Son shall not see life; but the wrath of God abideth on him” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.35-36" class="scriptureRef">John 3:35–36</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p5" pid="O1fTtChVkEOng1NHF7nDEw" hash="rHT-Bw">The coming of the Savior was prophesied by many prophets in the Bible and in the Book of Mormon. The Old Testament prophet Isaiah predicted the coming of the Savior’s birth when he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p6" pid="1mRfHEikjU2sLjsv4XmQng" hash="X1VKwQ">“Therefore the Lord himself shall give you a sign; Behold, a virgin shall conceive, and bear a son, and shall call his name Immanuel” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/7.14" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 7:14</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p7" pid="DM6de1fWX0it0GmbQMM3qQ" hash="iYCOww">“For unto us a child is born, unto us a son is given: and the government shall be upon his shoulder: and his name shall be called Wonderful, Counsellor, The mighty God, The everlasting Father, The Prince of Peace” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/9.6" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 9:6</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p8" pid="033C8zuHxEqTo2zFLqZAUw" hash="dUuRwg">The Book of Mormon, as another testament of Jesus Christ, records that an angel appeared unto King Benjamin and declared the glad tidings of great joy, 124 years before the coming of Christ. The angel said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p9" pid="uCeRCzJFW0uUoPcACDDgZg" hash="FNp0aA">“For behold, the time cometh, and is not far distant, that with power, the Lord Omnipotent who reigneth, who was, and is from all eternity to all eternity, shall come down from heaven among the children of men, and shall dwell in a tabernacle of clay, and shall go forth amongst men, working mighty miracles, such as healing the sick, raising the dead, causing the lame to walk, the blind to receive their sight, and the deaf to hear, and curing all manner of diseases. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p10" pid="dcHKpakuy0Sz57csQ2Woxw" hash="p_K3aA">“And he shall be called Jesus Christ, the Son of God, the Father of heaven and earth, the Creator of all things from the beginning; and his mother shall be called Mary” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/3.5,8" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 3:5, 8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p11" pid="qk6WII445UOPBsyZ3597aA" hash="qFhYIg">Throughout the thousand years of Book of Mormon history, many prophets bore solemn witness of the divinity of Jesus Christ as the Son of God, of His premortal godhood, of His earthly ministry—His suffering, His death, His resurrection—and of the plan of salvation by which we can make His atonement effective in our lives. These prophets spoke from pure knowledge, knowledge that came by personal visitations of the Savior to them, by the testimony of angels who spoke with them, by visions, and by the power of the Holy Ghost. They knew whereof they spoke and could not be shaken from their testimonies.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p12" pid="WCimhun2IU6T8r0ZTR5_Wg" hash="hm68Rg">Let us consider the example of Jacob. Jacob was confronted by Sherem, who denied Christ and contended with Jacob and demanded a sign. Sherem preached with much flattery and much power of speech, questioning Jacob’s testimony. Jacob said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p13" pid="iEsiHedGzkSnc6_KYS7QWQ" hash="dSMAEQ">“And he had hope to shake me from the faith, notwithstanding the many revelations and the many things which I had seen concerning these things; for I truly had seen angels, and they had ministered unto me. And also, I had heard the voice of the Lord speaking unto me in very word, from time to time; wherefore, I could not be shaken” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/7.5" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 7:5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p14" pid="xat8qj7I7Uush0jKqGSYeQ" hash="MTmQpQ">President Ezra Taft Benson, our beloved prophet, has encouraged us to study the Book of Mormon, for, as he said, “the book that will get a man ‘nearer to God by abiding by its precepts, than by any other book’ needs to be studied constantly.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p15" pid="uoI8zRCzeEa6lzzS-_OUsw" hash="bCJbsw">I hope and pray that we will follow the admonition of our beloved prophet, President Benson, and constantly study the Book of Mormon. We all need the assurance that we are living in obedience to the commandments of God so that we can receive the Spirit and be guided by it in our daily lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p16" pid="BAzLbDK45UG5EVTwojFQAA" hash="IlogLQ">The Savior, as the Son of God, showed you and me the great example of obedience in keeping the commandments of His Father. Nephi tells us that Christ was baptized so men can follow in His footsteps and receive the Holy Ghost:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p17" pid="gfGgJ2xijEuVdrdWmNiQ-w" hash="_H5mtA">“Know ye not that he was holy? But notwithstanding he being holy, he showeth unto the children of men that, according to the flesh he humbleth himself before the Father, and witnesseth unto the Father that he would be obedient unto him in keeping his commandments” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.7" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p18" pid="wiGYLVb7DEucC0DVqGBmLA" hash="vGmJ2w">Several weeks ago I was assigned to a stake conference in Provo. The Sunday morning welfare meeting was scheduled to begin at 7:30 <small>A.M.</small>, so it was necessary that I leave home about 6:15 <small>A.M.</small> Just as I came to an intersection before turning onto the on-ramp to enter the freeway, the light changed to red. As I stopped for the light at that early hour, now about 6:30 <small>A.M.</small>, there were no cars in sight. Mine was the only car parked at the stop light.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p19" pid="hncx1H-HK0KPOjhNSI8XXg" hash="-35t9A">The thought did cross my mind that if I ignored the red light, no one would be hurt or endangered, for not a car was in sight at that early hour. Nevertheless, I waited out the light change and proceeded on the green light. If I had turned left, no one would have known, but I would know that I was breaking the traffic code, and surely the Lord would know. I was reminded of the scripture which says:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p20" pid="_meAlSLYsU-0Tmr3G0nyAQ" hash="NjcJUg">“Therefore to him that knoweth to do good, and doeth it not, to him it is sin” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/4.17" class="scriptureRef">James 4:17</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p21" pid="-06herlI7U-YOMJ-ivzcvg" hash="e1Nn6g">Brothers and sisters, oftentimes we are tempted to compromise with circumstances of the moment, but we must exercise care and live the principles of righteous living at all times so we will know what to do when called upon to make a decision of far greater importance. We must always be examples to the world as members of the Lord’s kingdom and keep the laws of the land and the laws of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p22" pid="GhifKWW8JU65S2H0Hu7e4g" hash="7VB_tw">The Lord said in a latter-day revelation:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p23" pid="IuzOXaN45US5KAZ4jan9tw" hash="RQWKZg">“Wherefore, be not weary in well-doing, for ye are laying the foundation of a great work. And out of small things proceedeth that which is great.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p24" pid="hqqc3C8Y6kiAewzGIyrqNA" hash="ZGRn9g">“Behold, the Lord requireth the heart and a willing mind; and the willing and obedient shall eat the good of the land of Zion in these last days” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.33-34" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:33–34</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p25" pid="s1FGnSO8-EWfhGc_CI6bVw" hash="FBfDTg">Recently, as a member of the Utah South Area Presidency, I was invited to participate in an institute program with men and women at the Utah State penitentiary. As I visited these men and women, my heart went out to them, for they are all our Heavenly Father’s children. Many are there because of the wrong choices they made in life when temptation was put before them. I saw pain and suffering in their eyes, and yet, as I think of their loved ones—parents, brothers, sisters, wives, children—they, too, have suffered much and perhaps are still faced with more suffering in the future. President Kimball said we should hate the sin but love the sinner. He further stated that suffering can make saints of people as they learn patience, long-suffering, and self-mastery.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p26" pid="iuC_uQhlJE-_qt_Um86vTg" hash="gaxSTQ">He also said the sufferings of our Savior were part of his education. “Though he were a Son, yet learned he obedience by the things which he suffered;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p27" pid="1jacRjxXKU-BRaRXXoq4uA" hash="khW5bg">“And being made perfect, he became the author of eternal salvation unto all them that obey him” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/5.8-9" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 5:8–9</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p28" pid="R3BNutX4i0WA4jf6jMQN8g" hash="aAcknQ">Elder James E. Talmage wrote, “No pang that is suffered by man or woman upon the earth will be without its compensating effect … if it be met with patience” (as quoted in Spencer W. Kimball, “Tragedy or Destiny,” in <span class="emphasis">Speeches of the Year, 1955–56,</span> Provo: Brigham Young University, pp. 5–6).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p29" pid="3Dqf5aOGYkOGbCUL1FcvrQ" hash="2xguSQ">On the other hand, wrong choices can crush us with their mighty impact, if we yield to weaknesses, complaints, and criticisms.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p30" pid="CTf7O4XZtEOlkp4WmOxc0A" hash="CN_71g">In closing, may I quote Orson F. Whitney, who said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p31" pid="lxZAOy2iWE64AGJTt7N9tw" hash="nce8TA">“No pain that we suffer, no trial that we experience is wasted. It ministers to our education, to the development of such qualities as patience, faith, fortitude and humility. All that we suffer and all that we endure, especially when we endure it patiently, builds up our characters, purifies our hearts, expands our souls, and makes us more tender and charitable, more worthy to be called the children of God … and it is through sorrow and suffering, toil and tribulation, that we gain the education that we come here to acquire and which will make us more like our Father and Mother in heaven” (as quoted in “Tragedy or Destiny,” p. 6).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p32" pid="_OPTtTWJr0yCkrxQxVWMFQ" hash="yShj7A">The Lord, who suffered much for the sins of all mankind and was crucified and resurrected, said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p33" pid="c2h8pJdzg0-giC25wik0eg" hash="KjCKmg">“If ye keep my commandments, ye shall abide in my love; even as I have kept my Father’s commandments, and abide in his love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p34" pid="bpDK4IB3tkqmxGj-wSw6Eg" hash="eXYw_w">“These things have I spoken unto you, that my joy might remain in you, and that your joy might be full.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior.p35" pid="_ETqtHISYkCrgdce2qltnQ" hash="i1oemA">“This is my commandment, That ye love one another, as I have loved you” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/15.10-12" class="scriptureRef">John 15:10–12</a>). In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1987/04/looking-to-the-savior</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1987-general-conference/1987-04-5040-elder-adney-y-komatsu-64k-eng.mp3" length="4750496" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 1987 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Please Hear the Call!</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My brothers and sisters, I would like to recall to your minds the statement of invitation made by the First Presidency in December of 1985, and I quote:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_92905_000_016" doc-version="2" hash="gqI0AA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="-S8xx7VohEWBgLPHRan7ow" hash="MvLW2g">Please Hear the Call!</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="qfoK8-3T4EuRXAwb-WJsLw" hash="LuJyCw">Adney Y. Komatsu</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2378.jpg" alt="Elder Adney Y. Komatsu" pid="Jk1ziMnPnUuhjGVCJ-IWwQ" hash="S3GJDQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p1" pid="XlwWRMbouEOYWrMObSO6nQ" hash="zjtrZQ">My brothers and sisters, I would like to recall to your minds the statement of invitation made by the First Presidency in December of 1985, and I quote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p2" pid="IkhZxr6j8E-oMYxN8pdggQ" hash="gpYTLQ">“At this Christmas season we rejoice in the blessings that come of membership and <span class="emphasis">activity </span>in this Church whose head is the Son of God, the Lord Jesus Christ. In deep sincerity we express our love and gratitude for our brethren and sisters everywhere.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p3" pid="pNnCZXjx10CwxTTZDSVgZg" hash="_Rl3Qg">“We are aware of some who are inactive, of others who have become critical and are prone to find fault, and of those who have been disfellowshipped or excommunicated because of serious transgressions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p4" pid="ZJbgvAru0026J4w1XfoaBA" hash="nwynrQ">“To all such we reach out in love. We are anxious to forgive in the spirit of Him who said: ‘I, the Lord, will forgive whom I will forgive, but of you it is required to forgive all men.’ (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p5" pid="MrsC962TpUmAE4aAgMj6yA" hash="AHIQAw">“We encourage Church members to forgive those who may have wronged them. To those who have ceased <span class="emphasis">activity</span> and to those who have become critical, we say, ‘Come back. Come back and feast at the table of the Lord, and taste again the sweet and satisfying fruits of fellowship with the saints.’” (“An Invitation to Come Back,” <span class="emphasis">Church News, </span>22 Dec. 1985, p. 3; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p6" pid="3gObRREwskiFzZ77LiePqw" hash="cywidA">While most of us in the Church may think of activities as primarily fun and games, there is a part that <span class="emphasis">activities </span>play in the Church that reaches far beyond this shallow perception.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p7" pid="zxpMZ9u3Yk-8-K3kiqj-nA" hash="w9deEA">For those who have experienced Church discipline, feelings of isolation and loneliness are very real. This is the case whether the discipline is informal or formal. In the case of formal excommunication, the isolation and loneliness are more than a feeling. This action results in a person’s name being removed from the Church membership records and the withdrawal of the gift of the Holy Ghost given at the time of baptism and confirmation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p8" pid="wQA6sSD6gEe_ishokxMmwA" hash="N_qQMw">Most of us have experienced times of isolation and loneliness in our lives. Have you ever been in a city, airport, train station, or the like and, while surrounded by hundreds or even thousands of people, yet felt alone? Have you on occasion, when uniquely challenged in your family as a child, a teen, or even an adult, felt alone while living with your family under the same roof? Have you on other occasions felt alone and lonely even while sitting among others in a Church meeting or a school class?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p9" pid="ZMtm973Nv0yMwtrxi7JczA" hash="KN7nZg">The fact that people are physically nearby, regardless of the setting, does not always equate to feelings of acceptance, understanding, inclusion, and fellowship. In too many cases, the reverse may be true. Feelings of acceptance and inclusion come when someone invites us into their circle of friendship and activity. Far beyond fun and games, activities represent at least one nonthreatening way to accept, include, understand, and fellowship others. Perceived in this manner, activities become another vehicle to show charity, love, kindness, forgiveness, service, and to include and not exclude. Amulek said, “If ye do not remember to be charitable, ye are as dross, which the refiners do cast out, (it being of no worth).” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/34.29" class="scriptureRef">Alma 34:29</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p10" pid="eLUL9Qly8kK30jOCl-dRbg" hash="SOjirg">Those whose formal Church participation may be limited for a season can experience the warmth of loving arms and open hearts as they are invited to participate in activities in the Church. Their season of limitation is softened as they are warmly included in family home evenings, dinners, socials, firesides, roadshows, dramas, interest groups, homemaking activities, family outings, ward camps, reunions, and the like.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p11" pid="x0MkIBRCOUawleyZ_-6Q5g" hash="xJhIPw">Through activities, individuals can sense a feeling of being included, wanted, and needed. Participating in Church activities provides opportunities to associate with members of the quorum, Relief Society, or ward on neutral grounds. Again, their season of limitation can be softened as they are fellowshipped and included socially in activities. Their participation in activities is often the forerunner to their participation in meetings of worship on the Sabbath, even though for a time they must participate in worship and teaching settings as spectators.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p12" pid="5Lk6B-7_7Em3wYAhBmrKrw" hash="T9XknA">Some critical issues are:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p13" pid="1aVu4OxfKkCHKST8-0KZvQ" hash="UJZmgg">Are activities an integral part of your family, your quorum, Relief Society, or Church unit?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p14" pid="VXMDr-db9kC22qnb7-TQ3g" hash="XWH73w">Are activities planned and conducted on a regular basis that include those working their way back into full fellowship and those who are less active in the fold?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p15" pid="HOzmfiej7E2a88P_97LCyA" hash="P0QPQg">Do your activities represent safe harbors of acceptance, brotherhood, and sisterhood?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p16" pid="_fkr-m93NUqCU6YbX1rHFg" hash="lpd3lA">Are you helping those who are struggling to recapture their faith and testimony look forward to the day when their privilege and blessings to participate fully in Church might be reinstated?</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.f2">
	<p pid="J-c9qs2sYE-MjLIwmG48IQ" hash="f6so_Q">Through a variety of family, priesthood, Relief Society, or ward and stake activities, we can create a setting that—</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="0ZYN68yQqECzB7_iNs5WFA" hash="spToRA">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="rQnOnHKT1ke6LTVsOIRJJw" hash="b3FbHQ">Helps all of us participate in wholesome activities that should be free from the sensuality and coarseness of many activities offered and promoted by the world.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="orGRszmKX06i39K0vs1WCw" hash="sQdgDQ">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="WovfXVoJnES16xnEQr52Gw" hash="UCftPg">Places a premium on including rather than excluding individuals and groups, regardless of age, station in life, Church callings, etc.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="6UutJtr4IkaShrvFoL7IVQ" hash="SYE61Q">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="Ve4jlTPePkSIdPMopVuhcA" hash="rxLIiw">Offers opportunities for participation to the active, those who are less active, and those who are winning their way back to full fellowship.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Ocz_4r2UTEynJMyuTiZ0tg" hash="3dyFOA">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="2suKFhy0q0akah4bU5CHvA" hash="cK8tAw">Displays forgiveness and forgetting as individuals feel the warmth and concern of loving arms and open hearts. When we do not forgive and forget, the Lord warns: “My disciples, in days of old, sought occasion against one another and forgave not one another in their hearts; … for this evil they were afflicted and sorely chastened.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p17" pid="a9Qh2LORo0arHNqafqz0HA" hash="u0unUA">“Wherefore, I say unto you, that ye ought to forgive one another; for he that forgiveth not his brother his trespasses standeth condemned before the Lord; for there remaineth in him the greater sin.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.8-9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:8–9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p18" pid="hV9x4gswVkqL95k8Fdoa_w" hash="AWqTDw">When a person returns to full fellowship in the Church as a result of love, kindness, and forgiveness from those who care, the feeling of joy is almost inexpressible. This depth of joy is described in the Book of Mormon when Alma met Ammon in a joyful meeting:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p19" pid="2ScngNeIiUyyZts4rFsTFg" hash="Nafm6w">“Now the joy of Ammon was so great even that he was full; yea, he was swallowed up in the joy of his God, even to the exhausting of his strength; and he fell again to the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p20" pid="cabA4Gn2oEKO43Rv8XS6-Q" hash="GSa2MA">“Now was not this exceeding joy? Behold, this is joy which none receiveth save it be the truly penitent and humble seeker of happiness.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/27.17-18" class="scriptureRef">Alma 27:17–18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p21" pid="D23sT_9wAUab1ZH8812oRA" hash="KhIjyA">Activities can be so much more than fun and games, and so much more than momentary pleasure. Activities planned with purpose and carried out with real efforts aimed at helping participants on their path to perfection bring joy everlasting and occupy an important place in the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p22" pid="OcGg9W8DYUC7y2h6JD-hxg" hash="B_Xb6A">We need to be reminded that activities sponsored by the Church are not new. In each administration of the thirteen modern-day prophets who have presided over the Church, activities have been an important part of the Latter-day Saint way of life. Church activities continue to be one means to include rather than exclude, to be a participant rather than a spectator, to find moments of joy among challenges of adversity, to promote socialization and unity rather than isolation and disharmony, to offer neutral and nonjudgmental circumstances for those who are winning their way back to full fellowship in the Church with the Saints and household of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p23" pid="1NuG8U8s1EKZpmZru89B_w" hash="ZQX73Q">In closing, I would like to continue quoting from the First Presidency’s Christmas message: “We are confident that many have longed to return, but have felt awkward about doing so. We assure you that you will find open arms to receive you and willing hands to assist you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p24" pid="twDWjSt3YUSDIwCG6nl7Ew" hash="83kqUg">“This is the Christmas season when we honor the birth of the Lord who gave His life for the sins of all. We know there are many who carry heavy burdens of guilt and bitterness. To such we say, ‘Set them aside and give heed to the words of the Savior: “Come unto me, all ye that labour and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest. … For my yoke is easy, and my burden is light.”’” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/11.28-30" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 11:28–30</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p25" pid="yWZLx95aWEmY0c3rGOulOw" hash="PaCWXw">The First Presidency continues by saying:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p26" pid="ng6oeu3AW0yky78rOvqtgw" hash="y9yGRQ">“We plead with you. We pray for you. We invite and welcome you with love and appreciation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p27" pid="AnWueq8ZJkGzlUx_NDs0Nw" hash="Lktg2g">“Sincerely your brethren, The First Presidency.” (“An Invitation to Come Back,” p. 3.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call.p28" pid="1-_efA8zhU6naovCWIT_jQ" hash="q4WYzw">May I invite all to come unto Christ. Come back, and partake of His joy. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1992/04/please-hear-the-call</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1992-general-conference/1992-04-2070-elder-adney-y-komatsu-64k-eng.mp3" length="4838748" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 1992 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gratitude</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1993/10/gratitude?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers, sisters, and friends, as I approach this final assignment as a General Authority and as this phase of my service draws to a close, I am filled with gratitude and appreciation for the many blessings my family and I have received duri</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/gratitude" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_93911_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="IkHGEQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/gratitude.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="S5qcruXEQkCIItQFP36LwQ" hash="gk1uRw">Gratitude</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="OFmB3GSa9Ee0drrs9R7GBg" hash="LuJyCw">Adney Y. Komatsu</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/gratitude.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2378.jpg" alt="Elder Adney Y. Komatsu" pid="mDW-wVJ6LUCs9yrui5bgFQ" hash="S3GJDQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/gratitude.p1" pid="KYMzjT4yZE2tMcIyIBAVCA" hash="ck3cyw">My dear brothers, sisters, and friends, as I approach this final assignment as a General Authority and as this phase of my service draws to a close, I am filled with gratitude and appreciation for the many blessings my family and I have received during this time. I would like to express my sincere love and appreciation to my wife and companion for sustaining me through these many years. With her support and sustaining influence, all the assignments have been a great pleasure and joy. No matter what the call or assignment, she was always there to support and assist, to be concerned about and interested in the new responsibilities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/gratitude.p2" pid="AmOLI0C4tkiYWt10k9kSbA" hash="tE2F6w">I would also like to thank our children for their love and support during the many years while our assignments have required that we live away from them. Without their support, it would have been very difficult to find peace and joy in the work. It has been a great experience to participate in the various callings, and every assignment has been accomplished with their full support.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/gratitude.p3" pid="RVy6wZrGXEmAVRlnWZcDlw" hash="dzvs9A">I also would like to thank the many General Authorities and friends who have helped us over the years in so many ways. We are grateful for their kindnesses and their concerns for us and our welfare.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/gratitude.p4" pid="8zEOCGwpKUel0oS9NQAuCA" hash="f-tqNg">As I review our experiences and try to express my feelings this day, you can imagine that many thoughts are crossing my mind. As I attempt to sort through them, I would like to continue the theme of appreciation for my family and friends by sharing with you an admonition that was given by the Lord to the Prophet Joseph Smith and Oliver Cowdery in Harmony, Pennsylvania, in April 1829. It applies as much—and perhaps even more—to us today than it did to those people in 1829. It is recorded in the Doctrine and Covenants, section 6, verse 12, and states, “Trifle not with sacred things.” [<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:12</a>] There are many sacred things within the gospel, but one of the most sacred is the covenants we make in the holy temple. The words <span class="emphasis">trifle</span> and <span class="emphasis">sacred</span> are an important part of the admonition that cautions us not to take for granted or make light of the sacred, holy, and honorable blessings received.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/gratitude.p5" pid="ZSudIZmd4kGqLm9fKuee4w" hash="DAP8SQ">The relationships between husbands and wives are sacred, and we should never trifle with that great blessing. Many couples enter into marriage without understanding the importance of the admonition not to trifle with sacred things, and divorce often follows.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/gratitude.p6" pid="qTngk5fsN0ya3FMJlVa3HA" hash="Gv4ZNg">Likewise, we should follow this admonition in relationships between parents and children. We must never take our children for granted and always keep our relationships sacred, honorable, and holy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/gratitude.p7" pid="yX58kLPQ1kafTDnNin8Tug" hash="-BYeYA">In 1986 while speaking to the men of the Church in a priesthood session of conference, President Ezra Taft Benson, our prophet, gave them the following directives. Even though he was speaking specifically to the young priesthood brethren, the same directives apply to young women as well. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/gratitude.p8" pid="u027VLz5eUWzKE7511uJkQ" hash="sy7Nww">“My young brethren [and sisters], I counsel each of you to draw close to your own mother. Respect her. Honor her. Receive your mother’s counsel as she loves and instructs you in righteousness. And honor and obey your father as he stands as the head of the home, emulating his manly qualities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/gratitude.p9" pid="6IaQrs931EOpN9XRLbqyqg" hash="43G-Ag">“Young men [and young women], the family unit is forever, and you should do everything in your power to strengthen that unit. In your own family, encourage family home evenings and be an active participant. Encourage family prayer and be on your knees with your family in that sacred circle. Do your part to develop real family unity and solidarity. In such homes, there is no generation gap” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1986, p. 43).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/gratitude.p10" pid="D6135TaNnE-jK-DcvmzyEw" hash="vHWzzw">I am grateful for many opportunities I’ve had to bear my testimony of the truth of the gospel to many people in many parts of the world during my years of service in the Church. We have made many friends and acquaintances in different parts of the world, and their friendship is very sacred and dear to us. Friendship is something you cannot buy for money. You work for it, honor it, and it becomes important and sacred in our lives. Once more I bear you my witness that I know the gospel of Jesus Christ has been restored in its fulness. Our loving Heavenly Father sent his Only Begotten Son into the world to bring about an understanding of sacrifice and blessings. Through the Resurrection, the sting of death was conquered, and Jesus Christ became the first fruits of the Resurrection to show us there is life hereafter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/gratitude.p11" pid="WfaKQIQUt0az4tPu9bbpaA" hash="03M2FQ">Let us all be diligent and obedient in keeping the commandments of the Lord, that we may be worthy to receive the blessings he has in store for the faithful, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1993/10/gratitude</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1993-general-conference/1993-10-2050-elder-adney-y-komatsu-64k-eng.mp3" length="2709179" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 1993 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
