<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Aileen H. Clyde</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Aileen H. Clyde.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Aileen%20H.%20Clyde.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Aileen H. Clyde.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 1991 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>“Charity Suffereth Long”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long?lang=eng</link>
      <description>One of the great blessings of my childhood was that my mother spent significant time reading to me and my younger brother Howard. She had a great sense of the importance of good books, and she used them to teach and entertain us. This all served to e</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_91911_000_031" doc-version="2" hash="A515HQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="6NFpYlKAEES8c4nCOuSyxA" hash="r2KDJQ">“Charity Suffereth Long”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="zmwMUbEfCEqdXsu46_Xptw" hash="LaJxyg">Aileen H. Clyde</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-20fa.jpg" alt="Aileen H. Clyde" pid="7cZS3lrbOE2Ll5e1GZG6Rg" hash="2RaIXw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p1" pid="TqB_QwEJv0i5CyblnNkblA" hash="PMmwhg">One of the great blessings of my childhood was that my mother spent significant time reading to me and my younger brother Howard. She had a great sense of the importance of good books, and she used them to teach and entertain us. This all served to expand our limited young lives to matters far beyond our daily experience. The reading had begun when I was a runabout preschooler and Howard, who had been born with severe physical disabilities and could not run about, needed special attention. The blessing for me was that I got special attention, too.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p2" pid="T0CByRxKXUyli09jOg8Bew" hash="bdSaIg">The books were wide-ranging and grew in sophistication as we grew. I remember nursery rhymes, poetry, folktales from Russia, the adventure in <span class="emphasis">Thunder Cave</span>—and the scriptures. Together, we read parables, incidents such as the woman at the well, even the great abstractions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p3" pid="jcAqN73i9EOI9E-WOEh_yw" hash="ix6obQ">One day Mother read: “Charity suffereth long, and is kind; charity envieth not; charity vaunteth not itself, is not puffed up. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p4" pid="HUxm_9sYv0mgByrsXX02MQ" hash="CQVhaw">“Beareth all things, believeth all things, hopeth all things, endureth all things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p5" pid="bvcnzZ43xUuAAgFrWGQccw" hash="GwK5GA">“Charity never faileth.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/13.4,7-8" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 13:4, 7–8</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.45-46" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:45–46</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p6" pid="vLRTnh4tQU6euC9kLIGdFQ" hash="qyaCLg">Howard interrupted the reading, as he often did, with a question, “What <span class="emphasis">is</span> charity?” He wanted to know the meaning of what we had just heard; I was still caught up in the way it sounded. I only wanted to go on with the reading, but I could tell Mother was pleased with his inquisitiveness. She taught us then, and later, that good questions can be important if we are truly searching to understand, and that sometimes good answers that are good enough may take a lifetime of looking. Then she put down the New Testament and read from the Book of Mormon:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p7" pid="9FWD2_dNeUiDgs5B_KDsqg" hash="ahd9Cw">“But charity is the pure love of Christ, and it endureth forever; and whoso is found possessed of it at the last day, it shall be well with him [or her].” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.47" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:47</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p8" pid="aGoXF7-uR0uWbuhTBBJrwg" hash="ikuLfg">There it was, in one verse, the concentrated essence of a much larger whole, a definition given for a profound yet available truth. What I heard that day was clearly beyond my childhood comprehension, but the spirit of love was there and was as real as any of the other details of my young life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p9" pid="b3bppGO9n0SgRbBQVDsO5g" hash="ASLHZw">The scriptures give us examples of other questioners whose queries taught them new ways to think about love. In the twenty-second chapter of Matthew, Christ was asked by a Pharisee who wanted to trick him, what was the <span class="emphasis">greatest</span> commandment. Christ answered, “Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p10" pid="4OKwmHw1AESiDCJKN98oSw" hash="ZtTJog">“And the second is like unto it, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.37,39" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:37, 39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p11" pid="p8WI_IfO_kWQMfwFFlntUQ" hash="hFHloA">In Luke’s record, the lawyer who had asked the question wanted to know more. Perhaps he feared he might waste his love, so he asked, “Who is my neighbour?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.29" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:29</a>.) And Christ gave the parable of the good Samaritan as an answer. The Samaritan saw what others with eyes had walked by without seeing. He did what he <span class="emphasis">could</span> do that no one else <span class="emphasis">would</span> do, and he dignified himself and put us all in awe of him because we didn’t expect the Samaritan to be our neighbor. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.30-37" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:30–37</a>.) <span class="emphasis">We</span> wouldn’t tempt Christ by asking him whom we should love or serve, but I think occasionally we wonder if we really know.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p12" pid="pRb-JyGL8kasmywVs2eHMw" hash="Vw8Hhg">It is interesting to me that Jesus chose a Samaritan as an example of love unfeigned for the Pharisees. They were so remarkable for their observance of the letter of the law that this teaching must have caused at least some of them to see in new ways and with new spirit the freedom to love that Christ was offering them. That is the challenge for us, to allow Christ’s teachings, magnified by the Holy Spirit, to guide us to <span class="emphasis">his</span> ways of seeing and being.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p13" pid="T1DvKX3GXUqjYQG_8TiXbw" hash="x0uNfg">Now, understanding charity or being charitable is not easy. And our scriptures have not indicated that it would be. Even “charity suffereth long” requires our thoughtful interpretation. The “suffering” that may come from loving is the result of our great caring. It comes because another matters to us so much.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p14" pid="Y4iezx6X8kul4lLNCtJmZw" hash="exEZnA">To avoid that kind of suffering, we would have to avoid what gives us life and hope and joy—our capacity to love deeply. As an antidote against the suffering that will surely come as we have loved ones die, or see them struggle or be misled, or have them misunderstand us or even betray us, we can find relief in charity to others. We accepted bearing one another’s burdens and mourning with those who mourn, as we accepted Christ in our baptism. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.8-9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:8–9</a>.) His spirit and power will comfort us as we extend ourselves in help and love to those who need us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p15" pid="IKA7KwOwyUudL0unlYIM3w" hash="0iO3Vw">If charity is not always quick to our understanding, it may occasionally be quick to our misunderstanding. It is not charity or kindness to endure any type of abuse or unrighteousness that may be inflicted on us by others. God’s commandment that as we love him, we must respect ourselves, suggests we must not accept disrespect from others. It is not charity to let another repeatedly deny our divine nature and agency. It is not charity to bow down in despair and helplessness. That kind of suffering should be ended, and that is very difficult to do alone. There are priesthood leaders and other loving servants who will give aid and strength when they <span class="emphasis">know</span> of the need. We must be willing to let others help us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p16" pid="LnDH_Yh93ECuuBxrDG3D3Q" hash="ofdsZg">A striking feature of the effect of a deepened understanding of Christ’s love is how such comprehension dignifies and lifts the individual to action. Julia Mavimbela, a Church member in Soweto, South Africa, tells how her conversion brought her from bitterness at her life’s circumstances to faith and strength to help those around her and beyond her. She taught gardening to relieve hunger, and she organized women for peace to calm their strife-torn country.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p17" pid="9QnfthTE3kSXoJz51uxnXg" hash="xCaxbw">In Thailand in the late 1970s, Sister Srilaxana worked as a translator of the scriptures five days a week and then traveled throughout her country at her own expense each weekend, visiting fledgling Relief Societies. These followers of Christ did what it was in their souls, to do to serve God’s children. They did what their individuality permitted, and their examples invite us to do the same.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p18" pid="4QqHe-cnhECFbptRstnVbQ" hash="gmd_cA">Charitable, compassionate service is the central mission of our church’s Relief Society organization. We are now nearly three million members worldwide, and we rejoice in our great, diversified sisterhood. We know that our society, which marks its 150th anniversary next year, has accomplished much good. We have learned that we can do <span class="emphasis">many</span> things together that would be impossible if we worked alone. But our major focus, as a society, is to bless the individual woman as she grows in her knowledge of Christ’s gospel and reflects her knowledge by the choices she makes to serve others in righteousness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p19" pid="k3uWttAbjE6Qz8LkvODZhA" hash="MSE5Vg">At last October’s conference, Bishop Glenn L. Pace admonished all of us to look around us to do what we could as individuals to relieve pain, or loneliness, or injustice in our own communities. He promised that if we did, a compassion would enter our hearts, and through the Holy Ghost sanctification could take place within our souls, and we would become more like our Savior. (See <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1990, pp. 8–10.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long.p20" pid="cVDOe_tI30aB9IEmCy1RiA" hash="9hbVMw">I pray in all humility that our faith in God may move us to such action and that we may thus know, by the Holy Spirit, the meaning of charity so that we can exercise it in our lives, in the name of our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1991/10/charity-suffereth-long</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1991-general-conference/1991-10-5030-aileen-h-clyde-64k-eng.mp3" length="5022173" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 1991 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mission of Relief Society</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1992/04/the-mission-of-relief-society?lang=eng</link>
      <description>And now here we are—well into the last decade of the twentieth century in March 1992. We marvel together at our diversity of place, of language, of culture, and even of personal description. We celebrate the power demonstrated by this great internati</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-mission-of-relief-society" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_92905_000_040" doc-version="2" hash="n9fVFg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-mission-of-relief-society.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="RrQRKdejHU2SUiDJ72l3aw" hash="PfoC-w">The Mission of Relief Society</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="3hBeV09tcU-i8gMeZjXBEw" hash="LaJxyg">Aileen H. Clyde</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-mission-of-relief-society.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-20fa.jpg" alt="Aileen H. Clyde" pid="VcJXpBC4uU2ra1uQe7NC_Q" hash="2RaIXw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-mission-of-relief-society.p1" pid="dxAM2m0-tku0Ipr3dILTDA" hash="xsnV7g">And now here we are—well into the last decade of the twentieth century in March 1992. We marvel together at our diversity of place, of language, of culture, and even of personal description. We celebrate the power demonstrated by this great international society that binds us together with unity of purpose and sisterhood. The mission of Relief Society is founded in the gospel of Jesus Christ, and women throughout the world are responding increasingly to his teachings. Their faith elevates their lives, and as their testimonies grow, they lift and teach those around them. This society’s aim is to include them all and to bless their lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-mission-of-relief-society.p2" pid="sRZJGkRbEUOd1PTU-mpsYw" hash="LwIErg">Christ taught clearly that regardless of our living conditions, or our marital status, or our gender, we may know his love. When he met the woman at the well, as he crossed Samaria on his way to Galilee, she couldn’t believe he spoke to her. She was a Samaritan—he was a Jew. Her awareness of their differences, no doubt the legacy of long tradition, complicated her understanding him. He engaged her in a thoughtful conversation, and she began to sense that this visit had meaning far beyond the importance of drinking from a well. The exchange itself freed her from the inhibitions she expressed when he first spoke to her. When he offered the living “water springing up into everlasting life,” a new awareness came upon her, and she began to hear what he was teaching “in spirit and in truth.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/4.14,23" class="scriptureRef">John 4:14, 23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-mission-of-relief-society.p3" pid="DSPm0RHwUU6jOFbqMYvEIg" hash="ncFp6A">Her hearing became her knowing, and her testimony brought other Samaritans to him. They later said to the woman, “Now we believe, not because of thy saying: for we have heard him ourselves, and know that this is indeed the Christ, the Saviour of the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/4.42" class="scriptureRef">John 4:42</a>.) Relief Society women throughout this world have first in their purposes to know him themselves and to build their personal testimony of Christ’s love, which he so freely offers to all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-mission-of-relief-society.p4" pid="bw64Jsbi_UGupovCA76iWg" hash="A1ZUzg">Some of us need the blessing of more fully realizing our importance as individuals to our Savior. We have record of his high expectations for us. When a woman who had sinned was brought by scribes and Pharisees to be stoned, Jesus said, “He that is without sin among you, let him first cast a stone at her.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.7" class="scriptureRef">John 8:7</a>.) One by one, probably because of his presence, their own consciences lifted their condemnation of her, and they walked away. Christ then spoke those words of power that could cleanse the world, “Neither do I condemn thee: go, and sin no more.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.11" class="scriptureRef">John 8:11</a>.) His invitation was clear; the initiative was hers. Freedom from past acts was within her reach through her vision of his merciful love. Regardless of what had brought her to that point, a life of dignity and service, of righteousness and happiness was possible.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-mission-of-relief-society.p5" pid="1z7UyR-100GD4FT_jXBMvw" hash="Hs9j7g">From the beginning—150 years ago—Relief Society has offered women ways to strengthen their own lives and ways to help them strengthen the lives of others. The others might be our own family, our neighbor, or the stranger who has come to our awareness. The ways sometimes come by assignment and often come from personal initiative. The needs are everywhere, and the key to our ability to meet them is Christ’s admonition that we love one another as he has loved us. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/13.34" class="scriptureRef">John 13:34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-mission-of-relief-society.p6" pid="Olgf6qX4PkKWy38qu2TmIQ" hash="9x0qyw">The aim of this society to build testimonies, bless individuals, exercise charity, strengthen all families, and find joy in our sisterhood turns on the fulcrum of Christ’s love. May these principles of serving and growing help us see ourselves in new ways as women. May we see clearly the way before us to be righteous disciples of our atoning Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-mission-of-relief-society.p7" pid="K3jf2s_54USX8u_k0bEBig" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1992/04/the-mission-of-relief-society</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/relief-society-sesquicentennial-satellite-broadcast/1992-03-0020-aileen-h-clyde-64k-eng.mp3" length="4971603" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 1992 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confidence through Conversion</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I am so pleased to join with you in this great congregation of Relief Society women and Young Women and leaders of our Primary children. It is good to have President Hinckley, President Monson, President Hunter, and other priesthood leaders with us t</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_92911_000_037" doc-version="2" hash="vG_GWw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="DyvVp-X0F0eUswYBdZGe0Q" hash="R-uPXQ">Confidence through Conversion</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Ry0YR94nlkGQECPtfDoayA" hash="LaJxyg">Aileen H. Clyde</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p1" pid="3o2NjHTx4kKbO8O1UhvicA" hash="_qifPA">I am so pleased to join with you in this great congregation of Relief Society women and Young Women and leaders of our Primary children. It is good to have President Hinckley, President Monson, President Hunter, and other priesthood leaders with us tonight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p2" pid="icccac7Sx0u6-yOZN_U_jQ" hash="C_wPFw">I think we live in a <span class="emphasis">wonderful</span> time, and I call it wonderful because each of us has available to us personally the knowledge we need to live confident, righteous, even happy lives. We do live, as women and men always have, in complicated, variable and sometimes abusive circumstances. But because of the restored gospel, each of us has, or has available to us, a kind of knowledge that assures our survival, even our triumphant survival of the unsettling conditions that may threaten our balance and our progress.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p3" pid="c1C_4ddzukar7zTqBocnOA" hash="xuXTnw">Long ago, Moses stood on a mountain and talked with God. God showed him the world in which we all live. It was a <span class="emphasis">rare</span> vision—unlike any other I have seen recorded: “And Moses beheld the world and the ends thereof, and all the children of men which are, and which were created.” The scripture says, “He greatly marveled and wondered.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.8" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:8</a>.) Can you even begin to imagine what it would be like to see everyone and everything that ever was or will be on this earth? This filled Moses with awe, and he said to himself, “Now, for this cause I know that man is nothing, which thing I never had supposed.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.10" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:10</a>.) Then the Lord taught him a most important and central truth. He said, “This is my work and my glory—to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>.) And I would add <span class="emphasis">every</span> man and <span class="emphasis">every</span> woman. What a wonder, to Moses and to us, that we, who may feel as nothing when we compare ourselves to the vast universe, are in fact the reason for its creation and for the creation of the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p4" pid="JcYWzlz6rEmFqLVLt3_diQ" hash="V-V1NA">I think it is important to stretch our minds and try to comprehend, as Moses was shown, the paradox of being small and great at the same time. The scriptures help us keep in our awareness our unique and eternal identities. We had existence as individuals long before this life. We had <span class="emphasis">agency</span> then, and we <span class="emphasis">chose</span> to come to earth, though we knew there would be hazards and hard things here. We had sufficient confidence then to choose to follow the plan of Jesus Christ. We knew that his help would come in showing us ways to live righteously, ways to love and serve each other, and ways to shun the bad and seek the good.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p5" pid="UnpvUrTJVk-HRdxPU04SyQ" hash="v8B8xQ">Then a transition takes place and we find ourselves here—one of the ones Moses saw—part of a great panorama, and yet struggling as individuals to find the identity we once knew, as well as the sense of purpose and belonging we once had. As we gain our gospel knowledge here on earth, where we have to learn it all over again, we see this precious truth—that in our premortal life we exercised our agency when we chose Christ as our leader. He does his part and each of us can do ours to make covenants and build a partnership with him. How that happens is described by King Benjamin in the Book of Mormon:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p6" pid="VjnvwYC_OECJgCY8IzcxcA" hash="wqJjXw">“And now, because of the covenant which ye have made ye shall be called the children of Christ, his sons, and his daughters; for behold, this day he hath spiritually begotten you; for ye say that your hearts are changed through faith on his name; therefore, ye are born of him and have become his sons and his daughters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p7" pid="_-4c9nKJZkKoBAsImr9MwQ" hash="3eNPTw">“And under this head ye are made free, and there is no other head whereby ye can be made free. There is no other name given whereby salvation cometh; therefore, I would that ye should take upon you the name of Christ, all you that have entered into the covenant with God that ye should be obedient unto the end of your lives.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/5.7-8" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 5:7–8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p8" pid="vZF2zKMnWkqPtAK5BTWy0Q" hash="McpWQQ">My whole hope in speaking to you about gospel knowledge of our individual importance to our Heavenly Father and our Savior is that it will build our confidence in our own ability to make good decisions that will help us grow spiritually. Some people want a strong authoritative voice to say, “Do this” or “Do that.” Some want God to tell them exactly what to do before they risk anything. Recently at a BYU fireside address, Elder Dallin Oaks said: “Personal decision making is one of the sources of the growth we are meant to experience in mortality. Persons who try to shift all decision making to the Lord and plead for revelation in every choice will soon find circumstances where they pray for guidance and don’t receive it. For example, this is likely to occur in those numerous circumstances where choices are trivial or where either choice is acceptable. We should study things out in our minds, using the reasoning powers our Creator has placed within us. Then we should pray for guidance and act upon it if we receive it, and upon our own best judgment if we do not.” (Dallin H. Oaks, “Our Strength Can Become Our Downfall,” Fireside of BYU Stakes, 7 June 1992, pp. 3–4.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p9" pid="Pnea7-8v40a83S9w_U6RoA" hash="mJToWQ">When we are converted to the gospel of Jesus Christ we become both humble and courageous. Our conversion strengthens us greatly in our decision making. A good example of the kinds of real circumstances good people face in this life can be found in the Old Testament in the very short, five-page book of Ruth. Each time I read it I see something new. Lately I have been thinking of it as a story of conversion, of courage and decision making. It is about another time, another culture, yet it is about us too.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p10" pid="W-BC6g65PkCpNDvDc4s1vw" hash="9nSx8A">Naomi and her husband, Elimelech, and their two sons had gone into the enemy country of Moab because there was a great famine in Israel, their home. In due time their sons married Moabite wives, named Orpah and Ruth. Then in a ten-year period, the father and the two sons died. Naomi had heard that the famine had lifted in Judah, and she wanted to return to her people. She counsels her daughters-in-law to return to their mothers’ homes. Naomi called them her daughters and kissed them, and they wept with their love for her. (Now isn’t that quite remarkable? I fail to understand how this clear and well-known record hasn’t had more influence on all the unfunny mother-in-law jokes that abound in the world.) But eventually Orpah decides to stay in Moab, and again Naomi says to Ruth, “Behold, thy sister in law has gone back to her people, and unto her gods: return thou after thy sister in law.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ruth/1.15" class="scriptureRef">Ruth 1:15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p11" pid="YeQzssZ3rE-go89VzfL9sA" hash="8GFlaA">At this point, in majestic Hebraic poetry, Ruth announces her decision and confirms her conversion. “Intreat me not to leave thee, or to return from following after thee: for whither thou goest, I will go; and where thou lodgest, I will lodge: thy people shall be my people, and thy God my God.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ruth/1.16" class="scriptureRef">Ruth 1:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p12" pid="MY1V-mU8tEGvymPQhB9aTw" hash="6XlO5Q">When Naomi, herself realistic and wise, saw Ruth’s steadfastness, she “left off speaking to her” (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/ruth/1.18" class="scriptureRef">Ruth 1:18</a>), which does not mean she stopped talking with her, but that she quit trying to convince her of the difficulties she would face in Israel. Ruth, the Moabitess, <span class="emphasis">would</span> face bigotry, poverty, and much insecurity, but she was converted, and she <span class="emphasis">had</span> decided. She and Naomi became a great team, facing together not only the problems before them, but the opportunities that would come also.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p13" pid="z56FX7INdEyQFHZnyElN0w" hash="5iZxmQ">In time, Ruth married Boaz, and a child was born to them. “And the women said to Naomi, Blessed be the Lord … for thy daughter in law, which loveth thee, which is better to thee than seven sons, hath born [a child].</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p14" pid="cla-TYAZU0uQyJXYYQ_CqA" hash="-KFrfg">“And Naomi took the child … and became nurse unto it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p15" pid="pJ4w6FroAUGlLUvyRSwwMg" hash="TJInOA">“And the women her neighbours gave it a name, saying, There is a son born to Naomi; and they called his name Obed: he is the father of Jesse, the father of David.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ruth/4.14-17" class="scriptureRef">Ruth 4:14–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p16" pid="Oo14LDDsKkGDGzOp2YfMGg" hash="8acayg">Now that was a kind of a prophecy which is very important to us. In a culture hostile to the leadership of women, these women—Naomi and Ruth—lived to bring about an end the scripture’s writer carefully emphasizes: Obed, the father of Jesse, the father of David, through whose lines, which are carefully detailed for us in the first chapter of Matthew, came Jesus who is called Christ. Would you ever have expected the small book of Ruth to foretell such a great event?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p17" pid="L6vbEwZp-EW_P5D0ujJyuw" hash="B9eA9w">Ruth confidently met hardships not uncommon in our time—the death of a loved one, loneliness in a new place, and the need to work hard for her bread. Her small efforts, linked significantly to a later great event, tell me that each of us can take seriously the importance of our daily lives and decisions as we choose to follow God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p18" pid="6MB5g6_ss0CoiTuLev3euw" hash="gUXgZw">What I have told you tonight is my personal testimony. I am grateful for what I understand of agency and for the trust I have in my Heavenly Father and His guidance. I am grateful for the atonement of my Savior, who perfectly understood the risks. I am grateful for the blessings of faith and charity which fill my soul with joy and gladness and cause me to say, we <span class="emphasis">do </span>live in a wonderful time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion.p19" pid="uOBksJRLdUu5jteAGgr6NQ" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1992/10/confidence-through-conversion</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1992-general-womens-meeting/1992-09-0010-aileen-h-clyde-64k-eng.mp3" length="5279263" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 1992 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relief Society: Charity, the Guiding Principle</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1993/10/relief-society-charity-the-guiding-principle?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Thank you for that beautiful music. Thank you to those who wrote it and to those who performed it. I am grateful for the personal nature of that powerful hymn. It is a testimony of Christ’s love and what can come from our relationship with him. As Re</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/relief-society-charity-the-guiding-principle" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_93911_000_036" doc-version="2" hash="8RAi9A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/relief-society-charity-the-guiding-principle.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="4lFJc37j_EKl1B5iQg4H4A" hash="HizwEg">Relief Society:</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="AzlBMjzXO0e5XDpEpf9D0g" hash="YPoIJQ">Charity, the Guiding Principle</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="YiF2z-tf0E-2MhBQlp1lzg" hash="LaJxyg">Aileen H. Clyde</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/relief-society-charity-the-guiding-principle.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/relief-society-charity-the-guiding-principle.p1" pid="4-rFcs5XNU-GVF6A581Ugw" hash="FHmjkQ">Thank you for that beautiful music. Thank you to those who wrote it and to those who performed it. I am grateful for the personal nature of that powerful hymn. It is a testimony of Christ’s love and what can come from our relationship with him. As Relief Society members, we both <span class="emphasis">claim</span> and <span class="emphasis">celebrate</span> our place as his disciples, and I pray that what I say here will somehow nourish our understanding of his great goodness to us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/relief-society-charity-the-guiding-principle.p2" pid="d5jks6ljB0CaRE3jNWSZOg" hash="yy78Nw">This society, organized and dedicated to charity, has grown in 151 years from twenty women to more than 3.4 million women worldwide. The idea of a women’s organization in the fledgling Church of 1842 came from the initiative of righteous women. As a result of their inquiry, a prophet of God brought into being an entity for women we call Relief Society. Only by priesthood power, and through the authority of a prophet, could the women of the Church be organized in a way that would bind them to the whole of the Church and keep them an integral part of building God’s kingdom. Shortly after the founding, the Prophet Joseph Smith said, “I now turn the key to you in the name of God and this Society shall <span class="emphasis">rejoice</span> and knowledge and intelligence shall flow down from this time—this is the beginning of better days to this Society” (emphasis added).<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> In the book <span class="emphasis">Women of Covenant,</span> a recently published history of Relief Society, we read that the temporal duties of the Relief Society organization would change as contemporary circumstances would require, but its spiritual mandate was a <span class="emphasis">permanent</span> mandate. The Prophet Joseph Smith said, “Teach the female part of the community … [and] save souls.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> In 1906, President Joseph F. Smith restated the purpose for us: They (meaning Relief Society) should “look after the spiritual welfare and salvation of the mothers and daughters of Zion; and to see that none is neglected, but that all are guarded against misfortune, calamity, the powers of darkness, and the evils that threaten them in the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/relief-society-charity-the-guiding-principle.p3" pid="xajXUaHyYUij_S2Q-NANwg" hash="UiG0mQ">When President Elaine Jack was called in 1990, and Chieko Okazaki and I became her counselors, we humbly sought to be instruments to augment and multiply many “better days” for our sisters throughout the world. We were well aware that their circumstances vary greatly, and we knew that it was their spiritual welfare that Relief Society must not neglect. We centered on Jacob chapter 4, verse 13: “For the Spirit speaketh the truth and lieth not. Wherefore, it speaketh of things as they really are, and of things as they really will be; wherefore, these things are manifested unto us plainly, for the salvation of our souls.” [<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.13" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:13</a>] We knew that women struggling to clarify their identities could best do that not by comparing themselves to other women but by understanding their important place as full and equal partners with men in receiving, in righteousness, the saving ordinances established by Christ. We saw that men and women are baptized, are offered the gift of the Holy Ghost, partake of the sacrament, and make sacred covenants in the temples of the Church in exactly the same ways. We would not try to describe an ideal Mormon woman. We would seek instead to teach that Christ is our model and that as we are filled with his love, we are his disciples. We sought the blessing described in Moroni chapter 7, verse 48, that “we shall be like him.” [<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.48" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:48</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/relief-society-charity-the-guiding-principle.p4" pid="YaXNBcGUF0OpMi42eT7ojQ" hash="KBMuGw">We looked at our organization and we saw that structurally, Relief Society can be described today as Sunday lessons, visiting teaching, homemaking meetings, and welfare and compassionate service. These avenues provide ways for our members to increase their knowledge of gospel principles and to offer watch care for one another. We see the homemaking meeting as an hour and a half a month where the importance of our homes as places of nurture and sanctuary can be emphasized. By participating there, we can better serve our families, build a righteous sisterhood, and develop and exercise charity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/relief-society-charity-the-guiding-principle.p5" pid="iH6oRy70CUqrRUKgEnDNTQ" hash="zG2Saw">But looking only at the structure does not tell the story. Relief Society is being inaugurated in many places in the world where Church membership is new. This allows us to see clearly that our society’s strength comes when the structure is enlivened by the faith, character, and works of its members. Whether you belong to a long-established ward or a struggling branch, what <span class="emphasis">you</span> bring to the work as a participating member will greatly affect what happens to you and to others around you. Teaching and saving souls, seeing that “none is neglected,” is a great cause. This work calls on us <span class="emphasis">all</span> and calls for our honest best.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/relief-society-charity-the-guiding-principle.p6" pid="F0liaiQLv06Xulzp0E6zsA" hash="14ocdw">For Relief Society, the <span class="emphasis">charity</span> of our motto is not an abstraction. It is a love beyond the emotion we might feel for or from others. It isn’t a “what’s in it for me?” kind of love. Being friendly, generous, and respectful of others moves us along the way from self-concern, but the selflessness of the kind of love that Christ commanded us to learn is a high step indeed. “Bless them that curse you, do good to them that hate you, and pray for them who despitefully use you” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/12.44" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 12:44</a>). He <span class="emphasis">promises</span> that as we learn that kind of love, we can become perfect!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/relief-society-charity-the-guiding-principle.p7" pid="m7RKbLh07keFvTi4YXL_cg" hash="rhgxmw">I have seen some of that in practice lately. A woman whom I had not met before came to my home and recounted her heartbreak at a marriage ruined by deceit and cruelty. She grieved for her young adult children, who were confused and wounded. She had served as a ward Relief Society president three times and as a stake Relief Society president. That service had shown her both irrefutable evidence of God’s goodness and mercy, and some of the difficult and painful realities that many suffer; even so, she was surprised at how unprepared she felt to face her own tragedy. At last she said, “All I can do now is cling to my faith in God and pray that my love of Christ and for my children will help me survive.” For the present, her pain had clouded her ability to see her own courage and resolve. In the midst of such trouble, she was steadfast in Christ, and her intent was charity. I knew she and her children still had much to endure and to work through, but the words from Moroni echoed for us both that “whoso is found possessed of [charity] at the last day, it shall be well with [her” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.47" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:47</a>). Through her excruciating experience of sifting for the true nature of love, she was literally offering what God requires of each of us, a broken heart and a contrite spirit. Her offering was also building in <span class="emphasis">her</span> strength and peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/relief-society-charity-the-guiding-principle.p8" pid="GivIVVVePU-KZZZNufYMNg" hash="Fk_4Dg">Another example of the power of selfless love is the experience of my friends Thales and Charone Smith, recently returned from a humanitarian mission in Albania. He a pediatrician and she a nurse, they were the Church’s first missionaries there. They went about this work as they had through forty-six years as partners in marriage. Each found ample opportunity to use their individual attributes. Thales worked as a clinical instructor in a pediatric hospital that served a wide range of services for children. Charone was assigned to a dystrophy hospital, where eighty children from infancy to two or three years of age were treated for nutritional deficiencies and other severe problems. Because the hospital served a wide radius, mothers and fathers could seldom visit. Some children were abandoned there because of the poverty and desperate circumstances of their parents. When Charone arrived, the tiny patients were apathetic and unresponsive. Most were swaddled so that they lay in their beds listlessly. She observed that the doctors and nurses were professional and did well to keep the children fed and clean, but that was all done on a strict schedule. Demonstrativeness and individual caring were completely lacking. Charone was assigned to the care of ten children. She began singing and talking to them as she worked. At first they didn’t even look at her. She held them during their feedings instead of propping their bottles, and she commented to them about each other. Within two weeks, they were looking at her and following her gestures with their eyes. After six weeks, the changes could be seen by anyone. The children had begun to smile, they gained weight, and their personalities began to emerge. Charone exercised their limbs and gave them practice sitting up. Her charges progressed so well that the doctors modified her schedule so that she and others could nurture all eighty children. Although the little patients still faced difficulties, by the time Charone left, all were thriving as individuals. Love is not just good, it is essential to life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/relief-society-charity-the-guiding-principle.p9" pid="QmoBeNhq2EiZgqZyINjWfg" hash="bEtAPQ">There is much evidence of the goodness of you women and of the principles that motivate your service and fidelity. As you seek God’s Spirit, work with priesthood leaders, use your capacity to analyze needs, and move with courage, you dignify us all. Your work blesses lives and builds God’s kingdom on earth. Relief Society teaches that exercising charity and participating fully in the blessings of the essential ordinances of the restored gospel lead us to become more like Christ. This is surely the “knowledge and intelligence” that will lead to “better days” for all, and even to eternal life and godliness. To this I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1993/10/relief-society-charity-the-guiding-principle</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/1993-general-relief-society-meeting/1993-09-0020-aileen-h-clyde-64k-eng.mp3" length="5821770" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 1993 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charity and Learning</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The women of our church have mobilized themselves many times in loving service to one another, to their families, and to their larger communities. The tasks we undertake may vary significantly, but we believe the how, or the way we go about such work</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_94911_000_037" doc-version="2" hash="fS3TpA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="MTr9HNump0yEqjAYrXVhuA" hash="FUC_4w">Charity and Learning</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="kWx-o_cMz06pmw9XYO0aeA" hash="LaJxyg">Aileen H. Clyde</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-20fa.jpg" alt="Aileen H. Clyde" pid="83mhd54rCUazvFRMJ9uchA" hash="2RaIXw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p1" pid="BcGZbK_NyUyqix62XteQqg" hash="zF92Lg">The women of our church have mobilized themselves many times in loving service to one another, to their families, and to their larger communities. The tasks we undertake may vary significantly, but we believe the how, or the way we go about such work, separates us from the world because of our desire to be guided spiritually and to act with charity. Our scriptural records suggest to us that charity, the word we use for the highest form of love, even “the pure love of Christ” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.47" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:47</a>), is <span class="emphasis">learned.</span> As we learn, we are capable of being kind, without envy, not easily provoked, rejoicing in truth, bearing, believing, hoping, enduring all things (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/13.4-7" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 13:4–7</a>). Charity comes to us as we move from grace to grace and as we build precept on precept:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p2" pid="g2O6srEN9kmkelbfXZ31fg" hash="C6XHEw">“For behold, thus saith the Lord God: I will give unto the children of men line upon line, precept upon precept, here a little and there a little; and blessed are those who hearken unto my precepts, and lend an ear unto my counsel, for they shall learn wisdom” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/28.30" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 28:30</a>). Relief Society women do seek to learn wisdom, but we place learning charity first.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p3" pid="Rvw5Cl77u0Wc1CyJ4aDGFQ" hash="kjhOtA">Charity develops in us as we see ourselves moving in our lives from a “what’s in it for me” kind of love to the love of family and friends and, blessedly, beyond that to an awareness of our Lord’s unconditional love for us that tells us of our divine kinship with one another <span class="emphasis">and</span> with him. Such love, or charity, does not spring whole and steady in most lives, but it can come as we learn and grow and reach for ways to know God’s love. The scriptures are a great help to us in understanding this. There we read that love precedes knowledge of God. In <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-jn/4.8-11" class="scriptureRef">1 Jn. 4:8–11</a>:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p4" pid="tLOOa62_rku4oALPae8Z0w" hash="inEK7g">“He [or she] that loveth not knoweth not God; for God is love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p5" pid="72s1OYrzSUyR2hpUcYvbLw" hash="f7tkuw">“In this was manifested the love of God toward us, because that God sent his only begotten Son into the world, that we might live through him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p6" pid="ORogs721P0ee8NNsFI7Z7w" hash="uQUlWg">“Herein is love, not that we loved God, but that he loved us, and sent his Son to be the propitiation for our sins.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p7" pid="hB5tomnQt0mjNrkutv1G1w" hash="3wL60g">“Beloved, if God so loved us, we ought also to love one another.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p8" pid="MFbzFcXz1ku5tCbxKdibdQ" hash="QEPeGQ">What we “ought” to do in charity for ourselves and one another sometimes comes with swift ease, but more often comes through courageous, corrected, and unselfish effort. The Relief Society organization offers women opportunities that can augment their personal endeavors to develop and exercise charity. Through our cooperative efforts, Relief Society members can help one another feel supported and loved, particularly in times of need and crisis. We test our efforts by following Christ’s way of unconditional love and understanding. We believe our acts of kindness and demonstrated love have meaning to the degree that they draw the Holy Spirit into our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p9" pid="EfY5PxrLf0mwoxK3ipKQTg" hash="bmjQGA">Just as important, Relief Society gives us opportunity to teach one another the saving principles and ordinances, which come to us through priesthood power and are recorded in scripture. We may become instruments then to “save souls,” as the Prophet Joseph Smith envisioned in 1842. Today, as at Relief Society’s founding, women of the Church see charity as the salient way of developing our capacities to <span class="emphasis">know</span> God, not merely to know <span class="emphasis">about</span> God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p10" pid="WJ5rXqJ79kuWBpdTEjAGcQ" hash="y8Oj_g">In our Savior’s great intercessory prayer recorded in the seventeenth chapter of John, he prayed for us, “And this is life eternal, that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou has sent” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17:3</a>). Then he spoke of the Apostles and of the believers of that time: “For I have given unto them the words which thou gavest me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.8" class="scriptureRef">John 17:8</a>). The kind of knowing which came to Christ’s Apostles and other believers of that time was a gift of the Spirit, but note the importance of the words which Christ conveyed to them orally, which then were conveyed by them to any who would hear their testimonies, and later are conveyed to us as written testaments. The reality of God and Christ and our relationship to them comes to us through a chain of knowing conveyed by words, even holy words, <span class="emphasis">and</span> by the Holy Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p11" pid="dtgHfLoYIk-CeVaMorxGBw" hash="L5NdOA">It is because of our awareness of the importance of words in transmitting redeeming truths to one another that Relief Society has embarked on an effort to encourage learning by offering help with basic reading skills to those who need them and by motivating those of us who now read to read more meaningfully.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p12" pid="NeoJviEhqUyzI819d49dQw" hash="iZN9Gg">Being able to read well and with understanding is an important path to knowing God, and it is a reliable and universal way. I call it universal because as human beings we are all born with a genetic endowment for recognizing and formulating language. It is just one of the wonderful ways we are! Our Creator meant for us to value and develop our ability to communicate with him and with each other. He expects us to use these capacities to learn righteous ways, to lift one another, and to develop our divine natures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p13" pid="esSt8vF0pE63OSur4_i7Dg" hash="9c6mZQ">That may be the motivation for us to be together here tonight. We have experienced sitting in large congregations such as this before. We go to some trouble to be together—in crowds—to listen to words, heads tilted. Some are receiving instructions. Some are meditating on what has been suggested. Some are weighing what is said, unsure for now of its meaning for them. This is a process we were created to use.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p14" pid="fXOgjpLQO0y3zc1YEyK5Wg" hash="-jcp8w">Each of us has had the experience of matching a truth or a realization through inspiring words or music from others to something deep within our souls. When that connection happens, it feels like a small explosion of knowing. We are lifted and warmed; both our minds and our hearts are involved. These experiences, at least momentarily, verify our kinship with one another and with God. They help us sense anew who we are and who we may become. As we understand such communication, we can see better the opportunities to learn that lie unused all around us. It becomes easier to identify the ways we have become prone to routine, allowing comfortable habits to insulate us from using our minds with spiritual power to see “a more excellent way” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/12.31" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 12:31</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p15" pid="YOK9f1FS8UCbY8aVKzpjqA" hash="9vL0lA">I would be negligent if I did not acknowledge for us all how much more complex and various the avenues of communication to our minds are today. Television, audio, video, satellite broadcasting, as well as print media, have greatly enlarged the audience for this Relief Society meeting tonight. We are blessed by that. But others, with other purposes, will use the same technologies to communicate to us alluringly. It requires alert discrimination to choose what may focus the mind toward excellence and what may distract, confuse, or deceive us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p16" pid="CuoR4Ex_R0OgsUlpfxSu1w" hash="sOIcCw">“Wherefore, beware lest ye are deceived; and that ye may not be deceived seek ye earnestly the best gifts, always remembering for what they are given;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p17" pid="cRPcYHd4DEq0Y_yP-KgU6Q" hash="xH1btw">“For verily I say unto you, they are given for the benefit of those who love me and keep all my commandments, and him [or her] that seeketh so to do” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/46.8-9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 46:8–9</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p18" pid="iKkxljRgJkyZjAuBvZzPCQ" hash="-vOHKA">As a Relief Society officer, it has been my great blessing to meet with many of God’s daughters who are committed to keeping his commandments, who have made and kept sacred covenants, and who make sincere efforts to know his word. None of these women is typical because each has different dimensions depending on particular circumstances which vary widely. They distinguish themselves from the world as they seek to verify the reality of spiritual gifts and of God’s love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p19" pid="wakeG6sL_k2zzEovPslWHA" hash="CoV-oA">In late spring this year, I met such a one in California whose faith and testimony stirred my soul. She was slight and soft-spoken and described herself as a boat person. She had learned English and qualified for scholarships to attend college after she arrived in the United States. In addition to her studies in chemical engineering, she married, joined the Church, and had four children. Her capacity to read was a significant tool in meeting her many challenges. She described her great effort to interpret her college texts in a language different from her native tongue. She told how her reading of the Book of Mormon had deepened her understanding not only of scriptural truths but also of her exacting studies of mathematics and chemistry.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p20" pid="ALG9DoY6tEmR4bLyx0oURA" hash="xeczuA">Sometime after she graduated, her husband left her and their children without support, and she found it necessary to seek employment. She felt that she was hired at a laboratory because of the advantage of her minority status, but she had no experience and did not know the procedures that others there found routine. As she had only the Lord to turn to, she began to sequester herself at work to pray for help. She also discovered that while reading the Book of Mormon, her mind would become clear, and she found herself with effective ideas of how to implement her assignments. Her progress has been such that now when other lab workers are stymied with a project, they come to her for clarification and direction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p21" pid="MR0KGIoKh0qQkDDlbgEgSA" hash="3sRUpQ">She testified of her sure knowledge of God’s reality and particularly of his love. Her struggles for her family require all of her physical and spiritual strength. Now, on Saturdays, she often takes her children to market to buy food which they prepare together and then take to a homeless shelter. She greatly desires that her children gain an understanding of what her life was like when she had nothing. She is teaching them to understand God’s love by helping them exercise charity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p22" pid="Yw-iPpzDe0CCtIwbYccSkA" hash="Z2nCVA">In trying to fully comprehend the meaning of her testimony, I found help in <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.23" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:23</a>:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p23" pid="UpndNwQMGEaESYkLOP5l_A" hash="DAL5UA">“And now, he imparteth his word by angels unto men, yea, not only men but women also. Now this is not all; little children do have words given unto them many times, which confound the wise and the learned.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning.p24" pid="EGN9XBkdrkOVWXdhamTmew" hash="SPdcZw">I testify to you that God lives and is good and his spiritual gifts are available to us all. May we know him and Christ our Savior in ways that qualify us to offer pure love to one another by the Holy Spirit, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1994/10/charity-and-learning</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/1994-general-relief-society-meeting/1994-09-0030-aileen-h-clyde-64k-eng.mp3" length="6223041" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 1994 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covenant of Love</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love?lang=eng</link>
      <description>“For the mountains shall depart, and the hills be removed; but my kindness shall not depart from thee, neither shall the covenant of my peace be removed, saith the Lord” (; see also ).</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95905_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="f7Ewcg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="gZy7xzaFhEmEOVamTDKJSg" hash="ofOJpQ">Covenant of Love</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="2L12Km-0YEaMkzKFUbXqLg" hash="LaJxyg">Aileen H. Clyde</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-20fa.jpg" alt="Aileen H. Clyde" pid="tWMwADCkuE2dlnwjVREPbQ" hash="2RaIXw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p1" pid="y_Jcl16KwkavwaLNznQm5Q" hash="pHlHhA">“For the mountains shall depart, and the hills be removed; but my kindness shall not depart from thee, neither shall the covenant of my peace be removed, saith the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/54.10" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 54:10</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/22.10" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 22:10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p2" pid="oy6VwmlqQkqDClRDeA-jig" hash="gK7vNA">Such scriptural language overwhelms my reasoning and floods me again with the reality of God’s love and of our importance to him. Did he speak to our intelligences in that way in the long-ago council when we understood enough to choose to follow Christ? It was surely then, before our mortal experience, that we began with our part of building the covenant relationship with the Savior which is vital to our eternal lives. I believe we chose to be guided then, as we need to be guided now, by his loving care for our divine and unique identities. Our decision then was of the greatest import. Now, when we face crossroads and dilemmas, we can look again to that same source for courage to move forward on our journey.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p3" pid="rXc_K1rInkaE84Hmso65Rw" hash="lL8Q9w">“Fear thou not; for I am with thee: be not dismayed; for I am thy God: I will strengthen thee; yea, I will help thee; yea, I will uphold thee with the right hand of my righteousness” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/41.10" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 41:10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p4" pid="ZkItpoSJMk-Qqdyp-OuliQ" hash="M8SlQA">Of the many blessings that have come to me through my knowledge of Christ’s gospel, I am most grateful for the doctrine that teaches us that our lives here have eternal meaning and are for the glory of God. We are central in his great work. He teaches that as we receive his light, we can reflect that light in the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p5" pid="J-V5NVQ08EePZNHioIL4xA" hash="Fz53dw">There is a constant struggle to balance our knowledge of light against the error and fear that are among the hallmarks of our world. Today we see temptations of old in new ways. They can be magnified and multicolored by technology which gives them avenues everywhere. These portrayals are aimed at the young, the naive, and the vulnerable—indeed, they are aimed at each one of us. All manner of violence is depicted in arcade games, and we even see horrifying violent acts in our own neighborhoods. Amidst the danger, our love waxes cold, and we may seek a defense in the very weapons that threaten us. Worse yet, we may be turned by fear to looking for protection <span class="emphasis">from</span> one another rather than keeping our promise to be a light and a protection <span class="emphasis">for</span> one another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p6" pid="Cbgn_ZLZr0iam6Gc--mhWg" hash="SksY0w">The Joseph Smith translation of Matthew 16 brings clarity to distinctions that Christ’s disciples need to understand:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p7" pid="aIVMP2UVy0-2wo9lnPLAXw" hash="aex8dA">“Break not my commandments for to save your lives; for whosoever will save his life in this world, shall lose it in the world to come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p8" pid="HNjnilzrK0ivKVQsjTth5A" hash="ml-_mQ">“And whosoever will lose his life in this world, for my sake, shall find it in the world to come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p9" pid="H28rumhn9Ee6bIkXPZJrPA" hash="zJh4Xg">“Therefore, forsake the world, and save your souls” (JST, Matt. 16:27–29).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p10" pid="sLaqxVr3V0Cg0ClbofM4bw" hash="rpi6Nw">We must depend upon the light of Christ to understand this teaching, but we cannot allow our fears to separate us from the possession of our souls. Hear what is recorded in the 101st section of Doctrine and Covenants:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p11" pid="3xtOXS1j6EiQ_A1plRVfkg" hash="qlRCWQ">“Wherefore, fear not even unto death; for in this world your joy is not full, but in me your joy is full.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p12" pid="NtlWuRSNQ0yuzkpitAzY1g" hash="SVr-Qw">“Therefore, care not for the body, neither the life of the body; but care for the soul, and for the life of the soul.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p13" pid="4C1gWOeDyUGOxk6_opIOcQ" hash="XYJnTg">“And seek the face of the Lord always, that in patience ye may possess your souls, and ye shall have eternal life” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/101.36-38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 101:36–38</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p14" pid="xx8_O6p_a0GDRzR_aPu1zg" hash="GYzwsg">It is a response of the soul when we sense and accept the loving promises that Christ extends to us. Listen to Isaiah’s description of what our Lord has already done for us:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p15" pid="xGpHdjjx0EWxA8fkpc7xcA" hash="32zcOg">“Thus saith God the Lord, he that created the heavens, and stretched them out; he that spread forth the earth, and that which cometh out of it; he that giveth breath unto the people upon it, and spirit to them that walk therein” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/42.5" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 42:5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p16" pid="e-9J8-KWG06mvfLV6_9o-A" hash="oOlvcg">Then Isaiah records the Lord’s soul-nourishing tenderness and the loving-kindness of his assurances:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p17" pid="iJekg2LoPkOeBxIbU5LbEg" hash="jZxO1g">“I the Lord have called thee in righteousness, and will hold thine hand, and will keep thee, and give thee for a covenant of the people, for a light of the Gentiles. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p18" pid="5pZIoOlyk0uABab4_neytQ" hash="5KTNow">“Behold, the former things are come to pass, and new things do I declare: before they spring forth I tell you of them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p19" pid="Kh8dLv-dx0SAR4Tp1DQiQQ" hash="H-hZnQ">“Sing unto the Lord a new song, and his praise from the end of the earth” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/42.6,9-10" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 42:6, 9–10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p20" pid="n2xkXayd5kS1Uugk4Xj9VQ" hash="Mb-9Ow">The book of Alma teaches that the song he has asked us to sing is a song of redeeming love (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.26" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:26</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p21" pid="krzx3gEZlE68A2IDH_surg" hash="bvljuw">Later, when the Savior was asked in Palestine to designate the first and great commandment, he unhesitatingly said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p22" pid="010afnpD4Uuvcb1uSRCFfg" hash="se2YSw">“Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p23" pid="7-3TAif-T0iug75ZZcXppg" hash="HnX8dA">“And the second [commandment] is like unto it, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.37,39" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:37, 39</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p24" pid="FbFre5fIxU2Ww3VPs4qaKg" hash="yEpo7A">These statements are both clear and comprehensive. They suggest the <span class="emphasis">beginning</span> of how we can engage ourselves in his covenant. And surely, since he knows us, he would not have required anything we cannot do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p25" pid="uW_BNB5Q9kiRR45LE-0elA" hash="cgxwsA">The love Christ commands requires a mighty change and great humility. It requires us to forsake pride and to be stripped of envy. It requires that we neither mock our sisters and brothers nor persecute <span class="emphasis">anyone.</span> Christ knew that for us to find any of those characteristics in ourselves would be onerous and would demand our great effort just to look. He said, “If thy hand or thy foot offend thee, cut them off, and cast them from thee” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/18.8" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 18:8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p26" pid="DBLtsWE4V0qM0XGjft79dg" hash="gulIcA">He was not suggesting our mutilation, but rather showing his awareness of how painful clearing ourselves of such offenses could be. When we have made the changes that only we can make, then, by the atoning blood of Christ, we may receive the forgiveness that only he can bring. The reciprocal nature of those actions suggests the high trust and respect the Lord has for our abilities. Anyone who has had experience with the Lord’s love knows of the sure courage that comes when we keep our part of that trust and honor him by seeking his Spirit and by living the best we can. We hear again:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p27" pid="kfAOriNNC0q2y-sM_BBZ9w" hash="i0L9Ow">“My kindness shall not depart from thee, neither shall the covenant of my peace be removed” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/54.10" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 54:10</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/22.10" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 22:10</a>) and “Behold, I will lay thy stones with fair colors, and lay thy foundations with sapphires” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/22.11" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 22:11</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/54.11" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 54:11</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p28" pid="RZmKD1_0NkSWDUCJeMKMKg" hash="Y4MoQA">Such scriptural language rivets my attention. In the midst of a troubling world, the foundations I rely on come by my covenants with the Lord. They are indeed like sapphires and are treasures beyond price. Through them I have eternal link to my loved ones and to God. They are the restored principles and ordinances of the gospel of Jesus Christ which are available to righteous women and men alike through the power of the holy priesthood of God. They include baptism, the gift of the Holy Ghost, the sacrament, and temple covenants. These are the ways given to us and freely chosen by us to vouchsafe our eternal lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p29" pid="otmZBuIZYUKC_XJjci9GUA" hash="GKZ2tw">“And now, because of the covenant which ye have made ye shall be called the children of Christ, his sons, and his daughters; for behold, this day he hath spiritually begotten you; for ye say that your hearts are changed through faith on his name; therefore, ye are born of him and have become his sons and his daughters” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/5.7" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 5:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p30" pid="ddcwYJCYtECHKxBuJxoxxQ" hash="CxIAEg">We are, then, because of his great love and because of our desire to be guided by his light, part of the family of Christ. Because of our covenants, we have protection from loneliness and alienation. Because of our relationship with him, we can reflect light and tenderness to one another and we can possess our own souls eternally.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love.p31" pid="6fkohJc8ykCKYjNz1UrPkw" hash="YTfehA">I testify of the great blessing it is to know these things. I am humbly grateful for scriptural testaments and for my knowledge that Christ is alive and heads his church. I know he can be alive in each of us as we keep his commandments, and I say this humbly in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/04/covenant-of-love</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1995-general-conference/1995-04-2050-aileen-h-clyde-64k-eng.mp3" length="5009192" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 1995 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is Relief Society For?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Tonight, in the presence of our prophet and his counselors, we gratefully remind ourselves and testify to the world that the Relief Society was divinely organized by a loving Heavenly Father acting through the Prophet Joseph Smith. And we witness tha</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95911_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="X_hgEQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Qq_qJSh5PUqMjc17Ro4CWg" hash="1ZSMtw">What Is Relief Society For?</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="qwcYbOLV8kqfpBIeHUkXlA" hash="LaJxyg">Aileen H. Clyde</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for.p1" pid="5gfMco-lM0Siw4VK-3xolg" hash="ZbgR1A">Tonight, in the presence of our prophet and his counselors, we gratefully remind ourselves and testify to the world that the Relief Society was divinely organized by a loving Heavenly Father acting through the Prophet Joseph Smith. And we witness that it continues to be led by prophets of God. I am humbled to be here with all of you in this general Relief Society meeting to hear the counsel of President Gordon B. Hinckley, <span class="emphasis">our</span> prophet for <span class="emphasis">our</span> time. We need his voice to guide us now as surely as our sisters needed a prophet’s intervention in 1842 when they brought to Joseph Smith a constitution for a female benevolent society in Nauvoo. They approached the Prophet Joseph and asked his counsel on their desire to serve in the kingdom by organizing themselves by their plan. He said he had something better for them: an order and a purpose which required priesthood leadership so that their good desires could bear even better fruit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for.p2" pid="QSdENhveOUCmRvKAHsRwxg" hash="P3TMMQ">Many organizations compete for our time. In fact, our commitments to callings in the various organizations of the Church can cause us to think we are not “working in Relief Society now,” or we may say, “when I <span class="emphasis">was</span> in the Relief Society. …” Sisters, as members of the Church, we are always in Relief Society. Yet it is not uncommon for women, especially those either new to the Church or new to Relief Society, to ask: “What is Relief Society for?” “Why should I participate?” “How can it help me?” All of us can benefit by reflecting on these questions and on the answers our prophets have given us and will yet give us on occasions such as this.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for.p3" pid="JLDdAmTgxUeGi8U5OLUgjQ" hash="UB9W-w">Quite simply, we participate in Relief Society out of the understanding that this is God’s organization for us and the conviction that, as he promised through his Prophet, because of it, we “shall rejoice, and knowledge and intelligence shall flow down from this time” <span class="emphasis">(History of the Church,</span> 4:607; quoted in <span class="emphasis">History of Relief Society, 1842–1966,</span> Salt Lake City: The General Board of Relief Society, 1966, p. 21). Or, in the words of the Prophet’s mother: Relief Society is where we can “cherish one another … and gain instruction, that we may all sit down in heaven together” (Minutes of the Female Relief Society of Nauvoo, 24 Mar. 1842; quoted in <span class="emphasis">History of Relief Society, 1842–1966,</span> p. 20). Sisters, we do need instruction. We need cherishing, and we need to cherish others. All teachers and most experienced students know the relationship between these two principles. We cannot teach those whom we do not love. We cannot learn from those who do not love us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for.p4" pid="N-RCf8h0TUOv503qNQHJNg" hash="rAdBtQ">Consider how the very powers of modern communications that promise to make of our world an interconnected network are the cause of much public worrying about our increasing isolation from one another. Even privately, in our wards and, yes, in our families too, we sometimes find ourselves, and often hear of others, feeling isolated or downright unloved because there is neither the time nor a sufficiently legitimate purpose to connect across the hall or across the street. It is that increasing vacuum of connecting, one to another or among our families or within our ward family, that calls us increasingly to participate in Relief Society.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for.p5" pid="tSZaNTxYtECsHEggyeOMxA" hash="lnMx_w">Peter gave strong instruction to the Saints of his day which applied to both men and women. May I reference it as it applies particularly to us: “Have fervent charity among yourselves. … Use hospitality one to another without grudging. As every [woman] hath received the gift, even so minister the same one to another, as good stewards of the manifold grace of God” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-pet/4.8-10" class="scriptureRef">1 Pet. 4:8–10</a>). How I would like to transfer the power of that scripture to every Relief Society meeting yet to be held. Would that something could happen every time that would cause each woman present—whether married or single, working at home or away from home, momentarily secure or immediately desperate—to feel her Heavenly Father’s Spirit and her sisters’ unfeigned love and encouragement.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for.p6" pid="yFWyKLIO0kKv1bd9OPzj8w" hash="7ksdOQ">Remember, my sisters: “Charity never faileth.” This is more than our motto. It is our divine commission. As sisters, let us love one another and love our brethren in this great work. Let us show in our charity our faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for.p7" pid="MX8ksTw4ykasrMkjiAyMhQ" hash="TX2jHQ">“Cleave unto charity, which is the greatest of all. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for.p8" pid="GebAanpIPEmEKiP9XJTP1w" hash="wFSlug">“It endureth forever; and whoso is found possessed of it at the last day, it shall be well with [her].</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for.p9" pid="4dcbvzAMf0-epD0zNwI0kw" hash="tUZFCQ">“Wherefore, my beloved [sisters], pray unto the Father with all the energy of heart, that ye may be filled with this love, which he hath bestowed upon all who are true followers of his Son, Jesus Christ” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.46-48" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:46–48</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for.p10" pid="hyrbrtu3EUaV-Den9T0tyw" hash="yyRZxA">The Relief Society was organized by God’s prophet Joseph and has been led and is led today by a prophet so that we may become true followers of Jesus Christ. That is the answer to the question, “Why Relief Society?” That is why we participate and that is what it can do for us: instruct us more perfectly in our covenant obligations and promises to be disciples of our Lord Jesus Christ. Or, as Joseph Smith instructed those first sisters in 1842: “[This] … Society is not only to relieve the poor, but to save souls” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 5:25). What does it mean to save souls? Let me give one example of the many I have witnessed as I have visited among you. A South African sister once told me that when her husband died and she was left to rear their six children, she relied on the teachings of the Bible for direction. She often pondered the meaning of Proverbs 13, verse 24, which is interpreted widely as “spare the rod and spoil the child.” [<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/13.24" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 13:24</a>] When she joined the Church she turned to the Book of Mormon, too, for understanding. There she found mention of another rod, the word of God which leads one along the path to the tree of life. Then she understood that sparing <span class="emphasis">this</span> rod would certainly spoil her children. Thus, she has learned to order her home, to bring the light of the gospel, to save the souls of her children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for.p11" pid="1rsFvsvC7UWsRYSuNm3KwQ" hash="9T_WJQ">I saw Sister Mavimbela again very recently when she received an award at Brigham Young University, and she has enlarged her sphere. In conversation she told me that by participating in her Relief Society in Soweto she has learned to apply its saving ways within her community. Using visiting teaching and welfare principles, such as those described in the Church’s manual <span class="emphasis">Providing in the Lord’s Way,</span> she has supervised more than a thousand children as they learn to garden and raise food for themselves and others. She has also enlisted more than 250 grandmothers in her community to help with the many tasks essential to the temporal and spiritual nurturing of children and the strengthening of families. Sister Mavimbela is saving souls. She is in the same mold as those great women, such as Eliza R. Snow, Phoebe Kimball, and Zina D. H. Young, who began to visit one another in Nauvoo for the purpose of feeding hungry families and shoring up struggling faith in difficult times. This is what Relief Society is for: to make of us women who can nourish body and soul, who can “succor [God’s children] according to their infirmities” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/7.12" class="scriptureRef">Alma 7:12</a>). This is the work our Savior did, and it is the work to which he called us when he ordered this society under the direction of the priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for.p12" pid="XXjinKw7gU-5Yn2ViukQRg" hash="kbwAaw">To speak so simply of Sister Mavimbela’s work can make it sound simple. We know it is not. These are complicated times whether we live in Soweto or San Francisco, Sapporo or São Paulo. It is so complicated in fact that “if possible, they shall deceive the very elect, who are the elect according to the covenant” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-m/1.22" class="scriptureRef">JS—M 1:22</a>). What will make it not possible for his disciples to be deceived is the capacity to discern the voice of truth from among all others that ask for our obedience. The word of God given us in scripture is, indeed, an iron rod which leads us on the path to eternal life. There the truth is spelled out; it can be held on to; it has been tried in the experience of generations. But not all truth brings a long tradition of acceptance with it. It requires us to know it when we see it. The Spirit must witness these things to us, make us recognize them as true—as of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for.p13" pid="v-cOB7iOK0WEGjsOBvrCJg" hash="6Z-GQw">Consider the <span class="emphasis">Savior’s</span> image when he spoke of the necessity of discerning truth. He likens knowing the truth to receiving “living water”; that is, water that is <span class="emphasis">fit</span> to drink: pure, running water. He tells the woman at the well: “If thou knewest the gift of God, and who it is that saith to thee, Give me to drink; thou wouldest have asked of him, and he would have given thee living water” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/4.10" class="scriptureRef">John 4:10</a>). When I think of lifesaving water and of wells, I also think of Hagar (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/21.14-20" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 21:14–20</a>). Hers is a complicated family story. She is forced alone into the wilderness of Beersheba with her young son, Ishmael. In due time the water and bread she has taken with her into the desert are consumed, and thirst and hunger overwhelm her and her little boy. Because she cannot bear to hear the cries of her son, the record tells us that she puts him in a shaded place and goes “a good way off” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/21.16" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 21:16</a>). There, she lifts up her voice and weeps. In response, an angel of God speaks comfort to her and reminds her that she is not forsaken. Then, we are told, “God opened her eyes, and she <span class="emphasis">saw</span> a well of water” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/21.19" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 21:19</a>; emphasis added). We, like Hagar, are required to see “a well of water.” We, like the woman at the well, must ask of the Lord: “Give me this water, that I thirst not” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/4.15" class="scriptureRef">John 4:15</a>). This is the purpose of Relief Society. It teaches us as daughters of God how to see and how to ask for that which we need of the Lord so that we need not thirst again. Remember the Prophet Joseph’s promise to us that through this society we “shall rejoice, and knowledge and intelligence shall flow.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for.p14" pid="XVsgzXtDz0yL9RzJriy4Gg" hash="QQiF9w">We must act so as to receive this promise. It does not come by removing ourselves “a good way off.” Sisters, I ask you to stand close to one another. Love one another, even cherish one another that you may have the Spirit to teach you “the truth of all things” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.5" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:5</a>). Instruct one another. Look with the discernment God has given you through the gift of the Holy Ghost. Listen for the still, small voice. I ask you to seek instruction in the word of God, both as written in the scriptures to prophets of old and as spoken tonight by a living prophet. See the well. Ask for the water that you “thirst not.” Obtain the promises which are held out to you by a loving Father in Heaven through the atonement of his Only Begotten Son, he who promised, “Whosoever drinketh of the water that I shall give [her] shall never thirst; but the water that I shall give [her] shall be in [her] a well of water springing up into everlasting life” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/4.14" class="scriptureRef">John 4:14</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for.p15" pid="GKBKCIohtU-3OIL4S6nqfw" hash="SOcYbw">I testify that this is true, that we are bound together in his church by his priesthood power to be able to build his kingdom on earth and to rejoice in our knowledge of him. And this I say in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/10/what-is-relief-society-for</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/1995-general-relief-society-meeting/1995-09-0030-aileen-h-clyde-64k-eng.mp3" length="6496298" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 1995 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confirmed in Faith</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Now let us rejoice since, as the hymn declares, we are no more strangers. We sing as an expression of our faith in God (particularly tonight it is his daughters who sing), of our knowledge that Christ and His people shall ever be one.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_96911_000_033" doc-version="2" hash="P4sA1Q">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="--xM8S8p_UqwGhN9ce07Gw" hash="qZEv1A">Confirmed in Faith</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="VWAvnpTfDE6iwQafwQSWdQ" hash="LaJxyg">Aileen H. Clyde</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p1" pid="UdgwpLThZkG89fWtg-NdCQ" hash="7rPGTw">Now let us rejoice since, as the hymn declares, we are no more strangers. We sing as an expression of our faith in God (particularly tonight it is his daughters who sing), of our knowledge that Christ and His people shall ever be one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p2" pid="5nFQYGbe80-hQ727lWlNWQ" hash="B2a0Ug">“And righteousness will I send down out of heaven; and truth will I send forth out of the earth, to bear testimony of mine Only Begotten; … and righteousness and truth will I cause to sweep the earth … , to gather out mine elect from the four quarters of the earth, unto a place which I shall prepare, … and it shall be called Zion” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/7.62" class="scriptureRef">Moses 7:62</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p3" pid="kgQHnlBdeUuX9LwLaaf1pw" hash="XZLFyg">While the Zion where all walk with God is not before us yet, the way to Zion through faith on Jesus Christ is before us. We live among evidence of the promise of the scripture that righteousness and truth are in the earth and that Christ has come to do for us what we cannot do for ourselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p4" pid="OidMCttlq02TRsqIMUFYzQ" hash="eVf3Mg">Relief Society women gathered here tonight and organized in many places in the four quarters of the earth are part of the evidence that righteousness and truth are sweeping forward in the world, because of their faith in Jesus Christ. Our Savior goes before us and invites us to a covenant relationship with Him to help us find our way. In <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/15.10" class="scriptureRef">John 15, verse 10</a>, we read, “If ye keep my commandments, ye shall abide in my love; even as I have kept my Father’s commandments, and abide in His love.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p5" pid="DUzrSc7pq0CCi6nV1PIsQQ" hash="U3Lblw">The reciprocal nature of our relationship to God is a basic truth of that relationship. Christ does not withhold His part; and we are here to learn better the ways to give our part. As our Savior knew and returned His Father’s love, He gained the strength to do all that He was commanded. And then came the promise that is ours when we abide in Christ and allow His words to abide in us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p6" pid="hkKeT-AoOUiqNdg0fq5j4w" hash="eXYw_w">“These things have I spoken unto you, that my joy might remain in you, and that your joy might be full.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p7" pid="roQiC-78xEyD9-Iqo0Owpg" hash="PXz03A">“This is my commandment, That ye love one another, as I have loved you” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/15.11-12" class="scriptureRef">John 15:11–12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p8" pid="dV_hh8wCHE-U-4QtigK6mg" hash="9Km0NA">Our Heavenly Father and His Son expect us to rely on each other in relationships of love and trust by following the pattern they have shown. Every provision is made to help us find the necessary spiritual strength. In the Doctrine and Covenants we read:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p9" pid="34r6uHnYOEin8NlLtL5wQw" hash="hZBp8A">“To some it is given by the Holy Ghost to know that Jesus Christ is the Son of God, and that he was crucified for the sins of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p10" pid="96svoI0jokW4HbNTqAnRSA" hash="ZuKVgw">“To others it is given to believe on their words, that they also might have eternal life if they continue faithful” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/46.13-14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 46:13–14</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p11" pid="U5RB__Zv_kGxPapmWfg-nA" hash="FrGawg">We are promised, then, that we grow spiritually as we believe in the words of those who know, those whose faith has produced the capacity to endure and to move forward. Faith is power in us and gives us the ability to do. Many of us have seen examples of such faith in our lives, but often they slip by us quickly. In 1839 Mary Fielding Smith, wife of Hyrum Smith, wrote a letter to her brother Joseph Fielding, and we have it in the record. It frames with clarity the reciprocal nature of our relationships with one another and with God in the ways we are taught in the scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p12" pid="Bxc56GpqJk6M0eWNreTRgw" hash="dOCj8g">“Dear Brother:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p13" pid="uicztpSSV0u4-sGz9NWCMA" hash="rtl1jg">“… You have, I suppose, heard of the imprisonment of my dear husband, with his brother Joseph, Elder Rigdon, and others, who were kept from us nearly six months; and I suppose no one felt the painful effects of their confinement more than myself. I was left in a way that called for the exercise of all the courage and grace I possessed. My husband was taken from me by an armed force, at a time when I needed, in a particular manner, the kindest care and attention of such a friend, instead of which, the care of a large family was suddenly and unexpectedly left upon myself, and, in a few days after, my dear little Joseph F. was added to the number. Shortly after his birth I took a severe cold, which brought on chills and fever; this, together with the anxiety of mind I had to endure, threatened to bring me to the gates of death. I was at least four months entirely unable to take any care either of myself or child; but the Lord was merciful in so ordering things that my dear sister could be with me. Her child was five months old when mine was born; so she had strength given her to nurse them both.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p14" pid="Xop9s25BtkKRpPDjtdhAEg" hash="l3hxHw">“You will also have heard of our being driven, as a people, from the State, [Missouri] and from our homes; this happened during my sickness, and I had to be removed more than two hundred miles, chiefly on my bed. I suffered much on my journey; but in three or four weeks after we arrived in Illinois, I began to amend, and my health is now as good as ever. … We are now living in Commerce, on the bank of the great Mississippi river. The situation is very pleasant; you would be much pleased to see it. How long we may be permitted to enjoy it I know not; but the Lord knows what is best for us. I feel but little concerned about where I am, if I can keep my mind staid upon God; for, you know in this there is perfect peace. I believe the Lord is overruling all things for our good. I suppose our enemies look upon us with astonishment and disappointment” (quoted in Carol Cornwall Madsen, <span class="emphasis">In Their Own Words: Women and the Story of Nauvoo</span> [1994], 98–99).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p15" pid="BoxbCc9j7kaTMD8hkEisTw" hash="fvuNMw">Mary Fielding Smith collected every resource available to her to manage the searing events that filled her daily life. While her moving and articulate letter may be rare, her experience with God isn’t. Today, everywhere I go in the Church I see similar dignity exemplified by women and by men whose trials differ in circumstance but are similar in the courage and grace they require.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p16" pid="MkZhq1it-U2RbwopkvUb_Q" hash="zZyt5w">God’s care for us has caused Him, by revelation, to provide not only the means for our salvation, but he provides for ways we can help each other meet the challenges to that salvation. The Lord’s organization for women is here so we may bring relief to those who need us. Such important work demands our understanding that to God all things are spiritual (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/29.34" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 29:34</a>). As women in the Church, we have knowledge many others lack; consequently we remind ourselves our work is not dedicated to triviality or entertainment. We have all been blessed with the truths we feel when we sing “I Am a Child of God” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 301), but we need to remember in our hearts that our experiences here require us also to be adults of God. Again, the scripture verifies the maturing required of us: “When I was a child, I spake as a child, I understood as a child, I thought as a child: but when I became [an adult], I put away childish things” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/13.11" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 13:11</a>). We do not seek to lose the fresh teachableness of children; we seek to claim steadfastness and the courage to act on our hard-won convictions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p17" pid="kBlo1dkwekW3-WUmRheZhQ" hash="5nHaVQ">We have the opportunity to serve in a time when many among us are lonely or addicted, abused or abandoned, sincerely seeking or full of faith. The ways Relief Society can teach and build are long established, but they have no momentum without the gifts and offerings of individual women day by day. Our external persecutors may be very different from Mary Fielding Smith’s, but they are real. Many feel they are trying, too often in isolation, to survive an avalanche of pressing duties. Some lament their loss of kinship with others or their sense of direction to the future. These feelings, indeed all tribulations, are common to our humanity; but we find there are antidotes as we develop our personal and shared faith and demonstrate our faith by action.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p18" pid="CczzJQdbk0il4_m_JuMHyg" hash="pPvByw">Earlier this year I was greatly moved as I participated in a meeting in Lagos, Nigeria, in a building with spare concrete walls and a heavy, flat tin roof. Relief Society leaders with their priesthood advisers had been counseling together there for more than two hours. We had worked together to better understand the ways that could be employed to give strength to their important callings, to build their faith, and to help conquer the tribulation that surrounded them in that sprawling city.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p19" pid="PR6rT03MaUaJS2UFSr37PQ" hash="BpV6ew">As we finished the closing hymn and said an amen to a heartfelt prayer, a thunderous roar filled the room. It was rain. The deluge on the tin roof made any parting conversation impossible. Water was already coursing through the streets and splashing immediately against the door. Our meetings had been scheduled in the afternoon so that most could be home by dark. Now, as we sat waiting and wordless because of the din, it was obvious they not only faced the heightened dangers of darkness, but they would be thoroughly drenched as they returned to their homes. I thought of Alma as he waded through tribulation (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/8.14-15" class="scriptureRef">Alma 8:14–15</a>), and then I remembered the blessing that came to him. I was struck for the moment with the somewhat similar conditions in Ammonihah for Alma and for our Saints in Lagos, Nigeria. An angel had said to Alma, “Lift up thy head and rejoice, … for thou hast been faithful in keeping the commandments of God from the time which thou receivedst thy first message from him” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/8.15" class="scriptureRef">Alma 8:15</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p20" pid="pscQDrgkLkuSEA5liOVaAA" hash="xoOSLA">There were those in that clattering room who were going forth, as Alma did, to teach and help save others through the power of their faith. When the rain did not yield, they rose, one by one, two or three at a time. We embraced or shook hands solemnly, and they went forth. They were confirmed in their new knowledge that God’s matchless power, His mercy and long-suffering, prevented their being cut off and consigned to endless misery and woe (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/5.12" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 5:12</a>). They had new courage to face, with hope, their immediate journey and their eternal future. They gave me courage too.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith.p21" pid="H85c6UaMVUe5Jxx59f6J4A" hash="fK_ncg">I testify that we belong to God as He is our creator. His Son’s Atonement vouchsafes our eternal life at great cost because of great love. I know these things are true. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1996/10/confirmed-in-faith</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/1996-general-relief-society-meeting/1996-09-0010-aileen-h-clyde-64k-eng.mp3" length="5633642" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 1996 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
