<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Allan F. Packer</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Allan F. Packer.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Allan%20F.%20Packer.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Allan F. Packer.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2009 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2009 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Finding Strength in Challenging Times!</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Having the capacity to receive personal inspiration will be necessary in the coming days.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50015887_000_007" doc-version="2" hash="f6lMtw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="93JpMEYw8U-GaZXrAgpcGA" hash="glyppQ">Finding Strength in Challenging Times!</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Q4-LGjsSnEmf2m-uR_TOEQ" hash="9WMEpg">Elder Allan F. Packer</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="Lga44YFCG0mCjVn-3sS0CA" hash="w7PX3Q">Having the capacity to receive personal inspiration will be necessary in the coming days.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p1" pid="GvlpEn0t-UGdtYDq5F_gQw" hash="H_JMoQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="17"></span>Elder Andersen, we extend our love, blessings, and support as you fill this new calling. Brothers and sisters, individuals and families across the world are challenged by current conditions. While I believe there are serious challenges ahead, I also know it is a wonderful time to be alive, especially for the youth. I see my children and grandchildren having full, satisfying lives even as they have challenges, setbacks, and obstacles to overcome.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p2" pid="5VyXAk2HbUqfPdzBkeAeRQ" hash="neXvVw">These are the days when prophecies are being fulfilled. We live in the dispensation of the fulness of times, which is the time to prepare for the Savior’s return. It is also the time to work out our own salvation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p3" pid="nRdA9gRIUEGydioj6d4ANQ" hash="33L4Zw">When the winds blow and the rains pour, they blow and pour on all. Those who have built their foundations on bedrock rather than sand survive the storms.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> There is a way to build on bedrock by developing a deep personal conversion to the gospel of Jesus Christ and knowing how to receive inspiration. We must know—and know that we know. We must stand spiritually and temporally independent of all worldly creatures.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> This begins by understanding that God the Father is the Father of our spirits and that He loves us, that Jesus Christ is our Redeemer and Savior, and that the Holy Ghost can communicate with our minds and our hearts.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> This is how we receive inspiration. We need to learn how to recognize and apply these promptings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p4" pid="aMqwI6PinE63ruE6Q8wasg" hash="2weIKg">When I was a young man in high school, one of my passions was American football. I played middle linebacker. The coach worked the team hard, teaching us the basics. We practiced until the skills became natural and automatic. During one play against our biggest rival, I had an experience that has helped me over the years. We were on defense. I knew my assigned opponent, and as the play unfolded, he moved to my right into the line of scrimmage. There was a lot of noise from players and fans. I reacted as the coach had taught us and followed my man into the line, not knowing if he had the ball. To my surprise, I felt the ball partially in my hands. I gave it a tug, but my opponent didn’t let go. As we tugged back and forth, amid all the noise I heard a voice yelling, “Packer, tackle him!” That was enough to bring me to my senses, so I dropped him on the spot.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p5" pid="4lCjVnG0HUOHhixVa6xVbQ" hash="XjyVmg">I have wondered how I heard that voice above all the other noise. I had become acquainted with the voice of the coach during the practices, and I had learned to trust it. I knew that what he taught worked.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p6" pid="1XaUl9A_8kCvMLJ1LGMBkw" hash="y7ei-g">We need to be acquainted with the promptings of the Holy Ghost, and we need to practice and apply gospel teachings until they become natural and automatic. These promptings become the foundation of our testimonies. Then our testimonies will keep us happy and safe in troubled times.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p7" pid="Nk1H_GUPJE6N8VAM-4obdA" hash="PDwmQg">Elder Dallin H. Oaks defined a testimony this way: “A testimony of the gospel is a personal witness borne to our souls by the Holy Ghost that certain facts of eternal significance are true and that we know them to be true.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> At another time Elder Oaks said, “Testimony is to know and to feel, conversion is to do and to become.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p8" pid="lV9MYVr34kWymLB-NpWr3w" hash="CeSUIQ">There are several things we can do to develop a deep conversion and learn how to receive divine inspiration. First, we must have a desire. Alma said, “For I know that he granteth unto men according to their desire, whether it be unto death or unto life … according to their wills.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p9" pid="Zdnv_0rRJUyBmNX56nWC5Q" hash="mnas2A">Next, Alma challenged us to experiment on the word: “We will compare the word unto a seed. Now, if ye give <span class="pageBreak" page-number="18"></span>place, that a seed may be planted in your heart, behold, if it be a true seed, or a good seed, if ye do not cast it out by your unbelief, that ye will resist the Spirit of the Lord, behold, it will begin to swell within your breasts; and when you feel these swelling motions, ye will begin to say within yourselves—It must needs be that this is a good seed, or that the word is good, for it beginneth to enlarge my soul; yea, it beginneth to enlighten my understanding, yea, it beginneth to be delicious to me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p10" pid="v1eGol99BEGsAHmXLH9A-g" hash="XiqCCQ">To study and learn is the next step. This includes pondering, which broadens and deepens our testimonies. “But, behold, I say unto you, that you must study it out in your mind; then you must ask me if it be right.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p11" pid="uUhQB_ceN0eWbUD4yzGRdQ" hash="01Xrgw">We can learn how answers come through inspiration. They come as thoughts and feelings to our minds and hearts.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Occasionally answers may come as a burning in the bosom. Elijah taught that answers come as a “still small voice.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> The Lord said, “And if it is right I will cause that your bosom shall burn within you; therefore, you shall feel that it is right.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p12" pid="gsofF7tUpUWr13VP0rLkxw" hash="zQRtAA">Joseph Smith told us to watch for answers by paying attention to the thoughts and feelings that come into our minds. Over time we will learn to recognize these as promptings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p13" pid="GQKw-Y26UkWVe4lja_pp0g" hash="BgMylA">He said: “A person may profit by noticing the first intimation of the spirit of revelation; for instance, when you feel pure intelligence flowing into you, it may give you sudden strokes of ideas, so that by noticing it, you may find it fulfilled the same day or soon; (i.e.) those things that were presented unto your minds by the Spirit of God, will come to pass; and thus by learning the Spirit of God and understanding it, you may grow into the principle of revelation, until you become perfect in Christ Jesus.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p14" pid="3BErypHmjE6ivKki7kA3DA" hash="O7YFJw">Developing this capacity helps us gain testimonies and becomes the means for obtaining additional inspiration in the future.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p15" pid="2RaZSwTtG0SArt2soDjiow" hash="YwQXWg">While testimonies can come as dramatic manifestations, they usually do not. Sometimes people think they need to have an experience like Joseph Smith’s vision before they gain testimonies. If we have unrealistic expectations of how, when, or where answers come, we risk missing the answers which come as quiet, reassuring feelings and thoughts that most often come after our prayers, while we are doing something else. These answers can be equally convincing and powerful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p16" pid="TrNAfRXsjEuNwCS2mYIxKA" hash="1Qk3-g">Over time we will receive answers and learn how inspiration comes. This is something each person learns for himself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p17" pid="qiys_joCakmCoNjnD5V6lA" hash="rUfQ9Q">Next, asking for a testimony of truth opens the window of inspiration. Prayer is the most common and powerful way to invite inspiration. Merely asking a question,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> even in our minds, will start to open the window. The scriptures teach, “Ask, and it shall be given you; seek, and ye shall find; knock, and it shall be opened unto you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p18" pid="vHAcnyGpnEaiaOJISF2lPw" hash="U7mV1A">Jesus also taught us to apply the doctrine in our lives: “If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it be of God, or whether I speak of myself.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p19" pid="Gy-bI7ccJUuifwEvj8TAVA" hash="B4Prjw">In time, a personal witness will come and we will know—and know that we know. We will then be independent of all other worldly things, for “by the power of the Holy Ghost [we] may know the truth of all things”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> which are right<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> and expedient<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> for us. We will receive strength, comfort, and help to make good decisions and act with confidence in troubled times.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p20" pid="CQRZEZ9GzkiEMR8mWlubew" hash="iRYXxA">This witness is not limited to the leaders but is available to all men, women, youth, and even little children. Having the capacity to receive <span class="pageBreak" page-number="19"></span>personal inspiration will be necessary in the coming days.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p21" pid="oXxuzg9BTE6his75Gt9fug" hash="xeQl2A">As a youth I learned that my testimony could grow by fulfilling my priesthood duties. I had a desire to know. I studied and pondered; I prayed for answers. One day while sitting at the sacrament table as a priest, I felt and I knew.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p22" pid="zA1tx52c9Euc0JEc_GZuNA" hash="MEXVtw">This is a great time to be alive! The Lord needs each of us. This is our day; it is our time! From one of our hymns, we read:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="oyYwwhUQeEuQD7boONmedw" hash="IkDYyA">
            <span class="emphasis">Rise up, O men [and I add women] of God!</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="BEiz5ryHJketGbfwBrz_UA" hash="yK9emg">
            <span class="emphasis">Have done with lesser things.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="z8qik8QgW0-X1VwFAU4A3g" hash="CkNciA">
            <span class="emphasis">Give heart and soul and mind and strength</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="_QOFM5Hk3kCvOXmSY4cKdw" hash="10WvZg">
            <span class="emphasis">To serve the King of Kings.</span>
            <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times.p23" pid="AEFO4xNLxUaw1Ycvu6dgmw" hash="09Lpbw">I bear testimony of our Heavenly Father, the Father of our spirits; of Jesus Christ, our Redeemer and Savior; and of the Holy Ghost, who is the means through which we receive divine guidance. I bear testimony that we can personally receive inspiration. May we know the voice through which that inspiration comes, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2009/04/finding-strength-in-challenging-times</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2009-general-conference/2009-04-1050-elder-allan-f-packer-64k-eng.mp3" length="5056048" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2009 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Book</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/10/the-book?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Allan F. Packer discusses how family history and temple work are essential to the Lord's work of salvation and how we can participate.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10991_000_54packer" doc-version="7" hash="ggvO_w">
			
			<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.head1">
				<h1 class="title" pid="S67ZfW3eD06peHXvY0MVhQ" hash="ATSLwg">The Book</h1>
				<div class="byline">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p2" pid="JIe33WdRj0ee74aYNQ_iLQ" hash="vu7FQQ">By Elder Allan F. Packer</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p3" pid="2fozm57qq0mEaXA3jURyWg" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
					<a href="gl://image/?pid=QS0SFcXa40CDNCqS0JjbrA"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255563/8ecf4be9384442fdbc9b8cf44a0627d8/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255563/8ecf4be9384442fdbc9b8cf44a0627d8/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255563/8ecf4be9384442fdbc9b8cf44a0627d8/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x279="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255563/8ecf4be9384442fdbc9b8cf44a0627d8/200x279.jpg" data-src-320x447="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255563/8ecf4be9384442fdbc9b8cf44a0627d8/320x447.jpg" data-src-460x643="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255563/8ecf4be9384442fdbc9b8cf44a0627d8/460x643.jpg" data-src-640x894="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255563/8ecf4be9384442fdbc9b8cf44a0627d8/640x894.jpg" data-src-1024x1431="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255563/8ecf4be9384442fdbc9b8cf44a0627d8/1024x1431.jpg" data-src-2048x2863="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255563/8ecf4be9384442fdbc9b8cf44a0627d8/2048x2863.jpg" data-src-3856x5391="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255563/8ecf4be9384442fdbc9b8cf44a0627d8/3856x5391.jpg" altText="Elder Allan F. Packer" pid="QS0SFcXa40CDNCqS0JjbrA" hash="ypyCxQ"></img></a>
				</div>
				<p class="kicker" pid="yuQJYsBxbUKJS19Bmf_1wQ" hash="VdAPqA">Family history and temple work should be a regular part of our personal worship.</p>
			<p class="authorName" pid="cVNf8Qt6jUmXoUxCJmsV1Q" hash="vu7FQQ1">By Elder Allan F. Packer</p></div>
			<div class="bodyBlock" pid="qTEi_Ash30qXbXAlgDu01A" hash="ih745Q">
				<span class="story">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p5" pid="B97ofNi4E0aTLsltk4AVSA" hash="QKnkPg">As a young 12-year-old Scout, I received a gift of a much-desired addition to my Scouting equipment. It was a hatchet with a heavy leather cover! On the next overnight hike, we arrived in camp after dark, wet and cold from the heavy snow on the trail. All I could think about was building a big roaring fire. I immediately went to work chopping a fallen tree with my new hatchet. As I chopped, I was frustrated because it didn’t seem to be cutting very well. In my frustration, I worked harder. Disappointed, I returned to camp with only a few pieces of wood. By the light of someone else’s fire, I discovered the problem. I hadn’t taken the cover off the hatchet. I can report, however, the cover was chopped to shreds. The lesson: I became distracted with other things.</p>
				</span>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p6" pid="bM66fgQmcUyYDRiQy9LYpA" hash="HSITXg">As we work toward exaltation, we must work on all of the requirements and not become distracted by focusing on one or two requirements or other unrelated things. Seeking the kingdom of God leads to joy and happiness.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> If needed, we must be willing to <span class="emphasis">change.</span> Frequent small corrections are less painful and disruptive than large course corrections.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p7" pid="MDIOkxw9kkSlbb5zCvxYTA" hash="vN5p_w">Not long ago, Sister Packer and I traveled to several foreign countries. We prepared our passports and other documents. We obtained the shots, medical exams, visas, and stamps. As we arrived, our documents were inspected, and when all the requirements were met, we were allowed to enter.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p8" pid="70W_Xrtas0eFYBUcFr5F1Q" hash="CSeeUQ">Qualifying for exaltation is like entering another country. We must each obtain our spiritual passport. We do not <span class="emphasis">set</span> the requirements, but, individually, we must meet all of them. The plan of salvation contains all of the doctrines, laws, commandments, and ordinances needed for <span class="emphasis">all</span> to qualify for exaltation.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Then, “through the Atonement of [Jesus] Christ, all mankind may be saved.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> The Church helps but cannot do it for us. Qualifying for exaltation becomes a quest of a lifetime.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p9" pid="lqsjTifOi0ilR0UtEk1_9Q" hash="UnGYtA">Christ organized His Church to help us. He has called 15 men we sustain as prophets, seers, and revelators to guide the Church and to teach the people. The First Presidency<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> and the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> are of equal power and authority,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> with the senior Apostle designated as the President of the Church. The Seventy are called to assist.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> The leaders did not set the requirements for exaltation. God did! These leaders are called to teach, expound, exhort, and even <span class="emphasis">warn</span> so that we stay on course.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p10" pid="lU7IbnK2gEeqaISV81djiQ" hash="Q7hb8A">As explained in the Church handbook: “In fulfilling its purpose to help individuals and families qualify for exaltation, the Church focuses on divinely appointed responsibilities. These include helping members live the gospel of Jesus Christ, gathering Israel through missionary work, caring for the poor and needy, and enabling the salvation of the dead by building temples and performing vicarious ordinances.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> These four focuses and all other laws, commandments, and ordinances are required and not optional. Through the Atonement of Jesus Christ and by doing each of these, we are adding required stamps to our spiritual passports.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p11" pid="Eyhj71d5I0Cwm1-yK1hU8w" hash="dDbvNA">During this conference we are being taught about changes that will help us all be better prepared.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p12" pid="Pv-6vH7jUE2LiL_KAFV_Qg" hash="jNKS7A">The family is the center of the plan of salvation and perhaps why it is also called the “great plan of happiness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> President Boyd K. Packer has said, “The ultimate end of all activity in the Church is that a man and his wife and their children can be happy at home.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p13" pid="YE2pBrGjrkylf5rfDzJRJA" hash="K1OTBQ">President Spencer W. Kimball said, “Our success, individually and as a Church, will largely be determined by how faithfully we focus on living the gospel in the home.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Temple and family history work is part of living the gospel at home. It should be a family activity far more than a Church activity.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p14" pid="z-8Wr2PhY0u96O0kCOnwPw" hash="_G0fmQ">There has been a renewed emphasis on family history and temple work from the First Presidency and the Quorum of the Twelve.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> Your response to this emphasis will increase your individual and family joy and happiness.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p15" pid="t1BPc6AMDEmcrayK-dtkjA" hash="f46c3A">From the Doctrine and Covenants we read: “The great day of the Lord is at hand. … Let us, therefore, as a church and a people, and as Latter-day Saints, offer unto the Lord an offering in righteousness; and let us present in his holy temple, … a book containing the records of our dead, which shall be worthy of all acceptation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p16" pid="Tz7sIQvVDkKxLVzRTaOrXw" hash="r24LKQ">This “book” will be prepared using the records of names and ordinances in the Church’s FamilyTree database.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p17" pid="OrMemZ48lE6K-d74AhrOeA" hash="2Iz-LA">I am checking and adding records to this database because I want the names of all those I love to be in the book. Don’t you?</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p18" pid="BKWXWqObMEuXAt52Y5c_Pw" hash="O536gQ"><a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/128.18" class="scriptureRef">Doctrine and Covenants section 128</a> says, “For we without [our ancestors] cannot be made perfect; neither can they without us be made perfect.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p19" pid="vn8v_8q6K0GCw9SIU6UJzg" hash="4TJ7dA">Family history is more than genealogy, rules, names, dates, and places. It is more than a focus on the past. Family history also includes the present as we create our own history. It includes the future as we shape future history through our descendants. A young mother, for example, sharing her family stories and pictures with her children is doing family history work.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p20" pid="Zr2NLKedMkex9Mk9XIVYeg" hash="IlKHVg">Like partaking of the sacrament, attending meetings, reading the scriptures, and saying personal prayers, doing family history and temple work should be a regular part of our personal worship. The response of our youth and others to prophetic invitations has been inspiring and proves this work <span class="emphasis">can and should</span> be done by <span class="emphasis">all</span> members at <span class="emphasis">any</span> age.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p21" pid="ZZYJnuIDNEOdqE-fzeWcvQ" hash="9U_3gg">As Elder Quentin L. Cook explained, “We [now] have the doctrine, the temples, and the technology.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> Doing the work now is much easier and limited only by the number of members who make this a priority. The work still takes time and sacrifice, but <span class="emphasis">all</span> can do it, and with relative ease compared to just a few years ago.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p22" pid="421GbHfW8UWAd96Sihbp9w" hash="qpNA0A">To assist members, the Church has gathered records and provided tools so that much of the work can be done in our own homes or in the ward buildings and the temple. Most obstacles have been removed. <span class="emphasis">Whatever</span> your past perception, it is different now!</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p23" pid="rpE9azLxc0eeO71dQkXjuA" hash="eqR_Lg">However, there is one obstacle the Church cannot remove. It is an individual’s hesitation to do the work. All it requires is a decision and a little effort. It does not require a large block of time. Just a little time on a consistent basis will yield the joy of the work. Make the decision to take a step, to learn and ask others to help you. They will! The names you find and take to the temple will become the records for “the book.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p24" pid="h_rVToKgs06GO_oaAzk4JA" hash="rtgsEA">Even with the dramatic increase in member participation, we find that relatively few members of the Church are regularly involved in finding and doing temple ordinances for their family.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span><span class="emphasis"> This calls for a change in our priorities.</span> Don’t fight the change, embrace it! Change is part of the great plan of happiness.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p25" pid="00jAPw_uqkqrfQCGo7IUaA" hash="2mIGLg">This work needs to be done, not for the benefit of the Church but for our dead and for ourselves. We and our deceased ancestors need the stamps in our spiritual passports.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p26" pid="H8-YDZ85wEqqFrteE8jUIQ" hash="xnGdig">The “welding together”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> of our families across generations can occur only in the temples through the sealing ordinances. The steps are simple: <span class="emphasis">just find a name and take it to the temple.</span> Over time you will be able to help others do it also.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p27" pid="aBZuO63u2kKI7gJOz8aBEw" hash="_eHNoQ">With few exceptions, everyone—<span class="emphasis">everyone</span>—can do this!</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p28" pid="KFFmWXsdYEKiDUib038cvw" hash="36pNTg">There are tangible blessings which attend this work. Many parents and leaders are concerned about current world conditions and the impact on families and youth.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p29" pid="_JFStCbXKEeUvFEVvfr7EA" hash="xIGXew">Elder David A. Bednar has promised: “I invite the young people of the Church to learn about and experience the Spirit of Elijah. … I promise [that] you will be protected against the intensifying influence of the adversary. As you participate in and love this holy work, you will be safeguarded in your youth and throughout your lives.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p30" pid="WsNRo5jnqkqiByMK6wwjKg" hash="LnQTyQ">Brothers and sisters, it’s time to take the cover off our hatchets and go to work. We must not sacrifice our exaltation or that of our families for less important interests.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p31" pid="8QOufxwGa0q591i5ei8YxQ" hash="yzXHxg">This is the work of God, to be done by members and nonmembers alike, young and old, male and female.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p32" pid="pNNf9eVSQ0KZg1p3HZNiiQ" hash="S68SZQ">I close quoting the first verse of hymn 324, changing one word:</p>
				<div class="poetry">
					<div class="stanza">
						<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p" pid="aDViJnbD3UOLfpnBFeX1ug" hash="CvVtIw">Rise up, O [Saints] of God!</p>
						<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p" pid="ceZnyZz6LEytcVkNz1uB9Q" hash="yK9emg">Have done with lesser things.</p>
						<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p" pid="XIWVajtpjEukWqCSB-5TzQ" hash="CkNciA">Give heart and soul and mind and strength</p>
						<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p" pid="9FyalVFzSECB503_CESiFA" hash="s5cFfg">To serve the King of Kings.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span></p>
					</div>
				</div>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-book.p37" pid="c_5xBIoYW0yLFmASsnKNhw" hash="ooYKXQ">Jesus Christ is the King! I testify of Him in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div>
			
		</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/10/the-book</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2014-general-conference/2014-10-5040-elder-allan-f-packer-64k-eng.mp3" length="5588795" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
