<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Alvin R. Dyer</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Alvin R. Dyer.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Alvin%20R.%20Dyer.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Alvin R. Dyer.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1971 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Ye Shall Not Fear</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear?lang=eng</link>
      <description>On the day of Pentecost in Old Jerusalem, the apostle Peter declared unto the people that Jesus Christ, who had before been preached unto them, would come again, but that that day would be delayed until the restitution or restoration of all things, a</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03006_000_6020" doc-version="2" hash="BIg4OA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="zS8tyTuqNUS1Hi6dg0aALw" hash="4Au7Hg">Ye Shall Not Fear</h1><p class="authorName" guid="9fa5d73e-c6f7-450e-99ff-a976dcd27e7d" pid="LenhqhJQJUmybiSL4p8P1w" hash="pk737w">Alvin R. Dyer</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="075ae696-1489-4fbd-90bb-6135ad2162c9">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-31ec.jpg" alt="Elder Alvin R. Dyer" guid="1af8d869-9e97-45a1-9c02-de4e6bb2d088" pid="8LkU6EzGu06jhv8e4IM26g" hash="nXjfNg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p1" guid="76ea65d4-0f88-4224-9bf8-fa75c61c76fe" pid="H67orjJE20WwwgeoNnAr4Q" hash="QTUvpQ">On the day of Pentecost in Old Jerusalem, the apostle Peter declared unto the people that Jesus Christ, who had before been preached unto them, would come again, but that that day would be delayed until the restitution or restoration of all things, and that this event had been promised since the world began. The organization of the Church of Christ, known as The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints in this day and age, is part of that restoration.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p2" guid="22d6dcee-322f-4c73-9c30-373efea0425f" pid="87ynnMpx10-VEkpGhngK-A" hash="BLcQFA">On this day we reaffirm our conviction and testimony of that which transpired in the organization of the Church of Christ in this dispensation 141 years ago today. Upon that occasion, unto those who were assembled, the Lord referred to that which had already been accomplished in the restoration of the gospel through his servant Joseph Smith. Here are his words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p3" guid="d6be03f2-e179-4116-aab0-6fdae862d740" pid="k-tplwQ5eEi37d-TQeYV0g" hash="Um7Vlw">“And gave unto him commandments which inspired him;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p4" guid="82ac54e5-6e90-4dd1-a186-bf135d88a4ed" pid="8T4_kGzbxEu96xEuZtEJ3Q" hash="LCGjIw">“And gave him power from on high, by the means which were before prepared, to translate the Book of Mormon;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p5" guid="75f3c322-0479-4322-b587-9970557ce871" pid="v1enY5gfCUCed9c8W2rrMQ" hash="4NuWFw">“Which contains a record of a fallen people, and the fulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ to the Gentiles and to the Jews also;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p6" guid="3ef2c6b0-3665-4d62-94b2-acfd61500008" pid="4dS7KBvcv0StXh0gJGEWkQ" hash="u2SjXg">“Which was given by inspiration, and is confirmed to others by the ministering of angels, and is declared unto the world by them—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p7" guid="6130d7cd-3d07-4355-9d44-5615bc06c632" pid="QWHzfxINSUGEzf4JwckO1A" hash="ab2O2A">“Proving to the world that the holy scriptures are true, and that God does inspire men and call them to his holy work in this age and generation, as well as in generations of old;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p8" guid="29278ff2-15b9-46f3-8748-462a6896f2ba" pid="k-81hI_ulEOQjOkBIXFw5A" hash="J04JLA">“Thereby showing that he is the same God yesterday, today, and forever. Amen.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.7-12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:7–12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p9" guid="da599875-6d19-43d6-b387-ae594fc8c0d9" pid="bQyLOr4KIk2LVYfyEAS5Kg" hash="9e0DWg">The Church of Christ has been restored in this the last of all dispensations, which is called by the Lord “the dispensation of the fulness of times.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/112.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 112</a>.) When completed, it will produce a welding together of all former dispensations, with their keys, principals, and intelligence down from the time of Adam. Being the last, this dispensation presages the doctrines of last things in the preparation for the second coming of Christ the Lord and of the end of the mortal existence of man upon the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p10" guid="386399c7-e84b-49fa-a856-80a937a0e520" pid="mMuN-12fgkq2susP_XbNgg" hash="gH5S9g">The question of the nearness of the second coming of the Son of Man rests upon many in our present day. In pondering the question I have often thought of three things. The first is observed in these words of the Lord: “But of that day, and hour, no one knoweth; no, not the angels of God in heaven, but my Father only.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-m/1.40" class="scriptureRef">JS—M 1:40</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p11" guid="46742772-78fb-4549-9003-ea49b754b700" pid="4qhPc4TivEuDZeBavSXcHw" hash="chcztg">There are signs, however, which indicate the nearness of this great event. For instance, and secondly, living in the last dispensation; we must be aware of the fact that there will not be another. It follows that all that God has intended for the redemption and salvation of man upon the earth through the gospel plan will culminate in this dispensation. Actually, the Lord identifies this present day, in particular, as a time of preparation. Here is the instruction he gave by revelation in the early days of the Church:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p12" guid="255fd29a-5174-4a7e-a15f-39f514a53a14" pid="J1BATE44ukqcgVtT9kmTjA" hash="cv_XeQ">“Pray unto the Lord, call upon his holy name, make known his wonderful works among the people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p13" guid="cf84e77e-f4de-4766-939b-cb1b15420026" pid="8aNa1LyFLEa6i5rh_aM61w" hash="5_jrkQ">“Call upon the Lord, that his kingdom may go forth upon the earth, that the inhabitants thereof may receive it, and be prepared for the days to come, in the which the Son of Man shall come down in heaven, clothed in the brightness of his glory, to meet the kingdom of God which is set up on the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p14" guid="e45da328-4e01-4d32-9343-01d6e998bffc" pid="NWRF8Wkvhkm6LFVll7l4Tg" hash="-H6PyQ">“Wherefore, may the kingdom of God go forth, that the kingdom of heaven may come, that thou, O God, mayest be glorified in heaven so on earth, that thine enemies may be subdued; for thine is the honor, power and glory, forever and ever. Amen.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/65.4-6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 65:4–6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p15" guid="f5d6de82-cb9f-41b5-8a40-e27c32caff0d" pid="1-9X-s_ckE-hH_sej0dfoA" hash="YBpjXQ">The culmination of this dispensation in the sequence of the Lord’s time will see the glorious coming of the Son of Man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p16" guid="77e89656-20ae-4b62-9a4e-ee0cafbde996" pid="NSDKr5_BdkmvWpFwu5V1fA" hash="3OHuCg">The third condition which I often ponder concerns the day of the gentile, which day is now, wherein the gospel is being taken to the gentile nations of the earth, that they may, if obedient to the call, come in and be numbered with the house of Israel. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/13.title" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 13, 14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p17" guid="1865473c-2e18-4ca0-a0c1-c7a225758b9a" pid="-4KOZMRlD0yeATGBnn0z7g" hash="qKzhEA">The Lord, in a revelation to Joseph Smith, related this period to the nearness of his second coming. I quote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p18" guid="94392597-a3fc-4047-8aa8-6870ed4777ca" pid="qB69vmU9rEqBG0-9ud_xFQ" hash="Ao3QoA">“And when the times of the Gentiles is come in, a light shall break forth among them that sit in darkness, and it shall be the fulness of my gospel.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/45.28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 45:28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p19" guid="b70b8059-febd-49c5-9392-72efe2adbe77" pid="0ZL_mPjJq0i12Qu9s0v7hw" hash="rok6ZA">But there will be many among them who will not receive it. Of these the revelation continues:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p20" guid="2cfe2c9b-ed80-449d-8c60-d5dfc1d2c6f9" pid="MZJWqQUT-0iuDLeR9PUOyA" hash="ECoR9w">“But they receive it not; for they perceive not the light, and they turn their hearts from me because of the precepts of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/45.29" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 45:29</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p21" guid="999af713-2c2d-416c-b3dc-37d6d0372e10" pid="BFMTj6KhgEa5i-A5xgWupQ" hash="ffSj3Q">But as to the identification of the time that the gospel is taken to the gentiles, I quote from the same revelation:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p22" guid="5bf15b05-710c-4a46-86f9-f96711e11107" pid="9m2Fy3hI_kCcPsqDIApNNA" hash="T8eYtA">“And when the light shall begin to break forth, it shall be with them like unto a parable which I will show you—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p23" guid="7999e70d-1332-4099-a139-1814beb2bd68" pid="D4q8QT3QXku4rh029y05nA" hash="pE3xwg">“Ye look and behold the fig-trees, and ye see them with your eyes, and ye say when they begin to shoot forth, and their leaves are yet tender, that summer is now nigh at hand;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p24" guid="423ab080-28b9-4c34-921c-19f91ad6be77" pid="pn6dq5zDWEif9MlSnakmnQ" hash="1WRfQg">“Even so it shall be in that day when they shall see all these things, then shall they know that the hour is nigh.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/45.36-38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 45:36–38</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p25" guid="66f5312a-3fca-4eb5-8d02-36a796586bbf" pid="Qlgy8snuSU68iQBKg0ghrg" hash="lm72Wg">The turbulent and awesome conditions of the last days of mortal existence, some of which we now observe, have been spoken of by many of the prophets. The Lord’s remarks about these days are most direct, which he gave when asked these words by his disciples:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p26" guid="140d90db-03ee-498d-bc31-e9eff7263348" pid="2_urhyqwJ0qOwzhQDiS0FQ" hash="ArMkyA">“… Tell us when shall these things be which thou hast said concerning the destruction of the temple, and the Jews; and what is the sign of thy coming, and of the end of the world. …” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-m/1.4" class="scriptureRef">JS—M 1:4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p27" guid="42b9b98a-338c-4be0-aa5c-a0b37c7cfabe" pid="tCHkbTSBNEC8CEZ8-8ibdA" hash="FGyWVg">He gave them specific answers as to what would happen to the Jews and then gave attention to the conditions of the last days. Here are his words, in part:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p28" guid="5ebf634e-5845-459d-bc48-cfffc75ff0f1" pid="PxPKZOoQl0aZOMMF6vnOcw" hash="kR3zOQ">“And they shall hear of wars, and rumors of wars.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p29" guid="c009431d-5a68-490b-b89c-d57fbbbf3fa1" pid="L-gPNS6NekOdVl7AdcUGdA" hash="hjEMcQ">“Behold I speak for mine elect’s sake; for nation shall rise against nation, and kingdom against kingdom; there shall be famines, and pestilences, and earthquakes, in divers places.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p30" guid="b31bb034-1951-4467-ada7-9d9565802039" pid="sfsUG68nOkyFeyp3akoikg" hash="vlT0Fg">“And again, because iniquity shall abound, the love of many shall wax cold; but he that shall not be overcome, the same shall be saved.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p31" guid="f5426ab4-c6d1-4282-8b24-dd1b9ce82a7b" pid="0ECrc_LZ9k6jL11oIikrMw" hash="0pdAvw">“And again, this Gospel of the Kingdom shall be preached in all the world, for a witness unto all nations, and then shall the end come, or the destruction of the wicked.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-m/1.28-31" class="scriptureRef">JS—M 1:28–31</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p32" guid="3301017c-cd8e-418d-90b4-33bf8612b59e" pid="-rQi60JMIkSy1gheMg1Duw" hash="RFljLg">By way of assurance and hope, to build strength in the hearts of the Saints, the Lord has given this counsel by revelation, with which I close my remarks:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p33" guid="24c2bf8a-b403-4845-b7c4-15283e57d484" pid="Z8Pi02hpD0uP5C-z9naPng" hash="nX4MgQ">“… I say unto you, be one; and if ye are not one ye are not mine.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p34" guid="dcb08568-f69b-4e97-8c81-9cbe166cd1a9" pid="KySugC7Fh0aLURABwBa-tg" hash="r4kf0w">“And again, I say unto you that the enemy in the secret chambers seeketh your lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p35" guid="79b59f21-a343-46d9-9e7e-f5d5ecd5d40c" pid="k8zuYOldiEKL6Jr7JpH7fQ" hash="9ZCmGg">“Ye hear of wars in far countries, and you say that there will soon be great wars in far countries, but ye know not the hearts of man in your own land.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p36" guid="bc469154-03af-4462-8170-fc2abdfd549b" pid="vaLoVhp1WUGx_PBHMILHGw" hash="AziAVQ">“I tell you these things because of your prayers; wherefore, treasure up wisdom in your bosoms, lest the wickedness of men reveal these things unto you by their wickedness, in a manner which shall speak in your ears with a voice louder than that which shall shake the earth; but if ye are prepared ye shall not fear.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.28-30" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:28–30</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p37" guid="832362fc-63b2-4ecb-acc8-063a44b90910" pid="rYSi7AuPo0WObp84tx3QlQ" hash="2r-y5g">Ye shall not fear, for as the Lord said upon another occasion, the gathering and the faithfulness of the Saints is for a refuge against the awesome conditions which we must face. The Lord has given to us the pattern in all things, that we may not be deceived, for Satan is abroad in the land and he goeth forth deceiving the nations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear.p38" guid="c1346d5e-bbf1-4465-8341-2280c38f4b40" pid="hftrVXbNk0GnUlKGlJ9kww" hash="ITT4CA">I know, my brethren and sisters, that God lives. I know that Jesus is the Christ. I know that the message of the restoration is true, and if we are faithful, we need not fear that which must come about. I say this in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/04/ye-shall-not-fear</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1971-general-conference/1971-04-6050-elder-alvin-r-dyer-64k-eng.mp3" length="5384858" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1971 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Nobility of Man in Choosing Good Over Evil</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I feel honored this morning, my brothers and sisters, to be in the presence of the First Presidency of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and my fellow associates in the cause of Jesus the Master. This vast congregation is also most humb</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03012_000_6040" doc-version="2" hash="OOmURQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="HmF4xTVIHEGcB14oxOa1vw" hash="qdACXg">The Nobility of Man in Choosing Good Over Evil</h1><p class="authorName" guid="9fa5d73e-c6f7-450e-99ff-a976dcd27e7d" pid="pxR8o4byVE2f81HL4Rtk0Q" hash="pk737w">Alvin R. Dyer</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="8994d81f-0a4c-47c1-914f-97b8fd781d68">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-31ec.jpg" alt="Conference photo" guid="a934f886-3f6a-40e5-868e-0d9106045be7" pid="KXY4wCsyXkaJ5dVs-6LpMg" hash="nXjfNg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p1" guid="94cadf61-3ec6-4210-8906-751ccd7aa230" pid="5sq47JlR6EuNQx1cQFxVAA" hash="G4us9w">I feel honored this morning, my brothers and sisters, to be in the presence of the First Presidency of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and my fellow associates in the cause of Jesus the Master. This vast congregation is also most humbling. I have sought the inspiration of the Spirit in the few thoughts I have prepared.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p2" guid="20d7fb56-0c28-42be-a89a-90e01a2b5b41" pid="Yfjrttu_FkyEE6BGgR_hxQ" hash="YbRoVA">Men seek for a phrase or a slogan to motivate and give impetus to action under certain conditions. History refers to such statements as, “Give me liberty, or give me death!” or “I have not yet begun to fight,” and “Surrender? Never! We will die first.” Modern slogans have also had their effect, such as “V” for victory, and the peace and freedom symbols of crowds of demonstrators.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p3" guid="a5c50b0d-bec0-44c1-aba9-3bb24c79f455" pid="Pz4fKDQ4O0afX1lomthAHw" hash="kv6F7Q">Formulas for living—how to attain a peaceful world civilization—are common today, as exponents of opposing ideologies hurl their challenges. Men are constantly seeking for an answer to an easier and better way of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p4" guid="852a649b-ea54-4150-ac15-5dad0ce4151e" pid="51cTzuedAEKEDur3Ysuaig" hash="_exyjA">Be that as it may, concerning slogans as an answer to the problem, I am not prepared to say; but for a realistic and productive life, the Prophet Joseph Smith gives the following statements, which might well be a panacea for our troubles:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p5" guid="32a66d15-0baa-4dd4-91bf-1875a7c78b34" pid="eqwmhafV6UOeHWxhfEzmJg" hash="jtHRcw">“Cease to be idle; cease to be unclean; cease to find fault one with another; cease to sleep longer than is needful; retire to thy bed early, that ye may not be weary; arise early, that your bodies and your minds may be invigorated.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.124" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:124</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p6" guid="4eb6b775-d47d-4b70-aeed-2ff04d6310a8" pid="QFgQ_rLg7UOYUwu2K1MM3w" hash="2h-7EA">This is a very controversial subject, with many different ideas. I once heard of a man by the name of Wilson who slept so much that his friends nicknamed him “Rip Van Wilson.” He said, “I don’t sleep long. I just sleep slow.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p7" guid="afc1a490-abeb-40ea-9f7d-c6bf4dba4e79" pid="g3wvY3M-WE-dWoqPmmhwpQ" hash="QsLEzQ">A great thinker of our modern day supports the statement of the Lord concerning idleness, for said he:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p8" guid="2df8a972-3e33-4c29-bf03-0768b7ae5513" pid="HLj7NxJJb0Gxfmj62RWPGg" hash="Veq27A">“When a man shuns effort, he is in no position to resist temptation. So, through all the ages, idleness has been known as the parent of all the vices. … The dryrot of ennui, the vague self-disgust of those who cannot ‘deal with time,’ is the natural result of idleness. … The indolent ennui of the hopelessly rich and the indolent misery of the helplessly poor have this much in common. … ‘Life drives him hard’ who has nothing in the world to do.” (David Starr Jordan, <span class="emphasis">The Strength of Being Clean </span>[New York and Boston: H.M. Caldwell Co., 1900], pp. 18–19.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p9" guid="1d5ca192-f104-449e-9a1f-0966406ca5d9" pid="lTAm_b99vUmLHzsOwz-B3g" hash="rAyhMA">Concerning chastity and cleanliness, as associated with righteous dominion, the Lord gave this direction:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p10" guid="396e3301-f2c3-4359-a69c-f9dd45061e69" pid="XnLTM80ay0WMoMJIYoPj-Q" hash="mG0s4Q">“… let virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly; then shall thy confidence wax strong in the presence of God; and the doctrine of the priesthood shall distil upon thy soul as the dews from heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p11" guid="1c712c68-27b4-4b27-94ae-be6b18536906" pid="Fu-MY7x14kyKn4lq_scOCg" hash="KnSnqA">“The Holy Ghost shall be thy constant companion, and thy scepter an unchanging scepter of righteousness and truth; and thy dominion shall be an everlasting dominion, and without compulsory means it shall flow unto thee forever and ever.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.45-46" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:45–46</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p12" guid="c080a938-2ad8-48b2-84f6-0a4625a83288" pid="-dOIyataQUmA_1M69lVBTw" hash="V96Ahg">Concerning our fellowman and our attitude toward him, the Prophet Joseph Smith gave this purposeful thought:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p13" guid="b86c09eb-82de-4b75-ae8d-5d2f7d00d092" pid="nTJdC-_3d0eEuAi1VBffdg" hash="dYQ7Jw">“And let every man esteem his brother as himself, and practise virtue and holiness before me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p14" guid="5a33cb7a-60f8-4fda-8972-9db33f4b5004" pid="6Vw4p3NiUkuhlmdLMZ9-7A" hash="LQHh4w">“And again I say unto you, let every man esteem his brother as himself.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.24-25" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:24–25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p15" guid="be414088-defe-48f1-9a8e-fa207969a28b" pid="Or9vrGfUXkysN1lsT3mWlg" hash="hKRrVg">For a man to seek ascendance over another man by the suppressing of his rights is not virtuous and would not tie in with the words of the Master, who said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p16" guid="b5d148d6-de94-4a51-b16c-002eee5dc9ee" pid="cqx82JT8tkKwlRQulIXGaQ" hash="-QETEw">“Therefore all things whatsoever ye would that men should do to you, do ye even so to them: for this is the law and the prophets.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.12" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 7:12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p17" guid="3869d8c1-397d-4103-9075-37bd61e6fa84" pid="9YBxkdVBmEqovNfie7m8AA" hash="_iYhmA">As to sleep and rest, the Prophet Joseph Smith, in saying “Cease to sleep longer than is needful,” does not mean, as Dr. John A. Widtsoe states it, that “one should sleep a certain minimum number of hours. … Nine hours is a minimum for some adults, while others seem to keep healthy on seven or less.” (<span class="emphasis">The Word of Wisdom </span>[Deseret Book Co., 1938], p. 231.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p18" guid="2ddcf3ed-abf0-4622-98b5-dff996bc6d39" pid="iFEN23rjvEa9ApZQl0TRfg" hash="kmdBAg">Authorities on child nutrition insist that many undernourished children are lacking not good food but enough sleep. Perhaps the late TV shows are taking a toll in this regard.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p19" guid="603e52f0-097b-41ba-8ba6-cc84052a4a9a" pid="skTWMiLT7UG69E6Mh6BJjw" hash="FVDT1g">What I believe that the Prophet is saying about more sleep than is needful concerns the individual who goes far beyond the need, developing slothful and lazy habits, which deaden the senses and become a retarder of accomplishment. To overcome these things in life requires discipline and restraint.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p20" guid="083d8659-4450-41e4-8291-00f6ad3c319c" pid="5NjN3FBxkk-c4tBn8BsBTQ" hash="uedMCA">Soon after Adam and Eve, our first earthly parents, were driven from the Garden of Eden because of their yielding to temptation, they came to know the difference between right and wrong and good and evil, for thus the Lord declared: “… Behold, the man is become as one of us, to know good and evil. …” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/3.22" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 3:22</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p21" guid="42144afe-e6b1-4ada-8740-4f755e34f447" pid="mCn3b3R7rUKT8_CbpNebtw" hash="na-l3A">Without a knowledge of good and evil, the divine principle of agency would be ineffectual. The application of this law, while serving to elevate man, can also condemn him. For that in which we participate, whether it is good or evil, either defiles or exalts us. Concerning this, the Master has said: “There is nothing from without a man, that entering into him can defile him: but the things which come out of him, those are they that defile the man.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/7.15" class="scriptureRef">Mark 7:15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p22" guid="0864c85c-919e-4695-8c79-7dab3eccd83e" pid="isGID2m0qESqQ0kM-SO6Sg" hash="Pvl7xw">There is weakness in the thought that one can indulge heavily in both evil and good things at the same time. Many centuries ago Jesus said that “man cannot serve two masters,” he will either love one and despise the other or hate the one and love the other. The apostle James emphasized the importance of constantly choosing right over wrong. To those who attempt an allegiance to both right and wrong, he declared: “A double minded man is unstable in all his ways.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.8" class="scriptureRef">James 1:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p23" guid="1b277887-ee4d-487a-a7fe-358e710c0b2a" pid="iRu7wVRAR0adhTnraZbpAA" hash="-U3B8Q">Man is the sum result of what he thinks and does. Habit is the instrument that molds his character and makes of him essentially what he is. Habit can become a monster to tarnish and destroy, yet proper behavioral traits can bring lasting joy and achievement. To say no at the right time and then stand by it is the first element of success.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p24" guid="2526faff-8f0a-46f8-89ff-ab828b8bb52f" pid="7CXNqn0z10qDCgbbvYTn3Q" hash="NyhmWg">The effect that both good and bad habits have on our lives is all too real to be ignored. Bad habits that violate the commandments of physical health (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/89.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 89</a>) and of moral behavior (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121</a>), given by revelation to the Prophet Joseph Smith many years ago, will threaten and destroy all opportunities for real happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p25" guid="fa4a5121-d0d2-4902-aed1-bf748e0c2b16" pid="CZUNPzy1m0mKA8XwTmLKpg" hash="HKlDLQ">The experience of countless families, the demonstration of crowded hospitals, treating pitiful cases caused by drug addiction in its many forms, such as alcohol, tobacco, the use of capsules, and injections of a high and stimulating nature, are straining the stability of our present civilization.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p26" guid="d70322c7-b316-4268-bcec-f98b76ea6b03" pid="QibQBUuZMUKX7TQSMfd2ig" hash="6FMSIA">Sicknesses such as these, which sometimes induce improper and wrongful habits, should, of course, be treated with modern techniques. It is nevertheless true, however, that all too often that which we are unwilling to cope with, and which otherwise could be controlled by personal restraint, is regarded in our modern way of thinking as a form of sickness, and therefore the indulger is led to believe that he is free of moral obligation. Where such is the case, where one is led to believe that he can excuse injurious acts of indulgence upon the basis that what he does is the result of a sickness and that he is really not to blame, the psychological effect is most devastating and in reality is a compounding of the wrongful indulgence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p27" guid="ea4f86ac-2d21-48fd-83d5-febed40dd77d" pid="pogD5Uj5YUG7c0W0yPGEKg" hash="qKTsCg">The practice of restraint is a necessary attribute of every gentle and good man. Women without it become coarse and unrefined. To curb the appetites and passions, to screen wisely the thoughts that are permitted to enter our minds, to avoid the habit that does not produce the spiritual and abundant life, are experiences of life to be concerned with if the crown of achievement and the nobility of good character are to be possessed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p28" guid="46991d4b-f3be-42cc-98e6-70a2f2bcc78d" pid="eyfQvcgnDkSULu7nXZTjjg" hash="SKFOUA">Choosing good over evil and right over wrong is the crowning achievement of life, and in so doing man becomes the masterpiece of the Creator and fulfills the basic purposes of his mortal probation. An ancient prophet speaks of it in this way: “… he that ruleth his spirit [is greater] than he that taketh a city.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/16.32" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 16:32</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p29" guid="82c4dd07-73ff-40e4-bd35-ed747117fabb" pid="NNOvvINuFEWdPEg8uMvCRA" hash="85XedA">Among the last words spoken unto the beloved apostle John, while in vision on the Isle of Patmos, are these: “He that overcometh shall inherit all things; and I will be his God, and he shall be my son.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rev/21.7" class="scriptureRef">Rev. 21:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p30" guid="ce449d4f-bcd3-42d9-b1a5-38e1b86bc9b6" pid="Mt1Dw9D6kEW5swJnDc6q3A" hash="FWBcIg">The fusing of ritual and commandment with everyday living calls for the best that is in us, that by our agency we may feel the affected condition by choosing good rather than evil, thus not only glorifying ourselves but glorifying Him who has made all things possible.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p31" guid="ed86a9c7-a207-4e04-8728-f812e68290d6" pid="LPnNRbTvwUOc6qVWiOtZSQ" hash="2FI-OQ">Concerning the need of fusing obedience to the will of God, the Prophet Joseph Smith once gave this important counsel:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p32" guid="cf53d252-4200-4a2c-81f8-62d24c897320" pid="Gv2lb3Wvy0CtHSdQHgagUQ" hash="FlCTxA">“We take the sacred writings into our hands, and admit that they were given by direct inspiration for the good of man. We believe that God condescended to speak from the heavens and declare His will concerning the human family, to give them just and holy laws, to regulate their conduct, and guide them in a direct way, that in due time He might take them to Himself, and make them joint heirs with His Son. But when this fact is admitted, that the immediate will of heaven is contained in the Scriptures, are we not bound as rational creatures to live in accordance to all its precepts? Will the mere admission, that this is the will of heaven ever benefit us if we do not comply with all its teachings? Do we not offer violence to the Supreme Intelligence of heaven, when we admit the truth of its teachings, and do not obey them? Do we not descend below our own knowledge, … by such a course of conduct?” (<span class="emphasis">Documentary History of the Church, </span>vol. 2, p. 11.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p33" guid="dd4d07a5-e4b1-4101-887c-2d946f7e4130" pid="kmkt3Zx5nU6eFnp702OYCA" hash="v7iXqg">I bear my testimony to you, my brothers and sisters, that I know that the gospel is true. When I entered the top floor of the temple in the late afternoon Thursday, with General Authorities and the Regional Representatives of the Twelve and our wives, it seemed as though a thousand voices unseen were saying, “The gospel is true; the gospel is true.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p34" guid="b2945e83-7559-41af-8786-ba03d2aee2ba" pid="f_IBHnKcRUGGOrb4X2XF8A" hash="5tNGVw">I have had the assurance of this since the day, as a young missionary in Pennsylvania, when I placed a Book of Mormon in the hands of an investigator who went directly to a clump of bushes in a park to ask God if this book were true. He returned convinced and asked for baptism. And again when a farmer in Pennsylvania met us at the farm gate to say, “I have been expecting you. I have seen you in my dreams.” After a day and night of giving them a message of the restoration, I witnessed this family of five request baptism, which was accomplished by damming the creek in back of their barn.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p35" guid="4a139a96-b675-4d17-89bf-7a6b93dc095b" pid="CzAba6hMVkm3VmvmDWS16w" hash="ar9S0w">I know that God lives, that Jesus is the Christ, that Joseph Smith and his successors, including President Joseph Fielding Smith, are prophets of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil.p36" guid="d6640851-1246-412a-88b1-fc4fa752251d" pid="UZ64EvQ8W0SrEe7IDYNn7g" hash="MmE3gw">Of this I testify in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/10/the-nobility-of-man-in-choosing-good-over-evil</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1971-general-conference/1971-10-6040-elder-alvin-r-dyer-64k-eng.mp3" length="6984056" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 1971 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Last Dispensation</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I am both humbled and grateful, my brothers and sisters, for the confidence of the First Presidency and Council of the Twelve for the new assignment given me in the Historical Department of the Church. It is truly gratifying to be associated with men</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03020_000_2030" doc-version="2" hash="Yglx1w"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="6Jx8LzgwEUWTVTkawER3iQ" hash="klXiQQ">The Last Dispensation</h1><p class="authorName" guid="9fa5d73e-c6f7-450e-99ff-a976dcd27e7d" pid="mIjNlu-baEeAD_7437vnBw" hash="pk737w">Alvin R. Dyer</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="72bd4733-fb1e-4f2c-a797-cd121a49fdc4">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-31ec.jpg" alt="Elder Alvin R. Dyer" guid="5f8cdd3d-b159-4dea-926c-852d7abca4f1" pid="ZJ1khfUrvE-7eQGGDopYig" hash="nXjfNg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p1" guid="ee217c6a-964b-41e9-bd78-3b5b7f0e2947" pid="Y3QhliqMxEe91ZDvl1R1eg" hash="rENnoQ">I am both humbled and grateful, my brothers and sisters, for the confidence of the First Presidency and Council of the Twelve for the new assignment given me in the Historical Department of the Church. It is truly gratifying to be associated with men of the caliber of Leonard Arrington, the Church Historian; Earl Olson, the Church Archivist; and Donald Smith, Church Librarian; and the other brethren who have been called to assist.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p2" guid="04543341-3cd8-4f4b-a166-23b65223314a" pid="XnvdIwzJyEaY0WzaloP_2Q" hash="0erOvQ">These are men of great spiritual devotion who have great capability in their respective fields. We shall seek the guidance of the Spirit of the Lord, and the counsel and direction of the Brethren, in the important task that lies ahead of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p3" guid="6e86467b-c7c0-4a47-be66-5c1e36750f49" pid="LraJpNieDUqVMjyG81Bdsw" hash="vRyT3w">Association with the First Presidency and other leaders, and with you, my brothers and sisters, at conference time, is always a joy and a great spiritual influence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p4" guid="8c3fbdbc-91f3-43ee-b608-ef4f13688e49" pid="1d0iLru7LkmoVwRx61o_0g" hash="J-f9pA">The plan for a useful and successful life is contained in the gospel of Jesus Christ, given to us by the Redeemer of mankind, whose atoning sacrifice augments the plan and makes it possible for us to return to the presence of God our Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p5" guid="2ef09510-8e92-4422-9f10-942160f11202" pid="uiZx7UUr4EaVWDw_dtSXLA" hash="FBeA7Q">When mortality, or the second estate of man, is completed, each individual will be prepared to continue his eternal journey into that place which the judgment of this life will place upon him. In this righteous, but penetrating, judgment, each of us shall go into the next estate of eternal existence for which we are best suited.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p6" guid="2d0f9d2e-2bd4-493e-8806-e8cc36758cd1" pid="jJ78AA_R606N61SnRm_HUw" hash="UaR2yA">The principles of progression, or of retardation, judged by our behavior in the probation of mortality, are realities of concept, based upon revelation from God, both ancient and modern.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p7" guid="0a10872c-1dca-4270-b5ad-5c0d68540cd3" pid="dE87qZqbHkmzgcdNUaehcA" hash="84_m8g">In working out the plan of life and salvation down through the stream of time, men have developed among themselves periods of obedience to God’s holy laws and, on the other hand, periods of rebellion against these same laws.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p8" guid="767fbee4-afb2-4803-9815-e01542b5246a" pid="mJZuKai2aE20TqP5S3H4ww" hash="iOwZ_w">The declarations of the prophets of God contained in sacred historical writings tell of the changing conditions that have taken place among men. Clear reference is made to times of apostasy, when the rejection of truth has been so widespread that the holy priesthood of God, the channel through which God works in dealing with mankind, has been withdrawn from among men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p9" guid="5c910123-29a9-4a0d-816d-f91089ee35cf" pid="7LxHF4RUYUiBTBgS1xB7nQ" hash="u4p0VA">Oscillating from these periods of spiritual darkness have been periods of enlightenment when the will of God has been revealed unto man and has to some extent been adhered to. These periods of enlightenment are known as dispensations of the gospel of Jesus Christ, times when God dispenses the wisdom of the eternities unto mankind for their benefit and blessing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p10" guid="9f93d5b4-bc3d-43c9-ae36-5eda7bd4195f" pid="XcIrnQQwlkKPTgsaJRaTvA" hash="eKOAcQ">Pure knowledge, meaning revelation from God, is greater than the limited reasoning of men. The method that God has chosen to convey this knowledge unto mankind is through his chosen prophets, unto whom he sends his messengers with divine instructions and upon occasion by the majesty of his own appearance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p11" guid="179e8653-b087-4323-942b-193ba4fb3342" pid="aHnLfOtQk0q_h6O-Y0CyaQ" hash="-Uc69A">Thus, on the whole, as the pages of history are observed, noting the depressions and then again the periods of enlightenment that have held sway over mankind as they move through mortality, we come to know, broadly, that times of apostasy and times of restoration are two opposite poles of human existence. They are conditions between which mankind has oscillated, as internal and external conditions bear sway.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p12" guid="0cfde7f3-44f3-4bf5-8f7e-98a097057a4c" pid="zNkxz4dDgkemiFCcPGzYag" hash="ogoHmw">In the light of this concept, the gospel that Jesus Christ proclaimed during his earthlife was not new. It was actually a restoration of the same truths that had been declared in former dispensations. He himself declared these truths unto ancient prophets who had been chosen as his instruments. He was known unto them as Jehovah, and by that name he gave commandments to the children of Israel. He has directed the plan of salvation from the very beginning of mankind upon the earth, thereby establishing the dispensations of Adam, of Enoch, of Noah, of Moses and others, all bearing witness to a restoration by the divine dispensing of truths, making known unto mankind the redeeming principles of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p13" guid="4febf56c-b48a-4d4d-a796-05c917c119a9" pid="BaN2e09M30Kh9xWFGRgP1A" hash="obLNqw">The willingness of God to dispense these truths unto mankind has ever been present, but there have been times when mankind, because of wickedness and rebellion, would not receive them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p14" guid="d05397b9-ba79-4b99-b864-bbb430f8fbf0" pid="DM98aH53OkOvoXsiIOcV-g" hash="iClhuA">In the depths of rebellion and apostasy, the masses of people are never responsive to gospel truths.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p15" guid="89e3f3c8-1398-411a-9ddd-4de8a1e4967d" pid="iZDKIU1GbEabnn7dAUAHZQ" hash="wJRtSw">The reflected lack of the principles of freedom in governments and institutions stands as a stumbling block to the furtherance of God’s work among men. When the darkness and evil of apostasy have dominated the minds of men, apostasy has been fostered by the subjection of individual rights of freedom, and unrighteous dominion has been brought to bear by the institutions of men that know not God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p16" guid="79a7754b-4a15-4156-b46d-0b9b8801f736" pid="bIJh1zcn4kS_RST8LMlLUA" hash="AeBq-A">In these periods of darkness the forces of evil, under the direction of the evil one, the archenemy of Christ, implement doctrines of force, destroying the rights of the individual, making it almost impossible for those held in subjection to have the opportunity of repentance and regeneration. Without the spirit of freedom and the power of agency, there can be no functioning of the principles that would lead us to the gospel. It is difficult, if at all possible, to come to a state of regeneration so vital to progression and the fulfillment of the gospel plan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p17" guid="ed1b94ee-7c9f-44c1-a6b4-2343a598e5c0" pid="NAf549rMVkqiJ5RXjiKCuA" hash="NBBGmw">The gospel of Jesus Christ will not flower or expand its influence under conditions where the will of the individual is suppressed. Those who have gained a conviction of the truth and have then been thrust into a condition of individual bondage may survive the ordeal on the strength of the truths that they have previously found and individually accepted, as did the early Christian martyrs or the martyrs in any age who have stood up in death rather than denounce the truths that they have taken unto themselves by the power of agency. But under godless systems, where the individual never comes to know the truth, he is held by darkness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p18" guid="d87ebe49-024b-46ea-85a8-9fe021fda3d2" pid="mzD5dvF8n0yXBwB7-DgF3Q" hash="xkngKQ">From the dark ages, that period of time following the death of the apostles of the Lord in the meridian dispensation—which continued for about eleven hundred years, during which time there was no intelligent glorification of the individual—hardly a painted picture emerged that portrayed this important concept. Everything was lost in relentless subjection of the masses to the evil power of unrighteous dominion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p19" guid="a5374a88-5903-42ce-b31a-c2c7787301f0" pid="dcrn0WBRPUCwQ-E76BhMAA" hash="e1DUKw">Then came that period known as the Renaissance, which gave to men an inward longing for liberation of thought with the courage to face the evil forces that held them in subjection. Man again began to seek for freedom and truth. The Master of men had said many years before, “… ye shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.32" class="scriptureRef">John 8:32</a>.) But this and other scripture, for many years, they had not even been privileged to read.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p20" guid="9e42326b-f428-4cc6-89a9-f35cd4f1f959" pid="tV4QbqsACUKO7TQxP_6Rnw" hash="P5CS3A">But God began to work with men, and their hearts turned toward him; and whenever the spark of freedom was found, it was influenced and fed by the natural forces of agency. Soon the desire for freedom, matched with the courage to fight and die for it, spread among men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p21" guid="e0439603-b19b-43f6-97f9-968ababa7ffc" pid="XbToQM9yrEap2Mksc1Vz_g" hash="EXYd-Q">The question might well be asked, Why does freedom need to be restored as a forerunner to a new dispensation of the gospel of Jesus Christ? The answer is a simple one, for well the Lord knows that without the spirit of freedom in the souls of men, there could be no willing response to the gospel plan. For it is in the culture of freedom and the use of agency in that freedom that men come to know the difference between good and evil. This progress leads to yearnings in the hearts of good men, and eventually to gospel dispensations. This is the pattern to be noted down through the era of the historical writings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p22" guid="774ddf78-25a3-48ec-8640-30df2d6ebb4b" pid="iHYdGJFAYUe3fWZSjWp0vw" hash="imHckA">The continued longing for freedom led directly to the period known as the Reformation, which led to the foundation of America and the framing of the Constitution, concerning which the Lord has said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p23" guid="41af87a4-6bb3-49ed-900b-3413bdd4b802" pid="JDi6d1_a-0C3l79pcgCUmw" hash="TfjMdw">“According to the laws and constitution of the people, which I have suffered to be established, and should be maintained for the rights and protection of all flesh, according to just and holy principles.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/101.77" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 101:77</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p24" guid="89f27de6-ded4-4a4d-9d1e-57579bf37ac1" pid="5D_AW0YgLUi-VolwdmjXgA" hash="r76hTQ">All of this in its proper order leads directly to the greatest period in the experience of man upon the earth, a new dispensation of the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p25" guid="2f35232c-7f77-40b4-be50-be99a2a7f3f5" pid="16WCwVqLj0WjO4uSf0Vw_g" hash="nRKM4A">This period was foreseen and referred to by the apostle Peter as the times of restitution or restoration of all things involving a new gospel dispensation. Here are his words as he speaks also of the coming of the Lord at this particular time:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p26" guid="15e0455b-4ecb-44bd-b886-d7b8954bac2c" pid="qbl0e7Y-qUKAfQQRNuuFUA" hash="SmcXwQ">“And he shall send Jesus Christ, which before was preached unto you:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p27" guid="8da65105-b9fa-44d4-8b88-f94054954a13" pid="LkYBMMbiNUOm3sfIl2Meog" hash="YF4gaQ">“Whom the heaven must receive until the times of restitution of all things, which God hath spoken by the mouth of all his holy prophets since the world began.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/3.20-21" class="scriptureRef">Acts 3:20–21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p28" guid="6dfc70a0-ca88-49fd-99e8-fbf7e62782e9" pid="X9ILegZdmUKb03C431kkhw" hash="znsrIg">The significant feature of the present dispensation was the inauguration of the same by the personal visitation of God the Father and his Beloved Son, Jesus Christ, referred to in the sacred historical writings of this church as the Sacred Grove appearance, which occurred in the spring of 1820 near Palmyra, New York, 152 years ago.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p29" guid="c88c6aed-ef08-4ad6-b677-a9dcae9ff916" pid="iagAtFhNNki1Oc2iX_WeRQ" hash="suqwsA">Upon this occasion Joseph Smith became the first of the prophets of this new dispensation of the gospel; and by virtue of divine instruction given then and subsequent appearances of the Son of God and certain ancient prophets who hold keys of understanding pertaining to the gospel plan, he has caused to be established the kingdom of God upon the earth, that any of mankind may come unto it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p30" guid="e189e37f-03a1-48dd-b773-8cf88da72fde" pid="fxOMPzmHvES35FzEtaAIMw" hash="tHuzHg">The characteristics of this dispensation, as compared with other dispensations, are unique in that it is the last of all dispensations, concerning which the Prophet Joseph Smith received this divine information as contained in a revelation:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p31" guid="13898766-a70f-48e6-90ee-204acd86df6e" pid="pgNfZh4ShkeHM3R0cY4Phg" hash="2WoCMw">“Unto whom I have committed the keys of my kingdom, and a dispensation of the gospel for the last times; and for the fulness of times, in the which I will gather together in one all things, both which are in heaven, and which are on earth.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/27.13" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 27:13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p32" guid="8ef75a17-c1a1-4b72-877e-2d5046c81f7d" pid="5Ke6l2616kSyuwweC6Oi1g" hash="yZXwow">The apostle Paul, writing unto the Ephesian saints, speaks also of this important final dispensation in connection with the inheritances that will come to the faithful. I quote what he said and must have seen in vision:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p33" guid="9ece5534-1425-4f61-bb6d-1ff661d492d2" pid="ec-6wFn85kG4Vy6fhYGQwQ" hash="mHvpPQ">“That in the dispensation of the fulness of times he might gather together in one all things in Christ, both which are in heaven, and which are on earth; even in him.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/1.10" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 1:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p34" guid="516a9229-498c-4c00-a594-1e30b29e3fc6" pid="ggHAH0qnw0CVS5EtGk5X8g" hash="a2oJow">A dispensation of the gospel of Jesus Christ is now established with prophets, seers, and revelators. The church and kingdom of God has been established, and the inhabitants of the earth “may receive it, and be prepared for the days to come, in the which the Son of Man shall come down in heaven, clothed in the brightness of his glory, to meet the kingdom of God which is set up on the earth.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/65.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 65:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation.p35" guid="4339e34a-3bca-4086-b15e-a9bf785cea9c" pid="LDbzIW0lNEKvcmtISfiXAg" hash="cd6txg">Of these things I bear my personal witness as conveyed to me by the power of the Spirit, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/04/the-last-dispensation</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1972-general-conference/1972-04-2030-elder-alvin-r-dyer-64k-eng.mp3" length="7020580" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
