<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Angel Abrea</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Angel Abrea.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Angel%20Abrea.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Angel Abrea.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Apr 1981 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 1981 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Gracias</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1981/04/gracias?lang=eng</link>
      <description>A few days ago, when I received a phone call at the mission home in Rosario, Argentina, and President Kimball extended to me this calling, Sister Abrea and I were not only touched emotionally, but also overwhelmed by the tremendous responsibility. A </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/gracias" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03135_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="wZpQ4Q">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/gracias.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="LQNvxgdZX0S6sIWk4LI9BA" hash="xlt1mA">Gracias</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="lLogbHw10kiG7mELZJTBwg" hash="BC9Hdw">Elder Angel Abrea</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/gracias.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2334.jpg" alt="Elder Angel Abrea" pid="NTMQDVeuc0OPDFAiuEpNgg" hash="KNnmNw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/gracias.p1" pid="0ArXhiF1Qka7-yrpKZgmbg" hash="VuBW_g">A few days ago, when I received a phone call at the mission home in Rosario, Argentina, and President Kimball extended to me this calling, Sister Abrea and I were not only touched emotionally, but also overwhelmed by the tremendous responsibility. A feeling and a word immediately filled me. The feeling, gratitude; the word, <span class="emphasis">gracias</span>—thank you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/gracias.p2" pid="c_wxYmJWjUSzkowLdeHYoQ" hash="OqSNaA">Thank you to those two lady missionaries who, almost thirty-eight years ago, arrived at my door and brought the good news of the gospel. Thank you to my dear mother, who took me to Primary, to each meeting of the Church, with whom I read for the first time the Book of Mormon, and who even now, by means of her activity and faithful life in the Church, continues to set for me an example worth emulating.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/gracias.p3" pid="ZdiQp4nZSUmWudsV-MpSgQ" hash="FVPS9Q">Thank you to my father, who I know has accepted the word of the gospel and baptism beyond the veil, who, when I was a youth of eleven years, sat with me at my bed one Sunday morning and said to me, “Angel, if you are going to be a member of the Church, you will always have to comply with everything that it asks of you. You have accepted a commitment, and you should honor it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/gracias.p4" pid="G1i2AoAf4Eysrq-ND06sbg" hash="GVGtew">Thank you to my beloved wife, who has helped and sustained me, always full of faith and love for the gospel, a constant inspiration in my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/gracias.p5" pid="67ZaUSBC1k-oF4s2RM-QIw" hash="RapeEg">Thank you for my three daughters, who, because of their love and dedication to the Church, are a pride, joy, and happiness in my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/gracias.p6" pid="fORKsk3sb0aE6G4i7ZDtcg" hash="aDoMMg">Thank you to my leaders and teachers, who, many times under unfavorable circumstances, have done their part. Thank you to the hundreds of missionaries who have made possible the development of the Church in the countries of South America. And especially thank you to the parents of those missionaries who have sent their sons and daughters to unknown countries, perhaps with fear and anxiety, but with the surety that they would be doing what the Lord required at the time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/gracias.p7" pid="eFzK8TsGNUecWJBSQXj4-A" hash="5O4jSA">And finally, thank you, Father, for my testimony, for knowing without the slightest doubt that my Father in Heaven sent his Only Begotten Son in order to bring about the great work of redemption. Thank you, too, for the knowledge that Christ was resurrected and that he lives. Thank you for knowing that Joseph Smith received a divine mission to fulfill, that he carried it out, and that by his mission we arrived at the true knowledge of our Savior, Jesus Christ. Thank you because I know that The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is true and is the kingdom of God upon the earth and that it is presided over and directed by a modern prophet, President Kimball, who has been a continuous influence in my life, ever since the years of my early youth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/gracias.p8" pid="9lVQ_ObF60mDREhz6r0-qQ" hash="5fi_Kw">For this testimony, which is my surety, my rock, my sustenance, which I have received by the mediation of the Holy Ghost, I give infinite thanks, and I place all my talents, time, efforts, and all that I possess to the work to which I have been called. That would be my way to express in part my thanks. <span class="emphasis">Gracias.</span> I say these things in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1981/04/gracias</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1981-general-conference/1981-04-2060-elder-angel-abrea-64k-eng.mp3" length="2434116" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 1981 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The “Little Things” and Eternal Life</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life?lang=eng</link>
      <description>One extremely hot afternoon I was crossing the green agricultural lands of the Pampas in Argentina. The sun was scorching the highway to the point that the heat waves became visible. Nevertheless, I was confident and comfortable because I had just pu</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03141_000_012" doc-version="2" hash="ZXFFUw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="xsAGrzooVUObM4afBH5TdQ" hash="6IbRTg">The “Little Things” and Eternal Life</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="xI7DR8jQN0qUCS-mABAp2w" hash="BC9Hdw">Elder Angel Abrea</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2334.jpg" alt="Elder Angel Abrea" pid="TwDne2m3BEKJv8ObePsh2g" hash="KNnmNw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p1" pid="Or1m4uzfqkG2yPY5XfpxmA" hash="PiVe3w">One extremely hot afternoon I was crossing the green agricultural lands of the Pampas in Argentina. The sun was scorching the highway to the point that the heat waves became visible. Nevertheless, I was confident and comfortable because I had just purchased a brand-new car, fresh from the factory, with a big motor and plenty of power to conquer the elements and allow me to travel briskly in air-conditioned comfort.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p2" pid="g2BTYKJ_8E2PQYlnJuBF1g" hash="a9odFA">Suddenly, I noticed that the temperature in my new car had begun to climb and the big motor began to show signs of strain. When the temperature gauge got to the danger point, I pulled the car over to the side of the road in the hope that with my very limited knowledge of mechanics I could discover what was wrong with the car. I must admit I was rather disgusted to think that something could stop my big new car. It wasn’t long after I had lifted the hood that I discovered, to my amazement, that a myriad of colorful little butterflies had collected on the radiator, choked off the cooling process, and stopped the car. I was then struck with the realization of how a few hundred little butterflies, in their collective strength, could master the immense horsepower of the motor. No, it wasn’t an eagle, a hawk, or anything else more or less justifiable, but just a couple hundred little butterflies.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p3" pid="tEGKzBijpE-eEGMkNiRePA" hash="twu88Q">This incident made me think about what often happens in our own lives. I thought about the tremendous potential that exists in each one of us, potential that can direct us to eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p4" pid="o_a9UUiOv0KxDc1XDceOxA" hash="aJ3t4w">The Prophet Joseph Smith said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p5" pid="WCVvZn24f0ahZ2e0pj1BkQ" hash="kK0uVg">“Here, then, is eternal life—to know the only wise and true God; and you have got to learn how to be Gods yourselves, and to be kings and priests to God, the same as all Gods have done before you, namely, by going from one small degree to another, and from a small capacity to a great one; from grace to grace, from exaltation to exaltation, until you attain to the resurrection of the dead, and are able to dwell in everlasting burnings, and to sit in glory, as do those who sit enthroned in everlasting power. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p6" pid="j9AYOcZk4EOgX55XAVM8YQ" hash="758UUw">“… [You] shall be heirs of God and joint heirs with Jesus Christ. What is it? To inherit the same power, the same glory and the same exaltation, until you arrive at the station of a God, and ascend the throne of eternal power, the same as those who have gone before.” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith,</span> sel. Joseph Fielding Smith, Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1938, pp. 346–47.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p7" pid="JVpIuKMEPE-1BIoiqGjXTw" hash="4XsNJA">How many times do we allow little “butterflies” to reduce, restrain, or restrict our immense potential from guiding us to exaltation?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p8" pid="xgZKd1Zhe02MsHPr2QOaag" hash="BxvOAg">Proportionately they are relatively few, those who are detained in their journey by the so-called grave or serious sins, like those we might find in the newspaper headlines. Generally, it is not the mighty eagle that defeats us, but the tiny little “butterflies.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p9" pid="yAXXC3SH902sYvcg3XfAsw" hash="zvrPhw">To better illustrate this concept, I would like to mention some of those “road hazards” that become obstacles in our marvelous journey to the celestial kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p10" pid="ILOxfeYNxki45ulCXbASyQ" hash="r1h_kw">Have we thought about the tremendous spiritual deterioration that results from not keeping the Sabbath day holy? This commandment involves much more than just resting from our labors. Keeping the Sabbath day holy inherently builds spiritual character and prepares us for what is to come. By observing this commandment, we will have power over evil; we will be more capable of keeping the commandments of the Lord and maintaining ourselves unspotted from the sins of the world. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p11" pid="N9V46YZSHkayBuwltOYHcA" hash="1Y-Yng">More specifically, speaking about the Sabbath day, have we thought about the spiritual malnourishment that results from not attending our sacrament meetings, or attending them with a wrong attitude? The sacred covenant made by the members of the Church at baptism should be the prevailing thought and feeling in our hearts and minds as we partake of the sacrament. If we can achieve this, we will always have the Spirit of the Lord with us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p12" pid="cYrdYIe5qkeG6I7pWY_EbQ" hash="ct5q7w">No member of the Church can ignore or simply put aside the weekly renewal of this covenant and pretend to maintain the Spirit. If we really understand the purpose of our sacrament meetings, we will attend them not just to hear someone speak, which is of course important, but to renew the sacred covenants made with our Father in Heaven in the name of his son, Jesus Christ. Those who make a habit of not attending this weekly service, and fail to repent, put in great danger their spiritual stability and welfare.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p13" pid="Ta9OCe0q60i-nUar8Ga6qg" hash="esLqQg">Have we ever stopped to think what it means to our salvation when we neglect prayer, or don’t develop daily from our prayers repeatedly gratifying experiences? We are continually referring to the “power of prayer,”. but are we always willing to pay the price so that the promise we find in <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.18-20" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:18–20</a> may be fulfilled?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p14" pid="LL6KBhFPykGtmIxUGL39lA" hash="kFA4oA">“Behold, verily, verily, I say unto you, ye must watch and pray always lest ye enter into temptation; for Satan desireth to have you, that he may sift you as wheat.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p15" pid="M--j5b9nsU2KZbyuzGLB4Q" hash="pN5vwA">“Therefore ye must always pray unto the Father in my name;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p16" pid="X1BXsCY4rEORBlTQt1j4Xg" hash="RqQOkg">“And whatsoever ye shall ask the Father in my name, which is right, believing that ye shall receive, behold it shall be given unto you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p17" pid="Tc67uVv-sU-V-VYfSTautw" hash="W4S9Kw">Another example: do we realize that every time that we sustain the leaders of the Church we are duty bound to support them? The raised hand becomes a symbol of the covenant we make to support them. Each time we criticize or condemn them, we become literally covenant breakers. President Joseph F. Smith made the following comment about this problem:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p18" pid="S9pf-6GKdkO_7F0NLtrN7w" hash="V9JNOg">“The moment a man says he will not submit to the legally constituted authority of the Church, whether it be the teachers, the bishopric, the high council, his quorum, or the First Presidency, and in his heart confirms it and carries it out, that moment he cuts himself off from the privileges and blessings of the Priesthood and Church, and severs himself from the people of God, for he ignores the authority that the Lord has instituted in his Church.” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Doctrine,</span> 5th ed., Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1939, p. 45.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p19" pid="acyESXSl2Uiv1col_hd3Sg" hash="O9gx8A">I have had innumerable experiences listening to the reasons people have for not paying their tithing, most of which are just cases of a simple lack of faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p20" pid="9qKYmpy9B0WvP5c_zxnI6g" hash="1hF_9A">I remember once in 1957, while I was acting as a new president of a branch in Argentina, I decided to interview the members with respect to the importance of paying tithing. I found myself talking with one good brother of the branch whose name was Jose, who had difficulty paying his tithing. I asked him bluntly, “Brother Jose, why don’t you pay your tithing?” I’m sure Jose didn’t expect me to be so direct.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p21" pid="thMLJTDtjkyFgSgh4UtDTQ" hash="ZZ_pPw">After a moment of silence he responded: “As you know, President, I have two children. The wage of a laborer is very low. This month I have to buy my children shoes to go to school; and, mathematically, I just don’t have enough money.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p22" pid="Iin9n_DRME62CQGbJOItCg" hash="fSwgrg">In an instant response, I said, “Jose, I promise you that if you pay your tithing faithfully, your children will have their shoes to go to school, and you will be able to pay for all the needs of your home. I don’t know how he will do it, but the Lord always keeps his promises. Besides that,” I added, “If you still find that you don’t have enough money, I will give you back what you paid in tithing from my own pocket.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p23" pid="UF97P57-4UOmdicLEjyXsg" hash="omi7DA">On the way home, I wondered if what I had done was the right thing. Here I was, recently married, just getting started in my career, and faced with my own economic problems. I began to worry about my own shoes, let alone those of Jose’s family! Even though when I got home my dear wife wholeheartedly supported me and reassured me that everything would be all right, I must say that that night nobody prayed harder for Brother Jose’s economic welfare than I did.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p24" pid="Tp70gR8RdU2Ob9T9UYDqWg" hash="GEa7QQ">One month later, I once again sat down with Jose. Though the tears in his eyes almost made it impossible for him to speak, he said: “President, it is incredible. I paid my tithing; I was able to meet all of my obligations, and I even purchased the new shoes for my children, all without an increase in my wage. I know that the Lord keeps his promises!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p25" pid="z2esjXdIP0aqO2-1P5FU5w" hash="8TmBCw">Jose remains to this day a faithful tithe payer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p26" pid="Z8SGTg0f70enRjgZ8kp9Tg" hash="-iIJWw">Up until now, I have mentioned only a few of the problems arising from the little “butterflies” that we find in our eternal pathway. Of course, there are many more. We could mention, for example, the lack of self-control that leads many people to break the Word of Wisdom; the various excuses for not complying with the program of personal and family preparedness; the lack of encouragement and the apathy with regard to our genealogical responsibilities; the failure to return often to the temples of the Lord to do the necessary work for our kindred dead; in some cases the lack of interest, in other cases the fear, that precludes many from participating in missionary work. These are only examples of a list that goes on and on.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p27" pid="YX3TDY7jm0qrOmJB3Mijnw" hash="suLHZg">It is highly probable that we will never lose our status as members of the Church simply for not adhering to one or more of the aforementioned commandments. Nevertheless, whether individually or collectively, these little “butterflies” affect our spiritual development and, fundamentally, the real capability of each individual.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p28" pid="TCbvxgkouUia6FMurkwt6A" hash="T8LKIQ">“For the power is in them, wherein they are agents unto themselves. And inasmuch as men do good they shall in nowise lose their reward.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p29" pid="D2avg3CdYUWRg-fNOf1AIA" hash="x_vttw">The Lord hasn’t sent us to the world to fail. We have been invested with all of the talents and abilities necessary for the journey to arrive, to be once again in His presence. Our greatest challenge is to use faithfully and decidedly all that He has given us to reach our exaltation. If such is our accomplishment—if we “live by every word that proceedeth forth from the mouth of God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.44" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:44</a>)—at the end of our journey we will once again be part of a glorious experience such as we had at the start, when “all the sons of God shouted for joy.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/job/38.7" class="scriptureRef">Job 38:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life.p30" pid="7lwjbXL3SkK1MRSNxnvsBA" hash="R8Gqwg">I know that the Lord has made this possible and that he blesses us and will continue to bless us as we progress to our glorious destination. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1981/10/the-little-things-and-eternal-life</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1981-general-conference/1981-10-2040-elder-angel-abrea-64k-eng.mp3" length="6597231" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 1981 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sure Sound of the Trumpet</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet?lang=eng</link>
      <description>A few years ago I found myself in a small city park which was covered with trees and adorned with monuments, a plaza typical of many found throughout Argentina. I was watching a sculptor as he used a hammer and chisel to put the finishing touches on </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03174_000_031" doc-version="2" hash="3Ivv8A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="xrSDncVYc0m2kH3Bjz9N-w" hash="dipW6Q">The Sure Sound of the Trumpet</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="7vnC0NXkeki-_LO4gWSeag" hash="BC9Hdw">Elder Angel Abrea</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2334.jpg" alt="Elder Angel Abrea" pid="AOYb2t9KVkCtEOY9CBkRGw" hash="KNnmNw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p1" pid="ZlvUxfwd5k2n2RRx2GC_aA" hash="22wWFw">A few years ago I found myself in a small city park which was covered with trees and adorned with monuments, a plaza typical of many found throughout Argentina. I was watching a sculptor as he used a hammer and chisel to put the finishing touches on his project. His artwork portrayed a mother holding a child in her arms.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p2" pid="6rNzse-W80-DPpZUcLhMzw" hash="6sb51A">The artist was working to perfect the hands of the mother, which were fashioned of marble, and the results appeared to me to be masterful strokes in the sculptor’s own style.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p3" pid="ZpeXyPN5IUad2klQMPCbWg" hash="Z2fr9Q">As I stood there fascinated, eager to grasp knowledge of the artist’s skills, a shoeshine boy passing by stopped and stood by me. After attentively watching the progress of the final touches for a few moments, the industrious young boy turned to me and in amazement asked, “Sir, tell me, why is he breaking it now?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p4" pid="CDYDZYIZCEKy3dX0iabDEA" hash="6u0kag">The youth’s naive and unexpected query gave me cause to contemplate the examples which we constantly set, the impressions we give by our actions and our behavior. It made me realize how extremely important our examples can be, as is the force or weakness with which we convey our personal convictions in our everyday life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p5" pid="haUTVwm7qk2pjQ9vru85Ug" hash="Nc9DSw">The words of Paul came to my mind: “For if the trumpet give an uncertain sound, who shall prepare himself to the battle?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/14.8" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 14:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p6" pid="0HSc5PzSRkKm6PVSBGViig" hash="m9ZIFQ">According to the radius of our activity, or within our sphere of responsibility, each one of us influences a certain number of God’s sons and daughters. Our attitudes, actions, and words convey messages to others which in some way affect their lives, either positively or negatively.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p7" pid="sAfh24WpnUCtm3RtAdBeuQ" hash="q7iqhA">Our actions are the results of our ignorance or the fruits of our knowledge, the results of our disbelief or of the testimony which we possess. We cannot escape from ourselves or from that which we hold in our hearts. We become that which we pursue. The example which we set and the life we live are a reflection of all that we truly are.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p8" pid="Q-qEylAq5kGf6QUAbxuebw" hash="Y5rNYg">In the words of counsel which Alma gave to his son, Corianton, we see an illustration of how ill feelings that are harbored in our hearts lead to actions which set bad examples, with consequent adverse effects in the lives of others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p9" pid="z0TwDCy9bUmTsaIpa0rJpQ" hash="iUADcg">“Suffer not yourself to be led away by any vain or foolish thing; suffer not the devil to lead away your heart … for when they saw your conduct they would not believe in my words.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/39.11" class="scriptureRef">Alma 39:11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p10" pid="dj2jSIceU0-zUdELfXmWNQ" hash="S0BSmg">On the other hand, Nephi gives us a very meaningful example of the power of a testimony which produces an attitude of certainty and leaves no room for doubt when he was faced with the request from his father, Lehi. He answered, “I will go and do the things which the Lord hath commanded.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 3:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p11" pid="6y9N5b8Q-US64Kk_mCf51Q" hash="AX34ng">He did not say, “I will go and see what happens,” or, “I will go and see what the circumstances are,” which would have caused confusion and uncertainty; but, rather, his attitude was one of a person who does not doubt, and one who acts accordingly. It is interesting to note that Nephi did not only express his decision and determination to be obedient in carrying out his father’s request, but he further explained the reason for acting in this manner when he said, “For I know that the Lord giveth no commandments unto the children of men, save he shall prepare a way for them that they may accomplish the thing which he commandeth them.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 3:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p12" pid="xfZya1obXkCzIsXsic_5YQ" hash="yUrL_A">On another occasion Nephi received the following assignment from the Lord: “Thou shalt construct a ship, after the manner which I shall show thee, that I may carry thy people across these waters.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.8" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p13" pid="mLuoiTWyjk6sKKaDb0ySSA" hash="optsTw">After receiving this commandment, Nephi’s reaction was not the usual one that many people would expect, or that would be a logical response for some: “Look, Lord, I have never before built a ship. I don’t know how to do it. That which you ask of me is more than I can do. Furthermore, my brothers will certainly be opposed to this, which will make the task much more difficult. Is there not some other way to accomplish this project?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p14" pid="bkjSyv2Vk0-pLiTw19-n8Q" hash="hLc6qg">No such thoughts were alternatives used by Nephi when he made a decision. His answer was simply, “Lord, whither shall I go that I may find ore to molten, that I may make tools to construct the ship?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.9" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:9</a>.) In these words, Nephi’s firm determination and his decision to do what was asked of him are reflected in carrying out the mission which the Lord had assigned to him. Then, in the course of events, when his brothers began to murmur against him and opposed building the ship, he confronted them with the mighty strength of his testimony saying: “If God had commanded me to do all things I could do them. If he should command me that I should say unto this water, be thou earth, it should be earth; and if I should say it, it would be done.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p15" pid="WSjemGao7E6q4zbRxuQrdw" hash="MtwEPw">“And now, if the Lord has such great power, and has wrought so many miracles among the children of men, how is it that he cannot instruct me, that I should build a ship?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.50-51" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:50–51</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p16" pid="mTdw4UQsf0KeXh_OGo9pVQ" hash="o2qo0Q">Attitudes and actions which produce teaching examples are those which are motivated by a strong testimony.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p17" pid="I8cNV8932EGeqadRWUHdjQ" hash="l_k4yA">The convictions which we treasure in our hearts are more important than our very lives if those convictions and treasures are the results of a fervent testimony, one received through revelation. They give us the kind of courage which allows us to face the trials of life with the assurance that our Father in Heaven will approve our actions regardless of the circumstances which surround us, the ignorance of many, or the hardship of the trials.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p18" pid="8wXNOMnaNUG_hEr7p55bhw" hash="DA81xA">In the world today there are millions of people who are ready to do what seems possible, but the prize is for those who are ready to do what seems impossible. If certain things can be done, personal efficiency and skill can carry them through. If it cannot be done, faith and testimony can do it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p19" pid="fq9p0xP2RUKRKVY33yJ7PA" hash="bn2eDg">As sons and daughters of God we have not received the commandments, which show us the way to return to him on a conditional basis, to fulfill only if it seems possible or if ideal circumstances permit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p20" pid="Fv4xKBVhU0O1yJyIkawRZw" hash="aJ6Jjg">To be obedient, to do that which the Lord requires of us, has been and always will be a constant principle in the lives of those whom the Lord has called to be his prophets. As an example, we might mention that at one time the Prophet Joseph Smith said, “I made this my rule, ‘When the Lord commands, do it.’” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 2:170.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p21" pid="95V1ff3MI0WACYzaHRlZiw" hash="73q0Xg">Without any doubt, Joseph Smith was a prophet with a great spirit of accomplishment and tenacity. On one occasion he said to his cousin, George A. Smith: “Never be discouraged. If I were sunk in the lowest pit of Nova Scotia, with the Rocky Mountains piled on me, I would hang on, exercise faith, and keep up good courage, and I would come out on top.” (John Henry Evans, <span class="emphasis">Joseph Smith, an American Prophet,</span> New York: MacMillan Co., 1946, p. 9.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p22" pid="TwteZjfYq0mvuaalwligog" hash="C66zoA">The life of the prophet of whom I bear testimony was an example of that which he proclaimed, having always given a clear message of his convictions and testimony.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p23" pid="UgqopDUJMEGc0PB5lAD9mw" hash="OyfXLw">This kind of determination, an exemplary way of life, is not reserved for only a small minority, as some would believe, but rather it should be the constant attitude of those who desire to follow the Lord’s counsel in order to attain the promised blessings: “Be thou faithful unto death, and I will give thee a crown of life.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rev/2.10" class="scriptureRef">Rev. 2:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p24" pid="9r5L8lRS6Eu2b8mfJ9IQ7A" hash="xCq7UQ">In the scriptures we find examples of how, through their actions, parents can send “messages” into the lives of their children which will lead them into paths of darkness or, on the other hand, which can teach them clearly those things which will lead them into salvation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p25" pid="h7LnGDQNpE-AkzIh8-W3kg" hash="0ARxHg">Jacob, speaking to the Nephites, told them, “Wherefore, ye shall remember your children, how that ye have grieved their hearts because of the example that ye have set before them; and also, remember that ye may, because of your filthiness, bring your children unto destruction, and their sins be heaped upon your heads at the last day.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/3.10" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 3:10</a>.) The dramatic power of example by parents in the lives of children is clearly demonstrated in those words.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p26" pid="2BWSxnba8EyovfKMsyQ69A" hash="HSn2tQ">Sometimes bad examples, or “the uncertain sound of the trumpet,” which children receive in the home comes in the form of criticism of Church authorities, or in speaking kind words and thoughts outside the home but within it speaking words which are harsh and brusque. The sound is unclear if children observe the payment of tithing when and if it is convenient, or if they hear justifications for not paying it in moments when faith weakens. It is a distorted sound when they see that observance of the Sabbath depends on which sport event is scheduled for the day, or if the weather is ideal for an outing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p27" pid="LEEEI63iYE6DKbZbeDpVrA" hash="dl8DZg">Those who act in this manner can be compared to the person whom President Hugh B. Brown described when he said, “He who knows the precepts and neglects to obey them is like one that lights a candle in the darkness and then closes his eyes.” (<span class="emphasis">Relief Society Magazine,</span> Oct. 1969, p. 725.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p28" pid="D-4v1LDJA0uOb4hQ8DwXGw" hash="6bPYTQ">Now let us consider the sure sound of the trumpet, the other side of the issue, in the example of Joshua. When it became necessary for his people to make a firm commitment and take a definite stand, he said to them in his final speech, “And if it seem evil unto you to serve the Lord, choose you this day whom ye will serve; … but as for me and my house, we will serve the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/24.15" class="scriptureRef">Josh. 24:15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p29" pid="oeZTJcw72Ey-CBFZkoS5UA" hash="WwGplQ">Imagine the impact it would have if every parent took the same attitude and the same determination which Joshua took! What a loud and clear sound the message would have when carried into the lives of the children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p30" pid="dDkvhyXjQUuqK3KObixkNw" hash="1pPA5w">In the building of eternal families, we need more models, we need more guiding lights, and certainly we need fewer excuse-makers and fewer advocates of darkness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p31" pid="gxRLuEEkTU6K7KN_tOhD_g" hash="8owi6g">It is one thing to talk about the gospel, but it is quite another to live it. It is one thing to preach about Christ, but it is another to follow in his footsteps.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p32" pid="RFVrnGr6V0Oaseehnvy3-w" hash="hYdymg">When the gospel is incorporated in the life of each one of us, it molds our decisions and determines our actions. We become models and examples who can teach others the path to follow leading to life eternal only when we live the principles of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p33" pid="Ch8pU8tWDkqLj2KtuoawHw" hash="AMvAng">In the great mission to which we have been called, to be saviors of men, may we follow the admonition of the Lord:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p34" pid="kSBElXRJl0Oi5F1m_zeMcA" hash="ZVgRxg">“Verily I say unto you all: Arise and shine forth, that thy light may be a standard for the nations.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/115.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 115:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p35" pid="7ttXMFGcOkC25qgkmO59Nw" hash="kZYcSQ">We cannot fail in that trust because our Savior, Jesus Christ, has shown us by example: “Behold I am the light; I have set an example for you.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.16" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p36" pid="WILpGiT52EiAnGnwrK9iHw" hash="gN8qoQ">We know the goal; we have the example; now let us put forth the effort and make the decision to follow in that path.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p37" pid="CrzPObMCNEu163nBBuMc6Q" hash="Cg01mw">“And now, my beloved brethren, I know by this that unless a man shall endure to the end, in following the example of the Son of the living God, he cannot be saved.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.16" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet.p38" pid="lfGhb7NCp0O4rchscfhTKQ" hash="J0aqGQ">In the name of the Redeemer, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1984/04/the-sure-sound-of-the-trumpet</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1984-general-conference/1984-04-5020-elder-angel-abrea-64k-eng.mp3" length="6160088" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 1984 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assurance That Comes from Knowing</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The story is told that on one occasion, a traveler asked a farmer who was seated in the doorway of his humble cabin, “How’s the cotton crop going to be this year?”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03226_000_012" doc-version="2" hash="EdNZSw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="dyZmWwqPmUKXgze9LpTdHA" hash="1gRxXw">Assurance That Comes from Knowing</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="MJk_fIGkL02PzboXu8OQlw" hash="BC9Hdw">Elder Angel Abrea</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2334.jpg" alt="Elder Angel Abrea" pid="-SuWkCK0cUK-Fvy8w0D0og" hash="KNnmNw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p1" pid="WJPlgdIgOEylSWr00qtiNg" hash="McSH8A">The story is told that on one occasion, a traveler asked a farmer who was seated in the doorway of his humble cabin, “How’s the cotton crop going to be this year?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p2" pid="m47wV6PKuEmMNxbK5xJg5Q" hash="NW64cA">The farmer replied, “There won’t be any. I didn’t bother to plant it because I was afraid of the boll weevil.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p3" pid="feYzuVu6Ik-XQAjO9r83FQ" hash="YMawzw">Upon hearing this, the traveler asked further, “Well, are you going to harvest a big corn crop?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p4" pid="-wocEpB8ukmyVZg9kFxL9A" hash="gOZ7eA">“It’s the same,” came the response. “I was afraid we wouldn’t get enough rain for the kernels to mature.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p5" pid="O-4m5_EwBEarS6cIAie3SA" hash="xhT_yA">The traveler pursued, “At least you will have a good potato harvest!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p6" pid="toeE8cW5ukCSsgbwvZyRvg" hash="S361zA">“Nope. Not any; I didn’t dare plant them because I was afraid of insects.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p7" pid="Bj3e9oxekEKOcqzX3P_r9Q" hash="3dviNQ">With frustration, and somewhat impatiently, the traveler then asked, “Well, what is it that you have planted?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p8" pid="vpyb-tPgbEWiOaSti6IqWw" hash="h3weOQ">“Nothing, my good man,” came the answer. “I’d rather be safe than sorry.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p9" pid="mNjmDNVhXU-bZoRIrpBQKg" hash="oUwsug">The response from the farmer is a good example of a false security arising from fear and lack of conviction. It is an illusion of security resulting from uncertainty and confusion, an imaginary safe route definitely confused and distorted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p10" pid="N3Agi--mWketkgADkt5OfQ" hash="7V3hpw">Certainly this is one of the evils which afflicts this generation—the security of not doing, the security of not being. It is the same type of evil that the Savior referred to when he pointed out the uselessness of the unprofitable servant (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.30" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:30</a>), of the fig tree that didn’t bear fruit (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/21.19-22" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 21:19–22</a>), of the light that did not shine (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/11.33-36" class="scriptureRef">Luke 11:33–36</a>), and of the salt that had lost its savor (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/14.34-35" class="scriptureRef">Luke 14:34–35</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p11" pid="D0MhqZvFSE6a52FqeOE22A" hash="oFMIzg">Jesus Christ did not alter concepts in order to make incorrect actions compatible with a false sense of reality; he always clarified them in order to eliminate neutrality and ambiguity and to expose hypocrisy and deviant actions, thereby setting the standard by which the children of God will be judged.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p12" pid="ThyjBpYoQEmwz_himVWMMw" hash="O0yzYQ">He described things as they were and lived his life as a clear example to us all of how to live and how to act, even saying, “For I have given you an example” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/13.15" class="scriptureRef">John 13:15</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p13" pid="XJ2FiSery0iaH5YtC5WqxQ" hash="kkpLhQ">Today there are many people, just as the farmer in our story, who, out of fear, create within themselves mental scarecrows and eventually end up believing that these scarecrows are real. In this manner they base their lives on false principles. It is unimportant to them that their ideas are not true; these ideas are the trenches they dig to defend themselves from fear, the commotion they make to drive away the truth. For example, the “scarecrow” of security is a confused and distorted imitation of true security. It provides these people with the illusion they need to weigh different situations and act as they want, using as their yardstick precepts totally apart from reality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p14" pid="eVeLpLy8_k-Cqj02YVeefw" hash="a9b73w">In the face of this distorted understanding of the truth, Latter-day Saints who have received the assignment through revelation to “take upon you the name of Christ, and speak the truth in soberness” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:21</a>) could appear to be proud and lacking humility to those who hold to incorrect concepts. This is because faithful members of the Church are filled with a deep assurance that comes from a firm testimony of the gospel, a sure knowledge of the divinity of the work in which we have embarked, received through revelation from the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p15" pid="rGg8R65030aWai03Al75Lw" hash="45-G8w">This assurance and firm commitment “to stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things, and in all places that ye may be in, even until death” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:9</a>) could appear as boastful pride before those accustomed to using mental scarecrows.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p16" pid="7eaPvcv4xESBTX2HUSALVw" hash="yhlmmA">But it is not that way. To confuse pride with safety, and vanity with testimony, shows lack of understanding by those who have not allowed the tempering of the Spirit to enter their hearts, who have not had the experience Nephi did when he said, “I did cry unto the Lord; and behold he did visit me, and did soften my heart that I did believe all the words which had been spoken by my father” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/2.16" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 2:16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p17" pid="NRulKh8zFkyxfOPsFP0_Lg" hash="SJjnyw">So in most cases the problem is not with the sower, but with the soil where the seed is planted, and very often those who are insecure challenge the self-confident person, not necessarily because of his self-confidence but because, by comparison, their own insecurity becomes evident.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p18" pid="GuQcl7zxVE66adZRuNn8gw" hash="V96aZA">The important point is not to look for causes of insecurity, but rather to look for reasons why faithful members of the Church of Jesus Christ have such a deep assurance in their lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p19" pid="9MuPWny06kawSHnv0GKgEw" hash="AU4_9w">A powerful example of this is the Prophet Joseph Smith, who searched for an explanation for the persecution he endured, yet at the same time testified to the truthfulness of his vision:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p20" pid="J10eZJae2E2U-n0hEQg-Jw" hash="Hg6e5w">“I had actually seen a light, and in the midst of that light I saw two Personages, and they did in reality speak to me; and though I was hated and persecuted for saying that I had seen a vision, yet it was true; and while they were persecuting me, reviling me, and speaking all manner of evil against me falsely for so saying, I was led to say in my heart: Why persecute me for telling the truth? I have actually seen a vision; and who am I that I can withstand God, or why does the world think to make me deny what I have actually seen? For I had seen a vision; I knew it, and I knew that God knew it, and I could not deny it, neither dared I do it; at least I knew that by so doing I would offend God, and come under condemnation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p21" pid="OcUs6hLkLESTTvnaZwzo7g" hash="PC8UYA">“I had now got my mind satisfied so far as the sectarian world was concerned” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.25-26" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:25–26</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p22" pid="kdn_LWBZGE6qUGXeAuQAiA" hash="IeEerw">What better way could he express the reality of his vision than to say, “I knew it, and I knew that God knew it”?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p23" pid="Uz254P1rp0WZqHm-IbUUjw" hash="GpTk_w">From this powerful and firm testimony, this knowledge from on high, came the assurance as portrayed by the words of the Prophet. How could it be otherwise since Joseph Smith had the sure knowledge that he knew that God knew what he knew?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p24" pid="xGhZ-2GU_0qZ2K7oYHq3IQ" hash="I85sNw">Is this pride? Definitely not. This is assurance that comes from knowing. This is a sure knowledge which, through the Holy Ghost, “shall come upon you and which shall dwell in your heart” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/8.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 8:2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p25" pid="XkJhBAB6qE6mRHPwlN_VyA" hash="KUFYwA">This is the assurance found in the lives of faithful Latter-day Saints, coming from a change brought about by the power of the Spirit, that prompts them to bear testimony of the divinity of the work. It is that same conversion, that same power, that same Spirit which Alma experienced when he called the people to repentance. In his search to remove scarecrows from the people he said, “Do ye not suppose that I know of these things myself? Behold, I testify unto you that I do know that these things whereof I have spoken are true. And how do ye suppose that I know of their surety?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p26" pid="kVW8mtUdIEWQ6K6Zf0kSHA" hash="O8RjoQ">“Behold, I say unto you they are made known unto me by the Holy Spirit of God. Behold, I have fasted and prayed many days that I might know these things of myself. And now I do know of myself that they are true; for the Lord God hath made them manifest unto me by his Holy Spirit; and this is the spirit of revelation which is in me” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.45-46" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:45–46</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p27" pid="1MIIVM2FckCn2A0OQuzilw" hash="oJbRrw">The world may claim that this is pride, but members of the Lord’s kingdom, those who do not live by borrowed light, those who have gained a testimony for themselves that this work is true, call it assurance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p28" pid="GWILSELcAkWcjNUzVv4-Hw" hash="elArgg">It is the testimony, it is the true knowledge that “God hath not given us the spirit of fear; but of power, and of love, and of a sound mind” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/1.7" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 1:7</a>). This gives us the courage, the strength, and the commitment to testify of Christ and his gospel regardless of circumstances or external factors. But for the weak, the unsure, or those who question that the Latter-day Saints are Christians, these circumstances and external factors prove to be more important than learning of Christ and gaining a testimony.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p29" pid="cv83pL8490G3WrRFNtgoxg" hash="2_j3Yg">The assurance seen in faithful members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is the result of being “doers of the word, and not hearers only” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.22" class="scriptureRef">James 1:22</a>); it is the result of striving to “live by every word that proceedeth forth from the mouth of God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.44" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:44</a>) instead of talking of God yet not conforming actions to His word, as do those who are insecure. It is this assurance, the firm testimony of thousands of missionaries who are “occupied” with all their “heart, might, mind and strength” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/4.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 4:2</a>) in serving their fellowmen, as contrasted with millions who are “preoccupied” with worldly involvements and give only lip service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p30" pid="MD2JA9bbjkmQj2egiA1F5A" hash="ml_GTQ">It is important, then, in our determination to proclaim the gospel, in our desire to clarify the thinking of confused and insecure people, in our decision to be part of that great work of our Father in Heaven “to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>), that we should remember, as King Benjamin admonished his people, to “always retain in remembrance, the greatness of God, and your own nothingness, … and humble yourselves even in the depths of humility, calling on the name of the Lord daily, and standing steadfastly in the faith” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.11" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:11</a>). “No one can assist in this work except he shall be humble” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/12.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 12:8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p31" pid="P5AWoXb0dEqg7Eo5IKqVhw" hash="Rvj7Yg">There is no guarantee of a great reward for anyone; there is no way that any of God’s children can be assured of blessings from the Most High without worthy actions in their lives. The Lord’s blessings are the fruits of obedience to the laws on which they are predicated.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p32" pid="4w7B-NRzrkaamfos30UKgQ" hash="V88ANQ">Therefore, since we do have the truth, it is fundamental that we do not be boastful about it. Our pride, if it should exist at all, along with our eternal gratitude, should arise from how we make use of that truth and the manner in which we apply it in our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p33" pid="IGb5rrP8NkqsplsKoUiK-g" hash="KNHEUw">We can pass through this mortal existence listening attentively and patiently to the best of instructions, or we can be spectators watching the expounding of great and profound principles without allowing these principles to crystalize within us by applying them in daily living.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p34" pid="qxLPqyYbzke-q7nR6FjzjQ" hash="BUWdbg">We are saved only in direct proportion to the knowledge we gain, but the simple accumulation of facts will in no way save us if we do not possess wisdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p35" pid="fglzfmxyP02-hBldDx4Wzw" hash="UksWrQ">Wisdom is not to be proclaimed or exhibited, but rather, it is to be sought, to be treasured; we need to pray for it and then express it by living a worthy life, according to the knowledge we have obtained. Change and the development of talents and hidden qualities in each of us are produced by putting into practice the knowledge we have obtained.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p36" pid="QM-mJjEdLUOu-R8FM3P_AA" hash="ntoMvA">What is most important, then, is what we do with our lives. For faithful members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, the truth is not an end in itself. Our lives are a constant quest and example of a dynamic relationship between truth and knowledge, between living and being.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p37" pid="ZCXFiPlt2ECGnSExlR_Spg" hash="Y9t3sw">As President Joseph F. Smith said, “Pure intelligence comprises not only knowledge, but also the power to properly apply that knowledge” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Doctrine,</span> 5th ed., Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1939, p. 58).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p38" pid="0_M7bo_uWkmuLWs3gSkciQ" hash="gDYE3A">In majestic clarity the Savior declared concerning this subject, “My doctrine is not mine, but his that sent me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p39" pid="gvNAafc1Y0eIKClrAHsPvA" hash="q24zug">“If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it be of God, or whether I speak of myself” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/7.16-17" class="scriptureRef">John 7:16–17</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p40" pid="-RXpptyAI0eIW-p9NpCCmA" hash="2KjFtA">It is from this principle that Latter-day Saints receive the strength of their testimonies, the assurance of their convictions, as they practice what they preach in their daily lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing.p41" pid="MTAsbnu5RUaFC15Ip1SubA" hash="gvtcog">To all those faithful Latter-day Saints who share their testimonies concerning the truthfulness of this work in the four corners of the earth, I wish to add mine, with the assurance that I know that God knows I know that The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints has the power to administer the saving ordinances that crown the efforts of all those who, through an obedient and faithful life, come unto Christ. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1988/04/assurance-that-comes-from-knowing</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1988-general-conference/1988-04-2050-elder-angel-abrea-64k-eng.mp3" length="6308571" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 1988 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patience in Affliction</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction?lang=eng</link>
      <description>At a time when persecution intensified toward the newly organized Church, the Lord said to Joseph Smith and Oliver Cowdery, “Be patient in afflictions, for thou shalt have many; but endure them, for, lo, I am with thee, even unto the end of thy days.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_92905_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="C4E8Gw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="QbmTYjCQLUyDHsA5CerrCw" hash="mMolAA">Patience in Affliction</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="tUHfOv4TAE6VAnBpl08A6g" hash="CBEvNw">Angel Abrea</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2334.jpg" alt="Elder Angel Abrea" pid="KcRzD5r9xkOIu6pKWyVPow" hash="KNnmNw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p1" pid="kHCekKAOYUexvOSRZ1imXA" hash="5ISE4g">At a time when persecution intensified toward the newly organized Church, the Lord said to Joseph Smith and Oliver Cowdery, “Be patient in afflictions, for thou shalt have many; but endure them, for, lo, I am with thee, even unto the end of thy days.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/24.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 24:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p2" pid="Ze9eE9yz10K5Ha0AVIK4ew" hash="2GI0HA">Tribulation, afflictions, and trials will constantly be with us in our sojourn here in this segment of eternity, just as the Savior said, “In the world ye shall have tribulation.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/16.33" class="scriptureRef">John 16:33</a>.) Therefore, the great challenge in this earthly life is not to determine how to escape the afflictions and problems, but rather to carefully prepare ourselves to meet them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p3" pid="Pcei_xRla0a0O0Zsa9geSA" hash="_-aotg">I say prepare ourselves because it demands persistent effort to develop patience as a personal attribute. In practicing patience, one comes to understand it and to acquire it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p4" pid="7l8QJmflOUy3mYEEZaODaA" hash="8LIyDg">From Liberty Jail, in a time of anguish and deep suffering for the gospel’s sake, the Prophet Joseph Smith wrote the following message to the Saints: “Dear brethren, do not think that our hearts faint, as though some strange thing had happened unto us, for we have seen and been assured of all these things beforehand, and have an assurance of a better hope than that of our persecutors. Therefore God hath made broad our shoulders for the burden. We glory in our tribulation, because we know that God is with us, that He is our friend, and that He will save our souls.” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith, </span>p. 123.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p5" pid="wouwQLnEiEydowN6p_AdPA" hash="xwSW-w">We must have patience in order to withstand pain and grief without complaint or discouragement, which detract from the Spirit. It’s necessary to have patience in the face of tribulation and persecution for the cause of truth, which sets an example because the manner in which we bear our cross will be an influence to others to help lighten their load.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p6" pid="mDFpaKZnUk6fiuwHzZvsdg" hash="8ErKOw">It must be in the same manner and in the same spirit as was that of the sons of Mosiah when they were entrusted with the task to “go forth among the Lamanites, thy brethren, and establish my word; yet ye shall be patient in long-suffering and afflictions, that ye may show forth good examples unto them in me, and I will make an instrument of thee in my hands unto the salvation of many souls.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/17.11" class="scriptureRef">Alma 17:11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p7" pid="JKroYAyhAU2UYgpzJIFPjA" hash="tFqgSQ">Patience must be our constant companion during the journey which carries us toward that great goal, “Continue in patience until ye are perfected,” the counsel the Lord gave to the elders of the Church. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/67.13" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 67:13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p8" pid="flFUiT9UA0COcmSdN6L3VA" hash="JFrUAA">It should be made clear that we are not talking here about a passive patience which waits only for the passing of time to heal or resolve things which <span class="emphasis">happen to us, </span>but rather a patience that is active, which <span class="emphasis">makes things happen. </span>Such was the patience Paul described in his epistle to the Romans when he used the words “by patient continuance in well doing.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/2.7" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 2:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p9" pid="sxGR6cvKs0e-PuOCht0A7w" hash="MrZxAA">Perhaps one of the best examples of patience which gives us an eternal perspective of its application in our lives is found in the words of Peter: “For what glory is it, if, when ye be buffeted for your faults, ye shall take it patiently? but if, when ye do well, and suffer for it, ye take it patiently, this is acceptable with God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-pet/2.20" class="scriptureRef">1 Pet. 2:20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p10" pid="rGYeuVJCG0ydpeKCMaT6jQ" hash="Dk4OVw">Patience in affliction and adversity means to persist firmly and never forsake that which we know to be true, standing firm with the hope that in the Lord’s due time we will gain an understanding of that which we do not understand now and which causes us suffering.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p11" pid="1A3kuDJAskOPR2DPKilXIQ" hash="CUuhXg">Then the promise in Malachi will become a reality: “Then shall ye return, and discern … between him that serveth God and him that serveth him not.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/3.18" class="scriptureRef">Mal. 3:18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p12" pid="6uRaZoPTfEK1Tis6gunU8w" hash="Vl5A4Q">Into the life of the faithful sister whose son was killed while on a mission came many questions which raced through her mind and those asked by disbelievers, creating doubts, such as, “Why was my son killed if he was a good missionary and an excellent son?” “My son was serving the Lord and was a great example to his brothers who are preparing to go into the mission field. Why?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p13" pid="jN9JFaxVv0Cc-NKHlB_jSA" hash="YyyXAA">Patience in affliction and suffering means answering as she did to all those questions: “I don’t know, nor do I have all the answers, but one thing I do know is that someday, in the Lord’s divine timetable, I shall see my son again and be reunited with him.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p14" pid="Rovnds_gxkehTeL8uVkl_Q" hash="_qp2EA">Wasn’t the reply of this sister prompted by the same spirit which gave place to the words of Nephi, “I know that he loveth his children; nevertheless, I do not know the meaning of all things”? (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/11.17" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 11:17</a>.) What a beautiful example of faith which brings a feeling of assurance while facing the unknown!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p15" pid="va1hP6N_B06w4t_qRGmsFg" hash="_XcSDw">In the face of persecution and threats to which the early Christians were subjected, patience filled with testimony was manifest in their faith and hope in Christ as recorded in the words of Paul:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p16" pid="8Q4-Y_2Kk0yKeqHVWWjqIA" hash="58bIYw">“We are troubled on every side, yet not distressed; we are perplexed, but not in despair;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p17" pid="_KeWPFuaEUyfNfJSPJPxUg" hash="Yr80Og">“Persecuted, but not forsaken; cast down, but not destroyed;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p18" pid="_0DyjfvQRUip3t24jIHPOA" hash="gXmX-Q">“Always bearing about in the body the dying of the Lord Jesus, that the life also of Jesus might be made manifest in our body. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p19" pid="-x590hM6P0SPEXKxQVI3bw" hash="dlzVMg">“Knowing that he which raised up the Lord Jesus shall raise up us also by Jesus, and shall present us with you. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p20" pid="if6H42LBQ0K0QwgLQL2Gww" hash="JB6wug">“For which cause we faint not; but though our outward man perish, yet the inward man is renewed day by day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p21" pid="0cx4vFvQOU6fPAhnmCa7cg" hash="vj0BmQ">“For our light affliction, which is but for a moment, worketh for us a far more exceeding and eternal weight of glory.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-cor/4.8-10,14,16-17" class="scriptureRef">2 Cor. 4:8–10, 14, 16–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p22" pid="V2lDZurOUUaD7iCKvwnxIg" hash="RZ23RQ">Patience in affliction and suffering describes the life of Christ, the great exemplar. In moments of great suffering and pain which transpired in Gethsemane, He was able to express in fervent prayer, “O my Father, if it be possible, let this cup pass from me: nevertheless not as I will, but as thou wilt” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/26.39" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 26:39</a>), giving us the example and a frame of reference for a life of obedience and perseverance, despite circumstances or external conditions in which we could find ourselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p23" pid="1aPraa-3qki5GIV-y3Fp1Q" hash="CVYtDA">How many times do we conclude our prayers with, “Let this cup pass from me”?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p24" pid="hgI5-KvHX0CKaw_YsJmzzQ" hash="dTa_gQ">Under circumstances when the symbolic cup might represent sickness, pain, anxiety, unemployment, or the suffering of a loved one, are we able to continue our prayer with, “Nevertheless not as I will, but as thou wilt”? This very word, this key word <span class="emphasis">nevertheless, </span>conveys the firm conviction that we are placing everything in the hands of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p25" pid="jT-Hl59LykCwDBitDm_uvQ" hash="AWHyew">When at times on life’s journey it becomes our lot to travel with the criticism of skeptics, the hate of some, the rejection of others, the impatience of many, or a friend’s betrayal, we must be able to pray in such a manner that an abiding faith and a strong testimony that the Lord will be with us to the end will compel us to say, “Nevertheless, Father, Thy will be done, and with Thy help, in patience I will follow firmly on the path that takes me back to Thee.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p26" pid="S4ZdYEL10kuyzDMxCHXkIw" hash="91Rsfw">In the year 1833, through the Prophet Joseph Smith, the Lord consoled the Saints, who had been “afflicted, and persecuted, and cast out from the land of their inheritance” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/101.1" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 101:1</a>), with words of comfort and hope, saying, “Let your hearts be comforted … ; all flesh is in mine hands; be still and know that I am God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/101.16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 101:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p27" pid="z4B2oIrmxE2omQHOATe3aQ" hash="r_5dpQ">To Enoch, who was slow of speech and in a time of great tribulation, the Lord said, “Open thy mouth, and it shall be filled, and I will give thee utterance, for all flesh is in my hands, and I will do as seemeth me good.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/6.32" class="scriptureRef">Moses 6:32</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p28" pid="3xzJJfEC6Ua40mf-ooKaLA" hash="SF7x8Q">To Joseph Smith in moments of trial, and referring to his enemies, the Lord said, “Hold on thy way, … for their bounds are set, they cannot pass.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/122.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 122:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p29" pid="pXKtKsm9PE6sx4XQW15UTg" hash="e8rafQ">These key words of counsel were given when those receiving them were passing through adverse circumstances: “all flesh is in my hands”; “know that I am God”; “I will do as seemeth me good”; “their bounds are set, they cannot pass.” In moments of trial those words appeal to patience and perseverance, founded in principles which are a testimony in and of themselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p30" pid="2BNQpuuoj0iQiAJlF69Rzw" hash="PKHssQ">In the words of the Savior, life eternal is to know God (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17:3</a>), and that implies a knowledge of His attributes and a testimony of them. To know God consists of knowing even ourselves, for as the Prophet Joseph Smith said, “If men do not comprehend the character of God, they do not comprehend themselves.” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith, </span>p. 343.) To know God is much more than to talk about God. Elder Bruce R. McConkie explained that it is “to think what he thinks, to feel what he feels.” (<span class="emphasis">Doctrinal New Testament Commentary, </span>3 vols., Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1973, 1:762.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p31" pid="fcVAThUgYky1HLEupK1ReA" hash="pcO3dA">How can we do otherwise than patiently endure the trials of life if we know God and understand that He is omnipotent? With Nephi we can say that “he is mightier than all the earth.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/4.1" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 4:1</a>.) We know and can testify of His omniscience, and with Lehi we can say, “All things have been done in the wisdom of him who knoweth all things.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.24" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p32" pid="z_N2VEhEKUyFAySTHCG5sA" hash="pv2Oog">Based on that knowledge, cemented in a strong testimony of the attributes of our Heavenly Father, the faithful Latter-day Saint—instead of despairing because a goal on his or her agenda was not realized, because his or her timetable does not bring a solution to the problems, or comfort does not come to calm the troubles of today—waits patiently for fulfillment of promises, according to the Lord’s timetable, the Lord who “knoweth all the times which are appointed unto man.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/40.10" class="scriptureRef">Alma 40:10</a>.) The faithful Latter-day Saint waits patiently because, certainly, faith, “the assurance of things hoped for” (JST, Heb. 11:1), is exercised with the conviction that the promises will be fulfilled “in his own time, and in his own way, and according to his own will.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.68" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:68</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p33" pid="LMc7Tc3M9EeEi8qosZzuSw" hash="bECYUQ">God does live and He does fulfill His promises, and to the many testimonies given, I wish to add mine. I know that even in times of affliction and tribulation, if we patiently endure in faith, blessings of comfort and hope will come into our lives, and we will be able to partake of that “incomprehensible joy” of which Ammon and his brothers received. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/27.17-18" class="scriptureRef">Alma 27:17–18</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/28.8" class="scriptureRef">Alma 28:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p34" pid="oSyj6crRoUOcQyFcGIblng" hash="J4-L5Q">Therefore, in the words of Joseph Smith, “Stand fast, ye Saints of God, hold on a little while longer, and the storm of life will be past, and you will be rewarded by that God whose servants you are, and who will duly appreciate all your toils and afflictions for Christ’s sake and the Gospel’s.” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith, </span>p. 185.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction.p35" pid="vYt2fqy1Fka_foNj0PAiqA" hash="dOXrtQ">These things I say in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1992/04/patience-in-affliction</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1992-general-conference/1992-04-2050-elder-angel-abrea-64k-eng.mp3" length="5788087" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 1992 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Own Personal Testimony</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Holy Ghost has the power to bring light and understanding to our lives, but we must pay the price to seek and win His companionship.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10033256_000_020" doc-version="2" hash="0s2Jdg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="7JV8xQClz0yFKCmgs0bu5g" hash="RW4Mbg">Your Own Personal Testimony</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="W4HP-6Nv5EydTRTlbjMLTA" hash="BC9Hdw">Elder Angel Abrea</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="Zn3qL6eu_UGRvVC82dRKMQ" hash="wEKMaQ">The Holy Ghost has the power to bring light and understanding to our lives, but we must pay the price to seek and win His companionship.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1763.jpg" alt="Elder Angel Abrea" pid="Up6vrLVO40GabPcLXfhhdA" hash="Io4yjA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.p1" pid="U58FQtLNq0GhR-CnANyBiQ" hash="7XLLnw">I would like to have an imaginary conversation about personal testimony with the priesthood holders. I believe that this colloquial way will help me to convey my message. For the purpose of our discussion, I will use the names of my grandsons; please imagine that these names are yours and that I am speaking directly to each one of you young men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.p2" pid="vWKqyuZBCUyhxdaIPwxtGw" hash="IssTjA">My dear James, when you were a young boy you bore your testimony and said, “I know the gospel is true. I know that Jesus Christ is the Son of God. I know that Joseph Smith was a true prophet.” You knew those things because others told you. Because of your trust in your parents, your bishop, and others, you never questioned that knowledge. But now, as you grow more independent in understanding, comprehension, and perception of all the different variables that this intense and beautiful life presents to you, frequently you realize that not all men have the same testimony or the “peace of God, which passeth all understanding” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/philip/4.7" class="scriptureRef">Philip. 4:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.p3" pid="veitLSMmVU-FqiB3TwPtwg" hash="Ms1v4g">Maybe, Jonathan, you have already realized that some adults are cynical and will not talk to you about the beautiful concepts of the Atonement, the Resurrection, and eternal life. Instead, they will tell you to “eat, drink, and be merry, for tomorrow we die” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/28.7" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 28:7</a>). Others you will see groping and grasping, looking for answers which they do not find. And yet they will still try to demonstrate to you a knowledge of that which they do not have. Even others will say, “Well, maybe these things are true, but maybe they aren’t. The best thing we can do is live our own lives the way we see fit, and then if there is a life after this one, we will see what happens.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.p4" pid="VBoIHM0zfU6YKkNor3xYew" hash="m8GSjw">Now, Andrew, I can understand the thoughts and feelings you may have in your mind and heart. I can understand that when you listen to these different messages, you may ask yourself what is right and what is not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.p5" pid="INPW_ipkykyoZUhXQTZU4g" hash="xEP9LQ">I’m sure that many questions have come to your mind. The truth is that you will not be condemned for wondering or questioning if you make a sincere effort to find the answer. Our mental powers have been given to us to use. Faith based on personal prayer, study, and obedience is more lasting than blind faith; it is more rewarding, and for sure it is better grounded.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.p6" pid="AaunCtT3Z0CX1E_2PnEk7A" hash="0-HaXg">And you, Paul, do you remember when the Savior said: “Verily I say unto you, Except ye be converted, and become as little children, ye shall not enter into the kingdom of heaven. Whosoever therefore shall humble himself as this little child, the same is greatest in the kingdom of heaven”? (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/18.3-4" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 18:3–4</a>). We are benefited by retaining the humility and teachableness of a child, but we must be sure to continue growing and not be content with the limited knowledge or comprehension of the gospel which a child has. Remember, Paul, what the Apostle of your same name said to the Corinthians: “Brethren, be not children in understanding: howbeit in malice be ye children, but in understanding be men” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/14.20" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 14:20</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.p7" pid="Cd8pNGItbEWkYdGmhrJsmw" hash="WrxHwQ">Well now, my dear Russell, you will ask yourself, “In that case, do I have to go and look for the answer myself? Can anybody have this kind of testimony? Is it a gift only for a few? Do those who say they <span class="emphasis">know</span> really only <span class="emphasis">think</span> they know, or have they convinced themselves through a psychological trick?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.p8" pid="lz0wmk3ag0W4C4Ltv0EnGw" hash="dwWjFg">In answer to your questions, and to give more light to these things, let me tell you that Elder John A. Widtsoe said that those who truly have a testimony of the gospel have “the highest type of knowledge. It comes as a revelation when truth is known and obeyed. … It is really <span class="emphasis">man’s chief possession</span>” (“What Does It Mean to Have a Testimony?” <span class="emphasis">Improvement Era,</span> May 1945, 273; emphasis added). Do you realize that a testimony is defined as “the highest type of knowledge” and “man’s chief possession” and that in the Doctrine and Covenants the Savior mentions it as a knowledge “which shall dwell in your heart”? (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/8.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 8:2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.p9" pid="kDXosPnnXEu9u9Uxcu3Zlg" hash="gIOQdQ">Maybe it will be difficult to understand this at your age, but our testimony is something that we will take with us to the next life. We will leave all our earthly possessions behind, but that knowledge, that inner conviction, will remain with us. Think of Joseph Smith: those who took his life could not take his chief possession—his testimony. The Prophet Joseph took that priceless possession with him through death’s veil into eternity, where the Lord had promised him “a throne for you in the kingdom of my Father” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/132.49" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 132:49</a>). But at the same time, that testimony, together with “a fame and name that cannot be slain” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/135.3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 135:3</a>), remains here with us. We hear the resounding witness of God’s Prophet testifying “that [Christ] lives! For we saw him, even on the right hand of God; and we heard the voice bearing record that he is the Only Begotten of the Father” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.22-23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:22–23</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.p10" pid="5Ov47Ogw00ytNfbIM2ZmQQ" hash="soY-MA">My dear Matthew, now that you have been able to see the eternal dimension of a testimony, we can continue with our conversation, showing that you can have your own testimony if you do what is necessary to obtain one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.p11" pid="h9WD_1lQn0mu9JjxBTLqzA" hash="6V1UPg">In one of those difficult times that the faithful and dedicated young Nephi had with his rebellious brothers, he reminded them of the following guide to obtaining a testimony. The Lord declared, “If ye will not harden your hearts, and ask me in faith, believing that ye shall receive, with diligence in keeping my commandments, surely these things shall be made known unto you” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/15.11" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 15:11</a>). Now, we can review the steps Nephi described.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.p12" pid="cPdpfk2XH0yKGxuD08D6PA" hash="b2NpmA">First, <span class="emphasis">don’t harden your heart.</span> Seek to know. In other words, have an intense, consuming desire to know. Give place for a seed to be planted in your heart. And if you do this, do you know what the promise is? Alma tells us, “He that will not harden his heart, to him is given … to know the mysteries of God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/12.10" class="scriptureRef">Alma 12:10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.p13" pid="RYOf36DnhE-n8eSs7SEQnA" hash="tN5qzw">Second, <span class="emphasis">ask in faith.</span> In your study of the scriptures, have you noted how many times the phrase “believing that ye shall receive” accompanies the commandment of praying and asking? In the process of asking for knowledge, we have to exercise faith—believing before receiving. To illustrate this part of our conversation, Alma gives us a good example when he explained how he obtained his testimony:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.p14" pid="G7Tmr5U1hkC7nM5KNJil4g" hash="5nsnwA">“Behold, I have fasted and prayed many days that I might know these things of myself. And now I do know of myself that they are true; for the Lord God hath made them manifest unto me by his Holy Spirit; and this is the spirit of revelation which is in me” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.46" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:46</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.p15" pid="XUD_EAmFeEawtmRTzusP8A" hash="A3erfw">Third, <span class="emphasis">keep the commandments.</span> I think that the words of the Book of Mormon point out the blessings that we can obtain if we abound in good works. King Benjamin declared to his people, “If you believe all these things see that ye do them” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.10" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:10</a>). And the great missionary Ammon said, “Yea, he that repenteth and exerciseth faith, and bringeth forth good works, and prayeth continually without ceasing—unto such it is given to know the mysteries of God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/26.22" class="scriptureRef">Alma 26:22</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.p16" pid="O9moLbcvekK9yeby8O3ecw" hash="VB06oA">Now, Cole, we have analyzed the different steps we should follow in our search for a testimony. But there is yet the most important help available that can give us confirmation and absolute assurance, and it is your right when you live worthy to receive the companionship of the Holy Ghost. Remember the promise in Moroni: “And by the power of the Holy Ghost ye may know the truth of all things” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.5" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:5</a>). Pay attention that I said to <span class="emphasis">receive</span> the companionship of the Holy Ghost. The Holy Ghost has the power to bring light and understanding to our lives, but we must pay the price to seek and win His companionship.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.p17" pid="T8lAi-yg7Ui1nPuS0GT3Fg" hash="YmVAqw">Elder Marion G. Romney once wrote: “It is the mission of the Holy Ghost to reveal the truth of heaven to those who qualify to receive it. Every one of us, if we will, may so qualify. We must ever keep in mind, however, that he will not dwell in an unholy environment. He is used to the society of God, for he is an associate of the Father and the Son. When we receive the gift of the Holy Ghost, we are commanded to receive him; he is not commanded to come to us. But if, with all our hearts, we truly seek him, he will come to us and guide us in the making of decisions at every crisis of our lives” (“Revelation in Our Personal Affairs,” <span class="emphasis">Relief Society Magazine,</span> Oct. 1955, 647). The Holy Ghost is given to us to witness of the Father and the Son; that Jesus Christ is our Redeemer; that there is a prophet upon the earth who presides over the true Church that carries the Savior’s name, even The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints; and that all the works and promises of God will be fulfilled in His time and in His own way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony.p18" pid="GFr7s7V990mCrGNJJF5q2w" hash="v4kbzA">And now, my youngest grandson, Tate, we can end this conversation, mentioning what a testimony is. Maybe the best way to define it would be by looking at what a testimony represents in our lives. It is to say, “I will go and do the things which the Lord hath commanded, for I know” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 3:7</a>), and then to act in consequence. It is to have the peace that comes with knowing that all possible has been done, that all talents have been exercised to the maximum. It is to follow the commandment of the Lord to Joshua: “Be strong and of a good courage; be not afraid, neither be thou dismayed: for the Lord thy God is with thee whithersoever thou goest” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/1.9" class="scriptureRef">Josh. 1:9</a>). And it is to “be patient in afflictions” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/31.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 31:9</a>). It is to never give up, but to stand up as an example to others. It is to “be ready always to give an answer to every man that asketh you a reason of the hope that is in you with meekness and fear” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-pet/3.15" class="scriptureRef">1 Pet. 3:15</a>). It is to declare His generation: “Jesus Christ [is] the Son of God, the Father of heaven and earth, the Creator of all things from the beginning” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/3.8" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 3:8</a>). Yes, these and many other characteristics and actions model a testimony. And this is my testimony to you in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2000/04/your-own-personal-testimony</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2000-general-conference/2000-04-3030-elder-angel-abrea-64k-eng.mp3" length="5913218" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
