<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Anne C. Pingree</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Anne C. Pingree.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Anne%20C.%20Pingree.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Anne C. Pingree.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2002 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2002 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Charity: One Family, One Home at a Time</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As covenant women, … we can alter the face of the earth one family and one home at a time through charity, our small and simple acts of pure love.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029898_000_037" doc-version="2" hash="vtWdSQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Ysb9bM6iLEuf9lkvJyOqYw" hash="rCD-qg">Charity:</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="_bd-RGHJLEuzAvPmj0_dXQ" hash="V88yvQ">One Family, One Home at a Time</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="F49_Byc_PUu8fuxbXfwuDw" hash="2a9k5w">Anne C. Pingree</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="khmhF5Nfyk-xDrCdLz7NZg" hash="h7Q9lQ">As covenant women, … we can alter the face of the earth one family and one home at a time through charity, our small and simple acts of pure love.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-aa9.jpg" alt="Anne C. Pingree" pid="ywgpk_p6202D24T64z2Sfg" hash="yT6ONQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time.p1" pid="-ZOc6pgttk-Rrz-8H0nyMA" hash="y4ejgg">Some years ago my husband and I visited the eastern sector of Berlin, Germany. Chunks of what was once the infamous wall dividing the citizens of that city were lying about—preserved as a memorial to the triumph of freedom over bondage. Written on one piece of the wall in bold, uneven red letters were these words: <span class="emphasis">“Many small people in many small places doing many small things can alter the face of the earth.”</span> To me that phrase speaks of what each of us—as covenant women—can do to make a difference as we step forward offering our hearts and hands to the Lord by lifting and loving others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time.p2" pid="9C2pCgGHYkq3kFX6tr4gHQ" hash="ecKNig">It matters not whether we are new converts or lifelong members; single, married, divorced, or widowed; whether we’re rich, poor, educated, or uneducated; living in a modern city or in the most remote jungle village. We, as covenant women, have consecrated ourselves to the cause of Christ through our baptismal and temple covenants. We can alter the face of the earth <span class="emphasis">one family and one home at a time</span> through charity, our small and simple acts of pure love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time.p3" pid="XZxIymL35k2SnADobfPLbg" hash="bN6ABg">Charity, the Savior’s pure love, is the “highest, noblest, strongest kind of love,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> which we “pray unto the Father with all the energy of heart”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> to possess. Elder Dallin H. Oaks teaches us that charity “is not an <span class="emphasis">act</span> but a <span class="emphasis">condition</span> or state of being [one becomes].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Our day-to-day offerings of charity are “written not with ink, but with the Spirit of the living God; … in [the] fleshy tables of [our] heart[s].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Little by little our charitable acts change our natures, define our characters, and ultimately make us women with the courage and commitment to say to the Lord, “Here am I; send me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time.p4" pid="aBBaTKetNEiuyxU7qjYP-Q" hash="9j5aWA">As our exemplar, the Savior showed us what charity means through His own actions. Besides ministering to multitudes, Jesus demonstrated the depth of His love and care for His family. Even while suffering terrible agony on the cross, He thought of His mother and her needs:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time.p5" pid="mignv0YKxESHclzOVZfMjQ" hash="YFADdg">“Now there stood by the cross of Jesus his mother. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time.p6" pid="21BS5M9ijky-i09Y4zPqlQ" hash="n9mvkg">“When Jesus therefore saw his mother, and the disciple standing by, whom he loved, he saith unto his mother, Woman, behold thy son!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time.p7" pid="Q1HdZw63A0CKz_Q7cS1wJA" hash="OO3UIA">“Then saith he to the disciple, Behold thy mother! And from that hour that disciple took her unto his own home.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time.p8" pid="257IGRqmYEeK-pD0PA1zSA" hash="99EahA">I find it touching that this scripture shows the depth of John’s devotion to Mary by saying that he “took her unto his own home.” I believe the most important acts of charity are small and simple in nature, eternal in consequence, and are rendered within the walls of our own homes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time.p9" pid="5DSQWLxVhESIDOeJ91fz_g" hash="bvGf4A">As we try to deal patiently and lovingly every day with fussy babies, challenging teenagers, difficult roommates, less-active spouses, or elderly, disabled parents, we may ask ourselves: “Is what I am doing really important? Does it matter or make a difference?” Dear sisters, what you are doing with your families <span class="emphasis">matters!</span> It matters so very, very much. Daily, each of us learns and relearns at home that charity, the Savior’s pure love, never faileth. So many Relief Society sisters do great good serving in their families. These faithful women do not receive the praise of the world—nor do they seek it—but “of some have compassion, making a difference.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time.p10" pid="362cVeBsckWA9WZB46iKCg" hash="xME9Cg">Who are these women who make a difference? In Nauvoo our early Relief Society sisters, in the midst of grinding poverty, opened their hearts and welcomed into their homes many new converts streaming into the city. They shared their food, their clothing, and more important, <span class="emphasis">they shared their faith</span> in the redeeming love of the Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time.p11" pid="AInYJhzuTEWVhZtKM_SGVg" hash="1DyFpg">In our times, Sister Knell is a covenant woman who makes a difference. She is a widow in her 80s with a 47-year-old son, mentally and physically disabled from birth. A few years ago this dear sister set out to do what seemed impossible to everyone else—to teach her son Keith to read. Learning to read was his greatest desire, but doctors had said Keith was incapable of reading. With faith in her heart and a desire to bless her son’s life, this humble widow said to her son, “I know Heavenly Father will bless you so you can read the Book of Mormon.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time.p12" pid="KIIp2miPwUW7_DlmC5U1jw" hash="4U5kFg">Sister Knell wrote the following: “It was hard work for Keith, and it wasn’t easy for me, either. At first there were some bad days, because I got upset. It has been a time-consuming, word-by-word struggle. I sit by his side each morning. I point to each word with a pencil to help him stay on track. After seven long years and one month, Keith finally finished reading the Book of Mormon.” His mother said, “Hearing him read a verse without help is a thrill I just cannot put into words.” She testifies, “I know miracles do happen when we put our trust in the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time.p13" pid="sdJfU3CHRkOPW4yakLB2lw" hash="L2oN7w">Throughout the world in Africa, Asia, the Pacific, North and South America, and Europe, charitable women, united with their families, also make a difference in their communities. On the tiny island of Trinidad, Sister Ramoutar, a busy branch Relief Society president, and her family are helping neighborhood children. The Ramoutars live in a village that is a “drug-infested” place where many parents and adults are addicted to alcohol or are trafficking in drugs. The children are at great risk and are often without supervision. Many do not attend school.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time.p14" pid="Y9cAaXpHekyAzpie4lDWYw" hash="dn-uiw">Every Thursday night, as many as 30 children, ages 3 to 19 years, sit in the covered area outside of the Ramoutar home, eagerly participating in a group known as “Our One Big Happy Family.” Prayers, hymns, fun songs, and the sharing of good deeds done by the children each week are part of the activities. Sometimes doctors, policemen, teachers, or our own missionaries share useful lessons such as President Gordon B. Hinckley’s six B’s. The Ramoutar family rescues children through their small and simple acts of charity. As they have shared the gospel in their “One Big Happy Family,” others have joined the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time.p15" pid="xceNBukj9kuiSEClKLHP3w" hash="wfAtjA">Beloved Relief Society sisters, I know that wherever we live, in whatever circumstances we find ourselves, we, as covenant women, united in righteousness, can alter the face of the earth. I testify as did Alma that “by small and simple things are great things brought to pass.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> In our homes, those small and simple things—our daily acts of charity—proclaim our conviction, “Here am I; send me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time.p16" pid="s0ve01tFNUSvtXANpMJXtw" hash="dsWagg">I leave my witness that the greatest act of charity in time and all eternity was the Atonement of Jesus Christ. He willingly laid down His life to atone for my sins and yours. I express my devotion to His cause and my desire to serve Him always, wherever He calls me, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2002/10/charity-one-family-one-home-at-a-time</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2002-general-relief-society-meeting/2002-09-0030-anne-c-pingree-64k-eng.mp3" length="9297332" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2002 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choose Ye Therefore Christ the Lord</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2003/10/choose-ye-therefore-christ-the-lord?lang=eng</link>
      <description>When a woman chooses to have Christ at the center of her own heart, … she brings the Lord into the core of her home and family.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choose-ye-therefore-christ-the-lord" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030835_000_038" doc-version="2" hash="JN40Qg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choose-ye-therefore-christ-the-lord.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="9kfQLI9rj0C-Ic2ZkF4-7g" hash="KvOp7A">Choose Ye Therefore Christ the Lord</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="DyFbu3CLPEWbwHmsF_i-_Q" hash="2a9k5w">Anne C. Pingree</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="6raUJ9G01Eyv5IrjnC1YPw" hash="ujU2cg">When a woman chooses to have Christ at the center of her own heart, … she brings the Lord into the core of her home and family.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choose-ye-therefore-christ-the-lord.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-aa9.jpg" alt="Anne C. Pingree" pid="2Rxk4o9mqUyRlBaQ_C7NAw" hash="yT6ONQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choose-ye-therefore-christ-the-lord.p1" pid="NIeRPzzaOk-ho3FpKJJw1w" hash="-wy46A">Sisters, it is a glorious doctrine to me that we can choose to give Christ <span class="emphasis">all</span> our heart—that we can choose to put our Savior and Redeemer at the center of our heart. In each of us, the restored gospel of Jesus Christ can be “written not with ink, but with the Spirit of the living God; not in tables of stone, but in fleshy tables of the heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> We chose to follow Christ in our first estate. What joyful news it is that we can choose Him each day during our sojourn on earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choose-ye-therefore-christ-the-lord.p2" pid="iiBzfxU6P0qWWNeMl9lXdA" hash="N9Emjw">As covenant women living in many nations, it is essential to have Christ at the core of our lives. In these “perilous times,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> oh, how we need Him! He is the source of strength and safety. He is light. He is life. His peace “passeth all understanding.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> As our personal Savior and Redeemer, He invites us, one by one, with outstretched arms to “come unto him”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> in the most personal ways. Sisters, when a woman accepts the Savior’s invitation, she is strengthened individually, and others are blessed through her righteous influence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choose-ye-therefore-christ-the-lord.p3" pid="bdtiRKC4o0-pckqwnHHn-g" hash="sSSLeA">I believe when a woman chooses to have Christ at the center of her own heart, at the nucleus of her personal world, she brings the Lord into the core of her home and family, be it a family of one or a family of many. Wherever she lives and whatever her circumstances, as the <span class="emphasis">heart</span> of the home and the family, what is in each woman’s heart is reflected in the environment and spirit of her home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choose-ye-therefore-christ-the-lord.p4" pid="CY1pYVe9a0W77xKi_QPHIg" hash="dkfExw">While we were on an assignment in Japan, a Church leader invited us to visit his home. We were honored to have this opportunity but wondered what his wife would think of her husband’s last-minute invitation to bring visitors from Salt Lake City home. En route, the man telephoned his wife, giving her what seemed to me about 15 minutes to prepare for this unexpected company.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choose-ye-therefore-christ-the-lord.p5" pid="nNKHZfu0sUO2_CGef287Kg" hash="kUdtUw">From the moment we stepped inside the front door, slipped off our shoes, and were graciously greeted by a young, soft-spoken Relief Society sister, I sensed a spirit of order, peace, and love. Little children scurried upstairs carrying their playthings. In this family of eight, with seven still living at home, it was clear what the family valued. Evidences of the Lord were all around—pictures of the Savior on the wall, a family photograph and picture of the temple in a prominent place, copies of well-used scriptures and Church videos neatly stacked on a nearby shelf. “The fruit of the Spirit, … love, joy, peace, … gentleness, goodness, faith,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> seemed to reside in that home. I imagined the small room filled with children of all ages as parents sat around the low table to “talk of Christ, [to] rejoice in Christ, [to] preach of Christ, [to] prophesy of Christ, … that [their] children may know to what source they may look for a remission of their sins.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> I sensed the answer the children in this home would give to the question posed by Elder Jeffrey R. Holland: “Do [our] children know that we love God with all our heart and that we long to see the face—and fall at the feet—of His Only Begotten Son?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> I believe the response to that question in this Japanese home would be a resounding <span class="emphasis">yes!</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choose-ye-therefore-christ-the-lord.p6" pid="Pc-uWxx4_k61ALYpn33Z1w" hash="5GwHCw">When a woman chooses to have Christ at the center of her heart, she’s choosing not only to practice Christlike behavior each day but also to teach her family to do the same. And as you know, dear sisters, it’s in that daily business of practicing Christlike behavior that we have some of our greatest challenges.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choose-ye-therefore-christ-the-lord.p7" pid="LRQGo0x1gE6vpK4QhoXIqg" hash="5H-K3A">One mother did her best to teach the steps of repentance in her home. Then came the day she helped her five-year-old son internalize the principles when she accompanied him to the store to account for a candy bar he had stolen. That experience is one the boy will <span class="emphasis">never</span> forget. He learned firsthand about taking responsibility for his actions. With fear in his heart, he returned the candy bar, offered an apology to the store manager, and promised never to steal again. I am pleased to report that he has kept that promise. I know—because I was the mother, and my son was the five-year-old.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choose-ye-therefore-christ-the-lord.p8" pid="loKuKAvnf0ag_piu63iVVw" hash="EJ2NUQ">Experiences like that come into every family, even when we work hard to ground our beloved children, grandchildren, nieces, and nephews in the gospel. “Trying to be like Jesus”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> does take practice, which then becomes habit. Choosing to make Christ the center of our hearts aids us in so many ways as we strive to teach others to put the Lord into their hearts. Sometimes we feel we are not making much progress, but on those discouraging days, I remember the comforting words of the Savior: “Be not weary in well-doing, for ye are laying the foundation of a great work.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choose-ye-therefore-christ-the-lord.p9" pid="wnCoXpU_i0-mBvk07EKkVw" hash="RIk1sA">As we choose that good part and put the Savior in the center of our lives by praying daily for His guidance and help, God gives us “power and wisdom.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> We are blessed with spiritual insights that can fortify our families. When Doug, the father of three small children, unexpectedly lost his job, unemployment benefits plus their small savings and some help from the extended family were the means of his family’s support. His wife, Lori, tried to be positive as they both took odd jobs to help cover their expenses. They continued doing all the right things—praying, reading the scriptures, attending the temple, and paying tithing. Yet in spite of hundreds of résumés and many inquiries, job interviews were few, and no job offer was forthcoming.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choose-ye-therefore-christ-the-lord.p10" pid="sjeYc0GnrkuGuiBinbQ16A" hash="fcNo6g">One day after almost six months of job searching, Lori called her mother. Tearfully and with some anger in her voice, she said: “I don’t think Heavenly Father is listening to us. I don’t think I can pray anymore. It doesn’t do any good.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choose-ye-therefore-christ-the-lord.p11" pid="2rRFnQD5dUe6D2NBCZMiRg" hash="0xTZyA">During that telephone conversation, inspired words and thoughts came to Lori’s mother as she bore her testimony and reminded her daughter of things she already knew: “Lori, you know better. You know that Heavenly Father loves you and is aware of your needs. But sometimes you have to wait. Perhaps this is your refiner’s fire. I don’t know. But what I do know is this: You need to go into your bedroom right now and kneel and pray, asking the Lord to comfort you and give you peace. Doug <span class="emphasis">will</span> find a job, but it may take a while longer. Remember all who love you and who are praying for you and who are helping you. You are very blessed.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choose-ye-therefore-christ-the-lord.p12" pid="GRWZ7MfiyESb4wEeiLyrNw" hash="7bxBkw">What Lori realized was that when she knelt down and prayed—because she was focused on the Lord—she redirected her thoughts. She brought the Savior’s love into her own life and into her home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choose-ye-therefore-christ-the-lord.p13" pid="KNnZUVZGmUqcjeZE4jiU4Q" hash="jFTA-Q">Dear sisters, I have felt the love of the Lord often in my life. On the good days and on those days when I have felt unequal to the challenges before me, I have turned to the Lord for help. I testify that He is <span class="emphasis">always</span> there, His merciful, loving arms outstretched to me and to you. With all my heart I declare that Jesus Christ is my strength. He is my hope. He is my Savior and Redeemer. With you I say, “As for <span class="emphasis">me</span> and <span class="emphasis">my house,</span> we will serve the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2003/10/choose-ye-therefore-christ-the-lord</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2003-general-relief-society-meeting/2003-09-0030-anne-c-pingree-64k-eng.mp3" length="4646452" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2003 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seeing the Promises Afar Off</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Faith, the spiritual ability to be persuaded of promises that are seen “afar off” … , is a sure measure of those who truly believe.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030835_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="16xFAw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="eTSYpXcBBkmSfojsQbYxJQ" hash="ci-AMQ">Seeing the Promises Afar Off</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="huctsBwrm0SOnfEsUndttQ" hash="2a9k5w">Anne C. Pingree</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="xDmmr6yMHUuSn1xiNJMOJA" hash="MxrF9w">Faith, the spiritual ability to be persuaded of promises that are seen “afar off” … , is a sure measure of those who truly believe.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-aa9.jpg" alt="Anne C. Pingree" pid="xVfXdSPPeEiVrcFS9DQSow" hash="yT6ONQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p1" pid="pMHjUnH6_kKWVY1R82bTYg" hash="TXb8uA">I will never forget a sauna-hot day in the lush rain forest of southeastern Nigeria. My husband and I had traveled to one of the most remote locations in our mission so he could conduct temple recommend interviews with members in the Ikot Eyo district. Some in this growing district had been Church members less than two years. All the members lived 3,000 miles away from the nearest temple in Johannesburg, South Africa. None had received their temple endowment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p2" pid="ONMkjKFfQkGSS12RZQ69HA" hash="eUSFHw">These members knew the appointed day each month we would come to their district, but even we didn’t know the exact hour we would arrive; nor could we call, for telephones were rare in that part of West Africa. So these committed African Saints gathered early in the morning to wait all day if necessary for their temple recommend interviews. When we arrived, I noticed among those waiting in the searing heat were two Relief Society sisters dressed in bold-patterned wrappers, white blouses, and the traditional African head-ties.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p3" pid="QjnNFr7Jt0eIYTVWpGhjww" hash="YaQpwQ">Many hours later, after all the interviews were completed, as my husband and I drove back along that sandy jungle trail, we were stunned when we saw these two sisters still walking. We realized they had trekked from their village—a distance of 18 miles round trip—just to obtain a temple recommend they knew they would never have the privilege of using.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p4" pid="LXKnxbxuIkWgbGKFCdG5TA" hash="7ar_2A">These Nigerian Saints believed the counsel of President Howard W. Hunter: “It would please the Lord for every adult member to be worthy of—and to carry—a current temple recommend, even if proximity to a temple does not allow immediate or frequent use of it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> In her hand, carefully wrapped in a clean handkerchief, each sister carried her precious temple recommend. I carry their examples of faith carefully wrapped in my heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p5" pid="l7nJeJwuzkWrDNwseo8uOg" hash="z1fRdA">These two covenant Relief Society sisters embody the meaning of Alma’s teaching “concerning faith—faith is <span class="emphasis">not </span>to have a perfect knowledge of things; therefore if ye have faith ye <span class="emphasis">hope</span> for things which are <span class="emphasis">not seen,</span> which are <span class="emphasis">true.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p6" pid="o9VWr_MfFkWDGXVezqm9AA" hash="QRg3BA">Faith is the most personal reflection of adoration for—and devotion to—our Heavenly Father and His Only Begotten Son, Jesus Christ. Anchored by this first and all-important principle of the gospel, we look to our Savior, knowing “Jesus [is] the author and finisher of our faith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p7" pid="SrPKMcOXEUuy8PNlBbmZCA" hash="Abq-lA">My great-great-aunt, Laura Clark Phelps, was the first member of the Clark family who joined the Church. She was a woman who uniquely demonstrated a faith in the Lord that stands fast, nothing wavering.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p8" pid="289rz6eU4EeJIcA3z87Viw" hash="A1ON7A">Laura’s legacy teaches much about the doctrine of faith as “the substance of things hoped for, the evidence of things not seen.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> She received her patriarchal blessing from Joseph Smith Sr. In it she was counseled to be faithful and she would have an inheritance in Zion. She was further told to “call upon God in faith, and if thou wilt thou shall have all of the desires of thine heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p9" pid="HQkmzpUqzE2TVT3YVw-Uuw" hash="v5YccA">Laura and her husband knew the Prophet Joseph Smith. On one occasion, the Prophet and his brother Hyrum came running to their farm outside Far West, Missouri, where Laura hid them behind the clothes curtain. She calmly faced the mob leaders who rushed in shortly afterwards in search of the Prophet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p10" pid="wXSE_Zb2VUGyTLPnWZPGDg" hash="zJXUqg">Laura experienced the joys and privations of the early Church members in this dispensation. Her faith deepened as she was driven from her homes and separated from her husband on various occasions. As an efficient midwife, she worked and traveled day and night in all kinds of weather to help provide for her family. This overexertion and exposure took their toll. She died at the young age of 34, leaving behind her husband and five children. She did not live to see her children, her grandchildren, or her great-grandchildren following her in faith. She did not experience the blessings of receiving her own temple endowment in this earth life, blessings I believe she would have cherished.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p11" pid="5m3oas22Dky4EWVOre-TJQ" hash="-oZsbQ">Laura’s faithful life bears witness of this verse from Hebrews: “These all died in faith, not having received the promises, but having seen them afar off, and were persuaded of them, and embraced them, and confessed that they were strangers and pilgrims on the earth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> Faith lived in Laura, and Laura lived her faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p12" pid="D9wDvvfUpE2crOlBPsG3GA" hash="jFy9Xw">I love my great-great-aunt Laura and carry her example in my heart. She, like those Relief Society sisters in Nigeria, reminds me “all things are possible to [them] that [believe].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p13" pid="WLGZYs5H2EqYElGWwftRBA" hash="CXtw1w">Faith, the spiritual ability to be persuaded of promises that are seen “afar off” but that may not be attained in this life, is a sure measure of those who truly believe. Elder Bruce R. McConkie expressed this truth in these words: “Faith in its full and pure form requires an unshakable assurance and … absolute confidence that [God] will hear our pleas and grant our petitions”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> in His own due time. Believing that, we too can “stand fast in the faith”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> today and tomorrow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p14" pid="wp0e2NUCX0OJB3eeugCxEw" hash="IT6QLQ">It matters not where we live or what our individual circumstances may be. Each day our righteous living can demonstrate a faith in Jesus Christ that sees beyond mortal heartaches, disappointments, and unfulfilled promises. It is a glorious thing to possess a faith that enables us to look forward to that day “when all that was promised the Saints will be given.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p15" pid="Wf2t-LpdDEelAD_9JJ4FXg" hash="Ndp2zQ">As they walked with faith in every footstep along that sandy jungle trail in West Africa, those valiant Nigerian sisters could not have imagined that the walls of a holy temple of God would one day rise in their own nation. They could not have imagined that the inspired words of another prophet of God, President Gordon B. Hinckley, would bring the promised blessings they hoped for and had seen “afar off.” They only knew that the Lord restored His gospel in these times, that a testimony of that gospel burned in their hearts, that faith lit their way in life. Then they acted on a prophet’s counsel to be worthy and to carry a temple recommend.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p16" pid="HIWnQHUcsUCFUp7E-nmysw" hash="qWXWzg">My husband and I tenderly recalled these sisters and so many other West African Saints on that remarkable day in April 2000 when President Gordon B. Hinckley said, “We announce at this conference that we hope to build a house of the Lord in Aba, Nigeria.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Brothers and sisters, I testify that sometimes “miracles … confirm … faith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> The temples of Africa are a magnificent representation of miracles wrought by the faith of so many Saints in the small villages and large cities spread across that vast continent.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p17" pid="bipGaYT3k0aQ_WacHymy3g" hash="nep5rg">I am deeply grateful that I have seen the faith that brought two pioneers in Africa many miles to a temple recommend interview. I rejoice that the temple in progress in Nigeria will bring these women, their families, and thousands more the opportunity to use their recommends as both a symbol and embodiment of their faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p18" pid="FqGXI8WHzkC2Z7so81cD6Q" hash="k0EFuw">Sometimes those blessings in our lives that we have yet to receive lie beyond the scope of mortal eyes. I testify that it is always faith that allows us to see “afar off” with spiritual vision all that God intends for His children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off.p19" pid="CTrwxpn3CEeyRmBfasIhxw" hash="SiK0oA">Just as surely as the sisters knew—who walked along that sandy jungle trail—I know that God lives. He loves each of us on every continent and desires to bless us one by one. I know that our faith in Jesus Christ can sustain us each day as we “do all things that lie in our power,” knowing with the “utmost assurance”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> that those promises we may see “afar off” will one day bring all the blessings we hope for. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2003/10/seeing-the-promises-afar-off</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2003-general-conference/2003-10-1040-anne-c-pingree-64k-eng.mp3" length="5228494" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2003 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Walking towards the Light of His Love</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Connections forged among covenant women in Relief Society can … enlighten, enliven, and enrich the journey of life.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030208_000_038" doc-version="2" hash="nT3IAA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="lI26-KeCGUOo7fYy_b4NxA" hash="HfVGng">Walking towards the Light of His Love</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="eBZAZa8VgU-AP8H0vM9QTQ" hash="2a9k5w">Anne C. Pingree</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="YGbEDKhPskW6H3FotYPDEQ" hash="3fz0PQ">Connections forged among covenant women in Relief Society can … enlighten, enliven, and enrich the journey of life.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-103.jpg" alt="Anne C. Pingree" pid="gX6hMSN10USCkO0E3IhX6w" hash="xJIXZA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.p1" pid="WI9GmehBmUez5qOdlIQG5w" hash="2PIGNQ">In the early spring mornings as the sun took a first peek over the mountains, Jan and I started walking together. As newly assigned visiting teaching partners, we were both young mothers with growing families and busy, demanding schedules.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.p2" pid="5LN06b3MZkenfU_7bdqtmA" hash="5PFVfA">Jan and her family were recent move-ins to our ward, and I wasn’t sure what we would talk about. Struggling, out of breath, up and down the inclines of a nearby mountain road, we walked and talked day after day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.p3" pid="dPxRPSh7WEO7yvv5uTAsrg" hash="De7Z_A">In the beginning, our conversations were lighthearted chatter about our husbands and children, their interests, and the schools in the area. Little by little we opened our hearts to one another, processing spiritual ideas and delving into our experiences to find the kernels of truth. It seemed as we worked to get our bodies in shape, we began to get our souls in shape. I loved this wonderful exertion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.p4" pid="RjDTqWWgXECaOsOag6_1ig" hash="Qgx8KA">I learned two unforgettable lessons from my journey with Jan that continue to enlighten my mind and fill my soul with joy. The first is that whatever the circumstances in your life, if you are spiritually prepared, there is no need to fear (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.30" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:30</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.p5" pid="XrjXvuzil0m090tPjCyflw" hash="l30xIQ">Long after we began our walks together, I discovered that years earlier Jan had made choices which took her step-by-step away from the Church and down a path she now regretted. About the time our lives intersected, she had determined to put her life in order. The longing in her heart was to prepare herself so that she could be sealed to her husband and children in the temple. Hers was a single-minded yearning, as Nephi phrased it, “[to] be reconciled unto Christ, and enter into the narrow gate, and walk in the strait path which leads to life, and continue in the path until the end of the day of probation” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/33.9" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 33:9</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.p6" pid="AgV8mx0trEeqNNVtjr_lAQ" hash="cWslAQ">You might expect that once Jan had determined as earnestly as Lamoni’s father in the Book of Mormon to “give away all [her] sins to know [the Lord]” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/22.18" class="scriptureRef">Alma 22:18</a>), her journey would be smoothed. Such was not the case. She was faced with some of life’s most soul-wrenching trials. Jan was diagnosed with a brain tumor, her husband lost his job, then the family lost their home and their car.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.p7" pid="ere9WUJCDkympog2xVGoGw" hash="uYEfEA">Yet Jan’s faith in Jesus Christ grew steadier as her way grew harder. As we trudged along together on our morning walks, I learned so much from Jan about how her faith in the Lord and daily spiritual preparation helped her conquer fear. She seemed to understand perfectly what President Gordon B. Hinckley has taught: “We would be wise to kneel before our God in supplication. He will help us. He will bless us. He will comfort and sustain us” (<span class="emphasis">Standing for Something</span> [2000], 178).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.p8" pid="gropFqTt80GwdH3LqGayEg" hash="_mCkTg">Although she was in the midst of terrible trials, it was obvious to me that Jan knew our prophet’s words are true. She never stopped her personal spiritual preparation as she moved forward fearlessly a day at a time with a radiant sense of calmness in her life. Over the course of those early hours together, I literally watched “the morning [break], the shadows flee … [and] the dawning of a brighter day” (“The Morning Breaks,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 1) as Jan’s repentance brought her a release from sins and then a deeply personal spiritual enlightenment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.p9" pid="3rbAZ4GH30aSZNWwUEnQAg" hash="HP5uWA">I asked Jan how she had come to feel peace when her life was in such turmoil and things were collapsing all around her. I believe the words of a hymn capture best what she felt and subsequently shared with me about the power of the Atonement in her life:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="uFtF3HaED0CAv6US3xcH_A" hash="XErSOQ">
            <span class="emphasis">The Lord is my light; the Lord is my strength.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="1c4rNtTsk0eH1zTt7Iu7RQ" hash="4f3Pkw">
            <span class="emphasis">I know in his might I’ll conquer at length.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="BGTvik6txE2I7L3DnCH_Cw" hash="JWC-Dg">
            <span class="emphasis">My weakness in mercy he covers with pow’r,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="6HmaeWLHHka9DcMXNaddtQ" hash="DWcCRA">
            <span class="emphasis">And, walking by faith, I am blest ev’ry hour.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.p10" pid="qGEHh7UJF0-KnRpVcsLzhg" hash="1ALpVQ">Because of her abiding faith, the Lord’s Atonement brought daily renewal to Jan. She submitted her will to the Lord <span class="emphasis">one prayer, one scripture,</span> and <span class="emphasis">one act of service</span> at a time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.p11" pid="rT876o-VU02IBQLbx8kgtw" hash="zRAS5w">Shortly before her death while she was in her 30s, I was among those gathered in the temple quietly rejoicing as she, her husband, and their children knelt at the altar and were sealed together for eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.p12" pid="4oIAeD4pHEqI4EgL6DAFQQ" hash="0ewTQw">The second unforgettable lesson that I learned from Jan is that when the sisters of Relief Society look “with an eye single to the glory of God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/4.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 4:5</a>), they can experience rich spiritual insights and share deep spiritual strength together.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.p13" pid="tCQ51xIw5UO9r7RVNqU0Dg" hash="dP6F6w">At the beginning of our walks, Jan and I weren’t walking at the same pace. As our hearts became “knit together in unity and in love” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.21" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:21</a>), we walked increasingly in step with one another both physically and spiritually. We buoyed each other up with our testimonies, bore one another’s burdens, strengthened and comforted one another as Relief Society sisters have always done.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.p14" pid="wSWBv5qdPk2ug-wDVcQrhg" hash="-9ysXA">Through my friendship with Jan I learned what a sacred kinship connects us as Relief Society sisters. Jan and I, like so many of you, grew from our assignment as visiting teaching partners into sisters and cherished friends. I testify that connections forged among covenant women in Relief Society can indeed <span class="emphasis">enlighten, enliven,</span> and <span class="emphasis">enrich</span> the journey of life because we can help each other learn how to put the Lord <span class="emphasis">first</span> in our <span class="emphasis">hearts</span> and in our <span class="emphasis">lives.</span> I know this because over 20 years ago, Jan helped me move closer to our Savior by the way she lived. She encouraged me to work beyond my own problems, to rejoice gratefully in the majesty of the Savior’s Atonement for my sins, to look forward with faith to what each new day brings, and to relish deep spiritual relationships available only through Relief Society.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.p15" pid="2NS0D_ZcLU64uHBA3ktjKQ" hash="3KwMdQ">I still walk in the mornings every chance I get. I still pause to study the beauties of this earth and to thank Heavenly Father for the mission of our Savior Jesus Christ. I often recall with deep gratitude the spirit Jan brought to our walks because of her great desire to feel the Savior’s redeeming love. Her love for the Lord flooded my heart then as fully as the rays of the rising sun continue to flood the land with light every morning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love.p16" pid="dv_Z3O83zEmii49y3yzz-Q" hash="5cZtKg">I bear testimony of our Savior, who said of Himself: “Behold, I am Jesus Christ, the Son of God. I am the life and the light of the world” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/11.28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 11:28</a>). Sisters, I know that by daily preparing ourselves a step at a time, each of us, like Jan, can move forward without fear, finding our way to Him as we personally feel the blessings of His infinite Atonement. I know that one of the supernal blessings of Relief Society is our connection to women who also bear testimony of our Lord. My prayer is that we will ever walk side by side towards the light of His redeeming love. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2004/10/walking-towards-the-light-of-his-love</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2004-general-relief-society-meeting/2004-09-0030-anne-c-pingree-64k-eng.mp3" length="4699723" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2004 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowing the Lord’s Will for You</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you?lang=eng</link>
      <description>May the Lord bless each of you in your personal quest to know His will for you and to submit your will to His.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10033479_000_040" doc-version="2" hash="C4W33A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="KP8lj_0HeEuZQivbjHJM8g" hash="l_XRZA">Knowing the Lord’s Will for You</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="1-NOc3-RjECAyyGtgcgLdA" hash="2a9k5w">Anne C. Pingree</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="Y_8WWB4kO0u2rtwIsx0w1g" hash="wUgwcw">May the Lord bless each of you in your personal quest to know His will for you and to submit your will to His.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-103.jpg" alt="Anne C. Pingree" pid="UVz5PQmmt0qUT7uXA3b4DA" hash="xJIXZA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.p1" pid="LFhhmOHjvEKVTLHH4UCVxA" hash="NVuZoA">To become an instrument in the hands of God is a great privilege and sacred responsibility. Wherever we live, whatever our circumstances, no matter our marital status or age, the Lord needs <span class="emphasis">each one</span> of us to fulfill her unique part in building His kingdom in this final dispensation. It is my testimony that we can <span class="emphasis">know</span> what the Lord wants us to do—and experience “the blessing which hath been bestowed upon us, that we have been made instruments in the hands of God to bring about this great work.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> My desire tonight is to share part of my very personal journey of coming to understand how we become such instruments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.p2" pid="2JkV6Qhry0KjLJrSdgJteA" hash="TmHPfg">I start where my journey ended—in this sublime truth taught by Elder Neal A. Maxwell: “The submission of one’s will is really the only uniquely personal thing we have to place on God’s altar. The many other things we ‘give,’ … are actually the things He has already given or loaned to us. However, when you and I finally submit ourselves, by letting our individual wills be swallowed up in God’s will, then we are really giving something to Him! It is the <span class="emphasis">only</span> possession which is truly ours to give!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.p3" pid="YkZ0la2a-0-iQk0quXWZCg" hash="w83N2g">I bear witness, my beloved sisters, that in order to truly be an instrument in the hands of God, in order to fully have that blessing bestowed upon us in “the day of this life” in which we “perform [our] labors,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> we <span class="emphasis">must,</span> as Elder Maxwell says, “finally submit ourselves”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> to the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.p4" pid="8ZGmDFhzB0GhriK9QXptkQ" hash="RrhHYA">The refining process in my life that led to my testimony of this principle began unexpectedly when in my mid-30s, I received my patriarchal blessing. I had fasted and prayed in preparation, wondering in my heart, “What does the Lord want <span class="emphasis">me</span> to do?” Full of happy anticipation and with our four young children in tow, my husband and I went to the elderly patriarch’s home. The blessing he gave me emphasized missionary work—over and over again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.p5" pid="JRLf237BeUqDk99zM9JSZA" hash="Y8lPIA">I hate to admit it, but I was disappointed and troubled. At that point in my life, I had barely read the Book of Mormon from cover to cover. Without question, I was unprepared to serve a mission. So I put my patriarchal blessing in a drawer. I did, however, begin a serious regimen of scripture study each day as I focused on rearing my growing family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.p6" pid="bwzvFxCNnEylSxU_3zDd2Q" hash="eHsdUw">The years passed, and my husband and I concentrated on preparing our children to serve missions. In sending our sons to many lands, I honestly believed I had fulfilled <span class="emphasis">my</span> missionary duty.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.p7" pid="5d_2RgO7ikyUBsEP3Yo3Bw" hash="jv0lGA">Then my husband was called to be a mission president in an unsettled, chaotic country in the developing world. It was 10,000 miles from home and light-years away from the culture and communication I knew. But, in the instant of my call as a full-time missionary, I felt a little like Alma and the sons of Mosiah—that I was called to be an “[instrument] in the hands of God to bring about this great work.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> I also felt something I am not sure they did—overwhelming fear!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.p8" pid="cbwDpol__EGY9dUkjIV-DQ" hash="eeG3Ag">Over subsequent days I pulled out my patriarchal blessing and read it again and again, searching for deeper understanding. Even knowing I was going to live out a promise I had received from a patriarch decades earlier did not alleviate my concerns. Could I leave my married and unmarried children and my aging father and mother-in-law behind? Would I know the right things to do and say? What would my husband and I eat? Would I be <span class="emphasis">safe</span> in a country that was politically unstable and dangerous? I felt inadequate on every level.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.p9" pid="bq9Yi3zmW0eW8Y-njETNMw" hash="AhhJXw">In my quest for peace, I redoubled my efforts to attend the temple. I pondered the meaning of my covenants in a way I had never done before. For me, at this defining crossroads in my life, my temple covenants served as a foundation and catalyst. Yes, I feared, but I realized I had <span class="emphasis">chosen</span> to make personal, binding, sacred commitments I meant to keep. When all was said and done, this wasn’t someone else’s service to perform. This was <span class="emphasis">my</span> mission call, and I determined to serve.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.p10" pid="rvZDc3CBYUWOwodd6w1WVw" hash="kitJdw">Joseph Smith’s father pronounced this blessing upon his son’s head: “The Lord thy God has called thee by name out of the heavens. Thou hast been called … to the great work of the Lord: to do a work in this generation which no other … would do as thyself, in all things according to the will of the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> The Prophet Joseph was called to his unique part of “the great work of the Lord,” and as overwhelmed and unprepared as I felt, I knew I was called to <span class="emphasis">my</span> portion of the work, too. This insight was helpful and gave me courage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.p11" pid="J5hmCuHuCkSLGzvDzKTzzw" hash="XZXG7A">In my constant prayers I continued to ask, “Father, how can I do what Thou hast called me to do?” One morning shortly before leaving for our mission field, two friends brought a gift—a small hymnal to take with me. Later, on that same day, the answer to my months of prayerful pleadings came from that hymnal. As I sought solace in a quiet place, these words came clearly into my mind:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="TKt7uNyu2kquK9wu5CXR1g" hash="JiafUw">
            <span class="emphasis">Fear not, I am with thee; oh, be not dismayed,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="PZLWQWXCLkGUK4_m66BmxQ" hash="Ba8YjA">
            <span class="emphasis">For I am thy God and will still give thee aid.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="HhYSFpskdkuiFBzZRDLoEQ" hash="xaF1rA">
            <span class="emphasis">I’ll strengthen thee, help thee, and cause thee to stand,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="B1tZcFvLUUGioU9e0wTzCw" hash="wRqusg">
            <span class="emphasis">Upheld by my righteous, omnipotent hand.</span>
            <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.p12" pid="mJ0O2C6flEiCVT9w9SEdZQ" hash="NyjIsg">Realizing in a most personal manner that the Lord would be with me and help me was just the beginning. I had much more to learn about <span class="emphasis">becoming</span> an instrument in God’s hands.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.p13" pid="QD_OeTEgu0KRvOw2hzYFHw" hash="Vu-Sfw">Far from home in a strange land, my husband and I embarked on our service, much as pioneers, with faith in every footstep. We were quite literally alone much of the time—finding our way within a culture we didn’t understand—expressed in dozens of languages we could not speak. The sentiment of Sarah Cleveland, one of our early Relief Society leaders in Nauvoo, described our feelings: “We have entered into this work in the name of the Lord. Let us boldly go forward.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.p14" pid="hRhExNoBc06EWFB0N_pjbg" hash="AbzraQ">My first lesson in the process of becoming an instrument in God’s hand had been to search the scriptures, fast, pray, attend the temple, and live faithful to the covenants I had made in the house of the Lord. My second lesson was that in order to “boldly go forward,” I needed to rely completely on the Lord and seek earnestly for personal revelation. In order to receive that revelation, I would have to live worthily to have the constant companionship of the Holy Ghost with me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.p15" pid="7sc87XMwjk-n-m1Ax79SfQ" hash="-O_U1w">My last lesson was precisely what Elder Maxwell explained. In even the smallest details of each day, I submitted my will to the Lord’s, for I so needed His help, His guidance, and His protection. As I did, gradually my relationship with my Father in Heaven changed—in profound ways—that continue to bless me and my family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.p16" pid="dbvhyKMHwkewthv1PYC6eQ" hash="dRaZtQ">My life’s journey is different from yours. Each of you could teach me much from your experiences of submitting your will to the Lord’s as you earnestly seek to know His will for you. We can rejoice together in the restored gospel of Jesus Christ, gratefully acknowledging the blessing of having a testimony of the Savior and His Atonement for each of us. This I know—our individual efforts to become instruments in the hands of God have not been easy and have stretched us spiritually, enriching our mortal journeys in the most personal, glorious ways.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you.p17" pid="EYmzuMW1VE2nAfnjjOrSiQ" hash="6qeIGA">Dear sisters, may the Lord bless each of you in your personal quest to know <span class="emphasis">His</span> will for you and to submit <span class="emphasis">your</span> will to His. I testify that our individual will “is the only possession which is truly <span class="emphasis">ours</span> to give.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2005/10/knowing-the-lords-will-for-you</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2005-general-relief-society-meeting/2005-09-0030-anne-c-pingree-64k-eng.mp3" length="10307435" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2005 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Grow Up unto the Lord</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Determined service to others, even in difficult circumstances, is required of those who truly desire “to grow up unto the Lord.”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006561_000_026" doc-version="3" hash="SrasEA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="qTUrYBC9ZUCxGX6O_PInPA" hash="dJNB-g">To Grow Up unto the Lord</h1><p class="authorName" uuid="6b302fb4-7382-4195-a7f6-e19f9af79d9f" pid="Z4OawW99zkSCJguy5ph6CQ" hash="2a9k5w">Anne C. Pingree</p><p class="kicker" pid="C4_Oc6a-E0Od635jSwfswQ" hash="tHmAQg">Determined service to others, even in difficult circumstances, is required of those who truly desire “to grow up unto the Lord.”</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" uuid="3773ed67-3488-4bcc-bc6b-53baaa557ebc">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.t1" uuid="">
      <img src="en2006lp.nfo-o-df.jpg" alt="Anne C. Pingree" uuid="91ace484-3213-46d1-aca7-36f8397b3c28" pid="uikBccvkyEKaSSmXcA3fLg" hash="n2Oe1g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.p1" uuid="8dc34652-e940-4985-9af4-93e9c17bc505" pid="7kw2hjuxTkKs4CtkeRmc4w" hash="94aC9Q">Some months ago, I rode in a car with two courageous senior sister missionaries. They were determined to find a ward member’s apartment in the heart of an inner-city neighborhood in the eastern United States. As I sat in the backseat holding my breath, the car’s guidance system regularly blared, “Wrong turn, wrong turn!” Undaunted, the missionary reading the map just kept suggesting way after way through the maze of city streets until finally we found the home of the sister whom they had promised to teach how to read and write.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.p2" uuid="df4ca08e-347b-4706-8660-9fa28e9b5061" pid="u6WTjH_bJUej7kL92pmdjw" hash="27rBsg">In their actions and attitudes, these remarkable sisters embodied something that is much more than a reflection of their mortal years. They demonstrated true spiritual maturity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.p3" uuid="cd3f557a-598d-4ca6-b54b-7ee3ac881b05" pid="R7ahSuNggk29dmNzh1np5Q" hash="O80fig">Helaman, the great Book of Mormon prophet, named his sons Nephi and Lehi after their forebears, and “they began to grow up unto the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Young or older, all of us must do the same.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.p4" uuid="234b7e38-b0f6-41a1-8474-89df1d814334" pid="5bbD4Wqb4U6xvUQ1A2rEQQ" hash="0LPN_w">This idea of growing up unto the Lord is a compelling one. Unlike the process of growing up physically, we will not mature spiritually until we <span class="emphasis">choose,</span> as the Apostle Paul phrased it, to “put away childish things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.p5" uuid="f4896dd6-16ff-47e0-bfda-2c5c808aa22a" pid="aEdD173TvUOkeiQvjFIAHA" hash="T7niDA">Daily prayer and scripture study, adherence to commandments and to covenants made at baptism and in the temple are at the core of growing up unto the Lord. We learn to walk in His ways as we do what draws us closer to Heavenly Father and as we teach our children and others to do the same. We “put away childish things” as we choose to become Christlike and serve others as He would have us do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.p6" uuid="e1f4b141-63b6-4470-8a87-5186d287b8dc" pid="Zvh6lhMC4UO_MlO-CATj3A" hash="Qvu-_w">When the Church was organized in this dispensation, the Lord explained that those who “shall be received by baptism into his church” would be, in part, those “willing to take upon them the name of Jesus Christ, having a determination to serve him to the end.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> That means remaining “steadfast and immovable, always abounding in good works”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> each day of our lives. Today, as the Church grows in 170 nations throughout the earth, <span class="emphasis">determined service to others,</span> even in difficult circumstances, is required of those who truly desire “to grow up unto the Lord.” This expansion of the Church means many of us will have opportunities to serve those who are new converts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.p7" uuid="0d4f2aac-f5a2-4451-9037-54465492d975" pid="YthPgGpKo0SZUgsimKqssw" hash="UvAPVw">I participated in a memorable example of such determined service to those who are new to the gospel when I accompanied those dedicated sister missionaries—one a widow close to 80 years and the other a single parent in her 60s—who would not be deterred by wrong turns. I also witnessed another example of it in that same ward.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.p8" uuid="acd810a0-6464-4d94-a951-f188fa3708df" pid="YamiM4vq_Ea-UsVUF7cScg" hash="UkVZwQ">This ward is composed of members of many ages, from a variety of countries, all with varying economic circumstances and Church experience. A number of those with the most Church experience are busy graduate-student couples with demanding schedules and young families.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.p9" uuid="612edd3d-6499-4582-8639-6b466386f50b" pid="-SPtFu7wGEqruwWFJNp4uw" hash="g5scGw">What I saw was a young mother serving as a visiting teaching mentor to newer converts in the ward. While her husband cared for their baby, she enthusiastically modeled loving watchcare to two African sisters. This watchcare involved teaching these sisters not only how to function in a new country but also how to adapt to their new religion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.p10" uuid="632c67ae-dc61-44d3-afa2-5fc3e76bef3d" pid="fGUL66ql4EWM5zDWgVWh5A" hash="XtYpSQ">Through her example she taught these African sisters how the Lord would have us serve each other. The words of the Apostle Paul tenderly describe what I saw in this visiting teaching mentor’s actions toward these new converts: “We were gentle among you, … being affectionately desirous of you, … willing to have imparted unto you, not the gospel of God only, but also our own souls, because ye were <span class="emphasis">dear</span> unto us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> With each visit, the young mentor brought good cheer, a gentle helping hand, and the visiting teaching message.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.p11" uuid="1e055975-0f33-4ccd-a080-dcc873677cd5" pid="T2Uo1yb-SkqwP0h-PF_FgQ" hash="fyMDjA">In time, together the sisters prepared the visiting teaching message to share in other sisters’ homes. Assessing needs, giving on-the-spot service as they went, they became true Relief Society sisters committed to lifting, comforting, and encouraging one another. I doubt I will ever hear the phrase “hearts knit together in unity and in love”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> that I won’t think of those three happy, loving women demonstrating through their determined service to others what it means “to grow up unto the Lord.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.p12" uuid="c7b05952-fe22-4fee-a083-583fbdcaa368" pid="QnQBMi0iWEm4TZaP1qAchg" hash="90QtSw">Besides steadfast, determined service, another way we choose to grow up unto the Lord is through <span class="emphasis">our willingness to “press forward”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> in faith</span>—even when we don’t quite know what to do. Consider Nephi’s account of being commanded to build a ship. He recounted the circumstance:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.p13" uuid="07bd7d70-1b6a-4034-a1b9-c03413388f00" pid="o2bFjdJ7QU6hwvDr9bU-Cg" hash="n50SsA">“And it came to pass that the Lord spake unto me, saying: Thou shalt construct a ship, after the manner which I shall show thee. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.p14" uuid="fe22f594-f38e-4270-948a-e95c02730cb5" pid="pQqEW0kwOkO62ndfDpGcnA" hash="HOD7rg">“And I said: Lord, whither shall I go that I may find ore to molten, that I may make tools … ?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.p15" uuid="8ad43ecd-9bd2-4ee7-9914-fdea2ae2551e" pid="ADZuu8nsU0iWmceUoTnLQw" hash="jfQaow">Nephi did not question the task to be done. Rather, in this situation, he evidenced, as he had in others, this mature spiritual insight: “And thus we see that the commandments of God must be fulfilled. And if it so be that the children of men keep the commandments of God he doth nourish them, and strengthen them, and provide means whereby they can accomplish the thing which he has commanded them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> In short, Nephi looked for a resolution rather than at the roadblocks, because he knew—he <span class="emphasis">knew</span>—that in this process of growing up unto the Lord, God could and would help him fulfill every commandment he received.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.p16" uuid="56b7defb-573d-4f9f-9975-bcb3951d2c65" pid="n1MHPpJwP0OKE2eMNTTQkA" hash="HYWZ9A">In that same inner-city ward, I observed a similar type of faith in the gentle, loving care of a bishop who wasted no time despairing over the vast needs of an ever-growing number of new converts. Rather, he pressed forward by rallying the more experienced members of the Aaronic and Melchizedek Priesthood quorums to help prepare new converts from Africa and Latin America for their priesthood responsibilities. The newer brethren were taught how to hold the trays while passing the sacrament, how to kneel and reverently bless the bread and water. Their more seasoned, often younger brethren, practiced along with them the words of the sacramental prayers so they would feel confident in giving them. Then, together, all the brethren discussed the sacred nature of this important priesthood ordinance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.p17" uuid="fff45e43-e91d-464d-bb84-ee8881f80514" pid="fLRuMBcZskSkABRYFOj8eA" hash="3otdnA">We’ve all had experiences where we’ve had to demonstrate our determination to serve others and our willingness to press forward in faith. When my husband telephoned to tell me that our mission call had been changed to a challenging assignment in Africa, I responded, “I can do that. I think I can do that.” I demonstrated by my words my commitment to move forward in faith—trusting once again that the Lord would help me. I was showing my willingness “to grow up unto the Lord.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord.p18" uuid="e3c5aa15-08e7-449a-bd28-62917c4db147" pid="tqVft1wekUu_7tIS4iziBA" hash="uHV1NA">As that faithful bishop, those dedicated sisters, and I might attest, in this ongoing process of growing up unto the Lord, we will be asked to do all we can, in some cases, even more than we know how to do. The challenges may be formidable and the route sometimes unknown. But inevitable wrong turns notwithstanding, those who strive to be truly Christlike—with steadfast determination to serve others and a willingness to press forward in faith—can come to echo this grand spiritual truth shared by Nephi as he continued his shipbuilding: “And I … did … pray oft unto the Lord; wherefore the Lord showed unto me great things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> To be shown “great things”—what a gift, what a blessing to those who have chosen “to grow up unto the Lord.” May ours be lives of gentle, loving, steadfast spiritual maturity, I humbly pray, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/04/to-grow-up-unto-the-lord</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2006-general-conference/2006-04-4040-anne-c-pingree-64k-eng.mp3" length="5516005" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2006 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Look, Reach, and Come unto Christ</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Messiah extends His arm of mercy to us, always eager to receive us—if we choose to come to Him.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006562_000_044" doc-version="2" hash="sH3zDA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="3omELf0AHkKA_ngERX84Dw" hash="9T0yCw">To Look, Reach, and Come unto Christ</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="XZhTOvg6P0aR43LdycAT4g" hash="2a9k5w">Anne C. Pingree</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="S4bMLDki4kmr-o2Ipmu50w" hash="CI9uZw">The Messiah extends His arm of mercy to us, always eager to receive us—if we choose to come to Him.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/PingreeAC_03.jpg" alt="Anne C. Pingree" pid="3aP1FEGei0Sm5SR0XB1ZIg" hash="eAUpJQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p1" pid="cUf-bTM2LUSMOB0AKBRJrw" hash="kLHWVQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="113"></span>In Minerva Teichert’s magnificent painting <span class="emphasis">Christ in a Red Robe,</span> the Savior of mankind, with nail prints in His hands, stands majestically with outstretched arms. In tenderness and compassion He looks down upon the women straining to reach Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p2" pid="I80hvhJz2Euy3tIlVGqY8A" hash="KXhQdQ">I love the symbolism of women reaching out to touch the Savior. We long to be close to the Lord, for we know that He loves each of us and desires to encircle us “eternally in the arms of his love.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> His touch can heal ailments spiritual, emotional, or physical. He is our Advocate, Exemplar, Good Shepherd, and Redeemer. Where else would we look, where else would we reach, where else would we come but to Jesus Christ, “the author and finisher of our faith”?<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p3" pid="4F90o33TWEW8hMRJ-GZA-A" hash="TEF6hA">He pronounced: “Yea, verily … , if ye will come unto me ye shall have eternal life. Behold, mine arm of mercy is extended towards you, and whosoever will come, him will I receive.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> His promise invites us not only to reach towards Him but also to take the all-important next step: to come unto Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p4" pid="iZ1KkxZd_UCNfFBCde6Phw" hash="F2GSng">This is such a motivating, cheering doctrine. The Messiah extends His arm of mercy to us, always eager to receive us—if we <span class="emphasis">choose</span> to come to Him. When we do come to the Savior with “full purpose of heart,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> we will feel His loving touch in the most personal ways.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p5" pid="BghwAZ2cSkCyZLPvxadFlw" hash="uWnqPw">A “certain woman”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> made that choice and felt His touch. “And a woman having an issue of blood twelve years, which had spent all her living upon physicians, neither could be healed of any,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p6" pid="jaeQdqBMOUaVT0dxYZRtEA" hash="mf97gA">“Came behind him, and touched the border of his garment: and immediately her issue of blood stanched.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p7" pid="Af2rRVPhmUWESh53TIcuhw" hash="gwlgVA">“And Jesus said, Who touched me? When all denied, Peter and they that were with him said, Master, the multitude throng thee and press thee, and sayest thou, Who touched me?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p8" pid="vrdhVVrClUSlExMI-1AUsw" hash="gsCj5w">“And Jesus said, Somebody hath touched me: for I perceive that virtue is gone out of me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p9" pid="wO1j07f6002P8iSVm8KDJQ" hash="UPoPCw">“And when the woman saw that she was not hid, she came trembling, and falling down before him, she declared unto him before all the people for what cause she had touched him, and how she was healed immediately.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p10" pid="Ixm2YNs4ukmMthfHv3jKdA" hash="JnoLWw">“And he said unto her, Daughter, be of good comfort: thy faith hath made thee whole; go in peace.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p11" pid="GBdoUvEzfka6Sf0VIk4qnQ" hash="u3xv5w">I have asked myself what might have happened if this woman with the issue of blood had not believed in the Savior enough to make whatever effort was necessary to touch the border of His robe. In that throng I imagine getting even that close to Him took some doing. Yet, “nothing wavering,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> she persisted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p12" pid="offOlYemJkaFtXDZaCxtvA" hash="q2_h4w">In like manner, we must demonstrate that faith in the Lord has penetrated our hearts deeply enough to move us to action.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p13" pid="YDuj6rMhJEKcEfBiCcUVCA" hash="P_Veyw">A friend told me of an instance when she was inconsolable. She felt such sorrow over a family tragedy that on one day she could not even leave her home. Unannounced, a Relief Society sister came to her door and said, “I had the feeling you needed me.” The sister did not probe or ask for details but rather enfolded my friend in her arms and asked, “Would you like to have a prayer?” After their prayer the sister left. That kind touch and sensitive approach did much to heal my friend’s broken heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p14" pid="yl58tbhUk0mQNg7TxyY4Sg" hash="6w_N2w">This loving Relief Society sister not only listened to the Spirit, but she acted upon that prompting. In a real sense, she showed that the virtue found in the doctrines of salvation had touched her so profoundly that she worked daily to be Christlike. Her actions reflected her personal understanding that “charity never faileth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p15" pid="kJZxkVIiSEW2VZeiTs9bcg" hash="0mHKkA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="114"></span>Of the millions of you faithful Relief Society sisters who, like this compassionate sister, reflect that everlasting love of Christ,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> which is charity, President Gordon B. Hinckley has said, “Innumerable are the deeds of these remarkable and wonderful and unselfish women in succoring those in distress, in binding up the wounds of those who have been hurt, in giving cheer and comfort to those in distress, … in lifting up those who have fallen and giving them strength and encouragement and the will to go forward.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p16" pid="mTyRgNaYPUum87JazuDCNA" hash="UrYZ2w">That very will to go forward toward our Savior sometimes requires on-the-spot repentance. It’s recognizing we’ve made mistakes or haven’t done what we could to encourage or help someone. These personal course corrections in thought, action, or word are essential for all who desire to come unto Christ. They represent individual choices about how we will touch each other literally and figuratively.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p17" pid="jA6LdwMvx0y9Y1UEh-TJVg" hash="2Erb6A">We draw closer to the Savior as we encircle others in loving arms. Or we don’t. We balm emotional or physical wounds. Or we don’t. We look at each other with a loving rather than a critical eye. Or we don’t. We ask forgiveness for harm we have caused, even if it was unintended. Or we don’t. We do the hard spiritual work of forgiving those who have given us offense. Or we don’t. We quickly correct our errors or oversights in personal relationships when we become aware of them. Or we don’t.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p18" pid="5PLlBoH8RkONyfCNtynrTw" hash="P1D0iQ">Like you, I know what it means to make essential course corrections. I remember a time when, without any intent to do so, I offended a sister in my ward. I needed to reconcile this issue, but I must admit that my pride kept me from going to her and asking for her forgiveness. Family, other commitments, on and on—I found ways to postpone my repentance. I was sure things would work out on their own. But they didn’t.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p19" pid="CZCnYYkMMUKnDfo8IyIXDA" hash="jXpNJQ">In the stillness of not one night but several, I awoke with a clear realization that I was not taking the course the Lord would want me to take. I was not acting on my faith that His arm of mercy was truly extended towards me—if I would act aright. I prayed for strength and courage, humbled myself, and went to the sister’s home <span class="pageBreak" page-number="115"></span>and asked for her forgiveness. For us both, it proved to be a sweet, healing experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p20" pid="Ubre6Hzh0kG9V_v5c9FK-A" hash="gtoosQ">Sometimes a personal course correction is as immediate as retracing our hurried steps toward the exit after Church meetings and instead crossing the foyer to greet a lonely sister who we know will talk long. Often it will be as long-term as regularly rising above feelings of resentment for family members who treat us thoughtlessly—all while we are trying to build positive relationships. Regularly, these individual course corrections, which are crucial instances of repentance, yield “the peaceable fruit of righteousness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p21" pid="5xd6z_eRbEOtlOTFqT4-yQ" hash="R1h7AA">Seeking that fruit of righteousness, it is no wonder that we, like the women in Minerva Teichert’s glorious artwork, stretch with longing and adoration toward the Savior, for we know He extends “the arm of mercy towards them that put their trust in him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Because this glorious promise is true, where else would we look, where else would we reach, where else would we come but to Jesus Christ, the Light of the World, the Lamb of God, our Messiah?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p22" pid="rdcf2YBmckKJrDp-2IexvQ" hash="msFObw">I know that “the Son of Righteousness arise[s] with healing in his wings”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> not only for that certain woman with an issue of blood, but also for each one of us. He would guide and bless and gather us—if we will <span class="emphasis">choose</span> to come unto Him. May we do so every day of our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ.p23" pid="DRzkwfFly0-l774yq1gp6g" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/10/to-look-reach-and-come-unto-christ</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2006-general-relief-society-meeting/2006-09-0040-anne-c-pingree-64k-eng.mp3" length="9830970" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2006 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
