<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Barbara Thompson</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Barbara Thompson.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Barbara%20Thompson.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Barbara Thompson.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2007 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>I Will Strengthen Thee; I Will Help Thee</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The greatest help we will have in strengthening families is to know and follow the doctrines of Christ.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008332_000_043" doc-version="2" hash="h-XSaA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="zD7RoTC0ekOII8sU8JZxVA" hash="lvVucw">I Will Strengthen Thee; I Will Help Thee</h1><p class="authorName" guid="c0160a8b-1d06-4c6f-b084-314a04c3025a" pid="-nO3afTP_UaqhoGrTkWr-w" hash="eIJIKQ">Barbara Thompson</p><p class="kicker" pid="sAXfuU5GPE2-v7m5KQwH8Q" hash="MghCfw">The greatest help we will have in strengthening families is to know and follow the doctrines of Christ.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="9064b866-d34d-47a0-8c31-9b3b48d0fffb">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/ThompsonB_07.jpg" alt="Barbara Thompson" guid="bdaf8daa-d447-41f1-bcbd-0537db2138d2" pid="ApODu4GRfU6I1fvCtfe36w" hash="zTQOOw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="oOM6tkJsHUq-G3ak0h3CCQ" hash="S64xgQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="115"></span>Several months ago Sister Beck asked if I would consider speaking about families and tell a little about my experiences with families. I am a single woman and do not have any children of my own. I think Sister Beck thought that I was qualified to talk about families because I have never made a mistake with any of my own children. Many women can’t claim that.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="5rEr6DbyqUGWYnKHQ70New" hash="ADmBjw">I am a social worker by profession and have worked with many families over the years—mostly with families who are experiencing troubles or great challenges. I have seen some heartbreaking situations where children have been badly hurt—both physically and emotionally. I have seen children who have been abandoned and forgotten due to the substance abuse or addictions of their parents. I have seen 18-year-olds who have been in foster care and are now out on their own without any support and backing of a loving family to help them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="M3KDWooc60qK3pKWW-LGJg" hash="DdiJ7w">Thankfully, most of us don’t have abuse or neglect in our families, but every family will experience some type of challenge—illness, death, disobedience, financial problems, and so forth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="FOG8cxPteEKs-che16WTAw" hash="Yi5V_g">These problems raise some serious questions. What is happening to families? What is the difference between a stable family and one that is dysfunctional? What are some simple things that will help families? And who can provide relief to families?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="Wrb8Vy6lMkODBklEG5WP1w" hash="iznvug">Today I want to touch briefly on these questions and give you several observations I have made over the years in hopes that they may help.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.t2" guid="f1e535d9-9d7f-4093-ac92-a7b500ba63a5">
        <h3 class="title" guid="e07eb4bd-4b51-4613-aff3-9f81b6f05a74" pid="j5i6ZlUE0EqImd7K3AjlVw" hash="n6cvmg">What Is Happening to Families?</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="yX-qzDhDV0qph5AWWuo6Hg" hash="kTyiww">Satan is working overtime to attack the family. He tells us that marriage is <span class="pageBreak" page-number="116"></span>not important, that children do not need a father and a mother, and that strong families are not important. He tells us that moral values are old-fashioned and silly. When challenges come, Satan tells us to abandon our beliefs and go with the ways of the world. He entices us with fame and fortune and tells us where to find the easy life. He attacks our faith in God and tries to discourage even the strongest and most loving families. Satan is delighted when we give in—even just a little.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.t3" guid="0daefa91-0bba-4640-a519-eae49c8beca5">
        <h3 class="title" guid="59e075cb-dfd1-41d0-ae4f-0be452022ec3" pid="9TSiVSxALUOgF6FKLgcvrQ" hash="ndTUbg">What Is the Difference between a Stable Family and One That Is Dysfunctional?</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="EjRm_TpOQke5KgZXlTr8QA" hash="WdylaQ">The members of a stable family know who they are, where they are going, and what they want to achieve. The members of a dysfunctional family do not know who they are; they have no plan, no anchor, and no core set of values or standards to set their course.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="ssJuq40CRUO8zZ51CXPAfA" hash="i78V5w">Some of the parents of dysfunctional families were taught good values but have gotten on the wrong path due to alcohol, drugs, or other addictions that have taken away their good judgment and their ability to make correct decisions. In a stable family, loving parents teach by example and don’t just tell their children to do something. They do it with them and show them how things are done.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.t4" guid="04ba4ea9-a00f-415a-8b9f-111c0c4fddc9">
        <h3 class="title" guid="fec05d3b-ec95-4e44-be0f-74e290b81d81" pid="I7O0nGS8ekWS-A8WkRdxSw" hash="SPXQpg">What Are Some Simple Things That Will Help Families?</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="tR-cmEu9s0m--tHCZXbVHg" hash="bSCUIw">Remember, children are precious. They are spirit children of God. I have seen the resiliency of the human soul shine forth at times when I couldn’t imagine how a child could survive.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="UE_h8hEI7EusbmmfqHJvjA" hash="DOzPpw">Dear sisters, love and nurture your children. Tell them you love them. Put your arms around them. Appropriate physical affection will accomplish miracles. Express kind words. Show them by example how to work. Teach them to pray. President James E. Faust said, “Praying together as a family is a bonding experience. Younger children can learn how to pray as they hear the prayers of their parents and older siblings. … Individual prayer and family prayer are indispensable to personal and family happiness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="1nHqIANEL0Kc-b68g_cNuA" hash="8Y18Jg">Read to your children. Read from the scriptures. Help them learn that the scriptures will guide them throughout their entire lives. Have family home evening with them. Let them know that family time together is very important to you.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="9n6uBNASS0KMFaYHupDdZw" hash="AvUaXg">Children are generally very accepting of their parents and the mistakes parents make. They often forgive, forget, and move on much more quickly than adults do. Don’t feel guilty. Apologize when you have made a mistake. Seek the child’s forgiveness. Change your ways and move on.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="q-y0rZiEwEO0F1cQM2VK_A" hash="AuibZQ">Remember that it takes a lot of patience to raise a child. As precious as they are, children can be exasperating, frustrating, and sometimes even naughty. It takes a tremendous amount of patience and restraint in order to avoid doing or saying things we will later regret. Sometimes parents need to put themselves in “time-out” in order to avoid making serious mistakes. Removing yourself from the room for a minute in order to regain control is often very helpful.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="uQ4B6VzlFkaOCI6Phu4Ifg" hash="-ltQFw">
          <span class="pageBreak" page-number="117"></span>No better advice can be found than that given in “The Family: A Proclamation to the World.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Read it. Study it. Adopt it as your family standard. Make it the topic in several family home evening lessons so no one in the family has any misunderstanding about how your family operates.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.t5" guid="9c2d6b0f-9706-4b6a-bcbe-af752d01cd7f">
        <h3 class="title" guid="5fdccbed-789c-48bf-a53f-edc24ba8499d" pid="Ie8qld0PRkeGuX-WfTuL3A" hash="xPjnuQ">Who Can Provide Relief to Families?</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="SeGQjheae0eI9eyKk0uH9Q" hash="TvyCrg">Obviously, the first responsibility for teaching children and strengthening the family lies with parents. However, there are many others who can help. I have wonderful parents, but they did not do it alone.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="i00vl1MVw0yTGwJdlf10MA" hash="rD7R9w">I was in the Tabernacle when President Gordon B. Hinckley first delivered the proclamation on the family at the general Relief Society meeting in September of 1995. That was a great occasion. I felt the significance of the message. I also found myself thinking, “This is a great guide for parents. It is also a big responsibility for parents.” I thought for a moment that it really didn’t pertain too much to me since I wasn’t married and didn’t have any children. But almost as quickly I thought, “But it does pertain to me. I am a member of a family. I am a daughter, a sister, an aunt, a cousin, a niece, and a granddaughter. I do have responsibilities—and blessings—because I am a member of a family. Even if I were the only living member of my family, I am still a member of God’s family, and I have a responsibility to help strengthen other families.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="hYDF1hYihEi4nxM0LeQktA" hash="ajs6Sw">Elder Robert D. Hales said, “Strengthening families is our sacred duty as parents, children, extended family members, leaders, teachers, and individual members of the Church.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="FQ3BpAFPSESlK18bE0ggXQ" hash="fV4N7Q">As Relief Society sisters we can help one another to strengthen families. We are given opportunities to serve in many capacities. We constantly come in contact with children and youth who may need just what we can offer. You older sisters have much good advice and experience to share with younger mothers. Sometimes a Young Women leader or a Primary teacher says or does just the thing that is needed to reinforce what a parent is trying to teach. And obviously we don’t need any particular calling to reach out to a friend or neighbor.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="yqTj5HIs0UG_BeUKXWzlNA" hash="8by8Tw">The greatest help we will have in strengthening families is to know and follow the doctrines of Christ and rely on Him to help us. So often as I have worked with families with problems, I have found myself wishing that these families knew of the Savior and were teaching their children the doctrines of Jesus Christ.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="VCBMqbuqsU-JP7MKPnPW-Q" hash="iO6Rnw">“And lo, he shall suffer temptations, and pain of body, hunger, thirst, and fatigue, even more than man can suffer, except it be unto death.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="7yUGl-ofp0q3WcnBHU7T6Q" hash="vLUDzA">Christ has suffered everything we could possibly imagine. He knows how we feel. He understands. He will help.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="9aDWUG8ZHUWHUMFhFU4Dng" hash="Ooq9aQ">The scriptures are full of examples of how Christ has helped and will help. Some of my favorites are:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="F0yS7hbmDkWP00tQeJ0fxw" hash="SssqMw">“Come unto me, all ye that labour and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="nqi4L8yvxES4cYbN1UKqrw" hash="kRgTRw">“Whosoever shall put their trust in God shall be supported in their trials, and their troubles, and their afflictions, and shall be lifted up at the last day.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="h6W-nS5fyEKu4035u04l2A" hash="0S3Q4g">“Be thou humble; and the Lord thy God shall lead thee by the hand, and give thee answer to thy prayers.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="SIgLsR0BUkeZ_r5Ehta1qA" hash="vDxLBA">“As often as thou hast inquired thou hast received instruction of my Spirit.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="cZDjhUQ6rUCAS-c5l89HbQ" hash="svteKw">“Be faithful and diligent in keeping the commandments of God, and I will encircle thee in the arms of my love.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="j_0cCC8nOUygQGX6jRWenw" hash="bytaBg">President Hinckley said, “It is imperative that you not neglect your families. Nothing you have is more precious. … When all is said and done, it is this family relationship which we will take with us into the life beyond.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="lktSKu6fbkuCpZdHBHUFXg" hash="Kalrug">Remember the great love of our Savior. He said in <a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/41.10" class="scriptureRef">Isaiah 41:10</a>, “Fear thou not; for I am with thee: be not dismayed; for I am thy God: I will strengthen thee; yea, I will help thee.” Then in <a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/41.13" class="scriptureRef">verse 13</a> He says again, “I will help thee.” And once more in <a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/41.14" class="scriptureRef">verse 14</a> He says, “I will help thee.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="-KgAuW8AyU-xskIFFi1Orw" hash="28Zbow">Believe the Savior. He will help us. He loves us. He wants us to be happy.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.p" pid="ZXuI4fEtv06KvVHgBslMGQ" hash="wEY9lQ">I testify that our Lord and Savior lives. I testify that He will help us. He has helped me many times, and He will help you. This I know. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee.f1"><title>Notes</title><ol class="number" guid=""><li guid="aa6b127f-dd6f-455a-b80e-ab2cf3c6303b" pid="VX9-adUdaUSF_OchlWTXRw" hash="2piR7Q1">
        <span class="label">1.</span>
        <p guid="02c34a51-0179-43bd-a7c5-ca145175729b" pid="2JnEgxlLVUKN_ag3brQJ6Q" hash="EZ3ItQ">“Challenges Facing the Family,” <span class="emphasis">Worldwide Leadership Training Meeting,</span> Jan. 10, 2004, 2.</p>
      </li><li guid="5816edea-5103-4ba4-bb81-81537a8eb4c8" pid="IihB8Mx1YU2VXc5ss2UZjw" hash="-JQg3Q1">
        <span class="label">2.</span>
        <p guid="4d7a27b5-1550-43f9-8a00-309ad9bff9ad" pid="J-jT6tfMOEOkrclxhekP8Q" hash="Uo_AIQ">See <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> Oct. 2004, 49; <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1995, 102.</p>
      </li><li guid="a3950853-606a-40a0-b97a-2344c31bff81" pid="QzOVWCwfC0iDPySiMYJGWg" hash="6NUb5Q1">
        <span class="label">3.</span>
        <p guid="9a9ad0f4-8996-48c8-b788-5a039f6849f3" pid="NBAvSso7vUWa6WhzF5F4mQ" hash="3KL4eQ">“Strengthening Families: Our Sacred Duty,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> July 1999, 37; <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1999, 32.</p>
      </li><li guid="6d25becb-5e63-485d-a419-8322b4deaf8d" pid="LK8D9IMqOECuk6iQ_sbl3A" hash="eoU_zQ1">
        <span class="label">4.</span>
        <p guid="1c445dac-294e-4f52-bbd2-7df016e9a78c" pid="ridwJSeI3UWIzIKqY0RsVg" hash="bzrFDA">
          <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/3.7" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 3:7</a>.</p>
      </li><li guid="3789de81-0b32-41e9-80df-c2b3c7493aa9" pid="tsn-49hYtkKffKXKiSe5rg" hash="JqAWiA1">
        <span class="label">5.</span>
        <p guid="d0b886be-27e7-47ef-8d2b-58164bb0d759" pid="Cx8JoAB3MkqhAw-HlO1msg" hash="0nRyxw">
          <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/11.28" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 11:28</a>.</p>
      </li><li guid="740f3e12-1865-43c4-be2d-96e41ae31ad7" pid="SCAaqNQanUS7vu-Mbz9GxQ" hash="Z2fE9Q1">
        <span class="label">6.</span>
        <p guid="badf8f6d-3798-4b01-ac63-a4caa47b5f1e" pid="qLA03M-lPkCRZaizc7WFnQ" hash="a7-ZoQ">
          <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/36.3" class="scriptureRef">Alma 36:3</a>.</p>
      </li><li guid="2e4780fe-4b68-452c-9e29-e46f5c3e0e36" pid="zC_vdS3sEUe0YdwSlXosjA" hash="cKBqTQ1">
        <span class="label">7.</span>
        <p guid="1f92e311-0b13-4ae5-b1aa-1e8d12ad8e3b" pid="0koTQ6aTsUKkpjYI3TG_MA" hash="1Kodlw">
          <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/112.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 112:10</a>.</p>
      </li><li guid="3f39785d-53e4-4376-9f4a-f11c47aa7892" pid="biBwzoogM0WP22qYL-B6Qw" hash="HDewOg1">
        <span class="label">8.</span>
        <p guid="c8153459-d44c-490e-9c4d-b382a3206bb2" pid="SYevIIZbzkCeGzocHe0n0w" hash="ijdRzw">
          <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:14</a>.</p>
      </li><li guid="9a53f609-758f-470c-b12a-b2f4692632b9" pid="qQLdcZUCuEu0PE_vzQURQA" hash="7FFF9w1">
        <span class="label">9.</span>
        <p guid="18b76781-7196-4901-ae43-ed49f4fc3f50" pid="nliZrsJQuE-QFdaS3OSo9Q" hash="Jz7n-A">
          <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.20" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:20</a>.</p>
      </li><li guid="19f195b1-cac8-411a-8ea6-12587f6e2fd5" pid="IPSrxBkeDEiD2BqpkUdLKQ" hash="W8siQQ1">
        <span class="label">10.</span>
        <p guid="ada2d05e-8af3-4445-ab64-50896077a540" pid="x-cY7Xqfb0CFw9obe-Bbgg" hash="QWoIxA">“Rejoicing in the Privilege to Serve,” <span class="emphasis">Worldwide Leadership Training Meeting,</span> June 21, 2003, 22.</p>
      </li></ol></div>
    <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/ThompsonB_07.jpg" alt="Barbara Thompson" guid="bdaf8daa-d447-41f1-bcbd-0537db2138d2" pid="zKsVf1FTb0-d4fXH1k-M5w" hash="zTQOOw1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="bdaf8daa-d447-41f1-bcbd-0537db2138d2"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/10/i-will-strengthen-thee-i-will-help-thee</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2007-general-relief-society-meeting/2007-09-0030-barbara-thompson-64k-eng.mp3" length="10012263" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2007 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Now Let Us Rejoice</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Participation in Relief Society is part of our glorious heritage and blessing as women in the Lord’s Church.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00009501_000_038" doc-version="2" hash="23bOJw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="sdJuJ4A9VEeaaQEnfSm8Zg" hash="zviGaA">Now Let Us Rejoice</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="jiQOs4cvxEi_6cnnFzZtag" hash="eIJIKQ">Barbara Thompson</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="fIN76xWscEihh-Aj1tq5hA" hash="cZc_xA">Participation in Relief Society is part of our glorious heritage and blessing as women in the Lord’s Church.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p1" pid="ahicuYROJk2dDYvLDQapqA" hash="CnUwdw">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="114"></span>My dear sisters, how blessed we are! Not only are we members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, but we are also members of Relief Society—“the Lord’s organization for women.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Relief Society is evidence of God’s love for His daughters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p2" pid="Yc8okOgMP0aqfSEG1lZGwA" hash="agJ09g">Doesn’t your heart thrill as you recall the history of Relief Society and remember our very exciting beginnings? On March 17, 1842, at the first Relief Society meeting, the Prophet Joseph Smith declared that “the Church was never perfectly organized until the women were thus organized.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> He then organized the sisters “under the priesthood after the pattern of the priesthood.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> The small, diverse group of women assembled at that first Relief Society were dedicated women, similar to Relief Society members today. There were young women and older women, women who were formally educated and women with no formal education. There were married women, mothers, and single women. There were wealthy women and some who were very poor. They each had a love for one another, a love for the Lord, and a desire to serve. By remembering what Relief Society sisters did in the past, we can better understand and be guided today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p3" pid="Jjyh1yG-VEapyX5SWka1qw" hash="C-x_uw">At the first Relief Society meeting, the sisters were asked by Joseph Smith to assist the Brethren “in looking to the wants of the poor—searching after objects of charity, and in administering to their wants.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> He further admonished the sisters to act “according to those sympathies which God has planted in your bosoms.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p4" pid="GtL6Rv5w_E6whHCu3S1YlQ" hash="sEWQkA">The sisters took this charge to heart and became a society dedicated to serving the poor and needy. Sister Emma Smith said, “We are going to do something extraordinary. When a boat is stuck on the rapids, with a multitude of Mormons on board we shall consider that a loud call for relief. We expect extraordinary occasions and pressing calls.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p5" pid="8r36-30m90inilgRPpepfw" hash="N4871Q">In the early days of the Church, sisters provided relief as they went from house to house. Doing what we now call visiting teaching, the sisters went about ministering to all—caring for and attending to the needs of others and ensuring that people had food, <span class="pageBreak" page-number="115"></span>clothing, shelter and providing relief when needed. If a sister had something to share, she would contribute it to the visiting sisters. If she was in need, the sisters would help provide for her.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p6" pid="moU9sZQde0WJzcL2nFDy8w" hash="vs55Tw">Let’s devote ourselves to Relief Society, as advised by President Boyd K. Packer: “Service in the Relief Society magnifies and sanctifies each individual sister. … When you devote yourself to the Relief Society and organize it and operate it and participate in it, you sustain the cause that will bless every woman who comes within its influence.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p7" pid="6k-MLnhtH0ewyUglriuV5Q" hash="UBT3ig">Just as Emma described the boat stuck on the rapids and the people needing help, we can liken that to our day when we see such things as a neighbor who is ill, a child who needs instruction, a teen needing a friend, or a family who has lost their income and needs assistance to get back on their feet. We hear of calamities, storms, or personal tragedy in the lives of our sisters everywhere. We need not rush about trying to find things to do or causes to take up.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p8" pid="ZHD9dS4mtEqBWnubYJujdA" hash="fV4U7w">Remember, most often the help needed is in our own homes, neighborhoods, and communities. A kind word of encouragement, a note of thanks, a phone call, a loving smile, a helpful deed, and a reminder that God loves us are often what is needed most. We can lift and bless others in so many ways.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p9" pid="FM0wE64bBUyy4Zic8MpcjA" hash="mS1ZuA">Relief Society is not just a class on Sunday. It isn’t just a place we go if we are not teaching in the Primary or Young Women organizations. It is the Lord’s organization for women. Participation in Relief Society is part of our glorious heritage and blessing as women in the Lord’s Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p10" pid="zMxT6sXFkUKal1yaOcIs-Q" hash="K3wIUA">In those early meetings of Relief Society, Joseph Smith advised the sisters to teach one another the gospel of Jesus Christ. He said, “The … Society is not only to relieve the poor, but to save souls.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> He further said, “I now turn the key to you in the name of God, and this Society shall rejoice, and knowledge and intelligence shall flow down from this time.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Oh, I love this statement. It reminds me to rejoice in the blessings God has for the women of this Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p11" pid="rrreuMByHkOYbXs_Gq_V_A" hash="egNhyw">Relief Society women have always sought to learn and grow. We know that “the glory of God is intelligence.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p12" pid="lCWy2A5l-UKTC_5aWOkjsQ" hash="Nr0C6A">In 1830, in a revelation given through the Prophet Joseph to his wife, Emma, the Lord declared that she should “expound scriptures, and … exhort the church, according as it shall be given thee by my Spirit.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> This charge was given not only to Emma, but Joseph clarified that all of the sisters should seek after this gift.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> Women taught the gospel of Jesus Christ and followed the Savior in word and in deed. The sisters nourished one another by the good word of God.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p13" pid="39P7mPu8IEay2ufk0DVW0g" hash="-ZoirA">Some women have said that it is frightening to teach a class or speak in front of a group. I can assure you I know from experience that it can be rather intimidating. Let’s remember what Eliza R. Snow once said to her niece who was called upon to speak in front of a group. When her niece arose, she was unable to say anything because fear overcame her. She finally just sat down. Eliza kindly and gently advised her, “Never mind, but when you are asked to speak again, try and have something to say.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p14" pid="lzffKKkFmESxlGeXIp0zRA" hash="HBjpBg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="116"></span>We will have something to say as we prepare ourselves as the Lord has instructed. He says to “preach my gospel by the Spirit,” and those who preach and those who receive “understand one another, and both are edified and rejoice together.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> As we fervently prepare using the scriptures and approved Church materials and ask the Lord for help, He will give us “the unspeakable gift of the Holy Ghost”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> and we will know what to say so that all are edified.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p15" pid="51Xw9dpbQEyOaZnVWwRDrw" hash="1XJ6qQ">At a wonderful Relief Society meeting, Eliza R. Snow recorded in the minutes that “nearly all present arose and spoke, and the spirit of the Lord like a purifying stream, refreshed every heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> We hope our sisters today feel nourished, edified, and uplifted every time they attend a Sunday lesson, go visiting teaching, participate in an activity, or perform any act of service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p16" pid="GpHgI-xcI0eTPQ5NFFHp7g" hash="NTC6cA">Sisters, now more than ever, we need women to step up and be strong. We need women who declare the truth with strength, faith, and boldness. We need women to set an example of righteousness. We need women to be “anxiously engaged in a good cause.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> We need to live so that our lives bear witness that we love our Heavenly Father and the Savior Jesus Christ and that we will do what They have asked us to do. We need to rescue “all that is finest down deep inside of [us]”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> so that as daughters of God we can do our part to build the kingdom of God. We will have help to do this. As Joseph declared, “If you live up to your privileges, the angels cannot be restrained from being your associates.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p17" pid="8GPbyv1VoUedzVCuvfIzVw" hash="hvp_WQ">Let us bear one another’s burdens, mourn with those who mourn, comfort those who stand in need of comfort, and thus keep the covenants we have made.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p18" pid="0rG8D2ySMkyuoP59_NpoFw" hash="HPrOjw">We are most blessed. The Savior stands at the head of this Church. We are led by living prophets, seers, and revelators. We have the holy scriptures to read, study, and gain answers for our daily lives. We have holy temples throughout the world where we can obtain the ordinances necessary to help us return to our Heavenly Father. <span class="emphasis">And </span>we have one another to help us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p19" pid="zWGFnf5KbEC-f3kBsgUO3w" hash="_CEjzA">I see “the image of God engraven upon [the] countenances”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> of you good women as I travel to many places in the world. I hear of your good deeds and remarkable dedication. I see the Light of Christ reflected in your eyes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p20" pid="2mrNdKWwAk6106V279SmTQ" hash="4ucEvg">I know that, as Emma encouraged, we can do something extraordinary today. We can be a righteous army of women armed with love, compassion, kindness, service, and faith. We can be a mighty force for good in this world. Then we will be what President Packer describes: “The Relief Society might be likened to a refuge—the place of safety and protection. … You will be safe within it. It encircles each sister like a protecting wall.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> We must have this place of safety and protection!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p21" pid="qv9PTfnlBEmVl0NIlPmyJg" hash="Io1_OA">Don’t you just get excited to belong to Relief Society? As we remember what these noble women did in the past, we will be guided today and in the future.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice.p22" pid="LUZDOGQmkkK1e15mrSWXaA" hash="1-kmLA">I testify that God, our Heavenly Father, and His Son, Jesus Christ, live and love us. I testify that we are led by a prophet of God. I testify that as we keep our covenants, we will be blessed immeasurably. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2008/10/now-let-us-rejoice</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2008-general-relief-society-meeting/2008-09-0030-barbara-thompson-64k-eng.mp3" length="5241168" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>His Arm Is Sufficient</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We seek to increase in faith and personal righteousness, strengthen our families and homes, and serve the Lord and His children.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50015887_000_028" doc-version="2" hash="HdR0AQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="gbpHbL4QmkOH7SYCR6d7hQ" hash="DCKe9A">His Arm Is Sufficient</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="lqsZbGVQE0Kpx81dGv6y_g" hash="eIJIKQ">Barbara Thompson</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="K3ntBd18Mkid_7FJPg4UtA" hash="LAPQlg">We seek to increase in faith and personal righteousness, strengthen our families and homes, and serve the Lord and His children.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p1" pid="9odcXKiowk-LG8AakaLdig" hash="_9ZMxA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="83"></span>Many years ago while serving on the Relief Society general board, I was on an assignment to teach and train some Relief Society and priesthood leaders. We had arrived just in time for the meeting to begin, after having spent the morning teaching in another city.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p2" pid="OdCCVjyjwUuSX0yP2kpxOg" hash="As2gbQ">I was the first speaker, following the opening song and prayer. The opening song was announced as “The Time Is Far Spent.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p3" pid="Fl_X7Xf0R0K4PSbNajAoqQ" hash="b5PbaA">I was not familiar with the title of this hymn and thought that it was odd that this was to be the opening song. I hadn’t even spoken, and already they were singing that the time was far spent!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p4" pid="HrGYqbo6nESl7Bnvh19Afw" hash="kcNBew">As we began singing the song, I soon realized that it referred to the little time that is remaining to publish the gospel message and bring souls to Christ. The words of the fourth verse ran through my mind the whole evening and many times since then. It says:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="h0XxSkYBM0eY73RAHd8heQ" hash="EW0bjQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Be fixed in your purpose, for Satan will try you;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="tzzMa_iFHEO4ePLvxmsfTg" hash="FKFWDA">
            <span class="emphasis">The weight of your calling he perfectly knows.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="OMEhPdU0IESgE46nWaQNOg" hash="BGL48g">
            <span class="emphasis">Your path may be thorny, but Jesus is nigh you;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="2ufeMC4vWUS09jsSi1jb-w" hash="3jif0g">
            <span class="emphasis">His arm is sufficient, tho demons oppose.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="_Wfxo4GHh0-rNv7Ke9gZpw" hash="Yu6wNQ">
            <span class="emphasis">His arm is sufficient, tho demons oppose.</span>
            <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p5" pid="jFem2m5HEki0jaFuqT3CJQ" hash="wI7sQw">The message of that verse is that whatever happens in life, Jesus Christ has the power to save. Through His divine sacrifice, He has provided the way for us to gain eternal life. Truly, His work is “to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> He has asked for our assistance in helping one another do the things that will lead to eternal life.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.f3">
	<p pid="NdXhAdWXVUedyf0EVpmmMg" hash="nhWsKg">Last September in the general Relief Society meeting, Sister Beck outlined three things to help us in our goal to obtain eternal life. They are:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="la5WPLZNFEqd8SIfpmOq6Q" hash="CBS2Bg">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="hm1SQAQ8dk-3N5EApK9q1w" hash="pzl-hg">“Increase in faith and personal righteousness.”</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="8X7fbCTrekWUKSBR4cPVaQ" hash="3b6pzg">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="dIW6aCL8C0Wc63QElVTm6w" hash="yE67pA">“Strengthen families and homes.”</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="vko-CXclYkSQWZwFLoPgkQ" hash="9emTIA">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="fyC5XMFGfk6inFBhNn2JCQ" hash="dUIMxw">“Serve the Lord and His children.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> This also means to seek out and care for the poor and needy.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p6" pid="O8ifJIJqakOa1JIiRHu-pA" hash="GI2ZWg">We know Satan will tempt and try us as we seek to do these things, but the Lord has promised that He will strengthen us. He will help us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="742u93YnOkOFaqkhOfBLbg" hash="pzl-hg1">Increase in Faith and Personal Righteousness</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p7" pid="txnMCKFxvkq_CEQkJYEYVw" hash="iepYjw">As a child I was taught by my parents that my Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ love me. I was taught that “I am a child of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> I can’t remember when I didn’t know this. They taught me that Jesus Christ is our Savior and only through Him can we be saved.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p8" pid="5PK4kInZp0KjPhF5qx1wlA" hash="axUsIA">I was also taught that in order for my faith to increase, I needed to pray every day. In fact, I needed to pray always.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> I was taught that as I read and studied the scriptures, my knowledge and testimony of the truthfulness of the gospel would grow. I was taught to love God and that I could show my love by keeping His commandments.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> I also learned as a child about the importance of the temple. In my youth I learned that making and keeping sacred temple covenants would keep me on course to eternal life.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p9" pid="JkZbq_7DoEKY-_SVm_o_tQ" hash="UPI9vA">Each of us must follow these principles throughout our lives to increase our faith and personal righteousness.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="HBuEMEvy1EeaX6mJueZCgw" hash="yE67pA1">Strengthen Families and Homes</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p10" pid="umQUXF6ZvUSlqLWOLn-NaQ" hash="-n-fUw">It is the responsibility and blessing of each of us to strengthen our families and homes. Each of us is in a different family situation. Some families have a mother and father with children at home. Some couples no longer have children at home. Many members of the Church are single, and some are single parents. Others are widows or widowers living alone.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p11" pid="3cpeVJUsfkSIqAM4ERcrNg" hash="mZZ5ww">No matter what our family looks like, each of us can work to strengthen our own families or help in strengthening others.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p12" pid="C8M9wUxZVEGauT360RNbHw" hash="Ioo0Sw">Some ways to strengthen families are illustrated by the following example. I had an assignment in the Boise, Idaho, area. After training on Saturday afternoon, I stayed in the home of my niece and her family. That evening before the children went to bed, we had a short family home evening and a scripture story. Their father told about the family of Lehi and how he taught his children that they must hold fast to the iron rod, which is the word of God.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Holding fast to the iron rod would keep them safe and lead them to joy and happiness. If they should let go of the iron rod, there was danger of drowning in the river of dirty water.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p13" pid="6QlV-SeQSEaekSYSOSNw3A" hash="DPtlFQ">To demonstrate this to the children, their mother became the “iron rod” that they must cling to, and their father played the role of the devil, trying to pull the children away from safety and happiness. The children loved the story and learned how important it is to hold fast to the iron rod.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p14" pid="ZyYvv4ADGkW3tVzFi7IeFw" hash="6wNobw">After the scripture story it was time for family prayer. Their mother reminded the children to pray for the bishop, who was having serious eye problems. Three-year-old Brooklyn offered the prayer that evening. She thanked Heavenly Father for their blessings, and then she fervently asked Him to “bless the bishop because his eyes are broken.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p15" pid="X5ytx_cddk25PCDyX-WACw" hash="Lt6dig">The next morning we got to sacrament meeting and got seated. Brooklyn and her five-year-old sister, Kennedy, looked up on the stand and saw the bishop standing there. The girls pointed to the bishop and excitedly said to their mother, “Look, there’s the bishop.” Then a knowing look passed between these two little girls that seemed to say “We prayed for the bishop, and now he is better.” They prayed in faith, knowing that Heavenly Father would hear their humble prayers.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p16" pid="kFqK4a-6Q0SDYROgN281Bw" hash="Q1odyg">Scriptures, family home evening, and family prayer will strengthen families. We need to take every opportunity to strengthen families and support one another to stay on the right path.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="5Jt5PzvOZ0Whw_Ptw2DclA" hash="nvKVag">Serve the Lord and His Children, and Seek Out and Care for the Poor and Needy</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p17" pid="l_7ArO59G0GiLt9L2nzFxA" hash="HfKwjw">Throughout His mortal life the Savior taught that we should care for one another and help one another. He healed the sick, caused the lame to walk, restored sight to the blind, and unstopped the ears of the deaf. <span class="pageBreak" page-number="85"></span>He taught the people the gospel. He blessed the people and performed many mighty miracles.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p18" pid="ftQedDTEykeGwnR6UCBhqw" hash="4J81Zg">There are opportunities everywhere to help those in need. I submit to you that at some time in our lives, each of us will be poor in some way and will need the help of another person. For “are we not all beggars?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p19" pid="DDvKj62FXkSdxR38EqLZFA" hash="GCdRnA">President Spencer W. Kimball said: “God does notice us, and he watches over us. But it is usually through another person that he meets our needs. Therefore, it is vital that we serve each other.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p20" pid="sjNwem9M9UaXKUFSOM843Q" hash="ZtIVJQ">Last summer when I was away from home, a fierce wind and rainstorm blew through our neighborhood. A huge tree had fallen from my neighbor’s yard, filling my yard and knocking down power lines. The tree needed to be removed before the damage could be repaired and power restored to my home.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p21" pid="mR9icExzsUOfiu3fQpitSA" hash="y-xcwg">Early in the morning I called my brother, who planned to find some equipment and come as soon as he could. I also called my bishop. Within minutes my bishop, home teacher, former stake president, and 10 men from my ward were there with their chain saws and made quick work of this disaster. My visiting teachers brought in dinner that evening. Many more men from the high priests group, the elders quorum, and the neighborhood came on subsequent evenings to assist me and my family in cleaning up the mess.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p22" pid="_XCYTKTC-EyUXc4RNaGcMQ" hash="U7ddww">I was needy on that occasion. I needed help from others. My discouragement turned into joy and gratitude. I felt loved and cared for. These people were quick to recognize one in need. They lived their testimony and demonstrated the reality of their covenants.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p23" pid="HJXFxnkOOU2eig63aGmDBw" hash="mUpbXw">At Church headquarters we often receive thank-you notes from people not of our church who have been served by you after a flood, hurricane, earthquake, or other disaster. Thank you for always being willing to serve, love, give, and thus be a true disciple of Jesus Christ.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient.p24" pid="-kTqW9HDqkS1kd16Whfowg" hash="GaNBAw">We must be “fixed in [our] purpose”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> as we seek to increase in faith and personal righteousness, strengthen our families and homes, and serve the Lord and His children. Though Satan may oppose our efforts, I testify of Jesus Christ and the power of His atoning sacrifice, enabling us to do His will and magnifying our efforts in the process. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2009/04/his-arm-is-sufficient</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2009-general-conference/2009-04-4040-barbara-thompson-64k-eng.mp3" length="4471510" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind the Gap</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Gaps can be reminders of ways in which we can improve or, if ignored, can be stumbling blocks in our lives.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50019113_000_040" doc-version="2" hash="BIyuVw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="xaI5nPLJ0UaiT2vyoIudjA" hash="KbbALg">Mind the Gap</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="i2dzCSs5DkqzqFpUBzMLQQ" hash="eIJIKQ">Barbara Thompson</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="Ap_zdU3L5UmGhP-tVBiBag" hash="AOSopA">Gaps can be reminders of ways in which we can improve or, if ignored, can be stumbling blocks in our lives.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p1" pid="VUq2WLctI0K1xwnrPPZZtw" hash="M0orxA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="118"></span>Several years ago I visited some dear friends in London, England. During this visit I traveled on the tube—a subway system of underground trains that people use frequently to get from place to place. In each of these busy subway stations, there are warning signs about dangers that people may encounter. Lights flash on and off to notify people that a train is approaching and they need to stand back. There is also a sign to remind people that there is danger—a gap between the train and the station platform. The sign says, “Mind the Gap.” This reminds people not to let their foot get caught in the gap and not to drop anything in the gap because it will go under the train and be lost. The caution sign is needed and warns people of a very real danger. In order to be safe, people must “mind the gap.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p2" pid="i4ogoA0HpkqrK0t59E5PDQ" hash="87ZKAw">Many of us have gaps in our own lives. Sometimes it is the difference between what we know and what we actually do or the gap between our goals and what we actually accomplish. These gaps can be reminders of ways in which we can improve or, if ignored, can be stumbling blocks in our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p3" pid="AyTD2_LojkiZwTkA1AqacA" hash="EGnv7w">I want to mention a few gaps I see either in my own life or in the lives of others. The ones I will address tonight are the following:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p4" pid="4Hy81kxpNUqTAAMnv3MnDg" hash="s2gLvA">First, the gap between <span class="emphasis">believing</span> you are a daughter of God and <span class="emphasis">knowing</span> in your heart and soul that you are a precious, beloved daughter of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p5" pid="PaOw5AxCv0a0mWYGtQTnNw" hash="UTTxSw">Second, the gap between completion of the Young Women program and becoming a fully participating member of Relief Society—“the Lord’s organization for women.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p6" pid="cWvMXBcmvkOuSuNNi0nsYg" hash="lmm1lA">Third, the gap between <span class="emphasis">believing</span> in Jesus Christ and being <span class="emphasis">valiant</span> in the testimony of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p7" pid="5Lqz_NWIjkSF5ZAlk7LjIA" hash="4tHwIQ">Number one, the gap between believing and knowing that you are a precious, beloved daughter of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p8" pid="SPBXYKHhb0qYqGXiZm8H3w" hash="ojzWhQ">Most of us who have been in the Church for more than just a few months have sung the song “I Am a Child of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> I have sung this song since I was a young child and have always believed it. Even though most of us believe this, it seems that at times of hardship or difficulty we have a tendency to doubt or forget this.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p9" pid="bB16rC_b4EeVLChI-5h9AA" hash="AlQgGA">Some have said such things as: “If God really loved me, He would not let this illness come upon my child.” “If God loved me, He would help me find a worthy husband I could be married and sealed to in the holy temple.” “If God loved me, we would have enough money to buy a house for our family.” Or, “I have sinned and so God couldn’t possibly love me anymore.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p10" pid="cNlmTPl4tEqw6LOpYhX2xA" hash="k3844A">Unfortunately, we hear these types of statements all too often. You need to know that there is nothing that can “separate [you] from the love of Christ.” The scriptures clearly tell us that no tribulation, distress, persecution, power, nor any other creature can separate us from the love of God.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p11" pid="CMYmxe6Dy0yPdyAFLgyjLg" hash="qQIDRA">Our Heavenly Father loved us so much that He sent His Only Begotten Son to atone for our sins. The Savior not only suffered for every sin, but He also felt every pain, sorrow, discomfort, loneliness, and sadness that any of us could ever experience. Is this not great love? President Henry B. Eyring has said, “It is the Holy Ghost that testifies of the reality of God and allows us to feel the joy of His love.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p12" pid="RuQlasstOUqPzT-ay5kdBQ" hash="wC2CEw">We need to accept His love, love ourselves, and love others. Remember that every soul on this earth is also a child of God. We must treat each other with the love and kindness befitting a child of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p13" pid="IWq9Qcfu30atIdlWhKh7IA" hash="iowOWA">Most of you work very hard to perform your duty, to keep the commandments, and to obey the Lord. You need to be able to recognize the Lord’s approval. You need to know that the Lord is well pleased and has accepted your offering.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p14" pid="lORWwv_47UW822IfQvy0IA" hash="n2rb8A">Remember to mind this gap and to not let doubt and uncertainty enter into your minds. Be assured that God loves you dearly and you are His precious child.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p15" pid="oMHMkTqIT0Oy-vCCOUkk-w" hash="snsB-A">Next, the gap between completion of the Young Women program and becoming a fully participating member of Relief Society—the Lord’s organization for women.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p16" pid="G4raaPoyR0KrVOduJI5gzA" hash="uDzpKQ">In many countries, age 18 is when <span class="pageBreak" page-number="119"></span>a girl becomes a woman. For many, this is an exciting time when we feel that we are adults and ready to take on the world and conquer it. For young women in The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, this is also a time when we complete many of our Personal Progress goals, come into Relief Society, and accept callings of service in the Church. Our testimonies have been strengthened in Young Women, and we have mapped out a set of goals that will lead us to temple marriage and eternal families of our own.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p17" pid="KFbmeUnHaUqL2t_Y5jmcTQ" hash="LbsZVw">Unfortunately, some of our younger sisters are taking a “leave of absence” from full participation in the gospel and in Relief Society. Some have the attitude that “I will pick up with Relief Society when I get married or when I am older or when I am not so busy.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p18" pid="YmnHKo2fZ0esKQzh0Wae4Q" hash="LXp38w">When I left high school, my goals were to attend college for at least a couple of years, get married to a handsome man, and have four perfect, beautiful children (two boys and two girls). My husband was to have a large income so I wouldn’t need to work, and then I planned to do Church and community service. Thankfully, one of my goals was to be an active and faithful member of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p19" pid="kGMIF8qk5UG5lQoPNvI_dw" hash="5L38Zw">Well, as you may know, many of my goals were not realized in the way I had hoped. I finished college, served a mission, got a job, continued on with my schooling to earn a master’s degree, and continued working in my profession for many years. (I thought marriage was sure to happen 13 years ago when I opened a fortune cookie and read, “You will be married in less than a year.”) But there was no handsome man, no marriage, and no children. Nothing had gone as I had planned except for one thing. I tried to be an active and faithful member of the Church. For this I am most grateful. It has made all the difference in my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p20" pid="slHQZ2WSYU6QCRM2Weeirg" hash="gr-T3A">I had the opportunity to serve many years in Young Women and felt that gave me an opportunity to teach and testify to younger women who were developing their testimonies and seeking to progress in God’s appointed way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p21" pid="37-mMFmwrEaFYGH8m4pFag" hash="_QQRkw">I also had the opportunity to serve in Relief Society callings, which helped me to learn to serve others and increase my faith and gave me a great feeling of belonging. Even though I wasn’t married and had no children, I felt my life had meaning. There were times of discouragement, and at times I questioned the plan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p22" pid="CT6Tert0Q0mTDbPJfMsJDw" hash="4yH2mQ">One work colleague who was not a member of our Church said to me, “Why do you continue to go to a church that puts so much emphasis on marriage and families?” My simple answer to her was, “Because it is true!” I can be just as single and just as childless outside of the Church. But with the Church and gospel of Jesus Christ in my life, I found happiness and I knew I was on the path the Savior would have me follow. I found joy and many opportunities to serve, to love, and to grow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p23" pid="KGMWm1WSJEaZ2UqceBn_ag" hash="FUS48Q">Remember, it’s not just what you get out of active participation in Relief Society but what you can give and contribute as well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p24" pid="SIOoKSRfXE2pjBLZyMiMDg" hash="M_hv_g">My dear sisters, especially you younger single adults, I testify to you that God loves you; He is mindful of you; He has a plan for you. He needs you to serve His children. He needs you to be active and faithful and fully <span class="pageBreak" page-number="120"></span>participating women in His Church. He needs you to “comfort the weary and strengthen the weak.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p25" pid="NCAI0706b02Tddu_lxXLYQ" hash="ec_XFw">Sister Eliza R. Snow, second Relief Society general president, spoke to a large group of sisters—both teenage and adult women—gathered in Ogden, Utah, in 1873. She gave the following counsel that was timely then and is still appropriate today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p26" pid="9UxsOO8DUEqgUUa_tzJ06w" hash="QsDryg">Speaking to the younger women, she said: “If you associate together [meaning older and younger women], your minds are improved, you are gaining intelligence, and you are retrenching from ignorance. The Spirit of God will impart instruction to your minds, and you will impart it to each other. I say, God bless you my young sisters. Remember that you are Saints of God; and that you have important works to perform in Zion.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p27" pid="PhyB4Vv56kiH5apSZY1Bvw" hash="9cczIQ">She further counseled all women: “Paul the Apostle anciently spoke of holy women. It is the duty of each one of us to be a holy woman. We shall have elevated aims, if we are holy women. We shall feel that we are called to perform important duties. No one is exempt from them. There is no sister so isolated, and her sphere so narrow but what she can do a great deal towards establishing the Kingdom of God upon the earth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p28" pid="4TxTaMIRIkuHEfRpqVqqtQ" hash="Q77jhg">Please mind this gap, and don’t let a gap of inactivity come into your life in any manner. You need the Church, and the Church needs you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p29" pid="H_S4EhPFC0yxq7GFqAmi0w" hash="O5-Vmw">And finally, the gap between believing in Jesus Christ and being valiant in the testimony of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p30" pid="p2P8m_gGoES0wMrareXznQ" hash="mlUlRg">Many people believe in Jesus Christ—that He was born of Mary in humble circumstances in Bethlehem many years ago. Most believe that He grew to be a great teacher, a kind and noble soul. Some believe that He gave us a set of valued principles and commandments and that if we follow those teachings and keep those commandments, we will be blessed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p31" pid="oHessMchcUqNi24PGO3vXg" hash="ptJdbw">However, for us as Latter-day Saints, we know that we must do more than believe in Christ. We must have faith in Him, repent of our sins, be baptized in His name, and receive the gift of the Holy Ghost, and then we must endure faithfully to the end.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p32" pid="H1XNySKV1Ee9cMUjl9zlbg" hash="PxSv2g">We must share our testimonies with others. We must faithfully keep the covenants we have made with God. We know that all things will be revealed and given to those “who have endured valiantly for the gospel of Jesus Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p33" pid="gYlwyoXEmEibLmPOvkE0RA" hash="DYMTcQ">When we are converted, there is a natural tendency for us to share the gospel with those we love. Lehi was converted and wanted his family to partake of the goodness of the gospel.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Nephi talked of Christ, rejoiced in Christ, and preached of Christ so his children would know the source of the remission of their sins or, in other words, where they would find peace and joy.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p34" pid="MhUfEjSS3Emrenm3X0D0mw" hash="YKXxlw">When Enos was converted and received a remission of his sins, he was concerned for the welfare of his brethren. He wanted them to receive the blessings he had received.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p35" pid="TL3NudG19069oNjlcFPogw" hash="Kgzf9w">Throughout the scriptures we read of men and women who became converted and then desired to “strengthen” their brothers and sisters.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p36" pid="kBlD000TZUCAw5SRAnDxvg" hash="p7tJWw">Let your voice be heard among the faithful as you valiantly declare that He lives,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> that His Church has been restored, and that the plan of happiness is available to all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p37" pid="LC8a4KG6f0a5FTiDmMyTJg" hash="xpYIdg">As we mind these gaps by paying careful attention and removing ourselves from danger, we will begin to realize the fulness of the blessings of the gospel of Jesus Christ in our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap.p38" pid="gJSsP2cUqE2Wudeuf-xHGQ" hash="_Qp3Vw">My dear sisters, I love you. I know the Savior lives. I know He loves each one of us. I know this is His true Church. Of this I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2009/10/mind-the-gap</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2009-general-relief-society-meeting/2009-09-0030-barbara-thompson-64k-eng.mp3" length="6225603" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>And of Some Have Compassion, Making a Difference</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The beauty of visiting teaching is seeing lives changed, tears wiped away, testimonies growing, people loved, families strengthened.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021411_000_0030" doc-version="1" hash="YjlVLw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="vwPdz6LkV0edveYDY9V0rg" hash="ml4QDg">And of Some Have Compassion, Making a Difference</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="A4-inq5sw0-pwa_quDCqGg" hash="eIJIKQ">Barbara Thompson</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="ZdkkL9_6AkCqnZwMJJouUA" hash="Z1YWDA">The beauty of visiting teaching is seeing lives changed, tears wiped away, testimonies growing, people loved, families strengthened.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p1" pid="F_CEaV5nzE6IigcDPueHGA" hash="Ch1amw">My dear sisters, what a blessing it is to be with you, to feel your strength and love for the Lord. Thank you for the love and compassion you share with others on a daily basis.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p2" pid="WJ8tS8uBM0q1LvkoNYT_yA" hash="cSN0dg">In the early days of Relief Society in Nauvoo, we know that sisters traveled from house to house, ministering to one another, determining needs, bringing food, caring for the sick, and showing forth compassion for each woman and her family.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> This brings to mind the scripture in Jude: “And of some have compassion, making a difference.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> As I ponder upon this scripture and its meaning, my thoughts turn to the Savior and the many times the scriptures speak of the love and compassion Christ had for everyone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p3" pid="gMXD2hxw4Ee8lCgWEjsx_A" hash="NXROOg">In the New Testament we read often that Christ was “moved with compassion”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> upon the people as He responded to their needs. He had compassion when He saw that they were hungry and He fed them, or when they were sick and He healed them, or when they were in need of spiritual enrichment and He taught them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p4" pid="HDX8agTTKEuGxhJeLZ0iYw" hash="y_uFcw">Compassion means to feel love and mercy toward another person. It means to have sympathy and desire to relieve the suffering of others. It means to show kindness and tenderness toward another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p5" pid="aeqmmihWvUOUglQW1LsIlg" hash="FmzcVQ">The Savior has asked us to do the things which He has done,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> to bear one another’s burdens, to comfort those who need comfort, to mourn with those who mourn,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> to feed the hungry, visit the sick,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> to succor the weak, lift up the hands which hang down,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> and to “teach one another the doctrine of the kingdom.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> To me these words and actions describe visiting teachers—those who minister to others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p6" pid="qLndEsyZSUmmiJHEZ5vnqQ" hash="baE5qg">Visiting teaching gives women the opportunity to watch over, strengthen, and teach one another. Much like a teacher in the Aaronic Priesthood is charged with the responsibility “to watch over the church always, and [to] be with and strengthen them,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> a visiting teacher shows her love by prayerfully considering each woman she is called to serve.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p7" pid="_-bmVJcrBUCVEUmyk2ErDw" hash="3Ll3Sw">Sister Julie B. Beck has reminded us, “Because we follow the example and teachings of Jesus Christ, we value this sacred assignment to love, know, serve, understand, teach, and minister in His behalf.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.f2">
	<p pid="8ZCuoz-4fEeJjmiX66lTIA" hash="vFphfQ">Today I want to talk about two things:</p>
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="7HLVdQ6jGE2pkn0TAhYy-Q" hash="KlOCpA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="3RtH-1ssOUiJAVuVg2Dbpg" hash="AgwjCg">The blessings you bring to others as you serve as a visiting teacher.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="CglITpqY2kqtigVvxB42Tg" hash="xgj5Tw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="RCzydVzBsUeLwFtds7m9_Q" hash="EmzoIA">And the blessings you receive as you serve others.</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="ZAx45phck0atPARK9b2SNw" hash="AgwjCg1">The Blessings You Bring to Others as You Serve as a Visiting Teacher</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p8" pid="Za0cGYpHP02snie-Wm5asw" hash="vCFS1Q">Not long ago I visited with a group of women in Anchorage, Alaska. There were about 12 women in the room, and 6 more joined by speakerphone from cities and towns all over Alaska. Many of these women lived hundreds of miles away from the Church building. These women taught me about visiting teaching.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p9" pid="BdStXYfM5EG8I83xI0vBfw" hash="Pw0c7w">To make a personal visit to all of the sisters would require an airplane ride, travel by boat, or traveling very long distances by car. Obviously, the time and expense made in-home visits impossible. However, these sisters felt closely connected because they were fervently praying for one another and were seeking the guidance of the Holy Spirit to know what their sisters needed, even though they weren’t there in person very often. They managed to stay in contact by phone, by Internet, and by mail. They served with love because they had made covenants with the Lord and desired to bless and strengthen their sisters.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p10" pid="OpJGBreo00Su-CB-724t-Q" hash="5mHyeA">Another dedicated pair of visiting teachers in the Democratic Republic of Congo walked great distances to visit a woman and her baby. These sisters prayerfully prepared a message and wanted to know how they could make a difference in the life of the dear woman they were visiting. The woman was thrilled with their visit. For her their visit was a message from heaven given just to her. As the visiting teachers met in her humble home, the sister, her family, and the visiting teachers were all lifted and blessed. The long walk didn’t seem a sacrifice. These visiting teachers had compassion, making a difference for good and blessing the life of this woman.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p11" pid="DzFHJICwD0yZSnG7KNREIw" hash="wLESrw">Long distances, expense, and safety issues make in-person, monthly contacts impossible in some areas of the Church, but through the power of personal revelation, sisters who truly seek to love one another and are watching over and strengthening one another find meaningful ways to accomplish this call from the Lord.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p12" pid="SaHvPhvbNEy-6U5oueYM2A" hash="KUwPBg">An inspired Relief Society president counsels with her bishop and prayerfully makes visiting teaching assignments to assist him in watching over and caring for each woman in the ward. When we understand this process of counseling and revelation, we better understand our important responsibility to minister and can more confidently rely on the Spirit to guide our efforts.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p13" pid="8BUsC7B9ek2FJN7YpVzhxg" hash="J05hCg">I am one who has visited several women each month and then proudly declared with a sigh of relief, “My visiting teaching is done!” Well, the part I report on may be done, but if that is the only reason I do it, what a shame.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p14" pid="dnrsAthWEEuiBt9SJm3Agg" hash="_CX1Kg">The beauty of visiting teaching is not to see 100 percent on the monthly report; the beauty of visiting teaching is seeing lives changed, tears wiped away, testimonies growing, people loved, families strengthened, people cheered, the hungry fed, the sick visited, and those who are mourning comforted. Actually, visiting teaching is never <span class="emphasis">done</span> because we watch over and strengthen always.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p15" pid="rBOtN-7Jrk6RcHuLIyXklw" hash="mXDsCQ">Another blessing of visiting teaching is to increase in unity and love. The scriptures counsel us on how to achieve this: “And he commanded them that … they should look forward with one eye, having one faith and one baptism, having their hearts knit together in unity and in love one towards another.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p16" pid="4K9l-S2fKk-k0dTe_KGapg" hash="8j2abg">Many women have reported that the reason they came back into Church activity was because a faithful visiting teacher came month after month and ministered to them, rescuing them, loving them, blessing them.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p17" pid="dO23VxVO5E6np5OcCH-RVg" hash="tPWZXw">Sometimes the message will be the most important thing you share on a particular visit. Some women have little spiritual enrichment in their lives except for the message you will bring. The Visiting Teaching Messages in the <span class="emphasis">Liahona </span>and <span class="emphasis">Ensign</span> are gospel messages which help each woman increase her faith, strengthen her family, and emphasize charitable relief.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p18" pid="k1UyMuYpj0-a7KmVJA4l3Q" hash="7COkfw">At times the most important blessing about your visit will be to just listen. Listening brings comfort, understanding, and healing. Still another time you may need to roll up your sleeves and go to work in the home or help to calm a crying child.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="hr3unjdLtUy0J_FnNEs8_w" hash="hkvwQA">The Blessings You Receive as You Serve Others</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p19" pid="qRjXszs5nUumGZvKjLcawg" hash="6qCNrw">The blessings you receive as you serve others are many. I have sometimes said, “Oh, I’ve got to get my visiting teaching done!” (Those were the times I forgot I was visiting and teaching women. Those were the times I was looking at it as a burden rather than a blessing.) I can honestly say that when I went visiting teaching, I always felt better. I was lifted, loved, and blessed, usually much more than the sister I was visiting. My love increased. My desire to serve increased. And I could see what a beautiful way Heavenly Father has planned for us to watch over and care for one another.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p20" pid="b73d5HcN6kK-0c5QwQ3yqw" hash="ULYhYQ">Other blessings of being a visiting teacher are that we get to know and become friends with those we may not have known well otherwise. At times it allows us to be an answer to someone’s prayers. Also, personal revelation and spiritual experiences are closely connected with visiting teaching.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p21" pid="pfUWRVh7-UqZq0jHWMkftQ" hash="sRBZog">I have experienced some of the most humbling, joyful, and spiritual experiences of my life as I have sat in the homes of women in my own ward and around the world. We have taught one another the gospel. We have cried together, laughed together, solved problems together, and I have been lifted and blessed.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p22" pid="v5ftiJDZKUGROmviIzpBaw" hash="ZdqpNw">One evening near the end of the month, I was preparing to leave town and still hadn’t visited one of my sisters. It was later in the evening. I had no appointment. I didn’t call. I had no partner. But I decided it was important to visit my friend Julie. Julie’s daughter Ashley was born with a brittle-bone disease. Although Ashley was almost six years old, she was very small and unable to do much of anything besides move her arms and speak. She lay on a sheepskin rug all day, every day. Ashley was a happy, cheerful child, and I loved being around her.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p23" pid="-fF8uDxFb02CyPdKXGOzcA" hash="Ue1ykQ">On this particular night when I got to the home, Julie invited me in and Ashley called out that she wanted to show me something. I went in and knelt down on the floor on one side of Ashley, and her mother was on the other side. Ashley said, “Look what I can do!” Then with a little assistance from her mother, Ashley was able to turn on her side and back again. It had taken her almost six years to accomplish this wonderful goal. As we clapped and cheered and laughed and cried together on this special occasion, I thanked Heavenly Father that I had gone visiting teaching and had not missed this great event. Even though that visit was many years ago and sweet Ashley has since passed away, I will be forever grateful that I had that special experience with her.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p24" pid="5YKg6MmhTkCVgxyLMdTNkg" hash="JjSDqg">My own dear mother was a wonderful and dedicated visiting teacher for many years. She was continually thinking of ways she could bless the families she visited. She paid particular attention to the children of the women she visited, hoping to strengthen families. I can remember one five-year-old running up to my mother at church and declaring, “You are my visiting teacher. I love you!” Being part of the lives of wonderful women and their families was a blessing to my mother.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p25" pid="5YhVLipNr0iVhPhYT1LKJg" hash="EsEMMg">Not all experiences related to visiting teaching are warm and wonderful. Sometimes it is hard, such as visiting a home where you really aren’t welcome or when it is difficult to meet with a sister with a very busy schedule. It may take longer to build a good relationship with some sisters. But when we truly seek to love, care for, and pray for the sister, the Holy Ghost will help us find a way to watch over and strengthen her.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p26" pid="xVKaT5yDm02zbUUGlbGqBw" hash="0pVrMg">President Thomas S. Monson is a master at ministering as the Savior did. He is constantly found visiting and helping others. He has said: “We are surrounded by those in need of our attention, our encouragement, our support, our comfort, our kindness. … We are the Lord’s hands here upon the earth, with the mandate to serve and to lift His children. He is dependent upon each of us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p27" pid="wRrIBV2hw0KknO3UMJk5JA" hash="OldQ_g">“And no one can assist in this work except [she] shall be humble and full of love, having faith, hope, and charity, being temperate in all things, whatsoever shall be entrusted to [her] care.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p28" pid="CcXnL9bArEi9ima25dAPOg" hash="cpmVxw">The women we visit teach have been entrusted to our care. Let us have love and compassion and thus make a difference in the lives of those who have been entrusted to our care.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference.p29" pid="Y9pmGtMEFkKEe4YPlmSFNQ" hash="8t_yEw">Sisters, I love you. I pray that you will feel the love of our Heavenly Father and our Savior, Jesus Christ. I testify to you that the Savior lives, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/10/and-of-some-have-compassion-making-a-difference</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2010-general-relief-society-meeting/2010-09-0030-barbara-thompson-64k-eng.mp3" length="6245214" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2010 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cleave unto the Covenants</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As we have faith in Christ and cleave unto our covenants, we will receive the joy spoken of in the holy scriptures and promised by our latter-day prophets.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50029123_000_0030" doc-version="3" hash="JTDHzQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="-crdkqwVUUqC7ekdru8cKA" hash="V9f4NQ">Cleave unto the Covenants</h1><p class="authorName" guid="c0160a8b-1d06-4c6f-b084-314a04c3025a" pid="_Jr0_8fYWkCGHr0FhV1h8g" hash="eIJIKQ">Barbara Thompson</p><p class="kicker" pid="S12V0XOA-0OH6lVOFs-eNQ" hash="SUgFmQ">As we have faith in Christ and cleave unto our covenants, we will receive the joy spoken of in the holy scriptures and promised by our latter-day prophets.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="019e5a6f-afa4-4d6a-b091-e26421b4b3ce">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p1" guid="d2f7c5d4-6c59-4fef-8c53-2f9278b8f9e0" pid="to65ZQU5jEaZrt_MnnilSw" hash="pWNlKA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="117"></span>“Lift up thy heart and rejoice, and cleave unto the covenants which thou hast made.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> I cannot read this scripture without feeling joy. My heart rejoices as I think of the promises and many blessings which have been part of my life as I have sought to cleave unto the covenants which I have made with my Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p2" guid="3332c162-1ffd-4387-9bda-dafab95763e8" pid="H8az7so1wUGGfuuXhHOtnQ" hash="M8mTSQ">Since both of my parents have passed away, it became necessary this year to clean out their home to prepare it for sale. During these past few months, as my siblings and I cleaned and sorted through my parents’ home, we found family histories and many important papers and documents. It has been fascinating to read through personal histories and patriarchal blessings of my parents and grandparents. I have been reminded of the covenants they made and kept.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p3" guid="4f6d9793-3dc6-400e-bea4-8369c8639d31" pid="T9ABt3Z2zU2zLZzBbib1xA" hash="_qMqfA">My grandmother Ellen Hanks Rymer was a young mother in 1912 when she received her patriarchal blessing. When I read her blessing, these lines jumped off the page and stayed in my mind: “Thou wast chosen from before the foundation of the earth, and a chosen spirit to come forth in this day. … Thy testimony shall be magnified and thou shalt be able to testify. … The destroyer has sought to destroy thee, but if thou wilt cleave unto thy God, he [the destroyer] shall not have power to harm thee. Thou through thy faithfulness shalt have great power and the destroyer shall flee from before thee because of thy righteousness. … When the hour of fear and trials come upon thee if thou wilt retire to thy secret closet in prayer thy heart shall be comforted and the obstacles removed.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p4" guid="1141a2a7-4fa9-449c-9b79-6a86218a0b22" pid="UKHHAP_Zx0SedESPfaDluA" hash="yOMyqg">My grandmother was promised that if she would keep her covenants and stay close to God, Satan could have no power over her. She would find comfort and help in her trials. These promises were fulfilled in her life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p5" guid="45ec62db-e02b-4157-9fce-857ecf44f8fd" pid="R6SRwDml1UKCZYFz95uhVg" hash="WGck7Q">Today I want to talk about (1) the importance of cleaving unto covenants and (2) the joy and protection that come from keeping our covenants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p6" guid="4ad10c72-7137-4881-a7cc-8fa74fb83195" pid="vHHZL3GH4Uy1d2zM14zmEA" hash="Qb18eQ">Some of the examples I will use come from <span class="emphasis">Daughters in My Kingdom: The History and Work of Relief Society.</span> The book is filled with examples of women who have found great joy in keeping covenants.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.t2" guid="20762f7a-f57e-4f07-b175-ccb2b512d6fb">
        <h3 class="title" guid="1f0b40a9-8872-4263-aea9-5bcb42985a4d" pid="J27ThPnjRE-rff7C5gBbhQ" hash="RsLjrA">The Importance of Cleaving unto Covenants</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p7" guid="ec32e966-a1c3-4972-b2bb-fe79d4a20828" pid="r9sFbBbKYEuwblpESIYvyg" hash="S950DA">The Bible Dictionary tells us that a covenant is a contract made between God and man. “God in his good pleasure fixes the terms, which man accepts. … The gospel is so arranged that principles and ordinances are received by covenant placing the recipient under strong obligation and responsibility to honor the commitment.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> In the phrase “cleave unto covenants,” the word <span class="emphasis">cleave</span> means “to adhere firmly and closely” to something.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p8" guid="3c51d2dc-d177-4d6e-86d4-cea46ec453cc" pid="5NHF5u5vzU6J5thrH2J3zA" hash="ii8LLQ">In the scriptures we learn of men and women who have made covenants with God. God has given instructions on what to do to honor those covenants, and then as those covenants have been kept, the promised blessings have followed.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p9" guid="11475074-1c53-43e1-b620-2f2d848f65ed" pid="d-16UeEV30-uS66GPQeJ6g" hash="vpp5VQ">For example, through the ordinance of baptism, we make a covenant with our Heavenly Father. We prepare ourselves for baptism by having faith in the Lord Jesus Christ, repenting of our sins, and being willing to take upon us the name of Christ. We make a commitment to keep the commandments of God and remember the Savior always. We covenant to “bear one another’s burdens, that they may be light.” We indicate that we are willing to mourn with those who mourn and comfort those who need comfort.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p10" guid="80bdd7df-193a-4d5c-bc28-bd13e3591103" pid="hyPaCaIuu0yaoBLnmAHJpQ" hash="wxZE7g">In holy temples other sacred ordinances are received and other covenants are made. In the early days of the Restoration, the Prophet Joseph Smith was anxious for the Saints to have the promised blessings of the temple. The Lord said, “Let this house be built unto my name, that I may reveal mine ordinances therein unto my people.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p11" guid="8a8bf139-68b7-4dd3-8b19-0b01f12261ba" pid="fsH52RuEiU-MXVq_ypQ8xA" hash="6V9jZg">“One of the Lord’s purposes in <span class="pageBreak" page-number="118"></span>organizing the Relief Society was to prepare His daughters for the greater blessings of the priesthood found in the ordinances and covenants of the temple. The … sisters in Nauvoo anticipated the completion of the temple with great excitement, for they knew, as the Prophet Joseph Smith promised Mercy Fielding Thompson, that the endowment would bring them ‘out of darkness into marvelous light.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p12" guid="0b5a13fb-ffa2-441a-a668-1cbac5ff6c4f" pid="J3o75UqI7UiRpCF_vu6gHg" hash="eINKjw">“More than 5,000 Saints thronged the Nauvoo Temple after its dedication so they could receive the endowment and the sealing ordinance before embarking on their journey” to the Salt Lake Valley.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> President Brigham Young and many Church leaders and temple workers spent their time, day and night, serving in the temple so this important work could be performed for the Saints.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p13" guid="abd47bea-ba1c-42f6-8552-e4cd877ea8ab" pid="WfoVsfwyH0ei4nHNGM730A" hash="WmJJhQ">Our covenants sustain us whether in good times or in difficult times. President Boyd K. Packer reminds us that “we are a covenant people. We covenant to give of our resources in time and money and talent—all we are and all we possess—to the interest of the kingdom of God upon the earth. In simple terms, we covenant to do good. We are a covenant people, and the temple is the center of our covenants. It is the source of the covenant.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p14" guid="f150c00d-a19f-42d4-9246-64e2ba2f8c70" pid="l27hoF4hEUaSspjWWvoc1Q" hash="LtAx7g">The scriptures remind us, “And this shall be our covenant—that we will walk in all the ordinances of the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p15" guid="c16ecb00-bb5e-418f-b79b-163af51f7b96" pid="DXnyYz9w3E65bGpJYzz87g" hash="BaYlMg">Great are the blessings we receive as we cleave unto our covenants.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.t3" guid="baf35e87-0bc7-4940-8701-90db5e45173a">
        <h3 class="title" guid="5da4e019-5a48-47a1-84af-d106b96d4431" pid="FmZ_4m8q2k2KvQTeBfSFYg" hash="qjWmaQ">Joy and Protection Come from Keeping Our Covenants</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p16" guid="4b33481e-6320-4909-86a5-956b77bfebf8" pid="BPQ-Y8KGAUaSCzeyCRw3NA" hash="PCAWgQ">In the Book of Mormon we read King Benjamin’s sermon. He taught the people about Jesus Christ, that He would come to the earth and suffer all manner of afflictions. He taught the people that Christ would atone for the sins of all mankind and that His name was the only name by which man could obtain salvation.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p17" guid="cdf2dfee-2871-46e2-b912-7553a2f2d607" pid="DmrBDA8b10KdHmSkne_1IQ" hash="F5tbkQ">After listening to these beautiful teachings, the people were humbled and desired with their whole hearts to be free of sin and to be purified. They repented and professed their faith in Jesus Christ. They made covenants with God that they would keep His commandments.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p18" guid="c7a38437-7983-48d6-a318-6b3287b7dabe" pid="y0-qPER8Z0W4xSlBGYQyzQ" hash="b_9Yxw">“The Spirit of the Lord came upon them, and they were filled with joy, having received a remission of their sins, and having peace of conscience, because of the exceeding faith which they had in Jesus Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p19" guid="b15ef4e6-d7c0-4f09-9673-3aa27edf08b1" pid="Q4gKutYoZE-aX8zJQIm3jQ" hash="SHsrpA">Another example of the joy which comes through faithfulness in keeping the commandments of God and sharing His gospel with others is demonstrated by Ammon. Ammon and his brethren were instrumental in helping thousands of people come unto Christ. These are some of the words Ammon used to describe his feelings as so many people were baptized and made covenants with God:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p20" guid="02fb9b6b-ac1e-43aa-b316-412afdb4294c" pid="uuc1KcOjxEyOGMTuRRdiQw" hash="qtYM_w">“How great reason have we to rejoice.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p21" guid="5a3ecf77-658a-415b-a087-72a9358e811f" pid="jUCm8L53FEWv9s52ULZz1A" hash="jMsOfw">“My joy is full, yea, my heart is brim with joy, and I will rejoice in my God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p22" guid="d4cfaa4e-92f0-4205-99f8-570e898d39d7" pid="1p84ORBrZ0mACIS2E2inHg" hash="Stbmdg">“I cannot say the smallest part which I feel.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p23" guid="715f8c49-7a20-48c7-9ec3-a14d788770d3" pid="5eLmp8Fb4kq9J5h8kcIOHw" hash="3JAEtA">“There never were men that had so great reason to rejoice as we.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p24" guid="19c85052-30b6-4654-9e7c-dfc5d303534f" pid="SuEHxFwQuUy4lbD9Zj_dxg" hash="MD4uoQ">Making and keeping sacred covenants enables us to have the Holy Spirit with us. This is the Spirit that “shall fill your soul with joy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p25" guid="4d9e8815-41e6-4acd-89b5-5f0cd835b061" pid="YPHCuxjH3UGT0tlGtDyt9w" hash="-DK5jg">World War II caused much suffering for many people throughout the world. The Saints in Germany endured many trials. A faithful Relief Society president in Stuttgart, Germany, was <span class="pageBreak" page-number="119"></span>Sister Maria Speidel. In speaking of their trials, she said: “Our trust in the Lord and our testimony of his Church have been our pillar of strength. … With joy we sing the songs of Zion and put our trust in the Lord. He maketh all things well.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p26" guid="efc2ffed-01cc-473f-a9db-9feaab6b9e91" pid="OaovxITtPUesreX-am4Tgw" hash="TSLkIA">Again, as members kept their covenants, they felt joy even in the face of tremendous challenges.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p27" guid="cd0ecbd8-32fb-4318-ac90-344264b5d9ef" pid="B2qqdRiQYUidbNKO7p3X9g" hash="_od0aQ">Sarah Rich was a righteous woman living in Nauvoo who was called to serve in the temple prior to the Saints being expelled from the city. These are her words about the blessings of temple covenants: “Many were the blessings we had received in the house of the Lord, which has caused us joy and comfort in the midst of all our sorrows and enabled us to have faith in God, knowing He would guide us and sustain us in the unknown journey that lay before us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p28" guid="4e284ac2-4483-403b-a1f1-0ba2f4cbb029" pid="YfI1gK-tfE2s1jQgr8zXRg" hash="PvNt7A">Earlier the Saints had finished the Kirtland Temple, and many participated in the dedication. After the dedication the temple was received by the Lord. The Lord told them to “greatly rejoice in consequence of the blessings which shall be poured out … upon the heads of [His] people.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p29" guid="164b64c8-d399-487e-93ac-0593565ed1e7" pid="YlO96v5X6kqIZBZJg-alcA" hash="zGp2pQ">As more and more holy temples have been built across the earth, I have seen the blessings that come into the lives of the members. In 2008 I witnessed the joy on the faces of a couple from Ukraine as they told me about going to Freiberg, Germany, to receive their temple ordinances. The trip to the temple was a 27-hour bus ride each way for these dedicated members, and they were not able to go often. They were thrilled that the Kyiv Ukraine Temple would soon be completed and they would be able to attend much more often. That temple is now open, and thousands enjoy the blessings there.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p30" guid="efe59a59-5d54-4de8-880e-3f6e7079f750" pid="ogRJZQSAakuVoibjyswxEA" hash="H9TE6g">In reading from my grandmother’s personal history, I learned of her great joy in her covenants. She loved going to the temple and performing the ordinances for thousands of those who had died. It was her life’s mission. She served as a temple worker for over 20 years in the Manti Utah Temple. She wrote that she had experienced many miraculous healings in order for her to raise her children and to serve others by doing their work in the temple. As her grandchildren, if we knew anything about Grandma Rymer, it was that she was a righteous woman who kept her covenants and wanted us to do the same. When people sift through our possessions after we have died, will they find evidence that we have kept our covenants?</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p31" guid="c0bf45dd-171c-4799-b294-e1503e62ee4c" pid="NjqUt3M9nk6aMWjcOTA-cg" hash="rxvbPw">Our beloved prophet, President Thomas S. Monson, told us in our last general conference: “As you and I go to the holy houses of God, as we remember the covenants we make within, we will be more able to bear every trial and to overcome each temptation. In this sacred sanctuary we will find peace; we will be renewed and fortified.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p32" guid="6f68f27c-4907-451f-a508-c0a95f8bd633" pid="ZgPJQp5BYkukuehr_xLM4A" hash="ivg4eQ">Once again: “Lift up thy heart and rejoice, and cleave unto the covenants which thou hast made.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> Keeping covenants is true joy and happiness. This is comfort and peace. This is protection from the evils of the world. Keeping our covenants will help us in times of trial.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p33" guid="1a8fcd02-1893-4f36-8463-0b6294b115e6" pid="tsujY2gIFEGnUjkpDihDvA" hash="DqQrXw">I testify that as we have faith in Christ and cleave unto our covenants, we will receive the joy spoken of in the holy scriptures and promised by our latter-day prophets.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants.p34" guid="1a24636a-f026-4817-a437-17f8e876cbcf" pid="ITA0qT9wq0uDp39C4ffIfg" hash="DoPfxg">Dear sisters, I love you and hope you will experience this great joy in your own lives. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/10/cleave-unto-the-covenants</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2011-general-relief-society-meeting/2011-09-0030-barbara-thompson-64k-eng.mp3" length="5939401" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2011 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Revelation and Testimony</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony?lang=eng</link>
      <description>If we diligently keep the commandments and ask in faith, answers will come in the Lord’s own way and in His time.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50029123_000_1020" doc-version="2" hash="GoHkyA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="T-LCN-df2EGGybI-vkxCdw" hash="ICksWA">Personal Revelation and Testimony</h1><p class="authorName" guid="c0160a8b-1d06-4c6f-b084-314a04c3025a" pid="VnsE4XzuZk-Hvxr_Ymi5Xw" hash="eIJIKQ">Barbara Thompson</p><p class="kicker" pid="XNvQdNQFLEyM7utT9VeY6w" hash="nUaszw">If we diligently keep the commandments and ask in faith, answers will come in the Lord’s own way and in His time.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="a6de1d74-d353-4195-adcc-447aa3530d1c">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p1" guid="079ec8c7-fd81-4f0f-9e45-c85c5be7af48" pid="kB6gxsssvk-X7JmkRN-k3g" hash="mwhvxQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="9"></span>Many years ago when I was a college student, I was listening to general conference on the radio since we did not have a TV in our small apartment. The conference speakers were marvelous, and I was enjoying an outpouring of the Holy Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p2" guid="90e4406f-c9a0-4400-9636-aa27179f36da" pid="aXn1zNyRvEGFaYuIJG3xXQ" hash="FtuCgg">I remember well as one General Authority spoke about the Savior and His ministry and then bore a fervent testimony, the Holy Spirit confirmed to my soul that he had spoken the truth. At that moment I had no doubt that the Savior lives. I also had no doubt that I was experiencing personal revelation which confirmed to me “that Jesus Christ is the Son of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p3" guid="9044f534-e364-445f-afa2-c1182200b101" pid="Oe1XTgxFm0GlFnRXR56tSg" hash="NPYE_A">As an eight-year-old child I was baptized and confirmed and received the gift of the Holy Ghost. It was a wonderful blessing then but has become increasingly important as I have grown and experienced the gift of the Holy Ghost in many ways since then.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p4" guid="f2573a95-b3b6-4ea7-bcd7-1d371d4c1271" pid="aoclP4PSPE6Pk7WlNbyCGw" hash="whUM_Q">Often as we grow from childhood to adolescence and then to adulthood, we have challenges and experiences along the way which cause us to know that we need the divine help that comes through the Holy Spirit. As struggles come, we may ask ourselves, “What is the answer to my problem?” and “How can I know what to do?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p5" guid="c3007d3a-7206-4f51-9a9a-a1b8b4e44e6b" pid="QTXiDDKGk0CsKhztdu3H0Q" hash="kfPKYw">I often remember the account in the Book of Mormon about Lehi teaching his family the gospel. He shared with them many revelations and teachings about things to come in the latter days. Nephi had sought the guidance of the Lord in order to more fully understand the teachings of his father. He was lifted, blessed, and inspired to know that the teachings of his father were true. That enabled Nephi to carefully follow the commandments of the Lord and live a righteous life. He received personal revelation to guide him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p6" guid="a7660f8e-29ae-4cd1-8826-beb52efa451d" pid="Le3iA4iIHkmdFEKOXeaIlQ" hash="Z4rzQA">On the other hand, his brethren were disputing with each other because they did not understand the teachings of their father. Nephi then asked a very important question: “Have ye inquired of the Lord?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p7" guid="97908d12-ff84-4bc5-bee4-3a6371e17716" pid="4H7ymFh-n0StvLCydvlqhw" hash="ch6lsg">Their response was a weak one: “We have not; for the Lord maketh no such thing known unto us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p8" guid="4c28b80c-b072-4d6c-871d-b496ba327f51" pid="HCvAbWJYAUy2hlD1ov6hOQ" hash="o66qyw">Nephi took that opportunity to teach his brethren how to receive personal revelation. He said: “Do ye not remember the things which the Lord hath said?—If ye will not harden your hearts, and ask me in faith, believing that ye shall receive, with diligence in keeping my commandments, surely these things shall be made known unto you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p9" guid="f0508eb6-a847-4a19-be72-e530356e51ae" pid="hLgJzBbsDkOIfgNXWX5dpg" hash="4wB44w">The way to receive personal revelation is really quite clear. We need to desire to receive revelation, we must not harden our hearts, and then we need to ask in faith, truly believe that we will receive an answer, and then diligently keep the commandments of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p10" guid="bd339080-f9ff-4465-9292-4bf820ce5164" pid="mnqcMrn4A0aI1O_J2eKfWA" hash="lb1Arw">Following this pattern does not mean that every time we ask a question of God, the answer will immediately appear with every detail of what to do. However, it does mean that if we diligently keep the commandments and ask in faith, answers will come in the Lord’s own way and in His time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p11" guid="d3ea5cad-6ccd-44f1-9a9e-77fa4a8f26e7" pid="uZkIc6VPJUiWP-yY4BEDyg" hash="SANgEA">As a child I thought personal revelation or answers to prayers would come as an audible voice. Indeed, some revelation does come by hearing an actual voice. However, I have learned that the Spirit speaks in many ways.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p12" guid="78fd3c3f-9a05-4a75-9a69-90255b0276da" pid="1kX4ajqCC02Ru4zHbjrufQ" hash="GFUVlA">Doctrine and Covenants, section 6, explains several ways in which we can receive revelation:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p13" guid="cb595f94-d33e-4322-87ee-55eadf8bda81" pid="2rV-FsDmB0y5-ODpnz-yAg" hash="W7k-ug">“Thou hast inquired of me, and behold, as often as thou hast inquired thou hast received instruction of my Spirit.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p14" guid="6b158275-6ca6-4bb4-aab4-5bc8da5ec27f" pid="H3kE1-4cm0WsVNkCfsdvkQ" hash="OkER1A">“I did enlighten thy mind.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p15" guid="a7381f62-b863-4b38-867b-32a6c7a67d95" pid="2P-G9dP8y0CTvEyhVTmByw" hash="QcPn7Q">“Did I not speak peace to your mind concerning the matter?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p16" guid="68f5d508-67e1-4f05-a319-7d3b6353bc9d" pid="iCZs3uRWO0GYnldfwcXFHQ" hash="d-tHBg">In other scriptures we learn more about receiving revelation:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p17" guid="99c9b832-c78e-4732-b992-b7732089e5e6" pid="uz2IdTlLkUKu27Xnj-8YNg" hash="khyl3g">“I will tell you in your mind and in your heart, by the Holy Ghost, which shall come upon you and which shall dwell in your heart. Now, behold, this is the spirit of revelation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p18" guid="02a18887-ba03-4235-b353-7856db1a9f27" pid="fBGF3T9PuEi0b_dsiL3bzA" hash="BnuXUQ">“I will cause that your bosom shall burn within you; therefore, you shall feel that it is right.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p19" guid="792ae262-6cc4-4610-b300-6b7f4acf9f4e" pid="tpZRh0qwJEyrwnqoF5ZKIA" hash="PDZM1Q">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="10"></span>“I will impart unto you of my Spirit, which shall enlighten your mind, which shall fill your soul with joy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p20" guid="5ba5c9c7-e4a1-466f-8b42-14fa8d4ce81b" pid="bm0vmFC4VEem3OtKfTGGhg" hash="H-7HmQ">Most often personal revelation will come as we study the scriptures, listen to and follow the counsel of prophets and other Church leaders, and seek to live faithful, righteous lives. Sometimes inspiration will come from a single verse of scripture or from a line in a conference talk. Perhaps your answer will come when the Primary children are singing a beautiful song. These are all forms of revelation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p21" guid="a638161a-936f-468f-b3b3-a0f8ac51edc0" pid="nHxJQOLQHU-pyC6be2RGqw" hash="0ZnnQw">In the early days of the Restoration, many members diligently sought revelation and were blessed and inspired to know what to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p22" guid="9bbf083b-2ddd-43cd-8866-3746e6316be6" pid="So7hDk0i006APU_Ba9XGVA" hash="cyyoBQ">Sister Eliza R. Snow was given a charge from the prophet Brigham Young to help lift and teach the sisters of the Church. She “taught that individual women could receive inspiration to guide them in their personal lives, their families, and their Church responsibilities. She said: ‘Tell the sisters to go forth and discharge their duties, in humility and faithfulness and the Spirit of God will rest upon them and they will be blest in their labors. Let them seek for wisdom instead of power and they will have all the power they have wisdom to exercise.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p23" guid="2df952d2-35ec-4688-b0d9-eda403047d46" pid="WmGhyinF_UGEB5cuuM9jaQ" hash="H0py2Q">Sister Snow taught the sisters to seek guidance from the Holy Ghost. “She said that the Holy Ghost ‘satisfies and fills up every longing of the human heart, and fills up every vacuum. When I am filled with that Spirit, … my soul is satisfied.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p24" guid="b6608fbe-0d90-473e-84fa-8d82b620b08c" pid="-fmgjDsxJ0Wvl6ZslfZ8iQ" hash="Hh4NEw">President Dieter F. Uchtdorf has taught that “revelation and testimony do not always come with overwhelming force. For many, a testimony comes slowly—a piece at a time.” He further said: “Let us earnestly seek the light of personal inspiration. Let us plead with the Lord to endow our mind and soul with the spark of faith that will enable us to receive and recognize the divine ministering of the Holy Spirit.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p25" guid="c41d7b9f-b577-4513-8fab-efe27891121c" pid="m0Ok_sBlkkWv4p0JVNaBKg" hash="3Vs-hA">Our testimonies fortify us and strengthen us as we face challenges in our daily lives. Some people struggle with difficult health problems; some experience financial problems; others have challenges in their marriage or with their children; some suffer from loneliness or unfulfilled hopes and dreams. It is our testimony, combined with our faith in the Lord Jesus Christ and our knowledge of the plan of salvation, which helps to get us through these times of trial and hardship.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p26" guid="72845dc8-5f6d-48b7-b229-4e881b4628df" pid="_hOfjDQBPUqCgudtUQlvog" hash="42MmqQ">In the book <span class="emphasis">Daughters in My Kingdom,</span> we read about Sister Hedwig Biereichel, a woman in Germany who suffered much sorrow and deprivation during World War II. Because of her love and charitable nature, and even in her own great need, she willingly shared her food with starving prisoners of war. Later, when asked how she was able to “keep a testimony during all [those] trials,” she replied in effect, “I didn’t keep a testimony through those times—the testimony kept me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p27" guid="27f0b955-f7ef-4d2e-8d29-effa36763f84" pid="w4ZXcmtyKkSP3ei2lhwwtg" hash="QJ0wLA">Because we have a strong testimony doesn’t mean it will always remain that way. We must nourish and strengthen it in order that it will have sufficient power to sustain us. That is one reason why we “meet together oft”—so we can partake of the sacrament, renew our covenants, and be “nourished by the good word of God.” It is the good word of God that keeps us “continually watchful unto prayer, relying alone upon the merits <span class="pageBreak" page-number="11"></span>of Christ, who [is] the author and the finisher of [our] faith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p28" guid="3be2bdfe-cd38-4541-9805-27551cac3023" pid="XMhENhp37kmv5wnIa_axmg" hash="dFNNmQ">Elder David A. Bednar has taught us: “As you appropriately seek for and apply unto the spirit of revelation, I promise you will ‘walk in the light of the Lord’ (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/2.5" class="scriptureRef">Isaiah 2:5</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/12.5" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 12:5</a>). Sometimes the spirit of revelation will operate immediately and intensely, other times subtly and gradually, and often so delicately you may not even consciously recognize it. But regardless of the pattern whereby this blessing is received, the light it provides will illuminate and enlarge your soul, enlighten your understanding (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.7" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:7</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.28" class="scriptureRef">32:28</a>), and direct and protect you and your family.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony.p29" guid="df429ab1-64a3-4666-adc4-1fa4043d13ea" pid="VT2pLm8ER0yKsitNIS7XtQ" hash="yC3FWg">The Lord desires to bless us with guidance, wisdom, and direction in our lives. He desires to pour down His Spirit upon us. Again, for personal revelation we need to desire to receive it, we must not harden our hearts, and then we need to ask in faith, truly believe that we will receive an answer, and then diligently keep the commandments of God. Then as we seek answers to our questions, He will bless us with His Spirit. Of this I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/10/personal-revelation-and-testimony</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2011-general-conference/2011-10-1020-barbara-thompson-64k-eng.mp3" length="4750156" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
