<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Barbara W. Winder</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Barbara W. Winder.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Barbara%20W.%20Winder.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Barbara W. Winder.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 1984 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>“I Love the Sisters of the Church”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1984/04/i-love-the-sisters-of-the-church?lang=eng</link>
      <description>This is very, very awesome. I think coming to a general conference of the Church and meeting here in the Tabernacle is such a great honor and a privilege at any time, but to have the privilege of being here in the presence of the prophet, when we kno</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/i-love-the-sisters-of-the-church" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03174_000_026" doc-version="2" hash="WfYfGA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/i-love-the-sisters-of-the-church.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="fhTc6IWdhkC2lbxdn8pufw" hash="OVZ4kw">“I Love the Sisters of the Church”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="P3kRPTnFyUCJ0obnmXTlFw" hash="wrhaCQ">Barbara W. Winder</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/i-love-the-sisters-of-the-church.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-25ce.jpg" alt="Barbara W. Winder" pid="O07gcNnS_EetzksCqcMGrA" hash="M9fnmw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/i-love-the-sisters-of-the-church.p1" pid="s0OmJ1wfMEaviMhJC12okA" hash="BCZvgg">This is very, very awesome. I think coming to a general conference of the Church and meeting here in the Tabernacle is such a great honor and a privilege at any time, but to have the privilege of being here in the presence of the prophet, when we know that his health has not enabled him to always be with us, is such a special thrill. And to hear the words of these great leaders has so touched and so moved me—I do acknowledge my gratitude to you. How marvelous was the address of President Hinckley today as he bore witness!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/i-love-the-sisters-of-the-church.p2" pid="6vN-VB8AP0iLgcH3zvPsBg" hash="nWx1Gg">I know that it was more than an airplane trip that brought my husband, President Richard Winder, and me to this point. My husband has been serving as the mission president of the great California San Diego Mission, and we had to slip quietly away to come to this conference this weekend. I have a testimony of the revelation and inspiration that the Lord gives. In spite of the inadequacies that I feel, I know that the Lord does help and cause his work to move forward.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/i-love-the-sisters-of-the-church.p3" pid="DWncF9avmUKGi5jM6CdDsg" hash="3oZt5w">Yes, I am the same Sister Winder, my dear elders and sisters in San Diego, who was with you less than a week ago helping you to remember those skills your mothers have taught you—keeping your shirts ironed and white and the buttons sewn on, carrying your scriptures. Even the little white handbook is still with me. I am that same Sister Winder. I am the same Sister Winder who, just two short years before that, sat in the councils with these great sisters whom you heard yesterday, learning and being tutored by them, my great teachers, along with their boards and their counselors, many of whom have been my dear, dear friends and teachers. I am so grateful to them and to the many wonderful brethren with whom I have had the opportunity to serve and learn. How I appreciate you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/i-love-the-sisters-of-the-church.p4" pid="YV-PDZHCWEyXM8CG04ywKg" hash="ysRltQ">We women are under the direction of the priesthood. I feel that I have been taught by those who have followed that direction to help bring women today through troubled times, to the point of being caring wives and mothers, faithful members of the Lord’s kingdom, and contributing members of the communities in which they live. These are strengths that have been given to our Latter-day Saint women.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/i-love-the-sisters-of-the-church.p5" pid="Jb_lqqvDk0Cn5M7nASKpYA" hash="ucPaGg">May I also express my gratitude today to my parents and to my husband’s parents for their teaching of righteous principles and for the worthy examples that they have given us. It was a hard, hard asphalt that our plane landed on, but it didn’t matter because there were our four children and their mates and our wonderful little grandchildren letting me know that home was here. How grateful I am to them for their support.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/i-love-the-sisters-of-the-church.p6" pid="qODzNFh6xUuOkIMoGKF5qw" hash="p9f6Tg">I want to express gratitude also to a husband with whom I have served for over thirty years in sweet bonds of marriage, having been married in the Salt Lake Temple, sealed together by President Harold B. Lee. We, too, have made commitments, and we have served together in harmony and unity of purpose, supporting one another through these years in various Church callings and assignments. I couldn’t help thinking of the words of Paul as he admonished the Church to serve in unity and purpose, and as he taught that all parts must function for the good of the whole. So it is in a marriage and in a family that we must function together. I think we were taught so beautifully yesterday.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/i-love-the-sisters-of-the-church.p7" pid="5iaCiMzoP0GVeqElVLWYZg" hash="iJ8tmQ">I love the sisters of the Church, and I think I would like to relate a little from that wonderful priesthood section of the eighty-fourth section of the Doctrine and Covenants. It also says the body has need of every member, that all may be edified together and that the system may be perfect. In a way similar to the words of Paul, the members of the Lord’s Church today have been asked to have the same care one for another that they have for themselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/i-love-the-sisters-of-the-church.p8" pid="8EBDJgRCZU6sIsBwVZ-ssA" hash="Tlm4VA">And so it is that I feel for the sisters of the Church this love, and sense the worth of each individual. I want so, and desire so, that we be unified, one together with the priesthood, serving and building the kingdom of God here today and spreading the joy of the gospel to those who are so in need of it. This is His kingdom. We have a great responsibility to share it. I know that God lives, that he loves us. This is my testimony to you, and I pledge my service to you, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1984/04/i-love-the-sisters-of-the-church</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1984-general-conference/1984-04-4030-barbara-w-winder-64k-eng.mp3" length="3906206" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 1984 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Striving Together: Transforming Our Beliefs into Action</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action?lang=eng</link>
      <description>President Hinckley, Elder Larsen, Brethren, Sister Kapp, Sister Young, and sisters. We have been blessed tonight by the music and the spoken word and by a rich outpouring of the Spirit. I am humbled and honored by this call to serve the Lord and you,</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03180_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="lik-Jw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="1-eMtBXi3EqJAaTKDQQEcQ" hash="RoED3A">Striving Together:</h1><p class="subtitle" pid="yKg0m_-ZL0CNoLdsR44dwg" hash="XH-kXA">Transforming Our Beliefs into Action</p><p class="authorName" guid="bb3e4011-fe49-4d3a-b877-e95b9be3dbcc" pid="PVvRErOwQE28waUHFusMaw" hash="wrhaCQ">Barbara W. Winder</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="8b30049b-d4ae-465e-8bed-fbd015f0a6da">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-25ce.jpg" alt="Barbara W. Winder" guid="4c21916a-78ea-4bd0-9e9d-b89e23ca54dd" pid="lc5LyjmvR0W8EH2dzRRxGw" hash="M9fnmw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="JwSbJF-LJEqX6dqgTze-Tw" hash="oe2Jag">President Hinckley, Elder Larsen, Brethren, Sister Kapp, Sister Young, and sisters. We have been blessed tonight by the music and the spoken word and by a rich outpouring of the Spirit. I am humbled and honored by this call to serve the Lord and you, and feel greatly the responsibility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="YuJ3q-QIqkePDZYKvUBQXQ" hash="uLlZzQ">Here we are in the Tabernacle. And I picture you in every corner of the world in your chapels and stake centers, in your branches—the greatest generations the Lord has ever sent to earth, capable, righteous, willing women, each of you contributing in your own way to the building of the kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="UpknS_GU2kygNz4Wiv1zwg" hash="cccIIA">We are a covenant people, as Sister Young has so beautifully explained and as Sister Kapp has so beautifully illustrated. We have promised to live our lives in ways that reflect the gospel principles, concerned about and supportive of those about us. President Kimball has said that “great women and men are always more anxious to serve than to have dominion.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1979, p. 104.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="dJUYVuIbIUCVGZ5SQIeLMA" hash="XMkihg">Since my husband’s release as president of the California San Diego Mission, I look at him and my eyes grow misty. At such times he must think the responsibilities of my calling are great (and they are) or that I have burdens and difficult decisions to make (and I do). But my tears are for the respect and admiration I feel for him and for his deep commitment to the Lord, no matter what the call is. When the call came for me to fill this responsibility, he immediately did what was necessary to conclude our mission business and, without hesitation, actively supported me. The ability to do this, I believe, comes from an understanding of gospel principles, knowledge of the covenants we make, determination to live in accordance with that knowledge—and <span class="emphasis">a great love of the Lord.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="SmoBGF7JnEmf9aj3DKwPdg" hash="FNiCGg">Again from President Kimball: “The real heroines … are women who are more concerned with being righteous than with being selfish. … [They] have true humility, which places a higher value on integrity than on visibility.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1979, p. 104.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="43V2kY3SW02lbHyR1Fozkw" hash="8nA7zQ">Already I have seen examples of women who so impress me with their spirit and dedication to the Lord; their lives reveal consistent gratitude and faith. There are single women who have found their way into the hearts of entire wards through their good works; mothers of various ages and circumstances (married, widowed, or divorced) who allow nothing to obstruct their mission to rear children in righteousness; wives who nurture and sustain their husbands in sometimes difficult situations; and women who are willing to defend the home and hearth in the public arena and through community service. I have become aware of the refining process through which these women go as they forget themselves in the service of others and sacrifice as they strive to build the kingdom, fulfilling the admonition of President Kimball to “be a much needed force for love and truth and righteousness, … <span class="emphasis">nurturing</span> families, friends, and neighbors.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1979, p. 103.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="23IYzXIKa0GgXXE7CeWQRg" hash="oXK_hw">We are striving together with one heart and one mind to become that Zion society in which our beliefs are transformed into action.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="ukiPdEr1OUKrvH6Zsxt52w" hash="jyBQJg">Recently at a fast and testimony meeting, a young woman stood and expressed gratitude for her Primary class and commented how well, with the encouragement of their mothers, each girl had responded to both class work and activities. Then, during that same meeting, a sister stood and thanked her Heavenly Father for the new call to be president of the Young Women. She committed herself to that service, then pleaded with the mothers to see that the girls would be there.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="hO8AfALGsEmVJrPmi1q5vQ" hash="8UdNhQ">Primary and Young Women workers actively participate in Relief Society through their visiting teaching and compassionate service work and through talents shared during homemaking meeting. Sisters, we need to actively support each other as we teach and train. As sisters in the gospel, we are linked together by the service we render so that individuals and families will be strengthened.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="qpRUqcFF-Uu-0Rid08u3ZA" hash="li8Kuw">In <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.8-9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:8–9</a> we are told that we are “to be called his people, … willing to bear one another’s burdens, that they may be light, … willing to mourn with those that mourn; yea, and comfort those that stand in need of comfort.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="QNfsumzF-k-QpAMbloGr4A" hash="PGnSMw">When the people understood the baptismal promises Alma set forth, “they clapped their hands for joy, and exclaimed: This is the desire of our hearts.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.11" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:11</a>.)</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.f1"><p pid="GS0lDNcqCkCUC-E6E9RKQw" hash="kTJZKw">What was the desire of their hearts? To have fulfilled the baptismal promises, which are—</p><ol class="number" guid="02b2c5e5-939c-4e9b-8eee-9f0d9cff0b0e"><li guid="44f60c5c-ce03-47b6-af60-68c3107d6ad4" pid="nO3r-TnGjUyPV4oF3KwcOg" hash="o5XozQ">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p guid="c5dd2afe-cb84-4834-bad8-6441d5de2eba" pid="V6TZ659-ukS_t-jTpJtNGg" hash="3jDDkQ">That their sins would be washed away.</p>
        </li><li guid="0373e98f-c3ae-4b78-b412-864c4a210162" pid="1UAzLMxbB0O7VpTMDuWEfQ" hash="znpPtQ">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p guid="44dabcfc-870a-48e9-bd80-f8fa5c992810" pid="xhkPvTMgQEWYbdvtt2zaPw" hash="yN8d6A">That their names would be numbered with the “children of Christ” (Mosiah 5:7), meaning membership in his church.</p>
        </li><li guid="09c2221c-715e-4e36-a4bd-c8f3248c9069" pid="E1Icmk70SU-kAxIqn_n2Xg" hash="5pSDBg">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p guid="9ea5fe54-ba38-445e-8400-59bbcc1f73b9" pid="jpwWwCZXNkiHweNYewTN0A" hash="tVndbw">That they would receive the gift of the Holy Ghost.</p>
        </li><li guid="9321c6a6-8099-46f5-96fb-ee06d0f7a223" pid="SJ83y1RaVkOME7nWmCjzYA" hash="3tmCQg">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p guid="c5316717-063e-445d-910b-6dbc7ef225f1" pid="tpXcogxcA0ai2n6MdiC-8Q" hash="noY2JQ">That by keeping the commandments they would have eternal life.</p>
        </li></ol></div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="KFvgdVK-KUShmfckfqrFuw" hash="Hm3hCA">“Baptism by itself, of course, is not sufficient to allow us to be called ‘children of Christ.’ We must continue on a course of righteousness.” (<span class="emphasis">Relief Society Courses of Study,</span> 1984, p. 26.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="ko8_SgcRO0CojrCRCQJKrQ" hash="7OpYXg">As we live for the constant companionship of the Spirit, we can hear and respond to the still, small voice and be led in what we do and say.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="9GF0eQXv2kOi-rRgpvIzbQ" hash="yj2rkA">In the following words Elder John A. Widtsoe reminds us that our covenants bring more value to our daily acts:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="Objs4v69gkWu8YkF62-9DA" hash="gY-Z5g">“A piece of silver always has a certain value as it passes from hand to hand; it is weighed and we sell it in the market place; but, when that piece of silver is coined into a dollar, it receives the stamp of government service; it becomes a coin of the realm, and it moves from hand to hand to accomplish the work of the realm. So, every act of man, the moment it is fitted into the great plan, the plan of salvation, receives spiritual coinage, and passes from hand to hand, from mind to mind, to accomplish the great work of God.” (In Conference Report, Apr. 1922, p. 97.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="FeV7xXxlnUGROt9EHNxYBQ" hash="8YrBQA">My 87-year-old mother-in-law was called to serve as my visiting teacher. She has received “spiritual coinage.” She has captured the essence of transforming her beliefs into action as she cheerfully and faithful finds me (not an easy task) at odd hours and gives me a brief, uplifting message. She encourages me, fits the topic to my life, and uplifts me spiritually. Even leaders need to be encouraged.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="sWaayue7O0KdotTPMUzgKA" hash="Qoan6Q">The Lord ofttimes sends his children to answer the prayers of another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="M8WlNddVZEiDUa3V-VOr9w" hash="vhZ1lg">A friend lost two sons in a motorcycle accident and for a time she felt inconsolable grief. She was unable to reach the bishop and had turned to the Lord in fervent prayer. When she looked up, her visiting teacher was at the door and stated simply, “I felt that I was needed.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="GxX5A_UHXU6GdTYtpDSq0g" hash="yV7gBQ">In another situation, a sister’s mother passed away. A friend, knowing the sister’s loss, wanted to help, but was uncertain what she should do. Should she take flowers or food? Her husband suggested she ask the Lord what to take. The answer came, “Just go.” Upon her arrival, the sister was immediately comforted by her friend’s presence and asked her to pray with her. Then the grieved sister commented on what her friend had brought—a needed peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="88CY7hBXjU2_bb8IULarRg" hash="rXageQ">Many can visit, but because of the covenants we have made, we go in His name. We are able to say and do those things that we would not otherwise know to say and do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="WpdR1Lqd80Gj0_pxwMGWzw" hash="AyQqFg">Sisters, there are those in our church today who feel lonely and isolated. I have anguished over the cry of those sisters who want to contribute, who want to belong, who long for companionship and yet do not feel love and acceptance. I search, too, for the faces of the dear sisters we wish were here, who may be kept away with struggles of their own, whose presence would make us all stronger. We need you, each and every one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="Fixdsak4_U6IyUI-o8aTxQ" hash="BOuj7g">President Hinckley has told us, “God has given the women of this church a work to do in building his kingdom.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1983, p. 84.) Beautiful things can be done when sisters of the gospel work together.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="eNrbPOlIRkWtXiCmDAO7Vw" hash="9wflUw">Nephi tells us, regarding our baptismal covenant, “ye [are] in this strait and narrow path which leads to eternal life; yea, ye have entered in by the gate; ye have done according to the commandments of the Father and the Son; and ye have received the Holy Ghost.” Then he asks if all is done. “Nay; … ye must press forward with a steadfastness in Christ, having a perfect brightness of hope, and a love of God and of all men. Wherefore, if ye shall press forward, feasting upon the word of Christ, and endure to the end, … ye shall have eternal life.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.18-20" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:18–20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="aAGEDI1h6Eu9cqp663ZTzw" hash="RH7qhQ">Sisters, I encourage you to prepare yourselves and to prepare your families to receive the blessings of the covenant. We do this by keeping the commandments, by seeking the constant companionship of the Holy Ghost, and by transforming our beliefs into action.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="CRncQfXZ_kWNYadlYxa2PA" hash="8vBM9Q">As we strive together to give righteous, selfless service in His name, supporting one another, we become united, our light shining forth as a standard, bound together by the good we do, “no more strangers and foreigners, but fellowcitizens with the saints, and of the household of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/2.19" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 2:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action.p" pid="VWLabHCV1UWygoli6bTI6w" hash="Wl1p3A">I bear witness of these things in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-25ce.jpg" alt="Barbara W. Winder" guid="4c21916a-78ea-4bd0-9e9d-b89e23ca54dd" pid="1cWhDXjpS0yH_uLsJKHFQw" hash="M9fnmw1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="4c21916a-78ea-4bd0-9e9d-b89e23ca54dd"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1984/10/striving-together-transforming-our-beliefs-into-action</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1984-general-womens-meeting/1984-09-0040-barbara-w-winder-64k-eng.mp3" length="6146011" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 1984 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Draw Near unto Me through Obedience</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear sisters here and around the world, what a joy it is to meet with you united in spirit to learn how we draw nearer to our Heavenly Father and His Son Jesus Christ.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03193_000_037" doc-version="2" hash="wgA5mQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="goc-38Y1ukiztV1jTXDeSg" hash="0rwlDg">Draw Near unto Me through Obedience</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="HWTUyQMI4UyRfvZkdygVtQ" hash="wrhaCQ">Barbara W. Winder</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-25ce.jpg" alt="Barbara W. Winder" pid="_zfsfFTXf0KpkZvQmQ2ZYA" hash="M9fnmw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p1" pid="l1sfoC7L3k2K_HeYdpfzDA" hash="1s4D6g">My dear sisters here and around the world, what a joy it is to meet with you united in spirit to learn how we draw nearer to our Heavenly Father and His Son Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p2" pid="AfqKqvyeL0ya9unu6GkWVg" hash="c5IXaQ">We have heard tonight how we may do this through prayer and the use of the scriptures. We have also been reminded that as we partake of the sacrament each Sunday our minds and our hearts should be filled with our commitment to “remember him and keep his commandments.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.77" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:77</a>.) As we further listen to that prayer, we hear the promise “that they may always have his Spirit to be with them.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.77" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:77</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p3" pid="2VytzwQstESwkHMKfBmVSA" hash="u7M06Q">From the very beginning, God has taught his children that blessings come to those who are obedient. As He gave those special rules on Mount Sinai for the guidance of Israel, the Lord stated that He would <span class="emphasis">show mercy</span> to them that kept His commandments. (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.6" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:6</a>.) In Deuteronomy we are told that “the Lord commanded us … <span class="emphasis">for our good always.</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/deut/6.24" class="scriptureRef">Deut. 6:24</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p4" pid="G1IZz_NrDEiWBmOrODWAzQ" hash="tvbShA">King Benjamin, giving his farewell address after a long life of service and experience, said, “If ye do keep his commandments he doth bless you.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.22" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2:22</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p5" pid="OxRZBsmN_0Kx6J0WZiDTiA" hash="9cKxIA">Each of us can gain a sense of inner confidence and peace when we obey gospel principles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p6" pid="YFMziC6z1UqNJklrMwIyog" hash="tS27bQ">Several years ago, our newly married daughter and her husband began a series of moves from one place to another—graduate school, first job, and so on. These moves took them to various parts of the country. In each place the climate and soil conditions were different, but they determined they would follow the prophet’s advice and have a garden. Their first attempts at gardening were pathetic. The weeds grew much better than the vegetables. The gardens were “obedience gardens.” However, with continued effort, each year the gardens improved. They learned new techniques and developed skills. As children came to their family, each was taught to work and take responsibility in those “obedience gardens.” Now their gardens are attractive, worthwhile “survival” projects, as the family enjoys and shares the produce. They preserve the excess for later use. Besides the practical lessons they learned, they found peace and assurance in keeping the commandments. Surely the promise was fulfilled for them: the prophet’s advice had been for their good always.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p7" pid="yk1yIP8qXUax2CXs-tLs1g" hash="7-zW1A">Sometimes we think that because our circumstances are difficult, it is not practical to keep all the Lord’s commandments. There are those, for instance, who feel they cannot afford to pay tithing. But as we obey the commandments, we have the evidence of blessings, feelings of accomplishment, and inner peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p8" pid="w_YPgeJNLEyzZGX9XP4WCQ" hash="P96ljA">One dear sister and her husband who recently joined the Church had a home that was simply a wooden shell with no bathroom facilities, oven, or sink. Because of their very low income, they could not afford to feed their eight-year-old son, who had to live with his grandparents. This young couple found tithing a very difficult principle to obey.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p9" pid="CTG_dvYUt0SYdQ4LjU7H0g" hash="RUFrbQ">After being a member of the Church for five months, the young mother decided that she was going to keep the commandment of tithing. In order to do so, she gave all the money she had in her home to the bishop in the middle of the month, then wondered what would become of her, her husband, and their three-year-old daughter during the remaining fifteen days. They had no money saved, and very little food.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p10" pid="db6HQE8kokCbaN4IECKBXw" hash="t9Wx_w">“The windows of heaven” as described in Malachi 3:10 [<a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/3.10" class="scriptureRef">Mal. 3:10</a>] did open. That week a kind Relief Society sister brought fresh bread, their country’s staple food. In addition, an overdue debt was paid to the husband, and just three months later he received a substantial pay promotion in his work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p11" pid="0sT4dPaBnUWCnNxm8USOHg" hash="gFzUrw">Heavenly Father truly looked after their needs as they exercised great faith to be obedient.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p12" pid="LNn1a8RznESJZG9UTPOabA" hash="cuG_6w">In 1 Nephi we read, “If it so be that the children of men keep the commandments of God he doth nourish them, and strengthen them, and provide means whereby they can accomplish the thing which he has commanded them.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.3" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p13" pid="NwS59F_YA0-UmTaVqJzCqg" hash="Wfh7aQ">Again, listen to the words of King Benjamin: “I would desire that ye should consider on the blessed and happy state of those that keep the commandments of God. For behold, they are blessed in all things, both temporal and spiritual; and if they hold out faithful to the end they are received into heaven, that thereby they may dwell with God in a state of never-ending happiness. O remember, remember that these things are true.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.41" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2:41</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p14" pid="MqzNDL5IAk2zn2DkBf5MWQ" hash="wprLUQ">Obedience brings blessings here and now. Jesus said, “If ye know these things, happy are ye if ye <span class="emphasis">do</span> them.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/13.17" class="scriptureRef">John 13:17</a>; italics added.) Happiness and peace are found when we are in harmony with ourselves, with God, and with our fellowmen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p15" pid="9QYnv23rMkqmziiv-FoClg" hash="5M-hNw">Through obedience we build spiritual strength that sustains us during times of adversity. My friend and counselor Joy F. Evans tells of such a time in her life. She had four young children and was expecting her fifth child. The much-anticipated day of birth arrived—about six weeks early. They had expected to have “a” baby, but they had twins instead—Michael and Amy, premature and very small.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p16" pid="x_icgFQPV068AnQW_QdIQw" hash="44YVlg">They had already lost one child earlier, and Joy, being a nurse, felt certain those babies were also going to die. She was even afraid that her own lack of faith would contribute to their dying, and she wanted desperately for them to live!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p17" pid="T9pMvXmeJkS17n5_LtsDaA" hash="YKFt9A">In her words, “I think it was the first time I couldn’t say ‘Thy will be done.’ I just couldn’t say it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p18" pid="T-n4s3m4vECqcIo-RI-_8Q" hash="7WxSag">When her husband went home the second day after the babies’ birth, he prayed, not for the babies, but for his wife, their mother. Then a sweet assurance came to her that everything was all right: whatever happened was the Lord’s will. The babies did die, one after two days, and the other after three; but Joy still had her feeling of peace. She could draw from the wonderful reservoir of strength she had developed by keeping the commandments through the years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p19" pid="BuQT24Kjt0ONqrbS9aFDEA" hash="NWmcHw">Having the babies dressed appropriately for burial was very important to their mother, but they were so tiny that clothes could not be found small enough to fit them. When the Relief Society president came after the second baby died, she sensed Joy’s disappointment in not being able to dress the babies as she would like. The president went home and sewed busily that night. When she came back the next morning, the day of the graveside service, she had a darling little white suit for Michael and a dainty little white dress for Amy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p20" pid="P3oZ6i6ihkWpTM9hHyeePg" hash="EPSWZA">Peace can come to both the giver and the receiver as we follow the promptings of the Spirit to serve one another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p21" pid="WcewtHLpaEeNOjXk8OtO4w" hash="7HLhEg">The Lord said, “Keep my commandments, and <span class="emphasis">assist</span> to bring forth my work.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/11.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 11:9</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p22" pid="uTwFj82aq0ahPPS41wR2zw" hash="4hRyMw">Sisters, as women in the Church, each of us has an important role to fill in building His kingdom on earth. The way to do this is clear. We have been commanded to sanctify ourselves that our minds may become single to God so that we can stand firm in the faith, without wavering, until our work is completed. As we keep a time for regular scripture study and quiet time for prayers, we receive knowledge and inspiration. Then, through obedience, we put that information into action. We are sanctifying ourselves one step at a time as we accept personal responsibility for our actions and honor the covenants we make at baptism, in the temple, and as we take the sacrament each Sunday. We progress by living worthy to receive the blessings available to us, responding to those promptings to serve others, by loving one another, and by trying to obey the prophet’s voice in all things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p23" pid="GUHHWC6nzUuE35g8wDf9fQ" hash="VnYxpA">Elder Heber J. Grant said, “If we are striving, if we are working, if we are trying, to the best of our ability, to improve day by day, <span class="emphasis">then we are in the line of our duty.”</span> (In Conference Report, Apr. 1909, p. 111.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p24" pid="CnNtObYHOEmM3xjos7ZgRg" hash="8eMnMA">From a Thai refugee camp, Mary Ellen Edmunds expressed it well for all of us when she said, “For me I feel close to the Savior when I can do in a small way for someone else, what He would do if He were there. In a way, that’s what being an instrument is all about … to make it possible for His love to reach more of His children.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p25" pid="us3LewId0Uup5fnMXg4thw" hash="NwDm4Q">Sisters, we are those instruments. He needs us, and we need Him. Instruments that are in tune play beautiful melodies. Be obedient. Be prayerful. Remember Him. Keep His commandments. Draw near to Him and feel the joy and peace that will come as He draws near unto you. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.63" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:63</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience.p26" pid="Ut61fRmJ6kGnlcY32EWHHw" hash="fwFWXg">I know these things to be true and say them in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-unto-me-through-obedience</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/1985-general-womens-meeting/1985-09-0040-barbara-w-winder-64k-eng.mp3" length="11282927" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 1985 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hope in Christ</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I rejoice with you to be in the presence of our prophet and our priesthood leaders. To be with you sisters here and throughout the world, uniting our faith to learn gospel principles, is truly a privilege.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03206_000_035" doc-version="2" hash="jWesfA">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="EG5lq2jGoU2RhIZecq3WNA" hash="DDPadg">Hope in Christ</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="NzpdSekNk0q-HbcSTLZM8g" hash="wrhaCQ">Barbara W. Winder</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.t1">
			<img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-25ce.jpg" alt="Barbara W. Winder" pid="4RSQ128x00Op65d9VdaSeQ" hash="M9fnmw" />
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p1" pid="sBMLpHhEbkKYDFlvuosexg" hash="CM7JZA">I rejoice with you to be in the presence of our prophet and our priesthood leaders. To be with you sisters here and throughout the world, uniting our faith to learn gospel principles, is truly a privilege.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p2" pid="5Lt1Z4YLUka3FQD8-pQlXA" hash="WwRPlg">How fortunate we are to be members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints!</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p3" pid="MIUJk02ZD0W5_jRmh4Fa5A" hash="WvjGdQ">Sisters, the anxiety and disquieting influence of this earth life could have been avoided had we stayed nestled in the household of our heavenly parents, but then how could we have progressed? As our Father and the Savior planned for us to come to earth, they said, “We will prove them herewith, to see if they [you and I] will do all things whatsoever the Lord their God shall command them” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.25" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:25</a>). This was to become a testing ground; we would come to an understanding of good and evil, of happiness and suffering, of joy and pain. We knew the plan. We desired it; we endorsed it. We defended it. We even fought for it!</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p4" pid="UK1D8LLg_k-h8-sJqvIbkw" hash="gjDlvw">With eagerness and excitement, we came to earth to learn—each of us having our own particular set of circumstances with trials and temptations to overcome.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p5" pid="PZ4YlaRY2Eif8DWxhG9zoA" hash="H8va8Q">We were not left without hope. Our Savior, through his atonement, has made it possible for us to obtain salvation. He will not leave us helpless as we struggle to overcome the adversities of this life.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p6" pid="iJIW_Xr1h0WC_AO0UhG9pA" hash="C6VIpg">There are so many kinds of challenges: the frustrations and disappointments of disobedient children or a difficult marriage, the loneliness of an empty house when one is so eagerly seeking companionship, the long upward road to repentance, or the difficulty of keeping a positive attitude and counting our blessings even in times of hardship.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p7" pid="7QhyH2lgp02xvwtzmiE5Fg" hash="ewS36g">The example of the Savior’s life and the teachings that he left us are patterns for us to follow. He faced trials similar to those we experience; he handled each situation in a perfect manner. In the wilderness of Judea and the Garden of Gethsemane, we witness two of the most grievous temptations of Christ, but during no part of his days in the flesh was he free from temptation. Otherwise his life would have been no human life at all. We read in Mosiah, “And lo, he shall suffer temptations, and pain of body, hunger, thirst, and fatigue, even more than man can suffer” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/3.7" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 3:7</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p8" pid="_WUBl2BQkECUsPdnb_lWFw" hash="6wKjuA">He knew disappointment, and he knew discouragement, as witnessed by his lament for his people in Jerusalem and their failure to heed his message. “O Jerusalem, Jerusalem, … how often would I have gathered thy children together, even as a hen gathereth her chickens under her wings, and ye would not!” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/23.37" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 23:37</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p9" pid="L2jeu3M9ZU2oKw8KB-E7Rw" hash="OguuGg">Which of us has not known disappointment, discouragement, and despair? That is one of the tests for all of us. Consider the Prophet Joseph, as he languished in Liberty Jail in March of 1839, having been there for months, knowing that his people had been driven from their homes and were destitute. His cry is touching: “O God, where art thou? … How long shall thy hand be stayed?” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.1-2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:1–2</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p10" pid="p1euPRC7ikG4wzTmmySbDg" hash="-xqIVA">And then the soothing answer came from a kind and loving Father:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p11" pid="DFOtC2Cf4U6drIY_H81auQ" hash="9PgfSw">“Thine adversity and thine afflictions shall be but a small moment;</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p12" pid="bFWonZo8n0KndFjCrfQ8Vg" hash="n21SVQ">“And then, if thou endure it well, God shall exalt thee on high; thou shalt triumph over all thy foes” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.7-8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:7–8</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p13" pid="oHXPow-D8kmLpqmjOkl_Qg" hash="HqaMQg">An then, later, tenderly, “Know thou, my son, that all these things shall give thee experience, and shall be for thy good” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/122.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 122:7</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p14" pid="02UYYZ1CCkWURpFJ3emvwg" hash="nUpB-w">Most of us have witnessed how living the gospel can change the lives of people in a positive way. As an example of this, I recall a family that we met while in the mission field. The missionaries described the Barnes family as being a wonderful family, but with no evidence at all of Church influence in their lives. The father was rough and crude, a beer-drinking toughie. His children were afraid of him. Their home was far from tidy, and their appearance the same. They had had a hard life. But as the missionaries met with them, a marvelous transformation began taking place. They were impressed with the life and teachings of the Savior and made an effort to apply his teachings in their lives. Their very appearance and outlook on life began to change.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p15" pid="xgrdSlvB80-D4UkE4au1Bg" hash="k3fjUw">Learning about unconditional love and not being judgmental gave them a new approach with an adult son who is an alcoholic. Their new attitude, along with professional help, seems to be making a real difference in his life.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p16" pid="rNx01SSJokSIUWloymZ3tg" hash="mp1wLA">Learning to respect themselves as sons and daughters of our Heavenly Father, they threw away their cigarettes, and they stopped drinking. They cleaned themselves up and their surroundings as well. And now there is a loving spirit in their home, where they read the scriptures regularly.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p17" pid="GKgQuX-ctk2RVPg2w4CSgw" hash="swUp6A">Sister Barnes writes: “As we read the scriptures, we found that Jesus gave the instruction to ‘be of good cheer; thy sins be forgiven thee’ (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/9.2" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 9:2</a>), indicating that as we truly repent and forsake our sins, we may be optimistic about the future. He said, ‘Let not your heart be troubled: ye believe in God, believe also in me’ (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.1" class="scriptureRef">John 14:1</a>). And we <span class="emphasis">do</span> believe in him, and this belief has changed our lives. We now feel that we can say, as Paul did, ‘I can do all things through Christ which strengtheneth me’” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/philip/4.13" class="scriptureRef">Philip. 4:13</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p18" pid="gig9quioiE-kk4EMaLsbAA" hash="_SkZAg">This was the testimony of this good woman regarding the change in her life and in her family. This change was not unlike changes that have occurred with others. After King Benjamin exhorted his people to live a good life, having hope in Christ, “They all cried with one voice, saying: Yea, we believe all the words which thou hast spoken unto us; and also, we know of their surety and truth, because of the Spirit of the Lord … , which has wrought a mighty change in us, or in our hearts, that we have no more disposition to do evil, but to do good continually” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/5.2" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 5:2</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p19" pid="PTWH5xTiXkGKvTASBCcmfA" hash="YrtspQ">Just as Brother and Sister Barnes felt the Savior’s unconditional love as they studied the gospel and found hope in Christ; and just as the people of King Benjamin found hope in him, so can we find respect for ourselves and others, rid ourselves of self-defeating habits, be nonjudgmental, be optimistic and of good cheer, be assured of his love for us, and find hope in him.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p20" pid="tg1AGypfX0C57551vX5v6Q" hash="VbfP6A">I thrilled as I read the words of a young mother of six who is also an example of one who has overcome. Divorced, yet not feeling sorry for herself, she wrote: “By my acknowledgment of my errors and my express desire to live his commandments and do his will, I shared my burden with one who cannot fail, and I know that I can raise my children hand-in-hand with a loving Father in Heaven who desires their welfare even more than I do. This knowledge is a blessing beyond description.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p21" pid="wkJlij6F_kScU6o74H7CfQ" hash="EBXbOA">Another sister wrote: “On August 3, my twenty-one-year-old son broke his neck in a diving accident six hundred miles from home. He hovers near death, but we are at peace. We do not understand the reason this had to happen, but we do understand the gospel.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p22" pid="YCvjWn7qNky3yFJRxwkJ8w" hash="YfoeGQ">Elder Richard L. Evans was sensitive to the need to prepare spiritually and emotionally for difficult times:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p23" pid="nIK2btptqkemvBvRQeMx_A" hash="0EbQdQ">“We have to prepare even for what we are unprepared for and do the best we can … to improve, to repent, to be grateful for all that is good—and to have faith and hope even [in hard times]. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p24" pid="S0CaQhITuE-UEpg_ucmR8w" hash="F6CeXQ">“And whatever happens in the interim, there is solid assurance that life is everlasting, and that eternal progress is its purpose” (Richard L. Evans, <span class="emphasis">Thoughts for One Hundred Days: Volume Four,</span> Salt Lake City: Publishers Press, 1970, p. 169).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p25" pid="A9f9XX_Ix0OhOi-4KFKxTg" hash="Rqh1mg">Let us recognize and be grateful for the blessings we have. From the Savior comes hope! Understanding the gospel, doing his works of righteousness, and following the counsel of our prophet are our <span class="emphasis">assurance</span> of the realization of that hope.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p26" pid="4dtgZT37xEGBEkw10o3xSQ" hash="8wb9AA">I know from previous and sacred experiences that it is through the faith and hope we have in Christ that we can overcome our trials.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p27" pid="D3_WtkqsEUq4SHUMdIl1Ag" hash="rPU3bw">I am ever so grateful for my opportunities as well as my share of challenges. I feel indebted to my Savior for helping me through difficult times. And I hope and desire that each of us will rely on him to ease our pains, to soothe our distresses, to buoy us up, to invigorate us and help us overcome our trials! Draw close to him who extends divine invitation to each one personally:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p28" pid="cmp8ObeEZ0iNmxEIsyAJbQ" hash="aUTtaA">“Come unto me, all ye that labor and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p29" pid="1xofRVW4a0-y5NbaQFRYMw" hash="sU9a5g">“Take my yoke upon you, … and ye shall find rest unto your souls” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/11.28-29" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 11:28–29</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ.p30" pid="Oavok4RADEC09HSPHzQFbg" hash="elTxEg">I know that he lives. I know that he cares! This is my testimony and my hope for each of us. I say these things in the sacred name of our Savior, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1986/10/hope-in-christ</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1986-general-womens-meeting/1986-09-0030-barbara-w-winder-64k-eng.mp3" length="6312006" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 1986 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding Joy in Life</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sisters, we are all in stages of progression, whether we’re married or single. We have surely felt the comforting influence of the Spirit in these proceedings. Please know of my love and concern for you!</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03219_000_035" doc-version="2" hash="NXPrkA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="l4KtwpF_DUyc1L9naOX9AA" hash="JOBImQ">Finding Joy in Life</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="HuBiEVW8B0Os6wsM3GRxtw" hash="wrhaCQ">Barbara W. Winder</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-25ce.jpg" alt="Barbara W. Winde" pid="HUm3bRoq7EOyWbrOTXtOUg" hash="M9fnmw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p1" pid="pvMHQmKOi0-LDf1FfEDc0Q" hash="zrYn6A">Sisters, we are all in stages of progression, whether we’re married or single. We have surely felt the comforting influence of the Spirit in these proceedings. Please know of my love and concern for you!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p2" pid="GRV8MEDk0ky1W6KYoFId1w" hash="9XJeqg">How long has it been since you shouted for joy? In the Grand Council in heaven in our premortal existence, all the sons and daughters of God “shouted for joy” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/job/38.7" class="scriptureRef">Job 38:7</a>). Our Father in Heaven gave us the opportunity to be born, to assume the responsibilities of mortality, which offered the opportunity of a “fulness of joy” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/16.11" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 16:11</a>) but which also entailed risks of disobedience, sin, and heartache. Yet, as our Father’s plan unfolded and we became aware of our divine potential for future immortality, we did all shout for joy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p3" pid="0mG_XtBz-EK7p3NoB1FTsg" hash="MDH_qQ">Now we are here; do we doubt the Lord’s word, “Men are, that they might have joy” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.25" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:25</a>)?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p4" pid="J1RJLj_J3EW33ytjBDyyIA" hash="44vNew">We live in a critical time in the world’s history. Satan and his forces are busy. His temptations are relentless, deceiving many, sometimes even the very elect. He would lead us to believe that gospel standards which we know to be good—virtue, honesty, morality, courtesy, industry, cleanliness of mind and body—are no longer important. Let me reaffirm that the Lord’s eternal values are still true. The ways of the world may have changed, but the commandments of our Heavenly Father, given for our welfare, are still in force, and true joy comes only from doing his will.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p5" pid="sDnWdT6yVE6hpSkWjAtjfA" hash="0ptVLg">Do we find ourselves wishing our present experiences could soon be over, as we think we might be happier doing something else? Young mothers might think that life would be easier if the children were reared and gone, but this is an opportune time to teach gospel principles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p6" pid="eVNVVFQjDEam4AUQ0frKug" hash="R9DEFw">Mother taught me that we have an obligation to give, that others don’t owe us a living, and that more joy comes from giving than receiving.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p7" pid="fbW7vdRAPUOlqSdcVAE2qA" hash="QigF7A">As a child, I desired a birthday party. I invited all of my friends to come—it wasn’t even near my birthday—and I carefully instructed them to each bring me a dime. When Mother heard of my trick, she immediately gave me a scolding, sat me down, and carefully explained why what I did was not right. Then she went with me to each of my friends so that I could apologize. It was an embarrassing lesson, but one I have never forgotten.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p8" pid="LMHemnbk-Eub437Kw-34_g" hash="yPMmKQ">When we think of the Lord’s eternal plan for us, do we really want no difficulty, no struggle, no adversity? For the plan is to “prove [us] herewith, to see if [we] will do all things whatsoever the Lord [our] God shall command [us]” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.25" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:25</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p9" pid="MKldAtWkLEeaP3ps00bPlQ" hash="atI4hA">The Book of Mormon tells a beautiful example of a people who had been through much tribulation and yet had a remarkable experience of feeling eternal joy while in mortality. On the resurrected Savior’s first day among the Nephites, he taught much of his gospel. As he prepared to leave, he saw a people who displayed great faith and who hungered for his words. He was moved with such compassion toward them that he tarried longer and ministered to their personal needs. The scriptures tell us that “no one can conceive of the joy which filled [their] souls” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.16-19" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:16–19</a>). The Savior said unto them:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p10" pid="Xk0ukEhixEGgTBs1CIdO1Q" hash="L9AUuw">“Blessed are ye because of your faith. And now behold, my joy is full” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.20" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:20</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p11" pid="Q1pgHy-pdkCsKj1I47QfBQ" hash="Je8MSw">Joy, it seems, is not only happiness, but the resultant feeling of the Holy Ghost manifest within us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p12" pid="_rE9T2v7z0qbMZo6S8lZaw" hash="W-x_iQ">How can we provide a climate in our lives to foster the presence of the Holy Ghost, that our lives may be more joyful? Just as a reservoir stores water to bring relief and replenish the thirsty land, so we can store experiences, knowledge, and desires to replenish and fortify our spiritual needs. Four ways may be helpful in developing reservoirs of righteousness and spiritual self-reliance. We prepare by—</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.f2">
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="03QSPjHr00awfMx-FPJ9wg" hash="Gq9HEQ">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="CPoKJ7mNxU2SXZRSabpfAg" hash="oViZlw">Developing a cheerful disposition wherein the Spirit can dwell.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="gSQxFs3ohkGvvOCejT5ngQ" hash="l5Wnkw">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="E-J_ZSB4J06FPQ2t9cugtg" hash="zWtjtA">Learning the Savior’s will for us, that we may know our divine potential.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="_IsC-r8WKkmX5XwIfxNTUQ" hash="pIdkKQ">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="DlXgnB-2p0mF8aFDql3BEw" hash="nK5RTQ">Understanding and accepting his atoning sacrifice and repenting of our sins.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="aIdKQHSmhkS9h3vJ7vr_gw" hash="ktwJGA">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="eV9jua3_mU-l8tlzKSHyrQ" hash="-WSfXA">Keeping his commandments and having a firm determination to serve him.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p13" pid="uqIp46fz4kyW0ybdE8-GUw" hash="eKoO9A">Let’s examine these four points:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p14" pid="9WiieFmR20CY3wpW9PON1Q" hash="MiSvHA">First: Developing a cheerful disposition can permit an atmosphere wherein one’s spirit can be nurtured and encouraged to blossom and bear fruit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p15" pid="8Pxzm4oitkuTKF8vP_bBrQ" hash="YBbrCQ">Being pessimistic and negative about our experiences will not enhance the quality of our lives. A determination to be of good cheer can help us and those around us to enjoy life more fully.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p16" pid="_WvaH1PorEK09t_OCaoeww" hash="83rKGg">Elder Marvin J. Ashton reminds us:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p17" pid="KHrucc3wFEmsTA5nb-oYKw" hash="YcghNA">“With God’s help, good cheer permits us to rise above the depressing present or difficult circumstances. … It is sunshine when clouds block the light” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1986, p. 66). Each woman is responsible for her own happiness. Let us strive to cultivate this spirit of gladness in our homes and let it shine in our faces wherever we go.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p18" pid="uYyezgKLuUiViuPsE8tlqQ" hash="XkHD0Q">Years ago, when our four-month-old son had an operation, I felt forsaken and alone in a hospital waiting room. Another mother there was particularly comforting to me. She took me down the hall to meet her twelve-year-old daughter, who was suffering from leukemia. I found her to be like her mother, peacefully and cheerfully accepting this fatal illness. The girl was busy knitting dishcloths for her nurses. Her brightness helped me put my own concerns temporarily aside.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p19" pid="k9lUEsaJJEOypy9ZT6PAag" hash="Ixb8gQ">A few days later, our little one, now at home, was much better. I received a note from this mother. The affliction had taken my new young friend back to her Heavenly Father, but before she died, she asked her mother to send me a hand-knit dishcloth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p20" pid="2_ZYJYz3SEKVqdacxOU88A" hash="6GPPYA">What a beautiful example they were to me of “good cheer” even in such a difficult circumstance. They had learned to accept those things they could not change and remembered the Savior’s words, “Be of good cheer, and do not fear, for I the Lord am with you, and will stand by you” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:6</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p21" pid="pqaZldE2jEqhMeOCUEzONA" hash="r7WE9A">I, too, remembered the Savior’s words, “They who have endured the crosses of the world, … shall inherit the kingdom of God, … and their joy shall be full forever” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/9.18" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 9:18</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p22" pid="RYKor2DUEUexV_GSZjdGHg" hash="OBB6Kw">Second point: Learning the Savior’s will for us, will help us know of our divine potential and bring joy to our being.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p23" pid="lvoP7gXU7Euf_g9tVccYvg" hash="wYscfw">Sisters, take joy in knowing that we have a prophet of God on earth today! Give thanks for the governing, sustaining power of the priesthood! Rejoice in the glories of our womanhood! Both President Spencer W. Kimball and President Ezra Taft Benson have asked that we understand the dignity and worth of our role in the divine process of motherhood and that we, whether married or single, make our homes places of love and learning, of refuge and refinement (see <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1978, p. 101).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p24" pid="xnnJvFLrV0-hgweh-PqcAg" hash="iVs8Uw">Surely we are adding to our spiritual reservoir as we listen to our prophet’s voice, read the holy scriptures, fast and pray, and apply the teachings we learn to our lives through the confirmation we receive from the Holy Spirit, that still, small voice that brings “peace to [our] mind[s]” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:23</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p25" pid="yVyK02ZPrU-y7Oggpsc7Xg" hash="Fjou8w">There are some lovely women in the Church who are comfortable and content to let someone else do the teaching, give the service, fulfill the callings. Sisters, it is so important that each of us be willing to do whatever is required of us wherever we are called. We do not pick and choose what we will accept, just as we do not choose which commandments to obey.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p26" pid="BzHz9qzEO0uM_9obofSDRA" hash="FUBm9Q">The Lord says, beware of pride, lift up our hearts and rejoice and cleave unto the covenants we have made (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/25.13-14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 25:13–14</a>). We are admonished “to bear one another’s burdens, … comfort those that stand in need of comfort, and … stand as witnesses of God at all times” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.8-9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:8–9</a>). This may be hard to do because of worldly voices telling us to do otherwise. Let us stay close to the Lord and develop our divine potential by using our gifts and talents as he has advised us to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p27" pid="r6BZWFh4O0y6wERkLSfNuw" hash="zwIgPg">Let us rejoice as we work together with those who hold the priesthood, each assuming his or her responsibilities and sharing our gifts and talents, that all may be edified together.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p28" pid="Qvv-VEJ4P0G89stknFw9oQ" hash="IiC72g">Third point: Understanding the blessing of the Atonement enables us to repent and renew our baptismal covenants weekly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p29" pid="SgtvCyqVkky20REjn8Puvw" hash="BGvBCA">Joy is knowing that through the atoning sacrifice of Christ we can receive a remission of our sins, even as King Benjamin taught. His people prayed in great humility, having asked for forgiveness of their sins. “The Spirit of the Lord came upon them, and they were filled with joy, having received a remission of their sins, and having peace of conscience, because of the exceeding faith which they had in Jesus Christ” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.3" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:3</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p30" pid="E-soVItsI0WQxLox3N8QWQ" hash="ZSND3w">Elder James E. Talmage tells us that repentance “indicates a godly sorrow for sin, producing a reformation of life, and embodies (1) a conviction of guilt; (2) a desire to be relieved from the hurtful effects of sin; and (3) an earnest determination to forsake sin and to accomplish good” (<span class="emphasis">The Articles of Faith,</span> 12th ed., Salt Lake City: The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, 1924, p. 109). It involves confession for serious sins and restitution where necessary and possible.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p31" pid="tVqEuckFs0azax8-WDYX8w" hash="TyvlPA">Fourth Point: Keeping the commandments and having a firm determination to serve the Savior can bring joy indescribable here and eternal happiness hereafter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p32" pid="tlZ9JHbDK0y_LP7Gxw4F7w" hash="iNTfUg">King Benjamin taught that we should not have a mind to injure one another; rather, we should live peaceably, not suffer our children to go hungry, or naked, or transgress the laws of God, or fight and quarrel one with another, but love and serve one another (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.13-15" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:13–15</a>). He further stated, “I cannot tell you all the ways whereby ye may commit sin; … But … watch yourselves, and your thoughts, words, and … deeds, and observe the commandments of God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.29-30" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:29–30</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p33" pid="4tcFUW-MlUiu9rso4YnOTA" hash="OG2AQQ">The Savior said, “A new commandment I give unto you, That ye love one another; as I have loved you” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/13.34" class="scriptureRef">John 13:34</a>). That great love enabled him to live a life of service, even unto the laying down of his life for us. He would have us serve one another even as he has done.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p34" pid="dOF4vw51t0-fsTuwN-l2Ig" hash="RuUvcA">An elderly widow struggled with the pain of arthritis. When she came to live with her daughter, the mother retreated into her own uncomfortable world. She had to be assisted up and down the steps as she went in and out the door.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p35" pid="C-IWIUJ1Pk63aPnH3ssW8w" hash="vbInoA">Hoping to give her mother a positive experience, the daughter suggested that her mother might read to a blind neighbor. Reluctantly, the suffering widow agreed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p36" pid="Dt9SqmA9NkC5lB2NZs-Q1Q" hash="HcRvyQ">Moaning faintly at the effort, the widow allowed her daughter to help her down the steps. Then she hobbled up the street to make the dutiful visit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p37" pid="a28Y8GiEsUCGgnpm7F3XxA" hash="ZKH_WA">An hour passed. Two hours. At last, her family saw her returning, coming happily down the street. Amazingly, she came up the steps and into the house without assistance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p38" pid="s0P3ScSTwkmJlV4AbqlTRA" hash="oknS4w">“Well,” she told her daughter, “I sure did her a lot of good.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p39" pid="PVajkLIIY0mgtjhRXfKHaQ" hash="Wv3skg">The Savior admonished us to spread his gospel that all might come unto him. We participate as we prepare our homes to be “missionary training centers” for our children as well as ourselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p40" pid="7hUTFcybOky9YHNeClcEQQ" hash="xliV2Q">We can also participate in this great missionary cause by fellowshipping those who have wandered. It takes patience and diligence, but, oh, what joy is ours as we assist in bringing these, our brethren and sisters, again unto the Savior (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/31.35" class="scriptureRef">Alma 31:35</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.15-16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:15–16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p41" pid="FEpXdzYm10S-SXov7crO0Q" hash="IPt1Hw">May I share a story of one of our dear sisters. She wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p42" pid="RZfmGtocA0OrcnC9fEJ70A" hash="6s7oTA">“In our home were alcohol, drug abuse, two divorces. I was living in spiritual darkness with two tiny children, when ‘angels of mercy’ came one more time. Each month I peeked out my window as the visiting teachers tried to visit me. I hid myself quietly until they left. They never gave up, and I am so glad and thankful. I learned that God’s love never stops!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p43" pid="YsKjRIsZl0yxPjc2svI8cQ" hash="jeF3lg">This sister is now an endowed member in full fellowship and full of happiness and joy!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p44" pid="KjE4MhzdI0uyNVBi-b2mCA" hash="Fe1Ijg">Sisters, may we prepare our reservoirs of spiritual strength, wherein we can find joy! It is God’s reward for righteous living!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p45" pid="8-atjaR9eEeQuFP7Az_LmA" hash="pJUOkQ">Near the end of his life, having experienced years of trial, almost beyond our ability to comprehend, being dragged through the streets, tarred and feathered, having some of his closest associates turn against him, the Prophet Joseph Smith could yet testify and cheer us on as he exclaimed:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p46" pid="CyC2DKPKiUyiHXHDHXQXTA" hash="meMSvw">“Now, what do we hear in the gospel which we have received? A voice of gladness! A voice of mercy from heaven; … a voice of gladness for the living and the dead; glad tidings of great joy … Let your hearts rejoice, and be exceedingly glad” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/128.19,22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 128:19, 22</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life.p47" pid="DfdxxxN_FEmwwWBiGjfM4Q" hash="70yVLw">May we take joy in our faith, even our knowledge, that Jesus is the Christ, the Son of the living God, I say in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1987/10/finding-joy-in-life</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1987-general-womens-meeting/1987-09-0030-barbara-w-winder-64k-eng.mp3" length="7509476" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 1987 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Prepared People</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people?lang=eng</link>
      <description>“Make me an instrument of thy peace.” What meaningful words for the women of the Church!</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03232_000_034" doc-version="2" hash="nYN2UA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="JiQKehCLb0CNj5G13AQK0w" hash="zA4TTw">Becoming a Prepared People</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Y4oKUjKnZEiUkkIFQ3kAQQ" hash="wrhaCQ">Barbara W. Winder</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p1" pid="mEp7PPdklUCbRmIwADBUXQ" hash="zgDI-A">“Make me an instrument of thy peace.” What meaningful words for the women of the Church!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p2" pid="bt-xJt2h-kedyNTUfpLooA" hash="5yZj6Q">Others, too, teach us of women. In Proverbs we read, “Who can find a virtuous woman? for her price is far above rubies.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/31.10" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 31:10</a>; <a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/31.10-31" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 31:10–31</a>.) The virtuous woman described in Proverbs was a woman who was prepared. She worked willingly, stretched out her hand to the poor, saw to the physical needs of her household, sought after knowledge. She had profound reverence for the Lord. While many of her tasks may appear to be temporal in nature, her blessings were eternal ones.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p3" pid="P14_72kHB0C3mkpEmw1_oQ" hash="ITQtCA">When we speak of preparedness, often our first thoughts center on temporal or physical preparations—food, clothing, shelter. While these preparations are important and necessary, they are not all-inclusive.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p4" pid="K_o-KOsRl0uLY_6oSh6Rpw" hash="tyHyxw">There is a crucial balance between the temporal and the spiritual aspects of this principle. The Lord has said, “All things unto me are spiritual, and not at any time have I given unto you a law which was temporal.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/29.34" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 29:34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p5" pid="i3a3QxRXn0-V62HcYZv5Kg" hash="f_0ofQ">The Lord taught us a very important lesson when he visited the home of his friends Mary and Martha. While Martha attended to the needs of her guest, Mary sat and listened to the words of the Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p6" pid="N0GNMsOdSEyoahHCSP4Ftg" hash="n0oTsQ">We read: “But Martha was cumbered about much serving, and came to him, and said, Lord, dost thou not care that my sister hath left me to serve alone? Bid her therefore that she help me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p7" pid="Ggio0vNHXUicsYbBILHQBg" hash="8tVGJA">“And Jesus answered … , Martha, Martha, thou art careful and troubled about many things:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p8" pid="iuaIyhoyQkODxVJJhKIVJQ" hash="9iGjJg">“But one thing is needful: and Mary hath chosen that good part, which shall not be taken away from her.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.40-42" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:40–42</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p9" pid="JU_ShonZjkugJDJ9iUFJ-g" hash="y0JCPg">In his counsel, “but one thing is needful,” could the Lord have been referring to one thing lacking in Martha’s preparation? Probably. There is need for balance. Our physical preparation—including a clean, orderly home—makes it possible for the Spirit to be present. Likewise, the Spirit of the Lord brings an atmosphere of peace and contentment to our orderly home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p10" pid="7blXssZyPEGrHcAwNGnsoQ" hash="kJkRCw">One sister told of her preparation to receive a General Authority guest in her home for stake conference. Everything was to be perfect. Extensive cleaning and cooking were done. Her ten children were prepped as to what their roles should be. She worked hard! By the time he arrived she was exhausted and couldn’t enjoy his visit. Too late, she realized that spiritual preparation was “needful” also.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p11" pid="C6aFZmpivUib_o1i1c2seQ" hash="09mqIA">She stated, “It is because of our spiritual preparation that we can find answers to our everyday challenges. It is because of our spiritual preparation that we can find joy in enduring and overcoming our trials. It is because of our spiritual preparation that we can feel the greatest joy of all, a nearness and closeness to our Savior and Father in Heaven.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p12" pid="qCNbn3wo-Ueme4-bITwYJg" hash="SLcgjw">How, then, do we prepare?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p13" pid="eAsIFn7Xw0a2QSmx4K0Rew" hash="vT36lQ">We prepare by developing a strong relationship with our Heavenly Father through prayer, scripture study, and obedience to the commandments; by knowing our own worth; and by sustaining the priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p14" pid="lGuT77fTck-tQdKzx-qPeA" hash="L0uz8A">Qualities of spirituality do not come without effort. Like any other talent with which we are blessed, they must be constantly practiced. A famous pianist once said, “If I fail to practice for one day, I can tell the difference in my playing. If I fail to practice for two days, my family can tell the difference. If I fail for three days, the whole world can tell the difference.” This same principle applies to us in our quest for exaltation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p15" pid="CA1rPt8r3UOWhRZBhLd3Fw" hash="_wpQhw">In applying the parable of the ten virgins to our lives, our modern prophets have explained that the oil of preparation is accumulated drop by drop through daily righteous living.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p16" pid="cd-bPR_HZkqKMn0swuEjTg" hash="pszr3w">Consistently attending sacrament meetings adds oil to our lamps. So too will fasting, praying individually and as a family, visiting teaching, controlling our bodily appetites, teaching gospel principles, nourishing and nurturing, watching over one another, studying the scriptures, keeping the commandments. Each act of dedication and obedience is a drop of oil with which we can refuel our lamps. Keeping the commandments and following the words of the prophet may be the greatest preparation we can make for any eventuality to come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p17" pid="bNi30dIImUelg4VTaji8WQ" hash="xxN2nw">A few years ago while we were serving in the mission field, a minister who was investigating the Church said, “I hear you talk about the benefit of a living prophet. What sort of pronouncements has he made lately?” We replied, “The prophet has taught us that we need to live frugally. We need to stay out of debt, fix up our homes, and plant gardens that we may enjoy the fruit of our labor.” The minister thought for a moment and then said, “That is not what I would have imagined a prophet to say, but as I consider it, what better advice could be given?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p18" pid="ARF5gjknTk282arvd21H1g" hash="Ws-0XQ">Often the advice that is given by our prophets is so simple and practical that we overlook it and fail to heed it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p19" pid="NJSNLTTSBkyeUkgwbotr3A" hash="8FO0NQ">We are taught that we have great worth in the eyes of our Heavenly Father. The Primary children sing, “I am a child of God.” The Young Women recite their theme which begins, “We are daughters of our Heavenly Father, who loves us,” and the prophets have declared that virtuous women are more priceless than rubies.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p20" pid="HWIF9unHdk-mTk8ZjrJwiw" hash="0S2E6Q">Listen to this simple direction from our prophet to the young women of the Church, which applies to all of us: “Live up to your divine potential. Remember who you are and the divine heritage that is yours—you are literally the royal daughters of our Father in Heaven.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1986, p. 85.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p21" pid="V4jTVFGEbE-diZN-54WXaQ" hash="vpeTzQ">“Don’t settle for less than what the Lord wants you to be.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1986, p. 84.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p22" pid="6e1PChFSd0ubboydNswXvA" hash="dSQnCg">Unfortunately, many of us fail to recognize what the Lord wants us to be. A sister wrote to me recently, telling of some events that led her to realize how much her Heavenly Father loved her and had blessed her. She said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p23" pid="eoGEyTzyWEqnxVh2dIZwPQ" hash="geJsPw">“I have had very low self-esteem and have not felt ‘good enough’ to have a close relationship with [my Father in Heaven]. This has kept me self-centered and unable to serve as effectively as I could. During the last few months I have felt a yearning desire within me, an urgency, if you will, to draw nearer to my Father in Heaven. Lately I have felt his arm around me and his great love extending to me—a beautiful feeling of acceptance. With this have come many gifts: more patience, more self-control, [more understanding]. I know this is the Holy Ghost teaching me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p24" pid="a7nl9fvZdUiYfm7DXwVQhg" hash="9o7_Iw">“I have learned when priorities are in order and I prepare personally each day with prayer, scripture study, and physical care, I am happier and a more profitable servant.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p25" pid="Bo2tfOxGKUCPNm9cYsVFdg" hash="ixayIg">We learn from this that we also prepare by serving, teaching, nurturing, and helping others prepare. As we work daily to attain righteousness and a spiritual way of life, we have a responsibility to elevate others, to help them realize their divine potential, and to be an instrument in the hands of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p26" pid="nOR6ESfx9EOxT1SmT9TmZg" hash="On6GJQ">Yes, being a woman brings blessings and responsibilities. Often there are tasks which, when filled, are without visibility, acclaim, or attendant worldly power. Nonetheless they are vital to the progress of humankind. When we are diverted from our course, serious weaknesses may appear in our lives and in the lives of family members, as well as in society.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p27" pid="ml2Lx9SO4kqFzw-eFfOMyA" hash="pp4Rkg">Because of “the subtle craftiness of men [who] lie in wait to deceive” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/123.12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 123:12</a>), many, even of the very elect, are being deceived. How diligently, sisters, we must strive to reach out to those who “know not where to find [the truth” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/123.12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 123:12</a>) and bring them home again unto the fold. No effort is too great, no endeavor too much.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p28" pid="uZL7X5JOZUuE3cGMq5GTfA" hash="EHZ6mg">Our preparation does not always proceed just as we had planned it. My own mother has shared with me some of her goals and aspirations. Often as she began a project, something would happen to change her course of action: a mother-in-law in her waning years needed a home and special care, a younger sister needed help to complete her schooling. There were those with whom she worked who also desperately needed help. She was always there to serve. She gave this service graciously, and though not all her own personal plans were accomplished, she looks back on her life and says that if she had it to do all over again, she wouldn’t change anything. Service to others brings that kind of satisfaction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p29" pid="Psr_CXhjw0WT5doDlFFlig" hash="PcbdrQ">It is according to our natures, sisters, to have feelings of charity and benevolence. It isn’t always easy to put these feelings into action. But as women, we should pray for charitable desires and opportunities and then work to foster these godlike attributes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p30" pid="PrqjEroPIEGKeAm2fQWXcA" hash="sElV7w">I suppose that Emma Smith had more than her share of frustration and disappointment. Her life couldn’t have been easy as she suffered persecution along with her husband, the Prophet. It is reported that shortly before his martyrdom, Joseph sent a message to Emma in answer to her request for a blessing. He was not able to give her a blessing, but told her to write one, and when he saw her again he would sign it. I am impressed with the faith and the righteous intent revealed in her words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p31" pid="kkokRwgt90S9kDpSEx8HjQ" hash="bmscrw">“I desire the Spirit of God to know and understand myself. … I desire a fruitful, active mind, that I may be able to comprehend the designs of God, when revealed through His servants … I particularly desire wisdom to bring up all the children that are, or may be committed to my charge, in such a manner that they will be useful … in the Kingdom of God … I desire … that I may wear a cheerful countenance … and be a blessing to all. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p32" pid="LKaeFytDeUKRN5TjmtxCqw" hash="SiZ84A">“I desire with all my heart to honor and respect my husband.” (Ms., Historical Department, The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p33" pid="kAFQ8C4JpkGnxweXYY7BtQ" hash="VEzv1g">President Ezra Taft Benson has declared, “When we put God first, all other things fall into their proper place or drop out of our lives. Our love of the Lord will govern the claims for our affection, the demands on our time, the interests we pursue, and the order of our priorities.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1988, p. 4.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p34" pid="9faK9AfFTkW45PWGd3TKeg" hash="LxMR3g">We need to put God first and balance our spiritual and temporal preparations, that we might become virtuous women, righteous daughters, instruments in his hands to help prepare the way for his coming.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p35" pid="0UGc-E1tkUCmG2lNpV4vIA" hash="GwJ74w">Sisters, “shall we not go on in so great a cause?” as we read in the Doctrine and Covenants. “Go forward and not backward. Courage … and on, on to the victory! Let your hearts rejoice, and be exceedingly glad.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/128.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 128:22</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p36" pid="ZLTZyjwWjEye5ULHkzj0kQ" hash="yKbV4A">I pray, sisters, that we will rejoice and go on to victory as we prepare for the second coming of our Savior. I pray that we will not be led away by the subtle enticings of the world that sometimes come to us even from those near and dear to us—the enticings that say to us, “Seek for visibility; seek for power and influence; be sure your own needs are being met.” These are not the teachings of him whose coming we await. He says to us, rather, be the servant of all (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/9.35" class="scriptureRef">Mark 9:35</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/20.26-27" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 20:26–27</a>); “let your light so shine before men, that they may see your good works, and glorify your Father which is in heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.16" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p37" pid="Ie7XXurn0EaDjlTS3faJHQ" hash="PPHAqQ">I pray that we will not be discouraged and not be led away, not be deceived—but “cheerfully do all things that lie in our power; and then may we stand still, with the utmost assurance, to see the salvation of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/123.17" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 123:17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people.p38" pid="HvxxOgmo9Uu6K0GhULlBgw" hash="QFdKNQ">I know our Father lives and that Jesus is the Christ. We are engaged in his work. I say these things in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1988/10/becoming-a-prepared-people</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1988-general-womens-meeting/1988-09-0010-barbara-w-winder-64k-eng.mp3" length="7246797" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 1988 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instruments to Accomplish His Purposes</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, my heart is full to capacity. As we have been released in the normal rotation of assignments, we want to welcome those who have been newly called and to offer them our love and sincere support.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_90905_000_033" doc-version="2" hash="vVB9JQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="m4bSW_mZWEeIAmADByskOA" hash="dBjzWQ">Instruments to Accomplish His Purposes</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="nTSPUfPUM06fwMABcFGPXA" hash="wrhaCQ">Barbara W. Winder</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-25ce.jpg" alt="Sister Barbara W. Winder" pid="brLIjo9XZ0ewpkcgCF0YXw" hash="M9fnmw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes.p1" pid="Lwut75ECm06EizbVk8hKIA" hash="oUCLMQ">My dear brothers and sisters, my heart is full to capacity. As we have been released in the normal rotation of assignments, we want to welcome those who have been newly called and to offer them our love and sincere support.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes.p2" pid="2QF-mciKn0SSMMXXET6F4A" hash="91cz0g">Luther Burbank wrote: “Like the year [at the end of summer,] I pause now, toward the end of my allotted time, to glance backward and to gather my harvest of experience and growth and friendship and … memory. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes.p3" pid="KzxGi2DUzEOc1OaVrivEyw" hash="7djn4g">“[And] what has been my ‘harvest …’?</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes.f2">
	<ol class="symbol">
	  <li>
	    <p pid="G2FzfRklN0yYlhS8E1LAmA" hash="I2lXlg">—</p>
	    <p pid="vJDO4ia7CEGEVhEwbSrX2A" hash="rrUPoA">“The harvest of work accomplished and aims achieved. …</p>
	  </li>
	  <li>
	    <p pid="DPZU1PrVLk-Svo1uP8qujw" hash="I2lXlg1">—</p>
	    <p pid="AjLYJZpeDUiYeMwDc0rWHQ" hash="C04TzQ">“The harvested experiences and lessons that have moulded and impressed … my … life. …</p>
	  </li>
	  <li>
	    <p pid="XppxWDVj-0WHE-aGvj28qA" hash="I2lXlg2">—</p>
	    <p pid="H7tW2QTp30ureVj5C_xpqg" hash="9Cx_2A">“[And] the harvest of dear friendships, happy memories. …</p>
	  </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes.f3">
	<p pid="6pt8E2DKCkWk4MvZY-U09w" hash="i28xjw">Our harvested experiences and lessons have been molded with many of you:</p>
	<ol class="symbol">
	  <li>
	    <p pid="H9LJ22sI1E2WmfLS6vDelQ" hash="I2lXlg3">—</p>
	    <p pid="M8e8qAtdO0mGrqmJTM8s3Q" hash="FDR_bw">Your prayers on our behalf have been felt. We are grateful.</p>
	  </li>
	  <li>
	    <p pid="wS2x7KdGqkmuT4UEdCxiAQ" hash="I2lXlg4">—</p>
	    <p pid="k3W6OAxotkihVOjh3qVcfQ" hash="4CtTqA">Your yearnings and desires shared by letter or visit have become the pleadings of our prayers.</p>
	  </li>
	  <li>
	    <p pid="g_YR6ZaR60-poNu4tFYhfA" hash="I2lXlg5">—</p>
	    <p pid="W7pku0xl7kSRpMDDTcmTkA" hash="3gIOBA">Our assignments and invitations have brought us into your homes, families, and chapels, where we became acutely aware of how much you hunger and thirst after righteousness, for we with you, while we have been there, have been filled with the Holy Ghost. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/12.6" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 12:6</a>.)</p>
	  </li>
	  <li>
	    <p pid="8PFWSJLazEGQabuKpBNS6Q" hash="I2lXlg6">—</p>
	    <p pid="DwDiviKX2Ua96yococFLVg" hash="h2vNNw">We have watched your tender mercies and ministerings to one another.</p>
	  </li>
	  <li>
	    <p pid="7i-S8Svw0k6LrG2zvaAhOw" hash="I2lXlg7">—</p>
	    <p pid="q6mGWwhI3UKBsq9Dn9srFw" hash="_Ol-Iw">We have observed priesthood leaders and sisters and auxiliary leaders working together to strengthen families and bring them home to the Savior.</p>
	  </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes.f4">
	<p pid="8l-jUj4gMkCdo8V_sFOl5A" hash="yUJKuQ">The harvest of happy memories and dear friendships is perhaps the sweetest of all the blessings:</p>
	<ol class="symbol">
	  <li>
	    <p pid="4yPPTyVjHkS1Jhjk1cM35w" hash="I2lXlg8">—</p>
	    <p pid="rjoMuMaO3Uma1iTA8O3kQA" hash="JckRDw">“[For] that same sociality which exists among us here will exist among us there, only it will be coupled with eternal glory.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/130.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 130:2</a>.)</p>
	  </li>
	  <li>
	    <p pid="mREakqSZAk-RREDmW0VszA" hash="I2lXlg9">—</p>
	    <p pid="2IlnOWasGUOTRQ_RBvBdcQ" hash="B6Pihg">I am grateful for family support; grateful to have served with capable, committed counselors, general secretary, and board members, as well as officers and board members of our sister organizations, and our devoted, competent staff, volunteers, and hostesses. I am grateful for the support team in the Church offices.</p>
	  </li>
	  <li>
	    <p pid="-2_i_67niEGU3-JqaRKMrA" hash="I2lXlg10">—</p>
	    <p pid="0ORWkp7oYkK9ww6vnf3o_g" hash="bMvMFQ">It has been an honor and a privilege to serve with our dear General Authorities, noble sons of our Heavenly Father. I have learned from them as I have observed integrity, loyalty, charity, compassion, and a stalwart devotion to Deity. How blessed I feel to have been a part.</p>
	  </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes.p4" pid="Tsgrj4HHuk6bm72Uqn72Pg" hash="d9xRDQ">Six years ago my husband presided over the California San Diego Mission. We were called home a year early for me to fill this assignment. And now we return to specific missionary work. This time, he will preside over the Czechoslovakia mission, where he labored as a youth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes.p5" pid="26hUJvov2EiH0ptrNTCcsw" hash="HzQscA">It is humbling to look forward with my husband to yet another challenge. I desire to support him as he has supported me so steadfastly for the past six years. The spirit of missionary work is upon us, even as it was upon the sons of Mosiah:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes.p6" pid="md8IQy27OUuoFm2Uwms4qQ" hash="VLse_Q">“They fasted … and prayed much that the Lord would grant unto them … his Spirit to go with them, and abide with them, that they might be an instrument in the hands of God to bring … their brethren … to the knowledge of the truth.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/17.9" class="scriptureRef">Alma 17:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes.p7" pid="CxB56BYCnUWG8ZLEycp1LQ" hash="5n6gZQ">Recently while we were sitting in a mission presidents’ training meeting, the challenges of our California mission flooded back into my mind. And I knew we would again face similar concerns, even with yet unknown problems.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes.p8" pid="pN4d32xJC0ymtCxuX-qs0Q" hash="CmqSUA">In spite of these unsettled feelings, at the conclusion of the training meeting, I felt an excitement difficult to describe. I might liken it to how we may have felt in the premortal existence as we learned of the gospel plan. We knew there would be adversities in this earth life, yet we shouted for joy at the prospects of being able to come here.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes.p9" pid="6O3hc3MvxUSzYC6jYid12Q" hash="nTSJ_A">Now our excitement causes us to shout for joy as we gather our resources and prepare for this new opportunity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes.p10" pid="MskAcr9ldk2xsCnEXGCPyw" hash="oJmCSQ">I will forever treasure this time in the Relief Society filled with rich associations and experiences. Indeed, the Lord has allowed the harvest to be abundant, bursting with seed for yet another season. I am humbled and weak but I know with the help of the Lord we can be instruments to accomplish his purposes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes.p11" pid="Yxmdo3oc7ke0aAwuVhsiNA" hash="9yrvHw">May we all feel his strength as we seek to serve him. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1990/04/instruments-to-accomplish-his-purposes</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1990-general-conference/1990-04-5030-barbara-w-winder-64k-eng.mp3" length="5973055" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 1990 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
