<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Benjamín De Hoyos</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Benjamín De Hoyos.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Benjam%C3%ADn%20De%20Hoyos.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Benjamín De Hoyos.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>True Happiness: A Conscious Decision</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Happiness is a condition of the soul. This joyous state comes as a result of righteous living.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10033479_000_012" doc-version="2" hash="F2ydqQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="wBaHpALogkGbWR3sq27DgQ" hash="ZMdU6w">True Happiness:</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="rQ-Gk43GnECUbBZ65epyGw" hash="8oIxRQ">A Conscious Decision</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="woDgNPU0NEGBPcw9w2ricg" hash="WPKQaQ">Benjamín De Hoyos</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="zgDeS0S6m0KoPVpeuWHh2A" hash="x1JXVw">Happiness is a condition of the soul. This joyous state comes as a result of righteous living.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-10b.jpg" alt="Elder Benjamín De Hoyos" pid="nfKHupfo2USegdl6HXvwfg" hash="KtbrAA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.p1" pid="1KDLcCAsNkmk5qqSg3NkwQ" hash="8WXzqw">“Life is good, if we live in such a way to make it so.” This was a part of an inspirational message I read many years ago. What the message calls “a good life” comes as a result of the way we do things, of the words we choose to say, and even of the kind of thoughts we choose to have.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.p2" pid="etjIq9-0_UKZdomp-eUr5A" hash="-jdZGA">No one needs to feel alone on the road of life, for we are all invited to come unto Christ and be perfected in Him. Happiness is the purpose of the gospel and the purpose of the redeeming Atonement for all men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.p3" pid="wzzBkbqhjE6EyM5GAbH_xQ" hash="P88ZIw">The account in the book of Helaman expressed it in a concise way: “Thus we may see that the Lord is merciful <span class="emphasis">unto all</span> who will, in the sincerity of their hearts, call upon his holy name.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.p4" pid="yezSZzboL0-c1B3Y11hPng" hash="stKaqw">“Yea, thus we see that the gate of heaven is open <span class="emphasis">unto all,</span> even <span class="emphasis">to those who will</span> believe on the name of Jesus Christ, who is the Son of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.p5" pid="6tuRPr0g8kCxi6KKRY7lpg" hash="wrdaIQ">“Yea, we see that <span class="emphasis">whosoever will</span> may lay hold upon the word of God, which is quick and powerful, which shall … lead the man of Christ in a strait and narrow course …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.p6" pid="Udflv4JuxEiRMfzt-VRwRw" hash="CS_UsA">“And land their souls, yea, their immortal souls, at the right hand of God in the kingdom of heaven.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.p7" pid="eNbq-IttnkOtZ9m2iDv2pw" hash="4Zwgtg">My beloved brothers and sisters, we need to recognize that “wanting to” is the determining factor which leads us to lay hold upon the word of God and be happy. Perseverance in making correct decisions is what leads us to happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.p8" pid="b3Ec_vi6i0yfBRR4s0ZNxg" hash="OcPPbA">Happiness comes as a result of our obedience and our courage in always doing the will of God, even in the most difficult circumstances. When the prophet Lehi warned the inhabitants of Jerusalem, they mocked him, and, as with other ancient prophets, they sought to take away his life. I quote the prophet Nephi: “I … will show unto you that the tender mercies of the Lord are <span class="emphasis">over all those</span> whom he hath chosen, because of their faith, to make them mighty even unto the power of deliverance.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.p9" pid="buCX0pOF2kiuEVVsnsFIJA" hash="z3VPqQ">When I was serving as a missionary in northern Mexico, a few days after the baptismal service of the Valdez family, we received a telephone call from Brother Valdez asking us to come to his house. He had an important question for us. Now that he knew the will of the Lord regarding the Word of Wisdom, and even though it would be difficult to find a new job, he wondered if he should continue to work for the cigarette company where he had worked for many years. Only a few days later Brother Valdez again asked us to come by and visit him. He had decided to quit his job because he was not willing to go against his convictions. Then with a smile and emotion in his voice, he told us that the very day he quit his old job, another company had called to offer him a much better position.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.p10" pid="DFOzorX6dE-S2cFMS6jPVA" hash="wOC-0Q">Yes, we find happiness in the midst of the trial of our faith. The Lord manifests Himself to us through His tender mercies, which we find along the road of happiness. We see with increased clarity His hand in our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.p11" pid="-2NA2bMyQ0ix6oXWJ6nEbQ" hash="as0Tiw">Happiness is a condition of the soul. This joyous state comes as a result of righteous living.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.p12" pid="E5rWZfs5eE68NPhoIc5t4Q" hash="ffgv3Q">Some years ago while I was serving as a mission president, my wife, Evelia, witnessed a touching scene of happiness when she saw a faithful family enter the chapel. This mother and her two small children had walked from their humble home under oppressive heat to church that day. They never imagined they would find Elder Cruz, the dedicated missionary who, the year before, had shared the message of the restored gospel with them. This wonderful surprise was key in their recognizing the great happiness the gospel had brought into their lives. The children ran to embrace him, and while tears of joy ran down the cheeks of Elder Cruz, the mother clasped his hands in hers and profoundly thanked him for all he had done to bless their family. Surely they found that happiness which is prepared and reserved for the Saints.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.p13" pid="mDN9tZeQoUuiMCEsDkm3AA" hash="yPk-Hg">The Prophet Joseph stated, “Happiness is the object and design of our existence; and will be the end thereof, if we pursue the path that leads to it; and this path is virtue, uprightness, faithfulness, holiness, and keeping all the commandments of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.p14" pid="FPDCftlQNEm1LntDJscZoA" hash="TzIDzw">After the struggles of the long journey to the promised land and after 30 years of faithful efforts to keep the commandments of God,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> the untiring prophet Nephi of the Book of Mormon summarized the history of his people by saying, “And it came to pass that we lived after the manner of happiness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.p15" pid="EA3j6VrhmUCqsLOliWRAow" hash="_Hjs8Q">Happiness is defined in the Book of Mormon by the prophet-king Benjamin as “the blessed and happy state of those [that] keep the commandments of God. For behold, they are blessed in all things, both temporal and spiritual.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.p16" pid="SbQfxAH6zUi7x962xS5i_Q" hash="NEpi8A">Yes, my beloved brothers and sisters, life is good if we live in such a way to make it so. Believing, desiring, deciding, and choosing correctly are the simple actions that define an increase in happiness and an increase in the inner assurance that transcends this life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.p17" pid="eizBjI-DlkWuOM3JmDihZg" hash="IUycqA">Let us remember that the Lord Himself still calls to us saying, “Come unto me, all ye that labour and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> I know that He lives and that He continually calls at our door. He has restored His Church and the fulness of the gospel through the Prophet Joseph Smith and the coming forth of the Book of Mormon. Even today He directs His Church and kingdom through our beloved prophet, President Gordon B. Hinckley.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision.p18" pid="9QbgKs_YL0yjD4lBU7JdzQ" hash="sVxLGg">I leave with you my love and my humble testimony, in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2005/10/true-happiness-a-conscious-decision</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2005-general-conference/2005-10-2040-elder-benjamin-de-hoyos-64k-eng.mp3" length="3780096" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Called to Be Saints</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints?lang=eng</link>
      <description>How blessed we are to have been brought into this fellowship of the Latter-day Saints!</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50028768_000_5050" doc-version="2" hash="qqwzLg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.head1">
    <h1 class="title" pid="tsJVWcBTRU6xw_vM-hAtAA" hash="gTyGww">Called to Be Saints</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="y_QoalGrFkexiNo-hyl7hg" hash="WPKQaQ">Benjamín De Hoyos</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="-FtohtNnnEexnWjApukySQ" hash="4kLHVw">How blessed we are to have been brought into this fellowship of the Latter-day Saints!</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.p1" pid="N6y7P2Wdrkm9iYqns0H7jg" hash="bs-b2A">My dear brothers and sisters, I pray that the Holy Ghost will help me deliver my message.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.p2" pid="kPAkTf268EyGljyhCU4m7g" hash="pFwjww">In the course of my visits and conferences in stakes, wards, and branches, I am always filled with a profound sense of joy in meeting with the members of the Church, those who today as well as in the meridian of time are called Saints. The spirit of peace and love that I always feel when being with them helps me realize that I am in one of the stakes of Zion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.p3" pid="1OXwauAge0CJBP3GkEAJcQ" hash="CUJ7JA">Even though many come from families that have been members for two or more generations in the Church, many others are recent converts. To these we repeat the welcoming words of the Apostle Paul to the Ephesians:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.p4" pid="dI20n1N4l0WO6wXjr_EpSg" hash="v-vHNA"> “Now therefore ye are no more strangers and foreigners, but fellowcitizens with the saints, and of the household of God;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.p5" pid="OboLjijTN0WzqXw79x31gQ" hash="UMaOqA"> “And are built upon the foundation of the apostles and prophets, Jesus Christ himself being the chief corner stone” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/2.19-20" class="scriptureRef">Ephesians 2:19–20</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.p6" pid="O2wwqpnknkGFxtXsasgA5w" hash="6UzZPQ">Some years ago while serving in the office of public affairs of the Church in Mexico, we were invited to participate in a radio talk show. The purpose of the show was to describe and discuss the different religions of the world. Two of us were assigned to represent the Church in responding to questions that might be asked during this type of a program. After several commercial breaks, as they say in radio parlance, the program director made this comment: “We have with us this evening two elders from The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.” He paused and then asked, “Why does the Church have such a long name? Why don’t you use a shorter or more commercial name?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.p7" pid="fHAtOEaG3U6h628Yd0HB_Q" hash="uVSlGQ">My companion and I smiled at such a magnificent question and then proceeded to explain that the name of the Church was not chosen by man. It was given by the Savior through a prophet in these latter days: “For thus shall my church be called in the last days, even The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/115.4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 115:4</a>). The program director immediately and respectfully responded, “We will thus repeat it with great pleasure.” Now, I cannot remember how many times he repeated the significant name of the Church, but I do remember the sweet spirit that was present when we explained not only the name of the Church but also how it makes reference to the members of the Church—the Latter-day Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.p8" pid="u_uWroi08EmLtvM3HWgoJg" hash="_Q2IEQ">We read in the New Testament that the members of the Church of Jesus Christ were called Christians for the first time in Antioch (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/11.26" class="scriptureRef">Acts 11:26</a>), but they called <span class="emphasis">each other</span> Saints. How stirring it must have been for them to hear the Apostle Paul call them “fellowcitizens with the saints, and of the household of God” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/2.19" class="scriptureRef">Ephesians 2:19</a>) and also say they were “called <span class="emphasis">to be</span> saints” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/1.7" class="scriptureRef">Romans 1:7</a>; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.p9" pid="yUpHv3AfGEaUVk2dAn7Vhg" hash="AeZeYw">To the degree that members of the Church live the gospel and follow the counsel of the prophets, they will, little by little and even without noticing it, become sanctified. Humble members of the Church who conduct daily family prayer and scripture study, engage in family history, and consecrate their time to worship in the temple frequently, become Saints. They are those who are dedicated to creating eternal families. They are also those who set apart time from their busy lives to rescue those who have become alienated from the Church and encourage them to return and sit at the Lord’s table. They are those elders and sisters and mature couples who respond to a call to serve as the Lord’s missionaries. Yes, my brothers and sisters, they become Saints to the degree that they discover that warm and wonderful feeling that is called charity, or the pure love of Christ (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.42-48" class="scriptureRef">Moroni 7:42–48</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.p10" pid="g6ToMN3pTkSKFPwHnNA-Gg" hash="rN7zdg">The Saints, or members of the Church, also come to know our Savior through afflictions and trials. Let us not forget that even He had to suffer all things. “And he will take upon him death, that he may loose the bands of death which bind his people; and he will take upon him their infirmities, that his bowels may be filled with mercy, according to the flesh, that he may know according to the flesh how to succor his people according to their infirmities” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/7.12" class="scriptureRef">Alma 7:12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.p11" pid="7Ut0mFDOxUyEFn11jGydzQ" hash="0v9RmA">Over the last several years, I have witnessed the suffering of many people, including many of our Saints. We pray continually for them, petitioning the Lord’s intervention that their faith may not weaken and that they may move forward with patience. To these we repeat the comforting words of the prophet Jacob from the Book of Mormon:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.p12" pid="ThZU3MLhEUGWVDwImYnoTA" hash="TUEURw"> “O then, my beloved brethren, come unto the Lord, the Holy One. Remember that his paths are righteous. Behold, the way for man is narrow, but it lieth in a straight course before him, and the keeper of the gate is the Holy One of Israel; and he employeth no servant there; and there is none other way save it be by the gate; for he cannot be deceived, for the Lord God is his name.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.p13" pid="1Vx1wpH6-kegXxJ1O1MfCQ" hash="zPk7xQ"> “And whoso knocketh, to him will he open” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/9.41-42" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 9:41–42</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.p14" pid="7KpYxdKbMkWy2GO1bUBFlg" hash="z-B3lA">It does not matter the circumstances, trials, or challenges that might surround us; an understanding of the doctrine of Christ and His Atonement will be the source of our strength and peace—yes, brothers and sisters, that internal tranquility that is born of the Spirit and which the Lord gives to His faithful Saints. He nourishes us, saying: “Peace I leave with you. … Let not your heart be troubled, neither let it be afraid” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.27" class="scriptureRef">John 14:27</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.p15" pid="ACMLY6XdfUeu2RflmnAEuw" hash="0x6XTA">For many years I have been a witness to the faithfulness of the members of the Church, Saints of the latter days, who with faith in our Heavenly Father’s plan and in the Atonement of our Savior, Jesus Christ, have overcome tribulations and afflictions with bravery and great enthusiasm, thus persevering and continuing in the strait and narrow path of sanctification. I do not have words adequate to express my appreciation and admiration for all of those faithful Saints with whom I have had the privilege of associating!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.p16" pid="sbsG0hpg2kKJkV065vxKvw" hash="RC2IhA">Even though our understanding of the gospel may not be as deep as is our testimony of its truth, if we place our confidence in the Lord, we will be sustained in all of our difficulties, our trials, and our afflictions (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/36.3" class="scriptureRef">Alma 36:3</a>). This promise from the Lord to His Saints does not imply that we will be exempt from sufferings or trials but that we will be sustained through them and that we will know that it is the Lord who has sustained us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.p17" pid="NmGi_GHumkCwGZcITg1Xcw" hash="vD8m9A">My dear brothers and sisters, how blessed we are to have been brought into this fellowship of the Latter-day Saints! How blessed we are that our testimonies of the Savior are found alongside those of past and modern prophets!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints.p18" pid="WcH7aChof0C9463pPTHbEg" hash="DfMF4A">I testify that our Lord, the Holy One of Israel, lives and that He directs His Church, The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, through our beloved prophet, Thomas S. Monson. In the name of our Lord, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/04/called-to-be-saints</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2011-general-conference/2011-04-5050-elder-benjamin-de-hoyos-64k-eng.mp3" length="4624439" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>That Our Light May Be a Standard for the Nations</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder De Hoyos teaches that we can be a light by observing the Sabbath day, participating in family history and temple work, and teaching in the Savior’s way.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60003501_000_66dehoyos" doc-version="1" hash="gS78pg">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="vZTkWk_AyEGtalHQ4sOLWg" hash="VxIiVw">That Our Light May Be a Standard for the Nations</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p2" pid="y0adpTffykG_TpYgOfiYvA" hash="7uHaSQ1">By Elder Benjamín De Hoyos</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p3" pid="XkMHUBQXf0-BUkTQRm5uvw" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="prjR6eAYWUqZjxBvJ0h2hA" hash="HsQHow">The Savior’s gospel and His restored Church give us many opportunities for our light to be a part of the great standard for the nations.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="5RNsEOr5qEWjA8nF0RAMKA" hash="7uHaSQ">By Elder Benjamín De Hoyos</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p5" pid="7X3LyEQkFUCnttniejte-A" hash="Q2Kpfg">Years ago, while I was serving as a seminary teacher, I heard one of my coworkers ask his students to reflect on the following question: If you had lived in the Savior’s day, why do you think that you would have followed Him as one of His disciples? They reached the conclusion that those who follow the Savior in the present day and strive to be His disciples would probably also have done so back then.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p6" pid="LoJDBK7rNkuIFziPvnn8Hw" hash="lYQ5tQ">Since then, I have reflected on that question and their conclusion. I often wonder how I would have felt hearing the Savior Himself when He said the following in the Sermon on the Mount:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p7" pid="5L7rnJd1tkOaFrix22o-Ug" hash="UUOWCg">“Ye are the light of the world. A city that is set on an hill cannot be hid.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p8" pid="Zkowmf_lLEuNi21LjAYW_A" hash="r1g2lQ">“Neither do men light a candle, and put it under a bushel, but on a candlestick; and it giveth light unto all that are in the house.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p9" pid="vGNDmdw-u0WoSYC7t4uadw" hash="8AybCw">“Let your light so shine before men, that they may see your good works, and glorify your Father which is in heaven” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.14-16" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 5:14–16</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p10" pid="YMm_GicYuUWRJXDiNTBsow" hash="Io16Sg">Can you imagine how you would have felt hearing the Savior’s voice? In fact, we do not have to imagine. It has become a constant experience for us to hear the voice of the Lord because when we hear the voice of His servants, it is the same.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p11" pid="77qv-P0N6EGMPxQmJHEusw" hash="mBs9QA">In 1838, in a message similar to that given in the Sermon on the Mount, the Lord declared the following through the Prophet Joseph Smith:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p12" pid="Epe0uJWivUuA3UR_sNGtdw" hash="L8I2BA">“For thus shall my church be called in the last days, even The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p13" pid="X_EiPRiZP0ugtQ3uT2666g" hash="0XnLIw">“Verily I say unto you all: Arise and shine forth, that thy light may be a standard for the nations” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/115.4-5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 115:4–5</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p14" pid="DtupU6-byEez2lb--oUnUw" hash="FwmoWw">Our days are so extraordinary that they were even shown in a vision to the prophet Isaiah; he too saw and prophesied of this day of the Restoration of the Church of Jesus Christ and of its purpose, saying, “And he shall set up an ensign for the nations, and shall assemble the outcasts of Israel, and gather together the dispersed of Judah from the four corners of the earth” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/11.12" class="scriptureRef">Isaiah 11:12</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p15" pid="G16XmZYdf0evVY-JS8ChCw" hash="tW77Yg">In a scriptural context an ensign, or a standard, is a flag around which people would gather in a unity of purpose. In ancient times a standard served as a rallying point for soldiers in battle. Symbolically speaking, the Book of Mormon and the restored Church of Jesus Christ are standards to all nations. (See Guide to the Scriptures, “<a href="/scriptures/gs/ensign" class="scriptureRef">Ensign</a>,” scriptures.lds.org.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p16" pid="B3Vf_MxG1USsefCYuc-bLQ" hash="gbtujg">Without a doubt, one of the great standards of these latter days is this magnificent general conference, where the great work and plan of our Heavenly Father “to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>) is continually proclaimed.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p17" pid="yY3xEE2jwkKwvHVGEgommg" hash="_ZECHA">The continual holding of general conference is one of the greatest testimonies to the fact that we as Latter-day Saints “believe all that God has revealed, all that He does now reveal, and we believe that He will yet reveal many great and important things pertaining to the Kingdom of God” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/a-of-f/1.9" class="scriptureRef">Articles of Faith 1:9</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p18" pid="Kg-XzBQ2pUa1EPMCliGU1A" hash="rhmyMA">What, then, has the Lord revealed through President Thomas S. Monson that we need to continue doing so our light can be a standard for the nations? What are some of the important things to be done in this brilliant moment of building up Zion and of gathering Israel?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p19" pid="3Z9Ajp8570KkRYqwyOc-Fw" hash="WMau7g">The Lord has always revealed His will to us “line upon line, precept upon precept, here a little and there a little” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/28.30" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 28:30</a>). Therefore, we should not be surprised by what may seem like small things because of their simple and repetitive nature, for the Lord has already counseled us, telling us that “blessed are those who hearken unto my precepts, and lend an ear unto my counsel, for they shall learn wisdom; for unto him that receiveth I will give more” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/28.30" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 28:30</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p20" pid="WQU7Z56tmE2Oo5QQIfgqmw" hash="Ok-xow">I testify that by learning “line upon line, precept upon precept, here a little and there a little” and by hearkening to our leaders’ counsel, we will have oil for our lamps that will enable us to give light unto others as the Lord commanded us.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p21" pid="4zIUYs8Y2kS0NqtoOyTQUw" hash="e5wf6Q">While there are many things we can do to be a light and an ensign to others, I would like to focus on the following three: observing the Sabbath day, hastening the work of salvation on both sides of the veil, and teaching in the Savior’s way.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p22" pid="s0C1q5IAdUi4QPnYbyy9XQ" hash="XAKOZw">The light that we are talking about comes from the devotion that we give to Sabbath day observance, in the Church as well as in the home; it is the light that grows as we keep ourselves unspotted from the world; it is the light that comes from offering up our sacraments on His holy day and from paying our devotions to the Most High—all of which enable us to always have His Spirit with us. It is that light that grows and becomes visible when we return home with the feeling of forgiveness that President Henry B. Eyring spoke about in this past October general conference when he said: “Of all the blessings we can count, the greatest by far is the feeling of forgiveness that comes as we partake of the sacrament. We will feel greater love and appreciation for the Savior, whose infinite sacrifice made possible our being cleansed from sin” (“<a href="http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/10/gratitude-on-the-sabbath-day?lang=eng">Gratitude on the Sabbath Day,</a>”<span class="emphasis"> Ensign</span> or<span class="emphasis"> Liahona,</span> Nov. 2016, 100).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p23" pid="4BGT0B33I0Wro5VwqlqQnQ" hash="F2H_Bw">As we keep the Sabbath day holy and partake of the sacrament, we are not only cleansed, but our light also grows brighter.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p24" pid="gpUoaesX-Umiq-e3JCwjiQ" hash="r7T8Pg">Our light also grows as we dedicate and consecrate time to finding the names of our ancestors, taking their names to the temple, and teaching our family and others to do the same.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p25" pid="KzfPevFK_E6m5_pZPKv7tA" hash="VpJcbg">This sacred temple and family history work that we share with the Saints on both sides of the veil is moving forward more than ever as the Lord’s temples are being built. Now that the temples have special schedules for family groups who come with their own family name cards, my wife and I have had delightful experiences as we have served in the temple together with our children and our grandchildren.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p26" pid="x_qgCuAxZEGAhdr1D-h7_A" hash="uC21Tw">When we find and take names to the temple and teach others how to as well, together we shine as an ensign or standard.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p27" pid="N0U8Xxer2ESG2rlYsR0low" hash="_UK3dw">Learning to teach as the Savior taught is another way we can rise and shine. I rejoice along with everyone who is learning how to teach in the Savior’s way. Allow me to read from the cover of the new teaching manual: “The goal of every gospel teacher—every parent, every formally called teacher, every home teacher and visiting teacher, and every follower of Christ—is to teach the pure doctrine of the gospel, by the Spirit, … to help God’s children build their faith in the Savior and become more like Him” (<span class="emphasis"><a href="http://www.lds.org/manual/teaching-in-the-saviors-way/teaching-in-the-saviors-way?lang=eng">Teaching in the Savior’s Way</a></span> [2016]).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p28" pid="CRyi-OeE8EiVLvwQrmLaIg" hash="0WIiXQ">Right now, thousands of our faithful teachers hold up a light as they learn how to teach in the Savior’s way. In this context the new teacher council meeting is a way to rise and shine as the students meet around the standard of the doctrine of Christ, for “the key to teaching as the Savior taught is to live as the Savior lived” (<span class="emphasis"><a href="http://www.lds.org/manual/teaching-in-the-saviors-way/introduction-teaching-in-the-saviors-way?lang=eng">Teaching in the Savior’s Way</a>,</span> 4).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p29" pid="MTbJn7ZnrUyVFiW7uMKz1g" hash="lAiPwg">As we all teach and learn in His way and become more like Him, our light shines brighter and cannot be hid and becomes a standard to those who are looking for the Savior’s light.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p30" pid="e2n6cDdDUUSa1yWp2A7oFA" hash="NbtEbA">My dear brothers and sisters, we should not and must not hide our light. Our Savior commanded us to let our light shine like a city on a hill or like a light from a candlestick. As we do so, we will glorify our Father in Heaven. The Savior’s gospel and His restored Church give us many opportunities for our light to be a part of the great standard for the nations.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations.p31" pid="nxGvJkN3QUCfZmlQ_Z0PmQ" hash="3jKo-Q">I testify that Jesus Christ is the light that we must reflect, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2017/04/that-our-light-may-be-a-standard-for-the-nations</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2017-general-conference/2017-04-5060-benjamin-de-hoyos-64k-eng.mp3" length="5306748" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
