<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Bernard P. Brockbank</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Bernard P. Brockbank.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Bernard%20P.%20Brockbank.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Bernard P. Brockbank.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Love of God</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters: Jesus Christ is the head of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, and he has asked that we teach his commandments and promised that he would be with us even unto the end of the world. That is the commandment.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03006_000_5070" doc-version="2" hash="e1rW7g"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="GBnz1x4BakujgTmzJ1k92g" hash="noENZA">Love of God</h1><p class="authorName" guid="76eb7628-909e-43e4-b018-6c11b04f51a3" pid="pkSGPlQ2pkmFjxMz0bXCMQ" hash="XRQ3pw">Bernard P. Brockbank</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="e7c4ad6b-ff0d-44ca-ab9d-2e652d39bf35">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3056.jpg" alt="Elder Bernard P. Brockbank" guid="85dcbccc-8f13-4cab-8b95-08b147626d52" pid="S2R8oFWnQE6yEuYkUrHvNQ" hash="4NJQdA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p1" guid="4dd9f4af-e8a6-43b5-bd81-06362b88df26" pid="ghdRQtStb0WSZAwuAit-ZQ" hash="zKLTRw">My dear brothers and sisters: Jesus Christ is the head of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, and he has asked that we teach his commandments and promised that he would be with us even unto the end of the world. That is the commandment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p2" guid="114fdd8c-f8da-4deb-9815-d2976423216a" pid="cCWtoIbKvEms3bFNX6BbuQ" hash="DPO-9w">When the Savior lived on this earth, he taught that we are to love God and keep his commandments. Jesus said, “Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.37" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:37</a>.) This is the first and great commandment. It is much easier to know the commandment than it is to live it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p3" guid="b0ba906c-8a2d-451f-8893-9b2745865f7b" pid="nF1ZITYWvEWULe4xFCkfMA" hash="qrCSmQ">Why should the Lord command his children to love him with all their heart, and with all their soul, and with all their mind? There is great wisdom and divine security for mortal man in full and complete love for God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p4" guid="97b663f1-d970-4d01-bc3f-d51c80130366" pid="TU2mUrBhK0SBL7RpXjL2ow" hash="RiYmdQ">God created the heavens and the earth and all plant and animal life upon the earth. God created the universe with all of its profound greatness and blessings. The greatest of all miracles is God’s creation of man in his own image and likeness; eyes that can see, ears that can hear, minds that can reason were created within our mortal mothers. We know that our mortal mothers do not know how to make eyes that can see and ears that can hear and mortal minds that can reason. God said that he created man in his own image and likeness. Our creation and mortal birth is evidence of divine power. All that we have that is good for this life and eternal life comes from God. We owe our full respect, dedication, allegiance, and love to him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p5" guid="9cbf2f0e-bf71-49ee-83d1-5754a19c5693" pid="zR5gyZToqkaUIxQPm-wW0Q" hash="KPcqkA">The alternatives are to love Satan or some other part of God’s creations. Satan did not participate in any of the creations that were for the good of man. We owe him absolutely nothing. But some pay tribute to Satan through bad temper, quarreling, dishonesty, adultery, covetousness, drugs, disrespect for God and Jesus Christ, disrespect for the Sabbath day, nonpayment of tithes, hatred, etc.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p6" guid="b2a7253c-ea44-4b98-ab8b-3c17ac319d71" pid="DQOntfIDXki3a8vMICL7-A" hash="GhIjsg">Satan is an enemy to man and seeks to destroy his freedom and his obedience to the Lord and to keep man from developing his divine nature and godliness. Satan is the author of evil, sin, and wickedness, and we should not by our thoughts or acts love or serve him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p7" guid="01febdf6-ed93-4b96-bf32-169ca829e6e6" pid="CZabkf7Mzkiq7fPphUD_4Q" hash="MqgkoQ">Jesus Christ said, “No man can serve two masters: for either he will hate the one, and love the other; or else he will hold to the one, and despise the other. Ye cannot serve God and mammon.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.24" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 6:24</a>.) And may I say that we cannot serve both God and Satan. Some try but no one has succeeded.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p8" guid="688af5fc-6b5a-4c9c-a741-257f8138d61c" pid="E_mfEIOQ4UOctmBMReFgig" hash="3M1clA">Love for God brings love and respect for his children, and love for man’s relationship to the Lord, and a desire to commune with him. Prayers are uttered by many sincere people to various concepts of a supreme being or power. The pagans, the Buddhists, the Hindus, the Mohammedans, the sun and nature worshipers, and many others have their way of praying. Because of many man-made ways of praying, Jesus Christ gave a commandment on the proper way to pray. Here is the commandment—and many do not know that it is a commandment:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p9" guid="f9a320c3-6857-48be-86e1-3adbd21ab24e" pid="rF__cmqwkECvWMTeXHVL0Q" hash="h1av8Q">“After this manner therefore pray ye: Our Father which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy name.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p10" guid="c6d024fe-0424-477e-b69b-fad0082fdbe3" pid="Xmmx-AUac0uGL1UnRYoUAw" hash="V-LUqQ">“Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done in earth, as it is in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p11" guid="241f7d1e-192c-4f82-baae-0952d3293467" pid="Aqny8g_PzE-gnpkY3u7jwg" hash="i2CkRQ">“Give us this day our daily bread.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p12" guid="0a9673d6-37f9-47a0-b2da-f5202b679b84" pid="znHq1aTLkU-f6mL7dpLZtA" hash="dPze4w">“And forgive us our debts, as we forgive our debtors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p13" guid="53c28f26-0428-4086-b839-1508436e97b5" pid="PmrrlAjZ6EqE9t3Yg4lugg" hash="dzBc4A">“And lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil: For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever. Amen.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.9-13" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 6:9–13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p14" guid="965d57d8-0fce-436a-b08e-9d45777e3782" pid="lkVqBflNH0GrDzI5PBGfKQ" hash="tQpksg">This prayer contains the essentials of a sincere, dedicated, Christlike prayer. If we love our Father in heaven, we should pray and talk to him. We should desire to do his will and to have a program for his kingdom on earth as it is in heaven. The prayer teaches us to pray to be kingdom builders and to help build the kingdom of God on this earth. When we love God and sincerely pray for the kingdom of God to come to this earth, as it is in heaven, we commit ourselves to the giving of our time and talents and money.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p15" guid="c9965e37-7b28-4ac4-a27e-cbb128e97a3c" pid="BI4nT9fdq0-_8dhAC8_gPQ" hash="Qg1T-Q">When we say, “Father, thy will be done in earth, as it is in heaven,” we should be subject to the will and desires of our Heavenly Father, even as a little child is subject to the will of its earthly parents. To sincerely submit and agree with the Lord that his will be done shows respect, love, and oneness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p16" guid="0e28589d-3c44-445c-b1d3-a9c40176ef85" pid="OCvGSHcC4UmBbAPVPFDPFQ" hash="TC16IQ">Jesus Christ is the example of one who was dedicated and submitted himself to the building of the kingdom of God upon this earth and in doing the will of the Father. He said, “I came down from heaven, not to do mine own will, but the will of him that sent me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/6.38" class="scriptureRef">John 6:38</a>.) He also said, “The Son can do nothing of himself, but what he seeth the Father do: for what things soever he doeth, these also doeth the Son likewise.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.19" class="scriptureRef">John 5:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p17" guid="ffe63c79-2219-4cdf-b38a-afceaa3bb061" pid="_ISZOg3ock-x4MiGG6qNfw" hash="sh3HMQ">The prayer directs that we should ask our Heavenly Father to meet the temptations and adversities of this life. If we love and trust God, we should ask him to deliver us from evil. There is peaceful assurance and comfort in sincerely asking to be delivered from evil. In our family prayers, we should teach our children to ask the Lord to deliver them from evil. When did you ask, and follow the commandment of the Lord to be delivered from evil, and teach your children and those that you have the privilege of teaching?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p18" guid="ab68f4d0-b63f-48f7-87ac-0a36affbcc2f" pid="dNZ4OBCI30m-5e7Jxx-Aew" hash="FROnrg">The price the Lord has asked us to pay to be delivered from evil is to sincerely ask him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p19" guid="66ef7b2a-2cd4-4711-8b56-7c863ad0b33c" pid="p2v-YKzIwkO_KV5an4QLSg" hash="AeQFHQ">The prayer closes with these heavenly oriented words: “For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever.” It keeps our minds on the goal that we are all seeking—the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p20" guid="8d038bad-2e9f-45be-ace3-4e555bdd0075" pid="uOzg9tiUj0mgdFjY_fWGag" hash="4dX-3g">I would like to read the law from the Lord that is used to finance the building of the kingdom of God on this earth—the law of tithing as it is recorded in the Holy Bible.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p21" guid="d0772c3c-9ae0-4f4c-889e-186426bf68b8" pid="U9Sj3KgRdkeV-asLmHcQSg" hash="6hTvug">The Lord said, “For I am the Lord, I change not; therefore ye sons of Jacob are not consumed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p22" guid="1f9bb719-8221-436b-9005-740b9f149a78" pid="lY0WiM60iEuw2b4kPhOGLg" hash="Weh7qw">“Even from the days of your fathers ye are gone away from mine ordinances, and have not kept them. Return unto me, and I will return unto you, saith the Lord of hosts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p23" guid="64690a8e-1ca3-4a31-865e-3717b665d4e8" pid="CsVEun3cCkanJ_WUmhe2JQ" hash="YW8MmA">“But ye said, Wherein shall we return?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p24" guid="a8db6084-9385-437b-8cf3-3ca60ffba7c1" pid="Tq1xvmx1AkaBsW_STPsfsQ" hash="Qdk4DQ">And the Lord said, “Will a man rob God?” Within the sound of my voice there are some that do. “Yet ye have robbed me. But ye say, Wherein have we robbed thee? In tithes and offerings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p25" guid="9e6d0efe-8ee5-46ab-82ac-040b1ffb903c" pid="lo3j3mMvOUyZwXX6_pgkug" hash="0DSn2Q">“Ye are cursed with a curse: for ye have robbed me, even this whole nation.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p26" guid="e8876045-520e-4e09-9e79-a5b3bca34235" pid="QYlmhs6Y0EW6tHcVSGjyXA" hash="B2rq3w">And the Lord commanded, “Bring ye all the tithes into the storehouse, that there may be meat in mine house, and prove me now herewith, saith the Lord of hosts, if I will not open you the windows of heaven, and pour you out a blessing that there shall not be room enough to receive it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p27" guid="d0f0c688-2e4a-4efd-a134-8a47779d257d" pid="ktnZ87IlUk-a6IsZ7HbFlw" hash="6OsJXQ">“And I will rebuke the devourer for your sakes, and he shall not destroy the fruits of your ground; neither shall your vine cast her fruit before the time in the field, saith the Lord of hosts.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/3.6-11" class="scriptureRef">Mal. 3:6–11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p28" guid="bbfefe3a-92b4-4278-b491-87cd75c2fb07" pid="kDLmhX5lZ0mHfjtmWybCjw" hash="MoNMjA">Will a man rob God by not paying his tithes and offerings?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p29" guid="1a3e2d00-55bf-4ea9-adf1-5756371623d2" pid="KOl7m0PLFU2D_8UdxLQ_Yw" hash="S5aB3Q">Remember, the first and great commandment is to love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind. If we keep this commandment, we will not rob God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p30" guid="e5bd5bb6-4cce-4ae6-bf48-97680e69e843" pid="-EX5mVREi0i7EFfJ5mAZ5w" hash="wg_BzA">I recall a personal experience. A few years ago when my wife and I were involved with a young family, we were struggling to meet our financial needs, and we were in debt, and we were not honest in our payment of tithes and offerings. We were attending church and I thought that we loved the Lord, but one day my wife said to me, “Do you love God?” and I answered, “Yes.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p31" guid="6b7bb449-861c-4bf0-a0a7-7b81b5d288bf" pid="q0mhlYW110SIfUXHtqpg8A" hash="y4T6rQ">She said, “Do you love God as much as you love the grocer?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p32" guid="ceb454f5-edce-45b4-862f-3f4626ff2df9" pid="gzDliJJx1kmEqZkH1RVjkQ" hash="sXT61g">I replied, “I hope that I love him more than the grocer.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p33" guid="7ef8a985-235f-43af-b241-289434777998" pid="-muIBuUWQk2Ixlb1pBb10g" hash="xRwnZg">She said, “But you paid the grocer. Do you love God as much as the landlord? You paid him, didn’t you?” She then said, “The first and great commandment is to love God, and you know we have not paid our tithing.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p34" guid="ca0e6180-513c-40a0-bb99-69a9061dd0cb" pid="1idb6LPoVUKBJmRGkFDx6w" hash="2RmJXg">We repented and paid our tithes and offerings, and the Lord opened the windows of heaven and poured out blessings upon us. We consider it a great privilege to pay tithes and offerings to the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p35" guid="bae0bcd7-73c9-454f-b752-d1fc5bd0a85c" pid="MAfwE4Z7b0WZF2wYK_BisA" hash="PUxdBw">I would like to mention that when we were not honest with the Lord, we were disturbed and had difficulties and problems.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p36" guid="130e3c84-db2c-4842-8fdf-46ca260b8592" pid="J9a_xWqWMEO0xPzNw1sY7g" hash="0zqiow">We can perfect our lives by living the Lord’s commandments. And as has been quoted many times in this conference, the Lord has said, “If ye love me, keep my commandments.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.15" class="scriptureRef">John 14:15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p37" guid="4a64f1b2-cb41-49c4-bbe9-25ef36692925" pid="7eDO-0NxRE2Fj6gfQrR58A" hash="BhsSaQ">The Lord said to the Prophet Joseph Smith in 1831, “… the hour is not yet, but is nigh at hand, when peace shall be taken from the earth, and the devil shall have power over his own dominion.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.35" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:35</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p38" guid="ceec9b51-a7d6-4545-98e0-68347cc21930" pid="g16IxXSO302mWc9svsTo-w" hash="f-eTrg">We are in perilous times, and many love pleasure more than they love God. The devil has power over his own dominion. However, in these perilous times there is hope. The Lord is still at the head of his church. It is a great blessing to live in the latter days and to be a Latter-day Saint. The children of our Heavenly Father can receive peace, security, and happiness from loving him with all their hearts, and with all their souls, and with all their minds, and in keeping his commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p39" guid="06a187c6-ea0f-47b5-b9ef-76b8170b2839" pid="St2tafdVHkmsHPQSSZTWrw" hash="CV79Rw">I know that God lives and that my Redeemer lives. I know that I am a child of God and that I was created by God in his image and likeness. This is my greatest knowledge. God revealed this knowledge to me, and I have great peace and happiness from this witness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god.p40" guid="7c2b1ce6-ef33-49b1-b9a8-533a61508881" pid="wBEnAJR5Y0aVbu4ok0lEvw" hash="AjKWKQ">I express love for my Heavenly Father and for my Savior, Jesus Christ, and for the Holy Ghost, and for all mankind, and do so in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/04/love-of-god</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1971-general-conference/1971-04-5070-elder-bernard-p-brockbank-64k-eng.mp3" length="5471734" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ten Commandments</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters: There is great responsibility that goes with being a Latter-day Saint. There is no knowledge as important as knowledge revealed to man from God. I like to reflect on the following passage of scripture:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03012_000_2030" doc-version="2" hash="Nid0Gg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="nYeJLI_AC06vpSHyaxv-ng" hash="bFVo-Q">The Ten Commandments</h1><p class="authorName" guid="76eb7628-909e-43e4-b018-6c11b04f51a3" pid="3_SQgjIKRkqjIRWOEXuVjg" hash="XRQ3pw">Bernard P. Brockbank</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="e8201111-b881-4473-aa2c-71b6cb28c66c">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3056.jpg" alt="Conference photo" guid="f0706765-5f5f-42fb-8b8a-0df1a36c262c" pid="pSOusMB-0E-54uWJKfr--A" hash="4NJQdA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p1" guid="334ba54a-c5d6-4169-bb00-cef7bd9ca5da" pid="9w5pneIjnk2qNAgyK8J3YA" hash="8PaurA">My dear brothers and sisters: There is great responsibility that goes with being a Latter-day Saint. There is no knowledge as important as knowledge revealed to man from God. I like to reflect on the following passage of scripture:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p2" guid="c8daf38e-42ce-4856-93e5-d380986a7e91" pid="gNpcIBayy0OLHPAhe-_yOA" hash="P36qMw">“And God said, Let us make man in our image, after our likeness. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p3" guid="94b6d8ba-f983-433e-b5f7-89bc9b59408c" pid="yTYiey_ZREefqiWvZ3Lgbg" hash="UZB0kA">“So God created man in his own image, in the image of God created he him; male and female created he them.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/1.26-27" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 1:26–27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p4" guid="c15a9ec5-c3cf-485b-a6cf-08bb3ea6a26d" pid="-Jp_fihI_0O-ba4WffII2w" hash="Oz7kxw">Every child should be taught by his parents that he is a child of God and in the image and likeness of God. The world is hungry for this truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p5" guid="f7d137ab-c928-4221-a7ad-b9e727d749e5" pid="WqaL1f-SoE6hTRFOyFmiEw" hash="Y11j0w">God also said that he created man from the dust of the ground. Man’s mortal creation and birth are living evidence of divine power, and man is left without excuse. The Lord personally gave commandments that would help mankind to grow and develop his Godlike attributes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p6" guid="00402c3e-c505-4a34-bc64-abd2723a2df1" pid="9ml4W4Wy_UyKcAFsOmCFyQ" hash="3LC-2g">This afternoon I am going to read and briefly comment on the Ten Commandments of the Lord. Lower animals do not know or teach the Ten Commandments. We have several animals at our home. We have a peacock that is as colorful and beautiful as almost any creation. It has no use for the commandments of the Lord. It is a lower animal. The Ten Commandments were not given for the lower animals but for man, given for those who are in the image and likeness of God, but some pay little more attention to them than do some of the lower animals.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p7" guid="ba05e5aa-a28a-443f-9449-269777464da6" pid="xz_jUj4f40agQ_4VcLvYAg" hash="vVPgXg">God has warned and commanded his children not to love and worship idols or false gods made by the minds and hands of men. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p8" guid="05341cb5-e364-42f0-bd80-99cd6eaa05d7" pid="wZnoF8Ne60aAE70MwL6G3Q" hash="e06O1Q">“I am the Lord thy God. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p9" guid="4861bdcd-5209-4250-a70a-c50ae1f042d7" pid="lsZsL9cWQke6JKwhwk5y-A" hash="sdO0Jw">“Thou shalt have no other gods before me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p10" guid="bde1fe0f-df7c-4087-afea-ae43bce5a567" pid="PiJvQ3Ia4ECuGbXTE5AYxw" hash="6R6eQQ">“Thou shalt not make unto thee any graven image, or any likeness of any thing that is in heaven above, or that is in the earth beneath, or that is in the water under the earth:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p11" guid="c3fd327e-7d2e-4334-9dc2-89b2be2d9497" pid="WGUbOJ8B5Ea8wzKdnU3Gxg" hash="TjrHCg">“Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them, nor serve them: for I the Lord thy God am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity of the fathers upon the children unto the third and fourth generation of them that hate me;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p12" guid="c363e177-c97b-4fca-b698-f03d34444a8e" pid="rAFdLY1-h0a9vKmQEWrf0A" hash="TAa3Lg">“And shewing mercy unto thousands of them that love me, and keep my commandments.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.2-6" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:2–6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p13" guid="fc2e572d-6d51-404c-9118-5a31e00f2cfe" pid="5FDlI5RI4k-FkC325vWOeg" hash="NsCN3A">Fathers, if we fail to love the living God and if we show greater love and interest for worldly things and pleasures, God has said that he will visit the iniquity of the fathers upon the children unto the third and fourth generation of them that hate him. A father’s disrespect for the living God and Creator may be passed on to his posterity. Likewise, a father’s love and respect may be passed on to his children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p14" guid="5b8d7b29-81fa-452f-93c2-7db3c90984ea" pid="tN1KfKVqKkWk7Th2lsqiLw" hash="Xu_PUQ">The apostle Paul warned the saints at Rome of the perils and evils that come to man when he loves and worships false gods and worldly creations more than he loves God. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p15" guid="816540df-6db9-4300-b1c6-3cee1c5e824f" pid="x6kQBRHsDUCMKFmaGCakAQ" hash="on4EQg">“… when they knew God, they glorified him not as God, neither were thankful; but became vain in their imaginations, and their foolish heart was darkened.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p16" guid="7773213d-6c0a-43db-a151-7c67a4d498d8" pid="b9wh6JXLB0ysLQV5K7ZZYQ" hash="jeno_A">“Professing themselves to be wise, they became fools.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p17" guid="953a873c-fe34-40ce-88fa-4bd091f71597" pid="CMwgnRBaw0ejZ6BY32HbGQ" hash="M-pFHA">“Wherefore God also gave them up to uncleanness through the lusts of their own hearts, to dishonour their own bodies between themselves:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p18" guid="77e0b7b2-6eb5-46a8-bd39-46561c67014b" pid="aqG8WNMp80a99WtLgMla0g" hash="jEvZEw">“Who changed the truth of God into a lie, and <span class="emphasis">worshipped and served the creature </span>more than the Creator. …” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/1.21-22,24-25" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 1:21–22, 24–25</a>. Italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p19" guid="112fab0b-6940-4323-8f85-16327809fe57" pid="b4knS1QJyUCa0xjQg-e-cg" hash="YJnriw">Paul continues on to tell what happens in the lives of men who worship false man-made doctrines and love the creature more than the Creator. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p20" guid="6676aa91-7447-4183-8545-afc1438cab71" pid="KNUZ5u0XmUeRjrDxf5ajSg" hash="BaGwDQ">“… as they did not like to retain God in their knowledge, God gave them over to a reprobate mind, to do those things which are not convenient;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p21" guid="c0b25f1f-a9df-4875-bd40-ca64e066d2e0" pid="lQMq28GZQkSly2lBW-f8gw" hash="7daAMw">“Being filled with all unrighteousness, fornication, wickedness, covetousness, maliciousness; full of envy, murder, debate, deceit, malignity; whisperers,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p22" guid="2926c59a-316a-4547-a7f8-12f87fc3f2a1" pid="HTrmOGhTLEG8OSuDlkm3XQ" hash="_YqUCg">“Backbiters, haters of God, despiteful, proud, boasters, inventors of evil things, disobedient to parents.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/1.28-30" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 1:28–30</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p23" guid="8b9c32a9-c1d9-4f27-a29b-1c76dc2f33f8" pid="j_7PNqNNIkuzWbhGWXFKsQ" hash="WF2gTw">The same evil conditions that existed among many of the people in Rome at Paul’s time are abundantly with us today. Many do not want to retain God in their knowledge and are disobedient to parents, and as a result they are turned over to a reprobate mind to commit sin and evil acts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p24" guid="6d545c2b-428d-4d9a-858e-90af6c55877d" pid="6JX-8SX5Uk6leyrhQs9DFw" hash="S4g2tQ">Satan has been permitted to have power over all men who worship false gods and over all who will not hear and follow the voice of God. The Lord gave this important information about the power and influence of Satan. He said, “And he became Satan, yea, even the devil, the father of all lies, to deceive and to blind men, and to lead them captive at his will, even as many as would not hearken unto my voice.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/4.4" class="scriptureRef">Moses 4:4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p25" guid="da55d9fb-3e1a-47cc-b49c-b52b09b21402" pid="eNgwqBqojk6LwDQle0QDDA" hash="TTpefg">There is divine growth and safety in knowing and following the voice of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p26" guid="56c650df-ea3f-49aa-9d4b-0a8424d1a4d0" pid="3x6tfkDVpUWF8_A5F94LJg" hash="-08W2Q">Jesus Christ said, “And this is life eternal, that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17:3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p27" guid="8cd34162-5386-477f-b06f-9984d2fef28b" pid="2fgcoi-a0kiEvvzqKgA4fg" hash="3ewvAA">To know God and Jesus Christ is divine knowledge.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p28" guid="79e98f6b-635b-4cb3-8dd8-e118c5b0efea" pid="FFx55A3UAUyAiUX0hRFTIg" hash="D4mQVA">The Lord also commanded: “Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord thy God in vain; for the Lord will not hold him guiltless that taketh his name in vain.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.7" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p29" guid="751a982c-b993-46bd-842d-f3703492bc09" pid="41CDTSzknkSk2AozwryOYg" hash="uO5Kkg">Jesus Christ taught that we should hallow the name of our Heavenly Father; he said, “… Our Father which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy name.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.9" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 6:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p30" guid="ddc8d7c3-60d2-4953-ad22-53d796656be1" pid="8lzbmzcYoUqCLPoMUxpF8A" hash="eMEBeA">President David O. McKay once said, “Reverence for God’s name should be dominant in every home. Profanity should never be expressed in a home in this Church. … If there were more reverence in human hearts, there would be less room for sin and sorrow and increased capacity for joy and gladness. …” (<span class="emphasis">Man May Know for Himself </span>[Deseret Book Co., 1967], p. 29.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p31" guid="8d859e36-8f88-45be-b35e-40a7a652be29" pid="GJ1NDYv3tUqGgSKKRS0eLA" hash="skUUtg">Ruskin wrote, “Reverence is the noblest state in which a man can live in the world. Reverence is one of the signs of strength; irreverence one of the surest indications of weakness. No man will rise high who jeers at sacred things. …”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p32" guid="3dceb713-e449-4790-8fda-6fcc6885c6f5" pid="NH_JZvJK9UWmpJF7jHbNmw" hash="UaKAvg">Nobleness and dignity are the fruits of reverence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p33" guid="f1dab618-2061-40a7-aa5d-2261d36a1dad" pid="4TD-a-ul9UCQ5X0uZwtMhQ" hash="_mVPVA">The Lord personally gave counsel to his children regarding the importance and sacredness of the Sabbath day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p34" guid="be8d37ee-2c89-46b9-85c3-e85ffb1f2bc0" pid="do8w9r-9nUuDcVwM7mIh0w" hash="1o-pJg">He said, “Remember the sabbath day, to keep it holy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p35" guid="4454dd6e-8264-44d0-b043-269f96890831" pid="_ZGWfMbZJEyBYS_vu7CUSw" hash="NlI92A">“Six days shalt thou labour, and do all thy work:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p36" guid="bafa17bc-338c-433d-a8cd-98a9962391fc" pid="LQ5GAnj-60am6xlUyEWHHw" hash="YU4E9w">“But the seventh day is the sabbath of the Lord thy God: in it thou shalt not do any work, thou, nor thy son, nor thy daughter, thy manservant, nor thy maidservant, nor thy cattle, nor thy stranger that is within thy gates:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p37" guid="2e2f4d13-fb9a-4144-8db6-bcf942ad868f" pid="QTiOxKsvDkuRIH3nu-9mPg" hash="o2JLUA">“For in six days the Lord made heaven and earth, the sea, and all that in them is, and rested the seventh day: wherefore the Lord blessed the sabbath day, and hallowed it.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.8-11" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:8–11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p38" guid="7e284ab7-195d-4056-9a04-604df96773cc" pid="t0HZQg2h6k-DWJ7xDyOHiw" hash="MMbBzw">The Lord blessed the Sabbath day and hallowed it, and he has asked us to remember the Sabbath day, to keep it holy. It is a day for spiritual thought and growth; a day to meet with the saints and to partake of the sacrament; a special hallowed day to read the words of God as recorded in his sacred scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p39" guid="2f1729d1-5b36-4bad-b653-3cebfa8aa380" pid="HhPCOPyTXE-9QAg4ZdRq4A" hash="VCOcEQ">Fathers who disrespect that which God hallowed and fail to keep the Sabbath day holy will generally pass this sin on to their posterity. It is a sin to unhallow that which God hath hallowed. Keeping the Sabbath day holy has a hallowing effect on the soul of man, and love for God and his commandments is increased.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p40" guid="0818d897-07cf-4a43-a562-0f1c350085f6" pid="iYtooKX5Mk-sTse2y67R_w" hash="4cfn9w">The Lord said in another commandment: “Honour thy father and thy mother: that thy days may be long upon the land which the Lord thy God giveth thee.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.12" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:12</a>.) The Lord gave no exceptions. Respect for father and mother is respect for your own birth and life. Obedience to commandment brings personal growth and lasting happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p41" guid="8948ec80-8cb0-4210-86f8-910620e3902b" pid="2Z408k-uxUauqwRNeYCWXA" hash="-oUyFw">God said, “Thou shalt not kill.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.13" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:13</a>.) We should have sacred respect for all forms of life. We should not kill just for the pleasure of killing. All life on this earth was created and placed here by God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p42" guid="7b5f5580-69c9-4b19-9614-5c65d3d5a090" pid="ZEgZvYIwZ0qs_GD1Q9WGcg" hash="TSnJBA">God commanded his children, “Thou shalt not commit adultery.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.14" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:14</a>.) God will judge man on the basis of this divine law. Adultery is sex relations with anyone of the opposite sex other than your legally and lawfully wedded husband or wife.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p43" guid="c481d8e5-6e18-4d2d-8a5b-6960f3508cb3" pid="HUvR7JFyx0y7IecibE_zLg" hash="rm-XjA">The Lord said: “… he that committeth adultery, and repenteth not, shall be cast out.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p44" guid="315e9e74-64a5-4d7a-9ada-d48f3058d0d7" pid="ywK6GjaNFkmoe4fDAjrMKQ" hash="hAScQg">“But he that has committed adultery and repents with all his heart, and forsaketh it, and doeth it no more, thou shalt forgive;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p45" guid="9462f94f-d652-4e79-819e-c9b6184eab77" pid="He4gmASboUa6aZ5VYFqfVQ" hash="2s46Fw">“But if he doeth it again, he shall not be forgiven, but shall be cast out.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.24-26" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:24–26</a>.) I may add that “cast out” may carry the penalty of excommunication from The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p46" guid="44995c08-991d-45b8-8b5d-c199f6c45526" pid="jQkyUgGgrEmlE_T14mYLtQ" hash="gALmDQ">The apostle Paul said, “… be not deceived: neither fornicators, nor idolators, nor adulterers, nor effeminate, nor abusers of themselves with mankind … shall inherit the kingdom of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/6.9-10" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 6:9–10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p47" guid="78d79d88-c79b-4ddb-a53e-1758110dde81" pid="tyhJMzjSUkOQv0-Mw-hWog" hash="x6_o4w">Fornication and homosexual acts are inspired by the devil and are grievous sins in the sight of God. Fornication and adultery will destroy man’s Godlike potential and bring man nearer the lower animal status.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p48" guid="46d80576-1d96-453a-9e1f-e2f7655ba5fd" pid="7LplsNgznEKICzbk_uYwGQ" hash="lYhEjA">Another divine commandment is “Thou shalt not steal.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.15" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p49" guid="346d1497-be7c-40a2-ac93-c6c0575e3b6a" pid="rBxdwjukwEeEqyfnbJH0ww" hash="1DyNAQ">The man who is honest with his God in paying his tithes and offerings is usually honest with his fellowmen. The Lord said, “Will a man rob God?” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/3.8" class="scriptureRef">Mal. 3:8</a>.) And I add, “Will a man rob his fellowmen?” The stigma of a dishonest mind and countenance is degrading and degenerating. Deep-rooted honesty in the heart of man radiates peace and happiness in his countenance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p50" guid="b0495408-df53-4655-9268-691904285177" pid="-2BDIFvVzEOtr1hqve5i5A" hash="M-vuhQ">The Lord said, “Thou shalt not bear false witness against thy neighbour.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.16" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:16</a>.) The Lord said, “Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/19.19" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 19:19</a>.) All Latter-day Saints are called to save souls and not belittle or condemn them. Bearing false witness against one’s neighbor is an act inspired by Satan and will generate within the mind fear, hatred, and godlessness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p51" guid="5192195d-e04d-4e98-9c32-cc58045da58d" pid="wYqEXy5XRUmk8elSLDyBMA" hash="q9qwBA">The Lord said, “Thou shalt not covet thy neighbour’s house.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.17" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p52" guid="30a68ed8-3b0d-4f8a-b043-dfc4d078be59" pid="3QH7LooiYkW4XV2b-zJVoQ" hash="4HbZ4A">Jesus Christ said, “See that ye love one another; cease to be covetous; learn to impart one to another as the gospel requires.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.123" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:123</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p53" guid="bb82fba8-4427-4380-88ab-ab0bcb23560e" pid="P41LLxnAkUGIWy72Bifdfw" hash="Woo1Pw">The God-given Ten Commandments are still a basic part of God’s way of life and a basic part of the gospel of the kingdom. The way we live and respect the Lord and his commandments in the home has a relationship to the degree of glory that we will merit in the hereafter. If all mankind would live the Ten Commandments, we would have self-respect, peace, love, and happiness on this earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p54" guid="0b956071-b7aa-48aa-93da-ed117a2b7ea2" pid="GPZRikrGq0OB6n3sxn3jfw" hash="pUXfdw">All Latter-day Saints are urgently needed today to live and teach the gospel of the kingdom. Saints, let your light so shine that others seeing your lives and good works will also desire to honor their God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments.p55" guid="32970ef8-4f3e-47b1-9f07-66515a2f7a00" pid="Ped89BDvbU2D_rdub5RrXg" hash="upX1kw">I bear witness that God lives, that Jesus Christ is our Savior, mediator, and our divine example to follow, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/10/the-ten-commandments</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1971-general-conference/1971-10-2030-elder-bernard-p-brockbank-64k-eng.mp3" length="12241038" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowing God</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, we have been fed the bread of life at this conference, the bread that feeds the spirit and brings out the divine nature in the human soul. The bread of life is built around Jesus Christ and his gospel of love and salvati</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03020_000_7040" doc-version="2" hash="fYyOJg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="UtekTk_1KkCYGn5T2GFX_A" hash="B7UzCA">Knowing God</h1><p class="authorName" guid="76eb7628-909e-43e4-b018-6c11b04f51a3" pid="_PeQr0hVTU2MR573QvAWdA" hash="XRQ3pw">Bernard P. Brockbank</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="9d76e2e3-4435-4147-b1cc-d8bf64b2ec85">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3056.jpg" alt="Elder Bernard P. Brockbank" guid="ecc7559d-5bdb-4bf2-9386-47d2cdea694a" pid="OoL88a2ekEqLqAAgIDZngA" hash="4NJQdA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p1" guid="0ca2daed-c3ea-4984-a94f-81be632bd41d" pid="qA791v3jHECpFgMQt_A1vA" hash="cno48w">My dear brothers and sisters, we have been fed the bread of life at this conference, the bread that feeds the spirit and brings out the divine nature in the human soul. The bread of life is built around Jesus Christ and his gospel of love and salvation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p2" guid="9a597d3b-615c-4287-99b2-dbfaa6affa8c" pid="tkPp3NZyqEm8OHd9hjpt9A" hash="9DmDTQ">A few years ago on our television set we had a set of rabbit ears for an antenna, and the pictures and messages were not clear. They were foggy and there was what they call “snow” on the set. Often we were unable to understand the message.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p3" guid="7bf12b85-d218-4d8f-83f9-a96cbbf9111f" pid="2d058VuB50iPh2yd8Em4nQ" hash="xEUmaA">You cannot pick up the celestial message, the bread of life, the word of God, with rabbit ears on your human mind, your human body; the message will not be clear. You need your antenna high, well placed, and turned toward the divine message. You need to keep the mind clear and focused on the heavenly message. It takes time to plan and install in the human heart and mind an antenna to pick up spiritual revelation and inspiration from God. You must be in tune. If you’re out of tune, you’re out of harmony, and static and wrong impressions come from satanic and worldly sources.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p4" guid="4db764f2-7d82-4414-9fdc-f1aef4e34007" pid="Ci3aHgubDka4KbOHM3QO6A" hash="q_7Z3w">Jesus Christ said, “… this is life eternal, that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17:3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p5" guid="ea8fa8a4-e387-4fb2-a502-7b99bbe7867d" pid="qIpVzgVl2UKZxF9WvORI8A" hash="IfykCA">We can receive eternal life and salvation from knowing the only true God and Jesus Christ, whom he has sent. Many believe that there is a God, many say that they know there is a God, but many do not act like they <span class="emphasis">know </span>God. There is a great difference in believing or knowing that there is a God and in knowing God. When we claim that we know God, it bears great responsibility, and an apostle has given us information to check our knowledge of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p6" guid="e413d6bf-816a-4bb2-a45d-2f63d328c07f" pid="PV0oKqtNSU6wV6bvJdIpKg" hash="ZiCLuw">The apostle John said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p7" guid="c74779bc-f714-4535-80a5-09ad849a01a1" pid="D1W46T6k2USPQ7wdopxZlQ" hash="xNrWVQ">“And hereby we do know that we know him, if we keep his commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p8" guid="cc693b0b-12b3-48d8-8546-b09f979cc2ef" pid="T9OYQjHo1UGycBnxyIbDBA" hash="UVmUlQ">“He that saith, I know him, and keepeth not his commandments, is a liar, and the truth is not in him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p9" guid="f2157ecb-105a-4358-baa2-14afa893ec8f" pid="pHWaEh5o3keqEIha4f_qzg" hash="2DcEWA">“But whoso keepeth his word, in him verily is the love of God perfected: hereby know we that we are in him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p10" guid="76cf292f-38f7-4505-a3b1-56a16500b3f5" pid="kRSkPQWxIEuIMgyUxqLvWQ" hash="Vp6n8Q">“He that saith he abideth in him ought himself also so to walk, even as he walked.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-jn/2.3-6" class="scriptureRef">1 Jn. 2:3–6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p11" guid="5437dc9a-33a9-495b-8871-c9deb274a2c3" pid="coE0H2G4lEOS-0zxyznVfA" hash="7xtDtg">The apostle James said, “Thou believest that there is one God; thou doest well: the devils also believe, and tremble.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/2.19" class="scriptureRef">James 2:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p12" guid="f762bb0f-74c8-4763-bfde-258ea5b05dae" pid="DYWObGRv4kmCyRk1PyKiow" hash="nto24Q">Jesus was recognized by a man possessed of the devil, and the devil spoke out and said, “… I know thee who thou art, the Holy One of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/1.24" class="scriptureRef">Mark 1:24</a>.) The devils know God but do not respect his doctrine or keep his commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p13" guid="996029b9-c89e-49fb-a4d8-627ff1490357" pid="HiWNSHuAbUaKDDbMfS6tdA" hash="TgM7XA">Knowing God is related to keeping his commandments. Knowing God must come by direct revelation from God. You cannot know by the power of flesh and blood. This great lesson is taught by Jesus Christ in this message: The disciples were asked by Jesus Christ, “Whom say ye that I am?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p14" guid="568278db-a471-41bf-91a6-ed9d32249c5c" pid="hKf7Oh4Fx0eGASUYnyd9JA" hash="3d-4RA">“And Simon Peter answered and said, Thou art the Christ, the Son of the living God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p15" guid="fea404d4-2a51-4dd4-a2f3-1782d30e88c6" pid="IxVfhBBYbkCGr6Ie4MUUzw" hash="P5l7fQ">“And Jesus answered and said unto him, Blessed art thou, Simon Barjona: for flesh and blood hath not revealed it unto thee, but my Father which is in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p16" guid="367152cb-7a64-4e33-aa3f-f3c2214aff93" pid="a_ueOzHEKEOVS5Dtd26nZQ" hash="8_6uwQ">“And I say also unto thee, That thou art Peter, and upon this rock I will build my church; and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/16.15-18" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 16:15–18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p17" guid="3f3e9498-6d0c-4527-b33c-bd749da905e5" pid="0cKA36IC30mt4mpOA1ED4Q" hash="HmkVYQ">The Lord has indicated that the gates of hell cannot prevail against revelation from him to any one of his children who desires to know the living God and to know the living Jesus Christ. This is available by divine commitment and by divine will, that for anyone desiring to know God the Eternal Father and to know his Son Jesus Christ, God is under commitment and the gates of hell cannot prevail against that commitment; and it will be revealed through the power and principle of revelation direct from God to the one desiring to receive that information.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p18" guid="43693780-77a1-43bf-82ab-f40f376d7658" pid="bhDURt0nPEmif9StjKZpDA" hash="a15Snw">All through the life of Jesus Christ he showed his knowledge of the living God and his loyalty and allegiance to God. Jesus Christ loved his Heavenly Father. He even went so far as to say, “My Father and I are one. I came down from heaven to do the will of my Father.” (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/10.30" class="scriptureRef">John 10:30</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/6.38" class="scriptureRef">John 6:38</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p19" guid="04fde391-fcbf-4a79-953a-4aacb5f7e36c" pid="juOTVZmhHEymoCeerb7Xvw" hash="K-nbHA">Knowing God does not solve life’s problems, but gives purpose and strength to master them. Jesus, with his knowledge of his Heavenly Father, still had his problems to meet and to work out.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p20" guid="84760b2e-4072-495a-9b5f-f05793cab38e" pid="AUT_Byd28UC17gDSI0NWvg" hash="efQGqA">The answers to knowing God the Eternal Father are found in and through Jesus Christ. Jesus said, “I am the way, the truth, and the life: no man cometh unto the Father, but by me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.6" class="scriptureRef">John 14:6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p21" guid="f3f8df87-2541-41b1-9e6b-7d390de15554" pid="UiCY6PSA_UiOfTYYdm9ESg" hash="iC0Q7g">In order to know God the Eternal Father, we must receive that knowledge through the program and through Jesus Christ, who is the mediator between God and man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p22" guid="2675e3de-e8e1-4d72-ac48-2b31c274d522" pid="CAZFBZLtHUS6cF0ABPr4LA" hash="JoPi1g">Jesus also gave this information, which is often repeated and known well by many; he said, “I am the light of the world: he that followeth me shall not walk in darkness, but shall have the light of life.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.12" class="scriptureRef">John 8:12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p23" guid="365b7082-93bf-453e-bb34-72aec3ff72c1" pid="gtPG9XoXLkOnGEF06-ymtA" hash="y4sbMw">The light of life is divine light that permeates and radiates in the human soul and brings out the godlike qualities and attributes of godliness. The light of life is the gospel of Jesus Christ, the gospel of love. The light of life has within it the glorious promises from God of eternal life in his heavenly kingdom. The light of life will bring divine truth and happiness and peace into a troubled heart. The light of life brings divine light into the problems and troubles of this life and helps to turn life’s problems into steppingstones to eternal progression and to developing a godlike character.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p24" guid="5dd906a8-9bac-4c09-9cb4-29b7b0a6e9ca" pid="CUCyz7T7ykyBzJKnfrZOqg" hash="hIDiEg">Jesus also said: “… light is come into the world, and men loved darkness rather than light, because their deeds were evil.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p25" guid="3e7087b4-8f8a-4bb7-bd75-a4825bac97c8" pid="Y0yYBe2RvEW2WYEOCf2Fow" hash="uwHM1Q">“For every one that doeth evil hateth the light, neither cometh to the light, lest his deeds should be reproved.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p26" guid="15c2e2e6-ae67-4222-8525-663628e72050" pid="k5UUaKnstUqq85OyxYTb3Q" hash="tYa3Rw">“But he that doeth truth cometh to the light, that his deeds may be made manifest, that they are wrought in God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.19-21" class="scriptureRef">John 3:19–21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p27" guid="eb84ccfd-1c76-419c-9c1f-85ebf6082461" pid="GUKlcW4fn0u4N-FN5g94Tg" hash="tgZ1cA">To know God, you must walk in the light of life. To know God as a living child of God, we should know our relationship to him, our divine potential, and we should know that in knowing God there is great responsibility to respect and love and follow his counsel and his doctrines and his commandments and to grow as a child to become more godlike.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p28" guid="23b00be8-f80a-4707-9b43-a1644542709f" pid="f-uO6FsNMEGQcki-nbhReA" hash="XMnJPA">Jesus Christ gave this commandment and important counsel by revelation to the Prophet Joseph Smith. He said: “… ye are commanded in all things to ask of God, who giveth liberally; and that which the Spirit testifies unto you even so I would that ye should do in all holiness of heart, walking uprightly before me, considering the end of your salvation, doing all things with prayer and thanksgiving, that ye may not be seduced by evil spirits, or doctrines of devils, or the commandments of men; for some are of men, and others of devils.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p29" guid="2298dd82-3fb2-4227-abcc-59ca6c8ae8fb" pid="ScsyL4ZCFEGvTcvEGMR_Fg" hash="sOIcCw">“Wherefore, beware lest ye are deceived; and that ye may not be deceived seek ye earnestly the best gifts, always remembering for what they are given;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p30" guid="2bd0fce3-4939-4e42-998b-31e5ef8e5069" pid="hWZzqOxWskCQw8_8rf77Bw" hash="7az2rQ">“For verily I say unto you, they are given for the benefit of those who love me and keep all my commandments. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/46.7-9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 46:7–9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p31" guid="6153d175-c3f5-40db-b142-70a3158392f1" pid="JugBcsGSsU2VZ41FyI0VMQ" hash="3AEGNw">We must always keep in mind that God’s greatest gift is eternal life. Eternal life comes from knowing God and from knowing Jesus Christ. Jesus said, “If thou wilt do good, yea, and hold out faithful to the end, thou shalt be saved in the kingdom of God, which is the greatest of all the gifts of God; for there is no gift greater than the gift of salvation.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.13" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p32" guid="92b28faf-7167-406b-bdbc-f3e66d0f8f4b" pid="3aBwXxjopUWDQpCwn6m40g" hash="Nyqjnw">The central and basic principle of the gospel of Jesus Christ is love. He laid the basis of human brotherhood in love. It begins in God’s infinite love for his children, “For God so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son, that whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.16" class="scriptureRef">John 3:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p33" guid="5f157576-fc25-462a-8e32-fe54f5c57e9f" pid="_Nx0M__bbESf11VgB3UjEg" hash="V0-Hxw">As is mentioned by the Savior, to know God means to keep his commandments. The Lord also gave this in the first and great commandment relative to the importance of keeping his commandments, when we say that we love God. Here is the great commandment on love: “Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind. This is the first and great commandment.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.37-38" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:37–38</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p34" guid="989a3247-6831-45e9-a865-e2cec21ec818" pid="LcaTfE1o8UCFSE79Qyhj0A" hash="MLKhYA">Jesus also said, “If ye love me, keep my commandments.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.15" class="scriptureRef">John 14:15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p35" guid="2260471e-0267-4ad0-9440-15ef872445bc" pid="R6X2FnuhvUuUXthix9s32w" hash="OOQH9w">If we love God, we should keep his commandments. We should love his plan of life. We should love his Only Begotten Son, whom he sent to help us meet life and its problems and to redeem us from death, to make the resurrection and eternal life possible, and to give us the light of life that we may walk in his ways and in the divine light that will lead us to godlike blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p36" guid="c8fed7af-1c50-4d0f-8034-732cfa58f2f4" pid="l2XbrJwthUSwe8tQwm46yw" hash="qn6fXA">Jesus said, “This is my commandment, That ye love one another, as I have loved you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/15.12" class="scriptureRef">John 15:12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p37" guid="4502a6db-464d-4fdc-a5a1-86046b16bb01" pid="nw8-ggCLNECJ4bZaaVzmqQ" hash="u1dkUg">We must keep in mind that divine programs and divine ways have been given unto us through our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ; and the way to know God and the way to perfect the human body and bring out its godlike qualities so that we can be in harmony and be a child of God, living so that we can know God, are provided in the great principles of faith and repentance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p38" guid="4e978d56-b7a5-4222-86f7-ac726739f6ba" pid="F6RFJJnD4UC2mDbIRCJIFA" hash="sBIAWw">I would like to mention briefly repentance. Jesus said, “Repent: for the kingdom of heaven is at hand.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/4.17" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 4:17</a>.) The light is turned on in the human soul through the great principle of repentance. Jesus has asked us to repent of past sins, regrets, weaknesses, and failures, and to prepare and look ahead into the future of eternal life and salvation in the kingdom of heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p39" guid="ea72e180-394c-4c27-a2c7-05de19923a4c" pid="gFIX7tlFm0q8Nss1pUY_Hg" hash="ErEAsQ">Repentance by all who are accountable is required for preparation and progression, for entrance into the kingdom of heaven. Repentance is God’s purifying program and law for cleansing the human mind and body from weakness, imperfection, and sin. Repentance through Jesus Christ makes it possible for us to progress toward God’s greatest gift, the gift of salvation and eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p40" guid="965543c4-2144-4fea-8d03-a0d535efde77" pid="oyCQKVGeyUOxhR0Z5u6-hQ" hash="vU1crw">Repentance is a refining influence, a principle provided through the atonement and the sacrifice of Jesus Christ to help us purify our mortal minds and bodies and to bring out our divine nature and godlike qualities and character so that we can live in the presence of God in his celestial kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p41" guid="1413032e-97a8-4fe0-ac27-79e4d77a962a" pid="V0iShlDvR0mZ-_EE9lcccQ" hash="GyeEhA">The home and family is the place where knowledge of God and to know God should be taught, and the place where a loving God should be exemplified and taught to the children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p42" guid="0613f10a-2087-4598-8a80-9fd435ca7289" pid="LIlMCV8WWk2NOt09KpR7AA" hash="rD4fjQ">Parents, children should be taught in the home to know and to love God and to choose his doctrines and his commandments, and not to be misled or deceived by the doctrines of men or the doctrines of devils. They should be taught in the home their relationship to God and how to pray to him. Children should know that they are in the image and likeness of God, that they have godlike attributes and divine potential, that they are literally and truly children of God, with godlike capacities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p43" guid="94880664-0331-4286-8baa-a635bef4edee" pid="_cfdFX_pPUKJzhw3uAaqjw" hash="iZA7RA">They should be taught in the home that Jesus Christ is the proper way, the truth and the great example to follow in this life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p44" guid="8259b129-a91f-4a5f-9745-4f40c77dee70" pid="GBcG5VRtVE2kPHWUI06H6w" hash="ayLDRQ">They should be taught that the scriptures contain God’s way of life, his plan of salvation, and each child should have his own set of scriptures, if capable of reading and understanding, so that he can have them by his bedside and have access to them whenever he feels he would like to know more of his Heavenly Father’s plan of life and way of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p45" guid="b37ef02f-a2e2-40f5-927d-ff47e25e5af1" pid="TlFienUMaUqGJpTjuJtOeA" hash="sxy7Lw">It is not possible to choose God’s way of life and to know God unless we know his program. If we only know the ways of men and the ways of the devil, then we will choose those ways. Jesus Christ commanded that we search the scriptures, that we know the truth, and that the truth would make us free. We find the Lord’s truths in the holy scriptures, and there is no knowledge on the face of this earth greater than knowledge that has been given to us by our Heavenly Father and our Savior, Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p46" guid="b5ac2745-ee36-461f-a1e4-a6a5cfa495f2" pid="fhmHm_3bcE2bgR0UpAnrvQ" hash="23C5zg">Parents, is there love and respect for God in your home? The poet said: “There is beauty all around/When there’s love at home.” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns, </span>no. 169.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p47" guid="e8e3de23-3e23-4760-8b0a-4f42381f07b0" pid="CBCN_KTASkK14V9_YybDxg" hash="GE6a8Q">Parents, do you know God the Eternal Father in your home? Do you pray to a living God? Do you pray to a God that you know, and do you know your relationship to him?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p48" guid="bf2ebdb7-636a-40bb-bbe5-19b220f9370d" pid="35R3N4_HJEaMQvn-gIUaOQ" hash="2nqEZw">Parents, be careful that you do not permit the devil to come into your home. When the devil enters, he brings disrespect for God, hatred, quarreling, criticism, contention, divorce, and evil. When you know God and have respect for his plan, then there is peace and happiness in your home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p49" guid="082dd82f-8a4f-41c8-a485-94ed4b5c506c" pid="5R0RVrf2XEKoC5-IbxKY7Q" hash="seFgvQ">Are there virtue and purity in your family life? Is the Lord’s hallowed Sabbath day kept sacred in your home and among your family?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p50" guid="52db907c-cd61-461b-8214-643b04adb635" pid="Ova62HMGCEWmA7f59PcHlw" hash="ka9jXw">Now, just a word about what is happening in the world and going on among our children. They are being deceived, and that which is entirely wrong looks to be right because so many fine people indulge in use of these two destroyers [alcohol and tobacco] of the divine nature within man and their respect for God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p51" guid="bea6f71e-b710-4871-a2cd-4b21b5fd0cd3" pid="gjeofU9gYUyxRcW_NqZ6yA" hash="U3KoMg">Parents, do you drink alcohol? The Lord has warned that alcohol is not good for man. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/89.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 89:5</a>.) Alcohol is a drug that can destroy godlike character. Alcohol is not good for children and not good for adults.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p52" guid="adcfcb61-23d3-4f56-9b77-d4aec7a7374b" pid="BmbzjlIfP0abyxZG8gWrCw" hash="yF2z8Q">Parents, are you showing and teaching by example in your home how to use tobacco? Tobacco is a drug. Doctors say cigarettes are the nation’s greatest single health peril. A doctor speaking in Salt Lake City recently said that cigarettes kill five times more people than do traffic accidents. Jesus Christ said that “tobacco … is not good for man.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/89.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 89:8</a>.) Tobacco is not good for children and is not good for adults.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p53" guid="38364654-5272-4c52-9315-58c348b6e939" pid="1jRjoy4ITE23TSFPhmzKhg" hash="YPkQAA">A person who knows God would want to be like God, because God is perfect. God has all knowledge. God has power to create mankind from the dust of the earth. Anyone knowing God would have great respect for God. Anyone knowing the living God and indulging in the number one killer and destroyer of health of mankind shows a lack of love and knowledge and respect for God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p54" guid="b8e49938-3ea7-46d4-8c0f-360929fb3042" pid="Bq7NtJHNyke4bwW5F8-72w" hash="K-kbfw">Parents, is your example the example you want your children to follow? Do you teach self-control in your home? Do you teach divine principles so that the godlike qualities of your children can be manifest in their lives?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p55" guid="46079cb0-1875-46ed-a72a-ca70b1cf9c41" pid="ph5s6gwdDki19iooTjW9_A" hash="_hVArw">The home is the place to teach love for God and knowledge of God, and for people to know God and to pray to a God that they know.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p56" guid="b4c06f43-1275-4fc8-a715-05c20605bafc" pid="jci4KtS4z0uJCh6cq12Bxg" hash="DHQ7CQ">President Harold B. Lee has said, “The most important work you will do for the Church will be within the walls of your own home.” I repeat, “The most important work you will do for the Church will be within the walls of your own home.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p57" guid="ba2459df-094b-405b-9926-8499878c60f0" pid="mdYkgdG4QkeTkIxMnaqHUw" hash="8ILTgw">May we recall again these words of the Prophet David O. McKay: “No other success can compensate for failure in the home.” And may I add: No other success can compensate for failure to know the living God and the living Jesus Christ in your home and with your family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p58" guid="573a24c3-b19e-4e42-84cd-0312b04c00c1" pid="6XGhvO5ITUWZ6BTMQ1HNJA" hash="B9z2PA">Parents, your children are from God. There is no other answer from God. They have divine potential, and it is your responsibility to help them to know and love God, the only true God, and Jesus Christ, their Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god.p59" guid="f1517dff-b348-4b45-aea9-84fd120d9296" pid="GayUQOrCnkWKULhMPQM2Sw" hash="VPNsSg">I say this in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/04/knowing-god</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1972-general-conference/1972-04-7040-elder-bernard-p-brockbank-64k-eng.mp3" length="7202787" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entrance into the Kingdom of God</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters: One of the great experiences of life is to be among the Saints. We all have the responsibility of preparing ourselves and others for entrance back into the kingdom of God.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03027_000_2020" doc-version="2" hash="QLN-Qg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="-wYnCLkgbkOKXQuCH1wM9Q" hash="jpJBRw">Entrance into the Kingdom of God</h1><p class="authorName" guid="76eb7628-909e-43e4-b018-6c11b04f51a3" pid="zggTIaiCokqf444xNYsIVw" hash="XRQ3pw">Bernard P. Brockbank</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="eea9bb3b-6eb3-47a8-a52b-8b5812572dae">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p1" guid="0254a0dd-572a-4975-b52d-39e88aa04b72" pid="4aSWJvhrRk61otpljtVQ1w" hash="yH1KlQ">My dear brothers and sisters: One of the great experiences of life is to be among the Saints. We all have the responsibility of preparing ourselves and others for entrance back into the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p2" guid="f2c3911b-63f5-4580-8038-9d9c57bf126e" pid="r1dipXpdfUKBtDoD0EMS4g" hash="Cre-3A">The atoning sacrifice of Jesus Christ made it possible for all mankind to be resurrected and to be raised to immortality. Resurrection and immortality are universal gifts from God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p3" guid="cf8ef778-204b-42b5-bb2d-0b728c608604" pid="S_rfdx0cLEKHPpXlr42qQg" hash="P0a8hg">The apostle Paul taught: “For as in Adam all die, even so in Christ shall all be made alive.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/15.22" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 15:22</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p4" guid="8e85dde2-6e13-48da-90e1-c7b8140520aa" pid="TQ-I7J1idEquhutNSy_muQ" hash="yvDhsQ">But to be resurrected and immortal is not all that is required for entrance into eternal life in the kingdom of God. Eternal life in the kingdom of God is far beyond his universal gift of immortality and is God’s greatest gift to all mankind; it can only be brought about through obedience to the doctrines and commandments taught by Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p5" guid="be668a80-8396-444c-a243-b16a9260763d" pid="Sk74RypEpkmsveu6E_Ij2A" hash="2rdg-g">Jesus said, “I am the way, the truth and the life: no man cometh unto the Father, but by me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.6" class="scriptureRef">John 14:6</a>.) He said, “… no man cometh unto the Father, but by me.” This is the Lord’s way, and coming unto the Father is a divine and sacred gift that must be merited.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p6" guid="7d46fb29-0741-410f-9357-0694049b6d2a" pid="AircF0eCEEiDlVHk1JvFWQ" hash="rF_PJQ">Again, Jesus Christ said, “… Trifle not with sacred things. If thou wilt do good, yea, and hold out faithful to the end, thou shalt be saved in the kingdom of God, which is the greatest of all of the gifts of God, for there is no gift greater than the gift of salvation.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.12-13" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:12–13</a>.) God’s greatest gift and blessing to his children is eternal life with him in his heavenly kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p7" guid="c80e0c35-6bc4-4c0f-89ad-ec40fea2cac2" pid="-xZaKoLK-EqoaQ9aKc9gcQ" hash="Cxp16g">Today there is much controversy and contention among the doctrines and philosophies of men relative to the requirements for entrance into the kingdom of God. Many have been deceived by the teachings of men that works and obedience to God’s commandments are not essential, and some base their contention on scriptures. For example, Paul said, “For by grace are ye saved through faith; and that not of yourselves: it is the gift of God: Not of works, lest any man should boast.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/2.8-9" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 2:8–9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p8" guid="88fa8427-a087-4842-aaf2-d746a398b038" pid="K0M19B08fEyOLx9HeaZUOQ" hash="o8TmAA">The resurrection and immortality are gifts from God, through Jesus Christ, and not from the works and efforts of mortal men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p9" guid="55195122-c268-4ac1-93ec-4aca98f510bd" pid="Qq4vF6ZGOEeO9v_oAu-MJg" hash="vWw_DA">Many try to justify their claims with the statement of Jesus to the thief on the cross, when the thief said to Jesus, “Lord, remember me when thou comest into thy kingdom,” and Jesus said unto him, “Verily I say unto thee, To day shalt thou be with me in paradise.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/23.42-43" class="scriptureRef">Luke 23:42–43</a>.) Jesus and the thief went to paradise. There are those who teach that paradise and heaven are one and the same place, but this is not according to the teachings of the holy scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p10" guid="d50d5c72-a8d7-411b-9f17-343a42829567" pid="IB1-E1Err0yEoCuajCDn5A" hash="modkLA">After mortal death the spirit goes to paradise and remains there until the appointed time for its resurrection into immortality and eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p11" guid="eb49dcaa-a738-47f6-8904-71bda9065598" pid="JVR_dtvfxES_C0Sxi-QEvw" hash="4m9oXw">Heaven, which is the kingdom of God, is where those who have been obedient to God’s plan of life and salvation go after judgment and the resurrection.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p12" guid="1a2b2f6d-c3f1-4cfd-a52d-7acbb1e4e232" pid="gfpDg-mWpUqDPKNWTmT3Nw" hash="Q7NDAQ">The spirit of Jesus, after his death, went to paradise and not to the kingdom of heaven. It was not until after his resurrection that he mentioned returning to the kingdom of heaven. You will recall his words to Mary as she stood by the sepulcher weeping: “Touch me not, for I am not yet ascended to my Father: but go to my brethren, and say unto them, I ascend unto my Father, and your Father; and to my God, and your God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/20.17" class="scriptureRef">John 20:17</a>.) His spirit had been to paradise, but he had not yet ascended to his Father in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p13" guid="a1a0ad72-26ca-414f-af73-7c966f4b2cdd" pid="N6EwrLadfUieS_ekTXKf2A" hash="U1UO4Q">Jesus warned that not very many would find their way and prepare themselves to live in the kingdom of heaven. He said, “Enter ye in at the strait gate: … Because strait is the gate, and narrow is the way, which leadeth unto life, and few there be that find it.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.13-14" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 7:13–14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p14" guid="c4f3e41b-1cd7-4fad-95bf-e5f0530d7daf" pid="OyYjx0NCm0uZ-XBhPLDMJg" hash="Q001lg">Many, according to Jesus, will be misled and deceived by false teachers and false prophets, and some will desire to follow the ways of the world and will destroy their divine opportunity to enter into the kingdom of heaven. He said, “… wide is the gate, and broad is the way, that leadeth to destruction, and many there be which go in thereat.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.13" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 7:13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p15" guid="0e0ba5cb-3808-40fd-ae30-414faf334dc9" pid="YKOcMryWt0a6AZEOv5nsAA" hash="6lr43Q">Contrary to what many think, just believing in God and being virtuous and pure are not sufficient to qualify a person for entrance into the kingdom of heaven. The Savior’s parable about the ten virgins and their desire to enter the kingdom of heaven makes this point very clear. Jesus said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p16" guid="83d78882-2426-4186-b888-018697ca3331" pid="cvusLOOxh0q-NYn29qVW0w" hash="d0V4PA">“Then shall the kingdom of heaven be likened unto ten virgins, which took their lamps, and went forth to meet the bridegroom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p17" guid="92bfc19a-9f8c-42eb-9a89-834d9dafc84c" pid="SIZzUTqCXkSrP5M0MRmbHg" hash="6XOJYQ">“And five of them were wise, and five were foolish.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p18" guid="9441da19-45a4-41b4-9b5b-089b126939c7" pid="Ekf5gJr0tEexyFSYcIqBow" hash="SisJ2A">“They that were foolish took their lamps, and took no oil with them:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p19" guid="7245cd36-3f44-4a00-845d-239e3d95f10d" pid="LYPJVGjRgkK5skiOyFQeOQ" hash="iQsDlA">“But the wise took oil in their vessels with their lamps.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p20" guid="f25778e1-0d8e-460e-8cfc-c1abc01d2957" pid="eLHt8qqMsEGjJxNMrK-X3w" hash="OD0GGw">“While the bridegroom tarried, they all slumbered and slept.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p21" guid="66e6c19b-92ce-4c17-a5cc-ced467706517" pid="PDs4XWrDp0CxjqKaiHmchA" hash="mK23SQ">“And at midnight there was a cry made, Behold, the bridegroom cometh; go ye out to meet him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p22" guid="efd2b7b8-8212-4e5c-82db-02c2fe0fda77" pid="zvPLneX3hUKu29a2Wk8BaA" hash="lWevcQ">“Then all those virgins arose, and trimmed their lamps.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p23" guid="42eead0e-175a-4db2-93ee-6d7c602f9a3b" pid="iIv7MylR6EWuOnlkGFW3SQ" hash="CyFCeg">“And the foolish said unto the wise, Give us of your oil; for our lamps are gone out.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p24" guid="4065785e-bd80-428a-9f8c-c2dbbb8848a5" pid="GoQlQRUOlki2rjCA816bZA" hash="JXveig">“But the wise answered, saying, Not so; lest there be not enough for us and you: but go ye rather to them that sell, and buy for yourselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p25" guid="02b8e4b0-5d63-4b3f-be86-9efb4b06a05c" pid="jZgQD_YWUkuO-abmykdW3Q" hash="tPptOQ">“And while they went to buy, the bridegroom came; and they that were ready went in with him to the marriage: and the door was shut.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p26" guid="287bac2f-8046-450c-9157-31d3658a3314" pid="hFD5DySpHkmyJyY31fBZwA" hash="0CJRoA">“Afterward came also the other virgins, saying, Lord, Lord, open to us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p27" guid="336d3648-9e67-4542-bb86-e56247cb095e" pid="vejj2RZQ4kaAodGdJMRB9A" hash="olT5Xw">“But he answered and said, Verily I say unto you, I know you not.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.1-12" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:1–12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p28" guid="cde5385c-9b52-4b66-8cb4-54b6b27969e4" pid="A03zYeAbG0akQNfNFc_iEw" hash="iYjagg">Take note that the Lord was not talking about five thieves and sinners and five good people; he was talking about ten virgins, ten pure people who believed in God and had a desire to enter into the kingdom of heaven. The five foolish virgins had failed to prepare. Their lights were out; they were in darkness. Their urgent pleas and hasty preparation were not sufficient, and they heard these words from the lips of their God: “I know you not.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p29" guid="824ea494-252b-42be-8752-2f7b5cc995c8" pid="WPDrOP71pEGsc35iruE4Mw" hash="9r_6HA">What a shame to be clean and yet unprepared! What a tragedy to fail in service to God and in helping to build his kingdom on earth as it is in heaven! What a shame to be in darkness when the light of Christ has been made possible for everyone!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p30" guid="abb731ee-d9ae-4c89-b3c9-7dacc8bd77fe" pid="wTXeSc3hbU2oFxSDhXapWg" hash="oQwlqQ">Jesus, speaking of good people who failed to qualify for entrance into the kingdom of heaven, said, “These are they who are not valiant in the testimony of Jesus; wherefore, they obtain not the crown over the kingdom of our God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.79" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:79</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p31" guid="cfbf3241-02f9-4e60-9ccc-81540f0a9e0b" pid="XHVrWbTHOEi_QyeiIt3GVQ" hash="IcQ_uQ">It is a divine warning from the teachings of Jesus Christ that one must be prepared to enter into the kingdom of heaven and must have the light of life that is made possible through following Jesus Christ. Jesus said, “I am the light of the world: he that followeth me shall not walk in darkness, but shall have the light of life.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.12" class="scriptureRef">John 8:12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p32" guid="ea80edcf-fb92-45ac-bfd2-6635bf286786" pid="RMTXl797BU-u8F0c_IGrRQ" hash="hkMOpw">The light of life can come only through following Jesus Christ. The light of life is divine light and is required in the immortal soul before entrance back into the kingdom of God. You cannot obtain the divine light of life from men. It does not come from just being good. It can only come through repentance and by living the gospel plan of life and salvation as given by Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p33" guid="d898629e-847e-4edc-9007-29d7983072ad" pid="eb6Qd6mxfU61G1npnDno_w" hash="MNrlPA">When Jesus lived on the earth, he found a very religious group of people known as the Pharisees. They believed in God; they accepted the teaching of the prophets in the Old Testament. They accepted the Ten Commandments and would not even pick up a stone on the Sabbath day in their compliance with the commandment relative to keeping the Sabbath day holy. Yet Jesus said of the devout, praying Pharisees:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p34" guid="1aa9cc42-d5ae-4b17-9d02-a62e560e0115" pid="H29S2DQ3XE2vmo2H3FZstg" hash="Nqekmg">“This people draweth nigh unto me with their mouth, and honoureth me with their lips; but their heart is far from me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p35" guid="dd76c910-5128-409e-95ef-c8e30f8b76ed" pid="sbvdhX9MV0uHWrSJTSDK-A" hash="2ti3pg">“But in vain they do worship me, teaching for doctrines the commandments of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/15.8-9" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 15:8–9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p36" guid="423027b9-db93-418c-b9da-06251fb71e51" pid="fatwqOtRlkeKnn438aFwwQ" hash="-0_0iw">They had changed the Lord’s commandments into commandments of men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p37" guid="162973a7-599e-45b7-80f6-6b938a633506" pid="2arTDdrTkUiGhZjvghNRNA" hash="QnMVpA">In his Sermon on the Mount Jesus Christ also mentioned to these people their qualification for entering into the kingdom of heaven through the Pharisee religion, with its man-made doctrines and commandments. He said, “For I say unto you, That except your righteousness shall exceed the righteousness of the scribes and Pharisees, ye shall in no case enter into the kingdom of heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.20" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p38" guid="20c31003-abba-4042-8e0b-acb17cfc2ee8" pid="bqurwbqfAEK_iefl-vNbDQ" hash="1RR63Q">The Pharisees, in all of their dedication and their love for God and the ancient prophets and their obedience to man-made righteousness, which appeared to be taken from the scriptures, did not qualify for entrance into the kingdom of heaven. The Pharisees were worshiping a mystical god of spirit, and they were unable to know the living God when he appeared before them. He tried with all of his godly power to convince them, but they would rather defend their man-made church and their man-made doctrines than accept the church and teachings of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p39" guid="52400366-94c7-492d-8713-74aaad992bcf" pid="Lsr5xUsSzkilpsdy-X0psA" hash="mAVIsg">All men should know what acts will keep them from entering the kingdom of heaven. According to the apostle Paul, the following works of the flesh will keep a person out of the kingdom of God: “… Adultery, fornication, uncleanness, lasciviousness, Idolatry, witchcraft, hatred, variance, emulations, wrath, strife, seditions, heresies, Envyings, murders, drunkenness, revellings, and such like: … they which do such things shall not inherit the kingdom of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/gal/5.19-21" class="scriptureRef">Gal. 5:19–21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p40" guid="588b6f98-0398-4da8-850c-79006927eb8c" pid="8KNxdXoIHU-EKd3xNuhwEA" hash="X2h5Xg">Indulgence in works of the flesh will destroy man’s divine nature and potential godliness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p41" guid="c672d64a-0b59-46df-95bd-bdb5ffd9e731" pid="j2W_OBMeUkK3Jdkl4RWAsQ" hash="dC99wg">Repentance makes it possible to cleanse the mind and body of these sins, except murder, and all other weaknesses, and to turn to the Lord’s way of life. He said, “Repent: for the kingdom of heaven is at hand.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/4.17" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 4:17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p42" guid="4bc20e27-70af-404e-9af8-39edeb92a960" pid="uAWm7SRVtk6m4yKsVly6TQ" hash="oX2Pjg">Repentance is God’s way, with the help of his doctrines and commandments, to purify and cleanse the mind and body of its weaknesses and imperfections. Repentance prepares the mind and the body to receive the gospel and to take on the divine light of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p43" guid="9e41e530-f54a-48af-94e1-26ae1386d376" pid="COwXGxATO0W5PMTPWexpkA" hash="NNlNnA">Repentance frees the conscience and cleanses the mind. Jesus said, “Behold, he who has repented of his sins, the same is forgiven, and I, the Lord, remember them no more. By this ye may know if a man repenteth of his sins—behold, he will confess them and forsake them.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.42-43" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:42–43</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p44" guid="bfe37e35-9282-469b-8db0-b7c7bfe11fe3" pid="LLFcB0svY06TODsSLXhynw" hash="MFlEEg">Repentance prepares the mind and body to know the living God and the living Jesus Christ and to receive the gospel and take on the divine light of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p45" guid="e6a113e4-6ace-4638-a636-e45d90a144b2" pid="aF3pfSCNmEuRECHGjQr5XA" hash="v0KcIQ">It is important to know that all of the requirements for entrance into the kingdom of God were personally given by Jesus Christ and are recorded in his holy scriptures. There will be many good people turned away from entrance into the kingdom of heaven because they failed to know and follow the Lord’s plan of life. They were more interested in following doctrines of men and commandments of men than they were in following the doctrines of the Lord, as recorded in his scriptures. They were more interested in defending their sect or denomination than in knowing the truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p46" guid="d618a480-ff46-4417-b18c-25607b903b39" pid="i6CDi6NsHUyqGmDn489tTA" hash="PmsuxA">Here are some of the keys that Jesus Christ gave to help one qualify for entrance back into the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p47" guid="8e8815a7-f799-4d38-8e1c-347e7320e6f0" pid="x4oLgUDwOk2RCZMuzIjEeg" hash="QOSZMA">Jesus said, “Verily, verily, I say unto thee, Except a man be born again, he cannot see the kingdom of God” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.3" class="scriptureRef">John 3:3</a>); “Except a man be born of water and of the Spirit, he cannot enter into the kingdom of God” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.5" class="scriptureRef">John 3:5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p48" guid="36b1185a-7cfe-40af-9356-fcaff4e55fe2" pid="5kM3cNv2rUe6DEEZ9RHMiQ" hash="tfecLQ">In <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17, verse 3</a>, another key is recorded by Jesus Christ: “… this is life eternal, that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p49" guid="62788162-64ad-4bc9-899f-b1e42acd0807" pid="jk4UaK0RZEiSdFrDUuAhbA" hash="IgXKZQ">Wouldn’t you think it is important to know God the Eternal Father and Jesus Christ if you expect to live with them in the kingdom of heaven? Many feel that they know God and know Jesus Christ, but they fail to keep their commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p50" guid="ee7fe43e-135b-4859-be1b-ead72b5bbbdc" pid="8Mu8gl3eAECzyD_dBxUldQ" hash="9Vcp8A">Hear the words of the apostle John to all who claim to know God. He said, “And hereby we do know that we know him, if we keep his commandments. He that saith, I know him, and keepeth not his commandments, is a liar, and the truth is not in him.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-jn/2.3-4" class="scriptureRef">1 John 2:3–4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p51" guid="5e0c8441-3858-4404-88cd-2fc91041bc73" pid="Ifx-0m0fckCxQ1L_ZEqxEw" hash="EAeQ5w">Knowing God is shown by keeping his commandments. People who accept and live doctrines of men do not know the living God. When you know the living God and the living Jesus Christ, you will also know your divine relationship to God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p52" guid="f026227c-2cf0-40bf-943f-0c13e4bd973e" pid="Nc7-dh5mDEaD4E-nQm_tYg" hash="6JMvgg">Jesus asked us to pray to our Father in heaven and to “seek ye first the kingdom of God, and his righteousness.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.33" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 6:33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p53" guid="826956e0-b5a9-43b2-8ef5-d71b5b1d3517" pid="UyjLfDu9MEm5hO64k5CiwA" hash="PRFULQ">I pray that we may do so, and close with this divine commandment: “… let virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly; then shall thy confidence wax strong in the presence of God. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.45" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:45</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god.p54" guid="220f7194-2ad7-488d-b005-69d1e3cba00d" pid="p6ML0qNkqEyQvIXTLZd6tw" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/10/entrance-into-the-kingdom-of-god</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1972-general-conference/1972-10-2020-elder-bernard-p-brockbank-64k-eng.mp3" length="5496252" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>God’s Way to Eternal Life</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Lord’s thoughts and ways are higher than the thoughts and ways that come from men.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03040_000_7030" doc-version="2" hash="Np-qkg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="v0ShFBnmeUWn2ykr6uj7Vw" hash="eWDGxg">God’s Way to Eternal Life</h1><p class="authorName" guid="76eb7628-909e-43e4-b018-6c11b04f51a3" pid="o2pxqckpSkyMB_ocQBrPtQ" hash="XRQ3pw">Bernard P. Brockbank</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="04cff0f2-6da1-42f2-b26f-271b896395d3">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p1" guid="b7f23075-046f-4a2d-bc10-87737cbb13b7" pid="xfq3Eh9H8UCQHcGCVU1VKA" hash="TdrpTA">The Lord’s thoughts and ways are higher than the thoughts and ways that come from men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p2" guid="78413c26-d186-400c-b485-04bcdcbddd30" pid="pLqm80Q3_E6So0txrSX4UQ" hash="B2vyTw">The Lord said to man: “… my thoughts are not your thoughts, neither are your ways my ways, … for as the heavens are higher than the earth, so are my ways higher than your ways, and my thoughts than your thoughts.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/55.8-9" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 55:8–9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p3" guid="35597a56-90d2-42d7-86cf-e8a8e23616bc" pid="A5Cz-hXv6UCsh6levIcpcg" hash="z7KBlw">God’s way was to create man, male and female, in his own image and likeness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p4" guid="9cf5b6cd-0721-406a-9609-959e6eb6bea9" pid="cLFHN2Qw506IxXYYhiHPyA" hash="fV6G4Q">Man’s way is that man came from a lower form of life. God’s way justifies self-respect.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p5" guid="944b6b36-2418-42e4-9ebd-e21b84daefde" pid="1pXRRETIzUuRHQ3LxEh5OA" hash="q34cFg">God’s way provides man a divine way of life. The Lord promised his children salvation in the kingdom of God if they would live and follow his ways. It is important to know that man can become godlike through the thoughts and ways of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p6" guid="406157a4-da76-4a64-bb41-dcc06d3e1d88" pid="FZRdw6LqQkKnxHc6ZiraEg" hash="A_eJfQ">The Lord’s way was to send a savior who would live and teach the ways of a living God. “For God so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son, that whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life. For God sent not his Son into the world to condemn the world; but that the world through him might be saved.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.16-17" class="scriptureRef">John 3:16–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p7" guid="980ef65d-b036-400d-9f78-6bda4ef397bb" pid="WkTje1L0wkCoJ68i8NNHzg" hash="6gSPgg">Jesus Christ said, “… I came down from heaven, not to do mine own will, but the will of him that sent me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/6.38" class="scriptureRef">John 6:38</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p8" guid="03bf19ca-7a12-4400-9d9c-ca58dcc44c38" pid="PrkCQdXgAkGJqJz9mCHbMg" hash="h3xRcA">“And this is the will of him that sent me, that every one which seeth the Son, and believeth on him, may have everlasting life. …” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/6.40" class="scriptureRef">John 6:40</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p9" guid="7f71e592-6b83-43c6-8829-f530b394a0cf" pid="ic9smtCJ_k--uKO4F9rjiA" hash="yRGfpA">“… the Son can do nothing of himself, but what he seeth the Father do: for what things soever he doeth, these also doeth the Son likewise.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.19" class="scriptureRef">John 5:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p10" guid="92c66ae9-3893-42f9-80bc-826e3604f116" pid="GzTIdDyWBkS4NE4cw8ku3A" hash="Wkp4uw">“… all men should honour the Son,” he said, “even as they honour the Father. He that honoureth not the Son honoureth not the Father which hath sent him. … He that heareth my word, and believeth on him that sent me, hath everlasting life, and shall not come into condemnation; but is passed from death unto life.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.23-24" class="scriptureRef">John 5:23–24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p11" guid="58daf2b0-bee5-4130-a624-c28c3159fce4" pid="A-rpjqxbI06AkI-pG5ng-w" hash="hwcVgw">God has provided one way and only one way for his mortal children to attain godlike perfection. Jesus Christ proclaimed, “I am the way, the truth, and the life: No man cometh unto the Father, but by me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.6" class="scriptureRef">John 14:6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p12" guid="2364424c-c737-409c-bdb3-40423e3e293d" pid="cNIb3BvwqU6qb6wvV5-4hQ" hash="KOZkXQ">Jesus Christ brought to this earth from heaven the Lord’s ways and the Lord’s truths.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p13" guid="46f0c76b-8d29-4bb4-a412-eb6c066dd128" pid="sWosvxW130eIB9igpLwfJw" hash="aBWV5g">Jesus Christ lived and exemplified the heavenly life, that the Father desires all of his children to live.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p14" guid="de87066a-ece6-462e-8bcc-63c6b50bed2b" pid="1gClDaMJtkKhJtKfzlQd3w" hash="vr9eCA">“… I am come,” Jesus said, “that they might have life, and that they might have it more abundantly.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/10.10" class="scriptureRef">John 10:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p15" guid="eb6488c8-6e57-48cc-87be-c49abafb9ede" pid="1MreLGy6zEuSdU88H1T32g" hash="ao8ihQ">The full, abundant, divine way of life can be gained by following and walking in the light of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p16" guid="28c959f7-80aa-400e-9623-8225c82492be" pid="SGujeg6GKk-Qj7E_tDlhlg" hash="RCbdyw">“… I am the light of the world”; Jesus said, “he that followeth me shall not walk in darkness, but shall have the light of life.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.12" class="scriptureRef">John 8:12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p17" guid="9200ec88-dfd3-414e-b38a-da7914044238" pid="8-Eas0lXiEK2Y3r2iujbXg" hash="OcFLSQ">“That which is of God is light; and he that receiveth light, and continueth in God, receiveth more light; and that light groweth brighter and brighter until the perfect day.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/50.24" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 50:24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p18" guid="7dd90ee3-89ce-4061-a2d2-0a6efa7ad2e0" pid="SeV1DZGisUSpk6hI_oMArg" hash="eBxaqw">By following the Son of God and by living worthy to receive the light of life we can take on the radiance of godliness. Not only can we be children of God, in his image and likeness, but we can be sons and daughters of God in this life and in the kingdom of heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p19" guid="d0a9126f-6204-4cc1-9e51-2dfc690d3564" pid="wmWZpJ19AUKIXICOtzPJWA" hash="WZR_LA">We have this promise from the Savior: “Behold, I am Jesus Christ, the Son of God. I am the life and light of the world. … verily, I say unto you, that as many as receive me, to them will I give power to become the sons of God. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/11.28,30" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 11:28, 30</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p20" guid="1f8c4e6e-aae8-411d-830c-16ea482c2217" pid="qtn5C8e2ZUendvIy1W-Hug" hash="Nlf8qw">God’s greatest gift to his children is for them to be saved in the kingdom of God. The Lord said, “If thou wilt do good, yea, and hold out faithful to the end, thou shalt be saved in the kingdom of God, … for there is no gift greater than the gift of salvation.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.13" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:13</a>.) This is the gift of all gifts; this is the diploma of all diplomas. This is the degree in salvation that qualifies one for eternal life in the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p21" guid="9f9a5964-1e91-4735-82ff-e6d5048b331e" pid="keu-v8KAd0Krt5rTWTtuaQ" hash="ibphjg">Jesus taught that few would find the way to salvation. He commanded his disciples to follow the Lord’s way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p22" guid="1f8d9708-3077-4749-9efe-1dc148c128e9" pid="7wQmaQTT40Kqyl7vf69Ktg" hash="FBB1Mg">He said, “Enter ye in at the strait gate: for wide is the gate, and broad is the way, that leadeth to destruction, and many there be which go in thereat: Because strait is the gate, and narrow is the way, which leadeth unto life, and few there be that find it.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.13-14" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 7:13–14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p23" guid="0c2156c4-1277-4ecb-97d2-eb07d6b69a74" pid="mWfoelNrTk2wIcTUlcFtfg" hash="9sgzdg">Yes, our Heavenly Father so loved us that he sent his only begotten Son down from heaven to this earth that whosoever believeth in him should not perish but have everlasting life, but few find the divine way. Only a few will follow Jesus Christ. Only a few will love God first. Only a few will keep God’s commandments. Because they love the lower thoughts and ways of men more than they love the higher thoughts and ways of God. “And this is the condemnation,” Jesus said, “that light is come into the world, and men loved darkness rather than light because their deeds were evil.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.19" class="scriptureRef">John 3:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p24" guid="63d5e592-dc1c-4fe7-851f-d29131eb57f7" pid="cVuUGz0TAkCqWa9vKseSjA" hash="lxYgzg">And again we read from the scriptures:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p25" guid="398fcb4c-44de-4be6-b416-728bf2b45337" pid="Q40rck7K1kOFPUqHhQ280w" hash="SjcyZA">“For you shall live by every word that proceedeth forth from the mouth of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p26" guid="5d1c2189-1f90-4551-9ba7-f993269e85fe" pid="wtOI2j3LqEali-jphhXZ6w" hash="Hnjzcw">“For the word of the Lord is truth, and whatsoever is truth is light, and whatsoever is light is Spirit, even the Spirit of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p27" guid="94f1d45c-d26e-4fc5-ba55-8743736eb7c0" pid="azyAbwcTfEa8k3riA04ICA" hash="7KnFhQ">“And the Spirit giveth light to every man that cometh into the world: and the Spirit enlighteneth every man through the world, that hearkeneth to the voice of the Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p28" guid="e0adb1c5-7951-4705-a1ef-6bf1aca37cf3" pid="7vkUUOMg9k-k1KWXp4t_JA" hash="b2R8MA">“And every one that hearkeneth to the voice of the Spirit cometh unto God, even the Father.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.44-47" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:44–47</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p29" guid="caadabe9-4cf9-45e9-a5e8-1fd07c4b4e02" pid="hY3UvbfzyU6c5kitymyBDg" hash="8Oq6PQ">The voice of the Lord continues, “And if your eye be single to my glory, your whole bodies shall be filled with light, and there shall be no darkness in you; and that body which is filled with light comprehendeth all things.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.67" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:67</a>.) What a glorious promise!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p30" guid="19db9f6a-4544-4292-90ee-c4171c77107c" pid="ab_ohZmH-ESAIbWrM01JUg" hash="8uVfdw">The light of the Savior is available to everyone who will follow him. This divine light, through repentance, will remove darkness and sin from the soul.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p31" guid="e1df3a0e-6e31-4bd1-a99a-67560f5d3997" pid="20IfB8JFdUC3kz-L8TDhtA" hash="PY41YA">Jesus showed the light of brightness of his divinity to three of his apostles:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p32" guid="7326d69d-9108-42cb-a81e-3f8d8e9cc8ed" pid="-NWtN50HPEu1AwEe1PtO6w" hash="nfrAPg">“… Jesus taketh Peter, James, and John … and bringeth them up into an high mountain …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p33" guid="a446c7c3-ea74-4954-b28b-7072b7f932fa" pid="uFkpo9njb0uemY5nnZSbww" hash="gPs2iA">“And was transfigured before them: and his face did shine as the sun, and his raiment was white as the light.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p34" guid="ff710c74-0ed0-442d-858c-5dae28cef175" pid="VE7VjLSrAUG3kr-DIafDMw" hash="qdobDQ">“While he yet spake, behold, a bright cloud overshadowed them: and behold a voice out of the cloud, which said, This is my beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased; hear ye him.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/17.1-2,5" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 17:1–2, 5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p35" guid="a3347f95-b8ba-4af8-a5eb-89e82733d075" pid="laxeHKbS7kmtsa4Y66BuyA" hash="6Vg5Og">Our Heavenly Father has commanded, “hear ye him.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p36" guid="f8cdaa8c-f072-4465-a528-05602b718ae7" pid="lQ6pq4qL4U6s2tlOsEjRkw" hash="wASekQ">Jesus Christ was truly a God, living in a mortal body, with divine power; he was sent from heaven, to show mankind God’s way to celestial perfection.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p37" guid="8d95be8f-96d5-47c8-ba64-3d4edb76c89e" pid="eKDn4LewVUSgy72TYdg7XA" hash="GGV2cQ">The Lord’s ways and his thoughts are found in his scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p38" guid="42ceea16-4746-4879-90fe-b52bb5fadd17" pid="S0K5ekCcAU2KOsNFuPibaQ" hash="HGdtWQ">In a parable, Jesus taught his disciples how they could partake of his life, his light and his power.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p39" guid="dcfb28dc-da42-4e50-b8c4-5ef0f5d7cbf5" pid="fsEHKlPLa0y08H_Lfja-dg" hash="rcOTJQ">He said, “I am the true vine, and my Father is the husbandman.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p40" guid="38a9d8f9-9924-48a1-af20-9ec055392a1e" pid="Wvlh-MwybkWzPt4U6kPEiw" hash="_fzOpg">“Every branch in me that beareth not fruit he taketh away: and every branch that beareth fruit, he purgeth it, that it may bring forth more fruit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p41" guid="64cc6576-7f1d-422b-9d99-ee6d4d56d87c" pid="KaQGBRGAG0izgyw3I6f95g" hash="fBcmBg">“Now ye are clean through the word which I have spoken unto you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p42" guid="49f4b608-f91c-4dcc-8d7f-8c45fa08b7a0" pid="AApajcOKnkShtmiUu4fCZQ" hash="rC0b2A">“Abide in me, and I in you. As the branch cannot bear fruit of itself, except it abide in the vine; no more can ye, except ye abide in me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p43" guid="f3655c8e-4bc2-47b2-866d-d69ce5f6e023" pid="hr5QXBVy3kSfV1XIE7AW8g" hash="oFoRuQ">“I am the vine, ye are the branches: He that abideth in me, and I in him, the same bringeth forth much fruit: for without me ye can do nothing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p44" guid="a9024fe3-e3b1-4079-8098-5ce60a61d087" pid="CCViOp9Q5kK3n9vvf7c3sg" hash="qca4ng">“If a man abide not in me, he is cast forth as a branch, and is withered; and men gather them, and cast them into the fire, and they are burned.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p45" guid="19741c4b-ad2d-4386-9d68-78a88dd480d1" pid="2i6XloUihkSj1Y9JulB7kA" hash="s6hXMQ">“If ye abide in me, and my words abide in you, ye shall ask what ye will, and it shall be done unto you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p46" guid="f6cdffb6-48b3-45ab-9a26-271105e92e77" pid="ikfrCY2AGE-6Al5l9TOysQ" hash="fPySLw">“Herein is my Father glorified, that ye bear much fruit; so shall ye be my disciples.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p47" guid="2818ae4c-2923-4138-b29c-803189f56860" pid="jCbYQ8DqVEe3pyfX0WlGqA" hash="kuGR-w">“As the Father hath loved me, so have I loved you: continue ye in my love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p48" guid="69a8c357-1aa6-43a8-a8cf-a3be83d6133f" pid="M0nWIt1TM0WaBAXiUaSa2w" hash="50Gyow">“… even as I have kept my Father’s commandments, and abide in his love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p49" guid="49d2617d-e027-476e-bea7-e0d8172596aa" pid="qAaSqjT3FEOQyovbqh1LXA" hash="yr9gKw">“These things have I spoken unto you, that my joy might remain in you, and that your joy might be full.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/15.1-11" class="scriptureRef">John 15:1–11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p50" guid="af494823-17ad-4998-a590-2ef4206d4d24" pid="UxAgDEbs906EN2r0jlz_mQ" hash="9UyMqA">Jesus Christ is the vine and all who sincerely want to become godlike, prepared to live with their Heavenly Father in his kingdom, must receive their strength and power from the Savior. No man cometh unto the Father but by and through Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p51" guid="d2a8f137-6027-4c15-8652-4178c4776893" pid="e2mK0Fy5bk65tNIth2dPHg" hash="wnrRxQ">The nonproducing branches on the vine, some lost in the darkness and sin of the world, some weak and sick from the blight of evil, some branches fluttering in the winds of worldly pleasure and disrespect for the power to produce godlike fruit through the divine vine, having disrespect for Jesus Christ and for the Father and for their commandments, will be pruned from the vine. They will be cut away from their source of divine nourishment and their chance to become godlike. Pruned away from their divine opportunity, as a child of God, to partake of the light and divine way of life, their chance to live with God was foolishly dissipated away. They failed to feed on the living bread of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p52" guid="83bc1dc6-2fc2-4573-bf17-a41aac68a834" pid="I5o7b-ks50-mguuBje8eAA" hash="Z26LeA">All of God’s children are branches on the vine; all have the opportunity to partake of the life, example, and commandments of Jesus Christ and to become like him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p53" guid="c48096b3-e66b-4ac8-8981-9ec9233ab453" pid="A7eP-Z7zTUaIGDTfSsbz1g" hash="RrZF-g">The Lord also commanded man to build godlike perfection into his life. He said, “… I would that ye should be perfect even as I, or your Father who is in heaven is perfect.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/12.48" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 12:48</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p54" guid="56f7a501-5d65-466c-bb6f-698faad68455" pid="LFvYEWZEJEuil1g_e2wiKw" hash="51aLZQ">Divine perfection can only come through and by Jesus Christ, by knowing and following his ways, his truths, and his life. To be perfect we should be charitable, loving, honest, virtuous, upright, clean, and possess every godlike attribute. To become perfect, a child of God should live like a child of God. We can attain perfection by knowing and loving God with all our heart, and with all our soul, and with all our mind; and by loving our neighbors as ourselves. This leaves no love for the devil or for the darkness of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p55" guid="abfb3f77-6774-4ffe-b9e7-68dd340a04cb" pid="HJXQOYNGuE-YjJ9Eei-B1w" hash="FhYgjg">Perfection comes by seeking first the kingdom of God and his righteousness. Perfection comes by praying to a living God through a living Jesus Christ. Perfection comes by knowing and keeping all of God’s ways and commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p56" guid="4966ec0f-be1e-45c9-859b-4e58f60223f9" pid="ca5zVwybdUuF_KY7auqYNA" hash="sNxqCQ">The Apostle Paul, as he counseled the saints to completely and fully accept the Lord, said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p57" guid="c364bb0b-4a67-418e-a62a-aee320d4415a" pid="4MyKep6BRUaLiIfj0DggDQ" hash="hopo9Q">“Finally, my brethren, be strong in the Lord, and in the power of his might.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p58" guid="b4e7a62d-79d5-40a3-be0f-82f5da2a0ede" pid="-9l_OR9A9kGVgoXaj_DIhg" hash="_65-Ww">“Put on the whole armour of God, that ye may be able to stand against the wiles of the devil.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p59" guid="3e28ebdf-d7f2-4e09-95ef-a2a9200024f0" pid="EC8vu2maOUSu4U7ydQI59w" hash="Pf-XKQ">“For we wrestle not against flesh and blood, but against principalities, against powers, against the rulers of the darkness of this world, against spiritual wickedness in high places.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/6.10-12" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 6:10–12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p60" guid="a82be475-b651-4c1d-980a-91b471f69677" pid="RVI3RkC6UEqFL4b6OIEujQ" hash="S0kqdQ">Yes, we wrestle against the thoughts and ways of men that are contrary to the thoughts and ways of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p61" guid="92cd50d3-0137-466a-9aac-48c38a2a0a67" pid="P_QgYRU73UebiWgdicA5PQ" hash="f2NCXA">The whole armor of God will keep the divine light of Jesus Christ inside and the darkness of evil outside. All who wear the full armor of God will be filled with pure love, happiness, peace, and godlike self-respect.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p62" guid="985e1fb1-897c-4b91-b301-b81f2b9b3668" pid="3U7n84qt4UiqQjes3xA6Qw" hash="L9J9fQ">It is a blessing to have a living prophet and living apostles of the Lord to help us to know the higher thoughts and ways of the Lord and to encourage us to put on the whole armor of God and to be perfect even as our Father in heaven is perfect.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p63" guid="ae03aec6-0e9a-46d8-b1b7-3e787353d582" pid="ZWs9aFMYd0KcqKKYmjM4uQ" hash="XNZYZA">May we radiate from our countenance the light of life and walk as Jesus walked.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life.p64" guid="881ab14d-1565-4fde-8bf3-0498d54c0d54" pid="_aoV1LlwIkCqWFvLqR99Eg" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1973/10/gods-way-to-eternal-life</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1973-general-conference/1973-10-7030-elder-bernard-p-brockbank-64k-eng.mp3" length="5695003" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 1973 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hearken Unto the Voice of God</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Lord said, “… Hearken, O ye nations of the earth, and hear the words of that God who made you.” (.) Godliness in man goes undeveloped without the words of God and his program.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03044_000_043" doc-version="2" hash="BxCdJg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="S6AoDip1xkqae2CRRI1Jow" hash="g2kjZg">Hearken Unto the Voice of God</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="t7BTiQiBU0iftm-kzQNr0A" hash="XRQ3pw">Bernard P. Brockbank</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p1" pid="sTneDRXD-0O7W2hs_bpJnA" hash="FQb2FA">The Lord said, “… Hearken, O ye nations of the earth, and hear the words of that God who made you.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/43.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 43:23</a>.) Godliness in man goes undeveloped without the words of God and his program.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p2" pid="7UBuc4InKUSJRB3-guInPA" hash="1j4s9w">The Lord has commanded and warned man to obey and hearken unto his voice or to be subject to the power and dominion of the devil. The Lord said: “Wherefore, because that Satan rebelled against me, and sought to destroy the agency of man, which I, the Lord God, had given him, and also, that I should give unto him mine own power; by the power of mine Only Begotten, I caused that he should be cast down;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p3" pid="BQSCxEpd5ECjpKC_fXRnSA" hash="xPwokQ">That is a warning to all mankind. It is very important to know that Satan has power to deceive men and to blind men and to lead men captive at his will, even as many as will not hearken unto the voice of the Lord. Sin and evil come from Satan, and godliness and eternal life in the kingdom of God are from the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p4" pid="VxY4hWMmwkiZH7MeGMqUaA" hash="308ryw">“And he became Satan, yea, even the devil, the father of all lies, to deceive and to blind men, and to lead them captive at his will, even as many as would not hearken unto my voice.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/4.3-4" class="scriptureRef">Moses 4:3–4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p5" pid="x1lF-YREeUKAd-sUlOk41g" hash="7uDf9Q">The apostle John said, “He that committeth sin is of the devil; for the devil sinneth from the beginning. …” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-jn/3.8" class="scriptureRef">1 Jn. 3:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p6" pid="eKgarhV9VEqLQ9ReHrgQ6A" hash="B30NXA">Satan with his evil, deceitful, destructive plans was able to turn one-third of the spirits in heaven away from the voice of God and to influence them to follow his satanic voice. The Lord said of Satan: “… a third part of the hosts of heaven turned he away from me because of their agency;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p7" pid="9muNuY13YUG-GxFKdBLjOg" hash="X3vmOA">“And they were thrust down, and thus came the devil and his angels.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/29.36-37" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 29:36–37</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p8" pid="tUDqvvalVUOLRQXsSgCbZg" hash="V7EDeA">They were cast out of the kingdom of God because they had free agency to choose for themselves, and they chose to ignore and disrespect the voice of God and listened and followed the voice of the devil.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p9" pid="BgR0Cb69VUiucV0x3ACHNg" hash="D-Hy9A">Satan and his angels and their God-destroying plan are on earth today, and the Lord said of Satan, “… he goeth up and down, to and fro in the earth, seeking to destroy the souls of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/10.27" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 10:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p10" pid="WBtdkqwEVUiuviXH91YwHg" hash="OT8iAA">The devil tempted Adam and Eve. We are well acquainted with that story. They listened to his deceitful voice, and they were cast out of the Garden of Eden. Because of failure to hearken unto the voice of God, they were subject to the influence of the devil and were cast out.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p11" pid="m849pNVWeEOi6vSed-jdLw" hash="gS2omg">When the Lord restored his church, he warned man about the power of Satan. This came in the latter days. He said: “… the hour is not yet, but is nigh at hand, when peace shall be taken from the earth, and the devil shall have power over his own dominion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p12" pid="1-PkwVaDxUWGUOST8OcEpA" hash="s8cUHw">“And also the Lord shall have power over his saints, and shall reign in their midst, and shall come down in judgment upon … the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.35-36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:35–36</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p13" pid="BHyKECB5Q0atFxljxLZ_jA" hash="f5vkpw">President Harold B. Lee said, “Today you are witnessing the fulfillment [of a prophecy concerning Satan’s dominion]. Today is the day when the devil has power over his own dominion.” (Harold B. Lee, <span class="emphasis">Decisions for Successful Living,</span> Deseret Book Co., 1973, p. 221.) That is a prophetic statement from a prophet of God. He also said, “[Satan] is the master of deceit, adulteration and counterfeit. There is hardly a human appetite that he has not prostituted to his own evil designs; virtue he betrays into vice; and things invented and designed as benefactors to mankind he diverts to his own ends. No palace of art or temple of music was ever more glamorously decorated,” the prophet continued, “than the hell-holes of Satan that are labeled saloons, bars, road houses and gambling clubs. With blazing neon signs and lighted ‘white ways’ the cheap and the tawdry are dressed in tinseled garb, and with sensuous music from the nether regions issuing forth from such places, the passersby are enticed to partake.” (<span class="emphasis">Decisions for Successful Living,</span> p. 155.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p14" pid="JwzntcK-Qke-xUEzKIxalA" hash="A3ommw">Yes, it is true; the devil continues to deceive and to blind men. It is true; the devil continues to use the children of God to degenerate and destroy their own godliness. He entices them to sell their divine birthright for a pot of porridge. He deceives and lures men to improperly use their passions and appetites to degenerate and weaken their godlike minds. Their minds, then, become subject to the uncontrolled, improper use of the passions and appetites.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p15" pid="MdHRxG2K2kG2VL4qyvha1w" hash="2TSyHg">Jesus showed us the way to overpower and defeat the devil. He is the example. This has been repeated in this conference twice before. It bears a lot of repetition. An account of the Lord’s encounter and the temptations with Satan is recorded in the holy scriptures:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p16" pid="OrGWYCbJ6UGpHmRBS0ph3g" hash="uYFtsA">“And Jesus being full of the Holy Ghost returned from Jordan, and was led by the Spirit into the wilderness,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p17" pid="QvUSEW6yn069Dqjr70a_tQ" hash="E6aOXA">“Being forty days tempted of the devil. And in those days he did eat nothing: and when they were ended, he afterward hungered.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p18" pid="PcgPGSNy9EanmL3WvL9aOw" hash="LN4Z-w">“And the devil said unto him, If thou be the Son of God, command this stone that it be made bread.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p19" pid="1gLLVLHeCU20q9Udv0oezA" hash="0_VnAA">“And Jesus answered him, saying, It is written,”—here is the message; it is the written word of the Lord—“That man shall not live by bread alone, but by every word of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/4.1-4" class="scriptureRef">Luke 4:1–4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p20" pid="iVbDhzWTdkuLngy7-CIHFQ" hash="R2p3nA">The devil was rebuked and overpowered by the word of God, as recorded in his holy scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p21" pid="nikPlKuLAUyfODoKxeNh6g" hash="hqH95Q">“And the devil, taking him up into an high mountain, shewed unto him all the kingdoms of the world in a moment of time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p22" pid="YAEO2U8hAEqBCXXeo2xpgQ" hash="QYRI1A">“And the devil said unto him, All this power will I give thee, and the glory of them: for that is delivered unto me; and to whomsoever I will I give it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p23" pid="_CIRig62dEitQaFrEQo5lA" hash="fRqjiQ">“If thou therefore wilt worship me, all shall be thine,” the devil promised. (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/4.5-7" class="scriptureRef">Luke 4:5–7</a>.) Many have that same temptation today. Hear the answer of the Lord:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p24" pid="BesUKj7gLEW8b8sLOXmMkQ" hash="2wWvOQ">“And Jesus answered and said unto him, Get thee behind me, Satan: for it is written, Thou shalt worship the Lord thy God, and him only shalt thou serve.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/4.8" class="scriptureRef">Luke 4:8</a>.) He quoted again from the word of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p25" pid="CBQu3AxxcEq_VB97kwp1XA" hash="CvGoWA">“And [the devil] brought him to Jerusalem and set him on a pinnacle of the temple, and said unto him, If thou be the Son of God, cast thyself down from hence.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/4.9" class="scriptureRef">Luke 4:9</a>.) And the devil contorted and twisted the scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p26" pid="S6QHKCP0t0isY0UvPY7fsg" hash="xktSWg">“For it is written, He shall give his angels charge over thee, to keep thee:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p27" pid="o5cwCz3z90qSRL8IOzE5yA" hash="Hzhamw">“And in their hands they shall bear thee up, lest at any time thou dash thy foot against a stone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p28" pid="rekiZrCmvEajvPsoXbKHRg" hash="5vFPEg">“And Jesus answering said unto him, It is said,” and he quoted the scriptures again, “Thou shalt not tempt the Lord thy God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/4.10-12" class="scriptureRef">Luke 4:10–12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p29" pid="EQMcMX6mJUeBY3eBh414Dw" hash="gymlzg">Satan was rebuked and defeated by Jesus because Jesus knew and used the word of God—the commandments of God as recorded in his holy scriptures. Jesus hearkened unto the voice of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p30" pid="ZiKiGlPjdEma6-Ws27cCtg" hash="dVQn8A">We can also overcome the buffetings and temptations of Satan with the word of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p31" pid="TBKAMOdRyk2KfcIXlIRV6Q" hash="V20yaA">The devil deceitfully and dishonestly continues to offer man the world and the power of the world if man will but fall down and worship him. The devil wants us to love the world more than we love God. He wants us to be so foolish that we will love the creations of this earth more than the Creator.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p32" pid="9R5Jt0KlMkenxvxh2m0Esg" hash="PjpSoQ">The apostle John said, “Love not the world, neither the things that are in the world. If any man love the world, the love of the Father is not in him.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-jn/2.15" class="scriptureRef">1 Jn. 2:15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p33" pid="gd7EhVD3u0WnUN8lRd6JEQ" hash="sF0FBg">Jesus said, “For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the whole world, and lose his own soul? or what shall a man give in exchange for his soul?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/16.26" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 16:26</a>.) The devil would like man to accept the ways of the world in place of eternal life in the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p34" pid="5XU_hpXiq0aYJsSngThcig" hash="i4nidQ">Jesus commanded that we protect ourselves from the power and dominion of the devil. He said, “Wherefore, lift up your hearts and rejoice, and gird up your loins, and take upon you my whole armor. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/27.15" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 27:15</a>.) This has been quoted in this conference several times. But Jesus gave these words in these latter days, repeating words of the scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p35" pid="JagsOslJw0GVN--KHi2zeA" hash="vAYVRA">Take on the whole armor of God. The full armor of God is the full gospel of Jesus Christ. If we put on the full armor we will be able, in these troubled times, to “run and not be weary, and [to] walk and not faint.” And the destroying angel will pass us by and not be able to destroy our godliness. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/89.20-21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 89:20–21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p36" pid="sGUwvmnE30G2qxevy5Oobw" hash="kYAJvQ">Jesus counseled, “Pray always, that you may come off conqueror; yea, that you may conquer Satan, and that you may escape the hands of the servants of Satan that do uphold his work.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/10.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 10:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p37" pid="zU2Xk73oDkOzKH3ous7wNg" hash="rKbHpA">In our individual prayers we should sincerely ask our Father in heaven to help us meet and conquer the temptations of this life, and ask him to deliver us from evil. We have been commanded to ask.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p38" pid="ekKa5kf-MEqkGIS_p_oAog" hash="2fzGBQ">Proper sincere prayer to a living Father in heaven, through a living Savior and Mediator, is essential for protection from the power and evil influence of the devil. It is very important for the Saints to know that during today’s perilous times when peace has been taken from the earth, and Satan has power over his own dominion and over all that will not hearken unto the voice of God, that the Lord gave these comforting words, “… The Lord shall have power over his saints, and shall reign in their midst, and shall come down in judgment upon … the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:36</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p39" pid="3WQMrUCf5EuhwJ1VQulkog" hash="N7GavQ">Today the Lord has power over his Saints and is reigning in their midst and will soon come down in judgment upon the world. Through and by Jesus Christ man has the power and the opportunity if he keeps God’s commandments to become saintly and godlike.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p40" pid="cpLUdKlcokilluYCYxuSmA" hash="DMJUKw">I am thankful to be on earth when the Lord has power over his Saints and is reigning in their midst. The voice of the Lord is recorded in his scriptures and the voice of his prophets and his apostles. His prophets and apostles give the voice of the Lord today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p41" pid="zRpu9ReJeUi7VH_ddqZwLQ" hash="eWT15Q">It is a glorifying experience to mingle with the Saints. President Kimball is truly a prophet of God. He speaks for the Lord and all should hearken to his voice. He is full of dedicated love for the Lord and for his children. And he knows the refining power of repentance and the miracle of forgiveness. He is not only sustained by the Saints, but also by the priesthood and power of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god.p42" pid="wiDfJkDPk0W2yhp7_esNqw" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/04/hearken-unto-the-voice-of-god</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1974-general-conference/1974-04-7050-elder-bernard-p-brockbank-64k-eng.mp3" length="5983153" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 1974 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Divine Power of Repentance</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, the first uttered words of the Prince of Peace, as recorded in the New Testament, are “Repent … for the kingdom of heaven is at hand.” (.) Repentance is a divine principle and is required for man’s salvation into the kin</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03050_000_023" doc-version="2" hash="VfHGVw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="kTTbFoIFZU2jjyB_-1JjbA" hash="8FnM4w">The Divine Power of Repentance</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="wBRwzd3kzEWqjAZK73TgOw" hash="XRQ3pw">Bernard P. Brockbank</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3056.jpg" alt="Elder Bernard P. Brockbank" pid="a32x_HrCIEaL3ogaR1WLEw" hash="4NJQdA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p1" pid="EWhEKV3AxEOtBDO4QYGM_Q" hash="COmiKg">My dear brothers and sisters, the first uttered words of the Prince of Peace, as recorded in the New Testament, are “Repent … for the kingdom of heaven is at hand.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/3.2" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 3:2</a>.) Repentance is a divine principle and is required for man’s salvation into the kingdom of heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p2" pid="AouREasZLEuhhI_eFZEgKg" hash="_xfRCA">President David O. McKay, when speaking on the importance of repentance, said, “Every principle and ordinance of the gospel of Jesus Christ is significant and important in contributing to the progress, happiness, and eternal life of man, but there is none more essential to the salvation of the human family than the divine and eternally operative principle, repentance. Without it, no one can be saved. Without it, no one can … progress.” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Ideals,</span> Improvement Era, 1953, p. 13.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p3" pid="sjJAoFoYyUmYySC_BWN_sA" hash="d4mWVg">The atoning sacrifice of Jesus Christ, the Savior, made it possible for each individual to receive forgiveness of his sins. His atonement and teachings made it possible for me and for you to repent and to be prepared to enter into the kingdom of heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p4" pid="El0iQWYVPEavRcpV3mro7w" hash="JwQ9EA">President Spencer W. Kimball said, “When we think of the great sacrifice of our Lord Jesus Christ and the suffering he endured for us, we would be ingrates if we did not appreciate it so far as our power made it possible. He suffered and died for us, yet if we do not repent, all his anguish and pain on our account are futile.” (<span class="emphasis">The Miracle of Forgiveness,</span> Bookcraft, Inc., 1969, p. 145.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p5" pid="XeaLdSjijEmGscy1dFUVBQ" hash="rgdA6w">Jesus taught, “For behold, I, God, have suffered these things for all, that they might not suffer if they would repent;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p6" pid="nApSrWkMRUe_Vtd6bTnD7w" hash="536hMw">“But if they would not repent they must suffer even as I.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/19.16-17" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 19:16–17</a>.) I repeat, “But if they would not repent they must suffer even as I.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p7" pid="_ZYPQVH3m0GzvWuWSnSBxg" hash="Pj0f3g">The great prophet Abinadi gave this warning: “But remember that he that persists in his own carnal nature, and goes on in the ways of sin and rebellion against God, remaineth in his fallen state and the devil hath all power over him. Therefore, he is as though there was no redemption made, being an enemy to God; and also is the devil an enemy to God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/16.5" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 16:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p8" pid="YdLrX807wEOEVuTZ-3y6lQ" hash="U96O8w">The devil is strongly against man’s repenting and preparing himself for the kingdom of heaven. The devil’s mission and goal is to destroy man’s potential godliness and his preparation to be again with his Heavenly Father. Repentance will stop the devil and keep him from entering the hearts of men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p9" pid="1AjzI32VNUG18kgk2aUqoA" hash="eOZgPA">Jesus Christ lived his life and gave his life so that man might have the gospel and repent and prepare himself to live with God in the kingdom of heaven. Jesus said, “No unclean thing can enter into his kingdom; therefore nothing entereth into his rest save it be those who have washed their garments in my blood, because of their faith, and the repentance of all their sins, and their faithfulness unto the end.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.19" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 27:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p10" pid="nHZj0FTfJ0e3f4v_CVnfNQ" hash="1SeFbw">It is written in the scriptures, “All have sinned, and come short of the glory of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/3.23" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 3:23</a>.) “Repent ye therefore, and be converted, that your sins may be blotted out.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/3.19" class="scriptureRef">Acts 3:19</a>.) “For I the Lord cannot look upon sin with the least degree of allowance.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.31" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:31</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p11" pid="3SM9Y1MntUmqXQJ7BcT8hw" hash="lJatOg">President Harold B. Lee gave this counsel: “The heaviest burden that one has to bear in this life is the burden of sin.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> July 1973, p. 123.) The apostle Paul taught, “The wages of sin is death.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/6.23" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 6:23</a>.) The wages of sins that are not repented of is death—death to man’s potential godliness, death to man’s opportunity for eternal life with his Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p12" pid="0w4g3GnxP029G2Cxseogpg" hash="RaIftQ">The prophet Alma counseled the people, “Except ye repent ye can in nowise inherit the kingdom of heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.51" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:51</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p13" pid="EFksbIXJqkSdITmG6NWvfQ" hash="rM_8Kw">The apostle Peter said, “The Lord is not … willing that any should perish, but that all should come to repentance.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-pet/3.9" class="scriptureRef">2 Pet. 3:9</a>.) What is repentance? Repentance is sorrow for sin, with self-condemnation, and complete turning away from sin. It is, therefore, more than regret and remorse; it brings about changes and makes room for the Christ-like life in preparation for entering into the kingdom of heaven. Repentance is turning away from that which is not according to God’s commandments and striving and knowing and living according to his commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p14" pid="UzImdkkot0Sw87T-4acG0w" hash="prwfng">King Benjamin counseled his people on how to repent. “Ye must repent of your sins and forsake them, and humble yourselves before God; and ask in sincerity of heart that he would forgive you; and now, if you believe all these things, see that you do them. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p15" pid="B_X87uEdjE6XPBY8Hz4agQ" hash="GKxc2A">“And behold, I say unto you that as you do this ye shall always rejoice, and be filled with the love of God, and always retain a remission of your sins; and ye shall grow in the knowledge of the glory of him that created you.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.10,12" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:10, 12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p16" pid="G5DpBvc4f02EGIMDMxI3yA" hash="9J9l1A">Jesus taught the people, “I, the Lord, forgive sins, and am merciful unto those who confess their sins with humble hearts.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/61.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 61:2</a>.) “He who has repented of his sins,” the Lord said, “the same is forgiven, and I, the Lord, remember them no more.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:42</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p17" pid="Zk6Mkf59bUqhBPcVk8dJ4w" hash="FJLUog">The prophet Moses said that through repentance “ye might be sanctified from all sin, and enjoy the words of eternal life in this world, and eternal life in the world to come, even immortal glory.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/6.59" class="scriptureRef">Moses 6:59</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p18" pid="O2siCMcI8kSRt8kYDCpcgg" hash="mhUQpA">Jesus warned that only a few would confess and forsake their sins and pay the price to find the Lord’s way to the kingdom of heaven. Many will take and follow the course that leads to destruction, destruction of the divine privilege of living with God. The Savior commanded, “Enter ye in at the strait gate: for wide is the gate, and broad is the way, that leadeth to destruction, and many there be which go in thereat:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p19" pid="WfpxJHu-KUyQLPKkj3E0nA" hash="8a2t6A">“Because strait is the gate, and narrow is the way, which leadeth unto life, and few there be that find it.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.13-14" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 7:13–14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p20" pid="WA9JXHPZvUuRrCOx--3r9g" hash="4_Lktw">And why are there few that will find the Lord’s straight and narrow way which leadeth unto life and salvation into the kingdom of God? Because they will not repent. Because they will not learn and keep all of God’s commandments. They will not follow Jesus Christ. They will not find and follow the Lord’s living prophet and apostles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p21" pid="cinD6Mv_fkW-a_QeFgX4eQ" hash="65i7kg">What is God’s most important and greatest blessing for his obedient children? He commanded and promised, “Trifle not with sacred things. If thou wilt do good, yea, and hold out faithful to the end, thou shalt be saved in the kingdom of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.12-13" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:12–13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p22" pid="zVtJki8y0UWp6RnujeOKxg" hash="TJ9oOA">“Trifle not with sacred things.” Many trifle with the sacred commandment “Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.37" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:37</a>.) Some disrespect God and love his worldly creations more than they love God. They love the creature more than they love the Creator. Some love pleasure more than they love God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p23" pid="YU7IsOP69UGqlwvRazXi5w" hash="Df57iw">Many of the Lord’s children trifle with the sacred privilege of eternal marriage by the Lord’s priesthood in his temples. The Lord said that through his priesthood male and female should be “one flesh” when married. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/19.5-6" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 19:5–6</a>.) Many settle for “until death do you part.” They trifle with sacred things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p24" pid="EDUUjZ0-9EC7p1HERmrzkg" hash="HundFA">Many trifle with the sacred commandment “Thou shalt not commit adultery” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.14" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:14</a>) and indulge their minds and bodies in illicit, promiscuous sex acts. From the teachings of the scriptures we find that those that are guilty of illicit sex acts, unless they repent, cannot inherit the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p25" pid="B2NfcmlAKUaTDiV7vMd4ZQ" hash="apwpTg">Some trifle with the Lord’s sacred, hallowed Sabbath day and spend the day in sports, pleasure, and other worldly interests when they should have been resting from worldly interests and devoting time to the spiritual side of life in reading the scriptures, attending religious meetings, in developing greater love for God, self, neighbor, and family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p26" pid="Fi-4Ol5zXkmmL_WfZOPQMA" hash="VVpfAA">Some trifle with the sacred scriptures. Jesus commanded, “Search the scriptures.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.39" class="scriptureRef">John 5:39</a>.) They ignore the scriptures and fail to search them. Some trifle with the Lord’s divine law of tithing and choose to rob God of his tithing, and as a result, the Lord said they are cursed with a curse, and unless they repent they cannot inherit the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p27" pid="luQdokrhaU2HU5iqP7lLgg" hash="N8OZHQ">Some trifle with the sacred responsibility of doing their genealogy research and temple work for both the living and the dead. Some trifle with their sacred godlike minds and bodies and use drugs and stimulants to receive a lift when they should receive their lift from repentance and from knowing and loving God and living his commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p28" pid="j421PpI-7UOw74u8JkxThQ" hash="pPH08A">Some trifle with the priesthood of God and destroy and make mockery out of its power. The Lord said they do this because they become so engrossed in worldly interests. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.34-35" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:34–35</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p29" pid="lAvnx1xjUEOl6YBj5H6qTw" hash="rtng-A">Some trifle with the sacred right to have children. Some trifle with the sacred right to love their neighbors as themselves. Some trifle with their sacred right to pray to their Father in heaven. They make up excuses and philosophies that make prayers look unwise and foolish.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p30" pid="7BYPt3fvME-Clr0c22hSyQ" hash="iM9i3w">Some trifle with the sacred commandment, “Be ye therefore perfect, even as your Father which is in heaven is perfect.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.48" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:48</a>.) Perfection is the divine way and comes through repentance and following Jesus Christ. Each of us should make a list using God’s commandments of what we need to do to attain salvation in the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p31" pid="5sp0ZGbcpUi4sy1HXgRwIg" hash="rrOXaA">There is no progress toward the kingdom of God without repentance. Our president, Spencer W. Kimball, said, “Repentance is ever the key to a better, happier life.” All of us need it, whether our sins be minor or grievous ones.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p32" pid="xldwlvgFjU2zSb4KastYAQ" hash="EBh-6A">We all have need of the progress that comes from the purifying power of repentance. We need to comprehend more fully the potential godliness that we possess and the glorious opportunity to repent and to prepare to live some day in the kingdom of God. When did you last use the divine cleansing power of repentance?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p33" pid="AtMP8Na3W02R68djiBtiEA" hash="LBtbzA">“Remember,” Jesus said, “the worth of souls is great in the sight of God;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p34" pid="BovpFwwCkEG9Rn7809IX5g" hash="E3GzUw">“And how great is his joy in the soul that repenteth!” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.10,13" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:10, 13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance.p35" pid="dAFQBIfRwUWMrQu6eoWcLQ" hash="0Mjg1Q">Every day in our prayers we should thank God for the divine principle of repentance, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/10/the-divine-power-of-repentance</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1974-general-conference/1974-10-4030-elder-bernard-p-brockbank-64k-eng.mp3" length="5703311" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 1974 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Today Millions Are Waiting</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The greatest blessing that can come to mankind is to be numbered with the Saints of the Lord. Today there are millions of God’s children waiting to be taught the gospel of Jesus Christ. Yes, as Jesus said, “The harvest truly is great, but the laboure</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03057_000_022" doc-version="2" hash="NiYbWQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="XAmmN8ssiESBE7cxSLXiNg" hash="fGgb9A">Today Millions Are Waiting</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ne4LJ0PUz0KYgnTnyDvZTw" hash="XRQ3pw">Bernard P. Brockbank</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3056.jpg" alt="Elder Bernard P. Brockbank" pid="fYwb4QCkwUOoSKzDpADdDg" hash="4NJQdA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p1" pid="PCl5agWV90GXR6bHKjWjkA" hash="e2IZBQ">The greatest blessing that can come to mankind is to be numbered with the Saints of the Lord. Today there are millions of God’s children waiting to be taught the gospel of Jesus Christ. Yes, as Jesus said, “The harvest truly is great, but the labourers are few.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.2" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:2</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p2" pid="gJCQMGqdBEqt4ySZIzCyMQ" hash="UVrKbA">In accordance with latter-day revelation from the Lord, we are living in the last days of the dispensation of the fulness of times. And according to statisticians the world’s population has increased from one-fourth billion when Jesus Christ lived on this earth to over three and a half billion today and the increase continues.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p3" pid="GUw14tToqkyHh0Uck0nsLw" hash="YsQN_w">The phenomenal population growth in these, the latter days, is by divine power with divine purpose.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p4" pid="KK7-KqRfvkqd_lk99Uuvkg" hash="ydgG_g">The dispensation of the fulness of times has staggering statistics, perilous times, and worldwide need for millions of valiant Saints and missionaries.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p5" pid="IUDqfAVO8EGBNa7rD6hKRg" hash="GGnryg">The Lord, by revelation to his Prophet Joseph Smith, declared and commanded the Latter-day Saints to teach the gospel of Jesus Christ to every nation and people. He said, “Proclaim my gospel from land to land, and from city to city. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p6" pid="dJdRd7ieXEGATgMrJ7B1QA" hash="4TcZzg">“Bear testimony in every place, unto every people.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/66.5,7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 66:5, 7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p7" pid="XmnFXShEeUq8WpsrbwgXGQ" hash="trFYfg">“For verily the voice of the Lord is unto all men, and there is none to escape; and there is no eye that shall not see, neither ear that shall not hear, neither heart that shall not be penetrated.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:2</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p8" pid="I1rQzomRnUikitc2a4nMAQ" hash="SawkGg">“This gospel shall be preached unto every nation, and kindred, and tongue, and people.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/133.37" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 133:37</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p9" pid="g_QVVX9TtUqQlSA1hRLSMA" hash="ar_tfA">“Every man shall hear the fulness of the gospel in his own tongue, and in his own language, through those who are ordained unto this power.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/90.11" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 90:11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p10" pid="HWD8VAAElkyaUedZmKFIaA" hash="zE8pyg">The scriptures are filled with commands and promises and calls and rewards regarding missionary work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p11" pid="9KXakXOcA0ivED-LRKgoqA" hash="uqZqVA">The Lord gave this important warning by commandment to his Latter-day Saints: “Labor ye in my vineyard for the last time—for the last time call upon the inhabitants of the earth.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/43.28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 43:28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p12" pid="-bKdpyLNu0KtGsPqMWdBlg" hash="6GsALQ">“It is the eleventh hour, and the last time that I shall call laborers into my vineyard.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p13" pid="YcVOylNn5EiUXsPILZc7Gw" hash="EeSAPw">“And my vineyard has become corrupted every whit; and there is none which doeth good save it be a few; and they err in many instances because of priestcrafts, all having corrupt minds.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p14" pid="WYD14k1_c0Gvg64mdT0WpQ" hash="ka4W0Q">“And verily, verily, I say unto you, that this church have I established and called forth out of the wilderness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p15" pid="J4BUrII-aE2fAprFezX73g" hash="BYPTJQ">“And even so will I gather mine elect from the four quarters of the earth, even as many as will believe in me, and hearken unto my voice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p16" pid="imzSlXUkVUyNKQhEEpurwQ" hash="QMoyNQ">“Yea, verily, verily, I say unto you, that the field is white already to harvest; wherefore, thrust in your sickles, and reap with all your might, mind, and strength.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p17" pid="abZlsdgfi0-ImGp7cIUCUw" hash="Lg7jGw">“Open your mouths and they shall be filled. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p18" pid="W5DMnuEBIEORcN-tatoVzw" hash="87Vkbw">“Yea, open your mouths and spare not, and you shall be laden with sheaves upon your backs, for lo, I am with you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p19" pid="j8iKV7N0fEycunX1Q64E9g" hash="nh4pJA">“Yea, open your mouths and they shall be filled, saying: Repent, repent, and prepare ye the way of the Lord, and make his paths straight; for the kingdom of heaven is at hand;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p20" pid="ER8IrOxdIkCUVpS-f-ocXw" hash="46cpTw">“Yea, repent and be baptized, every one of you, for a remission of your sins; yea, be baptized even by water, and then cometh the baptism of fire and of the Holy Ghost.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/33.3-11" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 33:3–11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p21" pid="1MrGGbIMCUy8IeuzrwTrMQ" hash="9KlztA">Again, by commandment of the Lord missionary work is the duty and responsibility of every member of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p22" pid="ukDsVMuR106GPe9KpjHu-Q" hash="iUGLeg">Jesus said, “I give unto you a commandment, that every man, both elder, priest, teacher, and also member, go to with his might, with the labor of his hands, to prepare and accomplish the things which I have commanded.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p23" pid="0vKJLNwIHECrLwJddlVacA" hash="Zbkgrg">“And let your preaching be the warning voice, every man to his neighbor, in mildness and in meekness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p24" pid="SKd1TRP9YE6HiLBGTTwwBQ" hash="teqqzg">“And go ye out from among the wicked,” the Lord said. “Save yourselves.” And the Lord commanded, “Be ye clean that bear the vessels of the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.40-42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:40–42</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p25" pid="v-fsqiJrI0mTo-ajCJPIqw" hash="G3uTGg">Upon no other group of men in the world rests greater responsibility than upon the priesthood holders of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. And every member of the Lord’s church should live and prepare himself to be a savior of men. By preaching the gospel of salvation to the world, the Saints become saviors of men. Of his Saints the Lord said, “They were set to be a light unto the world, and to be saviors of men.” And he added these words of warning: “And inasmuch as they are not the saviors of men, they are as salt that has lost its savor, and is henceforth good for nothing but to be cast out and trodden under foot of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/103.9-10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 103:9–10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p26" pid="Vlwb3zOpfUmUYW0wUai-tw" hash="qwry1A">Saints who do not become saviors will be cast out and trodden under foot of men. Now is the time to do missionary work. Now is the time to be saviors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p27" pid="PaVameC8lU6JvSngUxSr_Q" hash="ErCAHw">To all who will teach the gospel of Jesus Christ to their friends and neighbors the Lord has promised salvation to their souls. Hear this divine counsel and promise:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p28" pid="ghFJeKZ-pUOWYRywik3-Dw" hash="L-e6NA">“O ye that embark in the service of God, see that ye serve him with all your heart, might, mind and strength, that ye may stand blameless before God at the last day. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p29" pid="lh_m7A7Sokm_Fb6GoN3Tpg" hash="k6F9uw">“For behold the field is white already to harvest; and lo, he that thrusteth in his sickle with his might, the same layeth up in store that he perisheth not, but bringeth salvation to his soul.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/4.2,4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 4:2, 4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p30" pid="KQNL6e-2tkCymE2MDNxeBg" hash="oiittw">I would like to quote several statements that were given by President Kimball. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p31" pid="1s-P53qXc0uVkl58UVQsbQ" hash="TiFpSw">“Perhaps the greatest reason for missionary work is to give the world its chance to hear and accept the gospel. The scriptures are replete with commands and promises and calls and rewards for teaching the gospel. I use the word <span class="emphasis">command</span> deliberately,” he said, “for it seems to be an insistent directive from which we, singly and collectively, cannot escape. … [Ours is a missionary church. We must prepare missionaries. We must be missionaries.] Every young man should fill a mission. … What an army we should have teaching Christ and him crucified! …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p32" pid="NR_GsSFqgU2fjZWCusjBZQ" hash="mhxUYg">“[We hope to go to all the world. How we’ll do that only the Lord knows, but we are trying to find out.] I believe that the Lord is anxious to put into our hands inventions of which we laymen have hardly had a glimpse. … He will open the gates and make possible the proselyting. … I believe the time has come when we must … change our sights and raise our goals.” (“When the World Will Be Converted,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Oct. 1974, pp. 4, 8, 10, 13, 14.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p33" pid="K_RFm8qpA0GSabDbRS_X8Q" hash="-uUEBA">Today the following words from the Lord should always be uppermost in our thoughts and actions. The Lord has commanded, “Remember the worth of souls is great in the sight of God;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p34" pid="e9jjqIWZbEW2wIkp9i5-_Q" hash="ACNDug">“For, behold, the Lord your Redeemer suffered death in the flesh; wherefore he suffered the pain of all men, that all men might repent and come unto him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p35" pid="0Nyj_Jhmjkydw9LCKSDMsw" hash="YbpMog">“And he hath risen again from the dead, that he might bring all men unto him, on conditions of repentance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p36" pid="F8zyyy9_V0ycunsVgCklyg" hash="59I36A">“And how great is his joy in the soul that repenteth!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p37" pid="8fUeZ2F1OEKUQJYw8X_cbA" hash="uRk9Jg">“Wherefore, you are called to cry repentance unto this people.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.10-14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:10–14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p38" pid="8lfPIik-D0m9OqZvOZWJFA" hash="HwBJ8w">Brothers and sisters, we are all called to cry repentance unto the people. “And if it so be that you should labor all your days in crying repentance into this people,” the Lord said, “and bring, save it be one soul unto me, how great shall be your joy with him in the kingdom of my Father.” What a blessing and achievement it is when you help one of God’s children to become godlike and prepare to live with our Heavenly Father in his celestial kingdom. “And now, if your joy will be great with one soul that you have brought unto me into the kingdom of my Father,” the Lord said, “how great will be your joy if you should bring many souls unto me!” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.15-16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:15–16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p39" pid="09yDrlCtRkWRjIcT47Al-Q" hash="Vw990A">Jesus said the harvest truly is great, but the laborers are few. Then he gave this important commandment that often we overlook, “Pray ye therefore the Lord of the harvest, that he would send forth labourers into his harvest.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.2" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:2</a>.) If all the Saints would pray to the Lord to send forth laborers unto the harvest, we’d have many more. A prophet of God said, “Every member a missionary.” That is a prophetic statement with prophetic power.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p40" pid="raiJhqpZe0S3js861eM6wQ" hash="qrE7Dw">The following divine promise has great eternal meaning to the Saints of the Lord. Jesus said, “By hearkening to observe all the words which I, the Lord their God, shall speak unto them, they shall never cease to prevail until the kingdoms of the world are subdued under my feet, and the earth is given unto the saints, to possess it forever and ever.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/103.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 103:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p41" pid="c_RYhR33JkuyKdHQGooZiQ" hash="BINLKQ">The number of saints that will possess this earth “forever and ever” depends, in part, on the missionary effort of the valiant Saints that live on this earth in the latter days.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p42" pid="YB03835VzEKQFKz01BaoDg" hash="2hu4kQ">Jesus said, “This is life eternal, that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17:3</a>.) We should give, we that have testimonies, the Lord’s children a chance and opportunity to know the only true God and Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting.p43" pid="mMlQ9WF4rE6Y-umk0xYD2Q" hash="O_rRHg">I love and sustain President Spencer W. Kimball. He’s truly a prophet of God. I bear witness that God lives, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/04/today-millions-are-waiting</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1975-general-conference/1975-04-3060-elder-bernard-p-brockbank-64k-eng.mp3" length="5426038" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 1975 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“The Leaves Are Commencing to Show on the Fig Tree”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Before the second coming of Jesus Christ, certain promised signs and wonders are to take place, making it possible for his Saints to know the approximate time of his coming. Jesus said: “Now learn a parable of the fig tree; When his branch is yet ten</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03070_000_034" doc-version="2" hash="q3lv6A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="YCdm_C-DM0yqYuZtr7qzzQ" hash="MW9mNQ">“The Leaves Are Commencing to Show on the Fig Tree”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="8x264_VFJk6x9O090L5I1w" hash="XRQ3pw">Bernard P. Brockbank</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3056.jpg" alt="Elder Bernard P. Brockbank" pid="7OCpvaQiKUGXOuL9GXlKtw" hash="4NJQdA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p1" pid="vob8tSacfk-XXeK6aLffEQ" hash="ziE1CQ">Before the second coming of Jesus Christ, certain promised signs and wonders are to take place, making it possible for his Saints to know the approximate time of his coming. Jesus said: “Now learn a parable of the fig tree; When his branch is yet tender, and putteth forth leaves, ye know that summer is nigh:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p2" pid="oyufiAnh-0CE46A3IKM7bQ" hash="ekaDAA">“So likewise ye, when ye shall see all these things, know that it is near, even at the doors.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/24.32-33" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 24:32–33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p3" pid="HjNqVGkeJ06V68GxF1NvHg" hash="B1PecA">President Kimball gave this counsel, “The leaves are commencing to show on the fig tree.” That is prophetic.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p4" pid="0cEIZRkxhESlvWrOExd58A" hash="aiH7jQ">
        <span class="emphasis">“What are some of these signs and wonders that shall take place in the last days, prior to the second coming of Jesus Christ?”</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p5" pid="yk6uKtdO4Ue3PCLRlzY4fA" hash="CLj_eg">“There shall arise false Christs, and false prophets,” the Lord said, “and shall shew great signs and wonders; insomuch that, if it were possible, they shall deceive the very elect.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/24.24" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 24:24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p6" pid="lVhNQDi9wECGQ5EtTYohcg" hash="VeMEMw">“Many shall come in my name saying, I am Christ; and shall deceive many.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/24.5" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 24:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p7" pid="bwIxu2Rx6Ee4iWttdY5fCw" hash="2nMKsA">The Lord said: “Peace shall be taken from the earth, and the devil shall have power over his own dominion.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.35" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:35</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p8" pid="a1ZHzoECM0y6ALSFBBn1Dg" hash="5R1USw">Many scriptures summarize the signs and world conditions, the wars, perils, and commotions of the last days. The prophetic words tell of plagues, scourges, tribulations, calamities, and disasters without parallel; of strife, rumors of wars, wars, “nation shall rise against nation, … kingdom against kingdom.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/24.7" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 24:7</a>.) There will be blood, carnage, and desolation. The scriptures speak of the elements being in commotion with floods, storms, fires, whirlwinds, and earthquakes with intensity unknown to men in former times, of evil, iniquity, wickedness, turmoil, murder, crime, and commotion among men beyond comprehension.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p9" pid="gASLMPZAt0mPPmu3rn097w" hash="PvG0JA">“For in those days,” saith the Lord, “shall be affliction, such as was not from the beginning of the creation.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/13.19" class="scriptureRef">Mark 13:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p10" pid="dLqHAU58qEyzEcntvG-97Q" hash="hqk31A">“All things shall be in commotion; … men’s hearts shall fail them; … fear shall come upon all people.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.91" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:91</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p11" pid="zyuyVWQSa0u1fHl8elYMbQ" hash="8mEzfg">“And as it was in the days of Noe, so shall it be also in the days of the Son of man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p12" pid="_4XvD-w6GU6Jq0NN-ZT9dA" hash="tZ8GCw">“They did eat, they drank, they married wives, they were given in marriage, until the day that Noe entered into the ark, and the flood came, and destroyed them all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p13" pid="5wbbPOIMw0OW8pu6ES_Fog" hash="XT0Lfw">“Likewise also as it was in the days of Lot; they did eat, they drank, they bought, they sold, they planted, they builded”—the times were lush—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p14" pid="UysRkexC60GMmkCWpvcitg" hash="CatdIQ">“But the same day that Lot went out of Sodom it rained fire and brimstone from heaven, and destroyed them all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p15" pid="x1z9nmYEQEO2CInRtbkZaQ" hash="rvsKmg">“Even thus shall it be in the day when the Son of man is revealed.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/17.26-30" class="scriptureRef">Luke 17:26–30</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p16" pid="4az3Ny4W_EeMzvsjrev51Q" hash="6cQlBA">The apostle Paul was inspired to give the following summary on the status of man and the world in the last days. He wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p17" pid="MwlTiDSy7kSbmW2KNAMN6g" hash="tbCBmg">“This know also, that in the last days perilous times shall come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p18" pid="7Xpq8i5eeUSyGHl37ibacw" hash="RnbYYw">“For men shall be lovers of their own selves, covetous, boasters, proud, blasphemers, disobedient to parents, unholy,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p19" pid="gKJMFGac7EKBcbijVLzwAg" hash="ydcVRg">“Without natural affection, trucebreakers, false accusers, incontinent, fierce, despisers of those that are good,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p20" pid="kzlwAtJSEk2RMsW_W4vLUQ" hash="5CX5FQ">“Traitors, heady, highminded, lovers of pleasures more than lovers of God;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p21" pid="goPZbzzn_kOXLSLfKTlz2w" hash="6DkTbQ">“Having a form of godliness, but denying the power thereof”; and then he warned, “from such turn away.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/3.1-5" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 3:1–5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p22" pid="0Z6tuC3CtEW7DCZWkZSVuA" hash="Il8xrQ">Speaking of these perilous times, Jesus said, “The saints also shall hardly escape; nevertheless, I, the Lord, am with them.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/63.34" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 63:34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p23" pid="U4sWD-WGy02h46A9NX2GiQ" hash="qaqRPw">However, in the last days the Saints have very important promises from the Lord. He said: “[I], the Lord shall have power over [my] saints, and shall reign in their midst, and shall come down in judgment upon … the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:36</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p24" pid="6a2YSYBRZUm53lsEWLHxsA" hash="I-3AlA">He said, “Unto you it shall be given to know the signs of the times and the signs of the coming of the Son of Man.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.11" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p25" pid="C_YAN2-fwkqjwvV95bg56Q" hash="8tp12g">“And, as I, the Lord, in the beginning cursed the land, even so in the last days have I blessed it, in its time, for the use of my saints, that they may partake the fatness thereof.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/61.17" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 61:17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p26" pid="-z0Chj56MkmiFOpUZpYgHQ" hash="Q7UTfQ">The Church of Jesus Christ is never again to be taken from the earth. This is one of the great signs of the times—it shall continue to grow and flourish and cover the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p27" pid="FZIgQtQyuUKprJ_Dq7hzOQ" hash="AckjIQ">The Holy Ghost and the priesthood of God will continue to be on the earth. There shall be in the last days living prophets and living apostles chosen and called by Jesus Christ. The Lord promised, “My disciples shall stand in holy places, and shall not be moved.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/45.32" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 45:32</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p28" pid="ISa1wJIsAUauooTVuUd6Bw" hash="KXEmvA">This is one of the most important signs of our time: “This gospel of the kingdom shall be preached in all the world for a witness unto all nations; and then shall the end come.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/24.14" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 24:14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p29" pid="OxHyE3zZ1EmDqeIgu25AkA" hash="fYZK-g">The devil is doing all that he can to hinder the progress of the message going to all the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p30" pid="oIDc8R9kDESu_A2jJd_pMg" hash="gJaOgg">Jesus commanded his disciples: “Go ye therefore, and teach all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p31" pid="shbfpBXR7EmgLdxCu9hDlw" hash="cm8Hqg">“Teaching them to observe all things whatsoever I have commanded you: and, lo, I am with you alway, even unto the end of the world. Amen.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/28.19-20" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 28:19–20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p32" pid="ptchgl708EGhiDlnONTPAw" hash="E9tGpA">Of Judah and Jerusalem in the last days the Lord promised, “Then will the Father gather them together again, and give unto them Jerusalem for the land of their inheritance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p33" pid="s-Bv3TLlVUqAmNBBbejC2Q" hash="BFXEBQ">“Then shall they break forth into joy—Sing together, ye waste places of Jerusalem; for the Father has comforted his people, he hath redeemed Jerusalem.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p34" pid="_CSuBQwsikqKikV1kYq48w" hash="UOtaEg">“The Father hath made bare his holy arm in the eyes of all the nations [We have witnessed part of this.], and all the ends of the earth shall see the salvation of the Father.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/20.33-35" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 20:33–35</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p35" pid="PxcggtOEb0SfmJpbCUf1Nw" hash="PezzLg">“And it shall come to pass that the time cometh, when the fulness of my gospel shall be preached unto them;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p36" pid="XBFIRrvtwEGolPoo3F8KKw" hash="NGi5Cw">“And they shall believe in me, that I am Jesus Christ the Son of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/20.30-31" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 20:30–31</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p37" pid="Rn_H9iJL4kKV97lt2Y4Log" hash="w-FvuQ">“Before the great day of the Lord shall come, Jacob shall flourish in the wilderness, and the Lamanites shall blossom as the rose.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p38" pid="M3Ru28nXi0ayQpkex1sgkw" hash="jLa2Xw">“Zion shall flourish upon the hills and rejoice upon the mountains, and shall be assembled together unto the place which I have appointed.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/49.24-25" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 49:24–25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p39" pid="TthsaAOvK0u2LgyQNpUZpw" hash="zMqPbg">“The poor and the meek shall have the gospel preached unto them, and they shall be looking forth for the time of my coming, for it is nigh at hand,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p40" pid="EVOROPJxFkiQt4JeCDz-aA" hash="WpCjsA">“And they shall learn the parable of the fig tree, for even now already summer is nigh.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/35.15-16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 35:15–16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p41" pid="ABTDG8l6VU-kGGSBlZ1h1A" hash="3yza3g">Now is the time every Latter-day Saint is urgently needed to be one with Jesus Christ and to be saviors of men. Of his Latter-day Saints, Jesus gave this counsel, “For they were set to be a light unto the world, and to be the saviors of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/103.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 103:9</a>.) I repeat, “For they were set to be a light unto the world, and to be the saviors of men.” The Lord then added this warning, “And inasmuch as they are not the saviors of men, they are as salt that has lost its savor, and is thenceforth good for nothing but to be cast out and trodden under foot of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/103.9-10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 103:9–10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p42" pid="MLabrNlKSUyUq4-wvt0_Yg" hash="7W41Sg">The Lord has spoken! Every Latter-day Saint is to be a light unto the world and is to be savior of men; and if they fail in this sacred, soul-saving assignment, they will be trodden under the foot of men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p43" pid="NybahWgtTUaB1f_kaTKB2Q" hash="cB6B3A">And again the Lord counseled his Saints: “I give unto you a commandment, that every man, both elder, priest, teacher, and also member, go to with his might, with the labor of his hands, to prepare and accomplish the things which I have commanded.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p44" pid="YucroLk4mkCtx8WpV_HHjw" hash="Zbkgrg">“And let your preaching be the warning voice, every man to his neighbor, in mildness and in meekness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p45" pid="1NetHYq-_UOurlJ2j0oe8A" hash="3n7s_A">“And go ye out from among the wicked. Save yourselves. Be ye clean that bear the vessels of the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.40-42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:40–42</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p46" pid="mIOjq1-gUEuU91GKrnqySA" hash="ygywCQ">President Kimball has called our attention recently to an ancient prophecy recorded in the Holy Bible that tells of conditions that will exist among the people in the last days. The prophet Joel said, “Put ye in the sickle, for the harvest is ripe: come, get you down; for the press is full, the fats overflow; for their wickedness is great.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p47" pid="dm2z27ZHJEeOBdcT_Nq9Bw" hash="9by-sQ">“Multitudes, multitudes in the valley of decision: for the day of the Lord is near in the valley of decision.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/joel/3.13-14" class="scriptureRef">Joel 3:13–14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p48" pid="1ZJdacTT9069jtCPbmMNiw" hash="v1cWlA">Today in most areas people have more than they have ever had. Their press is full, their fats overflow, wickedness is great, and there are multitudes of good, honest-in-heart people looking for a sacred purpose and way of life. This is true in the British Isles, contrary to what we sometimes read. It has never been better for most of the people than it is today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p49" pid="ATA3ndqA50m-KxD7RRU4DQ" hash="1cy0IQ">It seems reasonable and possible that one percent of the Lord’s children now living on this earth would accept his way of life and join his church if they were shown his way by his Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree.p50" pid="SAcm9TSF1Ee70qvau00Niw" hash="f0BClw">One percent would be approximately 36,000,000 and that is a multitude of potential Saints. Yes, there are multitudes, multitudes in the valley of decision waiting to see the saintly light that leads to divine perfection. Every possible missionary that is in harmony with the Holy Spirit is urgently needed. We have many that could still be called. May we that are privileged to live in the last days be valiant and let our light shine and may we be one with Jesus Christ in helping bring salvation to all mankind. In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/04/the-leaves-are-commencing-to-show-on-the-fig-tree</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1976-general-conference/1976-04-5060-elder-bernard-p-brockbank-64k-eng.mp3" length="11209063" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1976 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Living Christ</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ?lang=eng</link>
      <description>It has been a glorious privilege and blessing to spend over seven years of my life as a servant of the Lord in the British Isles and Ireland. These countries of my ancestors are beautiful, and we feel at home and love the people.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ" dup-mag="false" dup-conf="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03083_000_013" doc-version="3" hash="R_f11A"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="2AEJi2GWjkGtq5mir4Vklg" hash="FIMtqQ">The Living Christ</h1><p class="authorName" pid="cGoYbb90ZkW_nADFysvbBQ" hash="XRQ3pw">Bernard P. Brockbank</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3056.jpg" alt="Elder Bernard P. Brockbank" pid="9utzOD2tBU2pAsk17DMCTA" hash="4NJQdA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p1" pid="S2Ownse_1kaoVvtMm_irzw" hash="c-_IQw">It has been a glorious privilege and blessing to spend over seven years of my life as a servant of the Lord in the British Isles and Ireland. These countries of my ancestors are beautiful, and we feel at home and love the people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p2" pid="fzRr2H8UVUyPhsclaQezaQ" hash="P0WOEQ">President Kimball, the Latter-day Saints in the British Isles, Ireland, Rhodesia, and South Africa love, support, and sustain you as the Lord’s living prophet; and they also love and sustain the Lord’s living apostles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p3" pid="_bS1SpxUV0O83-GAWaZFZA" hash="zLgoHw">The Lord’s church is the only church that is required to have a living prophet and a quorum of twelve living apostles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p4" pid="Q-DwFNhQEEuoSmiB6hIdQQ" hash="N5gW3Q">The Latter-day Saints in Rhodesia and South Africa with their racial and equal rights problems desire that the will of the Lord be done in their lives and in their countries, and some of the Lord’s finest Saints live in these countries.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p5" pid="1RF9m05jFU2XSr38l_sSEA" hash="-dDZ3w">We are living in perilous, restless, uncertain times in the world and this is true in the British Isles. Many of the Christian churches are closing down some of their church buildings because the people will not support them. While this is taking place, The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints continues to grow and the number of those participating in the Church programs is increasing. I would like to briefly mention several statistics regarding the growth and progress of the Savior’s church in the British Isles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p6" pid="RU1bRXQL5kGfrjv2vmDrDg" hash="oo_t3g">In the year 1960 we had one mission serving 55 million people in England, Scotland, Wales, and Ireland with approximately 180 full-time missionaries.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p7" pid="itGpl9Ul3UusC4RqDp_1xg" hash="kiPj4A">In the early part of 1960 there were no stakes of the Church, and today we have 27 fully organized stakes and 5 more areas ready to be considered for stakehood. We also have 12 districts that are preparing to become stakes. In 1960 we had 11,000 members. Today, we have over 100,000 members. In 1960 there were no Church buildings adequate to serve the needs of a ward. Today, we have 175 beautiful chapels and 47 more under construction or in preliminary preparation for construction. There are in the British Isles 376 units of the Church including missions, stakes, districts, wards, branches, and other Church programs.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p8" pid="OmuxFrR8TUmxetlBPUciew" hash="RVuwrw">There are millions of the Lord’s covenant children in the British Isles that are waiting for the Lord’s missionaries and Latter-day Saints to reach and teach them the sacred principles and ordinances of the restored gospel of Jesus Christ as it is recorded in the holy scriptures. We are just scratching the surface of what needs to be done in these countries.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p9" pid="9ce6NmBVkUupDKamB8TXUA" hash="ABzpuQ">Many of the Christian churches in the British Isles do not consider or recognize The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints as a Christian church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p10" pid="BQnbWrhpuk-OsLz0U3tjsg" hash="xRqR9g">The following statement was printed in the <span class="emphasis">London Times:</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p11" pid="R4ADX6P7AEmg819GdiVZHQ" hash="XPeBDg">“Are the Mormons Christians? Certainly they claim to be followers of Christ and hence entitled to take their place alongside other denominations as another Christian church. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p12" pid="ZCZPgF4ELk6lhE-ZZrcXWQ" hash="3voMwg">“In fact, there is good reason for regarding them as a new religion rather than as another variety of Christianity. The Christ they follow is both the Christian Messiah of the New Testament, and the Risen Christ who visited the New World after the end of His ministry in the old one. Traditional Christianity—Roman Catholic [and] Protestant … —rejects the very existence of this Christ who reappeared on earth after the Ascension, and so the Christ followed by the Mormons is not the Christ followed by traditional Christianity.” (“Alcohol, tea, and smoking banned,” <span class="emphasis">The London Times,</span> June 18, 1976, special supplement on Mormons, p. II.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p13" pid="a53i6sB5nE6GZ4RacmQI1g" hash="YoC29g">It is true that many of the Christian churches worship a different Jesus Christ than is worshipped by the Mormons or The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. For example, from the Church of England’s Articles of Religion, article one, I quote: “There is but one living God, everlasting, without body, parts, or passions.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p14" pid="khwaizonwEi8fyNhXrea8A" hash="08bWQw">The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints worships a God and a Jesus Christ with bodies, with parts, and with passions. We also believe that the trinity of the Godhead is made up of three separate personages—God, the Eternal Father; Jesus Christ, the Son of God—our Savior; and the Holy Ghost. These two concepts of the Trinity and their attributes are completely different.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p15" pid="wNvDc3QG8EOiCZbaw6afwg" hash="lbScmQ">The Jesus Christ of the holy scriptures has a body of flesh and bones and passions before and after his resurrection.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p16" pid="J15YuoqHB02qIaIt9bfuvw" hash="G4gMUg">After his resurrection the Savior visited his apostles and said unto them: “Behold my hands and my feet, that it is I myself: handle me, and see; for a spirit hath not flesh and bones, as ye see me have.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p17" pid="m-K597FtqEentfXyN_zIBA" hash="m2_b7g">“And when he had thus spoken, he shewed them his hands and his feet.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/24.39-40" class="scriptureRef">Luke 24:39–40</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p18" pid="7EGPcT28qk6RFo4EkRahuA" hash="fpPm3g">Jesus warned man to beware of false Christs with these words: “Take heed that no man deceive you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p19" pid="1keWWnj1WU-H3_HKfh046A" hash="S9vhKA">“For many shall come in my name, saying, I am Christ; and shall deceive many. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p20" pid="ki_CvcjrokWdqPgqfcGQIQ" hash="QVsrig">“For there shall arise false Christs, and false prophets, and shall shew great signs and wonders; insomuch that, if it were possible, they shall deceive the very elect.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/24.4-5,24" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 24:4–5, 24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p21" pid="TmM1__BLoUS0juzgSRTHfQ" hash="zZh2nA">In the first commandment of the Ten Commandments, the Lord commanded man to worship the living God of the scriptures and not to create and worship man-conceived Deities. He said: “Thou shalt have no other gods before me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p22" pid="1KvMzt2R0ke14BhpCQ6vGA" hash="6R6eQQ">“Thou shalt not make unto thee any graven image, or any likeness of any thing that is in heaven above, or that is in the earth beneath, or that is in the water under the earth:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p23" pid="MWWellN5I0CVqn6C871yvg" hash="deB8ZA">“Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them, nor serve them.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.3-5" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:3–5</a>.) Many continue to bow down to man-made images.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p24" pid="6lVLTj_jEkC-h-hsr5d1xw" hash="_gCn7g">When the Savior lived on this earth he condemned the powerful Pharisee religion that professed to believe in the prophets and the scriptures but would not accept the living Jesus Christ. The Pharisees promised their disciples salvation in the kingdom of heaven, but because they would not accept the living Christ with a body of flesh, bones, and passions, Jesus denounced them saying: “Woe unto you, scribes and Pharisees, hypocrites! for ye shut up the kingdom of heaven against men: for ye neither go in yourselves, neither suffer ye them that are entering to go in.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/23.13" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 23:13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p25" pid="TOtb_CjAtkOL5Nws2BHpCA" hash="mcngJg">In latter-day revelation, the Lord again warned man not to be misled and deceived by religions that were organized without divine authority by men, by thrones, or by principalities that promise their disciples salvation in the kingdom of heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p26" pid="onSMuRS-Ck6nOkpUzvYCNA" hash="DFTvTA">He said: “I am the Lord thy God; and I give unto you this commandment—that no man shall come unto the Father but by me or by my word, which is my law. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p27" pid="M--FPBKQE0efjkNFoKccCw" hash="lCKLCQ">“And everything that is in the world, whether it be ordained of men, by thrones, or principalities, or powers, or things of name, whatsoever they may be, that are not by me or by my word, saith the Lord, shall be thrown down, and shall not remain after men are dead, neither in nor after the resurrection, saith the Lord your God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p28" pid="hziMxFApeEW4wV4ba5YENg" hash="8-SX1A">“For whatsoever things remain are by me; and whatsoever things are not by me shall be shaken and destroyed.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/132.12-14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 132:12–14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p29" pid="fl6j9XRcEEaJgYbC3w9s-g" hash="YlIHBA">There is only one way provided by the Lord for man to gain salvation and eternal life in the kingdom of God and that is by and through the living, personal Jesus Christ, and by knowing and living his commandments. We cannot obtain salvation and eternal life by worshipping fake Christs or by living the doctrines and commandments of men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p30" pid="nntGpA22hUCasIf80bOD5g" hash="Os_PFg">The Pharisees with their man-made doctrines and traditions were again condemned by the Savior. He said unto them: “This people draweth nigh unto me with their mouth, and honoureth me with their lips; but their heart is far from me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p31" pid="bFDsXnVu4kG1Ls9aWJ22sA" hash="5F5RbA">“… In vain they do worship me, teaching for doctrines the commandments of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/15.8-9" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 15:8–9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p32" pid="WlsyHZNqdEOPRF7GZugNmg" hash="G8JB6w">The belief that God has no body, parts, and passions is not a doctrine of Jesus Christ or a doctrine of the holy scriptures but is a doctrine of men, and to worship such a God is in vain.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p33" pid="qJIpKWnccE-nlk5PkVzG9A" hash="mjp25w">From the time when the Lord created man in his own image and likeness, men have created false gods to worship, such as golden calves, sculptured images, etc.; and billions through the centuries including the very elect have been deceived and misled.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p34" pid="9hICU_x2QkmKcm8-KVGgRg" hash="wxktVA">The sacred purpose of eternal life is to know the only true God and Jesus Christ. “This is life eternal,” Jesus said, “that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17:3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p35" pid="_YKJ5N3e4kSd5MR-mlID1w" hash="gidB0w">The message of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints to the people of the world is that God the Eternal Father and Jesus Christ live, that they are personages with immortal bodies of flesh and bones and passions, and that all mankind are children of God and are created in his image and likeness, and that Jesus Christ through his Prophet Joseph Smith restored his church with all of his doctrines, commandments, and ordinances as recorded in all of his holy scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ.p36" pid="WDXdK67w0E-94TrOQ6IcqA" hash="r0qNqg">I bear witness that Jesus Christ lives and that he will soon be returning to this earth in his majesty and glory, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1977/04/the-living-christ</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1977-general-conference/1977-04-2050-elder-bernard-p-brockbank-64k-eng.mp3" length="5876572" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 1977 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prayer to Our Heavenly Father</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Religions and doctrines originating with men cannot bring salvation to a child of God. The Lord counsels man in the Holy Bible that God’s ways did not come from man or from this earth. “My thoughts are not your thoughts, neither are your ways my ways</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03115_000_022" doc-version="2" hash="kucmvw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ymxUmrfRnE-Xta75r_j3JA" hash="Mm1Ehg">Prayer to Our Heavenly Father</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="dBECpg9oMUCxnTGEtS6YoQ" hash="XRQ3pw">Bernard P. Brockbank</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3056.jpg" alt="Elder Bernard P. Brockbank" pid="OJsa3wFmzUuRIFSm_db1Fw" hash="4NJQdA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p1" pid="3i2e1Z-W6kexUYkxVeaGTw" hash="hK8D1w">Religions and doctrines originating with men cannot bring salvation to a child of God. The Lord counsels man in the Holy Bible that God’s ways did not come from man or from this earth. “My thoughts are not your thoughts, neither are your ways my ways, saith the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p2" pid="H3EIFqFJoUq_MTSiroapFw" hash="n53njw">“For as the heavens are higher than the earth, so are my ways higher than your ways, and my thoughts than your thoughts” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/55.8-9" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 55:8–9</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p3" pid="LV-aCM6ES06zJUmdb6li7Q" hash="3qsRGA">The thoughts and ways of God provide for man the greatest opportunities and blessings of this life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p4" pid="xOhRp8A_HUS--X9Mo315rQ" hash="jaUBhg">The Lord gave man one of the highest goals for this life when he said, “And this is life eternal, that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17:3</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p5" pid="8t-xZ9GJt0yuFHq6fxawyg" hash="ZHvzPA">The Lord also commanded man—and it is well known by almost all Christians—“Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.37" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:37</a>). To know and love God are sacred blessings. One of the ways that we can come to know God and Jesus Christ is through sincere prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p6" pid="TfbQMMnDRkmgesfnp1XR-g" hash="GbyL4w">The Lord commands, “Pray always, and I will pour out my Spirit upon you, and great shall be your blessing—yea, even more than if you should obtain treasures of earth” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/19.38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 19:38</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p7" pid="MEOW1RWt_kKP2LecOkjbAA" hash="i6H4-w">In the Bible we are commanded to “pray without ceasing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p8" pid="-2TmUfZ5fkCTWUt1deDC0w" hash="0PxXOQ">“In everything give thanks: for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus concerning you” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-thes/5.17-18" class="scriptureRef">1 Thes. 5:17–18</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p9" pid="QoQgbOcyDE22-xZJicUdyQ" hash="Segxfw">Prayer to God will give you power to conquer and overcome the evil powers and influences of Satan and this world. The Lord said, “Pray always, that you may come off conqueror; yea, that you may conquer Satan, and that you may escape the hands of the servants of Satan that do uphold his work” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/10.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 10:5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p10" pid="PQEp02mslE-nbh7oro0TPw" hash="0kbU4g">Prayer to God is a sacred blessing. The Savior again counseled man on how to pray and we know the Lord’s Prayer well. The Lord said, “After this manner therefore pray ye: Our Father which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy name.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p11" pid="Vp3EhfARcUyRZEzfakKAlQ" hash="V-LUqQ">“Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done in earth, as it is in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p12" pid="aGex2l8LQEC2Uy1ooaWwXQ" hash="i2CkRQ">“Give us this day our daily bread.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p13" pid="lIk0eaKv8k2KtwXnqezp6w" hash="dPze4w">“And forgive us our debts, as we forgive our debtors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p14" pid="GJHaElIux02MtS9pW8ntzg" hash="x3F_CA">“And lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil: For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever. Amen” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.9-13" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 6:9–13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p15" pid="dgHRze0N90OSr_6tiiAlvA" hash="ZrD9PA">We should pray to our Father in Heaven with a hallowed heart; we should pray for his kingdom to come, and by so doing we commit ourselves to help build the kingdom of God on this earth. As we pray that the will of God be done on earth as it is in heaven, we commit ourselves to do the will of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p16" pid="-V-fhxuejEuJl4i6WF_NhQ" hash="hvtXkw">We should thank God for our “daily bread” and ask him to help us provide the necessities of this life. We should ask our Father for forgiveness of our sins and weaknesses, and commit ourselves to repentance, to the task of informing and improving in a sacred way our godlike minds and bodies.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p17" pid="m_nYgMbd20ifAjYi-xgzvA" hash="7E5xVA">We should ask our Father to help us meet the temptations of this life and to deliver us from evil. When we pray from our hearts and say “For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever,” we commit ourselves. Remember, the kingdom of God, the power of God, the glory of God should be man’s most cherished and important blessings and goals in this life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p18" pid="QfXgCBl5J02oMxJubxwdvA" hash="wL3QxQ">So important is the need to pray that the prophet Nephi taught “that ye should not perform any thing unto the Lord save in the first place ye shall pray unto the Father in the name of Christ, that he will consecrate thy performance unto thee, that thy performance may be for the welfare of thy soul” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/32.9" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 32:9</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p19" pid="M3JEZut-P0Wgjlo7rnFvgA" hash="Tlr37w">To pray meaningfully requires that one, insofar as possible, know the true character of God. As mentioned, we have been commanded to know God. Prayer leads to salvation, and ignorance is a deterrent to that goal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p20" pid="gzKNGkG9o0KIG6CdA5a1pQ" hash="2DNqRg">Jesus Christ promises man complete forgiveness if he repents, confesses, and forsakes his sins. Jesus gave these comforting words to those that repent. He said, “Behold, he who has repented of his sins, the same is forgiven, and I, the Lord, remember them no more.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p21" pid="i97IqGoxpkqDAodkoO1FXQ" hash="R0E3_w">“By this ye may know if a man repenteth of his sins—behold, he will confess them and forsake them” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.42-43" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:42–43</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p22" pid="a5NBJLXKFUWDGsmSutG9OA" hash="b0TALg">We should build that message into our hearts, and purify and build our minds and bodies in a godlike way through continued use of prayer, obedience, and repentance. Since prayer is a very important part of confession, confession must be to God as well as to others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p23" pid="qmuqNHvCS0Op56DquUHFGw" hash="BOa5qg">The Savior promises answers and blessings as the reward for sincere prayer. He taught and promised and said: “Ask, and it shall be given you; seek, and ye shall find; knock, and it shall be opened unto you:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p24" pid="XdawZAArjEeqnpRv1RzF7A" hash="ncgpZQ">“For every one that asketh receiveth; and he that seeketh findeth; and to him that knocketh it shall be opened” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.7-8" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 7:7–8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p25" pid="91pLHGZMdEujcoOOPu9_GA" hash="wpsiwQ">We should live and work, watch and wait, and continually pursue life prayerfully, repentantly, and purposefully.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p26" pid="4RfVTlPcbUKx8EDgez0x1Q" hash="TOvCOg">A prophet of God counsels man to pray always with these words: “And now, my beloved brethren, I perceive that ye ponder still in your hearts, and it grieveth me that I must speak concerning this thing. For if ye would hearken unto the Spirit which teacheth a man to pray ye would know that ye must pray; for the evil spirit teacheth not a man to pray, but teacheth him he must not pray.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p27" pid="fF0Gl9iEJ0Sv7Z6Rke0oPw" hash="kSCwOQ">“But behold, I say unto you that ye must pray always, and not faint; that ye must not perform any thing unto the Lord save in the first place ye shall pray unto the Father in the name of Christ, that he will consecrate thy performance unto thee, that thy performance may be for the welfare of thy soul” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/32.8-9" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 32:8–9</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p28" pid="FNqT0JiVc0ibgHJ5zlMvwA" hash="JDlOxA">Enos, a servant of the Lord—and this has been quoted a time or two in this conference, so apparently the Lord wanted emphasis on this—Enos speaks on the power of sincere prayer: “I will tell you of the wrestle which I had before God, before I received a remission of my sins.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p29" pid="jyXlbEtsSkK3U9EnZvZTKw" hash="TjEVGg">“Behold, I went to hunt beasts in the forests; and the words which I had often heard my father speak concerning eternal life, and the joy of the saints, sunk deep into my heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p30" pid="1AjMu685rkWhac9iW-MRfQ" hash="e2oQXw">“And my soul hungered; and I kneeled down before my Maker, and I cried unto him in mighty prayer and supplication for mine own soul; and all the day long did I cry unto him; yea, and when the night came I did still raise my voice high that it reached the heavens.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p31" pid="VpFCwH5vl06bIup717kSCg" hash="zA4NYQ">“And there came a voice unto me, saying: Enos, thy sins are forgiven thee, and thou shalt be blessed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p32" pid="oWTgqvwEpkWl_BWC6wICmA" hash="Gp1mRw">“And I, Enos, knew that God could not lie; wherefore, my guilt was swept away” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/enos/1.2-6" class="scriptureRef">Enos 1:2–6</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p33" pid="24g6KJ_Y0km_xs-JjXNkgA" hash="sWEfQQ">All of us, like Enos, need to continually have our sins and weaknesses swept away through repentance, confession, and sincere prayer. I repeat the Lord’s promise: “Behold, he who has repented of his sins, the same is forgiven, and I, the Lord, remember them no more.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p34" pid="oPfbFpX_nk6u1L4JIMbBlQ" hash="R0E3_w1">“By this ye may know if a man repenteth of his sins—behold, he will confess them and forsake them” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.42-43" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:42–43</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p35" pid="jwWC09oKx0CTb20UIZPc0g" hash="21fJvw">Repentance will purify and cleanse the mind and body and make room for greater perfection and godliness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p36" pid="cItFWXl-yESZa7U7NoxiFg" hash="aEeW9g">King Benjamin, when speaking to his people about prayer and repentance, gives valuable counsel on receiving answers from God. He taught: “Believe in God; believe that he is, and that he created all things, both in heaven and in earth; believe that he has all wisdom, and all power, both in heaven and in earth; believe that man doth not comprehend all the things which the Lord can comprehend.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p37" pid="T5klS6POg0WDd9BoN3GNgA" hash="hOxESA">“And again, believe that ye must repent of your sins and forsake them, and humble yourselves before God; and ask in sincerity of heart that he would forgive you; and now, if you believe all these things see that ye do them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p38" pid="ie1aNa3aKkC-7p5c2Ig3_Q" hash="ErASzw">“And again I say unto you as I have said before, that as ye have come to the knowledge of the glory of God, or if ye have known of his goodness and have tasted of his love, and have received a remission of your sins, which causeth such exceeding great joy in your souls, even so I would that ye should remember, and always retain in remembrance, the greatness of God, … and his goodness and long-suffering towards you, … and humble yourselves even in the depths of humility, calling on the name of the Lord daily, and standing steadfastly in the faith of that which is to come, which was spoken by the mouth of the angel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p39" pid="85-cRrKDPUmuPUPPmtdvwQ" hash="cgNYyg">“And behold, I say unto you that if ye do this ye shall always rejoice, and be filled with the love of God, and always retain a remission of your sins; and ye shall grow in the knowledge of the glory of him that created you, or in the knowledge of that which is just and true” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.9-12" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:9–12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p40" pid="_wuxnKq94ECR8dgZJP-Asw" hash="9Ku1Kg">The scriptures give us many promises regarding the power and the need of personal prayer. Jesus commanded men: “Ye must watch and pray always, lest ye be tempted by the devil, and ye be led away captive by him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p41" pid="uWd0mh9W8USlzr1xhS3hlw" hash="PuTgqg">“And as I have prayed among you even so shall ye pray in my church, among my people who do repent and are baptized in my name. Behold I am the light; I have set an example for you” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.15-16" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:15–16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p42" pid="X6zaD-uS00KRi8kGRrW8sQ" hash="DGd_Ag">“Behold, verily, verily, I say unto you,” the Lord continued, “ye must watch and pray always lest ye enter into temptation; for Satan desireth to have you, that he may sift you as wheat.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p43" pid="14m8-qE92kmde7NuAT1-DQ" hash="pN5vwA">“Therefore ye must always pray unto the Father in my name;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p44" pid="AWFJ6yN9pE2Xdq9-CKEijw" hash="X_1Uuw">“And whatsoever ye shall ask the Father in my name, which is right, believing that ye shall receive, behold it shall be given unto you” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.18-20" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:18–20</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p45" pid="qa8_4wSdbkCuMZpSw8ltvQ" hash="gXxjSg">Jesus Christ counsels man to have family prayer. He said, “Pray in your families unto the Father, always in my name, that your wives and your children may be blessed” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.21" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p46" pid="VCkVseaHnEGe9y2EcEVQpQ" hash="8F6mzw">Very few pray too much. It is not one of our weaknesses.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p47" pid="ySwnqK1XsUGb0JA1KtgtBw" hash="rApN7w">Parents have the sacred responsibility to teach their children the importance and value of prayer, and the responsibility to teach their children how pray. In many homes, even some of the best prayers are ignored and neglected. Prayer is sacred and Jesus said: “Trifle not with sacred things” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p48" pid="cKDeqxJhQ0a-DQRqu0NwnA" hash="DiOohw">Another blessing available through prayer is feeling the love of God in your heart and soul. We have in the scriptures this sacred promise: “Wherefore, my beloved brethren, pray unto the Father with all the energy of heart, that ye may be filled with this love, which he hath bestowed upon all who are true followers of his Son, Jesus Christ; that ye may become the sons of God; that when he shall appear we shall be like him, for we shall see him as he is; that we may have this hope; that we may be purified even as he is pure” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.48" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:48</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father.p49" pid="gA_rrc9Aa0un_PFkSB9ITQ" hash="xoi5jw">As the sons and daughters of a living God, a living Heavenly Father, we should stay close to him by humble prayer. We should stay close to him with a clean life, that our hearts may find peace in all of life’s sacred opportunities and blessings. I so pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3058.jpg" alt="The First Presidency as of 23 November 1918 " pid="MgBy6AwQPEqz6-GLkVMPBg" hash="XgE0HA" />
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1979/10/prayer-to-our-heavenly-father</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1979-general-conference/1979-10-4030-elder-bernard-p-brockbank-64k-eng.mp3" length="6651893" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 1979 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
