<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Bonnie D. Parkin</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Bonnie D. Parkin.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Bonnie%20D.%20Parkin.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Bonnie D. Parkin.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Mar 1995 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 1995 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Fat-Free Feasting</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/04/fat-free-feasting?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Is there a sweeter sight than mothers and daughters seated by each other? As I look across the lake of faces here in the Tabernacle and imagine the immense ocean of young women gathered in chapels around the world, I truly stand all amazed. For a far</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/fat-free-feasting" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95905_000_038" doc-version="2" hash="r3dV1g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/fat-free-feasting.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="58puwGtlw0Gt8pxtp12pWA" hash="INVKsQ">Fat-Free Feasting</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="-DaW2m5t4UW_itq3UaIm8A" hash="pZJd1w">Bonnie D. Parkin</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/fat-free-feasting.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/fat-free-feasting.p1" pid="BXSvWq0cqECTHX1eVkzV4w" hash="eWsCyA">Is there a sweeter sight than mothers and daughters seated by each other? As I look across the lake of faces here in the Tabernacle and imagine the immense ocean of young women gathered in chapels around the world, I truly stand all amazed. For a farm girl from Herriman, Utah, this is a humbling sight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/fat-free-feasting.p2" pid="0UPy2Jn4oEKtZJImlW5ACw" hash="1y3WXg">Sisters, I want to tell you a secret. I love to eat. Don’t you? When food has the perfect herbs, when it’s cooked just right, when it’s served like a work of sculpture, I’m in heaven. I can gain weight just reading a menu.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/fat-free-feasting.p3" pid="V2eOnw-pg0igB57wD-hsUg" hash="e2_MfA">And did you know that the Lord doesn’t expect us to diet? Trust me! Turn to 2 Nephi 9:51 [<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/9.51" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 9:51</a>]. Now look at the very last line. It says, “Let your soul delight in fatness.” But feast on what? Chocolate?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/fat-free-feasting.p4" pid="IpXTjD5030uPqNJMrAnQGw" hash="BH60_w">Look closely: Feast on his <span class="emphasis">word.</span> When was the last time you feasted on the word? Did you know that feasting could be so guilt-free?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/fat-free-feasting.p5" pid="B8isEo4W7kmSiYED3fIvTA" hash="PHjIPg">One of the joyous parts of my new calling is feasting with our presidency. We begin our meeting by studying the scriptures. President Hales starts us out by saying, “Does anyone have a scripture?” Someone always does. We look up cross-references, scour the Topical Guide, apply ideas to our own lives, and we think about you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/fat-free-feasting.p6" pid="iJCD9PH4D0-h9kWHM2SATg" hash="8JGtcw">This savoring the scriptures invites the Spirit. It’s a bonding time, when, in addition to a red pencil, we share our hearts, our understanding, our desires. We become more united, more able to serve you. Are you doing this kind of feasting in your Beehive, Mia Maid, Laurel, or Young Women presidency meetings? Try beginning those meetings with a thought from the scriptures. I think you’ll be surprised at the spirit scripture sharing will bring.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/fat-free-feasting.p7" pid="TmCPr-ZqrEilMVqP6-oQNg" hash="J4G1hw">I wasn’t very good at studying the scriptures as a young woman. I wish I would have! Not until I was living in Seattle, Washington, did a friend and I realize we were hungering to know what spiritual women in our ward knew. We wanted righteous children, “taught by their mothers” to be believing (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/56.47" class="scriptureRef">Alma 56:47</a>). And like a good dinner, the gospel becomes more exciting sharing it with a friend. I had Louise Nelson. We feasted together.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/fat-free-feasting.p8" pid="3bxt4jC2qUi0FnXENjwG2g" hash="xav_Nw">I remember sitting on an old worn couch reading scripture stories to my sons. As we studied, a power began to permeate our lives. I learned that Ruth left her family to join the believers, that Sariah reared children in the wilderness, that Esther risked her life to save others, and that, most important, Mary bore a son in a straw-filled stable and laid him in a manger. I learned that God worked miracles in the lives of others, and he could work wonders in mine too.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/fat-free-feasting.p9" pid="HKnc0IqpWE66E6_jm1-x6A" hash="fC_35w">I discovered the scriptures later than some. But I discovered them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/fat-free-feasting.p10" pid="Kt-4FtKN6U62pWXIz6GxHQ" hash="tonI6A">And now, like reading a good menu, I still <span class="emphasis">hunger</span> for their wise words. Why not gain some spiritual weight?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/fat-free-feasting.p11" pid="B54yfyxZXUK1VP-rvyIsFQ" hash="HpCXTw">It’s not always easy, and there are things I still don’t understand. But when I look past all that, craving the Lord’s companionship, the scriptures infuse my spirit with <span class="emphasis">the</span> Spirit. They will do the same for you. They will enlighten you, lift you, comfort you, strengthen you. They will envelop you in a warm blanket of heavenly love. How do I know? Because they do that for me. It is Heavenly Father’s promise to us. It is eating at the Lord’s table.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/fat-free-feasting.p12" pid="4Jy67tDJEUSL3l-g1evz-Q" hash="aGPajA">Beloved sisters, I invite you to experiment upon the word, to feast. As Jesus said: “Search the scriptures; … they are they which testify of me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.39" class="scriptureRef">John 5:39</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/fat-free-feasting.p13" pid="lUWKGIojyEuxrXeJPbhiqw" hash="rplbzw">I know that he lives, and that he loves us, and that his hand is outstretched still. May I serve you and him, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/04/fat-free-feasting</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/1995-general-young-women-meeting/1995-03-0020-bonnie-d-parkin-64k-eng.mp3" length="2326077" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 1995 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating Covenants</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants?lang=eng</link>
      <description>President Hinckley, as a leader of the young women of the Church, may I speak for them in saying we love, support, and sustain you as our prophet.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95905_000_032" doc-version="2" hash="UzuS2A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="LWEJQX_S-kuKs005rZ_6nQ" hash="gwNKKA">Celebrating Covenants</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="G35N_e8ajku2Rjf0hYZjsQ" hash="pZJd1w">Bonnie D. Parkin</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e54.jpg" alt="Bonnie D. Parkin" pid="LQZMMnOqrU2Tm2i2SP1u6A" hash="-vkzVg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p1" pid="sWQ-Qq4BIk-N2XqiWUYMHA" hash="NE1pzA">President Hinckley, as a leader of the young women of the Church, may I speak for them in saying we love, support, and sustain you as our prophet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p2" pid="vNTuGFDRRUKQnqlJMeXmaw" hash="ppGfxg">Dear brothers and sisters, standing here so soon after my call is much like being thrown into a mountain lake of glacial runoff—I am still getting used to the shock. You see, I am the mother of sons. Four sons. That’s right. Sons. You’d think that I would have been called to be the general den mother. Instead, my long desire for daughters has been filled twice: first, with four fantastic daughters-in-law, and second, with half a million young women around the world. Each one is unique and individually numbered and known in the eyes of our Heavenly Father. How do I know this? Because Heavenly Father has reached His tender hand from the heavens to hold and help <span class="emphasis">me,</span> Bonnie Parkin. Because the light of His Son has warmed my soul. Because I have made promises and covenants that have transformed my life as I’ve kept them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p3" pid="_O02wZvzB0mxekb27NHbcw" hash="Wxun-A">Have covenants renewed your life? Do you celebrate them?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p4" pid="FDxkVgWJiEi_Fj5fgEJIzg" hash="BObnNg">Recently we went to Pasadena, California, to the blessing of our first granddaughter, Jordan Emily. This was a unique experience for two reasons: first, my husband and I thought the Parkins were unable to have girls. And second, this blessing was the first official step in her mortality as a daughter of God. We feel so much joy as we anticipate the potential her life holds here.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p5" pid="ex7k5J4QDkiMGjnr-qcqdA" hash="cUetlQ">Jordan was fortunate. She was born to her parents who were sealed in the temple under the new and everlasting covenant. Provided her parents remain true to this agreement, Jordan will be beneficiary to those covenants by being in a home filled mostly with peace, love, protection, and understanding. Being born in the covenant is not the privilege of all members of the Church, but the blessings of the covenant will be made available to all who are worthy of them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p6" pid="-FeaXMuynkK2kHzPn1GhWg" hash="4nooYQ">We hope little Jordan’s life as a faithful Latter-day Saint will move from a baby receiving a priesthood blessing to a child of God receiving baptismal covenants, to a young woman keeping those first promises and preparing to be worthy and qualified to make and keep sacred covenants, to a woman entering into temple covenants, to a wife being sealed by the Holy Spirit of Promise, and finally to an exalted daughter returning home to our Heavenly Father’s open arms. This is our journey as Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p7" pid="1sowrfzmrUu-YeP0f7yLRg" hash="WwKXxQ">So often we talk of making and keeping covenants, but exactly what are they? At baptism, we demonstrate that we “are willing to bear one another’s burdens, that they may be light; … mourn with those that mourn; … comfort those that stand in need of comfort, and … stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things, and in all places” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.8-9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:8–9</a>). And that’s just the beginning! In the temple, we further covenant to be obedient, to sacrifice, to keep ourselves worthily pure, to contribute to the spreading of truth, to be chaste, to pray, to live the gospel, and to be forever faithful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p8" pid="udFxaCYnMkWd4Aouu7PBpw" hash="f2VV_w">Father in Heaven knows us as individuals. The covenants we make with Him are performed one on one. President Howard W. Hunter noted: “I have always been impressed that the Lord deals with us personally, individually. We do many things in groups in the Church, … but … the <span class="emphasis">most</span> important things are done individually. We bless babies one at a time, even if they are twins or triplets. We baptize and confirm children one at a time. We take the sacrament, are ordained to the priesthood, or move through the ordinances of the temple as individuals—as one person developing a [personal] relationship with our Father in Heaven. … <span class="emphasis">Heaven’s emphasis is on each individual, on every single person</span>” (“Eternal Investments,” address to CES religious educators, 10 Feb. 1989, p. 4; emphasis added). These individual commitments made directly with our Heavenly Father are things to celebrate. And to consecrate! Do you remember what happened when Alma invited his people to make these covenants? They celebrated! They “clapped their hands with joy.” I wonder why our covenants so often feel more like obligations than privileges.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p9" pid="kL1Uhh3SJEWQAxQ_0zeaPA" hash="rTqzpw">How did you feel the last time you partook of the sacrament? Did you ponder those covenants made in fonts and within temples? The sacrament enables us to renew our covenants. Thus, if we keep those covenants with honor and exactness, we can feel as fresh and as pure as we did when we were first baptized. We can feel as committed to a temple sealing as we did as a new bride or groom. We can feel as loved of God as our sweet little Jordan did when she received her name and blessing. Covenants keep us new.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p10" pid="EX2J3QxtQk2Hmmss8LHT0w" hash="HPRYkw">Do those covenants change the actions of our <span class="emphasis">daily</span> lives? They should. Even though it may be a struggle to keep them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p11" pid="sQ8_yhqX6UOS2HcziQE57g" hash="ZYP35w">We hear of Saints who hold on to their covenants even against great odds and in so doing find renewal and peace—not just in the life to come, but in <span class="emphasis">this</span> life. Because, just like covenant breaking, covenant keeping becomes habit forming.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p12" pid="hZMDPEqySUGEpauJPBdjFQ" hash="kAaadQ">We have all been victims of evil and unrighteousness, pain and suffering. I know a woman who was a victim. Her husband chose to be unfaithful to her. She suffered and she was in pain. It took many years, but life got better for her because she remained faithful to her covenants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p13" pid="IiXzRKkbGEKzKraPRZIYMg" hash="V8byQg">There are both stormy seas and calm waters in life. But as Ether tells us, “Hope cometh of faith, [and] maketh an anchor to the souls of men, which would make them sure and steadfast, always abounding in good works, being led to glorify God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.4" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:4</a>). Covenants anchor us to solid ground, which, amidst the storms, makes our promises <span class="emphasis">not only meaningful for eternity but vital for today.</span> Have your covenants moved you to sing the song of redeeming love?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p14" pid="-WQ-8SMcHUOjsB4FLfEGYg" hash="FGC6VQ">At a Relief Society meeting, a group of women were discussing how to teach youth to make and keep covenants. One woman who was struggling with a teenage daughter, listened as the women talked about faith, prayer, good example, and scriptures. Finally she blurted out, “I’ve tried all those things! And they’re not working!” Quietly she added, “Love is all that is working for us right now.” This good sister trusted that somehow her covenant to be charitable (even to her daughter) would make a difference. And it is.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p15" pid="5vJvtoOyh0yjBQF8uY18Qg" hash="r53I_w">Another young woman, Katie, was at camp. She felt angry and abandoned because of overwhelming family problems. Her testimony teetered, in serious jeopardy. But a concerned leader, in an effort to live up to his holy calling, wrote Katie a note saying, “I love you. I believe in you. You have a testimony, because I have heard you bear it in these ways.” Then he listed those ways. The note arrived at the right time; Katie was strengthened to live <span class="emphasis">her</span> covenants because someone else strived to live his.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p16" pid="SE1g-dvm6E-F3lVX4oIXwA" hash="ZXTF7w">Mark, a high school student in my ward, recently stood in fast meeting and talked about how he was finding strength to live his covenants. He summed it up with this formula succinctly and memorably. He said, “A scripture a day keeps Satan away.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p17" pid="22pcQnNfb0edEO263FG11w" hash="3uyTlA">What are the rewards of covenant keeping? Gentle-hearted King Benjamin said: “Because of the covenant which ye have made ye shall be called the children of Christ. … And under this head ye are made free” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/5.7-8" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 5:7–8</a>). And we will “be redeemed of God, and be numbered with those of the first resurrection, that [we] may have eternal life” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:9</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p18" pid="7pRLE0wVSEymD7fetbihTw" hash="41eqUg">Brothers and sisters, covenant keeping will help you recall the One with whom you’re yoked, and your burden will be lighter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p19" pid="OhjU4zWsW0mtW7klZ-2aCg" hash="_YjzCA">If you have slipped in your covenants, take heart! The Savior so wants us to fulfill our promises that He has provided an everlasting atonement. If your heart is not singing the song of redeeming love, return to your covenants. Celebrate them. Like our new granddaughter, you too can be pure. The renewal of your covenants will awaken you like cold glacial waters on a hot day. Then remember, millions of Church members all around the globe are daily keeping covenants against all odds. <span class="emphasis">You can too.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants.p20" pid="SclrAPb6P0iXBwhVpj-gOA" hash="6YBy0A">If you remember only one thing I say today, remember to <span class="emphasis">hold on to your covenants and celebrate them.</span> My covenants are an expression of my faith; they are why I stand before you today. Covenants help me focus on the big picture and not just the immediate. As my sons have served missions, I have seen covenants further the work of the Lord. Covenants help me make a difference in the lives of others. My covenants are not negotiable. They make the choice of righteousness easier. I humbly pray that our covenants might become a greater source of celebration and strength in our lives; that we may walk uprightly and steadfastly, that when we most need the Lord’s hand, it will be there waiting warmly. I treasure the covenants He has made with me and with all my heart hope to live faithful to them. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/04/celebrating-covenants</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1995-general-conference/1995-04-5030-bonnie-d-parkin-64k-eng.mp3" length="4967580" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 1995 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Anchor for Eternity—and Today</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Tonight we are privileged to be in the presence of a prophet, President Gordon B. Hinckley. His being here shows his love for each of us. Feeling his influence can help us gain a testimony of his divine calling. A personal testimony of the living pro</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_96905_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="Ez7AGA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="tV_jshlWJkaiuWW--I2WBA" hash="MG0wIQ">An Anchor for Eternity—</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="7Mm4mLLwCUed0wI-0w5XAw" hash="JiZMrA">and Today</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="xcdz0wTOb0WhTM_H2SOGgQ" hash="pZJd1w">Bonnie D. Parkin</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today.p1" pid="WN9SDjiejkeesgrAA4CBVA" hash="HHZ0Ww">Tonight we are privileged to be in the presence of a prophet, President Gordon B. Hinckley. His being here shows his love for each of us. Feeling his influence can help us gain a testimony of his divine calling. A personal testimony of the living prophet is not only an invaluable possession for eternity but an anchor to the truth today. This testimony of our prophet is a crucial thing in our Church, something upon which we place great emphasis: we talk of it often, hear it in testimony meeting, worry about it when asked by friends. But obtaining it is a responsibility that is ours alone—only the Holy Ghost will give it to us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today.p2" pid="WkGt7iy6oE2PCcMUsQqzmA" hash="HDJkQA">Do you have a testimony that President Hinckley is our Father’s living prophet? I want to help you understand how to gain this precious gift.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today.p3" pid="WquJyasZQ0GMeCMAB3j6XA" hash="nOa19w">As a young woman, I came to downtown Salt Lake one wintery day. I had parked in front of the Church Administration Building and was just putting a nickel in the meter when I noticed a man leaving the building. He wore a dark overcoat and a wool hat. But he had something more: a spirit that stirred my soul. I could not take my eyes off him, and as he descended the steps, I suddenly realized he was President David O. McKay. He said nothing as he passed me; he merely smiled gently and tipped his hat. The Spirit literally filled my being. I knew I had seen a prophet of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today.p4" pid="SiA4-1sfrEqq--NWdZs1vg" hash="Oo9ZMQ">Not everyone will have the opportunity to see a prophet face-to-face. Fortunately, that isn’t necessary. We can all receive the same witness I did on those steps long ago. More important than seeing a prophet is understanding the message he has for us. Applying that message is a sure way to gain a testimony of his holy calling.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today.p5" pid="oMaVXPKzrUi8tEj-w8yI8w" hash="ARBDvQ">Sister Diana Lacey, a leader in Farmington, New Mexico, was struggling to help young women view the Personal Progress program as something exciting and positive. She was finding no direction—until during general conference she heard President Hinckley tell the story of Caleb and Joshua, who, with 10 others, were sent to Canaan to report on its resources and people. Upon their return, the 10 reported all the negative things they saw, but Caleb and Joshua saw past those and spoke of the positive. Unfortunately, like today, the people chose to believe the doubters, and so only Caleb and Joshua were preserved to enter the promised land. President Hinckley added:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today.p6" pid="_ebK-3xlb0eo6_8JS49SNg" hash="xHpfqg">“We see some around us who are indifferent concerning the future of this work, who are apathetic, who speak of limitations, who express fears. … They have no vision concerning its future.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today.p7" pid="J4LOS7v6xk2ASvfPIqbq9Q" hash="9oH-bg">“Well was it said of old, ‘Where there is no vision, the people perish’ (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/29.18" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 29:18</a>)” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1995, 71).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today.p8" pid="Vgx7j-ZQFEadmdh3WTk0Rg" hash="bqvp4A">Sister Lacey was moved by this prophetic message and realized that Personal Progress is all about vision. She said: “I made a change and the results have astonished me. … By changing my attitude and the way I was approaching Personal Progress, it had an effect on the girls’ attitude. … The spirit of President Hinckley’s talk has been a blessing in my life.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today.p9" pid="To1a_Nyqo0ypLFN4ynv1AA" hash="jXuJKg">Do you see how Sister Lacey’s testimony was strengthened by following the prophet? She used the four steps Sister Virginia H. Pearce talked about: she listened to and read the words of President Hinckley, she identified a personal message, she put the message into action, and she noticed the changes in her life and feelings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today.p10" pid="iCoACxyLV0-nZORbnmbpnw" hash="ZlbBbA">I know a young woman who grew up in President Spencer W. Kimball’s ward. She had a fervent testimony of his calling, but while she was on her mission, President Kimball died. This young missionary worried about testifying of a prophet she didn’t know. One evening as she prayed for newly sustained President Ezra Taft Benson, she was immediately flooded with the warmth of the Spirit, and she gained a new testimony. “The Lord knew I needed to know,” she said, “and he knew I would share that witness in the conversion of others.” Sisters, this can happen for you!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today.p11" pid="sJbKzuF0LkOXXf-8RmyZOg" hash="vIQmdQ">President Hinckley has promised that every person has a right to have a personal witness (see <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1995, 5). I know that asking for this witness can be a little scary. We worry we just might not get an answer. Or, we know that if we get an answer, we will have to live accordingly!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today.p12" pid="s4U8J0mCDEicsDPtoSB53A" hash="Kihkfw">But think, what would a testimony of a living prophet do for you? How would it help you in your daily struggles? How would it change and bless your life?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today.p13" pid="OzzLWRXXikK8v_nCkQJ3tg" hash="HEeC7A">Only you and the Holy Ghost can answer these questions. If you do not now have a testimony of President Hinckley, rely on the testimonies of others as you gain your own. Pray for him, study his words, find a personal message, apply that message, and experience the good feelings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today.p14" pid="hT9WgnaiDk-8NxDEIiGKcQ" hash="2pamNA">Will you do it? Will you listen to his words now and find a message for your life? I hope and pray that you will. I bear testimony to you that I know we have a living prophet guiding us. May each of us go our way this night seeking or reaffirming our own divine testimony that God leads his Church through prophets and that Gordon B. Hinckley is his prophet now is my prayer in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1996/04/an-anchor-for-eternity-and-today</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/1996-general-young-women-meeting/1996-03-0060-bonnie-d-parkin-64k-eng.mp3" length="2707551" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 1996 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding Faith in Every Footstep</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1997/04/finding-faith-in-every-footstep?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Years from now your grandchildren will tell with amazement stories of your choices which changed their lives. You will be called their pioneers.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/finding-faith-in-every-footstep" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_97905_000_036" doc-version="2" hash="0T8uFQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/finding-faith-in-every-footstep.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="hbzV8aYDckeVwPfqTfBpDg" hash="frMDhw">Finding Faith in Every Footstep</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="s3SBycqEw0WgPQXIeFIzZg" hash="pZJd1w">Bonnie D. Parkin</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="XpgsUL2WHU2qlGj60vcWBA" hash="7vKo7Q">Years from now your grandchildren will tell with amazement stories of your choices which changed their lives. You will be called their pioneers.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/finding-faith-in-every-footstep.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e54.jpg" alt="Bonnie D. Parkin" pid="mcUXeFTXlUiMdh4gDXlxng" hash="-vkzVg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/finding-faith-in-every-footstep.p1" pid="xkxFsEq0SEe2FHj19OXyUQ" hash="vA0wHA">Anna Matilda Anderson was a young girl who lived in Sweden in the 1880s. When she and her family joined the Church, they were ridiculed for their beliefs. Anna’s mother decided they should move to America and join the Saints in Utah. Anna was 11 years old when she and her sister, Ida, were sent ahead to earn money and bring the rest of the family. They sailed to the United States, then traveled by train to Ogden, Utah, where Ida left by covered wagon to work for her sponsors in Idaho. Anna was completely alone on that train as it continued to Salt Lake City. She spoke no English and knew no one. Can you imagine the loneliness and terror of her ride?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/finding-faith-in-every-footstep.p2" pid="mXrC8ks06Uyb0h747cczjg" hash="PsPosA">The train pulled into the darkened Rio Grande station just before midnight. The relative who was to meet Anna was not there. Anna stood watching with dread as the station slowly emptied. Finally, she was alone with a German family who also had no one to meet them. The darkness was thick and threatening, closing in around her. She later recalled: “I started to cry and thought about the last thing my mother told me: ‘If you come to a place where you can’t understand what the people are saying, don’t forget to pray to your Father in Heaven because <span class="emphasis">He</span> can understand you.’” Anna knelt by her suitcase and pleaded with all her might for heavenly help. Haven’t we all said prayers like that?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/finding-faith-in-every-footstep.p3" pid="8zxOIUBt4Ue4HU-Gv00XUg" hash="-EwkXA">The German family motioned for Anna to follow them. Having no other choice, she walked behind them, crying. Arriving at Temple Square, they heard rapid footsteps. A woman was hurrying toward them, studying each person she passed. She looked at the German family, then pressed on. Anna caught the woman’s searching gaze. The woman stopped, unbelieving. She recognized the young girl! And with a shock, Anna recognized the woman. She was her Sunday School teacher who had left Sweden a year earlier! Pulling Anna tightly into her arms, the teacher wiped away her frightened tears. She told Anna: “I was awakened over and over again. … Images of the arriving immigrants raced through my mind. I could not go back to sleep. I was prompted to come to the temple to see if there was anyone I knew here” (journal of Anna Matilda Anderson, in author’s possession).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/finding-faith-in-every-footstep.p4" pid="_aPuvLlb-0OuTOgCSU0w4w" hash="xSoRFg">Can you believe it? A Sunday School teacher sent in a pitch-black night like an angel of light! “So you see,” Anna remembered, “my Heavenly Father <span class="emphasis">more</span> than answered my prayers. I only asked for someone who could understand me, and He sent someone I <span class="emphasis">knew.”</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/finding-faith-in-every-footstep.p5" pid="xp2lI71iS06TkBzIMmIqPw" hash="5mazag">Years later, Anna explained how she took that amazing journey alone: Her faith in the Lord assured her that something better was waiting just ahead. This gave her the courage to cross an ocean without her mother, pray to her Father in Heaven when she was lost, and walk toward the safe haven of the temple. Anna moved through the unknown and left a path for others to follow. One of those who followed Anna’s faith-filled footsteps was my husband. You see, Anna was his grandmother.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/finding-faith-in-every-footstep.p6" pid="Atb_KKpql0Wvg-pVeAO4mg" hash="CaiaeA">What Anna did must have been terribly frightening. Even though she probably didn’t know it, she was bravely blazing a trail for others to come behind. Anna was a pioneer. A pioneer stands up for what is right, dares to share the gospel in the face of opposition, and testifies of Christ through her actions. Just like Anna.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/finding-faith-in-every-footstep.p7" pid="hZiYNI0hZEO3oJPYLObkng" hash="_dlxGA">Do you see yourself in Anna’s story? Perhaps in your enthusiasm for the gospel or maybe in your fear of the unknown. We are all required to make journeys of faith. That is the gospel plan. Our path may not be crossing an ocean or walking alone from an empty train station. But whatever it is, it will demand faith in every footstep. Years from now your grandchildren will tell with amazement stories of your choices which changed their lives. <span class="emphasis">You</span> will be called <span class="emphasis">their</span> pioneers. Have you ever thought that as you step into the unknown like Anna, you are showing others the way? Let me share with you some details from the lives of other young women that illuminate the early pioneer experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/finding-faith-in-every-footstep.p8" pid="tj19IsPaeU-PAFMCiRcSjQ" hash="VCBtSw">Ruth May Fox said: “When the time came for our departure from England, I was in seventh heaven. … [We] left our home under cover of darkness to avoid the curiosity of neighbors. Could anything be more thrilling?” (in Susan Arrington Madsen, <span class="emphasis">I Walked to Zion: True Stories of Young Pioneers on the Mormon Trail</span> [1994], 30). The pioneer spirit is full of adventure!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/finding-faith-in-every-footstep.p9" pid="bBXIzR2ca0-VQfCRvVHSww" hash="z_bbJQ">Margaret Gay Judd Clawson wrote: “There were several very nice young men in our company. Especially one. He used to say such lovely things to me—told me that I was beautiful and intelligent, and even went so far as to say that I was amiable, something I had never been accused of before” (in <span class="emphasis">I Walked to Zion,</span> 144). Has anyone ever accused you of being agreeable or friendly? What a compliment!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/finding-faith-in-every-footstep.p10" pid="omaZGPtQYUWeL2Nx7i5u8A" hash="xLEl8w">Margaret McNeil Ballard recalled: “I walked every step of the way across the plains and drove a cow, and a large part of the way I carried my brother, James, on my back” (in <span class="emphasis">I Walked to Zion,</span> 126). Many of you also shoulder responsibilities for your siblings with love and strength.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/finding-faith-in-every-footstep.p11" pid="_ku9geWjpkynjSrgVsWXVA" hash="yiwO1g">How about this perspective from Susan Noble Grant: “Oh, children, you do not know how happy we were, even during these severe days of hardest trials! As young as I was, I knew the gospel had been restored. More than once I had heard Joseph Smith declare that our Heavenly Father and his Son Jesus, the resurrected Savior, had come and talked with him. … This testimony has never left me. And when I am gone, I want you to tell this to your children and grandchildren” (in <span class="emphasis">I Walked to Zion,</span> 98). What a legacy! Yet we too have heard a prophet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/finding-faith-in-every-footstep.p12" pid="UBw__NU3PEKc7uWjHCGvPA" hash="kr4PIA">Do these stories sound so different from what we write in our journals today? How many of us could do what Anna did? I believe all of us. Why? We show faith by the courageous choices we make each day. President Harold B. Lee gave some marvelous advice for modern pioneers: “Walk to the edge of the light, and perhaps a few steps into the darkness, and you will find that the light will appear and move ahead of you” (as quoted by Boyd K. Packer, in Lucile C. Tate, <span class="emphasis">Boyd K. Packer: A Watchman on the Tower</span> [1995], 138). We must walk by faith. That means stepping into the dark unknowns because we believe that Heavenly Father is awaiting us, like Anna’s Sunday School teacher, with open arms.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/finding-faith-in-every-footstep.p13" pid="tmi4pGBxnEG-KfCnwWw-bQ" hash="eY9Hkg">Our prayer tonight is that every one of us will gain strength from the pioneering spirit. Look in the mirror tonight. You’ll see someone unique, strong, and courageous. A pioneer. Hold on to that thought. Like Anna and thousands of others, you are going before, bravely showing loved ones the way to follow. That we will always find faith in every footstep is my prayer, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1997/04/finding-faith-in-every-footstep</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/1997-general-young-women-meeting/1997-03-0010-bonnie-d-parkin-64k-eng.mp3" length="3788696" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 1997 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feel the Love of the Lord</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2002/04/feel-the-love-of-the-lord?lang=eng</link>
      <description>If I could have one thing happen for every woman in this Church, it would be that they would feel the love of the Lord in their lives.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/feel-the-love-of-the-lord" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029598_000_033" doc-version="2" hash="wWf0Vg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/feel-the-love-of-the-lord.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="5hk0r8MzjkmN2P23GbDFqA" hash="iExagw">Feel the Love of the Lord</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="2K41-5-cP0KN1inO_G9BrA" hash="pZJd1w">Bonnie D. Parkin</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="zeFi7TQ4BUuYs4UveV5WoA" hash="Dl0A_A">If I could have one thing happen for every woman in this Church, it would be that they would feel the love of the Lord in their lives.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/feel-the-love-of-the-lord.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-101.jpg" alt="Bonnie D. Parkin" pid="wUZiuNpQrE6tXjuKgtAuKg" hash="FbtaIA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/feel-the-love-of-the-lord.p1" pid="Smrz2KJ25EGp-GDiB8fl8Q" hash="IWYqZg">Brothers and sisters, there is a saying: “Welcome the opportunity that takes you beyond your ordinary self if you would grow.” And I’m sure I’m going to grow. May I express our thanks to Sister Smoot, Sister Dew, and Sister Jensen for the great service they’ve given to all of us as members of the Church. I express my gratitude to my counselors, Kathy and Anne, for their willingness to serve. They are women of faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/feel-the-love-of-the-lord.p2" pid="z5Dil6hItEGH0NHJLtisqA" hash="vJ8r0Q">I am so grateful this day for my mother and father, for the teachings they gave me, for their love, for teaching me to work. I do know how to work. I am grateful for my husband. Jim is a wonderful companion. I love him, and I’m grateful for his support. He’s a man of integrity. I’m grateful for sons and for their wives, who have helped them become better men. I’m grateful for grandchildren. The other evening we drove down to the home of one of our sons to tell him about this calling. They had their children tucked in bed. I said to Brett and Angie, “I’ve been called to be the general Relief Society president.” And Brett said, “You? The president of the Relief Society for the whole Church?” Aren’t your children wonderful? He said what I have been feeling for the past few weeks.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/feel-the-love-of-the-lord.p3" pid="fVyR5Sp3Tk-oI2ZZ8ng-JQ" hash="56wC4w">Yesterday when we arrived home, I had a fax from our son David and his wife, Jennifer, in Belgium. David said, “Mother, I know you can do it. You may not remember, but you used to have a scripture on the fridge that said, ‘As for me and my house, we will serve the Lord’ (<a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/24.15" class="scriptureRef">Josh. 24:15</a>).” He said, “I was in and out of the fridge a lot, and I knew that you and Dad meant that.” I’m so grateful for our children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/feel-the-love-of-the-lord.p4" pid="eWWnm694m0-GNXgUlH4wxA" hash="uIQBog">I’m grateful to the women of the Church who have mentored me, who have loved me, who have taught me, who have believed in me. I’m grateful for the missionaries in the England London South Mission, for their goodness, for the way they keep their covenants. I’m grateful for the British Saints who loved me and helped me be part of that great land.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/feel-the-love-of-the-lord.p5" pid="s79-ZKR3gkacpVbjvCDywg" hash="BI7PPA">Now, brothers and sisters, I do not know why I was called, but I do know that I was called. I pledge to you my love, my support, and I ask that you be patient as I learn.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/feel-the-love-of-the-lord.p6" pid="x4AZyESm6E2JjPjeEmfRdw" hash="yz5K4A">I invite the young adult women of the Church, wherever you are, to look at Relief Society and know that you are needed there, that we love you, that together we can have a grand time. Please come and be with us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/feel-the-love-of-the-lord.p7" pid="Ewxyf91iWUWPV0zg6ZB6Zg" hash="WRWfNg">As Wallace Stegner wrote of the Mormons, “Their women were incredible.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> And they are today! I know that the Lord loves the women of the Church. If I could have one thing happen for every woman in this Church, it would be that they would feel the love of the Lord in their lives daily. I have felt the love of the Lord in my life, and I am so thankful for that. I’m thankful for the peace that I have felt.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/feel-the-love-of-the-lord.p8" pid="C1tqj00HFEq-bvdagLMKqA" hash="ybh9LA">I testify of my Savior Jesus Christ. I know He lives. I have felt His love; I have felt His forgiveness. I think of a sister missionary as she departed the mission. In her final testimony she said, “I came on a mission to let Heavenly Father know I loved Him, to express appreciation to Him, and to pay Him back,” and she said, “I’m leaving more in His debt than I ever was before I came.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/feel-the-love-of-the-lord.p9" pid="w0seobHgOE2JkbSP5R3JFg" hash="DI4KCw">I give testimony of the power of a prophet of God, President Gordon B. Hinckley, and I’m thankful for him and for his love and for all prophets who have had confidence in me. I testify of these things in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2002/04/feel-the-love-of-the-lord</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2002-general-conference/2002-04-5050-bonnie-d-parkin-64k-eng.mp3" length="2505789" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2002 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With Holiness of Heart</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Every time we reach out with love, patience, kindness, generosity, we honor our covenants by saying, “Here am I; send me.”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029898_000_035" doc-version="2" hash="usWotQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="7OQR0bOQsUSlRn4HHqm-UQ" hash="btzKRA">With Holiness of Heart</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="KBL3I9DSLUCsre3ADiuSYw" hash="pZJd1w">Bonnie D. Parkin</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="5DtN04MdYEuuYRNmLHndaw" hash="Jcz-NQ">Every time we reach out with love, patience, kindness, generosity, we honor our covenants by saying, “Here am I; send me.”</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-101.jpg" alt="Bonnie D. Parkin" pid="6VBwpBOKdE29_rZm_ReY5A" hash="FbtaIA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p1" pid="sMQnE9lUF0yUVAwIpxWmrQ" hash="1Pubxw">Although our numbers are much greater than those Relief Society sisters in Nauvoo, the spirit of our gathering is the same. Like us, they lifted, nurtured, and inspired each other; they prayed for each other; they consecrated all that they had to the kingdom. President Hinckley has described us as “a vast reservoir of faith and good works, … an anchor of devotion and loyalty and accomplishment.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> How remarkable that whether we are in the Conference Center or in a chapel in Mexico, or in a branch in Lithuania, we are sisters in Zion with a great work to do. And together, led by a prophet of God, we will do it! I hope you feel the love I have for you—love that is shared by my counselors, who are a rich blessing to me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p2" pid="X6HgtnS4LEO5aigZlBh4tw" hash="bShoog">To say I was overwhelmed when President Hinckley called me to serve as Relief Society general president is a huge understatement! Can’t you relate? But, voice trembling, I responded, “Here am I; send me.” After a Jewish friend learned what my calling entailed, she looked at me like I was crazy and asked, “Bonnie, why would you do that?” (At times like these, I often ask myself the same thing!) But there is only one reason I did it: I have made covenants with the Lord, and I know what that requires. Plus, I knew that you and I would serve together and that my willingness was on behalf of all of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p3" pid="8rgKnLy2j0aeSc5yEQXfbw" hash="sEdDUw">For centuries, righteous women have been stepping forward to join the cause of Christ. Many of you have only recently been baptized; your covenants are fresh in your hearts, your sacrifices still tender. As I think about you, I am reminded of Priscilla Staines from Wiltshire, England. Nineteen-year-old Priscilla joined the Church in 1843. Alone. She had to steal away in the night to be baptized, because of the persecutions of her neighbors and the displeasure of her family. She wrote: “We waited until midnight … and then repaired to a stream of water a quarter of a mile away. Here we found the water … frozen over, and the elder had to chop a hole in the ice large enough for the purpose of baptism. … None but God and his angels, and the few witnesses who stood on the bank with us, heard my covenant; but in the solemnity of that midnight hour it seemed as though all nature were listening, and the recording angel writing our words in the book of the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p4" pid="qjQKGQG6wESjjEolRJe7vQ" hash="Ul_O9g">Her words “None but God and his angels … heard my covenant” touch my soul, for like Priscilla—no matter our age, our gospel knowledge, our time in the Church—we are all women of covenant. That is a phrase we often hear in the Church, but what does it mean? How do covenants define who we are and how we live?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p5" pid="2-Iq1ZjNSEKcNnsdgxcyfQ" hash="HvQwMQ">Covenants—or binding promises between us and Heavenly Father—are essential for our eternal progression. Step-by-step, He tutors us to become like Him by enlisting us in His work. At baptism we covenant to love Him with all our hearts and love our sisters and brothers as ourselves. In the temple we further covenant to be obedient, selfless, faithful, honorable, charitable. We covenant to make sacrifices and consecrate all that we have. Forged through priesthood authority, our kept covenants bring blessings to fill our cups to overflowing. How often do you reflect that your covenants reach beyond mortality and connect you to the Divine? Making covenants is the expression of a willing heart; keeping covenants, the expression of a faithful heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p6" pid="qdmGcx9JBEiQ5gNm5QY5ZA" hash="REiOBQ">Sounds so simple on paper, doesn’t it? Of course, the doing is where we prove who we really are. Thus, every time we reach out with love, patience, kindness, generosity, we honor our covenants by saying, “Here am I; send me.” Usually we speak these words softly, unaccompanied by brass bands.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p7" pid="tTK70rU5dkaSVTKdDFfnrA" hash="xDSg6w">When have someone else’s covenants with the Lord blessed <span class="emphasis">your</span> life, brought you peace, nurtured your soul? When my husband and I were missionaries in England, we saw many elders and sisters whose lives were directly influenced by the covenants of worthy women. I was so thankful for mothers, sisters, aunts, teachers—like so many of you—whose honored covenants extended blessings to others by the way they taught those future missionaries.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p8" pid="yhLfU41SiEquuEcFyaFc3Q" hash="iaa-MA">Covenants not only coax us out of comfort zones and into new growth but lead others to do the same. Jesus said, “The works which ye have seen me do that shall ye also do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> His covenant keeping encourages ours.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p9" pid="FumDC9Kp2k2eMB1S6cEYpg" hash="DiC_iw">Covenants save us from needless suffering. For example, when we obey the prophet’s guidance, we are keeping a covenant. He has counseled us to avoid debt, maintain a food supply, and become self-reliant. Living within our means blesses us beyond that obedience. It teaches us gratitude, restraint, unselfishness; it brings peace from financial pressures and protection from materialism’s greed. Keeping our lamps filled means that unforeseen circumstances do not hinder opportunities to declare with devotion, “Here am I; send me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p10" pid="PpkcUrVHb0CLgT0uLkWA7A" hash="rJO6ng">Covenants renewed invigorate and refresh a weary soul. Each Sunday when we partake of the sacrament, what happens in our hearts when we hear those words to “always remember him”?<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Do we improve the following week by refocusing on what matters most? Yes, we face hard things; yes, making changes is strenuous. But have you ever wondered how our sisters survived being driven from Nauvoo, many walking the entire trek? When their feet were tired, they were carried by their covenants! What else could grant such spiritual and physical fortitude?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p11" pid="3t7l-hCheEGcyvD4BBAAWg" hash="LvZCog">Covenants also protect us from being “tossed to and fro, and carried about with every wind of doctrine, by the sleight of men, and cunning craftiness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Women of covenant stand firm when evil is called good and good is called evil. Whether it be in the college classroom, around the water cooler, or watching TV’s latest “experts,” remembering our covenants keeps us from being led astray.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p12" pid="CIzoN7NdckOfH7L34psNsw" hash="hYUv2g">Covenants can keep us and those we love spiritually safe and spiritually prepared by putting first things first. For instance, when it comes to families, we cannot afford indifference and distraction. Childhood is a vanishing wonder; so few have had the sunny days I knew growing up on a farm. President Hinckley has said: “Our problems, almost every one, arise out of the homes of the people. … If there is to be a change, … it must begin in the home. It is here that truth is learned, that integrity is cultivated, that self-discipline is instilled, and that love is nurtured.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p13" pid="RxfpS7-czUO5i-TvFtq19g" hash="8dNmhA">Sisters, the Lord needs women who will teach children to work and learn and serve and believe. Whether they are our own or another’s, we must stand up and state, “Here am I; send me to watch over your little ones, to put them first, to guide and protect them from evil, to love them.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p14" pid="5gXkzj5eZUOEamNLLnaIDw" hash="9cp9ew">Sometimes we are faced with keeping our covenants when there seems to be no logical reason to do so. I listened to a single sister tell of her experience of “coming to trust the Lord completely.” Her life had not worked out as she had expected. Sound familiar? This period of soul-searching was marked by changing jobs, new financial pressures, tugs from worldly philosophies. Now listen to what she did. She sat down with other sisters in her ward and found that they too were searching to find the peace the gospel brings. She asked for a priesthood blessing. She valiantly carried forward in her calling. She studied and tried to more fully commit her love, appreciation, and conviction to Jesus. She prayed. “I cried to the Lord,” she said, “and told Him I would do whatever He would ask of me.” She did all this despite those difficulties. And do you know what happened? No, her eternal companion did not appear on her doorstep. But peace made its way into her heart, and life got better.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p15" pid="Dz640H0SiECYHNZgHmoMow" hash="CQHtsQ">Sisters, we keep our covenants when we share our life’s wisdom to encourage another, when we visit teach with genuine compassion, when we help a younger sister know that her fresh perspective will bless us in Relief Society. We can do that!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p16" pid="s5FyP94Rr06fvY33AmZfJA" hash="z0dzIQ">When young Priscilla, our British convert of 1843, crossed the Atlantic, she was befriended by a woman the age of her mother. This older sister also felt the fire of covenants she had made. When they docked at the wharf in Nauvoo, she was by Priscilla’s side. Together, bold and believing, they joined with the Saints of God.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p17" pid="VJiPaVyyVE-n2TpWA2HfiQ" hash="pnsSzg">The spiritual integrity to keep our covenants comes from consistency in scripture study, prayer, service, and sacrifice. Such simple steps nurture our souls so we can say, “Send me to help a sister and her newborn; send me to tutor a struggling student; send me to love an outsider. Send me where you need me, when you need me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p18" pid="OGfTsjRVJkKNdHP1TALLmw" hash="UQHYuw">The Lord has called us to do all that we do with “holiness of heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> And holiness is a product of covenant living. I love the words of this hymn and the way they make me feel:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="zYx_Gs4DVkSEndjT5wYZFA" hash="SrQ3IA">
            <span class="emphasis">More holiness give me,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="18De5Wn4xkKK5MYmSwT0vw" hash="WvvJIg">
            <span class="emphasis">More strivings within,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="sg1wDmH9x0Of8zsxeSZohQ" hash="MbnclQ">
            <span class="emphasis">More patience in suff’ring,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="9gUZHdR_RUW5mlfaCPdWUw" hash="wwGoLg">
            <span class="emphasis">More sorrow for sin,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="ntXwVNypSU-MoP0pCEvhUg" hash="lnxjqg">
            <span class="emphasis">More faith in my Savior,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="FsA1lilPEE6tFiTKWDUDUg" hash="yvarNA">
            <span class="emphasis">More sense of his care,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="93cmqY2US0qXX6643bvdPA" hash="aKUPkg">
            <span class="emphasis">More joy in his service,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="qTbZRxZGWEGXfbBwjWwPeA" hash="bNGAaA">
            <span class="emphasis">More purpose in prayer.</span>
            <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p19" pid="qADO_Lm-6kifn_C80UPxEA" hash="of5uQQ">Holiness prompts the words “Here am I; send me.” When Priscilla Staines made her midnight covenant in those icy waters, she stepped forward into a new life, clothes nearly frozen yet heart warmed with joy. “There was no turning back,” she said. “I … set out for the reward of everlasting life, trusting in God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p20" pid="qZ6gxc7Q4k22Vik_SohIgQ" hash="0v2Rwg">President Hinckley, with the Relief Society sisters around the world, I commit to you that we stand united as women of covenant and hearken to your voice. In a host of different languages, hear the words of each Relief Society sister as we say, “Here am I; send me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart.p21" pid="OjQNie-dHEa0bWyc56X65g" hash="Wh8gxA">May our individual covenants that bind us to our loving Heavenly Father guide us, protect us, sanctify us, and allow us to do likewise for all His children, I so pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2002/10/with-holiness-of-heart</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2002-general-relief-society-meeting/2002-09-0010-bonnie-d-parkin-64k-eng.mp3" length="12251702" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2002 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choosing Charity: That Good Part</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I invite you to not only love each other more but love each other better.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030835_000_035" doc-version="2" hash="0daXGA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="8MRqIDUHwUOcengj_vVyJw" hash="007lsQ">Choosing Charity:</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="HuE26x_hN0-H9HEMyTgOrQ" hash="XkXjzw">That Good Part</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="XsCf26NeC0avbBXNeUSCvg" hash="pZJd1w">Bonnie D. Parkin</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="-6fBCI7Vw0WABIx_1txfOQ" hash="nAiCBQ">I invite you to not only love each other more but love each other better.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-101.jpg" alt="Bonnie D. Parkin" pid="ECLbjmX0Z0O0gAjdcoWDZQ" hash="FbtaIA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p1" pid="rOfDoZKrOEmugQo1NZVfDg" hash="jEm6fQ">It’s wonderful to be together as Relief Society sisters, covenant women in the Lord’s restored gospel. Each of you—no matter your age, stage of life, or circumstance—is needed, valued, and loved in Relief Society. Thank you for who you are; thank you for all that you do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p2" pid="frhv8mVq20KO1qjf2IpSSA" hash="cRFnQA">In my office hangs a wonderful painting depicting Jesus with Mary and Martha.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Every day as I am greeted by this piece, I reflect on our challenges as women. Sister Hughes, Sister Pingree, and I felt inspired to use the account of Mary and Martha as the theme for our meeting. The Lord taught, one thing is needful: choose that good part.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> That is what we are going to talk about tonight, choosing that good part.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p3" pid="7HQ3NvDqFUat24Ioy_DoOg" hash="YerzAQ">Martha lived in the small village of Bethany, where she “received [Jesus] into her house. And she had a sister called Mary, which <span class="emphasis">also</span> sat at Jesus’ feet and heard his word.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span><span class="emphasis">Both</span> women loved the Lord. And “Jesus loved Martha, and [Mary].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> In fact, their relationship breached convention, for at that time women were not usually able to discuss the gospel with men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p4" pid="NIuHNBAK-U6_aDvFyvN67g" hash="88OuFw">On one occasion Martha was making dinner and, as the scripture says, “was cumbered about much serving.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> In other words, she was stressed out!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p5" pid="JNQdAeqC30e5KMWxPyIbIQ" hash="-FzzSQ">Mary, on the other hand, “sat at Jesus’ feet, and heard his word,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> while Martha became increasingly upset that no one was helping her. Does that sound familiar? Do you think she was thinking, “Why is Mary sitting there while I’m sweating over this stove?” So Martha turned to Jesus and said, “Lord, dost thou not care that my sister hath left me to serve alone? bid her therefore that she help me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p6" pid="FdW9DS0Ub0SuYpr0g9DRpg" hash="a4EEJg">The Lord’s gentle invitation to Martha may have surprised her. “Martha, Martha, thou art careful and troubled about many things: But one thing is needful: and Mary hath chosen that good part, which shall not be taken away from her.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p7" pid="nqqqgDsvnk6aKh656Caf2A" hash="Lpi-8w">The Savior’s response strikingly clarified what mattered most. On that evening in Martha’s home, the good part was not in the kitchen; it was at the Lord’s feet. Dinner could wait.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p8" pid="sjwDTmoPjkaACo1hWBsWqA" hash="RwgD1g">Like Mary, I hunger to feast at the Savior’s feet, while, like Martha, I need to somehow find the laundry room floor, empty my in-box, and serve my husband something other than cold pizza. I have 15 grandchildren whose tender little spirits and daily challenges I want to better understand, yet I also have a slightly demanding Church calling! I don’t have lots of time. Like all of you, I have to choose. We all are trying to choose the good part which cannot be taken from us, to balance the spiritual and the temporal in our lives. Wouldn’t it be easy if we were choosing between visiting teaching or robbing a bank? Instead, our choices are often more subtle. We must choose between many worthy options.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p9" pid="Dm_aFrGgLkGgSiqlMAg8gg" hash="ut1dGg">Mary and Martha are you and me; they are every sister in Relief Society. These two loved the Lord and wanted to show that love. On this occasion, it seems to me that Mary expressed her love by hearing His word, while Martha expressed hers by serving Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p10" pid="QZ5zo9LEgEWSdL57Cuwkaw" hash="TDGAKw">Martha thought she was doing right and that her sister should be helping her.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p11" pid="eMHu4zkfR0SbTyNN7AiZ9g" hash="0znK5w">I don’t believe the Lord was saying there are Marthas and there are Marys. Jesus did not dismiss Martha’s concern, but instead redirected her focus by saying choose “that good part.” And what is that? The prophet Lehi taught that we “should look to the great Mediator, and hearken unto his great commandments; and be faithful unto his words, and choose eternal life, according to the will of his Holy Spirit.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p12" pid="uU47rr6640mn-R1ZvFtPCA" hash="2GnqLQ">The one thing that is needful is to choose eternal life. We choose daily. As we seek, listen, and follow the Lord, we are encircled in the arms of His love—a love that is pure.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p13" pid="ycpKG0GEn0WAb06xWwWuKA" hash="rsVcFA">Mormon teaches us that “charity is the pure love of Christ, and it endureth forever.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> The pure love of Christ. Let’s look at that. What does this phrase mean? We find part of the answer in Joshua: “Take diligent heed … to love the Lord your God … and to <span class="emphasis">serve him with all your heart and with all your soul.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> Charity is <span class="emphasis">our</span> love for the Lord, shown through our acts of service, patience, compassion, and understanding for one another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p14" pid="3jLHvPizokuIQJEBjRqoug" hash="s_Y09w">Additional insight into the pure love of Christ is found in Ether: “[Jesus has] loved the world, even unto the laying down of [His] life for the world, that [He might] take it again to prepare a place for the children of men. And now I know that <span class="emphasis">this love which [He has] for the children of men is charity.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Charity is <span class="emphasis">also</span> the <span class="emphasis">Lord’s</span> love for us, shown through His acts of service, patience, compassion, and understanding.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p15" pid="fEvakmZQnkOlc2qvT784pw" hash="5-T3bw">The “pure love of Christ”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> refers not only to <span class="emphasis">our</span> love for the Savior but to <span class="emphasis">His</span> love for each of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p16" pid="Dty9r0Lm1kyWEbsj6zuZ2w" hash="ShB0xg">The story of Mary and Martha also illustrates how the gift of charity can be diminished. Within Martha’s request for assistance was an unspoken but clear judgment: “I am right; she is wrong.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p17" pid="lEuEmuvUdkK934a6Ul6eAQ" hash="mFpImA">Do we judge one another? Do we criticize each other for individual choices, thinking we know better, when in fact we rarely understand another’s unique circumstance or individual inspiration? Have we ever said, “She works outside the home.” Or, “Her son didn’t serve a mission.” Or, “She’s too old for a calling.” Or, “She can’t—she’s single.” Such judgments, and so many others like them, rob us of the good part, that pure love of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p18" pid="ES3EeTLn5kSMWqQ0NXwCRg" hash="4yKFcw">We also lose sight of that good part when we compare ourselves to others. Her hair is cuter, my legs are fatter, her children are more talented, or her garden’s more productive—sisters, you know the drill. We just can’t do that. We cannot allow ourselves to feel inadequate by focusing on who we <span class="emphasis">aren’t</span> instead of on who we are! We are <span class="emphasis">all</span> sisters in Relief Society. We simply cannot criticize, gossip, or judge <span class="emphasis">and</span> keep the pure love of Christ. Can’t you hear the Lord’s sweet injunction: “Martha, Martha … ?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p19" pid="CYcD3xOJlEOSdosOQARu7w" hash="PzMfUA">Elder Marvin J. Ashton beautifully observed: “Perhaps the greatest charity comes when we are kind to each other, when we don’t judge or categorize someone else, when we simply give each other the benefit of the doubt or remain quiet. Charity is accepting someone’s differences, weaknesses, and shortcomings; having patience with someone who has let us down; or resisting the impulse to become offended when someone doesn’t handle something the way we might have hoped. Charity is refusing to take advantage of another’s weakness and being willing to forgive someone who has hurt us. Charity is expecting the best of each other.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p20" pid="P_trZ-KxsEG8wkOOYB67xQ" hash="RMoDCA">In exercising charity, we come to know a sister’s heart. When we know a sister’s heart, we are different. We won’t judge her. We will simply love her. I invite you to not only love each other more but love each other <span class="emphasis">better.</span> As we do this we will come to know with a surety that “charity never faileth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p21" pid="QgfvTYavwEawcDY88Nc_Rw" hash="oQ7wLA">As seemed the case with Martha, one of the first things to go when I become cumbered about and troubled is my charitable attitude. Is this true for you?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p22" pid="gbvf9x4jskme_drXIlNxVA" hash="EucoMw">I’ve learned that the best way to reclaim charity is to <span class="emphasis">un</span>cumber myself and simply love and serve the Lord. How do we do that? We start each day kneeling in prayer to our Father in Heaven, we hear His words through daily scripture study, and we follow the guidance we receive. We put Christ first, restoring charity’s circular love. “We love him, because he first loved us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> This is the reciprocating cycle of charity. Sisters, “charity never faileth.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p23" pid="_t3R39siDE-2OdnkW218VQ" hash="5aSUiQ">When I received this calling, I desired with all my heart to have enough charity to genuinely love <span class="emphasis">every single sister</span> in the Church. I desired that my increased love would help you feel the love of the Lord in your life. I prayed to my Heavenly Father “with all the energy of [my] heart, [to be] filled with this love, which he hath bestowed upon <span class="emphasis">all</span> who are true followers of his Son, Jesus Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p24" pid="f2iDXW8oH0iQiRioB68F4w" hash="70-G9g">Last December in Sunday School, our teacher suggested that at tithing settlement time we give the Lord a private accounting of our study and application of a gospel principle. I had the overwhelming feeling that my study should focus on charity. This prompting was confirmed in sacrament meeting, and I knew I had received direction from the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p25" pid="noh8i2eiOE20w9-V2cVPcg" hash="hUiNnw">In associating with many of you, I have experienced overwhelming love for you and your goodness. I have been humbled by your sustaining support. My desires to serve you have deepened. These are the feelings of charity; these are answers to my prayers; these are some of the sweetest moments of my calling. I must have made some progress, because some of my children are asking why I’ve been so nice lately. This December I will give my Father in Heaven an accounting of my efforts to understand and exercise charity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p26" pid="1XVuy1yW9keYPO2E__fD6w" hash="NgnJcw">Just as He did with Mary and Martha, the Lord will show us that good part which shall not be taken from us. He will grant us charity, that pure love of Christ, for “charity never faileth.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p27" pid="iXMxkjHz0EWMRBS0KNicCQ" hash="wAs3aw">Dear sisters, one thing is needful, to follow Him each day. Choose ye therefore Christ the Lord. Choose to feast upon His word. Choose to trust in Him above. Choose to wait upon His love. Choose to give Him all your heart. Choose ye therefore that good part.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part.p28" pid="cZoX1PKwN0WJYIIoxB_hQA" hash="Cz3I4Q">For this I pray, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2003/10/choosing-charity-that-good-part</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2003-general-relief-society-meeting/2003-09-0010-bonnie-d-parkin-64k-eng.mp3" length="6186631" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2003 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belonging Is Our Sacred Birthright</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I testify that you do fit, that you do belong to Relief Society—the Good Shepherd’s fold for women.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030208_000_036" doc-version="2" hash="ekTQug">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="hX2Je-ftj0-lELTQ-n9umA" hash="3LD4MQ">Belonging Is Our Sacred Birthright</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="YwWtQDSYsU-F5XGqXtWY9Q" hash="pZJd1w">Bonnie D. Parkin</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="xIKZwT0KGkqussO0uV2yzA" hash="APt15g">I testify that you do fit, that you do belong to Relief Society—the Good Shepherd’s fold for women.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-101.jpg" alt="Bonnie D. Parkin" pid="vl9YyExn9U2Gcsb-C4NjjA" hash="FbtaIA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p1" pid="5TQy0ZzSFEGIUFRt7RwpDg" hash="MK8QVA">Sisters, I rejoice that we’re together tonight. Thanks for your countless acts of compassion, your ever-expanding testimonies, your endless supply of casseroles! You make a difference and are sunshine for the soul!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p2" pid="qse_uinOAkW6_Md58FpIKA" hash="a_yKWA">In these perilous times, I find comfort in the promise that “if [we] are prepared [we] shall not fear.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Relief Society helps us be prepared—not just temporally, but spiritually. But Relief Society cannot help in our preparation without our participation! I worry that some of you feel you don’t fit in Relief Society, that you don’t belong! Whether you feel too young or too old, too rich or too poor, too intelligent or too undereducated, none of us is too different to belong! If I could have my heart’s desire, it would be that every one of you feel like you fit, like you belong. I testify that you <span class="emphasis">do</span> fit, that you <span class="emphasis">do</span> belong to Relief Society—the Good Shepherd’s fold for women.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p3" pid="3gg9rfojVkmxXRlUNGXEBA" hash="HqhrqQ">I empathize with President Joseph F. Smith when he said back in 1907, “Today it is too much the case that our young, vigorous, intelligent women feel that only the aged should be connected with the Relief Society.” Then he declared, <span class="emphasis">“This is a mistake.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p4" pid="hkiKvzP_L0GvsHM5JXVdDw" hash="tnZ5iQ">I recently visited Ethiopia, where I met Jennifer Smith. If ever a woman could say she didn’t fit, it was Sister Smith. She said: “I was so unlike any other [sister] in our branch. Language, clothing, culture, all seemed to be [a] gap [between us. But] when we spoke of the Savior … the gap narrowed. When we spoke of a loving Heavenly Father … , there was no gap.” She continued, “We cannot change nor take away the burdens of others, but we can include and belong to each other in love.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p5" pid="6uDwyY4yk0yJC4mxwWZ7Xw" hash="M0dv2Q">These sisters found a piece of Zion by becoming “of one heart and one mind.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> For “if ye are not one,” says the Lord, “ye are not mine.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> President Hinckley has said that if we “will be united and speak with one voice, [our] strength will be incalculable.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> As sisters in Zion, how do we become one? The same way we belong to a spouse or to a family: we share who we are—our feelings, our thoughts, our hearts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p6" pid="rWkfdkyiUEeGerTyltT6AQ" hash="oggAGA">In one ward, mothers introduce their daughters to Relief Society in a Sunday meeting when they turn 18. One mother tenderly expressed how her Relief Society sisters had nurtured her from her early marriage: “They have brought meals and hugs in time of sorrow, laughter, and support for celebration. They have taught me the gospel by visiting me and letting me visit them. They have allowed me to make mistakes on their time.” This mother then explained to her daughter how the daisies in their garden came from Carolyn, the lilies from Venice, the buttercups from Pauline. The daughter was amazed. Her mother replied, “These women are my sisters in every way, and I am grateful to bring you into their care.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p7" pid="XE7V5FFPJE65za9qWE3NhQ" hash="JnAMnw">It’s the variety in a garden that contributes to its beauty—we need daisies and lilies and buttercups; we need gardeners who water, nurture, and care. Unfortunately, Satan knows that sharing unites our sisterhood through the everyday and the eternities. He knows that selfishness will begin to destroy sharing, which destroys unity, which destroys Zion. Sisters, we cannot let the adversary divide us. You see, “A perfect oneness,” said Brigham Young, “will save a people.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> And I would add that a perfect oneness will save our society.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p8" pid="HkCNTcVQD0GZEbj06AkHvg" hash="ou-VRg">We are reminded by President Boyd K. Packer that “too many sisters … think that Relief Society is merely a class to attend. … Sisters,” he counseled, “you must graduate from <span class="emphasis">thinking</span> that you only <span class="emphasis">attend</span> Relief Society to <span class="emphasis">feeling</span> that you <span class="emphasis">belong</span> to it!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Our sense of belonging begins on Sunday as we hear each other’s voices. No teacher should give <span class="emphasis">her</span> lesson to a group of silent sisters, because the lesson is <span class="emphasis">our</span> lesson.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p9" pid="NuuB9HRTI0aGVT9ggNibHQ" hash="rP0Jzg">Belonging is being needed, loved, and missed when you’re away; belonging is needing, loving, and missing those who are away. That is the difference between <span class="emphasis">attending</span> and <span class="emphasis">belonging.</span> Relief Society is not just a Sunday class: it is a divine gift to us as women.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p10" pid="YFJFpufYBkWFRN2Ln2k9Yg" hash="XZJugA">Here are two reasons why <span class="emphasis">I</span> feel I belong to Relief Society—and it’s not just because of my current calling! I was feeling down last month when my visiting teachers came. Sue is divorced, and Cate is one of my former Laurels. They brought the message and a prayer. But they also brought real concern. I felt lifted and loved.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p11" pid="YF6Q5TutnE-TMUQUmQkHwg" hash="TWp4QQ">One of my sisters in Relief Society offered a prayer not long ago and asked Heavenly Father to bless me—by name—in my responsibilities. She didn’t know my specific needs, but she knew my heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p12" pid="mn-EFasrGU65s7lB8_XjqQ" hash="zazM3g">Now, maybe your visiting teachers haven’t come recently, or maybe you haven’t been prayed for by name. I’m sorry if that’s been so. But you don’t have to be visit taught to be a good visiting teacher; you don’t have to be prayed for to pray. In spite of our differences, if we will share generously and honestly, our sisters will also share; we will know one another’s hearts, and belonging will flower like a garden. Sister Smith and our Ethiopian sisters learned that differences don’t matter, for belonging is charity, the pure love of Christ, in action. And charity never faileth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p13" pid="7jsRd1s-2kCvLgx3Mg9vJA" hash="2FWlkA">Whether we serve in Primary or Young Women, whether we’re active or less so, whether we’re married or single, whether we’re spring chickens or fall hens, we all belong to Relief Society. I’m a fall hen, but I <span class="emphasis">feel</span> like a spring chicken! We need your voices, your feelings, your hearts. Relief Society needs you. And you know what? <span class="emphasis">You</span> need Relief Society. When you don’t participate, you’re depriving yourself <span class="emphasis">and</span> you’re depriving Relief Society.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p14" pid="AH1-fURodEmSWIB_hEKbsA" hash="eTFwyg">Sisters, we can have no divisions in Relief Society; all “members should have the same care one for another.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> “And whether one member suffer, all the members suffer with it; or one member be honoured, all the members rejoice with it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> For “the body hath need of <span class="emphasis">every</span> member, that <span class="emphasis">all</span> may be edified <span class="emphasis">together,</span> that the system may be kept perfect.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p15" pid="gJTRPa2Mqk2p0Ei86LPUlQ" hash="S1ZcJw">Yes, Relief Society can be more fun, more joyful, more unifying. Our burdens can be lightened, our loads lessened. Relief Society’s not perfect, because not one of us is. But we can work on it; we can perfect it together as we take our own steps forward. How? By just changing our attitudes: How we talk about Relief Society affects how others feel about Relief Society—especially young women.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p16" pid="PyIfvDToM0y1Pp89yLB9XQ" hash="6lPMtA">Be supportive of our Relief Society presidencies and teachers—let them learn on our time (just as we will learn on theirs). Forgive more and judge less. Be a caring, consistent visiting teacher. Attend home, family, and personal enrichment meeting with enthusiasm. Look for what’s <span class="emphasis">good</span> about Relief Society and build on it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p17" pid="aKYB8ZO10UqzvfTmEn1JNQ" hash="1m340w">President Joseph F. Smith issued a charge that we “take hold of this work [of Relief Society] with vigor, with intelligence and unitedly, for the building up of Zion.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> If we believe that the Lord’s Church has been restored—and we do—then we must believe that Relief Society is an essential part of His organizational fold. We need to stop asking <span class="emphasis">whether</span> we fit—because we do! Our differences are not so great that we cannot build Zion together.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p18" pid="YT1KnYmIm0iJt_ric6u6Hg" hash="5xg2Fw">Nearly a year ago, in Pasadena, California, Sister Janice Burgoyne was dying of cancer. She had shared generously of herself and was dearly loved. Her Relief Society sisters were bringing her meals, cleaning her house, caring for her two young sons, helping her husband plan a funeral. It was hard for Janice to receive so much help, knowing that her sisters would find that piece of old toast behind the couch. She worried her sisters would know more than her heart. But <span class="emphasis">because</span> her sisters knew her heart, it didn’t matter. They provided car pools, tutored homework, played her piano, changed bedding. And they did it day after day after day, without complaint, with boundless charity. Such sharing forever changed those sisters. Before she died, Janice turned to a Relief Society sister and asked with gratitude and awe, “How does anyone die without Relief Society?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p19" pid="sKHDBAENOka2_m24RJY0VA" hash="JiKiCw">To you, my dear sisters—and you are <span class="emphasis">my</span> sisters—I ask, “How does anyone <span class="emphasis">live</span> without Relief Society?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p20" pid="Lnhv32RCsEuSNMaTaibAcA" hash="6Ur6MQ">Belonging is our sacred birthright. How I’d like to bundle you in my arms and go to Relief Society with you. How I would like to know your hearts and have you know mine. Bring your hearts, your charitable hearts, to Relief Society. Bring your talents, your gifts, your individuality so that we can be one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p21" pid="P68JpJ5N4UmqPuxxigoVyw" hash="yPjBBA">I testify that “the good shepherd doth call after [us] … [to] bring [us] into his fold.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> We may not have all the answers, but we must trust that Relief Society is an essential part of His work, for</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="I9NYavJTSk-1x13ZOJpxGw" hash="feTdAg">
            <span class="emphasis">Though [our] path may wind across the mountains,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="RBk8jNh5j026Kee8Dhc4BQ" hash="TGa5WQ">
            <span class="emphasis">He knows the meadows where [we] feed. … </span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="HgGske6MCU-ifSwTxIRDAw" hash="OS8Lag">
            <span class="emphasis">He clothes the lilies of the field,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="PQbwmr8qPEOB-Yl3BgAPow" hash="gt7z4Q">
            <span class="emphasis">He feeds the lambs [of] His fold,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="ROrBq_HLyEiL7uEOJYkxvw" hash="t6uiJA">
            <span class="emphasis">And He will heal those who trust Him,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="BXL3ZJGGUE2yP8MaUB6jhQ" hash="wnzUBQ">
            <span class="emphasis">And make [our] hearts as gold.</span>
            <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright.p22" pid="JnznEgblqEull2itP8nZ6Q" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2004/10/belonging-is-our-sacred-birthright</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2004-general-relief-society-meeting/2004-09-0010-bonnie-d-parkin-64k-eng.mp3" length="5741297" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2004 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Has Relief Society Blessed Your Life?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Because Relief Society is divinely designed, it blesses not only women but the family and the Church.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030208_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="HlAWZg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="HP7kf4Zaik6oAW6zjtxXIQ" hash="q5cMZA">How Has Relief Society Blessed Your Life?</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="D94J94jV1UeovVlfGUhEeg" hash="pZJd1w">Bonnie D. Parkin</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="fX0-LkPNbEqUS8t_pdnOuA" hash="Oianeg">Because Relief Society is divinely designed, it blesses not only women but the family and the Church.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-101.jpg" alt="Bonnie D. Parkin" pid="damYX0W5fE6cmUdwwo50mQ" hash="FbtaIA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p1" pid="87GIzPEzFkOATSetkf0-tQ" hash="Ns-lRw">Looking back on his life, a man recently shared this tender story with me: “When I was growing up my father was less active in the Church. He struggled with alcohol and in his darkest moods could become harsh and accusing. He normally didn’t object to Mom serving in the ward. She worked in Primary for 38 years, and during much of that time she served in Young Women. She carried a heavy load. Her marriage was difficult, and I now know that she was discouraged at times, but I didn’t know it then.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p2" pid="860edGBtx0ezMkzzfuxqaQ" hash="f0ji7Q">“I didn’t realize until later that the sisters in our ward were her strength. She didn’t work in the Relief Society leadership, but she always attended the meetings, and she loved her friends there. I never thought of them as the ladies of Relief Society; they were simply Mom’s sisters. They cared about her and loved her. She had all brothers and all sons. She found the sisters she wanted and needed in our ward. I know she shared her feelings with them—feelings she couldn’t express anywhere else. None of that seemed ‘Relief Society’ to me then, but I understand now that it was.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p3" pid="dH2F8zwDS0OLBhx0JfbuXQ" hash="R_Btrg">This son’s memory of Relief Society touched my heart. Yes, Relief Society’s members are women, but Relief Society does not bless only the women; it blesses each one of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p4" pid="YH_w3c8wA0-IPFJphkUqbA" hash="q5cMZA1">How has Relief Society blessed <span class="emphasis">your</span> life?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p5" pid="daUidLLExU-K-mjaH30TJg" hash="B4U9Pg">I asked this question of President Hinckley. He responded: “Relief Society has blessed my family and the family of my dear wife for some seven generations. Since the earliest days of the Church, our mothers and daughters have been taught of their obligations to those in distress. They have been schooled in the finer points of homemaking, encouraged in their spiritual development, and guided in the realization of their full potential as women. Much of this has taken place in Relief Society and has then been brought home to bless the life of each member of my family.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p6" pid="DaxqPT-PPkKzEJ9yFvpJCA" hash="QXvMyQ">I have my own sweet memories of playing under my grandmother’s quilting frames as she and her Relief Society sisters stitched. I was young, but I knew that this was part of Relief Society—blessing the lives of others. I was mentored with love for Relief Society by my mother and my grandmother. I love Relief Society—I think I always have. Relief Society has helped me know the Savior and has strengthened my love for Him and my Heavenly Father. My belonging to Relief Society has provided me with many opportunities to learn, love, serve, and be filled with the love of the Lord in my life as I strive to keep my covenants, exercise charity, and strengthen my family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p7" pid="zNpt1Iabm0WNRj2fn5C2ew" hash="bCWZ_w">So I ask again, how many ways has Relief Society blessed your life?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p8" pid="_Sjks2wJDEOgi3xCDTeZiQ" hash="EY_V_g">Visiting the Missionary Training Center in Brazil, I said to the missionaries, “Tell me what you know about Relief Society.” One elder said, “Casseroles!” Another added, “My mother and sister belong to it.” Finally, one declared, “It’s the Lord’s organization for women.” He was right, but there’s more. Relief Society is “a <span class="emphasis">fundamental</span> part of the gospel.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p9" pid="mD11dDSvFUKfca-YY5_2lg" hash="kCqKIQ">The year 1842 was extremely difficult for the Prophet Joseph Smith. Former friends had turned on him. Other enemies wanted to abduct him from Nauvoo and blunt the growth of the Church. That same year he organized the Relief Society to care for the poor and needy and “to save souls.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> President J. Reuben Clark Jr. observed that amidst these trials, Joseph Smith “turned to the sisters for the consolation, for the uplift of which he stood in such sad need at that time.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> This is a moving and humbling thought: a prophet of God seeking the solace of his sisters—women to whom he had given the charge “charity never faileth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> To me this has echoes of those women who mourned with the Savior on Golgotha.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p10" pid="NVGdtAW7J0mmNkcbeDJ8dQ" hash="3zTBLQ">Relief Society has blessed prophets’ lives. How has it blessed yours?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p11" pid="MYfO2wNJs0GT3jj7DT4aTA" hash="BpLhxg">President Boyd K. Packer has said, “The defenses of the home and family are greatly reinforced when the wife and mother and daughters belong to Relief Society.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> Why? Because women are the heart of the home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p12" pid="a2MCxscNekqiacBkDvOy_A" hash="HUsIBg">My belonging to Relief Society has renewed, strengthened, and committed me to be a better wife and mother and daughter of God. My heart has been enlarged with gospel understanding and with love of the Savior and what He’s done for me. So to you, dear sisters, I say: Come to Relief Society! It will fill your homes with love and charity; it will nurture and strengthen you and your families. Your home needs your righteous heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p13" pid="rLzlgVKAk0uuye2g8cBmJQ" hash="XUrTYg">During a recent assignment to Peru, I visited the humble home of Brother and Sister Morales. It was filled with love. They are the parents of three children and have been members of the Church for four years. Sister Morales has learned much in Relief Society. To help provide for their family and their missionary son, she took in washing and ironing. She helped with two children of a neighbor who had to leave home to work. She supported her husband, who is struggling with kidney failure and was serving in the elders quorum. They discussed the Heber J. Grant lessons together in preparation for his teaching the lesson.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p14" pid="yrzxSnmouEaACD7QUClRyw" hash="br7CXw">I asked her, “Are you a visiting teacher?” With a smile on her face she responded, “Oh, yes, Sister Parkin. I visit four sisters. Two are less active, but I will love them back.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p15" pid="W52GsAsqx0umdmO2ZRDzHg" hash="D5TE2Q">Leaving their home, I noticed a hand-drawn sign above the door. It asked, “Did you read your scriptures today?” Relief Society is blessing this home, this ward, this neighborhood. How has it blessed you?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p16" pid="O2TpiRPDGk-fgTjpsokpjQ" hash="BH0sRw">Belonging to Relief Society is critical for newly baptized sisters and, by extension, their families. While serving with my husband as he presided over the England London South Mission, I met many new converts—like Gloria, a single mother. When she joined the Church, she joined Relief Society. It was a safe place where she could ask questions about her newfound faith. She heard women openly share their experiences, which led her to experiment upon the word of God.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> She’s received her patriarchal blessing; she’s been to the temple; she serves in the Church. I think of President Hinckley’s counsel to me: “[Women] need to be together in an environment that bolsters faith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Relief Society provides such an environment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p17" pid="ojyBPoZdAEOAqT6kkKQGFg" hash="JHxi1Q">I thought of the stripling warriors when I heard the son of a Relief Society sister say: “I have been blessed by the faith and example of my mother. By the time I became a priesthood holder, I had learned as much about home teaching from my mother’s visiting teaching efforts as by my father’s example of home teaching. … Her faith in the priesthood affects my faith and strengthens my desire to be [a] worthy … elder.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p18" pid="LZOOPNFNc0y5hm0_GuKtpQ" hash="IJo3jQ">Brothers and sisters, I am changed and blessed, I am better because of Relief Society. And I believe we all are.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p19" pid="07hVaDcldU6qrMQcqIa8-w" hash="WMFnhA">I pray that mothers and daughters will participate with more vigor, that husbands will support their wives, and that both mothers and fathers will prepare their daughters for Relief Society. I encourage priesthood leaders to shepherd God’s daughters, young and old, into Relief Society—one of the many miracles of the Restoration. As we take these steps, we will be overwhelmed with gratitude for this sacred organization.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life.p20" pid="_ge8q-W0q0i45AteIPLDlQ" hash="eAXx4A">Because Relief Society is divinely designed, it blesses not only women but the family and the Church. I testify that it is a fundamental part of the Lord’s restored gospel because it abides in charity—His pure love. Of this I bear witness, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2004/10/how-has-relief-society-blessed-your-life</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2004-general-conference/2004-10-2060-bonnie-d-parkin-64k-eng.mp3" length="4542373" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2004 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Moments</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments?lang=eng</link>
      <description>If we are seeking the Lord and His guidance, if our direction is to return to our Father in Heaven, the sweet moments will come.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10033479_000_038" doc-version="2" hash="6TJbiA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="FqM6V-g3n0GwllW1LEVzLA" hash="UzSOvA">Sweet Moments</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="A42stpxKSUGIDl4DH7OM5w" hash="pZJd1w">Bonnie D. Parkin</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="lB7-HpKzrkKQoB3-yc2AfQ" hash="Lieh-A">If we are seeking the Lord and His guidance, if our direction is to return to our Father in Heaven, the sweet moments will come.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-101.jpg" alt="Bonnie D. Parkin" pid="JupDaAUHkkecdFIzohP4Vg" hash="FbtaIA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p1" pid="BWiDJw35jkOzQcWe0ZQtnQ" hash="_CQAqQ">How thankful we are for our living prophet, President Gordon B. Hinckley, and for his words “God bless the Relief Society of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Every sister in this Church belongs to Relief Society. Every one of us can feel the love that is so plentiful in this divinely instituted organization.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p2" pid="uLkJrIHA4UqkfIDQarx11Q" hash="v3e17Q">My heart is tender for you sisters who have been seriously impacted by recent natural disasters. I rejoice at the accounts of righteous women serving and being served. Through service, both the servant and the served experience the love of the Lord. At this time of trial, I pray that you will feel His love and also my love and the love of your many Relief Society sisters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p3" pid="E5mBZypfe0WtWuFmCU_GOw" hash="4v1Xqg">The Prophet Joseph Smith set the course for Relief Society when he said to the sisters in 1842: “It is natural for females to have feelings of charity—you are now placed in a situation where you can act according to those sympathies which God has planted in your bosoms. If you live up to these principles how great and glorious!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p4" pid="aQHZ5yETyEuIFGQeqosz1w" hash="xBWzVA">The sisters of the early Relief Society were stirred to action by the Prophet Joseph. Today, we too have opportunities to serve as “instruments in the hands of God to bring about this great work.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p5" pid="n1bSqrGin0SldQltM0b7fg" hash="ilBX4Q">What does it mean to be an instrument in everyday terms? I think it means to nurture others. Joseph Smith called it acting “according to those sympathies” in our hearts. I have had many sweet moments when I have felt the Lord using me as an instrument. I believe that you too have been guided and helped as you teach, comfort, and encourage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p6" pid="E2tFe3yMR0SEt4ODiqOtqw" hash="bSzl1A">Yet as women we are pretty hard on ourselves! Believe me when I say each of us is much better than we think. We need to recognize and celebrate what we’re doing right. Much of what we do seems small and insignificant—just a part of daily living. When we are called “to give an account to Jehovah,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> as the Prophet Joseph counseled, I know that we will have much to share.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p7" pid="Y7DYBDUvN06R5poL4C1akA" hash="aWYPyQ">Let me give you an example. Recently I asked Elder William W. Parmley about his memories of his mother, LaVern Parmley, who served as the Primary general president for 23 years. He didn’t refer to her talks at conferences or the many programs she implemented. He spoke of one of his sweetest moments when he was 17 and preparing to go away to college. He remembered sitting with his mother as she taught him how to sew on a button. With children of all ages, small and simple acts have lasting impact.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p8" pid="aYIOL6QAuEe1Mkug1UuuDw" hash="l-h6kw">Not all of us have children to teach the basics of sewing to. The early sisters were a diverse group just like us. Some were married, some single, some widowed, but they were united in purpose. As I’ve been with you in many lands and many places, I have felt your love. Sisters, I love you, and I know the Lord loves you too.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p9" pid="qFXejfNnhESHj9-_4qtJMQ" hash="zFK1Cw">Now, many of you are single. You are students; you are working; you are new to Relief Society. Some of you have been longtime members. Please believe me when I say each of you is valued and needed. Each of you brings love, energy, perspective, and testimony to the work. Your efforts to live close to the Spirit bless us all because you have learned to rely on the Spirit for strength and direction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p10" pid="4DzNnLQB-UyJc1jZwYyi5Q" hash="N4kEBQ">One evening a single sister, Cynthia, felt prompted to go and see a sister she visit taught. The sister wasn’t home. As Cynthia walked home, she noticed a nurse outside a hospital with two children, both serious-burn victims. When Cynthia heard the nurse call the little girl’s name, a flash of recognition crossed her mind: she had known these two children as a missionary in Bolivia four years before. Becoming reacquainted on the lawn of the hospital, it was obvious the children were healing physically, but without any family support, they were suffering emotionally. Cynthia began visiting the children and nurturing them. Heeding the prompting of the Spirit, Cynthia became God’s instrument for blessing two homesick children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p11" pid="oGgWSI0YfkC-88yohaaVyg" hash="1T4Qfw">Was that effort because she was single? No. It was because she was attentive to the Spirit and had yielded her heart to God. If we are in tune with the Spirit, if we are seeking the Lord and His guidance, if our direction is to return to our Father in Heaven, the sweet moments will come. And we will treasure them, for we have become instruments in the hands of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p12" pid="R1N27TgFgE28-haO-SMY6A" hash="vWCMgA">Sometimes our lives take unexpected turns, and we have to move from “plan A” to “plan B.” One single sister wrote: “I don’t think I ever felt true happiness in my adult life until I came to the conclusion that my worth as a person and as a daughter of my Heavenly Father had nothing to do with my marital status. At that point, I began to focus on my spiritual and personal growth and not on whether I was ever going to marry.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p13" pid="XLqr8YgYkEOy0oBpQvzDyw" hash="JOa69g">See how much we learn and grow when we share with one another our witness that the Lord lives and loves us. As I’ve said before, if I could have one thing happen for each of you, it would be that you feel the love of the Lord in your life daily.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p14" pid="cWzyMdkazEmkLQVEtucDSA" hash="ZRaoXg">Sometimes that love comes in unexpected ways. Kristen was finishing a graduate degree and had recently given birth to her second child. She felt the other graduates had accomplished so much more and was reluctant to attend the graduation dinner. Her fears were confirmed when, at the dinner, the students were asked to list their professional accomplishments. Kristen recalled: “I suddenly felt embarrassed and ashamed. I had nothing to call myself, no lofty position, no impressive job title.” To make matters worse, the professor read the lists as he presented a diploma to each student. The woman ahead of Kristen had many accomplishments: she already had a PhD, was receiving a second master’s degree, and she’d even been a mayor! The woman received grand applause.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p15" pid="ZeSgWLpcp0eumfXnAHUgtA" hash="vbGs1g">Then it was Kristen’s turn. She handed the professor her blank sheet, trying to hold back the tears. The professor had been one of her teachers and had praised her performance. He looked at her blank paper. Without missing a beat he announced, “Kristen holds the most critical role in all of society.” He was quiet for a few seconds, then declared in a powerful voice, “She is the mother of her children.” Instead of a few courteous claps, people rose to their feet. There was just one standing ovation that night; it was for the mother in the room.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p16" pid="FaBbq_rsmEKkf4bEExD2IQ" hash="bqC85w">Mothers, you are instruments in God’s hands, with a divine responsibility to teach and nurture your children. Little ones so need your kind and loving hand. As you put them first, He will direct you how to best serve them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p17" pid="RDqWdtrfeEGyQ17btgHNVw" hash="wF39nQ">All of you with older children are needed in your homes. Yes, there are frustrations, but there are lots of joys. Look for them! Having raised four industrious sons, I learned a thing or two about being an instrument: Enjoy the energy of these years! Make your home a safe, happy, relaxed place where friends are welcome. Listen, love, share your stories of your childhood and teenage years with your children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p18" pid="opmhCKwIF0eudTjdAI1RXA" hash="Rx0dMQ">Have expectations for your children. We had a curfew and told our sons that the Holy Ghost goes to bed at midnight. When they didn’t come home, a few times the Holy Ghost told me to go out and find them. That surprised a few of their dates! We laugh about that now—but I must admit, laughter comes easier as they have grown older.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p19" pid="ezr2fwe5DUa1Ld2GVOEnww" hash="vV_6PA">Be there for your children. Sit on the bed and enjoy the late-night talks—try to stay awake! Pray for the Lord to inspire you. Forgive often. Choose your battles. Testify frequently of Jesus Christ and His goodness and of the Restoration. And most of all, let them know of your trust in the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p20" pid="qH1XqJWw0028POgC586PZA" hash="H7ollA">If your children are grown and gone; if you are single, divorced, or widowed; don’t let your circumstance dictate your willingness to share your life experiences. Your voice is needed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p21" pid="pJnBWMltiEiVL2n0vBcTow" hash="Yu6TEg">In a Relief Society Sunday lesson in my ward, we were discussing what makes a good marriage. One sister, Lisa, said: “I probably shouldn’t say anything because I’m divorced. But what keeps me going is my temple covenants.” After the lesson, I asked some new young adult Relief Society sisters what in this lesson had connected to them. They said, “Lisa’s comment impacted us most.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p22" pid="CFYwAHypdkG7qoHNJ5ls7w" hash="9ec2ew">Now, my dear older sisters, I see God’s image in your noble countenances. How your wisdom, patience, and experience have touched so many lives! My amazing mother-in-law, Mary, in her 90s used to say, “People think because I’m old I don’t know anything.” Let me tell you what she knew and what she did. While living in a senior residence, Mary asked the manager if they could use a room for church services. He told her no because the center was nondenominational. She refused to accept his answer! With some other senior sisters, Mary persisted until the company provided a room. Soon a branch was organized, and members were meeting each Sunday to partake of the sacrament and renew their covenants. Age is not a barrier to becoming an instrument in the hands of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p23" pid="T9Qc9S31nUKdbpST6pmCfA" hash="dk5IsA">There are countless ways to be instruments in God’s hands. For example, be the kind of visiting teacher you’ve always wanted; ask a young single adult about what she likes to do rather than why she’s not married; share instead of accumulate; carefully choose your dress, speech, and choice of entertainment; smile at your husband or child who knows they’ve caused frustration and heartache; put your arm around a young woman; teach in nursery with a happy heart; show by your attitude that you are finding joy in the journey. The Prophet Joseph said of such efforts, “If you live up to your privilege[s], the angels cannot be restrained from being your associates.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments.p24" pid="43hBNbxQ4EOqC7PgJc4smw" hash="vXVlEw">I testify we are engaged in the work of God. Thank you for your devotion to your families, to Relief Society, and to the Church. Thank you for being instruments in the hands of God to bring about this great work. May you feel God’s love in your lives and may you share that love with others is my prayer, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2005/10/sweet-moments</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2005-general-relief-society-meeting/2005-09-0010-bonnie-d-parkin-64k-eng.mp3" length="13786937" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2005 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eternally Encircled in His Love</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I know that [Heavenly Father] loves us, sisters, as does His Son, Jesus Christ. That love will never change—it is constant.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006562_000_042" doc-version="2" hash="mPrPWA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="D4Xwqv0PTkiY3V7eMBM17g" hash="XGgy6Q">Eternally Encircled in His Love</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="KwgxAk8e3UWTmneiTIXHZA" hash="pZJd1w">Bonnie D. Parkin</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="3hsjGdknmkeeuF-75IrTnA" hash="Sr4LtA">I know that [Heavenly Father] loves us, sisters, as does His Son, Jesus Christ. That love will never change—it is constant.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/ParkinB_02.jpg" alt="Bonnie D. Parkin" pid="kVgd88bM2kOBDtGFtkOlPQ" hash="C56Hyg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p1" pid="X55UQEhOqk6g-Wtl-_Qm3w" hash="5WNDhQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="108"></span>When I received this call, I pleaded with Heavenly Father to help me know what the sisters in the Church needed. I received a strong witness that we, His daughters, need to know that He loves us. We need to know that He sees the good in us. Feeling His love encourages us to press forward, reassures us that we are His, and confirms to us that He cherishes us even when we stumble and experience temporary setbacks.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p2" pid="39S4x1BuB0-oHy7XPcxPTw" hash="uGRmig">I had this message confirmed when I bore my testimony in the Sunday afternoon session of general conference in April of 2002. That morning I was told that Elder David B. Haight might not be able to participate in the conference. If that happened, I would have five minutes to bear my testimony. I prayed extra hard for Elder Haight that day! Sunday morning I watched him come into the Conference Center, and I started to relax—right up until the moment he exited during the congregational hymn. As I stood at the podium that afternoon, the teleprompter screen was blank! But the message that kept coming to my mind and heart was that women need to feel the Lord’s love in their lives daily. It was the message I knew I needed to convey that day, and it continues to be our message.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p3" pid="yCpCJwYiyUKwLhqq46QU8w" hash="vtgN_A">I have been humbled by your tender personal responses to this charge. Thank you for sharing how this message has blessed your life. Your words have confirmed that each one of us is entitled—and needs—to feel the Lord’s love in her life daily.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p4" pid="cmDk7fP0Ak6OJnwUonPkHQ" hash="4Ca7EA">Our Heavenly Father loved us before we came to this earth. I know that He loves us, sisters, as does His Son, Jesus Christ. That love will never change—it is constant. You can rely on it. We can trust it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p5" pid="_YifdawIa0-4L4OlS0GRnQ" hash="YaFIIQ">Just as the motto of Relief Society reminds us that “charity never faileth,” we must believe that the love of Christ will never fail us. All that we do in Relief Society should reflect the love of our Savior and the love of our Heavenly Father. This great love should be the source of our motivation to serve others. It must be both our point of origin and our destination!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p6" pid="Um08O32Yl0iPDHE6YXlPnA" hash="l5hgBw">I know of a young mother with five little children who called an older sister, her valued mentor, and asked, “Can we go on a hike?” Her friend knew that meant she needed to talk. Halfway through an eight-mile loop, the young mother finally said, “I just can’t believe that Heavenly Father loves me; I’ve made lots of mistakes in my life. I can’t feel that I’m worthy of His love; how can He possibly love me?” Sisters, this was a woman who had made temple covenants and was active in the Church. And yet she still felt unworthy of His love. The older sister quickly responded, “Of course He loves you. You’re His daughter.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p7" pid="GF96w8IBAEeryIMTiRFZKQ" hash="eK9k_A">Do we frequently reject the Lord’s love that He pours out upon us in much more abundance than we are willing to receive? Do we think we have to be perfect in order to deserve His love? When we allow ourselves to feel “encircled about eternally in the arms of his love,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> we feel safe, and we realize that we don’t need to be immediately perfect. We must acknowledge that perfection is a process. This is a gospel of eternal progress, and we must remember to appreciate the journey. <span class="emphasis">Eternal</span> means “without beginning or end,” so the encircling of His love is there for us every day. Remember, it’s constant—even when we don’t recognize it. I love Nephi’s description of this great gift: “The love of God … sheddeth itself abroad in the hearts of the children of men; wherefore, it is the most desirable above all things … <span class="emphasis">and the most joyous to the soul.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> I testify that this is true.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p8" pid="qYztDHTK6Ey-unlprNCPTw" hash="xAClVQ">I know there may be some who have a difficult time imagining what His love feels like. Think of a mother with her newborn baby. The warmth, safety, cherishing, and peace of a <span class="pageBreak" page-number="109"></span>mother’s embrace can help us understand what it feels like to be encircled in the arms of His love. A young adult Relief Society sister wrote, “Only in the love of my mother do I come close to understanding the magnitude and power of the love of the Savior.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p9" pid="9sMiLEt40km26Zyx7YGTFw" hash="v6gTlA">Mothers, can you see how essential you are in teaching this truth to your children? As you encircle your children with your love, they will catch glimpses of His love. President Gordon B. Hinckley urges us to “love the Lord [our] God, and love His Son, and be ever grateful for Their love for us. Whenever other love fades, there will be that shining, transcendent, everlasting love of God for each of us and the love of His Son, who gave His life”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> for us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p10" pid="NT-AiCJaR02cB8Y_twD3vw" hash="DxklgA">A mother who knows her relationship with God helps her children to know Him and to be encircled by His love. I was touched by the comments a daughter shared at the funeral of her 100-year-old mother: “When I was a teenager trying to plan my class schedule, I would come into the kitchen where Mother was ironing. I would present possible options for my studies. … She would listen to all of them. We would discuss the possibilities … and then she would say, ‘OK, Cathy, have you prayed about it?’ That was kind of embarrassing to me, and I would hesitate and then add, ‘Do you have to pray about everything?’ She answered simply, ‘I do.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p11" pid="KHpcLOLhxkOOiwPa2q3vrQ" hash="MbOkog">This mother listened. She shared her faith in the Lord; she set an example; she shared her expectations for her daughter to return continually to the Lord. As we approach the Lord, we feel His love draw us closer. Mothers, teach your children to always include the Lord in their lives, and help them to recognize His loving influence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p12" pid="Bozu9atMIECHTxHG5dfVwg" hash="JqOajA">My mother and I received our patriarchal blessings together. I was 20, and Mother was 49. I will never forget that day—how the patriarch placed his hands on Mother’s head and told her how often her life had been spared through bouts of rheumatic fever, heart disease, and many other illnesses. He recounted her life, enumerating the times she had blessed others. He told her of things the Lord had in store for her and offered guidance as to what she needed to do. I knew my mother’s life, and I listened as this patriarch, who was not acquainted with her, described her life. This experience was a witness to me that God lives, that He loves us, and that He knows us individually. I felt the Lord’s love for my mother—and for me—on that memorable day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p13" pid="MuYZ4uetukKnaZD3thMxYA" hash="sx0ang">The greatest evidence of our Savior’s love for us is His Atonement. His love overflows with grace, patience, long-suffering, mercy, and forgiveness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p14" pid="FLiklC4oGE-XEUHN8bJ_Bg" hash="4bjl2w">Now, as grandmothers we have a sacred responsibility to encircle our grandchildren in love. When a three-year-old girl was being sassy, her grandmother instructed her, “Don’t talk that way to your grandmother, because we are going to be friends for millions and millions of years.” Isn’t being a grandmother the best? Remember, sisters, love and covenants bind us together as eternal families.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p15" pid="B1UOvQhWzUWXlpsCfDFxgQ" hash="Eg4uBQ">The Lord’s love is often delivered through others as they respond to promptings of the Spirit. Are we hearing and following those promptings?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p16" pid="x-sbfWM9Z0CTBVCMB8VM6w" hash="IQIoUg">Because of financial struggles, one sister had to move from her beloved home and ward after living there for 22 years. That was painful. Of her first Sunday in her new ward, she said: “I felt very alone, even though I knew a few people. I was one of the first to Relief Society that morning. I sat there and watched the sisters file in and take their seats. They all seemed <span class="pageBreak" page-number="110"></span>to need their own row, not just their own seat. They didn’t sit by each other and they didn’t sit by me. I felt like an island.” Sisters, why do we do that to each other?! The sister continued: “Then Lisa came in. Her face lit up when she saw me and she charged over to me, popped down beside me, put her arm around me and gave me a big hug. It’s amazing how much a small gesture like that can mean. Her warmth”—and I would add, her love—“washed away my loneliness.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p17" pid="wjq9bGPYkEG30l-jeSD0BA" hash="-qyCyw">I fear sometimes we see the Lord’s love only in the big events of our lives; we must also see His love in the smallest of things. Don’t underestimate your ability to share His love through a simple, genuine gesture such as sitting next to another sister and making her feel welcome.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p18" pid="_inwLwl1vUaNNhwZKlg5FQ" hash="RtNp4g">Do <span class="emphasis">you</span> feel the Lord’s love in <span class="emphasis">your</span> life? How I feel His love may be different from how you experience it. The key is to come to understand how <span class="emphasis">you</span> feel that love. And once you’ve felt it, be willing to share it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p19" pid="AOFdPHkte0-mzAu7ySSiTA" hash="DRP9RQ">As a presidency we visited the devastated Gulf Coast following Hurricane Katrina. One evening at a fireside I stood at the pulpit and felt prompted that every sister in attendance needed someone to literally reach out and strengthen her. After the meeting, Sister Hughes, Sister Pingree, and I each stood by a different door and hugged every sister as she exited. We simply wanted to express our love for them. To any of those sisters who are listening tonight, we left your chapel feeling renewed because of the love of God that you shared with us. Thank you for taking care of each other—and the three of us!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p20" pid="0ZUOM86F_EmJKuNjQckgVA" hash="ppNUvQ">In my morning prayers I ask Heavenly Father to fill me with His love so that I can do His work with more heart. I know that I have been blessed because of this daily petition. As Relief Society sisters, we must strive to manifest the love of Christ, who always sought to please His Father by doing His will. Sisters, we must make every effort to follow His supreme example—to demonstrate such love through our thoughts, our speech, our actions—in all the things we do and are. We must not allow pride or vanity, selfishness or personal agendas to displace our reaching out to others in love. Quite simply and profoundly, we must first allow ourselves to be encircled by God’s love. We do this best by embracing the Savior’s eternal Atonement. Then we can expand that circle to include our family and all others. Such a circle is indeed heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love.p21" pid="L5pMHf3_xE6qAy3_hNmY2g" hash="49CQ0Q">My dear sisters, may the Lord bless you to feel His love daily as you keep your covenants, exercise charity, and strengthen families. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/10/eternally-encircled-in-his-love</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2006-general-relief-society-meeting/2006-09-0010-bonnie-d-parkin-64k-eng.mp3" length="6561249" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2006 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gratitude: A Path to Happiness</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Gratitude is a Spirit-filled principle. It opens our minds to a universe permeated with the richness of a living God.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008333_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="0cIK5w">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ESWgy3gJfkGqURk13opCtw" hash="gk1uRw">Gratitude:</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="8taQKde4m0iIEKSMk9nSBg" hash="wl-iCg">A Path to Happiness</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="KsJOMLGRVU-VsrK3b0kPxQ" hash="pZJd1w">Bonnie D. Parkin</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="y2CDnj-rFU2_3eq-GsyrZg" hash="dJ_f0w">Gratitude is a Spirit-filled principle. It opens our minds to a universe permeated with the richness of a living God.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/ParkinB_02.jpg" alt="Bonnie D. Parkin" pid="E6hd7zNc5kWjW2VT58raqA" hash="C56Hyg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.p1" pid="vH4k9XTYYUCU2LXIlTcMdA" hash="L66Mxg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="34"></span>This afternoon I am honored to represent those Relief Society leaders who, here in this very Tabernacle, shared the doctrines of the kingdom, emphasized the significance of women’s roles in the home and family, called each other to charitable service, and reminded their sisters of the joy that comes from righteous living.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.p2" pid="2AzU-RRfAkuaUT9ItAIUbg" hash="-EutNQ">From this pulpit in 1870, Eliza R. Snow asked thousands of women a question that I’d like to repeat today: “Do you know of any place on the face of the earth, where [a] woman has more liberty, and where she enjoys such high and glorious privileges as she does here, as a Latter-day Saint?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> I bear witness that the women of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints do enjoy grand and glorious privileges.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="Khb0GGRqzUWeEwWRW_DKkw" hash="pt19cA">Blessing Basket</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.p3" pid="RsIC8Z1ofUGNl-4EUDTmHQ" hash="oUQnFw">Let me share a sweet story with you. A family was going through a difficult time. It was hard for them not to focus on their challenges. The mother wrote: “Our world had completely crumpled, so we turned to Heavenly Father for guidance. Almost immediately we realized that we were surrounded by goodness and were being cheered on from every side. We began as a family to express our gratitude to each other as well as to the Lord daily. A close friend pointed out to me that our family’s ‘blessing basket’ was overflowing. From that conversation came a sort of game, which my children and I grew to love. Before family prayer each night we would talk about how our day had gone and then share with each other all of the many blessings that had been added to our ‘blessing basket.’ The more we expressed gratitude, the more there was to be grateful for. We felt the love of the Lord in a significant way as opportunities for growth presented themselves.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.p4" pid="WzsoRpiBV06zbuXFRKTa4g" hash="tb1Z6g">What would a “blessing basket” add to your family?</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="Wl_LU-RP3kCafhRSq6npwg" hash="yeEqtg">A Spirit-Filled Principle</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.p5" pid="Aw4AZJLAnk6o1NekNSkluQ" hash="2PVklg">
          <span class="pageBreak" page-number="35"></span>Gratitude requires awareness and effort, not only to feel it but to express it. Frequently we are oblivious to the Lord’s hand. We murmur, complain, resist, criticize; so often we are not grateful. In the Book of Mormon, we learn that those who murmur do not know “the dealings of that God who … created them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> The Lord counsels us not to murmur because it is then difficult for the Spirit to work with us.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.p6" pid="23UbJyB0DE-VSX6tEcXdbQ" hash="4I3QOg">Gratitude is a Spirit-filled principle. It opens our minds to a universe permeated with the richness of a living God. Through it, we become spiritually aware of the wonder of the smallest things, which gladden our hearts with their messages of God’s love. This grateful awareness heightens our sensitivity to divine direction. When we communicate gratitude, we can be filled with the Spirit and connected to those around us and the Lord. Gratitude inspires happiness and carries divine influence. “Live in thanksgiving daily,” said Amulek, “for the many mercies and blessings which he doth bestow upon you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.p7" pid="75NCO4hpmEyjUw99CG7hvQ" hash="0vnaOg">Mercies and blessings come in different forms—sometimes as hard things. Yet the Lord said, “Thou shalt thank the Lord thy God in <span class="emphasis">all</span> things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span><span class="emphasis">All things</span> means just that: good things, difficult things—not just some things. He has commanded us to be grateful because He knows being grateful will make us happy. This is another evidence of His love.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.p8" pid="311wAG6KPka7gjyhiaDu4A" hash="YRsH-g">How do you feel when someone expresses gratitude to you? One Sunday I sat next to a sister in Relief Society and got to know her a little better. A few days later I received an e-mail: “Thank you for sitting next to my daughter in Relief Society. You put your arm around her. You will never know how much that meant to her and to me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> This mother’s words surprised me and brought me happiness.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.p9" pid="o16iWinkJUmTwLK4ZDYWkQ" hash="JpgZsA">How do you feel when you express gratitude to another? I’d like to express gratitude to someone who cares about my grandchildren. A few months ago, while visiting in Texas, I asked six-year-old Thomas to tell me about his bishop. He said, “Oh, Grandmother, you will know him. He wears a dark suit, a white shirt like Papa, and he has shiny shoes and a red tie. He wears glasses and always has a smile.” I recognized Thomas’s bishop as soon as I saw him. My heart was filled with gratitude for him. Thank you, Bishop Goodman, and thank you, all you wonderful bishops.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="bm2aKJ76_0OC5vro1_7d3w" hash="lCOCCA">An Expression of Faith</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.p10" pid="a0am6XkQEkapfUZ1jncsQA" hash="BGh7Jg">Luke chapter 17 records the experience of the Savior when He healed 10 lepers. As you recall, only one of the cleansed lepers returned to express his appreciation. Isn’t it interesting that the Lord did not say, “Your <span class="emphasis">gratitude</span> has made you whole”? Instead, He said, “Thy <span class="emphasis">faith</span> hath made thee whole.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.p11" pid="H9cnZ6T6L0KK74E-m7ocuQ" hash="xWrx0w">The leper’s expression of gratitude was recognized by the Savior as an expression of his faith. As we pray and express gratitude to a loving but unseen Heavenly Father, we are also expressing our faith in Him. Gratitude is our sweet acknowledgment of the Lord’s hand in our lives; it is an expression of our faith.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="aNAOArwiTUKE_QyGs9l3-g" hash="sDl3RA">Gratitude in Tribulations: Hidden Blessings</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.p12" pid="r7FDazaQUUOW3Gcr4aMRcQ" hash="J9NMdA">In 1832 the Lord saw the need to prepare the Church for coming tribulations. Tribulations are frightening. And yet the Lord said: “Be of good cheer, for I will lead you along. The kingdom is yours and the blessings thereof are yours, and the riches of eternity are yours.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.p13" pid="Ht6sVysrp0-of4A_083t0g" hash="OOaeMw">“And he who receiveth <span class="emphasis">all</span> things with thankfulness shall be made glorious.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.p14" pid="94scJKte5k2Mli-Qzj6Qmg" hash="N2W5Tg">The kind of gratitude that receives even tribulations with thanksgiving requires a broken heart and a contrite spirit, humility to accept that which we cannot change, willingness to turn everything over to the Lord—even when we do not understand, thankfulness for hidden opportunities yet <span class="pageBreak" page-number="36"></span>to be revealed. Then comes a sense of peace.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.p15" pid="MLBtbB1IAkemWstw7w69Vw" hash="0NIbTA">When was the last time you thanked the Lord for a trial or tribulation? Adversity compels us to go to our knees; does gratitude for adversity do that as well?</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.p16" pid="nt6RXSURtEOsAlBKWcHW7A" hash="U53Flw">President David O. McKay observed, “We find in the bitter chill of adversity the real test of our gratitude … , which … goes beneath the surface of life, whether sad or joyous.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.t6">
        <h3 class="title" pid="tDkpUNcAzUqdf5pYlGMLcQ" hash="JZFLeA">Conclusion</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.p17" pid="LvDi31Gpskqfyqi5guvwkw" hash="m7O08Q">To my remarkable, faithful sisters of the Church, I thank you for the ways you extend the Lord’s love through your service: your care for families at the death of a loved one, your watchcare as you visit teach, your willingness to build testimonies in children as you serve in Primary, your time preparing young women for womanhood. Thank you for your devotion. I have experienced the love of the Lord through your faithfulness. I have been blessed to serve among you; my heart is brimming over with gratitude and love for each of you. I have deep gratitude for the priesthood brethren with whom I’ve served.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness.p18" pid="fllcXJrBZkOIBtXAu9b-Jw" hash="-sUlFA">My most profound gratitude is for my Savior—an obedient Son, who did all that His Father asked and atoned for every one of us. As I remember Him and acknowledge His goodness, I desire to be like Him. May we be blessed to feel of His love in our lives daily. “Thanks be unto God for his unspeakable gift.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> In His sacred name, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/04/gratitude-a-path-to-happiness</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2007-general-conference/2007-04-2040-bonnie-d-parkin-64k-eng.mp3" length="4498013" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2007 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
