<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Bonnie L. Oscarson</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Bonnie L. Oscarson.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Bonnie%20L.%20Oscarson.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Bonnie L. Oscarson.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Be Ye Converted</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted?lang=eng</link>
      <description>True conversion occurs as you continue to act upon the doctrines you know are true and keep the commandments, day after day, month after month.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10791_000_43oscarson" doc-version="6" hash="A38IXw">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="H42D6WKoMEqGCOsnXWN6Ng" hash="p17z4g">Be Ye Converted</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="686Aq4X4PU6WpdXzNae7WA" hash="TqkN2g">By Bonnie L. Oscarson</p>
		<p class="kicker" pid="858l7K0vkEKFbQtaWkto-g" hash="0b3A0Q">True conversion occurs as you continue to act upon the doctrines you know are true and keep the commandments, day after day, month after month. </p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="sgcBIzgaxkW0iJlHqgGjKw" hash="QvhOeA">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted.p5" pid="FhG6QGQJekONoT-E9xKLRA" hash="mAs6mA"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="76"></span>Brothers and sisters, what a humbling experience it is to stand at this pulpit where so many of the heroes of my life have stood. I would like to share with you some of the feelings of my heart and direct them especially to the youth.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted.p6" pid="VkAmtSg8uEeQOaiyf2mTiQ" hash="HVZIgw">One of the great heroes from the Old Testament was the prophet-warrior Joshua. He extended this invitation to the children of Israel, whom he led: “Choose you this day whom ye will serve; … but as for me and my house, we will serve the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Joshua’s declaration demonstrates true conversion to the gospel. For Joshua and all of us, conversion to gospel principles comes through righteously living the principles of the gospel and being true to our covenants with the Lord.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted.p7" pid="g8jNyR0t0Ue1uK6ZB_KG7A" hash="SYgy9Q">I would like to share a conversion story from my family history about another of my heroes. Her name is Agnes Hoggan, and she and her husband joined the Church in Scotland in 1861. Suffering great persecution in their homeland, they immigrated to America with their children. Several years later, Agnes became a widow with eight children to support and worked hard to keep them fed and clothed. Her 12-year-old daughter, Isabelle, was lucky enough to find employment as a servant to a wealthy, non-LDS family.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted.p8" pid="lJ16FYR0iE6Nrgqcs-kS4Q" hash="rpvs-w">Isabelle lived in their large home and helped look after their younger children. In exchange for her services, a small wage was paid each week to her mother. Isabelle was soon accepted as a member of the family and began to enjoy many of the same privileges, such as taking dance lessons, wearing beautiful clothing, and attending the theater. This arrangement continued for four years, until the family for whom Isabelle worked was transferred to another state. They had grown so fond of Isabelle that they approached her mother, Agnes, and asked for permission to legally adopt her. They promised they would provide her with a good education, see that she married well, and make her an heir to their estate with their own children. They would also continue to make payments to Agnes.</p>
		</span>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted.p9" pid="rHP6BlqP-USMEQPbm67uSA" hash="Blvh4g">This struggling widow and mother had a hard decision to make, but she did not hesitate for a moment. Listen to the words of her granddaughter, written many years later: “If her love had not compelled [her] to say no, she had an even better reason—she had come all the way from Scotland and had gone through tribulations and trials for the Gospel, and she did not intend, if humanly possible, to let a child of hers lose what she had come so far to gain.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> The wealthy family used every possible argument, and Isabelle herself cried and begged to be allowed to go, but Agnes remained firm. As you can imagine, 16-year-old Isabelle felt as if her life was ruined.</p>
		</span>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted.p10" pid="ZuGdud6MCkSD_8CmWjyhOg" hash="kr3ftQ">Isabelle Hoggan is my great-grandmother, and I am most grateful for the testimony and conviction that burned so brightly in her mother’s heart, which did not allow her to trade her daughter’s membership in the Church for worldly promises. Today, hundreds of her descendants who enjoy the blessings of membership in the Church are the beneficiaries of Agnes’s deep-seated faith and conversion to the gospel.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted.p11" pid="1qVhdD2j4k2THWtyXwJxZQ" hash="2fro4Q">Young friends, we live in perilous times, and the decisions which you are called upon to make on a daily, or even hourly, basis have eternal consequences. The decisions you make in your daily life will determine what happens to you later. If you do not yet have a firmly rooted testimony and conviction that The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is the kingdom of God on the earth, now is the time to do what it takes to gain that conviction. To delay making the effort required to earn that kind of conviction can be dangerous to your soul.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted.p12" pid="ZOBr4z5-M0O0laOXB7W6ag" hash="iwAb4Q">True conversion is more than merely having a knowledge of gospel principles and implies even more than just having a testimony of those principles. It is possible to have a testimony of the gospel without living it. Being truly converted means we are acting upon what we believe and allowing it to create “a mighty change in us, or in our hearts.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> In the booklet <span class="emphasis">True to the Faith,</span> we learn that “conversion is <span class="pageBreak" page-number="77"></span>a process, not an event. You become converted as a result of … righteous efforts to follow the Savior.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> It takes time, effort, and work. My great-great-grandmother had a strong conviction that the gospel was more important for her children than all that the world had to offer in the way of wealth and comfort because she had sacrificed, endured, and lived the gospel. Her conversion came through living the principles of the gospel and sacrificing for them.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted.p13" pid="hZ-8kOnmDUqnBawvBh9FkA" hash="gCrOjw">We have to go through that same process if we want to gain that same kind of commitment. The Savior taught, “If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it be of God, or whether I speak of myself.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Sometimes we try to do it backward. For example, we may take this approach: I will be happy to live the law of tithing, but first I need to know that it’s true. Maybe we even pray to gain a testimony of the law of tithing and hope the Lord will bless us with that testimony before we have ever filled out a tithing slip. It just doesn’t work that way. The Lord expects us to exercise faith. We have to consistently pay a full and honest tithe in order to gain a testimony of tithing. This same pattern applies to all the principles of the gospel, whether it is the law of chastity, the principle of modesty, the Word of Wisdom, or the law of the fast.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted.p14" pid="LYqytaW63EW0PaPA7RG8GA" hash="jS_AMQ">I would like to share an example of how living a principle helps us become converted to that principle. I was a young woman in the ’60s and the only LDS girl in my high school. It was a revolutionary period characterized by the rejection of traditional morals, drug use, and an “anything goes” mentality. Many of my peers were good people but found it easy to get caught up in the excitement of this new morality, which actually was just the old immorality. My parents and teachers at church had impressed upon me the value of treating my body with respect, keeping a clear mind, and most of all, learning to trust in the Lord’s commandments. I made the decision to avoid situations where I knew alcohol would be present and to stay clear of tobacco and drugs. It often meant I was not included at parties, and I rarely dated. Drug use was becoming more and more common among young people, and the dangers were not as well known as they are today. Many of my peers later suffered permanent damage from mind-altering drugs or got caught up in serious addictions. I was grateful to have been taught to live the Word of Wisdom in my home, and I gained a deep testimony of that principle of the gospel as I exercised faith and lived it. The good feeling that came to me from living a true gospel principle was the Spirit of the Holy Ghost confirming that the principle was true. That is when true conversion begins to take place.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted.p15" pid="SbJdHZpT00SJqN5n7dAE_A" hash="R9KjmQ">The prophet Moroni, in the Book of Mormon, taught, “I would show unto the world that faith is things which are hoped for and not seen; wherefore, dispute not because ye see not, for ye receive no witness until after the trial of your faith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> In our world where instant gratification is the expectation, we are often guilty of expecting the reward without having to work for it. I believe Moroni is telling us that we must do the work first and exercise faith by living the gospel, and then we will receive the witness that it is true. True conversion occurs as you continue to act upon the doctrines you know are true and keep the commandments, day after day, month after month.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted.p16" pid="6HK4LhUFAUqUEll1jspFcg" hash="OoxNTA">This is a glorious time to be a youth in the Church. You are the first to participate in the youth curriculum <span class="emphasis">Come, Follow Me,</span> which has as one of its main purposes your conversion to the gospel of Jesus Christ. It is well to remember that no matter how inspired your parents and youth leaders may be, “you have [the] primary responsibility for your own conversion. No one can be converted for you, and no one can force you to be converted.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> Conversion takes place as we are diligent about saying <span class="pageBreak" page-number="78"></span>our prayers, studying our scriptures, attending church, and being worthy to participate in temple ordinances. Conversion comes as we act upon the righteous principles we learn in our homes and in the classroom. Conversion comes as we live pure and virtuous lives and enjoy the companionship of the Holy Ghost. Conversion comes as we understand the Atonement of Jesus Christ, acknowledge Him as our Savior and Redeemer, and allow the Atonement to take effect in our lives.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted.p17" pid="sUwuqOKfAUSK2DjUYYnKbg" hash="-z0qJA">Your personal conversion will help you as you prepare to make covenants in the temple, serve missions, and establish your own future homes. As you are converted, you will have a desire to share with others what you have learned, and your confidence and ability to testify to others with conviction and power will increase. This desire to share the gospel with others and the confidence to testify boldly are natural results of true conversion. The Savior taught Peter, “When thou art converted, strengthen thy brethren.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted.p18" pid="mRyaRDn5_k6w4mIRJT9BcA" hash="F5jH2Q">Remember Joshua, the prophet-warrior? He was not only converted himself, but he worked tirelessly to the end of his life to bring the children of Israel to God. We read in the Old Testament, “And Israel served the Lord all the days of Joshua.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> A person who has experienced true conversion draws upon the power of the Atonement and receives salvation for his or her own soul, then reaches out to exert a powerful influence upon all those who know him or her.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted.p19" pid="z1Ykr4QS9USaU14GuHNIRg" hash="gXA75Q">Living the gospel and standing in holy places is not always easy or comfortable, but I testify that it is worth it! The Lord counseled Emma Smith to “lay aside the things of this world, and seek for the things of a better.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> I suspect we cannot begin to imagine just how magnificent those “things of a better” world are!</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted.p20" pid="dyQPLgRuokybsE0ujKV5-Q" hash="pzwKUw">I testify that we have a loving Heavenly Father whose greatest desire is to help and bless us in our efforts to live the gospel and be converted. He has clearly stated that His main focus and work is our “immortality and eternal life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> He desires to bring us home to His presence. I testify that as we act upon the doctrines of the gospel and put them into daily practice, we will become converted and will become the means of accomplishing much good in our families and in the world. May we all be blessed in our daily efforts to reach for that goal is my prayer in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2013/10/be-ye-converted</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2013-general-conference/2013-10-4030-bonnie-oscarson-64k-eng.mp3" length="5573054" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sisterhood: Oh, How We Need Each Other</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Bonnie L. Oscarson teaches that we can learn from girls and women of all ages and that we must avoid judging each other. </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10985_000_62oscarson" doc-version="2" hash="ls5I1Q">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="_RGmUruXAkuIyYwU5a1T2w" hash="M6uuIQ">Sisterhood: Oh, How We Need Each Other</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p" pid="ucojlSrH1UWSdVhjkfuR_g" hash="TqkN2g">By Bonnie L. Oscarson</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p" pid="hBaMKkEy5k25NyVRFiWxwg" hash="GW9UoA">Young Women General President</p>
		</div>
		<img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/leaders/bonnie-l-oscarson.jpg" altText="Bonnie L. Oscarson" pid="fYaX5Twzm0-he2Rf4-itww" hash="o6Xc4w" />
		<p class="kicker" pid="qKdZR7mGeUeJQp3KCHkBJg" hash="VeR6rA">We must stop concentrating on our differences and look for what we have in common.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="W8mHkuuDAECa6za6ip01gA" hash="TqkN2g1">By Bonnie L. Oscarson</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="d2LQQTR8JECiW5i_gihj5A" hash="pypmEw">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p5" pid="4RmBqMoehUuvIpXBLkVEsw" hash="VIA-wg">
			<span class="pageBreak" page-number="119"></span>In that video we saw eight countries and heard nine different languages. Imagine how many more languages were added on that final verse. It is thrilling to know that as a worldwide sisterhood we were able to raise our voices in testimony of the eternal truth that we are daughters of a loving Heavenly Father.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p6" pid="86SYfEVXPUKx4h1kE7b4iw" hash="OrnnpA">What a great privilege it is to be here on this historic occasion and address all the women of the Church ages eight and above. There is tremendous strength in our unity this evening. As I see all of us gathered together in the Conference Center and contemplate the thousands of others who are viewing this broadcast from locations around the world, the combined power of our testimonies and faith in Jesus Christ surely constitutes one of the most faith-filled and powerful assemblies of women in the history of the Church, if not the world.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p7" pid="GkF-5M1oUUyAV0xUAZRzsg" hash="jzCdXg">Tonight we rejoice in our many different roles as women in the Church. Though in many ways we are different and unique, we also acknowledge that we are all daughters of the same Heavenly Father, which makes us sisters. We are unified in building the kingdom of God and in the covenants which we have made, no matter what our circumstances. This combined assembly is, without a doubt, the most glorious sisterhood upon the face of the earth!<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p8" pid="MGGeabfvG0iJ0bFIMQK5EA" hash="JgPddw">To be sisters implies that there is an unbreakable bond between us. Sisters take care of each other, watch out for each other, comfort each other, and are there for each other through thick and thin. The Lord has said, “I say unto you, be one; and if ye are not one ye are not mine.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p9" pid="TggU24NLOkWv_kEnHbPVWw" hash="qzW4rQ">The adversary would have us be critical or judgmental of one another. He wants us to concentrate on our differences and compare ourselves to one another. You may love to exercise vigorously for an hour each day because it makes you feel so good, while I consider it to be a major athletic event if I walk up one flight of stairs instead of taking the elevator. We can still be friends, can’t we?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p10" pid="T8Ub8TP_cUOPlAWTWTsWQg" hash="3mgaJg">We as women can be particularly hard on ourselves. When we compare ourselves to one another, we will always feel inadequate or resentful of others. Sister Patricia T. Holland once said, “The point is, we simply cannot call ourselves Christian and continue to judge one another—or ourselves—so harshly.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> She goes on to say that there is nothing that is worth us losing our compassion and sisterhood over. We just need to relax and rejoice in our divine differences. We need to realize that we all desire to serve in the kingdom, using our unique talents and gifts in our own ways. Then we <span class="pageBreak" page-number="120"></span>can enjoy our sisterhood and our associations and begin to serve.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p11" pid="m_f-l5Kc5EaV_0EmOcgNNw" hash="eBBXxA">The fact of the matter is, we really and truly need each other. Women naturally seek friendship, support, and companionship. We have so much to learn from one another, and we often let self-imposed barriers keep us from enjoying associations which could be among the greatest blessings in our lives. For example, we women who are a little older need what you Primary-age girls have to offer. We can learn much from you about Christlike service and love.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p12" pid="4QfVcqAyAUmWqUPKIURxEA" hash="qsqCXw">I recently heard a wonderful story about a little girl named Sarah, whose mother had the opportunity to help another woman in her ward named Brenda, who had multiple sclerosis. Sarah loved to go with her mother to help Brenda. She would put lotion on Brenda’s hands and massage her fingers and arms because she was often in pain. Sarah then learned to gently stretch Brenda’s arms over her head to exercise her muscles. Sarah brushed Brenda’s hair and visited with her while her mother took care of her other needs. Sarah learned the importance and joy of serving another person and came to understand that even a child can make a big difference in someone’s life.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p13" pid="XIait9rmnUmL0iPPkUmRPA" hash="ySLRJg">I love the example we have in the <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/1" class="scriptureRef">first chapter of Luke</a> which describes the sweet relationship between Mary, the mother of Jesus, and her cousin Elisabeth. Mary was a young woman when she was informed of her remarkable mission to be the mother of the Son of God. Initially it must have seemed to be a heavy responsibility to bear alone. It was the Lord Himself who provided Mary with someone to share her load. Through the message of the angel Gabriel, Mary was given the name of a trusted and sympathetic woman to whom she could turn for support—her cousin Elisabeth.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p14" pid="HgIgXso8PEKBCjOO7NU3oQ" hash="E4UbnQ">This young maiden and her cousin, who was “well stricken in years,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> shared a common bond in their miraculous pregnancies, and I can only imagine how very important the three months they spent together were to both of them as they were able to talk together, empathize with each other, and support one another in their unique callings. What a wonderful model they are of feminine nurturing between generations.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p15" pid="TdYAY5BzSkiAOmTZtFKg5A" hash="NDQVSQ">Those of us who are a little more mature can have a tremendous influence on the younger generations. When my mother was just a little girl, neither of her parents was active in the Church. Even at the young age of five, she would walk by herself to church and attend her meetings—Primary, Sunday School, and sacrament meeting—all at different times.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p16" pid="5njex1wPPk6NU-W5xCDqOA" hash="lkcRhQ">I recently asked my mother why in the world she did that week after week when she had no support or encouragement at home. Her answer was: “I had Primary teachers who loved me.” These teachers cared about her and taught her the gospel. They taught her that she had a Father in Heaven, who loved her, and it was their concern for her that kept her coming week after week. My mother said to me, “That was one of the most important influences in my early life.” I hope I can thank those wonderful sisters someday! There is no age barrier when it comes to Christlike service.</p>
		</span>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p17" pid="pNbl6GRtF0WD_DyGR5JCOQ" hash="ueZsew">A couple of weeks ago, I met a stake Young Women president in California who told me that her 81-year-old mother had recently been called to be a Mia Maid adviser. I was so intrigued I gave her mother a call. When Sister Val Baker’s bishop asked to meet with her, she was looking forward to being called as a librarian or ward historian. When he asked her to serve as a Mia Maid adviser to the Young Women, her reaction was, “Are you sure?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p18" pid="PsG9Jh7vJUWxEdGF4v9eRQ" hash="lQ9kow">
				<span class="pageBreak" page-number="121"></span>Her bishop solemnly replied, “Sister Baker, make no mistake; this call is from the Lord.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p19" pid="tIYvH5E73kS4fRD6YKe6Jg" hash="NzkolQ">She said she had no other answer to that except, “Of course.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p20" pid="p-CNPDB4kUG2cl3TDr4nUA" hash="C0Lk2Q">I love the inspiration this bishop felt that the four Mia Maids in his ward have much to learn from the wisdom, experience, and lifelong example of this mature sister. And guess whom Sister Baker will go to when she needs help setting up her Facebook page?</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p21" pid="uIX0fQvfJkyWmSvQX4wQKg" hash="0BC92A">I think of the great help that the sisters in Relief Society can be in welcoming young sisters who have recently been in Young Women. Our young sisters frequently feel as if they don’t have a place or anything in common with those in Relief Society. Before they turn 18, they need Young Women leaders and mothers who will joyfully testify of the great blessings of Relief Society. They need to feel enthusiastic about becoming part of such a glorious organization. When young women begin attending Relief Society, what they need most is a friend to sit next to, an arm around their shoulders, and an opportunity to teach and serve. Let us all reach out to help one another through the transitions and milestones of our lives.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p22" pid="VTh80YupeUOg-MoETHya0A" hash="3ytqxg">Thank you to all the women of the Church who are reaching out across age and cultural lines to bless and serve others. Young women are serving Primary children and the elderly. Single sisters of all ages spend countless hours watching out for the needs of those around them. We recognize the thousands of young women who are giving up 18 months of their lives to share the gospel with the world. All of these things are evidence that, as our beloved hymn states, “The errand of angels is given to women.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p23" pid="vBzv0_07PUChnn9lR7WXLg" hash="VACtiQ">If there are barriers, it is because we ourselves have created them. We must stop concentrating on our differences and look for what we have in common; then we can begin to realize our greatest potential and achieve the greatest good in this world. Sister Marjorie P. Hinckley once said, “Oh, how we need each other. Those of us who are old need you who are young. And, hopefully, you who are young need some of us who are old. It is a sociological fact that women need women. We need deep and satisfying and loyal friendships with each other.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> Sister Hinckley was right; oh, how we need each other!</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p24" pid="sWLNo489Mk6eMXtSbbswpg" hash="4zRc5Q">Sisters, there is no other group of women in the world who have access to greater blessings than we do as Latter-day Saint women. We are members of the Lord’s Church, and regardless of our individual circumstances, we can all enjoy the full blessings of priesthood power through keeping the covenants we have made at baptism and in the temple. We have living prophets to lead and teach us, and we enjoy the great gift of the Holy Ghost, which serves as a comfort and guide in our lives. We are blessed to work hand in hand with righteous brothers as we strengthen homes and families. We have access to the strength and power of temple ordinances and so much more.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p25" pid="-q-hibUNrU2Yq4-hMLV-BQ" hash="OstOlw">In addition to enjoying all of these magnificent blessings, we have each other—sisters in the gospel of Jesus Christ. We have been blessed with tender and charitable natures which enable us to render Christlike love and service to those around us. As we look beyond our differences in age, culture, and circumstance to nurture and serve one another, we will be filled with the pure love of Christ and the inspiration which leads us to know when and whom to serve.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other.p26" pid="uGVRbtzDPEekPK1CZ_p8Gw" hash="pXCDbg">I extend to you an invitation that was issued once before by a Relief Society general president who said, “I invite you to not only love each other more but love each other <span class="emphasis">better.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> May we realize just how much we need each other, and may we all love one another better, is my prayer in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/04/sisterhood-oh-how-we-need-each-other</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/march-2014-general-womens-meeting/2014-03-0030-bonnie-l-oscarson-64k-eng.mp3" length="5441576" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defenders of the Family Proclamation</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sister Bonnie L. Oscarson encourages Latter-day Saint women to defend marriage, the divine roles of parents, and the sanctity of the home.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_12565_000_63oscarson" doc-version="6" hash="8vPVSw">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="-I3ps-RAgke70J99EAeI_g" hash="8sIMnw">Defenders of the Family Proclamation</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p2" pid="R4o_2pGJ1EaceZxaQgAo-A" hash="TqkN2g"> By Bonnie L. Oscarson </p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p3" pid="9AtFubOf_EqBJVLNJ6AAew" hash="GW9UoA">Young Women General President</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=y8EwqPXznkGoqfr5sKvccg"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" type="jpg" uri="bonnie-oscarson-sm-1190455.jpg" translate="no" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/100x135.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x67="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/50x67.jpg" data-src-100x135="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/100x135.jpg" data-src-200x271="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/200x271.jpg" data-src-320x434="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/320x434.jpg" data-src-460x624="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/460x624.jpg" data-src-640x868="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/640x868.jpg" data-src-1024x1389="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/1024x1389.jpg" data-src-2048x2779="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/2048x2779.jpg" data-src-3440x4669="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/3440x4669.jpg" pid="y8EwqPXznkGoqfr5sKvccg" hash="5kJWiA"></img></a>
		</div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="a6TyJ2OiQkWWiKUc2CL-wg" hash="Kjz5Kg">Let us help build the kingdom of God by standing up boldly and being defenders of marriage, parenthood, and the home.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="EqCWZ6gXUU-5Nb_5AoJE8A" hash="TqkN2g1"> By Bonnie L. Oscarson </p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="XA2YUQ1tIU-klNk0YdsVHA" hash="8JqAGQ">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p5" pid="bZ8NamqdDEerzAZ-NBawmA" hash="xDNYrw">What a privilege and joy to be a part of this marvelous assembly of girls and women. How blessed we are as women to be joined together this evening in unity and in love.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=YMb4uYmhD0WEf4d0sMQkcQ"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445736/f48bd482e1e54805a1ce399e2918030c/100x178.png" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x89="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445736/f48bd482e1e54805a1ce399e2918030c/50x89.png" data-src-100x178="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445736/f48bd482e1e54805a1ce399e2918030c/100x178.png" data-src-200x356="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445736/f48bd482e1e54805a1ce399e2918030c/200x356.png" data-src-320x569="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445736/f48bd482e1e54805a1ce399e2918030c/320x569.png" data-src-460x818="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445736/f48bd482e1e54805a1ce399e2918030c/460x818.png" data-src-640x1139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445736/f48bd482e1e54805a1ce399e2918030c/640x1139.png" data-src-1011x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445736/f48bd482e1e54805a1ce399e2918030c/1011x1800.png" altText="" pid="YMb4uYmhD0WEf4d0sMQkcQ" hash="Qjl6mg"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p6" pid="e82XUtvM-UCd7pq3kywz7A" hash="3bmWbQ">I recently read the story of Marie Madeline Cardon, who, with her family, received the message of the restored gospel of Jesus Christ from the first missionaries called to serve in Italy in 1850. She was a young woman of 17 or 18 years of age when they were baptized. One Sunday, while the family was holding a worship service in their home high in the Alps of northern Italy, an angry mob of men, including some of the local ministers, gathered around the house and began shouting, yelling, and calling for the missionaries to be brought outside. I don’t think they were anxious to be taught the gospel—they intended bodily harm. It was young Marie who marched out of the house to confront the mob.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p7" pid="3WSdtfh_Z0Kd5hofqCnunA" hash="8J8gyA"> They continued their vicious yells and demands for the missionaries to be brought out. Marie raised her Bible up in her hand and commanded them to depart. She told them that the elders were under her protection and that they could not harm one hair of their heads. Listen to her own words: “All stood aghast. … God was with me. He placed those words in my mouth, or I could not have spoken them. All was calm, instantly. That strong ferocious body of men stood helpless before a weak, trembling, yet fearless girl.” The ministers asked the mob to leave, which they did quietly in shame, fear, and remorse. The small flock completed their meeting in peace.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p8" pid="V0W8WKph-0mvBfaXlBoecQ" hash="oFU9pw">Can’t you just picture that brave young woman, the same age as many of you, standing up to a mob and defending her newly found beliefs with courage and conviction?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p9" pid="-E-WnUBTJE2m_EgyjenT3g" hash="ij8CdA">Sisters, few of us will ever have to face an angry mob, but there is a war going on in this world in which our most cherished and basic doctrines are under attack. I am speaking specifically of the doctrine of the family. The sanctity of the home and the essential purposes of the family are being questioned, criticized, and assaulted on every front.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p10" pid="TzGwEBDhfkifH-qbG_PE-Q" hash="y7M5_Q"> When President Gordon B. Hinckley first read “The Family: A Proclamation to the World” 20 years ago this year, we were grateful for and valued the clarity, simplicity, and truth of this revelatory document. Little did we realize then how very desperately we would need these basic declarations in today’s world as the criteria by which we could judge each new wind of worldly dogma coming at us from the media, the Internet, scholars, TV and films, and even legislators. The proclamation on the family has become our benchmark for judging the philosophies of the world, and I testify that the principles set forth within this statement are as true today as they were when they were given to us by a prophet of God nearly 20 years ago. </p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p11" pid="FcCPlcC3N0agpSq_O9vUEg" hash="ZmJ9FA">May I point out something obvious? Life rarely goes exactly according to plan for anyone, and we are very aware that not all women are experiencing what the proclamation describes. It is still important to understand and teach the Lord’s pattern and strive for the realization of that pattern the best we can.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p12" pid="i506qsQB20mP7CXvdaijsA" hash="RJLAjQ">Each of us has a part to play in the plan, and each of us is equally valued in the eyes of the Lord. We should remember that a loving Heavenly Father is aware of our righteous desires and will honor His promises that nothing will be withheld from those who faithfully keep their covenants. Heavenly Father has a mission and plan for each of us, but He also has His own timetable. One of the hardest challenges in this life is to have faith in the Lord’s timing. It’s a good idea to have an alternative plan in mind, which helps us to be covenant-keeping, charitable, and righteous women who build the kingdom of God no matter which way our lives go. We need to teach our daughters to aim for the ideal but plan for contingencies.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p13" pid="pbV4sL-hxUW3dIGvK52ZmA" hash="hZKSWQ">During this 20th anniversary year of the family proclamation, I would like to issue a challenge for all of us as women of the Church to be defenders of “The Family: A Proclamation to the World.” Just as Marie Madeline Cardon courageously defended the missionaries and her newly found beliefs, we need to boldly defend the Lord’s revealed doctrines describing marriage, families, the divine roles of men and women, and the importance of homes as sacred places—even when the world is shouting in our ears that these principles are outdated, limiting, or no longer relevant. Everyone, no matter what their marital circumstance or number of children, can be defenders of the Lord’s plan described in the family proclamation. If it is the Lord’s plan, it should also be our plan!</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p14" pid="h6AOGPthMEGztwBrNdsxfw" hash="AisZLg"> There are three principles taught in the proclamation which I think are especially in need of steadfast defenders. The first is marriage between a man and a woman. We are taught in the scriptures, “Nevertheless neither is the man without the woman, neither the woman without the man, in the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> For anyone to attain the fulness of priesthood blessings, there must be a husband and a wife sealed in the house of the Lord, working together in righteousness and remaining faithful to their covenants. This is the Lord’s plan for His children, and no amount of public discourse or criticism will change what the Lord has declared. We need to continue to model righteous marriages, seek for that blessing in our lives, and have faith if it is slow in coming. Let us be defenders of marriage as the Lord has ordained it while continuing to show love and compassion for those with differing views. </p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p15" pid="Lw06zwvLvUSMr1lMQvMf9A" hash="8RVlrQ"> The next principle which calls for our defending voices is elevating the divine roles of mothers and fathers. We eagerly teach our children to aim high in this life. We want to make sure that our daughters know that they have the potential to achieve and be whatever they can imagine. We hope they will love learning, be educated, talented, and maybe even become the next Marie Curie or Eliza R. Snow. </p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p16" pid="LY2Q5tlRX0y0jRZRfnp9cQ" hash="X1BlbQ">Do we also teach our sons and daughters there is no greater honor, no more elevated title, and no more important role in this life than that of mother or father? I would hope that as we encourage our children to reach for the very best in this life that we also teach them to honor and exalt the roles that mothers and fathers play in Heavenly Father’s plan.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p17" pid="DvI1B68JaE-J-chNw_coSw" hash="XpQUew">Our youngest daughter, Abby, saw a unique opportunity to stand as a defender of the role of mother. One day she got a notice from her children’s school that they were having Career Day presentations at the school. Parents were invited to send in an application if they wanted to come to school to teach the children about their jobs, and Abby felt impressed to apply to come and speak about motherhood. She didn’t hear back from the school, and when Career Day was getting close, she finally called the school, thinking they may have lost her application. The organizers scrambled around and found two teachers who agreed to have Abby come talk to their classes at the end of Career Day.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p18" pid="5pwbrbyDs0i3vt6q1Ae-dA" hash="nXFNqw">In her very fun presentation to the children, Abby taught them, among other things, that as a mother she needed to be somewhat of an expert in medicine, psychology, religion, teaching, music, literature, art, finance, decorating, hair styling, chauffeuring, sports, culinary arts, and so much more. The children were impressed. She finished by having the children remember their mothers by writing thank-you notes expressing gratitude for the many loving acts of service they received daily. Abby felt that the children saw their mothers in a whole new light and that being a mother or father was something of great worth. She applied to share again this year at Career Day and was invited to present to six classes.</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=_DobtgOWvUCIbGnsz4EtTw"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445732/be4e143127694d2e997bbf97eff54166/100x156.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x78="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445732/be4e143127694d2e997bbf97eff54166/50x78.jpg" data-src-100x156="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445732/be4e143127694d2e997bbf97eff54166/100x156.jpg" data-src-200x313="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445732/be4e143127694d2e997bbf97eff54166/200x313.jpg" data-src-320x502="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445732/be4e143127694d2e997bbf97eff54166/320x502.jpg" data-src-460x721="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445732/be4e143127694d2e997bbf97eff54166/460x721.jpg" data-src-640x1004="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445732/be4e143127694d2e997bbf97eff54166/640x1004.jpg" data-src-1024x1606="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445732/be4e143127694d2e997bbf97eff54166/1024x1606.jpg" data-src-1147x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445732/be4e143127694d2e997bbf97eff54166/1147x1800.jpg" altText="" pid="_DobtgOWvUCIbGnsz4EtTw" hash="SY-8Pg"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p19" pid="saT1YaJmEEWbNea0WH2olQ" hash="76qZ2g">Abby has said of her experience: “I feel like it could be easy in this world for a child to get the sense that being a parent is a secondary job or even sometimes a necessary inconvenience. I want every child to feel like they are the most important priority to their parent, and maybe telling them how important being a parent is to me will help them realize all that their parents do for them and why.”</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p20" pid="5p6UimPTcU2WhTfq5n8Ifw" hash="N3KTNg"> Our beloved prophet, President Thomas S. Monson, is a wonderful example of honoring women and motherhood, especially his own mother. In reference to our earthly mothers, he has said: “May each of us treasure this truth; one cannot forget mother and remember God. One cannot remember mother and forget God. Why? Because these two sacred persons, God and [our earthly] mother, partners in creation, in love, in sacrifice, in service, are as one.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p21" pid="d-H_Mzmp30O54_BwinRf-Q" hash="S-51mw"> The last principle we need to stand and defend is the sanctity of the home. We need to take a term which is sometimes spoken of with derision and elevate it. It is the term <span class="emphasis">homemaker.</span> All of us—women, men, youth, and children, single or married—can work at being homemakers. We should “make our homes” places of order, refuge, holiness, and safety. Our homes should be places where the Spirit of the Lord is felt in rich abundance and where the scriptures and the gospel are studied, taught, and lived. What a difference it would make in the world if all people would see themselves as makers of righteous homes. Let us defend the home as a place which is second only to the temple in holiness. </p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p22" pid="m3yhbVF1-U217J6DwpwaiA" hash="epn09Q">Sisters, I am grateful to be a woman in these latter days. We have opportunities and possibilities which no other generation of women has had in the world. Let us help build the kingdom of God by standing up boldly and being defenders of marriage, parenthood, and the home. The Lord needs us to be brave, steadfast, and immovable warriors who will defend His plan and teach the upcoming generations His truths.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation.p23" pid="S1iJT9RCn0WbkrQdqNtEtg" hash="libZzg">I bear witness that Heavenly Father lives and loves each of us. His Son, Jesus Christ, is our Savior and Redeemer. I leave this testimony with you in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/04/defenders-of-the-family-proclamation</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2015-general-conference/2015-03-0040-bonnie-l-oscarson-64k-eng.mp3" length="5537195" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do I Believe?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13285_000_52oscarson" doc-version="3" hash="XGV_-w"&gt;
	
	&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.head1"&gt;
		&lt;h1 class="title" pid="RQEz3SPIhUCTZxqmdqKnVw" hash="KTKCUg"&gt;Do I Believe?&lt;/h1&gt;
		&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p2" pid="ifVAzntrbkq-4XKa8zHAeA" hash="TqkN2g1"&gt;By Bonnie L. Oscarson&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p3" pid="IyRIQC960kCeobUSTeUaVA" hash="GW9UoA"&gt;Young Women General President&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=ymNa01iVckCECRuHdnWhyg"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" altText="Bonnie L. Oscarson" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/100x135.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x67="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/50x67.jpg" data-src-100x135="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/100x135.jpg" data-src-200x271="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/200x271.jpg" data-src-320x434="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/320x434.jpg" data-src-460x624="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/460x624.jpg" data-src-640x868="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/640x868.jpg" data-src-1024x1389="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/1024x1389.jpg" data-src-2048x2779="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/2048x2779.jpg" data-src-3440x4669="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255562/7de2dad240cd454f90ce8384311a1488/3440x4669.jpg" webURL="../../../../leaders/bonnie-l-oscarson.jpg" pid="ymNa01iVckCECRuHdnWhyg" hash="AAAAAA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="kicker" pid="kA6km1imgkikgDa0sy4uLA" hash="XjvaAw"&gt;If these things are true, then we have the greatest message of hope and help that the world has ever known.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="authorName" pid="EUrDaKRAHU6GeRJPCHmegg" hash="TqkN2g"&gt;By Bonnie L. Oscarson&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class="bodyBlock"&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p5" pid="mBAVtBIBqEuG6O2zvVEZyw" hash="0MBsLA"&gt;On March 30, just one year ago, little two-year-old Ethan Carnesecca, from American Fork, Utah, was admitted to the hospital with pneumonia and fluid around his lungs. Two days later, his condition had become so serious that he needed to be flown by helicopter to Primary Children’s Hospital in Salt Lake City. His worried mother, Michele, was allowed to ride in the front seat and accompany her son. She was given a headset so she could communicate with the others in the helicopter. She could hear the medics working on her sick little boy, and being a pediatric nurse herself, Michele knew enough to understand that Ethan was in serious trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=7HtHEQ1Ickuzs7f9Accrww"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709246/56fd0c697cd24800aa165602d5790142/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709246/56fd0c697cd24800aa165602d5790142/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709246/56fd0c697cd24800aa165602d5790142/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709246/56fd0c697cd24800aa165602d5790142/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709246/56fd0c697cd24800aa165602d5790142/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709246/56fd0c697cd24800aa165602d5790142/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709246/56fd0c697cd24800aa165602d5790142/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709246/56fd0c697cd24800aa165602d5790142/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709246/56fd0c697cd24800aa165602d5790142/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709246/56fd0c697cd24800aa165602d5790142/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Ethan Carnesecca while ill" pid="7HtHEQ1Ickuzs7f9Accrww" hash="hUSS_Q"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p6" pid="Jlnu9yM6gUqfrOlMVI69dw" hash="YtwiJw"&gt;In this critical moment, Michele noticed they were flying directly over the Draper Utah Temple. From the air, she looked out across the valley and could also see the Jordan River Temple, the Oquirrh Mountain Temple, and even the Salt Lake Temple in the distance. The thought came into her mind: “Do you believe it or not?”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p7" pid="nnTCxaHYA0GVk6JVsvj77g" hash="cN4kHw"&gt;She says of this experience:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p8" pid="0hnbKdDcR0W3h8RV_uOo0A" hash="1HM_og"&gt;“I had learned about the blessings of the temple and [that] ‘families are forever’ in Primary and in Young Women. I shared the message on families to the good people of Mexico on my mission. I was sealed to my eternal companion for time and all eternity in the temple. I taught lessons about families as a Young Women leader, and I shared stories about forever families with my children in family home evening. I KNEW it, but did I BELIEVE it? My answer came as quickly as the question popped into my head: the Spirit confirmed to my heart and mind the answer I already knew—I DID believe it!&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p9" pid="VBfPPyK-1EypEVHsoMcC-Q" hash="yjBCtQ"&gt;“At that moment I poured out my heart in prayer to my Heavenly Father, thanking Him for the knowledge and belief I had that families truly are forever. I thanked Him for His Son, Jesus Christ, who made it all possible. I thanked Him for my son, and I let my Heavenly Father know if He needed to bring my little Ethan to His heavenly home, it was OK. I trusted in my Heavenly Father completely, and I knew I would see Ethan again. I was so grateful that in a crisis moment, I had the knowledge AND the belief that the gospel was true. I had peace.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p10" pid="ijTr09tvdESPYFZTaFnTIw" hash="tSz6dg"&gt;Ethan spent many weeks in the hospital, receiving expert medical care. The prayers, fasting, and faith of loved ones, combined with that care, allowed him to leave the hospital and return home to be with his family. He is healthy and well today.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=xl88O2pf10eQ-5en94dwdw"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709253/911957833b22431d9ee08c9a6829d743/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709253/911957833b22431d9ee08c9a6829d743/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709253/911957833b22431d9ee08c9a6829d743/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709253/911957833b22431d9ee08c9a6829d743/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709253/911957833b22431d9ee08c9a6829d743/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709253/911957833b22431d9ee08c9a6829d743/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709253/911957833b22431d9ee08c9a6829d743/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709253/911957833b22431d9ee08c9a6829d743/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709253/911957833b22431d9ee08c9a6829d743/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709253/911957833b22431d9ee08c9a6829d743/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Carnesecca family" pid="xl88O2pf10eQ-5en94dwdw" hash="rk_giw"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=JIqbilfFEUCBgIrG-3hdjw"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709247/22af8952e4014cd89e69d2def66776ca/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709247/22af8952e4014cd89e69d2def66776ca/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709247/22af8952e4014cd89e69d2def66776ca/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709247/22af8952e4014cd89e69d2def66776ca/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709247/22af8952e4014cd89e69d2def66776ca/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709247/22af8952e4014cd89e69d2def66776ca/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709247/22af8952e4014cd89e69d2def66776ca/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709247/22af8952e4014cd89e69d2def66776ca/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709247/22af8952e4014cd89e69d2def66776ca/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709247/22af8952e4014cd89e69d2def66776ca/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Ethan Carnesecca recovered" pid="JIqbilfFEUCBgIrG-3hdjw" hash="ZXAwYg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p11" pid="sbt0IVgSLkaYLnmYYOB4lQ" hash="CrV6rQ"&gt;This defining moment for Michele confirmed to her that what she had been taught all of her life was more than just words; it is true.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p12" pid="UFH1OjI-lkOqlVMpRVV7LQ" hash="AGAXNQ"&gt;Do we sometimes become so accustomed to the blessings we have been given as members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints that we fail to fully comprehend the miracle and majesty of discipleship in the Lord’s true Church? Are we ever guilty of being complacent about the greatest gift we can be offered in this life? The Savior Himself taught, “If you keep my commandments and endure to the end you shall have eternal life, which gift is the greatest of all the gifts of God.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p13" pid="bUCAcTVEokyvhXcAEbkijg" hash="_mHStw"&gt;We believe that this Church is more than just a good place to go on Sundays and learn how to be a good person. It is more than just a lovely Christian social club where we can associate with people of good moral standing. It is not just a great set of ideas that parents can teach their children at home so they will be responsible, nice people. The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is infinitely more than all of these things.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p14" pid="DuQe0phXOkqJ2x5lf2tIdw" hash="Yj3XwQ"&gt;Think for just a minute about the profound claims we make as a religion. We believe that the same Church Jesus Christ established while on the earth has been restored once again by a prophet called of God in our time and that our leaders hold the same power and authority to act in God’s name that ancient Apostles held. It is called the priesthood of God. We claim that through this restored authority, we can receive saving ordinances, such as baptism, and enjoy the purifying and refining gift of the Holy Ghost to be with us at all times. We have apostles and prophets leading and directing this Church through priesthood keys, and we believe that God speaks to His children through these prophets.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p15" pid="dpdN5N0w2UGjVBPe35RiZw" hash="40_axg"&gt;We also believe that this priesthood power makes it possible to make covenants and receive ordinances in holy temples that will someday enable us to return to the presence of God and live with Him forever. We also claim that, through this power, families can be bound together for eternity when couples enter the new and everlasting covenant of marriage in sacred buildings that we believe are literally the houses of God. We believe that we can receive these saving ordinances not only for ourselves but also for our ancestors who lived on the earth without having the chance to participate in these essential saving ordinances. We believe we can perform ordinances for our ancestors by proxy in these same holy temples.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p16" pid="W_6a1larj0aCEWNCu354zA" hash="zYzpXQ"&gt;We believe that, through a prophet and the power of God, we have received additional scriptures, adding to the testimony of that in the Bible declaring that Jesus Christ is the Savior of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p17" pid="B2_T9AGDx0uP13dCgdlGyw" hash="dboxGw"&gt;We claim that The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is the kingdom of God and the only true Church on the earth. It is called the Church of Jesus Christ because He stands at the head; it is His Church, and all these things are possible because of His atoning sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p18" pid="w7bpvKeMm0aZTEd0Edlghg" hash="F7l8OQ"&gt;We believe that these distinguishing features can be found in no other place or organization on this earth. As good and sincere as other religions and churches are, none of them have the authority to provide the ordinances of salvation that are available in The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p19" pid="dbaPJihPZ0qjiobwQb9ewA" hash="Vjks9A"&gt;We have a knowledge of these things, but &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;do we believe them&lt;/span&gt;? If these things are true, then we have the greatest message of hope and help that the world has ever known. Believing them is a matter of eternal significance for us and for those we love.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p20" pid="fiu73VQGPUyRDLSS8i5yPA" hash="NV3PmA"&gt;To believe, we need to get the gospel from our heads into our hearts! It is possible for us to merely go through the motions of living the gospel because it is expected or because it is the culture in which we have grown up or because it is a habit. Perhaps some have not experienced what King Benjamin’s people felt following his compelling sermon: “They all cried with one voice, saying: Yea, we believe all the words which thou hast spoken unto us; and also, we know of their surety and truth, because of the Spirit of the Lord Omnipotent, which has wrought a mighty change in us, or in our hearts, that we have no more disposition to do evil, but to do good continually.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p21" pid="5678MvsuS0-cZtzxqIwOnQ" hash="-5ciUA"&gt;We all need to seek to have our hearts and very natures changed so that we no longer have a desire to follow the ways of the world but to please God. True conversion is a process that takes place over a period of time and involves a willingness to exercise faith. It comes when we search the scriptures instead of the Internet. It comes when we are obedient to the commandments of God. Conversion comes when we serve those around us. It comes from earnest prayer, regular temple attendance, and faithful fulfillment of our God-given responsibilities. It takes consistency and daily effort.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p22" pid="iJzdRAdhAk6IgN5IHithsg" hash="2vgBkQ"&gt;I am often asked, “What is the greatest challenge our youth face today?” I answer that I believe it is the ever-present influence of the “great and spacious building” in their lives.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; If the Book of Mormon was written specifically for our day, then surely we cannot miss the relevance for all of us of the messages in Lehi’s vision of the tree of life and the effect of those pointing their fingers and taunting from the great and spacious building.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p23" pid="coRjzz7kZUua73zA-EBcWQ" hash="bueuDA"&gt;What is most heartrending to me is the description of those who have already fought their way through the mists of darkness on the strait and narrow path, have clung to the rod of iron, have reached their goal, and have begun tasting of the pure and delicious fruit of the tree of life. Then the scripture says that those finely dressed people in the great and spacious building “were in the attitude of mocking and pointing their fingers towards those who had come at and were partaking of the fruit.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p24" pid="Et5NpXu_rEaliQhqDHJlYg" hash="yKEclw"&gt;“And &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;after they had tasted of the fruit &lt;/span&gt;they were ashamed, because of those that were scoffing at them; and they fell away into forbidden paths and were lost.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p25" pid="khjd8dDNc0O4VyrI4GbqRw" hash="aH0cvA"&gt;These verses describe those of us who already have the gospel of Jesus Christ in our lives. Whether we were born into it or had to fight our way through mists of darkness to find it, we have tasted of this fruit, which “is most precious and most desirable”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; and has the potential to bring us eternal life, “the greatest of all the gifts of God.” We need only to keep feasting and not heed those who would make fun of our beliefs or those who delight to create doubts or those who find fault with Church leaders and doctrine. It is a choice we make daily—to choose faith over doubt. Elder M. Russell Ballard has urged us to “stay in the boat, use your life jackets, and hold on with both hands.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p26" pid="v2773nY80Uez4kYP_F_vhA" hash="8WwxoQ"&gt;As members of the Lord’s true Church, we are already in the boat. We don’t have to go searching through the philosophies of the world for truth that will give us comfort, help, and direction to get us safely through the trials of life—we already have it! Just as Ethan’s mother could examine her long-held beliefs and declare confidently in a moment of crisis, “I do believe it,” so can we!&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe.p27" pid="JBNvyfuhNkuRT87_b2ECTA" hash="2Lxzyw"&gt;I bear witness that our membership in the Lord’s kingdom is a gift of immeasurable value. I testify that the blessings and peace the Lord has in store for those who are obedient and faithful exceed anything the human mind can comprehend. I leave this testimony with you in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/04/do-i-believe</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2016-general-conference/2016-04-4020-bonnie-l-oscarson-64k-eng.mp3" length="5483575" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rise Up in Strength, Sisters in Zion</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sister Oscarson teaches sisters that they need to rise up to become women of faith by studying and having a testimony of the essential doctrines of the gospel.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60001311_000_13oscarson" doc-version="1" hash="O46OYw">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="BsvHMZ3990SrtGLqOlJKCA" hash="q0_LmA">Rise Up in Strength, Sisters in Zion</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p2" pid="fWzLziUwgU-EaQTvg-PWzA" hash="TqkN2g1">By Bonnie L. Oscarson</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p3" pid="VMoH8CjR80qRYOafsOQoAg" hash="GW9UoA">Young Women General President</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="54D3s2ofFkWmyJ8KcSdjYA" hash="KMDWLA">To be converted covenant keepers, we need to study the essential doctrines of the gospel and have an unshakable testimony of their truthfulness.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="U7_4Zi9_qkmPf2PhJM0reQ" hash="TqkN2g">By Bonnie L. Oscarson</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p5" pid="yRsxPNrhAk-GvV9YqxqmvQ" hash="ZLooQA">What joy it is to be gathered in this Conference Center with the girls, young women, and women of the Church. We are also very aware that there are thousands of other groups of sisters, gathered throughout the world, watching these proceedings, and I’m grateful for the opportunity and means that allow us to join together in unity and purpose this evening.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p6" pid="EJPbRrMU-kuBXPQuoL8GPw" hash="MgoYhQ">In October 2006, President Gordon B. Hinckley gave a talk entitled “Rise Up, O Men of God,” named after a hymn written in 1911.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> It was a call to action for the men of the Church to rise up and improve themselves. That talk has echoed in my mind as I have prayed to know what to share with you.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p7" pid="YQ6eB_r4kkWnE7dBsrBgAQ" hash="n3qZRA">Sisters, we live in “perilous times.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> The conditions of our day should not be a surprise to us. They have been foretold for millennia as a warning and admonition so that we can be prepared. The <a href="/scriptures/bofm/morm/8" class="scriptureRef">8th chapter of Mormon</a> gives a disconcertingly accurate description of the conditions of our day. In this chapter, Moroni says he has seen our day, and it includes wars and rumors of wars, great pollutions, murders, robbing, and people who tell us that there is no right or wrong in God’s eyes. He describes people who are filled with pride, caught up in the wearing of expensive clothing, and who make fun of religion. He is shown people who are so obsessed with worldly things that they allow “the needy, and the naked, and the sick and the afflicted to pass by”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> without being noticed.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p8" pid="aT63PEu--UihHVnyW4AUIQ" hash="2j1EPg">Moroni asks a soul-searching question of us—we who are living in these times. He says, “Why are ye ashamed to take upon you the name of Christ?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> This indictment accurately describes the increasingly secular condition of our world.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p9" pid="VSwvA1E0B0OgTg5kTDvCRQ" hash="bOS1Fg">Joseph Smith—Matthew indicates that in the last days even the “very elect … according to the covenant”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> will be deceived. Those of the covenant include the girls, young women, and sisters of the Church who have been baptized and made covenants with their Heavenly Father. Even <span class="emphasis">we</span> are at risk of being deceived by false teachings.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p10" pid="nx49RLf3E0mhUfNAMOQkqg" hash="cQFceA">Sisters, I don’t believe that conditions are going to improve going forward. If current trends are an indication, we need to be prepared for the storms that lie ahead. It would be easy to throw our hands up in despair, but as covenant people we need never despair. As Elder Gary E. Stevenson has said, “Heavenly Father’s generous compensation for living in perilous times is that we also live in the fulness of times.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> I love the comfort of that statement.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p11" pid="LI2CSoplwEavT7eOf4WdIg" hash="IBBCfA">President Russell M. Nelson told us a year ago: “Attacks against the Church, its doctrine, and our way of life are going to increase. Because of this, we need women who have a bedrock understanding of the doctrine of Christ and who will use that understanding to teach and help raise a sin-resistant generation. We need women who can detect deception in all of its forms. We need women who know how to access the power that God makes available to covenant keepers and who express their beliefs with confidence and charity. We need women who have the courage and vision of our Mother Eve.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p12" pid="WYPZc9XX8kKiFaLrZK3yqQ" hash="0G40MQ">This message reassures me that despite the conditions of our day, we have many reasons to rejoice and be optimistic. I believe with all of my heart that we sisters do have the innate strength and faith that will allow us to meet the challenges of living in the last days. Sister Sheri Dew has written, “I believe that the moment we learn to unleash the full influence of converted, covenant-keeping women, the kingdom of God will change overnight.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p13" pid="szZvIBSTL02wLGeD9iDf3w" hash="4F45Rw">It will take concerted effort to be converted and to keep our covenants. To do so, we need to be girls and women who study the essential doctrines of the gospel and have an unshakable testimony of their truthfulness. There are three areas I believe are foundational to strong testimonies and that I consider to be essential to our understanding.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p14" pid="5y-UvF1MkEyWSkClRS7xQw" hash="2VylPA">First, we need to acknowledge the centrality of God our Eternal Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, to our faith and salvation. Jesus Christ is our Savior and Redeemer. We need to study and understand His Atonement and how to apply it daily; repentance is one of the greatest blessings each of us has to stay on course. We need to see Jesus Christ as our primary role model and the example of who we need to become. We need to continually teach our families and classes about our Father’s great plan of salvation, which includes the doctrine of Christ.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p15" pid="meK2p_dY2kWRMYeOIE8gHg" hash="_CClDQ">Second, we need to understand the need for the restoration of the doctrine, organization, and keys of authority in these latter days. We need to have a witness that the Prophet Joseph Smith was divinely chosen and appointed by the Lord to bring about this restoration and recognize that he organized the women of the Church after the organization that existed in Christ’s Church anciently.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p16" pid="SN6A4q24IUGYPln4osJnRw" hash="VbcDDw">And third, we need to study and understand temple ordinances and covenants. The temple holds a place at the very center of our most sacred beliefs, and the Lord asks that we attend, ponder, study, and find personal meaning and application individually. We will come to understand that through the ordinances of the temple, the power of godliness is manifest in our lives<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> and that because of temple ordinances, we can be armed with God’s power, and His name will be upon us, His glory round about us, and His angels have charge over us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> I wonder if we are fully drawing upon the power of those promises.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p17" pid="ogVFPGtayUGDBCoJ6DxffQ" hash="0rQqSQ">Sisters, even the very youngest in this audience can rise up in faith and play a significant role in building the kingdom of God. Children begin gaining their own testimonies by reading or listening to the scriptures, praying daily, and partaking of the sacrament in a meaningful way. All children and young women can encourage family home evenings and be full participants. You can be the first one on your knees as your family gathers for family prayer. Even if your homes are less than ideal, your personal examples of faithful gospel living can influence the lives of your family and friends.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p18" pid="mZz-GrLXdUWFy8JM7IIX_A" hash="kIWdfg">Young women of the Church need to see themselves as essential participants in the priesthood-directed work of salvation and not just as onlookers and supporters. You hold callings and are set apart by those holding priesthood keys to function as leaders with power and authority in this work. As you magnify your callings in class presidencies and prepare spiritually, counsel together, reach out to minister to your class members, and teach one another the gospel, you are taking your place in this work and both you and your peers will be blessed.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p19" pid="I5rYLhHddEq0vezLsaNu_w" hash="I3zkFg">All women need to see themselves as essential participants in the work of the priesthood. Women in this Church are presidents, counselors, teachers, members of councils, sisters, and mothers, and the kingdom of God cannot function unless we rise up and fulfill our duties with faith. Sometimes we just need to have a greater vision of what is possible.</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=SMuIoFMKN0u_YpIvaHcAfg"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810461/8030ed24d0824978bffecd419ff0780a/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810461/8030ed24d0824978bffecd419ff0780a/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810461/8030ed24d0824978bffecd419ff0780a/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810461/8030ed24d0824978bffecd419ff0780a/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810461/8030ed24d0824978bffecd419ff0780a/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810461/8030ed24d0824978bffecd419ff0780a/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810461/8030ed24d0824978bffecd419ff0780a/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810461/8030ed24d0824978bffecd419ff0780a/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810461/8030ed24d0824978bffecd419ff0780a/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810461/8030ed24d0824978bffecd419ff0780a/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Sister Maldonado with Sister Oscarson" pid="SMuIoFMKN0u_YpIvaHcAfg" hash="AAAAAA1"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p20" pid="kVH0VKPGbkq5xASwzup67A" hash="aj8vRw">I recently met a sister in Mexico who understands what it means to magnify her calling with faith. Marffissa Maldonado was called to teach a youth Sunday School class three years ago. She had 7 students attending when she was called, but she now has 20 who attend regularly. I asked her, in amazement, what she had done to bring about such an increase in numbers. She modestly said, “Oh, it wasn’t just me. All the class members helped.” Together, they saw the names of the less-actives on the roll and began to go out together and invite them to come back to church. They have also had a baptism because of their efforts.</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=WrDg7lIw-kiPDGJOIxQt9Q"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810468/c8628ff268fa44ab844c17d421a21e66/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810468/c8628ff268fa44ab844c17d421a21e66/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810468/c8628ff268fa44ab844c17d421a21e66/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810468/c8628ff268fa44ab844c17d421a21e66/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810468/c8628ff268fa44ab844c17d421a21e66/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810468/c8628ff268fa44ab844c17d421a21e66/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810468/c8628ff268fa44ab844c17d421a21e66/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810468/c8628ff268fa44ab844c17d421a21e66/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810468/c8628ff268fa44ab844c17d421a21e66/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810468/c8628ff268fa44ab844c17d421a21e66/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Sunday School class in Mexico" pid="WrDg7lIw-kiPDGJOIxQt9Q" hash="AAAAAA"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p21" pid="SJ7Jw2RZLUOw0RaENHIBNA" hash="5y-lIw">Sister Maldonado set up a social media site just for her class members called “I Am a Child of God,” and she posts inspirational thoughts and scriptures several times a week. She regularly texts her students with assignments and encouragement. She feels it is important to communicate in the ways they best relate to, and it is working. She told me simply, “I love my students.” I could feel that love as she told me of their efforts, and her example reminded me of what one person of faith and action can accomplish in this work with the help of the Lord.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p22" pid="jvsLlzlNSUCfMY7fKIUmyw" hash="zpkihQ">Our youth are being exposed to difficult questions on a daily basis, and many of us have loved ones who are struggling to find answers. The good news is that there <span class="emphasis">are</span> answers to the questions being asked. Listen to the recent messages from our leaders. We are being urged to study and understand our Heavenly Father’s plan of happiness. We have been reminded of the principles in the family proclamation.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> We are encouraged to teach and use these resources as the measuring sticks to keep us on the strait and narrow path.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p23" pid="GNBvTHoU4UmJ_X211v69cg" hash="UQZcDg">About a year ago, I visited with a mother of young children who decided to take a proactive approach to inoculating her children against the many negative influences they were being exposed to online and at school. She chooses a topic each week, often one that has generated a lot of discussion online, and she initiates meaningful discussions during the week when her children can ask questions and she can make sure they’re getting a balanced and fair perspective on the often-difficult issues. She is making her home a safe place to raise questions and have meaningful gospel instruction.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p24" pid="IVWcXNuFa0GM2XSmHYFK6A" hash="1Iu0vA">I worry that we live in such an atmosphere of avoiding offense that we sometimes altogether avoid teaching correct principles. We fail to teach our young women that preparing to be a mother is of utmost importance because we don’t want to offend those who aren’t married or those who can’t have children, or to be seen as stifling future choices. On the other hand, we may also fail to emphasize the importance of education because we don’t want to send the message that it is more important than marriage. We avoid declaring that our Heavenly Father defines marriage as being between a man and woman because we don’t want to offend those who experience same-sex attraction. And we may find it uncomfortable to discuss gender issues or healthy sexuality.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p25" pid="2JQLPYEcw0--Spmr66wqFQ" hash="NJIgwg">Certainly, sisters, we need to use sensitivity, but let us also use our common sense and our understanding of the plan of salvation to be bold and straightforward when it comes to teaching our children and youth the essential gospel principles they must understand to navigate the world in which they live. If we don’t teach our children and youth true doctrine—and teach it clearly—the world will teach them Satan’s lies.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion.p26" pid="96QtMh-ib0a-oSeDdqBAPg" hash="qMXliA">I love the gospel of Jesus Christ, and I am eternally grateful for the direction, power, and daily help I receive as a covenant daughter of God. I testify that the Lord has blessed us, as women who live in these perilous times, with all of the power, gifts, and strength that are needed in order to prepare the world for the Second Coming of the Lord Jesus Christ. I pray that we may all see our true potential and rise up to become the women of faith and courage our Father in Heaven needs us to be. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/10/rise-up-in-strength-sisters-in-zion</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2016-general-conference/2016-09-0030-bonnie-l-oscarson-64k-eng.mp3" length="6035956" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
