<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Bradley D. Foster</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Bradley D. Foster.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Bradley%20D.%20Foster.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Bradley D. Foster.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Mother Told Me</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Perhaps the reason we respond so universally to our mothers’ love is because it typifies the love of our Savior.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021388_000_038" doc-version="2" hash="WQP1uQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="fpwMpNd-pkitz4c86kGJoA" hash="PrMtuA">Mother Told Me</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="E7A9OO70yk28NSb6fUkIHw" hash="o9pNwg">Bradley D. Foster</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="-Oiqq_uHOE20GiKkwp4PXw" hash="wYTcTQ">Perhaps the reason we respond so universally to our mothers’ love is because it typifies the love of our Savior.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p1" pid="vLCEcCXKg0aGreMC7kRLIA" hash="LGu-aQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="98"></span>The Lord has placed upon parents the primary responsibility for the spiritual nurturing of their children. Sometimes this responsibility falls to a single parent. My own mother was relatively young when my father died, leaving her alone with four children. But she faced her adversity with faith and courage, promising us that if we stayed on the road of truth, the end would be better than the beginning. Like the children of valiant mothers in the Book of Mormon, “we [did] not doubt our [mother] knew it” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/56.48" class="scriptureRef">Alma 56:48</a>). Brothers and sisters, I understand in a personal way the great influence of mothers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p2" pid="BTkLAgG4_kGs4QDhF_L0oQ" hash="tL5w0g">My good friend Don Pearson shared an experience that highlights this influence. One night his four-year-old son asked him to read a bedtime story. Eric had picked out his favorite book: <span class="emphasis">The Ballooning Adventures of Paddy Pork,</span> a story about a family who lived on the isles of the sea and traveled from island to island by hot-air balloon. It was a picture book that had no words, so Brother Pearson made up words to the story.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p3" pid="J9-JsidPV0WCxrWv_dwdvA" hash="ALqAmQ">“Paddy is in a hot-air balloon. He is landing on an island now. He is dropping a line over the side of the balloon.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p4" pid="gsV9zusuA0WjApCG4ubuRA" hash="2MRjqA">Eric stopped him. “Dad, that is not a line. It’s a <span class="emphasis">rope.</span>”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p5" pid="5BfWg_nsaUuttcdVtmCUUA" hash="qckpiw">Brother Pearson looked at Eric and back at the picture book, and then he continued: “Paddy is getting out of the balloon and climbing down the tree. Oh no! His coat is caught on a limb!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p6" pid="b5KkKkW0AUuJOeZkoZIMHg" hash="o8G9oQ">Again Eric stopped him. “Dad, that’s not a coat. It’s a <span class="emphasis">jacket.</span>”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p7" pid="wXMwvCHoa0q1IWBRGsz-4w" hash="lrI7lQ">By now Brother Pearson was somewhat perplexed. He said, “Eric, there are no words in this book, just pictures. Why do you insist that it’s a jacket?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p8" pid="D468loc9yE28I7ai55IZjg" hash="9uWQTg">Eric answered, “Because Mother told me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p9" pid="gOpAJ015YkqSu7J9N8GRNA" hash="8X1j0g">His father closed the book and said, “Eric, who do you think is the last word, the ultimate authority in this house?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p10" pid="iRmIa7gyVU2NrFNrIGZDrA" hash="eW9F-g">This time Eric thought carefully before he answered, “You are, Dad.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p11" pid="mwrFALg-5UKbXr0HZG92oQ" hash="22ORbw">Brother Pearson beamed at his son. What an exceptional answer! “How did you know that?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p12" pid="A_EZ3G_Q1EuQikpTcFmRuQ" hash="YNtgmw">Eric quickly responded, “Mother told me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p13" pid="9uyEta8wwEehn_BZ3MwwIw" hash="HRkWcw">As President James E. Faust said: “There is no greater good in all the world than motherhood. The influence of a mother in the lives of her children is beyond calculation” (“Fathers, Mothers, Marriage,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Aug. 2004, 3).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p14" pid="6Kau6yMaAkykseNsf2dwnQ" hash="cKFaYA">By divine design, nurturing seems to be part of the spiritual heritage given to women. I’ve seen it in my daughters, and now I see it in my <span class="pageBreak" page-number="99"></span>granddaughters—even before they could walk, they wanted to carry and care for their little baby dolls.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p15" pid="fNNkLmAmKEeHmZuBlOuaTA" hash="fFrrOQ">In my profession as a farmer and a rancher, I’ve had a front-row seat to observe how a mother’s natural affection manifests itself even in nature. Each spring we take a herd of cows and their new calves up along Idaho’s Snake River, where they graze in the foothills for a month or so. Then we round them up and bring them down a road that leads to the corral. From there they are loaded onto trucks that carry them to their summer pastures in Montana.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p16" pid="WK9_0X91XEeYjXTchVsxFg" hash="TIhZcw">On one particularly hot spring day, I was helping with the roundup by riding at the back of the herd as it moved down the dusty road toward the corral. My job was to gather any calves that had wandered from the road. The pace was slow and provided me some time to think.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p17" pid="-jo_eiylTk2sZP19KP7kDA" hash="AAZL2A">Because it was so hot, the little calves kept running off into the trees to find shade. My thoughts turned to the youth of the Church who are sometimes distracted from the strait and narrow path. I also thought about those who have left the Church or who may feel that the Church has left their hearts while they were distracted. I thought to myself that a distraction doesn’t have to be evil to be effective—sometimes it can just be shade.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p18" pid="m3Hu8yUR4kipStLddeg2XA" hash="XUj9-A">After several hours of gathering up stray calves and with sweat running down my face, I yelled to the calves in frustration, “Just follow your mothers! They know where they’re going! They’ve been down this road before!” Their mothers knew that even though the road was hot and dusty now, the end would be better than the beginning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p19" pid="-T2iPND00E6wXF_fQ4LbEA" hash="Y7EjzQ">As soon as we got the herd into the corral, we noticed that three of the cows were pacing nervously at the gate. They could not find their calves and seemed to sense they were back on the road somewhere. One of the cowboys asked me what we should do. I said, “I bet I know where those calves are. Back a quarter of a mile [0.4 km] or so, there’s a stand of trees. I’m sure we’ll find them there.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p20" pid="DaMfMv3CskypLSDcm82R_Q" hash="eJvuLA">Sure enough, just as I had suspected, we found our lost calves taking a nap in the shade. Our approach startled them, and they resisted our efforts to round them up. They were frightened because we were <span class="emphasis">not</span> their mothers! The more we tried to push them toward the corral, the more stubborn they became. Finally I said to the cowboys, “I’m sorry. I know better than this. Let’s ride back and let their mothers out of the corral. The cows will come and get their calves, and the calves will follow their mothers.” I was right. The mother cows knew exactly where to go to find their calves, and they led them back to the corral, as I had expected.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p21" pid="LX4nuC__eUCy9Syj9CjwGw" hash="Plo3xw">Brothers and sisters, in a world where everyone is granted agency, some of our loved ones may stray for a season. But we can never give up. We must always go back for them—we must never stop trying. Our prophet, President Thomas S. Monson, has issued a plea for us to go rescue those of our loved ones who may be lost (see, for example, “Stand in Your Appointed Place,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 2003, 54–57). With the help of priesthood leaders, parents must continue to go back and find their lost ones, assuring them there will always be a “home” within the family and the Church, waiting for <span class="pageBreak" page-number="100"></span>their return. We never know when a heart may be turned. We never know when a soul may be weary and worn out by the world. When that happens, it seems our children almost always turn first toward Mother, with emotions like those expressed in a poem by Elizabeth Akers Allen:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="CMYCUwOOBUyFhteny_YHeg" hash="VkjnDQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Backward, flow backward, O tide of the years!</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="5EgBYsMEA0aLo5IrzRhbow" hash="xzMMnQ">
            <span class="emphasis">I am so weary of toil and of tears, …</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="eOv1UmMFWEWGb9OpEq7VFQ" hash="MBNZrw">
            <span class="emphasis">Tired of the hollow, the base, the untrue,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="9tgNgvP8GEKIwNIKPJ9ePA" hash="pf3Nuw">
            <span class="emphasis">Mother, O mother, my heart calls for you! …</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="jNfFThtEmkGKssc-mR3R7w" hash="LydDAg">
            <span class="emphasis">Over my heart, in the days that are flown,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="9DNYD3kzakK52_l5XjfguQ" hash="iFMUQg">
            <span class="emphasis">No love like mother-love ever has shone; …</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="Rx_OnbIKxUiCCmgjCOkeSQ" hash="asfsGQ">
            <span class="emphasis">None like a mother can charm away pain</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="EsVcG2JsQE6zjimtS3bETg" hash="-26EkA">
            <span class="emphasis">From the sick soul and the world-weary brain.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="I6JPYGXYLUK9fvF5AyMtCA" hash="WwCepg">
            <span class="emphasis">Slumber’s soft calms o’er my heavy lids creep;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="7ptR7ZBadUKnJOwUA0_2OA" hash="4GDK7w">
            <span class="emphasis">Rock me to sleep, mother, rock me to sleep!</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p22" pid="pxCegH66tEWtTddeTE93uA" hash="qI2obA">Perhaps the reason we respond so universally to our mothers’ love is because it typifies the love of our Savior. As President Joseph F. Smith said, “The love of a true mother comes nearer [to] being like the love of God than any other kind of love” (“The Love of Mother,” <span class="emphasis">Improvement Era,</span> Jan. 1910, 278).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p23" pid="8uy4K3N16EOCps5DyozhWg" hash="UrXn3Q">As in all things, the Savior set the perfect example in the love He showed for His earthly mother. In the final, most pivotal moment of His mortal life—after the anguish of Gethsemane, the mock trial, the crown of thorns, the heavy cross to which He was brutally nailed—Jesus looked down from the cross and saw His mother, Mary, who had come to be with her Son. His final act of love before He died was to ensure that His mother would be cared for, saying to His disciple, “Behold thy mother!” And from that point on the disciple took her unto his home. As the scriptures say, then Jesus knew that “all things were now accomplished,” and He bowed His head and died (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/19.27-28,30" class="scriptureRef">John 19:27–28, 30</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me.p24" pid="t9lZZKeRr06Iqvad57916Q" hash="7WLYvw">Today I stand before you to bear my witness that Jesus Christ is the very Savior and Redeemer of the world. This is His Church, The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. Our Heavenly Father wants all of His children to return to Him. I know this without contradiction because of the witness of the Holy Ghost to my heart. I didn’t always know—when I was younger I had to rely on my parents’ testimony. My mother assured me that if I stayed on the road of truth, even when it seemed hot and dusty, even when there were distractions, the end would be better than the beginning. I will be eternally grateful that Mother told me. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/04/mother-told-me</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2010-general-conference/2010-04-5030-elder-bradley-d-foster-64k-eng.mp3" length="4675575" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s Never Too Early and It’s Never Too Late</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Bradley D. Foster teaches us that it’s never too early and it’s never too late to teach our children the gospel of Jesus Christ.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13768_000_34foster" doc-version="3" hash="DmvPzQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="RnB265VytUuHwyr4J56VNA" hash="XgOaXQ">It’s Never Too Early and It’s Never Too Late</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p2" pid="5pWy5JIF9U-gWiIjfzm0CQ" hash="P5Llng">By Elder Bradley D. Foster</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p3" pid="ymhcHQgZH0i2KH6cfxTMNg" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=9qEotqLs_US-ZlT1K0X45g"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" alt="Elder Bradley D. Foster" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255527/94144737299a4d5f9b04a367c3576999/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255527/94144737299a4d5f9b04a367c3576999/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255527/94144737299a4d5f9b04a367c3576999/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x279="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255527/94144737299a4d5f9b04a367c3576999/200x279.jpg" data-src-320x446="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255527/94144737299a4d5f9b04a367c3576999/320x446.jpg" data-src-460x641="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255527/94144737299a4d5f9b04a367c3576999/460x641.jpg" data-src-640x892="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255527/94144737299a4d5f9b04a367c3576999/640x892.jpg" data-src-1024x1428="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255527/94144737299a4d5f9b04a367c3576999/1024x1428.jpg" data-src-2048x2857="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255527/94144737299a4d5f9b04a367c3576999/2048x2857.jpg" data-src-3652x5095="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255527/94144737299a4d5f9b04a367c3576999/3652x5095.jpg" pid="9qEotqLs_US-ZlT1K0X45g" hash="yzVYkA"></img></a></div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="wqPlOaif-0euLBIkOvZhtA" hash="jPg8Yw">It’s never too early and it’s never too late to lead, guide, and walk beside our children, because families are forever.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="zVTFWNDh6Uy8jeS5t0YcTQ" hash="o9pNwg">Bradley D. Foster</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p5" pid="2Y_hHWXl5E-386d-q4sNkA" hash="-CDR4w">Brothers and sisters, we are engaged in a battle with the world. In the past, the world competed for our children’s energy and time. Today, it fights for their identity and mind. Many loud and prominent voices are trying to define who our children are and what they should believe. We cannot let society give our family a makeover in the image of the world. We must win this battle. Everything depends on it.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p6" pid="hXvEEHUJj0agtLrBIneJ0w" hash="v8qbvQ">The children of the Church sing a song that teaches them about their real identity: “I am a child of God. … He has sent me here, has given me an earthly home with parents.” Then, the children’s plea to us: “Lead me, guide me, walk beside me. … Help me to understand his words before it grows too late.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p7" pid="8h2e6JO_TEmddcbS5diYgQ" hash="QAXNxA">President Russell M. Nelson taught us in our last general conference that, from here on out, we must be engaged in “intentional parenting.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> These are perilous times. But the good news is God knew this would be the case, and He has provided counsel in the scriptures for us to know how to help our children and our grandchildren.</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=MkXsDPYD2kSmJ5xTeb-Vmg"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579929/db8702d09a174294b95c6cf7e4afb50f/100x125.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x62="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579929/db8702d09a174294b95c6cf7e4afb50f/50x62.jpg" data-src-100x125="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579929/db8702d09a174294b95c6cf7e4afb50f/100x125.jpg" data-src-200x251="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579929/db8702d09a174294b95c6cf7e4afb50f/200x251.jpg" data-src-320x402="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579929/db8702d09a174294b95c6cf7e4afb50f/320x402.jpg" data-src-460x578="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579929/db8702d09a174294b95c6cf7e4afb50f/460x578.jpg" data-src-640x805="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579929/db8702d09a174294b95c6cf7e4afb50f/640x805.jpg" data-src-1024x1288="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579929/db8702d09a174294b95c6cf7e4afb50f/1024x1288.jpg" data-src-1431x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579929/db8702d09a174294b95c6cf7e4afb50f/1431x1800.jpg" altText="Savior with Book of Mormon children" pid="MkXsDPYD2kSmJ5xTeb-Vmg" hash="dLuV4Q"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p8" pid="0eWpCc81_0CHvVl2Pwqnow" hash="FKhAJQ">In the Book of Mormon, the Savior appeared to the Nephites. He gathered their little children around Him. He blessed them, prayed for them, and wept over them.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Then He said to the parents, “Behold your little ones.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p9" pid="CnX-crJAQUu33jXbBEnl0w" hash="P1XZfQ">The word <span class="emphasis">behold</span> means to look and see. What did Jesus want the parents to see in their little ones? Did He want them to catch a glimpse of their children’s divine potential?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p10" pid="wGYUO6Hr9ECE0K3fx4B9Lw" hash="n398kQ">As we look at our children and our grandchildren today, what does the Savior want us to see in them? Do we recognize that our children are the largest group of investigators of the Church? What must we do to bring about their lasting conversion?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p11" pid="1KY11wNXg025UMYNtnHdIg" hash="Ffvk7w">In the book of Matthew, the Savior teaches us about lasting conversion. A large group of people had gathered near the Sea of Galilee to hear Him teach.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p12" pid="l7JWu01Y0UGdlJlpLgMbfA" hash="MsAEbA">On this occasion, Jesus told a story about planting seeds—the parable of the sower.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> In explaining this to His disciples, and ultimately to us, He said, “When any one heareth the word of the kingdom, and understandeth it <span class="emphasis">not,</span> then cometh the wicked one, and catcheth away that which was sown in his heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> The message for parents is clear: there is a difference between hearing and understanding. If our children merely hear but do not understand the gospel, then the door is left open for Satan to remove these truths from their hearts.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p13" pid="HJ2kg5t3CEuiVm-4Kud9Zg" hash="460LKw">However, if we can help them grow roots of deep conversion, then in the heat of the day, when this life gets tough—and it will—the gospel of Jesus Christ can give them something within that cannot be affected from without. How can we ensure that these powerful truths are not just going in one ear and out the other? Hearing words just might not be enough.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p14" pid="CSBZeLR9AkqKPzE-I9FFKg" hash="uf9dXg">We all know that words evolve. Sometimes we say our words, and they hear their words. You might say to your young children, “You sound like a broken record.” They’d probably respond with, “Dad, what’s a record?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p15" pid="Oo3vTBI-806fupTcbQ2T3A" hash="A4bQqA">Our Heavenly Father wants us to succeed because really, after all, they were His children before they were ours. As parents in Zion, you have received the gift of the Holy Ghost. As you pray for guidance, “it will show unto you all things what ye should do”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> in teaching your children. As you develop processes of learning, “the power of the Holy Ghost carrieth it unto the hearts of the children.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p16" pid="7yDbgZeO5k2AJ9obr1zvKA" hash="-yp_2g">I can’t think of a better example of helping someone gain understanding than the story of Helen Keller. She was blind and deaf and lived in a world that was dark and quiet. A teacher named Anne Sullivan came to help her. How would you teach a child who can’t even see or hear you?</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=DCIAO6mbq0KH77ZQp8PLrw"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579931/c8dc658927094ee1bffc71f0069e7942/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579931/c8dc658927094ee1bffc71f0069e7942/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579931/c8dc658927094ee1bffc71f0069e7942/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579931/c8dc658927094ee1bffc71f0069e7942/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579931/c8dc658927094ee1bffc71f0069e7942/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579931/c8dc658927094ee1bffc71f0069e7942/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579931/c8dc658927094ee1bffc71f0069e7942/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579931/c8dc658927094ee1bffc71f0069e7942/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579931/c8dc658927094ee1bffc71f0069e7942/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579931/c8dc658927094ee1bffc71f0069e7942/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Helen Keller and Anne Sullivan" pid="DCIAO6mbq0KH77ZQp8PLrw" hash="zI1LbQ"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p17" pid="mDRZealyWEqsTdu70UcHiQ" hash="5YH-ZQ">For a long time, Anne struggled to connect with Helen. One day around noon, she took her out to the water pump. She put one of Helen’s hands under the waterspout and began to pump the water. Anne then spelled out the word <span class="emphasis">W-A-T-E-R</span> on Helen’s other hand. Nothing happened. So she tried again. <span class="emphasis">W-A-T-E-R</span>. Helen squeezed Anne’s hand because she began to understand. By nightfall, she had learned 30 words. Within a matter of months, she had learned 600 words and was able to read Braille. Helen Keller went on to earn a college degree and helped change the world for people who couldn’t see or hear.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> It was a miracle, and her teacher was the miracle worker, just like you will be, parents.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p18" pid="EN_JU0Z8X0628cg_sNKhiw" hash="RmZlAA">I saw the results of another great teacher while serving as the president of a single adult stake at BYU–Idaho. That experience changed my life. On one particular Tuesday evening, I interviewed a young man named Pablo, from Mexico City, who wanted to serve a mission. I asked him about his testimony and his desire to serve. His answers to my questions were perfect. Then I asked about his worthiness. His answers were exact. In fact, they were so good, I wondered, “Maybe he doesn’t understand what I’m asking him.” So I rephrased the questions and determined that he knew exactly what I meant and was completely honest.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p19" pid="cCbU15UgzUuSS2DPy0NSTA" hash="1oZGQw">I was so impressed with this young man that I asked him, “Pablo, who was it that helped you come to this point in your life standing so uprightly before the Lord?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p20" pid="ZUWyQdaqW0ahvXBsp7ATDA" hash="JB4wZw">He said, “My dad.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p21" pid="_4tH11ScJUKkAXb8f1kktQ" hash="8AJ_mw">I said, “Pablo, tell me your story.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p22" pid="q5N7Ljt76U-TDlxWLIbT8g" hash="gIFk6A">Pablo continued: “When I was nine, my dad took me aside and said, ‘Pablo, I was nine once too. Here are some things you may come across. You’ll see people cheating in school. You might be around people who swear. You’ll probably have days when you don’t want to go to church. Now, when these things happen—or anything else that troubles you—I want you to come and talk to me, and I’ll help you get through them. And then I’ll tell you what comes next.’”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p23" pid="5TZlYZX5v0ufxRAfqdiB-Q" hash="Kyz0jA">“So, Pablo, what did he tell you when you were 10?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p24" pid="LgfnKSfEqU6dpmE3Vejhmw" hash="A_-Bcw">“Well, he warned me about pornography and dirty jokes.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p25" pid="WF90eEdv80Cw_BLOJgavZQ" hash="dqOUDQ">“What about when you were 11?” I asked.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p26" pid="FYjNISbEQkGD_Xahg8VNRw" hash="hfqefg">“He cautioned me about things that could be addictive and reminded me about using my agency.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p27" pid="zbBHm9CqKEirQl2Kqt-ShQ" hash="dHkt8w">Here was a father, year after year, “line upon line; here a little, and there a little,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> who helped his son not only hear but also understand. Pablo’s father knew our children learn when they are ready to learn, not just when we are ready to teach them. I was proud of Pablo when we submitted his missionary application that night, but I was even prouder of Pablo’s dad.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p28" pid="LJa7KXSZLEmKiIB3nBvXBA" hash="bB0j5g">When I drove home that night, I asked myself, “What kind of father will Pablo be?” And the answer was crystal clear: he’ll be just like his dad. Jesus said, “The Son can do nothing of himself, but what he seeth the Father do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> This is the pattern of how Heavenly Father blesses His children from generation to generation.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p29" pid="Dk4uIujWdU2on56U913vSA" hash="Npa5MQ">As I continued to think about my experience with Pablo, I felt sad because my four daughters were grown and the nine grandchildren I had at the time didn’t live nearby. I then thought, “How could I ever help them the way Pablo’s father helped him? Had too much time gone by?” As I offered a prayer in my heart, the Spirit whispered this profound truth: “It’s never too early and it’s never too late to begin this important process.” I knew immediately what that meant. I could hardly wait to get home. I asked my wife, Sharol, to call all of our children and tell them that we needed to visit with them; I had something really important to tell them. My urgency startled them a little.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p30" pid="Cj73OXLsBU2Yiu40G4J39Q" hash="K5xBsA">We began with our oldest daughter and her husband. I said: “Your mother and I want you to know that we were your age once. We were 31, with a small family. We have an idea of what you might encounter. It might be a financial or health challenge. It may be a crisis of faith. You may just get overwhelmed with life. When these things happen, we want you to come and talk to us. We’ll help you get through them. Now, we don’t want to be in your business all the time, but we want you to know that we are always in your corner. And while we’re together, I want to tell you about an interview I just had with a young man named Pablo.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p31" pid="hjLJ9m2NREqnzUlJoqYjoA" hash="B0zS3A">After the story, I said, “We don’t want you to miss helping your children and our grandchildren understand these important truths.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p32" pid="FtjWFzzcAUG17ryGsNazrg" hash="SYm0uQ">Brothers and sisters, I now realize in a more meaningful way what the Lord expects of me as a father and as a grandfather in establishing a process to help my family not only hear but understand.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p33" pid="ZnZIGHBYzk2woGVtMoRMPw" hash="RLgV9A">As I grow older, I find myself reflecting on these words:</p>
			<div class="poetry">
				<div class="stanza">
					<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p34" pid="7DnekJP6-EOlYMOC7a2GnA" hash="VtLurg">O time, O time, go back in flight,</p>
					<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p35" pid="fmB7JjqrjUKJvBBjmrTUIw" hash="MWzzTw">And let them be my little children for just one more night!<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
				</div>
			</div>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p36" pid="IV1O_l0r-EecQJl5Y6Z3IA" hash="UFppkg">I know I can’t turn back time, but this I now know—that it’s never too early and it’s never too late to lead, guide, and walk beside our children, because families are forever.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late.p37" pid="aLF1q3_ITkahD5NoJh3r3w" hash="-J65eQ">It is my witness that our Heavenly Father loved us so much that He sent His Only Begotten Son to live the life of a mortal so that Jesus could say to us, “I’ve been where you are, I know what comes next, and I’ll help you through it.” I know He will. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/10/its-never-too-early-and-its-never-too-late</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2015-general-conference/2015-10-2040-elder-bradley-d-foster-64k-eng.mp3" length="4935484" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
