<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Brent H. Nielson</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Brent H. Nielson.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Brent%20H.%20Nielson.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Brent H. Nielson.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2009 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2009 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>A Call to the Rising Generation</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation?lang=eng</link>
      <description>There is no greater call than teaching “all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost.”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50019113_000_032" doc-version="2" hash="hja1dg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="zcNWg7UdUEy5tC-4CXHWAg" hash="VXD05w">A Call to the Rising Generation</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="PJpNrclBWUGya7dNb9xiww" hash="xL40Dg">Brent H. Nielson</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="WN3DlVgGH0OlhweiU7jUeg" hash="XPHYPw">There is no greater call than teaching “all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost.”</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p1" pid="ZQc7s__r1U6bxSxgOiS0xA" hash="2X3beg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="95"></span>As the Savior’s earthly ministry drew to a close, He appeared as a resurrected being to His Apostles. His charge to them is the same call He extends to you of the rising generation today: “Go ye therefore, and teach all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/28.19" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 28:19</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p2" pid="pDua2YcR70OGaqZS1G1zMw" hash="gf2zqw">On April 6, 1974, the Church sustained a new prophet, President Spencer W. Kimball. That same day I received my call to serve as a full-time missionary in Finland. I wasn’t aware at the time that President Kimball had just delivered a landmark address that week to the General Authorities and regional representatives of the Church. Later I learned that in that address President Kimball prophetically outlined his vision as to how we as a church would accomplish the Savior’s charge to “teach all nations.” In his address, President Kimball invited the members of the Church to lengthen their stride and enlarge their vision. He asked that every worthy young man prepare to serve an honorable full-time mission. He encouraged the members in each country to prepare to supply their own missionaries, and he called upon “able men to assist the Twelve [Apostles] to move out into the world and to open the doors of every nation” (“When the World Will Be Converted,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Oct. 1974, 10).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p3" pid="u9ubceoMzUaz2Kr13GPoNQ" hash="vG2-1w">President Kimball also said in his 1974 address that there were 3.3 million members of the Church, 18,600 full-time missionaries, and 633 stakes. He challenged us to do better and asked us to change our sights and raise our vision (see <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Oct. 1974, 7–8).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p4" pid="HASKf_s3g0OiajSTHaJXqg" hash="w2E0yA">In response, we as members of the Church began to pray regularly in our families, in our sacrament meetings, and in our stake conferences that the hearts of the leaders of nations would be softened and the doors opened to our missionaries. The members began to see more clearly their responsibility to share the gospel. Our young men stepped up, and a great army of missionaries was gathered. We witnessed President Kimball’s vision begin to unfold.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p5" pid="-IvidyG1SESjnvEZ95_ZzA" hash="YaAS8A">While serving in Finland, I learned that my mission president’s wife, Sister Lea Mahoney, was a native of Finland. As a young girl she had grown up in the eastern portion of Finland in a city named Viipuri. As the ravages of war engulfed Finland and other countries during World War II, she and her family left their home, and Viipuri became part of the Soviet Union and was renamed Vyborg. In our zone conferences, Sister Mahoney would tell us of those left behind in Viipuri and of her desire that the gospel be taken to them. Following President Kimball’s challenge, we unitedly prayed that the hearts of the leaders of that nation would be softened so that the gospel could be taken by our missionaries into the Soviet Union.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p6" pid="s8IyYCrda0y98Lrlw_U8jg" hash="mbtF4w">We would go to the border between Finland and the Soviet Union and see the guard towers and the fences, and we would wonder who those brave young men and young women would be and when they would cross that border to take the gospel to the people there. I must admit, at that time it seemed like an impossible task.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p7" pid="WS3o9d7AskilaRB-wKxJIw" hash="u7p3Mw">Three years ago, our son Eric received a mission call to serve in the Russia St. Petersburg Mission. In his first letter home, he wrote something like this: “Dear Mom and Dad, I have been assigned to my first city in Russia. Dad, you may have heard of it before. It is called Vyborg, but it was previously a Finnish city named Viipuri.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p8" pid="j6qNhsXo-0Kqak9mymjRnQ" hash="DtkV3g">Tears came to my eyes as I understood that Eric was in the very city we had prayed about 32 years earlier. Eric found a chapel there and a branch of faithful Saints. He was living and serving in a place that to me as a young man had seemed impossible to enter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p9" pid="tt_X64mN40SD0ImywEravw" hash="Hq16VQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="96"></span>I did not realize those many years ago, as we prayed for the borders to open and the missionaries to go in, that I was praying for our son. Most importantly for you of the rising generation, our son Eric did not realize that he and his companions were the answer to the prayers that had been offered by thousands of faithful Saints so many years ago. You of the rising generation are the fulfillment of prophecy that in our day “the truth of God will go forth boldly, nobly, and independent, till it has penetrated every continent, visited every clime, swept every country, and sounded in every ear, till the purposes of God shall be accomplished, and the Great Jehovah shall say the work is done” (Joseph Smith, in <span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 4:540).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p10" pid="jdlJ22q5gUqOvG1UyR8QQA" hash="57etnQ">Since President Kimball’s prophetic instruction 35 years ago, Church membership has grown to 13.5 million members. There are now 52,000 missionaries and over 2,800 stakes of Zion. Who are the laborers in the vineyard who have assisted in bringing to pass this marvelous work and a wonder? They are certainly the prophets and apostles seated before us today. They are also the wonderful stake presidents and bishops who have served so faithfully. But they are also your parents—the mothers and fathers—aunts and uncles, and brothers and sisters who sit beside you, the rising generation today. Most critical, however, is the fact that as we strive to take the gospel to all nations, we have just begun to scratch the surface.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p11" pid="uRkpG7VOfEiku_MezQNaUg" hash="1hUGKA">And so the torch is passed to a new generation. The Savior, through His prophet today, President Thomas S. Monson, has renewed the call as he declared:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p12" pid="mcvEkYFkJ06Dt603wF-aow" hash="rmUWCw">“Our keynote was sounded by our Lord and our Savior, who stands at the head of the great army of missionaries worldwide. After His Resurrection, He appeared to His 11 disciples. He could have given them any counsel, any expression, any warning that He chose to give. But what did He say? It’s recorded in <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/28.18-20" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 28:18–20</a>. He said as follows: …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p13" pid="p9eoR2LfYEiAByJOZq3Eng" hash="isJREg">“‘Go ye therefore, and teach all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p14" pid="zH4BxhT81EiA6j0OpUaJBA" hash="E-HKhA">“‘Teaching them to observe all things whatsoever I have commanded you: and, lo, I am with you alway, even unto the end of the world.’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p15" pid="lv33Afx-W06ADSWAhKLn0w" hash="LEo8vQ">President Monson continued:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p16" pid="TZ4E31cDwkulVK1OKKsU4g" hash="mk2a1w">“What a promise! If we respond <span class="pageBreak" page-number="97"></span>affirmatively to that sacred call, that binding authority, ‘I will be with you alway, even unto the end of the world.’ I can’t think of a greater promise” (“The Five M’s of Missionary Work,” <span class="emphasis">New Era, </span>Mar. 2007, 42).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p17" pid="neXkGMcwQUyfqZ3mOJUgqw" hash="k78Uhg">In the Book of Mormon, Jacob, quoting Zenos, spoke of our task today in the allegory of the tame and wild olive trees:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p18" pid="LhKqpfDdsEWvBFJc35X7jg" hash="kBKq9Q">“Wherefore, go to, and call servants, that we may labor diligently with our might in the vineyard, that we may prepare the way, that I may bring forth again the natural fruit, which natural fruit is good and the most precious above all other fruit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p19" pid="OcysZ5j1qUiVPG2PJkgYDQ" hash="xmM6Vg">“Wherefore, let us go to and labor with our might this last time, for behold the end draweth nigh, and this is for the last time that I shall prune my vineyard” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/5.61-62" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 5:61–62</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p20" pid="4JB1hWM98kuOs_H0EqfnqQ" hash="ojdmjw">The Savior’s call is to you of the rising generation. He is asking for worthy, prepared, faithful young men and young women who will heed the prophet’s voice, who will step up and say, as the Savior Himself said, “Here am I, send me” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.27" class="scriptureRef">Abraham 3:27</a>). The need has never been greater. The field has never been whiter. You are called to go “this last time” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/5.62" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 5:62</a>). There is no greater work; there is no greater call than teaching “all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/28.19" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 28:19</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p21" pid="Rctj7f4F40aUKQNNzY1Wig" hash="CqAzNQ">I solemnly proclaim and testify that the heavens are open, that not only has God spoken but that He speaks today. His Son, Jesus Christ, lives and is inviting you, as He invited His Apostles of old, Peter and Andrew: “Follow me, and I will make you fishers of men” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/4.19" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 4:19</a>). May you respond as they did, by leaving your nets straightway and following Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation.p22" pid="j6Q9vAH1fE2JMqSWBAKzdA" hash="riImdA">I pray that you of this rising generation will stand up for truth and righteousness and understand your sacred call to go and teach all nations, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2009/10/a-call-to-the-rising-generation</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2009-general-conference/2009-10-5030-elder-brent-h-nielson-64k-eng.mp3" length="4804928" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2009 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waiting for the Prodigal</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Brent H. Nielson shares a personal story about how to include, love, and wait for others who have lost their faith.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_12565_000_45nielson" doc-version="4" hash="CsdJIg">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="iCKh9dG3LE2DQ8Xc7Zq4fQ" hash="qZdL8w">Waiting for the Prodigal</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p2" pid="kd2_jspzu0G5Yw9qM_gZtQ" hash="L795Ww">By Elder Brent H. Nielson</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p3" pid="FJq4A-qT1kqRBw3kdmk--Q" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=_fIZejw5YEO-5q6pBjABgQ"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" type="jpg" uri="brent-h-nielson-10.jpg" translate="no" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255559/4d9c69a0183441f2b9e49b44b68d1aff/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255559/4d9c69a0183441f2b9e49b44b68d1aff/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255559/4d9c69a0183441f2b9e49b44b68d1aff/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x279="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255559/4d9c69a0183441f2b9e49b44b68d1aff/200x279.jpg" data-src-320x447="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255559/4d9c69a0183441f2b9e49b44b68d1aff/320x447.jpg" data-src-460x643="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255559/4d9c69a0183441f2b9e49b44b68d1aff/460x643.jpg" data-src-640x895="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255559/4d9c69a0183441f2b9e49b44b68d1aff/640x895.jpg" data-src-1024x1432="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255559/4d9c69a0183441f2b9e49b44b68d1aff/1024x1432.jpg" data-src-2048x2865="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255559/4d9c69a0183441f2b9e49b44b68d1aff/2048x2865.jpg" data-src-3985x5576="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255559/4d9c69a0183441f2b9e49b44b68d1aff/3985x5576.jpg" pid="_fIZejw5YEO-5q6pBjABgQ" hash="R3mu3w"></img></a>
		</div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="Rlci3s8-50WXY77q8sFs_g" hash="BeHNkg">May you and I receive the revelation to know how to best approach those in our lives who are lost.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="BuotfB2cAEuPdWa__rNuAg" hash="L795Ww1">By Elder Brent H. Nielson</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="gRBxOllWHUCPh6sGx8gjPA" hash="PtCQNQ">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p5" pid="CbJDuZLaZUCpyvBdYDjzpQ" hash="j3ITgg">The Savior Jesus Christ spent His earthly ministry teaching of His healing and redemptive power. On one occasion in <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15" class="scriptureRef">Luke chapter 15</a> in the New Testament, He was actually criticized for eating and spending time with sinners (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15.2" class="scriptureRef">Luke 15:2</a>). The Savior used this criticism as an opportunity to teach us all how to respond to those who have lost their way.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p6" pid="XjJkbqpAzUW5xs9X3yBMXg" hash="x3CcxA">He replied to His critics by asking them two important questions:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p7" pid="RAtcC3hSJUeOb_icQdTWNQ" hash="TZuaqA">“What man of you, having an hundred sheep, if he lose one of them, doth not leave the ninety and nine in the wilderness, and go after that which is lost, until he find it?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15.4" class="scriptureRef">Luke 15:4</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p8" pid="CG4HjjrTeUyZ4cPwsN1zGA" hash="SMMx8Q">“What woman having ten pieces of silver, if she lose one piece, doth not light a candle, and sweep the house, and seek diligently till she find it?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15.8" class="scriptureRef">Luke 15:8</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p9" pid="Pjlsx26yqUqoIsURfej87Q" hash="ErrASw">The Savior then teaches the parable of the prodigal son. This parable isn’t about 100 sheep or 10 pieces of silver; it is about one precious son who is lost. Through the parable, what does the Savior teach us about how to respond when a family member loses his or her way?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p10" pid="ioD8bQn7c0y1nubM6wO15w" hash="pJK50g">The prodigal son informs his father that he wants his inheritance now. He wants to leave the safety of his home and family and seek after worldly pursuits (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15.12-13" class="scriptureRef">Luke 15:12–13</a>). Please note that in the Savior’s parable the father lovingly responds by giving the son his inheritance. Certainly the father must have done everything he could to convince the son to stay. However, once the adult son makes his choice, the wise father lets him go. The father then demonstrates sincere love, and he watches and he waits (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15.20" class="scriptureRef">Luke 15:20</a>).</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p11" pid="f6w0Uuc490CPMDA6wZ26Sw" hash="9E7QYA">My family had a similar experience. My two faithful brothers, wonderful sister, and I were raised by exemplary parents. We were taught the gospel in our home, we successfully made it to adulthood, and all four of us were sealed in the temple to our spouses. However, in 1994 our sister, Susan, became disenchanted with the Church and some of its teachings. She was persuaded by those who mocked and criticized the early leaders of the Church. She allowed her faith in living prophets and apostles to diminish. Over time, her doubts overcame her faith, and she chose to leave the Church. Susan has given me permission to share her story with the hope that it might help others.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p12" pid="7xEONHGgVkqxw97QfA8CMA" hash="TcGx-g">My brothers and I and our widowed mother were devastated. We couldn’t imagine what possibly could have led her to abandon her faith. My sister’s choices seemed to be breaking our mother’s heart.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p13" pid="nUyH5_ZJ60OPWSKFPQqN4w" hash="Oo0aFA">My brothers and I had served as bishops and quorum presidents, and we had experienced the joy of success with ward and quorum members as we left the ninety and nine and went after the one. However, with our sister, our persistent efforts to rescue her and to invite her back only pushed her further and further away.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p14" pid="bDCNYS39eUmXNj3HNLnUmw" hash="4rZexw">As we sought heavenly guidance as to how we might properly respond to her, it became evident that we had to follow the example of the father in the parable of the prodigal son. Susan had made her choice, and we had to figuratively let her go—but not without her knowing and feeling our sincere love for her. And so, with renewed love and kindness, we watched and we waited.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p15" pid="XBfSuXfAO0aCM9sVZ36hEQ" hash="gdubMw">My mother never stopped loving and caring for Susan. Every time my mother attended the temple, she placed Susan’s name on the prayer roll and never lost hope. My older brother and his wife, who lived closest to Susan in California, invited her to all family events. They prepared dinner in their home each year on Susan’s birthday. They made sure they were always in touch with her and that she knew of their genuine love for her.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p16" pid="SCOTGTzxlEuzsFLT5zpRvw" hash="0eCWcg">My younger brother and his wife reached out to Susan’s children in Utah and cared for them and loved them. They made sure that her children were always invited to family gatherings, and when it came time for Susan’s granddaughter to be baptized, my brother was there to perform the ordinance. Susan also had loving home teachers and visiting teachers who never gave up.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p17" pid="EUqDDBVhkUmab0DsMJyZow" hash="jsnKxQ">As our children went on missions and were married, Susan was invited to and attended these family celebrations. We tried diligently to create family events so that Susan and her children could be with us and they would know that we loved them and that they were part of our family. As Susan received an advanced degree at a California university, we were all there to support her at her graduation. Although we could not embrace all of her choices, we could certainly embrace her. We loved, we watched, and we waited.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p18" pid="2U8NSvfWHEilP-jU7AqQtw" hash="EaIDnA">In 2006, after 12 years had passed since Susan left the Church, our daughter Katy moved with her husband to California so he could attend law school. They were in the same city as Susan. This young couple looked to their aunt Susan for help and support, and they loved her. Susan helped care for our two-year-old granddaughter, Lucy, and Susan found herself helping Lucy with her nightly prayers. Katy called me one day and asked if I thought Susan would ever come back to the Church. I assured her that I felt she would and that we needed to continue to be patient. As another three years passed, with continued love, we watched and we waited.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p19" pid="mnowy5BiO0GKnR50AJmA2A" hash="RhVz4A">Six years ago this weekend, my wife, Marcia, and I were sitting on the front row of this Conference Center. I was to be sustained as a new General Authority that day. Marcia, who is always in touch with the Spirit, had written a note to me that read, “I think it is time for Susan to come back.” My daughter Katy suggested that I leave and call Susan to invite her to watch general conference that day.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p20" pid="KxlE4VPhQ0-FPC0oDmHx4Q" hash="mrJnCA">Prompted by these two great women, I walked to the foyer and called my sister. I got her voice mail and simply invited her to watch that session of general conference. She got the message. To our delight, she felt impressed to watch all the sessions of conference. She heard from prophets and apostles she had loved in earlier years. She found new names she had not heard before, such as President Uchtdorf and Elders Bednar, Cook, Christofferson, and Andersen. During this and other unique heaven-sent experiences, my sister—like the prodigal son—came to herself (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15.17" class="scriptureRef">Luke 15:17</a>). The words of prophets and apostles and the love of her family moved her to turn and begin the walk back home. After 15 years our daughter and sister who was lost had been found. The watch and the wait were over.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p21" pid="PVKrC9Mqr0ergWiCIPbXsA" hash="I6OKyA">Susan describes this experience just as Lehi described it in the Book of Mormon. She let go of the iron rod and found herself in a mist of darkness (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/8.23" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 8:23</a>). She states that she did not know she was lost until her faith was reawakened by the Light of Christ, which brightly magnified the stark contrast between what she was experiencing in the world and what the Lord and her family were offering.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p22" pid="ydpfrjaBZUipRaMXgVXbNw" hash="6LK-qw">A miracle has occurred over the past six years. Susan has a renewed testimony of the Book of Mormon. She has received her temple recommend. She has served as an ordinance worker in the temple, and she currently teaches the Gospel Doctrine class in her ward. The windows of heaven have opened to her children and her grandchildren, and although there have been difficult consequences, it feels as if she never left.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p23" pid="BObptz1ZfESLLeCRIQ-zRQ" hash="fsLzEQ">Some of you, like the Nielson family, have family members who have temporarily lost their way. The Savior’s instruction to all who have 100 sheep is to leave the ninety and nine and go after and rescue the one. His instruction to those who have 10 pieces of silver and lose one is to search until you find it. When the lost one is your son or your daughter, your brother or your sister, and he or she has chosen to leave, we learned in our family that, after all we can do, we love that person with all of our hearts and we watch, we pray, and we wait for the Lord’s hand to be revealed.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p24" pid="HblmnB68u06Bx-GvIqKFkQ" hash="YdPSCQ">Perhaps the most important lesson the Lord taught me through this process happened during our family scripture study after my sister had left the Church. Our son David was reading as we studied together <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15" class="scriptureRef">Luke 15</a>. As he read the parable of the prodigal son, I heard it differently that day than I had ever heard it before. For some reason, I had always related to the son who stayed home. As David read that morning, I realized that in some ways <span class="emphasis">I</span> was the prodigal son. All of us fall short of the glory of the Father (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/3.23" class="scriptureRef">Romans 3:23</a>). All of us need the Savior’s Atonement to heal us. All of us are lost and need to be found. This revelation that day helped me know that my sister and I both needed the Savior’s love and His Atonement. Susan and I were actually on the same path back home.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p25" pid="poePIZaMfEC8vkPfeRaheA" hash="qRdmAA">The Savior’s words in the parable as He describes the father greeting his prodigal son are powerful, and I believe they may be the description of the experience you and I will have with the Father when we return to our heavenly home. They teach us of a father who loves, waits, and watches. These are the words of the Savior: “When he was yet a great way off, his father saw him, and had compassion, and ran, and fell on his neck, and kissed him” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15.20" class="scriptureRef">Luke 15:20</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal.p26" pid="2iFxtt2yNkWgmN56DQ144g" hash="di5ZmQ">May you and I receive the revelation to know how to best approach those in our lives who are lost and, when necessary, to have the patience and love of our Father in Heaven and His Son, Jesus Christ, as we love, watch, and wait for the prodigal. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/04/waiting-for-the-prodigal</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2015-general-conference/2015-04-4050-elder-brent-h-nielson-64k-eng.mp3" length="4999153" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
