<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Brian K. Ashton</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Brian K. Ashton.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Brian%20K.%20Ashton.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Brian K. Ashton.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Doctrine of Christ</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Brother Ashton teaches that the doctrine of Christ includes faith, repentance, baptism, the sacrament, the gift of the Holy Ghost, and enduring to the end.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60001311_000_62ashton" doc-version="2" hash="pCQCZg">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="CnBI838uPEqUihg3E4kdNQ" hash="k5Brug">The Doctrine of Christ</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p2" pid="dHpsqMm5OEGDR4vIhpUNRQ" hash="KFWnQg1">By Brian K. Ashton</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p3" pid="Tc6CDFPJ7kSili5jEBl-1g" hash="IEw8LA">Second Counselor in the Sunday School General Presidency</p>
		</div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="_SIOfPXZ50CMXSj7t4smjw" hash="LYfjTw">The doctrine of Christ allows us to access the spiritual power that will lift us from our current spiritual state to a state where we can become perfected.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="zP-BHBuOJ0iX8nzRbKCM4g" hash="KFWnQg">By Brian K. Ashton</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p5" pid="kCNdTHvwrkau7NHxyCiuag" hash="bgZd5w">Jesus’s visit to the Nephites after His Resurrection was carefully organized to teach us the things of greatest importance. It began with the Father testifying to the people that Jesus was His “Beloved Son, in whom [He was] well pleased.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Then Jesus Himself descended and testified of His atoning sacrifice,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> inviting the people to “know of a surety” that He was the Christ by coming forth and feeling the wound mark in His side and the prints of the nails in His hands and feet.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> These testimonies established without doubt that Jesus’s Atonement was complete and that the Father had fulfilled His covenant to provide a Savior. Jesus then taught the Nephites how to obtain all the blessings of the Father’s plan of happiness, which are made available to us because of the Savior’s Atonement, by teaching them the doctrine of Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p6" pid="HYFGCpWKxEGYYcDHskQQ1g" hash="kRqMbA">My message today focuses on the doctrine of Christ. The scriptures define the doctrine of Christ as exercising faith in Jesus Christ and His Atonement, repenting, being baptized, receiving the gift of the Holy Ghost, and enduring to the end.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.t1">
			<h2 pid="p1WP6SAM00eaajOyvACGTg" hash="XvdzNg">The Doctrine of Christ Allows Us to Obtain the Blessings of Christ’s Atonement</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p8" pid="ErQ9IGA1GkG7vAqwRjA8Cg" hash="oKGqog">The Atonement of Christ creates the conditions upon which we may rely upon “the merits, and mercy, and grace of the Holy Messiah,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> “be perfected in [Christ],”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> obtain every good thing,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> and gain eternal life.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p9" pid="7rka3yuM60uTKvR79WDzSA" hash="slIMFA">The doctrine of Christ on the other hand is the means—the only means—by which we can obtain all of the blessings made available to us through Jesus’s Atonement. It is the doctrine of Christ that allows us to access the spiritual power that will lift us from our current spiritual state to a state where we can become perfected like the Savior.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Of this process of rebirth, Elder D. Todd Christofferson has taught: “Being born again, unlike our physical birth, is more a process than an event. And engaging in that process is the central purpose of mortality.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p10" pid="AWxFbwp5NkqoIC7scus_zw" hash="ni1Ncw">Let’s explore each element of the doctrine of Christ.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p11" pid="N-yjYzWSy06Sf1khM2YtIg" hash="bD27zg"><span class="strong">First, faith in Jesus Christ and His Atonement.</span> The prophets have taught that faith begins by hearing the word of Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> The words of Christ testify of His atoning sacrifice and tell us how we may obtain forgiveness, blessings, and exaltation.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p12" pid="46kwKgFK8E-vNHBf_6baCg" hash="o9RUsw">Upon hearing the words of Christ, we exercise faith by choosing to follow the teachings and example of the Savior.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> To do this, Nephi taught that we must rely “wholly upon the merits of [Christ,] who is mighty to save.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> Because Jesus was a God in the premortal existence,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> lived a sinless life,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> and during His Atonement satisfied all the demands of justice for you and me,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> He has the power and keys to bring about the resurrection of all men,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> and He made it possible for mercy to overpower justice upon conditions of repentance.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> Once we understand that we can obtain mercy through Christ’s merits, we are able to “have faith unto repentance.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> To rely wholly upon Christ’s merits then is to trust that He did what was necessary to save us and then to act upon our belief.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p13" pid="iydY8KiuQ0qiGAGNFQTuVg" hash="8E7J-w">Faith also causes us to stop worrying so much about what others think of us and begin to care far more about what God thinks of us.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p14" pid="YgZ4KyvPVkaiH-sCOlbXYw" hash="Dgys1A"><span class="strong">Second, repentance.</span> Samuel the Lamanite taught, “If ye believe on [Christ’s] name ye will repent of all your sins.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> Repentance is a precious gift from our Heavenly Father that is made possible through the sacrifice of His Only Begotten Son. It is the process that the Father has given us by which we change, or turn, our thoughts, actions, and our very being so that we become more and more like the Savior.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> It is not just for big sins but is a daily process of self-evaluation and improvement<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span> that helps us to overcome our sins, our imperfections, our weaknesses, and our inadequacies.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26">26</span> Repentance causes us to become “true followers” of Christ, which fills us with love<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_27">27</span> and casts out our fears.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_28">28</span> Repentance is not a backup plan just in case our plan to live perfectly fails.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_29">29</span> Continual repentance is the only path that can bring us lasting joy and enable us to return to live with our Heavenly Father.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p15" pid="ZDb9esrPWE6tL69y-UdTVQ" hash="etYynw">Through repentance we become submissive and obedient to God’s will. Now, this is not done alone. A recognition of God’s goodness and our nothingness,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_30">30</span> combined with our best efforts to align our behavior with God’s will,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_31">31</span> brings grace into our lives.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_32">32</span> Grace “is divine means of help or strength, given through the bounteous mercy and love of Jesus Christ … to do good works that [we] otherwise would not be able to maintain if left to [our] own means.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_33">33</span> Because repentance is really about becoming like the Savior, which is impossible on our own, we desperately need the Savior’s grace in order to make necessary changes in our lives.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p16" pid="e94ak6AcCkGge-WBK6CDCw" hash="L5p4sw">As we repent, we replace our old, unrighteous behaviors, weaknesses, imperfections, and fears with new behaviors and beliefs that draw us closer to the Savior and help us to become like Him.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p17" pid="VxY3ZUGnKEqTH5lbtConsQ" hash="1R0-RQ"><span class="strong">Third, baptism and the sacrament. </span>The prophet Mormon taught that “the first fruits of repentance is baptism.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_34">34</span> To be complete, repentance must be combined with the ordinance of baptism administered by someone who holds the priesthood authority of God. For members of the Church, the covenants made at baptism and other occasions are renewed as we partake of the sacrament.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_35">35</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p18" pid="SFbTiEgsNEGK55cqe_dKag" hash="l0DVkg">In the ordinances of baptism and the sacrament, we covenant to keep the commandments of the Father and the Son, always remember Christ, and be willing to take Christ’s name (or His work and attributes<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_36">36</span>) upon us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_37">37</span> The Savior, in return, covenants to forgive, or remit, our sins<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_38">38</span> and “pour out his Spirit more abundantly upon [us].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_39">39</span> Christ also promises to prepare us for eternal life by helping us become like Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_40">40</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p19" pid="GdeD5VeCGUmPUVc4MUxJoQ" hash="1Gjxew">Douglas D. Holmes, First Counselor in the Young Men General Presidency, has written: “The ordinances of baptism and the sacrament symbolize both the end result and process of being born again. In baptism, we bury the old man of flesh and come forth to a newness of life.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_41">41</span> In the sacrament, we learn that this change is a step-by-step process, [where] little by little, week by week, we are transformed as we repent, covenant, and through increased endowments of the Spirit [become like the Savior].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_42">42</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p20" pid="eiNKmejq50q3ItSqHy8VtQ" hash="1K6eTQ">Ordinances and covenants are essential within the doctrine of Christ. It is through worthily receiving the ordinances of the priesthood and keeping the associated covenants that the power of godliness is manifest in our lives.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_43">43</span> Elder D. Todd Christofferson explained that “this ‘power of godliness’ comes in the person and by the influence of the Holy Ghost.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_44">44</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p21" pid="A2nAgrGMA06LGAB3lW28bw" hash="bJxt_w"><span class="strong">Fourth, the gift of the Holy Ghost.</span> After baptism we are given the gift of the Holy Ghost through the ordinance of confirmation.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_45">45</span> This gift, if we receive it, allows us to have the constant companionship of a God<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_46">46</span> and continual access to the grace that inherently comes with His influence.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p22" pid="D1hVbhjfaUKWxguCKCS2dQ" hash="lF9Qrw">As our constant companion, the Holy Ghost gives us additional power or strength to keep our covenants.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_47">47</span> He also sanctifies us,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_48">48</span> which means to make us “free from sin, pure, clean, and holy through the atonement of Jesus Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_49">49</span> The process of sanctification not only cleanses us, but it also endows us with needed spiritual gifts or divine attributes of the Savior<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_50">50</span> and changes our very nature,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_51">51</span> such “that we have no more disposition to do evil.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_52">52</span> Each time we receive the Holy Ghost into our lives through faith, repentance, ordinances, Christlike service, and other righteous endeavors, we are changed until step by step, little by little we become like Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_53">53</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p23" pid="LaSS7z53WU63VA-4SLd_mg" hash="gmcmzg"><span class="strong">Fifth, enduring to the end. </span>The prophet Nephi taught that after receiving the gift of the Holy Ghost, we must “endure to the end, in following the example of the Son of the living God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_54">54</span> Elder Dale G. Renlund described the process of enduring to the end as follows: “We may be perfected by repeatedly and iteratively … exercising faith in [Christ], repenting, partaking of the sacrament to renew the covenants and blessings of baptism, and receiving the Holy Ghost as a constant companion to a greater degree. As we do so, we become more like Christ and are able to endure to the end, with all that that entails.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_55">55</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p24" pid="nUfH5YYrZk6JRndyTJhi3Q" hash="MIcwTw">In other words, the reception of the Holy Ghost and the change that reception creates in us further builds our faith. Increased faith leads to additional repentance. As we then symbolically sacrifice our hearts and our sins upon the sacrament altar, we receive the Holy Ghost to a greater degree. Receiving the Holy Ghost to a greater degree further moves us along the path of being born again. As we continue in this process and obtain all the saving ordinances and covenants of the gospel, we receive “grace for grace” until we receive a fulness.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_56">56</span></p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.t2">
			<h2 pid="5K0Q9bhl9E-wbN7l7DjDAQ" hash="6WVjqg">We Must Apply the Doctrine of Christ in Our Lives</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p26" pid="bPgojNiLpECwMk1j7VNfQw" hash="kGWyhw">Brothers and sisters, as we apply the doctrine of Christ in our lives, we are blessed both temporally and spiritually, even in trials. Eventually we are able to “lay hold upon every good thing.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_57">57</span> I testify that this process has happened and continues to happen in my own life, step by step, little by little.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p27" pid="lV-T_1dN20eWHwYgsONAKA" hash="tJ_XTg">But more importantly, we must apply the doctrine of Christ in our lives because it provides the only path back to our Heavenly Father. It is the only way to receive the Savior and become His sons and daughters.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_58">58</span> In fact, the only way to be redeemed from sin and progress spiritually is to apply the doctrine of Christ in our lives.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_59">59</span> Alternatively, the Apostle John taught that “whosoever … abideth not in the doctrine of Christ, hath not God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_60">60</span> And Jesus Himself told the Nephite Twelve that if we fail to exercise faith in Christ, repent, be baptized, and endure to the end, we will be “hewn down and cast into the fire, from whence [we] can no more return.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_61">61</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p28" pid="mzFJm-vMc0eevC0IPyijFg" hash="pKiJdw">So how can we apply the doctrine of Christ more fully in our lives? One way would be to make a conscious effort each week to prepare for the sacrament by taking some time to prayerfully consider where we most need to improve. We could then bring a sacrifice of at least one thing that keeps us from being like Jesus Christ to the sacrament altar, pleading in faith for help, asking for necessary spiritual gifts, and covenanting to improve during the coming week.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_62">62</span> As we do so, the Holy Ghost will come into our lives to a greater degree, and we will have additional strength to overcome our imperfections.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ.p29" pid="9DcBp0ua00esLPYd83a6iw" hash="3mDSCQ">I testify that Jesus Christ is the Savior of the world and that His is the only name by which we can be saved.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_63">63</span> All things that are good are made available only through Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_64">64</span> But to actually “lay hold upon every good thing,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_65">65</span> including eternal life, we must continually apply the doctrine of Christ in our lives. In the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/10/the-doctrine-of-christ</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2016-general-conference/2016-10-5020-brian-k-ashton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5395897" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
