<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Bruce D. Porter</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Bruce D. Porter.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Bruce%20D.%20Porter.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Bruce D. Porter.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1995 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Redeemer of Israel</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The parable of the prodigal son is a parable of us all. It reminds us that we are, in some measure, prodigal sons and daughters of our Father in Heaven. For, as the Apostle Paul wrote, “all have sinned, and come short of the glory of God” ().</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95911_000_008" doc-version="2" hash="ktPxOg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="uWVN-g2OW06xF65txcs9SA" hash="HAo3Qg">Redeemer of Israel</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="PpNacxQYIE6DIXF6x4qOAg" hash="74YaMQ">Bruce D. Porter</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2108.jpg" alt="Elder Bruce D. Porter" pid="zmtQj2gWCEu1fCzsJ8Zg-Q" hash="Fj0lYw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel.p1" pid="U5xrAsFRpUOEHGi4MxmCpA" hash="U_pnGA">The parable of the prodigal son is a parable of us all. It reminds us that we are, in some measure, prodigal sons and daughters of our Father in Heaven. For, as the Apostle Paul wrote, “all have sinned, and come short of the glory of God” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/3.23" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 3:23</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel.p2" pid="CKCSYVn5CUexcL8sxm7Spw" hash="Xe3INA">Like the errant son of the Savior’s parable, we have come to “a far country” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15.13" class="scriptureRef">Luke 15:13</a>) separated from our premortal home. Like the prodigal, we share in a divine inheritance, but by our sins we squander a portion thereof and experience a “mighty famine” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15.14" class="scriptureRef">Luke 15:14</a>) of spirit. Like him, we learn through painful experience that worldly pleasures and pursuits are of no more worth than the husks of corn that swine eat. We yearn to be reconciled with our Father and return to his home.</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="qoX3HrBNbkyRkQtVSuC0ag" hash="XTSrEg">
            <span class="emphasis">How long we have wandered</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="db9xe6vhr0uMLKnmmMD6bw" hash="DRj_Ew">
            <span class="emphasis">As strangers in sin,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="5ubfT0BgfkWEwSfddiFCfg" hash="MyBZkQ">
            <span class="emphasis">And cried in the desert for thee!</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel.p3" pid="v1tP2BTlnkytSZ-Z6t_JdQ" hash="ASauNQ">In the parable of the prodigal son, only the eldest son remains true to his father; in his own words, “Neither transgressed I at any time thy commandment” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15.29" class="scriptureRef">Luke 15:29</a>). Similarly, in the plan of salvation, the Firstborn of the Father is sinless and without spot. Yet there is a vital difference. In the parable, the eldest son is jealous of the attention paid to the returning prodigal. In the plan of salvation, however, the eldest son <span class="emphasis">makes possible</span> the return of the prodigals.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel.p4" pid="-xPtD70Ej06MSZJ0UndxCA" hash="2tpFiA">The Father sends him forth to redeem his sons and daughters from bondage. The eldest is filled with compassion. “I will save them out of all their dwellingplaces, wherein they have sinned, and will cleanse them” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ezek/37.23" class="scriptureRef">Ezek. 37:23</a>). He journeys the long distance to find and bring home the prodigal ones. And there he finds us weary, hungry, and downtrodden. He feeds us and gives us drink. He lives among us and shares our burdens. Then, in a final act of supreme love, the eldest son takes of his own wealth and, one by one, he ransoms us. In order to pay the fulness of our debt, he is compelled to sacrifice his own fortune, yea, all that he has, every whit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel.p5" pid="RzyWQ8tm1UKq5trXHgsiJQ" hash="-vHFBg">There are those who refuse the proffered ransom. Chained by pride, they prefer bondage to repentance. But those who accept of his offering and forsake their errant ways receive healing at his hands and liberty as his gift. These he leads back to the Father with songs of everlasting joy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel.p6" pid="0RJW6xfUDE-SzdNNNt9lSg" hash="FJiEOg">I testify that the eldest son of our Father in Heaven did redeem us from the bondage of sin. We are a purchased people. In the words of Paul, “Ye are bought with a price” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/7.23" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 7:23</a>). In the Garden of Gethsemane, the Firstborn of the Father “descended below all things” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:6</a>); he bore “our griefs, and carried our sorrows” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/53.4" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 53:4</a>). At Golgotha, at the hands of men for whose very sins he had atoned, “he … poured out his soul unto death” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/53.12" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 53:12</a>), freely relinquishing his life as he overcame the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel.p7" pid="f-lDSTy6Dk62NxAUlhb9NQ" hash="OJNkmQ">In the premortal realm, he had been the God of Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob, the Creator of the earth, the great I AM. From these exalted heights, he descended, coming to earth in the most humble of circumstances that he might be no stranger to our sorrows. Instead of worldly station, he chose to be born in a lowly stable and live the simple life of a carpenter. He grew up in an obscure village in a despised precinct of Palestine. He made himself of no reputation, and was “a root out of a dry ground,” having “no beauty that we should desire him” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/53.2" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 53:2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel.p8" pid="H-IS_NyqSE2Vi_50svgYcg" hash="1G_5Ww">He might have had political power and honor; he chose instead to be a healer and a teacher. He might have won the favor of his people by freeing them from Roman oppression; instead, he saved them from their sins and was rejected by his own. He sacrificed the glory of Galilee to experience the humiliation and trial of Jerusalem. Then, in a most literal way, the Lord Jesus Christ paid the utmost demands of our ransom, as he bore “the pain of all men” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.11" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:11</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel.p9" pid="aGn7BY4UWU2963GIOgw6fQ" hash="_ioT6g">“And the world, because of their iniquity, shall judge him to be a thing of naught; wherefore they scourge him, and he suffereth it; and they smite him, and he suffereth it. Yea, they spit upon him, and he suffereth it, because of his loving kindness and his long-suffering towards the children of men” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/19.9" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 19:9</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel.p10" pid="EIEM8GJtRUGcvO2V4WQc3Q" hash="GFab7w">A few years ago I visited Jerusalem shortly before Christmas. The streets were cold and dreary; there was political tension in the air. Yet peace filled my heart to know that this was the city he loved so much, the very place of his eternal sacrifice; to know that here had lived he who was the Savior of all mankind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel.p11" pid="eeVERfFGRUi2_wOoJUVqHw" hash="ZZJN9w">I returned to the United States late on a Saturday evening. When the Sabbath dawned, my alarm awoke me to these words from “O Holy Night”:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel.f3">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="EITrHR7yBkGWutgt610MTw" hash="7-Abbg">
            <span class="emphasis">The King of kings lay thus in lowly manger,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="uKfc9tpq4kClmmC2mhtHmQ" hash="H5D9Xw">
            <span class="emphasis">In all our trials born to be our friend.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel.p12" pid="hWCAp9zffk-v8URRkVvcyg" hash="-RGWgw">And I began to weep as I contemplated the perfect life and glorious sacrifice of the Redeemer of Israel—he who was born the friend of the lowly and hope of the meek.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel.p13" pid="mK-f9UFH10e5KpxLEC-tlA" hash="q9yZYg">I bear testimony that the Lord Jesus Christ has paid the price of our sins, upon condition of repentance. He is the Firstborn of the Father. He is the Holy One of Israel. He is the first fruits of the Resurrection. I testify that he lives. I testify that he is in very deed, “our only delight, … our King, our Deliv’rer, our all!” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> 1985, no. 6.) In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/10/redeemer-of-israel</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1995-general-conference/1995-10-1060-elder-bruce-d-porter-64k-eng.mp3" length="3299717" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1995 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building the Kingdom</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom?lang=eng</link>
      <description>From its earliest days, the Lord’s Church has been built up by ordinary people who magnified their callings in humility and devotion.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029247_000_034" doc-version="2" hash="dn4Svg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="4fBR2ufWg0aFGz973PGaIQ" hash="-kAAWw">Building the Kingdom</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ajD_vYI_J0meBGsFz83vPw" hash="74YaMQ">Bruce D. Porter</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="D11Cjcf1WkOOBS_NibYIhg" hash="Q5mhtQ">From its earliest days, the Lord’s Church has been built up by ordinary people who magnified their callings in humility and devotion.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1389.jpg" alt="Elder Bruce D. Porter" pid="KDtHIncBMEi4IUN0P9vx4g" hash="mZNdVw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom.p1" pid="yVtBHgff0EiIUSC6L872pQ" hash="AChZ3w">Nearly 25 years ago, our family lived in Massachusetts, where I was enrolled in graduate school. My program of study was very demanding, leaving me little free time. One Sunday in church the ward Primary president approached me and asked if I might substitute as a Primary teacher for two weeks. Primary was then held on a weekday afternoon, and I knew it would be difficult to find room in my schedule to teach the class. But after some hesitation, I agreed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom.p2" pid="35YEIS9VYEeayGGKleTnLw" hash="mDv6Cw">The appointed day came to teach Primary. That afternoon I was in the university library, absorbed in a book on international politics. The subject I was studying seemed somehow more important than the upcoming Primary class. Consequently, I procrastinated until just 30 minutes before the class was to begin to review the lesson I was to teach. Then I walked from the library down to our ward chapel on the edge of campus. My reluctant attitude must have slowed my steps, for I arrived a few minutes late. As I stepped to the door of the Primary room, the children were just beginning to sing the opening hymn. It was a song I had never heard before, a song whose melody and message touched me deeply:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="Rb65dwHhQ0yzXtPPPQFaVQ" hash="e4GCbA">
            <span class="emphasis">As I have loved you,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="MPwW9zngs0KgMXSbhjYreg" hash="TYcMDQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Love one another.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="DHjj7kv5SEK2yBuGrd8Brw" hash="DMTmdw">
            <span class="emphasis">This new commandment:</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="1wtrzzMTj023g3unEzXrGQ" hash="TYcMDQ1">
            <span class="emphasis">Love one another.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="_I59upif-EmVntdREW2MdA" hash="ZeZUyQ">
            <span class="emphasis">By this shall men know</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="-SvRIfdd-0ewcxkY730_yw" hash="7j3j5A">
            <span class="emphasis">Ye are my disciples,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="zrxb4gQbjEyRVp8btzNNgQ" hash="HNVdZg">
            <span class="emphasis">If ye have love</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="t1LDL1OoSEKJJrmho1S_NA" hash="R7h0Hg">
            <span class="emphasis">One to another.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom.p3" pid="iUVQGgVFeUS-TCW5KneKPg" hash="2merYQ">As I stood there, transfixed in the doorway, the Spirit bore witness that I was looking at the most important class taking place in Cambridge, Massachusetts, that day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom.p4" pid="iEPGyPwts0-XAi3o79G1Rw" hash="5LyeFQ">Back at the university in dozens of classrooms and laboratories, dedicated scholars were pursuing answers to the world’s problems. Yet valuable though such efforts may have been, the university did not and could not hold the ultimate answers to the problems of a troubled world. Here before me was the Lord’s answer: the quiet building up of His kingdom on earth by the teaching of the gospel of Jesus Christ. What was taking place in Primary that day was a small part of a divinely revealed plan for the salvation of a fallen world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom.p5" pid="1sEwCj2GbE2C9mTFzS9Lvw" hash="yu7x8A">In October 1831, the Lord in reference to the Restoration declared, “The keys of the kingdom of God are committed unto man on the earth, and from thence shall the gospel roll forth unto the ends of the earth, as the stone which is cut out of the mountain without hands shall roll forth, until it has filled the whole earth” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/65.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 65:2</a>). The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is that kingdom whose destiny it is to fill the whole earth. In the miraculous wisdom of the Almighty, the building up of God’s kingdom in the latter days will take place by means as plain and simple as what I witnessed in Primary that day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom.p6" pid="rOWvqA9VeEWVS96iOmcshw" hash="_Gno2w">We rejoice to hear of temples being reared in every quarter of the earth and of far-flung nations opening their doors to the gospel. Built upon a foundation of apostles and prophets, the Lord’s Church is being taken to the whole world by missionaries called to proclaim His word. Sometimes, perhaps, we may be inclined to see the building of the kingdom as something that takes place beyond the horizon, far away from our own branch or ward. In truth, the Church advances both by outward expansion and by inward refinement. “For Zion must increase in beauty, and in holiness; her borders must be enlarged; her stakes must be strengthened” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/82.14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 82:14</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom.p7" pid="BiV-aBJIwEmS9FcFlcLI2A" hash="jYSWAw">We do not have to be called to serve far from home, nor do we have to hold a prominent place in the Church or in the world to build up the Lord’s kingdom. We build it in our own hearts as we cultivate the Spirit of God in our lives. We build it within our families by instilling faith in our children. And we build it through the organization of the Church as we magnify our callings and share the gospel with neighbors and friends.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom.p8" pid="aXO08hihu02g127cuO6Ukg" hash="U_uilA">As our missionaries labor in fields ready for harvest, others labor in fields at home to strengthen the kingdom in the ward and community where they reside. From its earliest days, the Lord’s Church has been built up by ordinary people who magnified their callings in humility and devotion. It does not matter to what office we are called to serve, only that we act “in all diligence” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.99" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:99</a>). In the words of modern revelation: “Be not weary in well-doing, for ye are laying the foundation of a great work. And out of small things proceedeth that which is great” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.33" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:33</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom.p9" pid="QduMMkexOUGDqMEttJRYcw" hash="6ZTnBw">President Joseph F. Smith observed once that “great causes are not won in a single generation” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Doctrine,</span> 5th ed. [1939], 119). More than anywhere else, it is within the family, in the quiet sanctuary of the home, that generations unite in building the kingdom of God. The rearing of children is a divine work. The First Presidency has called on the parents of the Church to hold family home evening and family prayer, to study the gospel in the home, and to spend time with children in wholesome activities. As fathers and mothers teach their children the eternal truths once taught to them, they pass on the torch of truth to yet another generation, and the kingdom waxes stronger.</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom.f3">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="UOGtkmN1OUGL-WeJD1VbRw" hash="V1D7DQ">
            <span class="emphasis">We are watchers of a beacon</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="0COfitX08EGcALwTb_Zb2w" hash="noikxg">
            <span class="emphasis">Whose light must never die.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom.p10" pid="1Vtid8__NkyVqm9cHmqCqQ" hash="Bm8WyQ">When I was growing up, my father often led our family in gospel discussions around the dinner table. Only with the perspective of years do I understand today the contribution those family hours made to my own testimony. I rejoice in the prophecy of Isaiah that the time will come when “upon every dwelling place of mount Zion” there shall be “a cloud … by day, and … a flaming fire by night” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/4.5" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 4:5</a>), when the Spirit of God will abide in the homes of His people continually.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom.p11" pid="sHbcoCa080edIgfTx53TZA" hash="yv86LQ">The Lord’s kingdom encompasses not only Church and family, but also the hearts and minds of His people. As the Savior taught during His mortal ministry, “The kingdom of God is within you” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/17.21" class="scriptureRef">Luke 17:21</a>). If we truly desire to contribute to the great latter-day work, our eyes will be single to the glory of God, our minds enlightened by “the testimony of Jesus” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rev/19.10" class="scriptureRef">Rev. 19:10</a>), our hearts pure and consecrated. Personal prayer, study, and pondering are vital to the building up of the kingdom within our own souls. It is in quiet moments of contemplation and communion with the Almighty that we come to know and love Him as our Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom.p12" pid="tAQGshC0YEugp9TjEAOmjQ" hash="aQc7pA">I bear witness that the kingdom of God has been restored to the earth, never to be taken away again. Under the direction of our Eternal Father, Jesus Christ is the Author and Finisher of this work, the cornerstone of the Church, and the Holy One of Israel. In the strength and power of the Lord, may we build up the kingdom of God on earth that it may be prepared to meet the kingdom of heaven at His coming. In the words of a battlefield anthem that might also stand as an anthem of the Restoration:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom.f4">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="yHotjQlZ00Cy6vREGt7wBA" hash="IUV5nw">
            <span class="emphasis">He has sounded forth the trumpet that shall never call retreat;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Xw_4cU2fGk-hhv8HBqxO3A" hash="5_lRxA">
            <span class="emphasis">He is sifting out the hearts of men before his judgment seat.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="zy77xylgMEWDZekELUYuPw" hash="bLuueQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Oh, be swift, my soul, to answer him; be jubilant my feet!</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="WSYB383D9EaWJrkb7oT5JA" hash="DRIkVA">
            <span class="emphasis">Our God is marching on.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom.p13" pid="M-6lAo_QlUq0-Mp7oMu1BA" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2001/04/building-the-kingdom</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2001-general-conference/2001-04-5050-elder-bruce-d-porter-64k-eng.mp3" length="5231278" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Broken Heart and a Contrite Spirit</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Those who have a broken heart and a contrite spirit are willing to do anything and everything that God asks of them.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008332_000_012" doc-version="2" hash="yfH47A"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="vBBv4aVax0uclEad5HEOXQ" hash="xbiw3g">A Broken Heart and a Contrite Spirit</h1><p class="authorName" guid="d08048e9-d9c9-4ac5-ad55-7e3253428714" pid="Q5j0xRW4X0i8RV-7H1FZCQ" hash="74YaMQ">Bruce D. Porter</p><p class="kicker" pid="0QDnccWbkkydPfJ_hI3NEg" hash="skhJrA">Those who have a broken heart and a contrite spirit are willing to do anything and everything that God asks of them.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="4d9c3a2f-e723-46bd-9318-706c27c6c3a8">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.t1">
      <img src="PorterBD_all.ob.jpg" alt="Elder Bruce D. Porter" guid="c429283b-4705-4c7a-862f-6a596e174e81" pid="29Daq1v6IUSWvlcs7Z83ng" hash="80ZVlQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.p" pid="-C1jCzhCSEKYMaqhu_-RNg" hash="1GgNUg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="31"></span>How I love Elder Joseph B. Wirthlin! The poet Rudyard Kipling wrote the following words in 1897, an admonition to the British Empire against pride:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.f1" guid="e51d6013-0b97-452a-861b-c20110e6afa8">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="64Wyo6iv_ECqv9XHxxho4g" hash="oFF_7A">
            <span class="emphasis">The tumult and the shouting dies;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="PSOuPZ4TVUynIT4qyflniA" hash="dVKMoA">
            <span class="emphasis">The captains and the kings depart.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="0SCCbFK560iWN4q7o0cCxg" hash="-xyUuw">
            <span class="emphasis">Still stands thine ancient sacrifice,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Zp2xyXfldEuSgEdrd6YOSA" hash="XrKylw">
            <span class="emphasis">An humble and a contrite heart.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.p" pid="89p2bR4q3k2SdUfj3nCJgQ" hash="DUcLOQ">When Kipling spoke of a contrite heart as an “<span class="emphasis">ancient</span> sacrifice,” perhaps he had in mind the words of King David in the 51st Psalm: “The sacrifices of God are a broken spirit:,a broken and a contrite heart” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/51.17" class="scriptureRef">v. 17</a>). David’s words show that even in Old Testament times, the Lord’s people understood that their hearts must be given to God, that burnt offerings alone were not enough.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.p" pid="VHOQKX-fH0mg8DS6KKc2HA" hash="lKJjSA">The sacrifices mandated during the Mosaic dispensation pointed symbolically to the atoning sacrifice of the Messiah, who alone could reconcile sinful man with God. As Amulek taught, “Behold, this is the whole meaning of the law, every whit pointing to that great and last sacrifice; … the Son of God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/34.14" class="scriptureRef">Alma 34:14</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.p" pid="BjmbIysBtUCSAUnECTqg8A" hash="c8ZA7A">After His Resurrection, Jesus Christ declared to the people in the New World:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.p" pid="6ePQHJWTNkWnZKXEkg_QsQ" hash="yJHWKQ">“Your sacrifices and your burnt offerings shall be done away, for I will accept none of [them]. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.p" pid="dpoGmasjBEeFRH0E1xTHEA" hash="jAF9lw">“And ye shall offer for a sacrifice unto me a broken heart and a contrite spirit. And whoso cometh unto me with a broken heart … , him will I baptize with fire and with the Holy Ghost” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/9.19-20" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 9:19–20</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.p" pid="ZVZw2rInukqaKGc4zceY5A" hash="JQMJxw">What are a broken heart and a contrite spirit? And why are they considered a sacrifice?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.p" pid="LZXUreZp_UiR2x3FwLWSKw" hash="USa88Q">As in all things, the Savior’s life offers us the perfect example: though Jesus of Nazareth was utterly without sin, He walked through life with a broken heart and a contrite spirit, as <span class="pageBreak" page-number="32"></span>manifested by His submission to the will of the Father. “For I came down from heaven, not to do mine own will, but the will of him that sent me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/6.38" class="scriptureRef">John 6:38</a>). To His disciples He said, “Learn of me; for I am meek and lowly in heart” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/11.29" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 11:29</a>). And when the time came to pay the ultimate sacrifice entailed in the Atonement, Christ shrank not to partake of the bitter cup but submitted completely to His Father’s will.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.p" pid="COG-EhXZUUOtwlkhjd3N6Q" hash="dQ3feQ">The Savior’s perfect submission to the Eternal Father is the very essence of a broken heart and a contrite spirit. Christ’s example teaches us that a broken heart is an eternal attribute of godliness. When our hearts are broken, we are completely open to the Spirit of God and recognize our dependence on Him for all that we have and all that we are. The sacrifice so entailed is a sacrifice of pride in all its forms. Like malleable clay in the hands of a skilled potter, the brokenhearted can be molded and shaped in the hands of the Master.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.p" pid="w8WYhHcWhES1_mu1iSGiaw" hash="8Idt4Q">A broken heart and a contrite spirit are also preconditions to repentance. Lehi taught:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.p" pid="hH5Nco0ug06uFyUiDStkcA" hash="X2F4aQ">“Wherefore, redemption cometh in and through the Holy Messiah. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.p" pid="4FA4_C4pXU6FNHvaZ0mcOg" hash="eHnhxQ">“Behold, he offereth himself a sacrifice for sin, to answer the ends of the law, unto all those who have a broken heart and a contrite spirit; and unto none else can the ends of the law be answered” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.6-7" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 2:6–7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.p" pid="hJxwZSN-qEykbcqU-Prg5A" hash="7H6QlQ">When we sin and desire forgiveness, a broken heart and a contrite spirit mean to experience “godly sorrow [that] worketh repentance” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-cor/7.10" class="scriptureRef">2 Corinthians 7:10</a>). This comes when our desire to be cleansed from sin is so consuming that our hearts ache with sorrow and we yearn to feel at peace with our Father in Heaven. Those who have a broken heart and a contrite spirit are willing to do anything and everything that God asks of them, without resistance or resentment. We cease doing things our way and learn to do them God’s way instead. In such a condition of submissiveness, the Atonement can take effect and true repentance can occur. The penitent will then experience the sanctifying power of the Holy Ghost, which will fill them with peace of conscience and the joy of reconciliation with God. In a wondrous union of divine attributes, the same God who teaches us to walk with a broken heart invites us to rejoice and to be of good cheer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.p" pid="D_L4WcYQVUin5V-R_cHtyw" hash="lQ9znA">When we have received a forgiveness of sins, a broken heart serves as a divine shield against temptation. Nephi prayed, “May the gates of hell be shut continually before me, because that my heart is broken and my spirit is contrite!” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/4.32" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 4:32</a>). King Benjamin taught his people that if they would walk in the depths of humility, they might ever rejoice, “be filled with the love of God, and always retain a remission of … sins” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.12" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:12</a>). When we yield our hearts to the Lord, the attractions of the world simply lose their luster.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.p" pid="-Y2XfazpuEipxLfzyCBDtg" hash="Kpby0w">There is yet another dimension of a broken heart—namely, our deep gratitude for Christ’s suffering on our behalf. In Gethsemane, the Savior “descended below all things” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:6</a>) as He bore the burden of sin for every human being. At Golgotha, He “poured out his soul unto death” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/53.12" class="scriptureRef">Isaiah 53:12</a>), and His great heart literally broke with an all-encompassing love for the children of God. When we remember the Savior and His suffering, our hearts too will break in gratitude for the Anointed One.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit.p" pid="UAnjXoFB5EKCNgw1N1KO3g" hash="d9XK5w">As we make the sacrifice to Him of all that we have and all that we are, the Lord will fill our hearts with peace. He will “bind up the brokenhearted” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/61.1" class="scriptureRef">Isaiah 61:1</a>) and grace our lives with the love of God, “sweet above all that is sweet, … and pure above all that is pure” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.42" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:42</a>). Of this I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <img src="PorterBD_all.ob.jpg" alt="Elder Bruce D. Porter" guid="c429283b-4705-4c7a-862f-6a596e174e81" pid="_n4zK8otKUyxFiaEnXCEkw" hash="80ZVlQ1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="c429283b-4705-4c7a-862f-6a596e174e81"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/10/a-broken-heart-and-a-contrite-spirit</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2007-general-conference/2007-10-2030-elder-bruce-d-porter-64k-eng.mp3" length="4174360" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful Mornings</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We need not fear the future, nor falter in hope and good cheer, because God is with us.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10785_000_56porter" doc-version="2" hash="1cLAJg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="HkbpHI1io0qMygXy8HoBEw" hash="-ii13Q">Beautiful Mornings</h1><p class="authorName" pid="s6pUI3lzmUamZcIvqfJMrw" hash="8n-Yiw">By Elder Bruce D. Porter</p><p class="kicker" pid="jSyydFd4AkuCeVWoP-pBrg" hash="vUfgIg">We need not fear the future, nor falter in hope and good cheer, because God is with us.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" pid="1x0Ok0i_E0G5P8ccuAcV2g" hash="fmbBjA">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p5" pid="cnleAda4SkSOYIoiQD0GHw" hash="k6vsIQ"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="107"></span>On a Thursday evening in Jerusalem, Jesus met with His disciples in an upper room to observe Passover. The men who joined Him did not know that this meal would someday be called the Last Supper. Had they known this and what it meant, they would have wept.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p6" pid="C2Pk9ijSykyH9m-JmUB-vQ" hash="AkZ6oA">Their Master, however, perfectly understood that the ordeal of Gethsemane and of Golgotha would shortly begin. The darkest hours in the history of the world were imminent; nevertheless, Jesus said to them, “In the world ye shall have tribulation: but be of good cheer; I have overcome the world” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/16.33" class="scriptureRef">John 16:33</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p7" pid="lNuDSKf4n0iJsmmnXHpnow" hash="iyRkSw">We live today in an era of turbulence and uncertainty, a time the Lord prophesied to Enoch would be marked by “days of wickedness and vengeance” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/7.60" class="scriptureRef">Moses 7:60</a>). Tribulation and difficult times may lie ahead, yet we too have cause for good cheer and rejoicing, for we live in the last dispensation, when God has restored His Church and kingdom to the earth in preparation for the return of His Son.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p8" pid="i3H9OF1lb0-8OMI7hK_j8A" hash="k5iJuA">President Boyd K. Packer once spoke of his grandchildren and the increasingly troubled world in which they live. He said: “They will see many events transpire in the course of their lifetime. Some of these shall tax their courage and extend their faith. But if they seek prayerfully for help and guidance, they shall be given power over adverse things.”</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p9" pid="GTxS_KS04kmNAJqK25_-dQ" hash="QQixMQ">And later he added: “The moral values upon which civilization itself must depend spiral downward at an ever-increasing pace. Nevertheless, I do not fear the future” (“Do Not Fear,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign</span> or <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> May 2004, 77, 78).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p10" pid="KMsRxlWOpkK8ZRl9xu7Myg" hash="lBbxiw">Brothers and sisters, we need not fear the future, nor falter in hope and good cheer, because God is with us. Among the first recorded words of counsel that Jesus gave to His newly called disciples in Galilee was the two-word admonition, “Fear not” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/5.10" class="scriptureRef">Luke 5:10</a>). He repeated that counsel many times during His ministry. To His Saints in our day, the Savior has said, “Be of good cheer, and do not fear, for I the Lord am with you, and will stand by you” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:6</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p11" pid="RUrGk-ohoUqjFmq75FEtLQ" hash="e9mvoQ">The Lord will stand by His Church and people and keep them in safety until His coming. There will be peace in Zion and in her stakes, for He has proclaimed “that the gathering together upon the land of Zion, and upon her stakes, may be for a defense, and for a refuge from the storm, and from wrath when it shall be poured out without mixture upon the whole earth” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/115.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 115:6</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p12" pid="OtCbNCenzEKsbEHZLA7Mgg" hash="YZV4Hg">The Church stands as a bulwark of safety for its members. Though conditions in the world may become very vexing at times, faithful Latter-day Saints will find sanctuary in the stakes of Zion. The Lord has decreed that the stone cut out of the mountain without hands shall roll forth until it has filled the whole earth (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/dan/2.31-45" class="scriptureRef">Daniel 2:31–45</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/65.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 65:2</a>). And no human power can stay its course, for God is the author of this work and Jesus Christ is the chief cornerstone.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p13" pid="LkOtN0dr1U6ZeJ5NGJncWw" hash="X6Ostw">The prophet Nephi beheld in vision that in the last days, the power of the Lamb of God would descend “upon the covenant people of the Lord” and they would be “armed with righteousness and with the power of God in great glory” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/14.14" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 14:14</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p14" pid="aZfCeeDGj0-5r6OIMch0Zg" hash="zdWWuA">Every one of us, and our families, can be armed with the power of God <span class="pageBreak" page-number="108"></span>as a defense if we will but remain true to The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and let the Spirit be our guide. Trials may come, and we may not understand everything that happens to us or around us. But if we humbly, quietly trust in the Lord, He will give us strength and guidance in every challenge we face. When our only desire is to please Him, we will be blessed with a deep inner peace.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p15" pid="snvRgEgGc06SSHLwfy16_Q" hash="tZ7R7g">In the early days of the Restoration, the members of the Church faced severe trials. President Brigham Young said of that time: “When surrounded by mobs, with death and destruction threatening on every hand, I am not aware but that I felt just as joyful [and] well in my spirits, as I do now. Prospects might appear dull and very dark, but I have never seen a time in this Gospel but what I knew that the result would be beneficial to the cause of truth” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of Presidents of the Church: Brigham Young</span> [1997], 357).</p>
				<span class="story">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p16" pid="AjPJ1kfWJUOiUVY30jlvKw" hash="LAIuVw">My missionary companion, Paul, was someone who always radiated good cheer. As a young father, he was stricken with multiple sclerosis. Yet despite the adversity that followed, he continued serving others with joy and good humor. He once entered my office seated in his first wheelchair and declared, “Life begins with a motorized wheelchair!” I will always remember him, a few years before he died, holding high the Olympic torch while riding in his wheelchair as hundreds cheered. Like that ever-burning flame, Paul’s faith never dimmed in the storm of life.</p>
				</span>
				<span class="story">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p17" pid="6_qM_Q88L0-PPWCrvN_sVA" hash="MJjbCg">When I was a student at Brigham Young University, I lived in a house with several young men. My roommate, Bruce, was the most optimistic person I have ever known. We never once heard him say anything negative about any person or any circumstance, and it was impossible not to feel buoyed up in his presence. His good cheer flowed from an abiding trust in the Savior and in His gospel.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p18" pid="nxsfUDtpHU-SAdgzqNWW2Q" hash="ZrqFCA">One cold, wintry day, another friend of mine, Tom, was walking across the university campus. It was only 7:00 in the morning, and the campus was deserted and dark. Heavy snow was falling, with a brisk wind. “What miserable weather,” Tom thought. He walked farther, and out in the darkness and snow, he heard someone singing.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p19" pid="3NsjrjBy10Kyn61Pw4NsEg" hash="RafwXg">Sure enough, through the driving snow came our ever-optimistic friend, Bruce. With his arms outstretched to the sky, he was singing a number from the Broadway musical <span class="emphasis">Oklahoma:</span> “Oh, what a beautiful morning! Oh, what a beautiful day! I’ve got a beautiful feeling, everything’s going my way” (see Richard Rodgers and Oscar Hammerstein II, “Oh, What a Beautiful Mornin’” [1943]).</p>
				</span>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p20" pid="q4n_myeB_kWTQ6Fogd-60w" hash="pmijMw">In the intervening years, that bright voice in a dark storm has become for me a symbol of what faith and hope are all about. Even in a darkening world, we as Latter-day Saints may sing with joy, knowing that the powers of heaven are with God’s Church and people. We may rejoice in the knowledge that a beautiful morning lies ahead—the dawn of the millennial day, when the Son of God shall rise in the East and reign again on the earth.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p21" pid="o9BwTK2zWkWI3ke9CKF7iA" hash="kh-Qig">I think also of two other beautiful mornings in the history of the world. In the spring of 1820, on the morning of a beautiful, clear day in Palmyra, New York, a young man named Joseph Smith entered a grove of trees and knelt in prayer. The answer to that prayer, the appearance of the Father and the Son, ushered in the dispensation of the fulness of times and the Restoration of the Church of Jesus Christ to the earth.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p22" pid="2YIQ44zXhUivsCaIkpuswQ" hash="U6vEvA">And yet another beautiful morning dawned nearly 2,000 years ago just outside the city wall of Jerusalem. The sun no doubt shone with exceptional radiance that Easter morning. A small company of women had come to visit a garden tomb, hoping to anoint the body of their crucified Lord. Two angels met them and declared: “Why seek ye the living among the dead? He is not here, but is risen” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/24.5-6" class="scriptureRef">Luke 24:5–6</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings.p23" pid="nqVVcux-hUyw3R1vd6WE9g" hash="jhbnAw">Of the triumph of Jesus Christ over sin and death, I bear witness. Of the merciful plan of our Eternal Father and His everlasting love, I testify. As we rise up each morning, may we look to heaven in faith and say, “Oh, what a beautiful morning,” I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2013/04/beautiful-mornings</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2013-general-conference/2013-04-5060-elder-bruce-d-porter-64k-eng.mp3" length="5005908" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
