<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Bruce C. Hafen</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Bruce C. Hafen.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Bruce%20C.%20Hafen.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Bruce C. Hafen.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 1996 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Covenant Marriage</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Three summers ago, I watched a new bride and groom, Tracy and Tom, emerge from a sacred temple. They laughed and held hands as family and friends gathered to take pictures. I saw happiness and promise in their faces as they greeted their reception gu</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_96911_000_012" doc-version="2" hash="pjtHxw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="g5MYuz3xxk6ofoujArAHRQ" hash="I2jOEw">Covenant Marriage</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="VxcLri0LdUWHLGyPgyXysg" hash="PHz0hA">Bruce C. Hafen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1fa8.jpg" alt="Elder Bruce C. Hafen" pid="DdvDNKZI6km5K3dFYTdCgw" hash="qrMpnA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p1" pid="D2o-qi4anUGliFOPNHqr9Q" hash="OBEmFA">Three summers ago, I watched a new bride and groom, Tracy and Tom, emerge from a sacred temple. They laughed and held hands as family and friends gathered to take pictures. I saw happiness and promise in their faces as they greeted their reception guests, who celebrated publicly the creation of a new family. I wondered that night how long it would be until these two faced the opposition that tests every marriage. Only then would they discover whether their marriage was based on a <span class="emphasis">contract</span> or a <span class="emphasis">covenant.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p2" pid="1Zk5FKf-_0SvXjuQqIr4rg" hash="g71yMQ">Another bride sighed blissfully on her wedding day, “Mom, I’m at the end of all my troubles!” “Yes,” replied her mother, “but at which end?” When troubles come, the parties to a <span class="emphasis">contractual</span> marriage seek happiness by walking away. They marry to obtain benefits and will stay only as long as they’re receiving what they bargained for. But when troubles come to a <span class="emphasis">covenant</span> marriage, the husband and wife work them through. They marry to give and to grow, bound by covenants to each other, to the community, and to God. <span class="emphasis">Contract</span> companions each give 50 percent; <span class="emphasis">covenant</span> companions each give 100 percent.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p3" pid="-iAstHmYEke7Z_J7F-na-g" hash="vOFw3w">Marriage is by nature a covenant, not just a private contract one may cancel at will. Jesus taught about contractual attitudes when he described the “hireling,” who performs his conditional promise of care only when he receives something in return. When the hireling “seeth the wolf coming,” he “leaveth the sheep, and fleeth … because he … careth not for the sheep.” By contrast, the Savior said, “I am the good shepherd, … and I lay down my life for the sheep.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Many people today marry as hirelings. And when the wolf comes, they flee. This idea is wrong. It curses the earth, turning parents’ hearts away from their children and from each other.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p4" pid="Hx-w8Ylndk-MiEob6tYd5A" hash="_X0bNg">Before their marriage, Tom and Tracy received an eternal perspective on covenants and wolves. They learned through the story of Adam and Eve about life’s purpose and how to return to God’s presence through obedience and the Atonement. Christ’s life is the story of giving the Atonement. The life of Adam and Eve is the story of receiving the Atonement, which empowered them to overcome their separation from God and all opposition until they were eternally “at one,” with the Lord, and with each other.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p5" pid="KpNCjOsQHEm5eI708bp6kg" hash="hnNO-g">Without the Fall, Lehi taught, Adam and Eve would never have known opposition. And “they would have had no children; wherefore they would have remained in a state of innocence, having no joy, for they knew no misery.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Astute parents will see a little connection here—no children, no misery! But left in the garden, they could never know joy. So the Lord taught them they would live and bear children in sorrow, sweat, and thorns.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p6" pid="bEfEt_hcek-GT3GLCUOahg" hash="I9CkiA">Still, the ground was cursed <span class="emphasis">for their sake:</span><span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> their path of affliction also led to the <span class="emphasis">joy</span> of both redemption and comprehension.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> That is why the husband and wife in a covenant marriage sustain and lift each other when the wolf comes. If Tom and Tracy had understood all this, perhaps they would have walked more slowly from the gardenlike temple grounds, like Adam and Eve, arm in arm, into a harsh and lonely world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p7" pid="5G5NiYIUIUmZqlnRJjCUGw" hash="U1qJqQ">And yet—marrying and raising children <span class="emphasis">can</span> yield the most valuable religious experiences of their lives. Covenant marriage requires a total leap of faith: they must keep their covenants without knowing what risks that may require of them. They must surrender unconditionally, obeying God and sacrificing for each other. Then they will discover what Alma called “incomprehensible joy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p8" pid="EhjdCFWT-0CDduMXp2g9Cg" hash="UNV7ZQ">Of course, some have no opportunity to marry. And some divorces are unavoidable. But the Lord will ultimately compensate those faithful ones who are denied mortal fulfillment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p9" pid="kLd2YctsoEGVqCLiTwiS4w" hash="iehwKQ">Every marriage is tested repeatedly by three kinds of wolves. The first wolf is natural adversity. After asking God for years to give them a first child, David and Fran had a baby with a serious heart defect. Following a three-week struggle, they buried their newborn son. Like Adam and Eve before them, they mourned together, brokenhearted, in faith before the Lord.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p10" pid="OVngoonVqEyubIbmbJxbgg" hash="44XF8w">Second, the wolf of their own imperfections will test them. One woman told me through her tears how her husband’s constant criticism finally destroyed not only their marriage but her entire sense of self-worth. He first complained about her cooking and housecleaning, and then about how she used her time, how she talked, looked, and reasoned. Eventually she felt utterly inept and dysfunctional. My heart ached for her, and for him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p11" pid="s2bHyODYC0SS88DUpwCXEw" hash="xiZFKQ">Contrast her with a young woman who had little self-confidence when she first married. Then her husband found so much to praise in her that she gradually began to believe she was a good person and that her opinions mattered. His belief in her rekindled her innate self-worth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p12" pid="DLiExwsa60yWz5TbHKDelg" hash="tTSjSg">The third wolf is the excessive individualism that has spawned today’s contractual attitudes. A seven-year-old girl came home from school crying, “Mom, don’t I belong to you? Our teacher said today that nobody <span class="emphasis">belongs</span> to anybody—children don’t belong to parents, husbands don’t belong to wives. I am <span class="emphasis">yours,</span> aren’t I, Mom?” Her mother held her close and whispered, “Of course you’re mine—and I’m yours, too.” Surely marriage partners must respect one another’s individual identity, and family members are neither slaves nor inanimate objects. But this teacher’s fear, shared today by many, is that the bonds of kinship and marriage are not valuable ties that bind, but are, instead, sheer bondage. Ours is the age of the waning of belonging.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p13" pid="E1jnvWUw_kGzqAcg2NmGqQ" hash="E5qx_g">The adversary has long cultivated this overemphasis on personal autonomy, and now he feverishly exploits it. Our deepest God-given instinct is to run to the arms of those who need us and sustain us. But he drives us away from each other today with wedges of distrust and suspicion. He exaggerates the need for having space, getting out, and being left alone. Some people believe him—and then they wonder why they feel left alone. And despite admirable exceptions, children in America’s growing number of single-parent families are clearly more at risk than children in two-parent families.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Further, the rates of divorce and births outside marriage are now so high that we may be witnessing “the collapse of marriage.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p14" pid="NlIarcJdeEej1GfDs_CA4w" hash="JwJmTg">Many people even wonder these days what marriage is. Should we prohibit same-sex marriage? Should we make divorce more difficult to obtain? Some say these questions are not society’s business, because marriage is a private contract. But as the modern prophets recently proclaimed, “marriage … is ordained of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> Even secular marriage was historically a three-party covenant among a man, a woman, and the state. Society has a huge interest in the outcome and the offspring of every marriage. So the public nature of marriage distinguishes it from all other relationships. Guests come to weddings because, as Wendell Berry said, sweethearts “say their vows to the community as much as to one another,” giving themselves not only to each other, but also to the common good “as no <span class="emphasis">contract</span> could ever join them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p15" pid="VSWUNuV-1EiaOYvXEAa2nw" hash="0RfbnA">When we observe the covenants we make at the altar of sacrifice, we discover hidden reservoirs of strength. I once said in exasperation to my wife, Marie, “The Lord placed Adam and Eve on the earth as full-grown people. Why couldn’t he have done that with this boy of ours, the one with the freckles and the unruly hair?” She replied, “The Lord gave us that child to make Christians out of us.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p16" pid="VnfsPDZZ60uTPsz3i2xCog" hash="TtcUeg">One night Marie exhausted herself for hours encouraging that child to finish a school assignment to build his own diorama of a Native American village on a cookie sheet. It was a test no hireling would have endured. At first he fought her efforts, but by bedtime, I saw him lay “his” diorama proudly on a counter. He started for his bed, then turned around, raced back across the room, and hugged his mother, grinning with his fourth-grade teeth. Later I asked Marie in complete awe, “How did you do it?” She said, “I just made up my mind that I couldn’t leave him, no matter what.” Then she added, <span class="emphasis">“I didn’t know I had it in me.”</span> She discovered deep, internal wellsprings of compassion because the bonds of her covenants gave her strength to lay down her life for her sheep, even an hour at a time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p17" pid="wYl5Ry5FlUGhOw9Ac-5owA" hash="EJBh_Q">Now I return to Tom and Tracy, who this year discovered wellsprings of their own. Their second baby threatened to come too early to live. They might have made a hireling’s convenient choice and gone on with their lives, letting a miscarriage occur. But because they tried to observe their covenants by sacrifice,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> active, energetic Tracy lay almost motionless at home for five weeks, then in a hospital bed for another five. Tom was with her virtually every hour when he was not working or sleeping. They prayed their child to earth. Then the baby required 11 more weeks in the hospital. But she is here, and she is theirs.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p18" pid="A9j3O2cwy0Se5Qav951fYw" hash="ZbCbMA">One night as Tracy waited patiently upon the Lord in the hospital, she sensed that perhaps her willingness to sacrifice herself for her baby was in some small way like the Good Shepherd’s sacrifice for her. She said, “I had expected that trying to give so much would be really difficult, but somehow this felt more like a privilege.” As many other parents in Zion have done, she and Tom gave their hearts to God by giving them to their child. In the process, they learned that theirs is a covenant marriage, one that binds them to each other and to the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage.p19" pid="xBMWORdoh0qLvHTfzI3N3A" hash="3DG67g">May we restore the concept of marriage as a covenant, even the new and everlasting covenant of marriage.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> And when the wolf comes, may we be as shepherds, not hirelings, willing to lay down our lives, a day at a time, for the sheep of our covenant. Then, like Adam and Eve, we will have joy.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1996/10/covenant-marriage</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1996-general-conference/1996-10-2040-elder-bruce-c-hafen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5111589" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 1996 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Atonement: All for All</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all?lang=eng</link>
      <description>When the Savior’s all and our all come together, we will find not only forgiveness of sin, … “we shall be like him.”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10031248_000_035" doc-version="2" hash="K-sVlw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="3_FnhgyOu0-6PJATPctDbA" hash="_etkRw">The Atonement:</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="U-CCkF51Z0C3VYEcocAzdw" hash="kRg_3A">All for All</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="lC6xRNguSEKfK3xqoLSw-g" hash="PHz0hA">Bruce C. Hafen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="bBmuBo_0ckWAvMjE7QFFeg" hash="Sj19vg">When the Savior’s all and our all come together, we will find not only forgiveness of sin, … “we shall be like him.”</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-5f5.jpg" alt="Elder Bruce C. Hafen" pid="Njd3XyYC1Uqvzb_xhCsTxA" hash="ISh1LQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p1" pid="gte1U65bzky6acEtb2yJDQ" hash="RawX8w">In recent years, we Latter-day Saints have been teaching, singing, and testifying much more about the Savior Jesus Christ. I rejoice that we are rejoicing more.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p2" pid="fUzVPgk7ukWg9SPDuO6crQ" hash="mFW09Q">As we “talk [more] of Christ,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> the gospel’s doctrinal fulness will come out of obscurity. For example, some of our friends can’t see how our Atonement beliefs relate to our beliefs about becoming more like our Heavenly Father. Others <span class="emphasis">mistakenly </span>think our Church is moving toward an understanding of the relationship between grace and works that draws on Protestant teachings. Such misconceptions prompt me to consider today the Restoration’s unique Atonement doctrine.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p3" pid="q6aaVlMXYEKOPOGidNaO2w" hash="W1wl0A">The Lord restored His gospel through Joseph Smith because there had been an apostasy. Since the fifth century, Christianity taught that Adam and Eve’s Fall was a tragic mistake, which led to the belief that humankind has an inherently evil nature. That view is wrong—not only about the Fall and human nature, but about the very purpose of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p4" pid="8cgausDMWUmjatL-TKffww" hash="iUQANg">The Fall was not a disaster. It wasn’t a mistake or an accident. It was a deliberate part of the plan of salvation. We are God’s spirit “offspring,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> sent to earth “innocent”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> of Adam’s transgression. Yet our Father’s plan subjects us to temptation and misery in this fallen world as the price to comprehend authentic joy. Without tasting the bitter, we actually <span class="emphasis">cannot</span> understand the sweet.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> We require mortality’s discipline and refinement as the “next step in [our] development” toward becoming like our Father.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> But growth means growing pains. It also means learning from our mistakes in a continual process made possible by the Savior’s grace, which He extends both during and <span class="emphasis">“after all we can do.”</span><span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p5" pid="a0ZUHXpx8USttEWx8JVdDg" hash="zy-A6Q">Adam and Eve learned constantly from their often harsh experience. They knew how a troubled family feels. Think of Cain and Abel. Yet because of the Atonement, they could <span class="emphasis">learn from their experience without being condemned by it.</span> Christ’s sacrifice didn’t just erase their choices and return them to an Eden of innocence. That would be a story with no plot and no character growth. His plan is <span class="emphasis">developmental—</span>line upon line, step by step, grace for grace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p6" pid="6fAlwf_kX0mO7UbemmZaYw" hash="cR_S5Q">So if you have problems in your life, don’t assume there is something wrong with you. Struggling with those problems is at the very core of life’s purpose. As we draw close to God, He will show us our weaknesses and through them make us wiser, stronger.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> If you’re seeing more of your weaknesses, that just might mean you’re moving nearer to God, not farther away.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p7" pid="WqmOHhM7bE2KJeCo85spDg" hash="9zhCBg">One early Australian convert said: “My past life [was] a wilderness of weeds, with hardly a flower Strewed among them. [But] now the weeds have vanished, and flowers Spring up in their place.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p8" pid="3lOEyFM58EecD-i-UoHEmA" hash="B-WJhQ">We grow in two ways—removing negative weeds and cultivating positive flowers. The Savior’s grace blesses both parts—if we do our part. First and repeatedly we must uproot the weeds of sin and bad choices. It isn’t enough just to <span class="emphasis">mow</span> the weeds. Yank them out by the roots, repenting fully to satisfy the conditions of mercy. But being forgiven is only part of our growth. We are not just paying a debt. Our purpose is to become celestial beings. So once we’ve cleared our heartland, we must continually plant, weed, and nourish the seeds of divine qualities. And then as our sweat and discipline stretch us to meet His gifts, “the flow’rs of grace appear,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> like hope and meekness. Even a tree of life can take root in this heart-garden, bearing fruit so sweet that it lightens all our burdens “through the joy of his Son.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> And when the flower of charity blooms here, we will love others with the power of Christ’s own love.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p9" pid="LT41WqYK3EG-I6y3n3DjJA" hash="CoTCrg">We need grace both to overcome sinful weeds and to grow divine flowers. We can do neither one fully by ourselves. But grace is not cheap. It is very expensive, even very <span class="emphasis">dear.</span> How much does this grace cost? Is it enough simply to believe in Christ? The man who found the pearl of great price gave “all that he had”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> for it. If we desire “all that [the] Father hath,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> God asks <span class="emphasis">all that we have.</span> To qualify for such exquisite treasure, in whatever way is ours, we must give the way Christ gave—every drop He had: “How exquisite you know not, yea, how hard to bear you know not.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> Paul said, <span class="emphasis">“If so be that we suffer with him,” </span>we are “joint-heirs with Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> All of His heart, all of our hearts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p10" pid="iigSjgo_BE2xTEANbwFYjg" hash="FCGMNg">What possible pearl could be worth such a price—for Him and for us? This earth is not our home. We are away at school, trying to master the lessons of “the great plan of happiness”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> so we can return home and <span class="emphasis">know what it means to be there.</span> Over and over the Lord tells us why the plan is worth our sacrifice—and His. Eve called it “the joy of our redemption.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> Jacob called it “that happiness which is prepared for the saints.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> Of necessity, the plan is full of thorns and tears—His and ours. But because He and we are so totally in this together, our being “at one” with Him in overcoming all opposition will itself bring us “incomprehensible joy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p11" pid="xsEm9MYrdEKDLWI_UKFtSA" hash="Iv04wA">Christ’s Atonement is at the very core of this plan. Without His dear, dear sacrifice, there would be no way home, no way to be together, no way to be like Him. He gave us all <span class="emphasis">He </span>had. Therefore, “how great is <span class="emphasis">his </span>joy,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> when even one of us “gets it”—when we look up from the weed patch and turn our face to the Son.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p12" pid="oPINTtWwREy--rMWHpaM8A" hash="Ky4bBg">Only the restored gospel has the fulness of these truths! Yet the adversary is engaged in one of history’s greatest cover-ups, trying to persuade people that this Church knows least—when in fact it knows most—about how our relationship with Christ makes true Christians of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p13" pid="Fx4n0eOszkawf-2HELJeFw" hash="HxDgUg">If we must give all that we have, then our giving only <span class="emphasis">almost</span> everything is not enough. If we <span class="emphasis">almost </span>keep the commandments, we <span class="emphasis">almost</span> receive the blessings. For example, some young people assume they can romp in sinful mud until taking a shower of repentance just before being interviewed for a mission or the temple. In the very act of transgression, some plan to repent. They mock the gift of mercy that true repentance allows.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p14" pid="4TKr7ri7U0O5Jaaj870LrQ" hash="78WTjQ">Some people want to keep one hand on the wall of the temple while touching the world’s “unclean things”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> with the other hand. We must put both hands on the temple and hold on for dear life. One hand is not even <span class="emphasis">almost</span> enough.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p15" pid="9BGDyDZlX02Uxnke0EdOyQ" hash="doK6ZA">The rich young man had given almost everything. When the Savior told him he must sell <span class="emphasis">all</span> his possessions, that wasn’t just a story about riches.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> We can have eternal life if we want it, but only if there is <span class="emphasis">nothing else </span>we want more.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p16" pid="r_i9P8p800K6jFZSYCBnHA" hash="0LlqpQ">So we must willingly give everything, because God Himself can’t make us grow against our will and without our full participation. Yet even when we utterly spend ourselves, we lack the power to create the perfection only God can complete. Our <span class="emphasis">all</span> by itself is still only <span class="emphasis">almost</span> enough—until it is finished by the <span class="emphasis">all</span> of Him who is the “finisher of our faith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> At that point, our imperfect but consecrated <span class="emphasis">almost</span> is enough.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p17" pid="_4-sw9mTzkepSk5matStLQ" hash="I8LZNw">My friend Donna grew up desiring to marry and raise a large family. But that blessing never came. Instead, she spent her adult years serving the people in her ward with unmeasured compassion and counseling disturbed children in a large school district. She had crippling arthritis and many long, blue days. Yet she always lifted and was always lifted by her friends and family. Once when teaching about Lehi’s dream, she said with gentle humor, “I’d put myself in that picture on the strait and narrow path, still holding to the iron rod but collapsed from fatigue right on the path.” In an inspired blessing given just before her death, Donna’s home teacher said the Lord “accepted” her. Donna cried. She had never felt her single life was acceptable. But the Lord said those who “observe their covenants<span class="emphasis"> by sacrifice</span> … are accepted of me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> I can envision Him walking the path from the tree of life to lift Donna up with gladness and carry her home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p18" pid="ul5t_2ibqEGVdeiFw6UQhw" hash="3dgZeg">Consider others who, like Donna, have consecrated themselves so fully that, for them, <span class="emphasis">almost</span> is enough:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p19" pid="Dn1KXxUQSU--YeejP1mawA" hash="AJZwxQ">Many missionaries in Europe and similar places who never stop offering their bruised hearts despite continual rejection.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p20" pid="wp_uuN_ki0GnOOxVtzKmJA" hash="FJQ6FQ">Those handcart pioneers who said they came to know God in their extremities and the price they paid to know Him was a privilege to pay.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p21" pid="ihUEpOUyiE2yH-yV-j7MmQ" hash="c8Y06w">A father who reached his outermost limits but still couldn’t influence his daughter’s choices; he could only crawl toward the Lord, pleading like Alma for his child.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p22" pid="UyK_0z17MEmtSm0-h00Vhw" hash="XwxWkg">A wife who encouraged her husband despite his years of weakness, until the seeds of repentance finally sprouted in his heart. She said, “I tried to look at him the way Christ would look at me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p23" pid="Ux2aR1I_IkS9HPkHcqrZzQ" hash="I1Ybqg">A husband whose wife suffered for years from a disabling emotional disorder; but to him it was always “our little challenge”—never just “her illness.” In the realm of their marriage, he was afflicted in her afflictions,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span> just as Christ in His infinite realm was afflicted in our afflictions.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26">26</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p24" pid="pxfP_LGdeUCSECyG2qfwlQ" hash="lt010A">The people in 3 Nephi 17 [<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.title" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17</a>] had survived destruction, doubt, and darkness just to get to the temple with Jesus. After listening to Him for hours in wonder, they grew too weary to comprehend Him. As He prepared to leave, they tearfully looked at Him with such total desire that He stayed and blessed their afflicted ones and their children. They didn’t even understand Him, but they wanted to be <span class="emphasis">with Him</span> more than they wanted any other thing. So He stayed. Their <span class="emphasis">almost</span> was enough.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p25" pid="qpCaGkdVr0armeq9hHr_YQ" hash="q7E8Fw">
        <span class="emphasis">Almost</span> is especially enough when our own sacrifices somehow echo the Savior’s sacrifice, however imperfect we are. We cannot really feel charity—Christ’s love for others—without at least tasting His suffering for others, because the love and the suffering are but two sides of a single reality. When we really are afflicted in the afflictions of other people, we may enter “the fellowship of his sufferings”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_27">27</span> enough to become joint-heirs with Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all.p26" pid="Y1Wr6cPHv06rrsDrcA9m6g" hash="FwhEAg">May we not shrink when we discover, paradoxically, how dear a price we must pay to receive what is, finally, a gift from Him. When the Savior’s all and our all come together, we will find not only forgiveness of sin, “we shall see him as he is,” and “we shall be<span class="emphasis"> like him.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_28">28</span> I love Him. I want to be with Him. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2004/04/the-atonement-all-for-all</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2004-general-conference/2004-04-5050-elder-bruce-c-hafen-64k-eng.mp3" length="6162768" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2004 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
