<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Carlos H. Amado</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Carlos H. Amado.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Carlos%20H.%20Amado.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Carlos H. Amado.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1989 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1989 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Adversity</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The day I arrived in Mexico City as a General Authority with my family, I received a telephone call from a former missionary companion who wanted to talk to me that night. His oldest son, who was just starting his first semester of college, had died </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03245_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="dmCnQg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="LsGbTFTWGkCEeWuR6kcUzw" hash="X2EtRQ">Overcoming Adversity</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="a6SAgSa4ykqvpoPhK-Qz0g" hash="1l1XZQ">Carlos H. Amado</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-20aa.jpg" alt="Elder Carlos H. Amado" pid="788f76VFEE69ZtW_1JQUDA" hash="YnvBXA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.p1" pid="Of4gWtC1mE-YWjkm79QKrg" hash="dmvXyQ">The day I arrived in Mexico City as a General Authority with my family, I received a telephone call from a former missionary companion who wanted to talk to me that night. His oldest son, who was just starting his first semester of college, had died in a tragic accident. He was only seventeen years old and full of enthusiasm for life. He was faithful in the Church, and a seminary graduate. Just two weeks before, he had talked to his parents about desires and goals in life. Now he was gone. They understand the plan of salvation well and are sealed for eternity, but the physical separation affects them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.p2" pid="3T07ghDvgEurozo6d4uPmA" hash="vz676g">Those who have gone through this kind of trial recognize that there are tragedies that are so difficult we cannot understand them. We do not have an answer in this life for every adversity. When trials come, it is time to turn our souls to God, who is the author of life and the only source of comfort. “Peace I leave with you, my peace I give unto you: not as the world giveth, give I unto you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.27" class="scriptureRef">John 14:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.p3" pid="m3eQkjOXdkqPONDTKb5ASg" hash="RZA7Zw">Some months ago I heard that the wife of a friend was again threatening miscarriage. I hurried, along with others who were concerned about the baby, to make sure that things would be well. While arrangements were still being made, we were told that it was too late. This was the third time she had gone through this painful experience. I asked myself: What can I say to comfort them? How will the Lord help them overcome this new blow?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.p4" pid="4TZt90DCb0iUkrcwCAcCZg" hash="jF5qyw">The day she left the hospital she heard about another sister from her stake who was going through the same experience. Full of trust in the Lord, she went to visit the sister and give her support. She changed her own tragedy into a blessing of comfort for others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.p5" pid="0EgABiCHoEGSQM-b_suY3A" hash="pS1I0Q">Thinking about her attitude, I remembered a lesson I learned many years ago when my father died. He died suddenly, leaving my mother a widow with fifteen children, ten of whom were dependent on her. This was a great tragedy in her life. Of course, the gospel, the fellowship of the Church, and our own testimonies gave us a solid base which comforted us and helped us to accept this loss with dignity. In spite of the fact that we never left her alone, it affected her deeply. Although she accepted the will of God, her soul did not find inner peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.p6" pid="EMHUf8mzgU-fml_59XeXoA" hash="tYdMuQ">One morning as we were traveling downtown on a bus, she began to feel her loneliness. I noticed it, but also knew that I couldn’t give her the comfort she needed. She cried in silence, but with dignity. A lady passenger came up and said: “You seem to be very sad.” My mother answered, “I have just lost my husband.” Then the lady asked, “Do you have children?” and my mother answered, “I have fifteen children, and each one of them has some trait that reminds me of their father. So I am constantly reminded of him.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.p7" pid="UemsdkN6x0KALqpr7PlWmw" hash="D70YIA">When she heard this, the woman said: “You are truly blessed, because you only lost your husband. I lost my husband, too, and my two daughters in an automobile accident, and I am living alone. So I do understand your pain and sorrow.” Then she added, “Only God can help us overcome trials like this.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.p8" pid="IBwhaiPftUS3QhyiAbwPHg" hash="6G2uew">Those who suffer great adversity and sorrow and go on to serve their fellowmen develop a great capacity to understand others. Like the prophets, they have acquired a higher understanding of the mind and will of Christ. To me, this woman was like an angel. She gave comfort and raised my mother’s thoughts toward God in a time of great trial. From that day on, each time my mother felt lonely or abandoned, she would say to me: “Son, pity the woman who lost all. I am grateful that the Lord has blessed me with fifteen children to be my companions in life.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.p9" pid="FbJk0jYUgEmfEeCuPFZW-A" hash="j2Ma6Q">This personal experience has helped me understand the importance of what God revealed to Joseph Smith in the Doctrine and Covenants:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.p10" pid="JNAgfQuth0OLiNi96qS-ww" hash="UYmTrQ">“Which suffering caused myself, even God, the greatest of all, to tremble because of pain, and to bleed at every pore, and to suffer both body and spirit—and would that I might not drink the bitter cup, and shrink—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.p11" pid="ZPMEgu3ikkCeQk3bRZY0tA" hash="1m1hWQ">“Nevertheless, glory be to the Father, and I partook and finished my preparations unto the children of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/19.18-19" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 19:18–19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.p12" pid="ui_xPyTbg0OjXe6opKEtFg" hash="A14kNQ">Christ has suffered more than any of us, and He knows the intensity of our afflictions. There is no suffering we have that He did not undergo in Gethsemane and on Calvary. That is why He understands and can help us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.p13" pid="U8vNrDr7zUKvQidM9ick1Q" hash="JyF4_A">Christ stated: “I am the resurrection, and the life: he that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/11.25" class="scriptureRef">John 11:25</a>.) The greatest tragedy that can happen to a person is not the loss of his possessions, or his intellect, or his mortal life, but rather to lose eternal life, which is the free gift of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.p14" pid="Sgyj1NkPxUag5ehlv1j_Dw" hash="RSYlOw">The scriptures are a witness of the various prophets—ordinary people, with extraordinary callings—who faced great tribulation and opposition. Father Lehi was commanded to abandon his gold, his silver, and his country. The sons of Mosiah had to renounce the throne. Job lost his lands, his cattle, and even his children, while Abinadi, Stephen, and Christ’s Apostles were killed in His service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.p15" pid="qkryfljF3kS_jjVJr2a-0A" hash="-ZHHzQ">For some, the true trial of our faith is to remain faithful, without murmuring against the Lord, when we lose earthly position, family members, or even when we are required to give our very lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.p16" pid="Shp4-qAuME6ba7Gii4uYaA" hash="q86cWQ">There is evidence in the scriptures that these great men trusted fully in the Savior, even without a full understanding of His purposes. The Prophet Joseph Smith learned, as he established the kingdom of God in this last dispensation, that the more he struggled to bless the lives of others, the greater was his opposition. He went to the Lord seeking justice. Christ did understand Joseph and suggested to him that he might have to suffer more. The Lord told him: “The Son of Man hath descended below them all. Art thou greater than he?” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/122.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 122:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.p17" pid="IdVxhDAiFEqtnIApbVn-Jg" hash="8p9JUA">Later, Joseph, with more understanding of the will and purposes of his Savior, accepted his glorious destiny by offering his life. It is not important to know the trials we may be required to go through in this mortal life. What is essential is our attitude in facing these trials and the lessons and experiences that we learn from them. These will help to refine our understanding and increase our spirituality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity.p18" pid="CG3yJ0lOE0q5vSzKDfgtsA" hash="Do0cfQ">Basically, we limit our vision to the events that happen in this life with the greatest emphasis placed on the present. Only when we fix our gaze on the heavenly things do we begin to understand the eternities. Only with the help of Christ can we fully overcome tragedy. It is necessary to develop our faith in Him as the Redeemer of the world. He taught us: “In the world ye shall have tribulation: but be of good cheer; I have overcome the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/16.33" class="scriptureRef">John 16:33</a>.) It is my prayer that when we have afflictions we will follow the pattern that He taught during His bitter experience in Gethsemane. He said: “If thou be willing, remove this cup from me: nevertheless not my will, but thine, be done.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/22.42" class="scriptureRef">Luke 22:42</a>.) This I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1989/10/overcoming-adversity</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1989-general-conference/1989-10-2060-elder-carlos-h-amado-64k-eng.mp3" length="4796784" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1989 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Eternal Vision</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision?lang=eng</link>
      <description>
         and  are common words in the restored church. Someone said, “The one who doesn’t live to serve doesn’t serve to live”—wise words which are applied to each priesthood holder. Another word to describe the priesthood is  literally, every man w</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_93911_000_020" doc-version="2" hash="OMA51A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="nUNajR4LmE2XP6D0Uoyp5w" hash="ZKTdRw">An Eternal Vision</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="eMI6oJaJa0q5dWnGEpDzZw" hash="1l1XZQ">Carlos H. Amado</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-20aa.jpg" alt="Elder Carlos H. Amado" pid="H78UsonxNkGITMmk3PU77A" hash="YnvBXA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p1" pid="noBvfNzrIESgjO3hP0sy2A" hash="gBfmzA">
        <span class="emphasis">Servant</span> and <span class="emphasis">service</span> are common words in the restored church. Someone said, “The one who doesn’t live to serve doesn’t serve to live”—wise words which are applied to each priesthood holder. Another word to describe the priesthood is <span class="emphasis">service;</span> literally, every man who receives the priesthood is “called to serve.” The Apostle Peter said about you, “But ye are a chosen generation, a royal priesthood, an holy nation, a peculiar people” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-pet/2.9" class="scriptureRef">1 Pet. 2:9</a>). I will illustrate with one story.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p2" pid="WYXIFP9gqUW80kzvPiR6Pw" hash="qri8Lg">María Coj was a seventeen-year-old member of the Church, the oldest of eight children. She was sick with cysticercosis, a parasitic infection that comes from eating contaminated food, that with time spread to her brain, causing terrible headaches and then blindness. To give her relief from the pain, it was necessary to move her from her home in Sololá to Guatemala City. Because of convulsions caused by the advances of the illness, her condition worsened, and it was only with life-support systems that she was kept alive. It was evident that she could not live long under those conditions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p3" pid="GA0evcsQEUaSXDv42tvOEQ" hash="pigbBA">At this same time, Erika Alonzo, a twelve-year-old and partially blind member of the Church, traveled twenty-two hours by bus from Honduras to Guatemala City to receive an eye operation. For two weeks she waited for an acceptable cornea from the United States to be transplanted to her eye, but none was available.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p4" pid="P0Ql8zeChUW83kwN6hJFFg" hash="eeOiNg">At this same time María died. Because her blindness was caused by pressure to her brain, her corneas were healthy. María’s father and mother authorized the cornea donation. The operation was a success.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p5" pid="5yLMACdh3kaqrBWMdjNMJw" hash="IdhgDg">On the twelfth of July 1993, Erika traveled to Sololá to meet the Coj family for the first time. The surprised family asked her, “Can you see?” She answered, “I see everything clearly.” It was a spiritual meeting. Sister Coj, who did not understand much Spanish because her native language is Cakchiquel, felt the love and the spirit of the conversation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p6" pid="N61uEDMT0EiG631R3f4hVQ" hash="G0i-Tg">Because of the donation of María’s eyes, Erika can now see and enjoy everything around her. The death of one person and the love of her parents blessed the life of another. The medical miracle of one person being able to look through eyes of another is a surprising reality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p7" pid="5xyy8CM2CEmwsVTO1LQ8kg" hash="GqH0_w">Spiritually speaking, as you Aaronic Priesthood youth contemplate the blessings of this life and of eternity through the eyes of your faithful parents, teachers, bishops, Apostles, and prophets, you will discover that, through the small donations of daily time to ponder, pray, and study the scriptures, they will teach you of the divine that is in you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p8" pid="O8MdJrcg3EKnVBY1eWwQwQ" hash="t-FHew">Expand your vision and recognize that you have ties with God; lift your sight and live worthy of the priesthood that you hold. Learn in your youth to control your passions, desires, and appetites. Seriously prepare yourselves to fulfill your glorious responsibility to preach the truths of the Restoration, which are that Jesus is the Christ and that salvation comes only through Him, that Joseph Smith was a prophet who was instructed by divine messengers to restore with power and authority all covenants and ordinances that are found in The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p9" pid="MRUqpTWstUqbKegZSvLCDQ" hash="eCDAFA">In each priesthood holder should burn the personal conviction that the mission of Jesus Christ was unique: The Son of the Eternal Heavenly Father and of a mortal mother, especially chosen, He became the Only Begotten Son of God, which qualified Him to be the Mediator, Savior, and Redeemer of mankind. Even though He was slandered, spit upon, slapped, whipped, and humiliated, “yet he opened not his mouth” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/53.7" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 53:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p10" pid="pDGubfaNTUeEzIvJS92j-g" hash="kwu6gA">He died at an early age; He was strong and young, of unlimited wisdom. When you are thirty-three, you will understand better. His sacrifice was painful but indispensable. He was the first to be resurrected, clothed in glory and eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p11" pid="Eo0W8SS_oEWKaW3eByiEbQ" hash="Ig0HYw">The atonement of the Son of God opened the possibility that all mankind could return to the presence of the Father. Now He teaches us, “Follow me, and do the things which ye have seen me do” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.12" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p12" pid="SelqnGhH4UaioEKweIgyWw" hash="9F_Phg">It will be your privilege to serve two years as a missionary with an eye single to glorify God and build His kingdom (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/4.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 4:5</a>). During that time, Christ will refine your spirit. He will mold your character and plant in your heart the principles that will permit you to live in righteousness and joy in this life and for eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p13" pid="fQH3JJKP9EmJTuK-DPmw3g" hash="9qWXBg">You might think that you will sacrifice much to leave your family, your education, and your comfortable life. Others might complain that missionary life is rigorous. The thousands who have served will testify to you that when you count your blessings, sacrifice does not exist.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p14" pid="cz2KxlJniUeonhxPVG3qRQ" hash="s7txRw">I would like to share an experience of faith. Being the only child, Elder Hermelindo Coy said good-bye to his mother and left for the first time in his life his small village in the mountains of Senahú, Guatemala. He entered the Missionary Training Center the fourteenth of March 1991. Although he had been a member of the Church for only two years and also very timid about talking to people, his determination to serve was great. His formal education was less than five years of elementary school in his native language of Kekchi. Spanish, the official language of Guatemala, was foreign to him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p15" pid="cFZPmgPubEuNLZXH6QCbZA" hash="Y8YGYQ">During his mission he learned to live with pain in his leg. He rarely complained. In August 1992 he noticed that in addition to the increase in the pain, something was abnormal about his knee. He had a medical exam—the diagnosis: <span class="emphasis">bone cancer.</span> A more careful exam revealed cancer in the liver, lungs, and lymphatic system; in other words, his illness was terminal. He did not understand the nature of the illness nor its seriousness. With the help of a translator and using examples from the farm life with which he was familiar, he understood that he had little time to live.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p16" pid="AXWPmGlDg0-6UHq4ClE_Ig" hash="HLzbtw">He never asked, Why is this happening to me? He did not lament, nor express negative feelings. He was obedient to all that was required of him. He was asked if he would like to return home, but he asked to remain in the mission and serve as long as possible, even until his death. By October of the same year, he walked with difficulty, requiring the use of a cane. He could work only a few hours each day. By December he was unable to walk. For the first time he was discouraged because he could not proselyte. His worry was always who would take care of his mother after he died.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p17" pid="btShT2T250iN4yA5825_UQ" hash="ZOkVtA">In one of his visits, the mission president asked him to teach more of the basic doctrine to his mother, who, along with mission nurses, was providing twenty-four-hour care. When he taught the plan of salvation to his mother in his native tongue, his face radiated assurance and light. Elder Coy was understanding with power and conviction what he was teaching.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p18" pid="AV3g2UcbxkKMKkygxidSlg" hash="eQoLlA">As his strength declined, he placed his complete trust in the Lord. On one occasion when the pain was very strong, he expressed in prayer, “Heavenly Father, I do not know the day nor the hour that I will die, but I want to know soon from thee about my new assignment.” He died in February 1993. His death blessed all the missionaries, leaders, members, and even nonmembers who learned of his courage to serve and endure to the end. His faith was so simple that it was contagious. He never feared death. He strengthened all who knew him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision.p19" pid="abQNWXWBokStXsF0nH4eBQ" hash="nJtZZw">My beloved youth, I promise you that as you serve with faith as did Elder Coy, and as you look through the eyes of your parents and leaders who love you also, your testimony will be strengthened, your vision will expand, which will illuminate all who are spiritually blind and will help them to return to Christ. Arise and shine; be like the over forty-nine thousand missionaries who today are taking the light, hope, and knowledge to those who need it. I add my own testimony of the divinity of this work in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1993/10/an-eternal-vision</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1993-general-conference/1993-10-3040-elder-carlos-h-amado-64k-eng.mp3" length="5628021" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 1993 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Basic Teachings from the History of Joseph Smith</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Conversion is a personal and spiritual process. Every individual must examine these principles for himself.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029598_000_031" doc-version="2" hash="73_y1Q">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="75pcRX8NjUuD1PxGsjbcww" hash="7Mpsfw">Some Basic Teachings from the History of Joseph Smith</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="UwzwJY2T3E2fAfVWRvx-9Q" hash="1l1XZQ">Carlos H. Amado</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="IbM5VRzQjkirapCeYH_7Ew" hash="15bLjQ">Conversion is a personal and spiritual process. Every individual must examine these principles for himself.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-edb.jpg" alt="Elder Carlos H. Amado" pid="HJ3d4tHcQ06VfoplYhd2cA" hash="iILdCQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p1" pid="YUrIOWneC02vCGiX9HAP-A" hash="Jetk1Q">The history of Joseph Smith was written to share the story of the Restoration of the Church in these latter days. The essence of the story is a demonstration of trust in the promises of the Lord, and a source of joy and certainty for all those who believe.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p2" pid="4sEDkPAv0kOYe7u_z73Wxg" hash="jT3Czw">I have been able to read it many times and in different circumstances. It impressed me as a child; it was a guide and source of strength when I was a teenager; I shared it with courage and enthusiasm as a young missionary; and even now it continues to fill me with astonishment and a deep sense of gratitude. Since Joseph Smith first recorded it, it remains as a blessing and a gift of faith, a legacy, for the sincere believer; it is an open invitation for those who look for the truth, and a permanent challenge to the unbeliever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p3" pid="q4WUcQEGbEycviZzlpL3SA" hash="Lz6snA">For those who are not yet members of the Church, I suggest you read the testimony of Joseph Smith with an open mind and real intent. You will feel his sincerity, and you will discover the establishment of the Church, restored in a miraculous way!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p4" pid="NXFHYTtqrkSrSk0cS-LSiQ" hash="KbyD6A">Although there is ample spiritual content to this fascinating story, I will limit my remarks to sharing five principles which, just as they did for the Prophet, will help you to come to know God.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="ErClGKBdUEm9X020gCAG8g" hash="gdBadg">Principle 1: Have a sincere desire to know the truth.</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p5" pid="zktZPpPKTE68AlwtOrBWXQ" hash="vYGWAg">Joseph Smith had an intense desire to know God and to do His will. You can develop that same desire, and God Himself can lead you to the truth. When you recognize that truth, do all that you can to live your life in accordance with it.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="GzAqdd6z4U6OS2IrC3SjaQ" hash="n35Snw">Principle 2: Learn the importance of reading the scriptures.</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p6" pid="Zf9dZ5c7SU6vd9FmajoYsw" hash="gId6iA">Joseph Smith knew them because he studied them. He said: “I was one day reading the Epistle of James, first chapter and fifth verse, which reads: <span class="emphasis">If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask of God, that giveth to all men liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given him</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.11" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:11</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p7" pid="cQXBnn8r8ECz5cZsHx4X5g" hash="YxXjOw">During his short ministry, Joseph Smith also received many other important revelations which were the result of reading the scriptures. You need to study them in order to come to know God, who is the source of all truth.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="kygGlDEiLUigc64KQrsXvw" hash="bLQvjQ">Principle 3: Learn the value of prayer.</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p8" pid="whgi78FB9UaK4ftYpG5CcQ" hash="A1A1sQ">The young Joseph said:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p9" pid="2Rh29NE8sk6Xh3TcDlE5_Q" hash="1Ru1PQ">“At length I came to the conclusion that I must either remain in darkness and confusion, or else I must do as James directs, that is, ask of God. …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p10" pid="s5Mx8qtuYEaf7DXVgxX6rg" hash="mKZ43A">“… It was the first time in my life that I had made such an attempt, for amidst all my anxieties I had never as yet made the attempt to pray vocally.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p11" pid="j0PfRc0JXEWnLc_qBp9IXA" hash="3PPg7g">“… I kneeled down and began to offer up the desires of my heart to God. …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p12" pid="XIRTfi3Yd0CksYxaLeCuPA" hash="MclCrA">“… I had found the testimony of James to be true—that a man who lacked wisdom might ask of God, and obtain, and not be upbraided” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.13-15,26" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:13–15, 26</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p13" pid="eewiVN0kRkyK-ebIoF1Z0Q" hash="DuQV-g">Our Heavenly Father, as a perfect father, knows all your spiritual and material needs and wants to bless you, which is why He has given you the commandment to seek Him and ask Him.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p14" pid="0I5DqcErOEOXp3jTcbvhdg" hash="URslOA">Joseph came to know the truth because he prayed. In our time, millions of members of this Church also testify of the reality of the Restoration because, following that counsel, they asked the Lord with faith. You have the same right to receive an answer to your prayers because <span class="emphasis">a testimony is a gift that God gives only to those who ask with real intent. </span>Try it, and the promise will be fulfilled.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="0_IouB2z3E2BUomTef1LuA" hash="dfMJxA">Principle 4: Discover the blessing of meditation.</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p15" pid="2ZccASVn_kiE43CVUILtQQ" hash="4BgDtA">Joseph Smith meditated often; he thought, analyzed, compared; he tried to find answers to what he read in the scriptures. He said:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p16" pid="c2GytWYW5UCdrTO4h16Ndg" hash="kSKGow">“During this time of great excitement my mind was called up to serious reflection and great uneasiness. …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p17" pid="PPXbo16CKUePI3S-rPzOKA" hash="kyFtHA">“… I often said to myself: … Who of all these parties are right; or, are they all wrong together? If any one of them be right, which is it, and how shall I know it? …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p18" pid="uWk8rFFGUU-d9WUaUZvqNQ" hash="VxP2SQ">“Never did any passage of scripture come with more power to the heart of man than this did at this time to mine. It seemed to enter with great force into every feeling of my heart. I reflected on it again and again” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.8,10,12" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:8, 10, 12</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p19" pid="s7u4y809yUaB0vlzVG3I9A" hash="YaQ5rA">To meditate about eternal truths is to think and to ask ourselves, over and over: “How can I know?” “How have others come to know?”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p20" pid="xpdfiyUXkEy6_3P0kEDL_w" hash="S5Y3pg">How can you come to a knowledge of these things? Please meditate about it seriously.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.t6">
        <h3 class="title" pid="jzy4nNGqckaztFQp8rOXFQ" hash="za6Bvw">Principle 5: Experience the joy of going to church.</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p21" pid="Ei7gm3vmUU2Wyou3r3hreA" hash="wx3xug">In his desire to know the truth, Joseph Smith went to various denominations in his community. About his experience with God the Father and His Son Jesus Christ, he described clearly the instructions he received about other churches:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p22" pid="E3sX09HvSk-9k6c2q_D7tA" hash="W_mLxg">“I asked the Personages who stood above me in the light, which of all the sects was right (for at this time it had never entered into my heart that all were wrong)—and which I should join. …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p23" pid="u4Z_ImTJHkyDcfrrSDjecg" hash="pFZ4tw">“… It was not my duty to join with any of them, but to continue as I was until further directed” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.18,26" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:18, 26</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p24" pid="PAgpRhXKV0yVHB8MneA3ug" hash="MXv-tA">All of us need to come to know the kingdom of God on earth and to receive a testimony of its truth. We go to church to feel the Spirit, learn His doctrine, renew our covenants, and receive the ordinances of salvation and exaltation to return to the presence of God with our families. You are cordially invited to come to church and see for yourself all these things.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p25" pid="L5YJV0VZ-0KeM7gYQweFBg" hash="ET2n4w">Conversion is a personal and spiritual process. Every individual must examine these principles for himself. It is not enough to make a halfhearted attempt, accompanied by doubts, fear, or lack of trust. God promises us, because of His mercy, that He will answer our petitions in accordance with our sincerity. Only those who seek with real intent will receive their answer, as a gift from God, through the Holy Ghost.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p26" pid="d2Ea8Dk-Fk2_tgGocwfb-A" hash="CPSDRw">The Holy Ghost is also called the Comforter and the Witness. To Him we owe our knowledge and our testimony that Christ is the Son of God.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p27" pid="VcS0y-uZ0Ue_pRUrx8Y64A" hash="I3WW6w">After you are baptized, if you remain worthy and faithful to your covenants, you will have the constant guidance of the Holy Ghost, through whisperings, impressions, feelings, dreams, and warnings.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p28" pid="r_Ngm0YFM02zqmujpnKaGg" hash="531yow">History and the scriptures tell us of people who heard, talked with, or in some other way had concrete evidence of the existence of God and His plan for our salvation. Nevertheless, many of them did not remain true to their convictions.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p29" pid="klcSfSnbzkCR7yH8xo5YVw" hash="Yx80GA">We learn from this that it is not what we learn through our physical senses but that which comes under the influence of the Holy Ghost which allows us to understand God’s purposes and to follow Him.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p30" pid="2uq9KoMMSUazfUQeNePmDg" hash="B2nyjQ">When someone has learned these basic principles and ceases to practice them, he loses the light and guide which helps him to understand God and His prophets. The outward sign we see is that they separate themselves, become less active, or even contend against the Church. The inward sign is that they have ceased to practice one or more of these five things:</p>
        <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.f2">
	  <ol class="number">
	    <li pid="eN7YRJCsS0CYdjD8r10atQ" hash="ajahhw">
            <span class="label">1.</span>
            <p pid="sJBq-Ft34U6p2V72NV1EEQ" hash="q8o47Q">They no longer have a sincere desire to know all the truth.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="HD4s7Acrg06ELX2IAlns2A" hash="Ecc5ZA">
            <span class="label">2.</span>
            <p pid="Abq9QAQThU-qgbUxV5KXcA" hash="5SCKag">They no longer read the scriptures.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="82hJjSjAP0O9ZBjHclIyXw" hash="K6g15w">
            <span class="label">3.</span>
            <p pid="XWjV5Jy_HkyCjTbB3vW_LQ" hash="5K36cQ">They no longer pray.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="1S9cXO8vYEK0mqjpd-1cPw" hash="GFcsBw">
            <span class="label">4.</span>
            <p pid="e0NaxPOZWEe9Z0rVf4p8tA" hash="cXJUWA">They no longer meditate about eternal truths.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="w6x_jOCBk0qciPmdYIUiQA" hash="WocFSw">
            <span class="label">5.</span>
            <p pid="BYAheuSWOEeg4cw3IdTJGQ" hash="hDLWSg">They no longer go to church.</p>
          </li>
	  </ol>
	</div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p31" pid="lnvRsXAnskSV7hnc8k_00A" hash="EAb1iA">It is wonderful that in a time of great religious confusion, while not yet 15 years old, in the midst of opposition and even persecution, Joseph Smith patiently and diligently demonstrated obedience and showed us the simple but effective way to draw closer to God.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p32" pid="w221__L47UG0h7eEeLuVpA" hash="L3W4pg">This process requires that we learn, precept upon precept, a little here and a little there, until we develop faith and clear understanding of our divine potential (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/28.30" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 28:30</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p33" pid="FNGz54zOx0yr_NYUOErxsw" hash="Dk-nIg">It is our responsibility to strengthen, day by day, the impressions that we feel through the Spirit, by applying these five principles.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith.p34" pid="XD3F0NgsHkS_4YVFPC00rA" hash="ej0bdA">It is my prayer that we may do this, constantly, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2002/04/some-basic-teachings-from-the-history-of-joseph-smith</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2002-general-conference/2002-04-5030-elder-carlos-h-amado-64k-eng.mp3" length="4537216" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2002 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Service, a Divine Quality</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Those who serve will strive to ennoble, build, and lift their fellowmen.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00009475_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="gzbv1g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="6O3oDZTv5E2N97SuX_sDxQ" hash="-Mot_w">Service, a Divine Quality</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="IJxRfYYqfkSWr_K1N5JZAA" hash="Qu6ipw">Elder Carlos H. Amado</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="2JbIX00c5U6ItA7XE5YgyQ" hash="14ya3A">Those who serve will strive to ennoble, build, and lift their fellowmen.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p1" pid="4VOmgEtCiUKZsMWgXjB3-Q" hash="SxgapA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="35"></span>All the things that Christ did for our salvation are unique. He was able to perform His redeeming work in approximately three years of ministry. Today I would like to highlight three purposes for the Savior’s life on earth.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="YTesziBDoEKy-m1payLIwQ" hash="AjSs4A">1. His Atoning Sacrifice</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p2" pid="avw0G4Jf-0urUj0Ac0u1tg" hash="In56vA">The first and greatest purpose was the unrivaled and amazing assignment that He received from His Father: to carry out an infinite and eternal sacrifice for all humanity.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p3" pid="MGHV-f7lQ0iykZeMROftUg" hash="-1asZQ">As Heavenly Father’s Only Begotten Son in the flesh, He inherited all of His Father’s divine qualities, and from His earthly mother, Mary, He inherited mortal characteristics.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p4" pid="deJwX6vZqU-VRCQUvJeGiA" hash="YY5jwg">Only His sacrifice could rescue us from our mortal and fallen state (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/34.8-14" class="scriptureRef">Alma 34:8–14</a>). He came to the world with the specific purpose to give His life, since only His life could give us eternal life.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p5" pid="T3ktUePrf0WKp8xeSOpfjg" hash="uG-l2w">No other mortal being, in the past, present, or future of the existence of the earth, has lived or will live to carry out the Atonement for our sins. He is our Savior and Redeemer (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.16" class="scriptureRef">John 3:16</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p6" pid="ndY4qUX5x0uMCXy2m23mXQ" hash="vEvLPA">He will return again to govern and rule among us with great power and glory.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="FRAD1vyxokyscgzEkwpNJg" hash="ZoY9ug">2. His Doctrine</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p7" pid="slNrT7Zpk0uRRgjuof58iQ" hash="n7PWRg">The second purpose for His having dwelt among us was to teach the doctrine that He learned from His Father, which includes the ordinances and covenants of salvation and exaltation (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/1.27" class="scriptureRef">Mark 1:27</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/7.16" class="scriptureRef">John 7:16</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p8" pid="N-8ZJflrBEmGxPrQ6cWUQg" hash="t-mUIA">His doctrine is one of love, forgiveness, and mercy. It is the way to live in peace and harmony among men and the way to return to live with God.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="tErEwG2rR0-QSnyv5hczHw" hash="-y1b_w">3. His Service to the Children of God</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p9" pid="nAXdyus-6EuLKl3h2KO2Iw" hash="TuZWvg">His third purpose was to build the kingdom by serving others. This was a different type of leadership. Service is a characteristic of His followers—a divine quality.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p10" pid="aIMlCJPXdEWl_X1PwuQzZg" hash="MyeGbw">“Ye call me Master and Lord: and ye say well; for so I am.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p11" pid="Dxmi9weHE0S-I4FNNd5HEA" hash="w3CV4w">“If I then, your Lord and Master, have washed your feet; ye also ought to wash one another’s feet.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p12" pid="rdHL5Fioa0-aUWc_owPzcw" hash="L1bMqA">“For I have given you an example, that ye should do as I have done to you” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/13.13-15" class="scriptureRef">John 13:13–15</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p13" pid="DAD6mGgwjESBZ4Hk7wiltg" hash="xHmIig">He lived to preach the gospel of the kingdom and to heal all manner of sickness (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/4.23-24" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 4:23–24</a>). To teach His doctrine and to serve our fellowmen are two responsibilities that we accepted when we were baptized. This converts us into true servants of Christ.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p14" pid="SS6eUgpSt0eGczJ_CyEhfg" hash="2NCgpg">On one occasion after teaching His doctrine, He had compassion on the people and performed the miracle of multiplying the loaves of bread and fish and feeding the multitude, revealing to us His character of compassion and service. The next day the multitude was even greater because of the food that they had received. He taught them with determination and with eternal vision:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p15" pid="7ApEV8R1sUylQQlZWJpwUg" hash="TtZ3dA">“Ye seek me, not because ye saw the miracles, but because ye did eat of the loaves, and were filled.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p16" pid="Jldeu5NwF0G5b1NOH-kHpw" hash="MjE2Mg">“Labour not for the meat which perisheth, but for that meat which endureth unto everlasting life, which the Son of man shall give unto you” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/6.26-27" class="scriptureRef">John 6:26–27</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p17" pid="ukUnqLc86EKKDKSZvLMPgA" hash="vVeWLA">As a Church we should feed the hungry, relieve the sick, clothe the naked, and give shelter to the destitute. With fast offerings we alleviate the basic and immediate needs of the members, and with the welfare plan we help meet their long-term needs. When there are natural disasters, through humanitarian service we provide assistance for our brothers and sisters who are not of our faith.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p18" pid="kjbXH7HBK0G5_r0JQ3FLOg" hash="6iAw8A">Without neglecting these temporal needs, The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, by commandment of the Lord, maintains the most sublime and lofty labor of service, which is to bless all men by teaching them <span class="pageBreak" page-number="36"></span>the doctrine of Christ and inviting them to receive the saving ordinances so that they might gain “immortality and eternal life” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>).</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="mC8yZAwf60SwkwQJMhLDtQ" hash="hFdR6w">A Change of Thought and Attitude</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p19" pid="bWlmgJM6QUaOyQqBoQKjyw" hash="DxAJoA">I know that God loves us. He allows us to exercise our moral agency even when we misuse it. He permits us to make our own decisions.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p20" pid="_9j9mPTUm0aXsf774Sqagg" hash="SISTDw">Christ cannot help us if we do not trust Him; He cannot teach us if we do not serve Him. He will not force us to do what’s right, but He will show us the way only when we decide to serve Him. Certainly, for us to serve in His kingdom, Christ requires that we experience a change of thought and attitude.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p21" pid="aAhutJffikGIeksq-z9-Gg" hash="Nd0OGw">“For how knoweth a man the master whom he has not served, and who is a stranger unto him, and is far from the thoughts and intents of his heart?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/5.13" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 5:13</a>).</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.t6">
        <h3 class="title" pid="3uhUcZs8Tky9PivSG0Z1_g" hash="J1xRaw">Blessings of Service</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p22" pid="5CZB_gd790KriPwxc_cbWA" hash="Pr0wZw">I testify that through serving our fellowmen we come to know the Lord.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p23" pid="WznmzBGkeka0t1m4NITrZg" hash="-muEpg">Service makes us strong in our faith and useful in His kingdom. Service gives us purpose and courage in life. It brings us closer to God and helps us refine our divine nature. It teaches us to love and understand our fellowmen, and it helps us forget about our personal desires, eliminating selfishness, pride, and ingratitude. It teaches us to think of the needs of others, which allows us to develop the virtues that the Savior possesses.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p24" pid="zcZ10tEkp0ud6fEpMUKltA" hash="jrbsJA">Kindness, love, patience, understanding, and unity will increase as we serve, while intolerance, jealousy, envy, greed, and selfishness decrease or disappear. The more we give of ourselves, the more our capacity to serve, understand, and love will grow.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p25" pid="KzjQKviXNkOnz6MEMecb-g" hash="cBxT9g">Those who serve will always seek to please God and live in harmony with Him. They will be full of peace; they will have a cheerful countenance and a spirit of kindness.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p26" pid="pt6XFbkwckigG6jAbW28ug" hash="pEHIJA">Those who serve will strive to ennoble, build, and lift their fellowmen; therefore, they will find the good in others, and they will not find reason or have time to become offended. They develop the virtue of praying for those who criticize. They don’t expect recognition or reward. They possess the love of Christ.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p27" pid="klHRHoH660elAnfgrQUGAw" hash="QZQc2A">Those who serve will always be willing to share what they possess and <span class="pageBreak" page-number="37"></span>what they know at all times, in all places, and with all people.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p28" pid="izspVRXo60irba28i8j_NQ" hash="2Uj8-A">Those who serve even in adversity will maintain a living hope of a better future. They will continue to be firm in the midst of a crisis because their hope is in Christ.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p29" pid="F203f8DqDE2qhC3uCRcrGg" hash="kyVfig">Those who serve will accept their assignments with humility, recognizing their limitations but convinced that two people can do all things they propose to do as long as one of the two people is God.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p30" pid="sX4CF_7TCEGXGVZ8vXTDOg" hash="OVGZVw">With divine inspiration, King Benjamin declared, “When ye are in the service of your fellow beings ye are only in the service of your God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.17" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2:17</a>). Those who serve will have greater understanding of the personality and attributes of God.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p31" pid="UrQD9ZUrxUaEf_mSMj0GpQ" hash="ioOgyg">Those who serve with devotion, even when things don’t turn out the way they would like, are not easily discouraged, fatigued, or frustrated because the promise of peace of mind and the companionship of the Holy Spirit will never abandon them.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.t7">
        <h3 class="title" pid="G6ck8ol13kivfBoVUvPyOw" hash="uXYuqw">Worldwide and Local Service</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p32" pid="odtl6-B0e0-IICccTgT-Mw" hash="IgREyA">In the Church there are tens of thousands of members who selflessly serve in more than 170 nations in a great diversity of tongues and languages. They give unselfish service through leadership, teaching, and care of others, without salary or material reward, without applause or worldly recognition. They give of their time, their talents, and their resources; they sacrifice all that they have and serve efficiently and marvelously well. After a certain time they are released to give the opportunity of service to others.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality.p33" pid="dRQjGuQpi0-N0fSk8WRfqA" hash="mk7jQQ">Because of His doctrine and His service, the restored Church of Jesus Christ is constantly blessing the lives of its members. We thank God for all of you faithful Saints who have felt the joy of service, who feel it now, and who will feel this joy as you serve others. We pray that God always will bless you for it. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2008/04/service-a-divine-quality</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2008-general-conference/2008-04-2060-elder-carlos-h-amado-64k-eng.mp3" length="4722304" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2008 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christ the Redeemer</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Carlos H. Amado testifies that all who have lived or will live on earth are blessed by the Atonement of Jesus Christ. </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10985_000_14amado" doc-version="3" hash="HRIYCQ">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="1VtvzQQuFUCW4MAip4d8NQ" hash="hm-aLQ">Christ the Redeemer</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p" pid="FaEfdAo_T0SDVfSafU23jw" hash="vpW-Zg">By Elder Carlos H. Amado</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p" pid="SnBzwzPIAUWEEGzq0O-7Zg" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
		</div>
		<img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/leaders/carlos-h-amado.jpg" altText="Elder Carlos H. Amado" pid="LRjJa1m6nEW3_Z6UfmqBRg" hash="6dZeKQ" />
		<p class="kicker" pid="kjruDP3IWkSDNHE4mhhDIA" hash="mRT0Sw">[The Redeemer’s] sacrifice blessed everyone, from Adam, the first, to the last of all human beings.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="LQ3FdhrxSU-Rcxt-NcRLqw" hash="vpW-Zg1">By Elder Carlos H. Amado</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p5" pid="O02PgrRfFE-KPAPga7spyA" hash="OmdWnQ">
			<span class="pageBreak" page-number="12"></span>Jesus Christ, the Son of God, was born and died in unique circumstances. He lived and grew up in humble conditions, without material things. He said of Himself, “Foxes have holes, and birds of the air have nests; but the Son of man hath not where to lay his head” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/9.58" class="scriptureRef">Luke 9:58</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p6" pid="8IS89vFT0kCY55CeiXF_lw" hash="uT0LUw">He never received honors, favors, recognition, nor preferred treatment from the political leaders of the earth or from the religious leaders of His day. Neither did He sit in the highest seats of the synagogues.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p7" pid="s4wQGeoW8kKBjMn8cW9ciQ" hash="TYetgg">His preaching was simple, and even though multitudes followed after Him, His ministry always consisted of blessing people one by one. He performed innumerable miracles among those who accepted Him as the One sent from God.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p8" pid="99ppqLFNrEqh8Il_xx48bA" hash="8pRGmw">He gave His Apostles authority and power to do miracles “and greater works” than those He performed (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.12" class="scriptureRef">John 14:12</a>), but He never delegated to them the privilege of forgiving sins. His enemies became indignant when they heard Him say, “Go, and sin no more” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.11" class="scriptureRef">John 8:11</a>) or “Thy sins are forgiven [thee]” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/7.48" class="scriptureRef">Luke 7:48</a>). That right belonged only to Him because He is the Son of God and because He would pay for those sins with His Atonement.</p>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.t1">
			<h2 class="title" pid="O8R7F6L750CPGDIXAIQsqA" hash="bjLbFQ">His Power over Death</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p10" pid="QqxF7au0N0iiNabeONmhpA" hash="4fFdoQ">His power over death was another divine attribute. Great Jairus, a ruler of the synagogue, pleaded “that he would come into his house: for he had one only daughter, … and she lay a dying” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/8.41-42" class="scriptureRef">Luke 8:41–42</a>). The Master heard his plea, and while they were walking, a servant came to Jairus and told him, “Thy daughter is dead; trouble not the Master” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/8.49" class="scriptureRef">Luke 8:49</a>). After entering the house, Jesus asked for everyone to go out, and straightway, taking her by the hand, He said to her, “Arise” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/8.54" class="scriptureRef">Luke 8:54</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p11" pid="BkF5IzAww0qZgjDRHGsCyg" hash="e9vcoA">On another occasion, while He was traveling to the city of Nain, He came upon a funeral procession, a widow weeping for the death of her only son. Full of mercy, He touched the bier and said, “Young man, I say unto thee, Arise” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/7.14" class="scriptureRef">Luke 7:14</a>). The people, upon seeing the miracle, exclaimed, “A great prophet is risen up among us; and … God hath visited his people” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/7.16" class="scriptureRef">Luke 7:16</a>). This miracle was even more noteworthy because they had already declared the young man legally dead and were on the way to bury him. With two young people brought back to life, the evidence of His authority and power over death astonished the believers and filled the defamers with fear.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p12" pid="cQvw2ldyUUSLGSZ8GXuGvw" hash="eRd2dw">The third occasion was the most impressive. Martha, Mary, and Lazarus were siblings whom Christ would often visit. When people informed Him that Lazarus was sick, He remained two days before leaving to come to the family. In consoling Martha after her brother’s death, He categorically testified to her, “I am the resurrection, and the life: he that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/11.25" class="scriptureRef">John 11:25</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p13" pid="e3nHNLM1zUumPI0JtEgUUg" hash="yt4_fg">When the Savior asked for the mourners to remove the stone from the sepulchre, Martha timidly whispered to Him, “Lord, by this time he stinketh: for he hath been dead four days” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/11.39" class="scriptureRef">John 11:39</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p14" pid="1WO5QmSNCUOubrHMGwDbKA" hash="Dt5SGg">Then Jesus lovingly reminded her, “Said I not unto thee, that, if thou wouldest believe, thou shouldest see the glory of God?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/11.40" class="scriptureRef">John 11:40</a>). And having said this, He cried out with a loud voice:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p15" pid="J50o1EKauUekwdKi2T_dfw" hash="kJeOUQ">“Lazarus, come forth.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p16" pid="7pttubBd40W0oHs85cagYQ" hash="6fb02A">“And he that was dead came forth” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/11.43-44" class="scriptureRef">John 11:43–44</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p17" pid="-_5rXZDEaESMlBODMg4ORQ" hash="j_HJ8Q">After Lazarus’s four days in the grave, the enemies of the Son of God were faced with irrefutable evidence they could not ignore, diminish, or distort, and they senselessly and maliciously “from that day forth … took counsel together for to put him to death” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/11.53" class="scriptureRef">John 11:53</a>).</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.t2">
			<h2 class="title" pid="9iVGxGI4dk63AuI7xSJQMg" hash="fluCZQ">The New Commandment</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p19" pid="_YzMojWZjEWspkSKCF-WuA" hash="QUnAnA">Later on, the living Christ celebrated in Jerusalem, along with His Apostles, His last Feast of the Passover, established the ordinance of the sacrament, and gave them the commandment to love one another through sincere service.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.t3">
			<h2 class="title" pid="WYQ1J6qa80esF2FYbHEf3Q" hash="si0JNw">His Agony in Gethsemane</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p21" pid="8i2ApH3JrEe8xHFFYewF8g" hash="wxFwNA">After that, in the most sublime show of His love for humankind, and <span class="pageBreak" page-number="13"></span>in the full exercise of His will, He walked bravely and determinedly to face His most demanding trial. In the Garden of Gethsemane, in utter loneliness, He suffered the most intense agony, bleeding from each pore. In total submission before His Father, He atoned for our sins and also took upon Him our illnesses and afflictions in order to know how to succor us (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/7.11-13" class="scriptureRef">Alma 7:11–13</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p22" pid="aRwK55fwtEWLNfYdS-J_PA" hash="c2Qlvw">We are indebted to Him and to our Heavenly Father because His sacrifice blessed everyone, from Adam, the first, to the last of all human beings.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.t4">
			<h2 class="title" pid="7rwI0cMB9kmEEuxSyHYJrg" hash="QIs6Fw">Condemnation and Crucifixion of the Savior</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p24" pid="3bB5EQ4eEkKpbnTw8ngVBA" hash="lf5--w">Once His agony in Gethsemane was concluded, He voluntarily gave Himself up to His detractors. Betrayed by one of His own, He was hurriedly condemned, in a manner both unjust and illegal, in a trial both manipulated and incomplete. That same night He was accused of the crime of blasphemy and condemned to death. In their hatred and thirst for vengeance—because He testified to them that He was the Son of God—His enemies plotted for Pilate to condemn Him. To that end, they changed the accusation of blasphemy to sedition so that His death would be by crucifixion.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p25" pid="f1-NgqavwEmt28tP-3DvxQ" hash="m0fMLQ">His condemnation among the Romans was even more cruel: their mockings and scorn regarding His spiritual kingdom, the humiliating coronation with a crown of thorns, His painful scourging, and the prolonged agony of His public Crucifixion were all a clear warning for every person who might dare to declare himself or herself His disciple.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p26" pid="60yECvcYPEKqEI05l7-u9Q" hash="GoFy2w">At each moment of His suffering, the Redeemer of the world showed exceptional self-control. He always thought of blessing others; with <span class="pageBreak" page-number="14"></span>kindness and tenderness, He pleaded for John to take care of His mother, Mary. He asked His Father in Heaven to forgive the executioners who crucified Him. With His work on earth fulfilled, He commended His spirit to God and breathed His last breath. The physical body of Christ was taken to the tomb and remained there three days.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.t5">
			<h2 class="title" pid="ZV-Tp7JXlEC9X_iqHcUnCA" hash="-WhokA">The Work of the Redeemer among the Dead</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p28" pid="MRT9lyIlbkiLfNmpbIPMlQ" hash="F8wYKw">While His disciples were suffering from sadness, discouragement, and uncertainty, our Savior, in another phase of His Father’s glorious plan, extended His ministry in a new way. In the short period of three days, He worked untiringly to organize the immense work of salvation among the dead. Those days became some of the most hope-filled of all for the family of God. During that visit He organized His faithful followers so that they would bear glad tidings of redemption to those who did not in life come to know of the glorious plan or who had rejected it. Now they would have the opportunity to be freed from their captivity and to be redeemed by the God of both the living and the dead (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/138.19,30-31" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 138:19, 30–31</a>).</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.t6">
			<h2 class="title" pid="nQpBJuJwU0mSiwnBFGK6Pg" hash="tgy0Uw">The Firstfruits of the Resurrection</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p30" pid="NejrkMphJEOAB4RT2LNtUA" hash="exu2tA">With His work completed in the spirit world, He returned to earth—forever to unite His spirit with His physical body. Even though He had authoritatively shown His power over death, the scriptural accounts of those He brought back to life before His Resurrection demonstrate that they were only coming back to a life that had been miraculously prolonged; they would yet die.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p31" pid="p7_dueWn7UW5liI1zCYauA" hash="wmfZxg">Christ was the first to be resurrected and never die again, to possess forever a perfect, eternal body. In His resurrected state, He appeared to Mary, who as soon as she recognized Him, began to worship Him. Our Redeemer, with great tenderness, warned her concerning His new and glorious condition: “Touch me not; for I am not yet ascended to my Father” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/20.17" class="scriptureRef">John 20:17</a>)—providing an additional witness that His ministry in the spirit world was real and complete. Then, using language that confirmed the reality of His Resurrection, He said, “I ascend unto my Father, and your Father; and to my God, and your God” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/20.17" class="scriptureRef">John 20:17</a>). After going to His Father, He returned again and appeared to His Apostles. “He shewed unto them his hands and his side. Then were the disciples glad, when they saw the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/20.20" class="scriptureRef">John 20:20</a>).</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.t7">
			<h2 class="title" pid="s0rXVcSca0WJYJWGiNK_6A" hash="DTvE2A">The Redeemer Will Return</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer.p33" pid="UvQuEilf4UKjoW6CEfTd3w" hash="JYugMw">I testify that Christ will return in a way very different from His first coming. He will come in power and glory with all the just and faithful Saints. He will come as King of kings and Lord of lords, as the Prince of Peace, the promised Messiah, the Savior and Redeemer, to judge the living and the dead. I love and serve Him with all my heart, and I plead that we may serve with joy and dedication and that we may remain faithful to Him until the end. In His name, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/04/christ-the-redeemer</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2014-general-conference/2014-04-1040-elder-carlos-h-amado-64k-eng.mp3" length="5069288" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2014 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
