<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Carl B. Cook</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Carl B. Cook.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Carl%20B.%20Cook.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Carl B. Cook.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>It Is Better to Look Up</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up?lang=eng</link>
      <description>If we, like President Monson, exercise our faith and look to God for help, we will not be overwhelmed with the burdens of life.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50029123_000_2050" doc-version="2" hash="y8PCcw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="4BeCoBJBsk2j_rT7bmhNYw" hash="ZjoKaQ">It Is Better to Look Up</h1><p class="authorName" guid="8d4f1588-d112-4b41-ab38-ef32a3cca25f" pid="MUcuwVDUbE-Btws6HokDnw" hash="04BLOQ">Carl B. Cook</p><p class="kicker" pid="dZVbhbaSRUeBVZx_g-Im5w" hash="Au2NFA">If we, like President Monson, exercise our faith and look to God for help, we will not be overwhelmed with the burdens of life.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="d2bc2c5a-1126-4027-8e7c-5b2bf9fa64b7">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p1" guid="f2aefc4b-0443-4e9f-8e9a-8565d7633e2b" pid="m3IAu6U7ZUeSi_WAgAyzSg" hash="A1BNWQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="33"></span>At the end of a particularly tiring day toward the end of my first week as a General Authority, my briefcase was overloaded and my mind was preoccupied with the question “How can I possibly do this?” I left the office of the Seventy and entered the elevator of the Church Administration Building. As the elevator descended, my head was down and I stared blankly at the floor.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p2" guid="e0f720e4-30e3-4fa9-be91-643c5f66fcb3" pid="VjsQ5a2aLE2Pmlyc8WLqmQ" hash="LH-B_g">The door opened and someone entered, but I didn’t look up. As the door closed, I heard someone ask, “What are you looking at down there?” I recognized that voice—it was President Thomas S. Monson.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p3" guid="66f13613-cf2a-4cd9-882e-6ad5f311b437" pid="LVa4FlVYF0S7g0niUZt0kQ" hash="DDgD7A">I quickly looked up and responded, “Oh, nothing.” (I’m sure that clever response inspired confidence in my abilities!)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p4" guid="3b8e4334-db4b-4b39-80f0-4503398f0f55" pid="WUIAVxx3F0yZo-ZslcBzYg" hash="Ye2brw">But he had seen my subdued countenance and my heavy briefcase. He smiled and lovingly suggested, while pointing heavenward, “It is better to look up!” As we traveled down one more level, he cheerfully explained that he was on his way to the temple. When he bid me farewell, his parting glance spoke again to my heart, “Now, remember, it is better to look up.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p5" guid="5c5ea976-ac90-494a-b3b1-52223b3ea6d6" pid="bfJJj-w390-eAUR2KfJEMg" hash="F_l9fA">As we parted, the words of a scripture came to mind: “Believe in God; believe that he is … ; believe that he has all wisdom, and all power, both in heaven and in earth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> As I thought of Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ’s power, my heart found the comfort I had sought in vain from the floor of that descending elevator.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p6" guid="a95dcd65-2d84-4bc2-b361-723910334d89" pid="aSzoHa9feUCqxxyRnu8DhQ" hash="clg9XA">Since then I have pondered this experience and the role of prophets. I was burdened and my head was down. As the prophet spoke, I looked to him. He redirected my focus to look up to God, where I could be healed and strengthened through Christ’s Atonement. That is what prophets do for us. They lead us to God.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p7" guid="59ab4881-d07d-4205-92eb-3f1342024eb4" pid="yb2gP91sxk2ldLBaAXhPJw" hash="JZLIwQ">I testify that President Monson is not only a prophet, seer, and revelator; he is also a wonderful example of living the principle of looking up. Of all people, he could feel weighed down by his responsibilities. Instead, he exercises great faith and is filled with optimism, wisdom, and love for others. His attitude is one of “can do” and “will do.” He trusts the Lord and relies on Him for strength, and the Lord blesses him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p8" guid="8c3cd6f3-9f61-4c3e-b591-91e5e29c03c7" pid="LJup0Vp95EiMHvY_4Qc5wA" hash="k8eoQQ">Experience has taught me that if we, like President Monson, exercise our faith and look to God for help, we will not be overwhelmed with the burdens of life. We will not feel incapable <span class="pageBreak" page-number="34"></span>of doing what we are called to do or need to do. We will be strengthened, and our lives will be filled with peace and joy.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> We will come to realize that most of what we worry about is not of eternal significance—and if it is, the Lord will help us. But we must have the faith to look up and the courage to follow His direction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p9" guid="a77b951d-cbfe-4f61-80b4-e806033fb0c9" pid="pbS9DV0gOEaEHS24ABByIw" hash="7he9NA">Why is it a challenge to consistently look up in our lives? Perhaps we lack the faith that such a simple act can solve our problems. For example, when the children of Israel were bitten by poisonous serpents, Moses was commanded to raise up a brass serpent on a pole. The brass serpent represented Christ. Those who looked up at the serpent, as admonished by the prophet, were healed.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> But many others failed to look up, and they perished.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p10" guid="3abdd776-a9e2-4c8f-b5d9-bd2c1dc1b725" pid="-WJuK7xRlkCEbe_Qw3ENNg" hash="1Ft9Hg">Alma agreed that the reason the Israelites did not look to the serpent was that they did not believe doing so would heal them. Alma’s words are relevant to us today:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p11" guid="806e4d1a-eeec-4877-96e5-da5170414cc6" pid="tBNzXnF4PEiL1RNQi110iA" hash="BZEJLA">“O my brethren, if ye could be healed by merely casting about your eyes that ye might be healed, would ye not behold quickly, or would ye rather harden your hearts in unbelief, and be slothful … ?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p12" guid="9e61c1c4-0647-4765-a407-f27258c9cef2" pid="fXcsQ5epUUCp0tauqYYPMA" hash="eMbDCg">“If so, wo shall come upon you; but if not so, then cast about your eyes and begin to believe in the Son of God, that he will come to redeem his people, and that he shall suffer and die to atone for [our] sins; and that he shall rise again from the dead.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p13" guid="de0d9de7-9d52-425b-bab7-d6138d5e7141" pid="vPMivMuWjUGICprLgrUQ-w" hash="3tlarg">President Monson’s encouragement to look up is a metaphor for remembering Christ. As we remember Him and trust in His power, we receive strength through His Atonement. It is the means whereby we can be relieved of our anxieties, our burdens, and our suffering. It is the means whereby we can be forgiven and healed from the pain of our sins. It is the means whereby we can receive the faith and strength to endure all things.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p14" guid="29ac40d5-471a-4fd6-b00f-c42c733fc83a" pid="QCN-du4cBEK5Z-f_XwYQng" hash="hsN_1Q">Recently Sister Cook and I attended a women’s conference in South Africa. After we listened to some inspiring messages on applying the Atonement in our lives, the stake Relief Society president invited everyone outside. We were each given a helium balloon. She explained that our balloon represented whatever burden, trial, or hardship was holding us back in our lives. On the count of three, we released our balloons, or our “burdens.” As we looked up and watched our burdens float away, there was an audible “Ahhhh.” That simple act of releasing our balloons provided a marvelous reminder of the indescribable joy that comes from looking up and thinking of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p15" guid="f09dffc4-bec9-4004-a294-75e47c77eb99" pid="tSS4PBc58UCDbBcAXOI-ng" hash="va4h2Q">Unlike releasing a helium balloon, spiritually looking up is not a one-time experience. We learn from the sacrament prayer that we are to always remember Him and to keep His commandments, that we may have His Spirit to be with us every day to guide us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p16" guid="1b58206a-d009-4f16-a9e7-d5899016d646" pid="-8Q7GeHjAUGPd_K3Yt-isg" hash="SotzjA">When the children of Israel were wandering in the wilderness, the Lord guided their journey each day as they looked to Him for direction. In Exodus we read, “And the Lord went before them by day in a pillar of a cloud, to lead them the way; and by night in a pillar of fire, to give them light.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> His leading was constant, and I give you my humble witness that the Lord can do the same for us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p17" guid="d9b81919-f98d-4b0a-9a7d-84c582efeba3" pid="6HUU1s2NxkGGWz9VZAZXbA" hash="y-UTiw">So how will He lead us today? Through prophets, apostles, and priesthood leaders and through feelings that come after we pour out our hearts and souls to Heavenly Father in prayer. He leads us as we forsake the things of the world, repent, and change. He leads us as we keep His commandments and try to be more <span class="pageBreak" page-number="35"></span>like Him. And He leads us through the Holy Ghost.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p18" guid="ea868d47-7d0b-4504-ae7c-9ddd032fb8fe" pid="Q9Xxphe-IUiioV_LL48BbA" hash="rBgaFQ">In order to be guided in life’s journey and have the constant companionship of the Holy Ghost, we must have a “hearing ear” and a “seeing eye,” both directed upward.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> We must act on the direction we receive. We must look up and step up. And as we do, I know we will cheer up, for God wants us to be happy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p19" guid="52c6b9db-ebdc-46dc-a9e9-cf8c5656bdf1" pid="XYwSzhCNJ0yy1jxZ9fCBEQ" hash="CDUxmg">We are Heavenly Father’s children. He wants to be a part of our lives, to bless us, and to help us. He will heal our wounds, dry our tears, and help us along our path to return to His presence. As we look to Him, He will lead us.</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.f1" guid="a3939486-367e-4b69-a508-aa4cc44a1612">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="nqL3GbLnw0WG05fq-Cv_QA" hash="6bTh5g">
            <span class="emphasis">The Lord is my light; then why should I fear?</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="2Rbp2EjveU-DKDuSltNYlw" hash="PNPmLA">
            <span class="emphasis">By day and by night his presence is near. …</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="oEq9WH_F-UW0oNDTku991Q" hash="Vq6_vg">
            <span class="emphasis">He is my joy and my song.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="28hsXu96eUubPyEZDC-N8w" hash="XWVF8w">
            <span class="emphasis">By day and by night he leads … me along.</span>
            <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p20" guid="1218530a-6ad6-4e09-9d24-f5ee247e8003" pid="VMBvWDel8EmOgf1TnbE2tA" hash="eXCOUQ">I bear testimony that sins are forgiven and burdens are lightened as we look to Christ. “Let us remember him, … and not hang down our heads,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> for, as President Monson said, “It is better to look up.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up.p21" guid="1b7d484f-76de-49c8-9bf8-493918ae46ef" pid="EEayKuZHxkG0bNaH7XohDw" hash="cI16Lg">I testify that Jesus is our Savior and Redeemer in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/10/it-is-better-to-look-up</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2011-general-conference/2011-10-2050-elder-carl-b-cook-64k-eng.mp3" length="4147405" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Serve</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/10/serve?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Cook teaches that although Church callings can be challenging, we are blessed as we serve with faith and dedication.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60001311_000_63cook" doc-version="1" hash="xMVS9g">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="lDKmX_5U2kabHK2VZQObZA" hash="oPIHYA">Serve</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p2" pid="shR2q4RslUGlbOwiTN20sQ" hash="qsAI6g1">By Elder Carl B. Cook</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p3" pid="6YJIktzL4kmuN82JTH5J6Q" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="MJyBCJNxLUG89TNqSnYB9g" hash="tPXCZg">Every member is needed, and every member needs an opportunity to serve.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="NQh01mND20qNl1rXvFhIAQ" hash="qsAI6g">By Elder Carl B. Cook</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p5" pid="LcdJSSdO2kidfbBaFu3iyQ" hash="-TkBHg">As a boy I enjoyed working with my Uncle Lyman and Aunt Dorothy on their farm. Uncle Lyman usually led our projects, and Aunt Dorothy often assisted and drove the old Dodge truck. I remember the rush of adrenaline when we got bogged down in the mud or tried to climb a steep hill: Uncle Lyman would yell, “Put ’er in compound, Dorothy!” That’s when I started to pray. Somehow, with the Lord’s help and after some grinding of gears, Aunt Dorothy found compound. With all wheels locked in and churning, the truck lunged forward and our work continued.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p6" pid="fqRJoJmd_k60V34F3Jalzw" hash="OcV0Ww">“Putting it in compound” refers to shifting into a special gear in which a number of gears are arranged to work together to generate more torque.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> A compound gear, along with four-wheel drive, allows you to gear down, power up, and move.</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=ES7Kqb8A_E2zX2MwwMRA1A"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814613/638e2dabc5fe44628e053334b8214e72/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814613/638e2dabc5fe44628e053334b8214e72/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814613/638e2dabc5fe44628e053334b8214e72/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814613/638e2dabc5fe44628e053334b8214e72/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814613/638e2dabc5fe44628e053334b8214e72/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814613/638e2dabc5fe44628e053334b8214e72/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814613/638e2dabc5fe44628e053334b8214e72/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814613/638e2dabc5fe44628e053334b8214e72/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814613/638e2dabc5fe44628e053334b8214e72/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814613/638e2dabc5fe44628e053334b8214e72/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Compound gears" pid="ES7Kqb8A_E2zX2MwwMRA1A" hash="vr5e7w"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p7" pid="GHxTU2Y_LEO9uE_6xXq5KA" hash="SK-iMQ">I like to think of each of us as part of a compound gear as we serve together in the Church—in wards and branches, in quorums and auxiliaries. Just as gears combine to provide greater power in compound, we have greater power when we join together. As we unite to serve one another, we accomplish much more together than we could on our own. It is thrilling to be engaged and unified as we serve and assist in the Lord’s work.</p>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.t1">
				<h2 pid="yDVYp6uVgEWLat_LhmSmIA" hash="eQRBKA">Serving Is a Blessing</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p9" pid="xlJAKHtU8k6MQbdBbYjhlQ" hash="fbGhCw">The opportunity to serve is one of the great blessings of membership in the Church.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> The Lord has said, “If thou lovest me thou shalt serve me,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> and we serve Him by serving others.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p10" pid="DIkixyVGR0-7dWCpCr6v9w" hash="7hij5A">As we serve, we draw closer to God.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> We come to know Him in ways that we otherwise might not. Our faith in Him increases. Our problems are put into perspective. Life becomes more satisfying. Our love for others increases, as well as our desire to serve. Through this blessed process, we become more like God, and we are better prepared to return to Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p11" pid="F9yWKdIR0U-lJIfD-WD2TA" hash="hamXEQ">As President Marion G. Romney taught: “Service is not something we endure on this earth so we can earn the right to live in the celestial kingdom. Service is the very fiber of which an exalted life in the celestial kingdom is made.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.t2">
				<h2 pid="m6YP9CAZg0-0X-zIOiG2QQ" hash="8RWqEQ">Serving Can Be Challenging</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p13" pid="9Ta8MSvF6UyFR01VqZiMiw" hash="_ZKApA">Serving in the Church, however, can be challenging if we are asked to do something that frightens us, if we grow weary of serving, or if we are called to do something that we do not initially find appealing.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p14" pid="AMdcRnALM0ign8T2fSpoSw" hash="uqXpww">Recently I received a new assignment. I had been serving in the Africa Southeast Area. It was thrilling to serve where the Church is relatively young and being established, and we loved the Saints. Then I was called to return to Church headquarters, and to be honest, I was less than enthusiastic. A change in assignment brought some unknowns.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p15" pid="3pNAp1KHDkSpSD9uRwm_mg" hash="ZnXjpQ">One night after contemplating the upcoming change, I dreamed about my great-great-grandfather Joseph Skeen. I knew from his journal that when he and his wife, Maria, moved to Nauvoo, he desired to serve, so he sought out the Prophet Joseph Smith and asked how he could help. The Prophet sent him to work on the prairie and told him to do the best he could, so he did. He worked on the Smiths’ farm.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p16" pid="dM_no7OJ20KdvTG70lq0Fg" hash="sjdBsw">I pondered the privilege that Joseph Skeen had in receiving his assignment that way. Suddenly I realized that I have the same privilege, as we all do. All Church callings come from God—through His appointed servants.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p17" pid="tg6zBrA_0kaz7pMm6Mb9yQ" hash="fm-PVw">I felt a distinct spiritual confirmation that my new assignment was inspired. It is important that we make that connection—that our callings literally come to us from God through our priesthood leaders. After this experience, my attitude changed, and I was filled with a deep desire to serve. I am grateful for the blessing of repentance and for my changed heart. I love my new assignment.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p18" pid="uftn7XS-dUmifOZk36phVw" hash="d3ZbXg">Even if we think that our Church calling was simply our priesthood leader’s idea or that it came to us because no one else would accept it, we will be blessed as we serve. But when we recognize God’s hand in our calling and serve with all our hearts, additional power comes into our service, and we become true servants of Jesus Christ.</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.t3">
				<h2 pid="ins4cDp9iUuUp6eyIW4DdA" hash="Q0PdIw">Serving Requires Faith</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p20" pid="0BtOt-0WrkGwS_saFuQIuA" hash="XPSNRw">Fulfilling callings requires faith. Shortly after Joseph began working on the farm, he and Maria became very sick. They had no money and were among strangers. It was a difficult time for them. In his journal, Joseph wrote, “We worked along [and] hung on to the Church with what little faith we had, though the devil tried to destroy us and turn us back.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p21" pid="RQrsyMaewE-DIRNpD4kz2Q" hash="Qelfgg">I, along with hundreds of other descendants, will be eternally grateful that Joseph and Maria did not turn back. Blessings come as we persevere in our callings and responsibilities and hang on with all the faith we have.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p22" pid="5EkGjl05TEGH9Vx2arFcPA" hash="JzRkUQ">I know a wonderful Gospel Doctrine teacher who lifts class members as she teaches, but that wasn’t always the case. After joining the Church, she received a calling to teach in Primary. She felt she had no teaching skills, but because she knew the importance of serving, she accepted. Fear quickly overcame her, and she stopped attending so she wouldn’t have to teach. Thankfully, her home teacher noticed her absence, visited her, and invited her back. The bishop and ward members assisted her. Eventually, with increased faith, she began teaching children. As she applied principles now taught in <span class="emphasis">Teaching in the Savior’s Way,</span> the Lord blessed her efforts and she became a gifted teacher.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p23" pid="ZnxgSGhudkehj3Hi3V0YYQ" hash="l7bGuw">The natural man or woman in all of us is inclined to allow us to excuse ourselves from serving for reasons such as “I am not ready to serve; I have more to learn,” “I’m tired and need a break,” “I’m too old—it’s someone else’s turn,” or “I am simply too busy.”</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p24" pid="W8q0WoPn7kqTs_7bZoK6fA" hash="hjGoAQ">Brothers and sisters, accepting and fulfilling a calling is an act of faith. We can trust in what our prophet, President Thomas S. Monson, repeatedly teaches: “Whom the Lord calls, the Lord qualifies” and “When we are on the Lord’s errand, we are entitled to the Lord’s help.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Whether we are overwhelmed or underwhelmed, whether we are scared to death or bored to death, the Lord wants us to gear down, power up, and serve.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p25" pid="gmuPvZjRMUG9a4O4MPma_w" hash="_inLVg">I see no signs that President Monson and his associates in the First Presidency and the Quorum of the Twelve are too busy or too tired. They exemplify in an inspiring way the power that comes into our lives as we exercise faith, accept assignments, and fulfill them with commitment and dedication. They “put [their shoulders] to the wheel”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> many years ago, and they continue to push forward, onward, and upward.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p26" pid="wW3oiyAmTUGbQhPix0PYQA" hash="pwF4OA">Yes, they serve in important callings, but <span class="emphasis">every</span> calling or assignment is important. President Gordon B. Hinckley, a previous prophet and President of the Church, said: “We are all in this great endeavor together. … Your obligation is as serious in your sphere of responsibility as is my obligation in my sphere. No calling in this church is small or of little consequence.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> Every calling is important.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.t4">
				<h2 pid="1KOgm6Q1wUmrX9VwmYdi9Q" hash="JN9fZg">Let Us Serve</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p28" pid="WMGOKdIS9EG9NNg5X_LgcQ" hash="CEblVQ">Let us rise up in faith, “put [our shoulders] to the wheel,” and move this “worthy work along.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> Let’s “put it in compound,” along with faithful Aunt Dorothy. As brothers and sisters, let’s serve.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p29" pid="b5hBdc9-J0yodnwoBTlLmw" hash="pyCiIg">If you want to make your bishop’s or branch president’s day, ask him the questions “How can I help?” “Where would the Lord have me serve?” As he prays and considers your personal, family, and employment responsibilities, he will be inspired to extend an appropriate calling. As you are set apart, you will receive a priesthood blessing to help you succeed. You <span class="emphasis">will</span> be blessed! Every member is needed, and every member needs an opportunity to serve.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.t5">
				<h2 pid="67hYZiprG0OXZBECP0ocsg" hash="Jo_jNw">Jesus Christ Is Our Exemplar</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p31" pid="ZvEz7sFtDEilKoJjUqKg5g" hash="1Q-TiQ">Jesus Christ, our great Exemplar, gave His life to His Father’s work. In the Grand Council before this world was organized, Jesus, chosen and anointed from the beginning, volunteered, “Here am I, send me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> In so doing, He literally became the servant of us all. Through Jesus Christ and the power we receive through His Atonement, we can also serve. He will help us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p32" pid="LSwriFEmnE-pzFRAEQ2fgA" hash="JCiEfA">I extend my heartfelt love to those of you who may not currently be able to serve in the Church in traditional ways because of personal circumstances but who live your life in a spirit of service. I pray that you will be blessed in your efforts. I also express appreciation to those who magnify callings week in and week out, as well as those who soon will be accepting calls to serve. All contributions and sacrifices are valued, especially by Him whom we serve. All who serve will receive God’s grace.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p33" pid="fdE2hFu2Rk6TiTQu5i5MBQ" hash="oiPrtQ">Whatever our age or circumstance, let service be our “watchcry.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> Serve in your calling. Serve a mission. Serve your mother. Serve a stranger. Serve your neighbor. Just serve.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/serve.p34" pid="3Nm1QImHmUm5qsBaaCd5wg" hash="V_aQnQ">May the Lord bless each of us in our efforts to serve and become true followers of Jesus Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> I testify that He lives and directs this work. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/10/serve</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2016-general-conference/2016-10-5030-carl-b-cook-64k-eng.mp3" length="5313249" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
