<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Carl B. Pratt</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Carl B. Pratt.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Carl%20B.%20Pratt.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Carl B. Pratt.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1997 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1997 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Care for New Converts</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1997/10/care-for-new-converts?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In building the kingdom of God, every positive act, every friendly greeting, every warm smile, every thoughtful, kind note contributes to the strength of the whole.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/care-for-new-converts" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_97911_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="r4wGDQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/care-for-new-converts.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="eJ9Bj2_sakKMe-90lCNo_w" hash="GCmLgw">Care for New Converts</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="0jZVoG2QU069zegE6wbiXw" hash="_8DQQg">Carl B. Pratt</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="rXVMBlQ9CUWWnIEENJ6zaQ" hash="DxOyUg">In building the kingdom of God, every positive act, every friendly greeting, every warm smile, every thoughtful, kind note contributes to the strength of the whole.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/care-for-new-converts.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e30.jpg" alt="Elder Carl B. Pratt" pid="G_0c9WLSK0K-9xxAeKzcKw" hash="NtW39A" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/care-for-new-converts.p1" pid="HfB1ayisgEqlJz1DpSyuDw" hash="ngkn1g">Brothers and sisters, I bring you greetings from the Saints of southern Mexico. I was born in Mexico, as were my father and my grandfather before me. Although I was raised and educated in the United States from about six years of age, I retained throughout my life a love for and a fascination with Latin America, its wonderful people, and its kaleidoscope of cultures. Although as a child I was always aware of my family roots in Mexico and their role in the establishment of the Lord’s kingdom there, my real love began when, as a young missionary in Argentina, I watched people, prepared by the Spirit, eagerly accept the gospel and I saw the peace and joy that it brought to their lives. My growing love was not just for Latin America but for the work of the Lord among the people there.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/care-for-new-converts.p2" pid="QdD5zEUnL0WZP2P-ONUZ5Q" hash="cfX9DA">So, in 1975, with less than four years out of law school, there was no hesitation on my part when I was offered a position as Church legal counsel in South America. With three small children, my wife and I moved to Montevideo, Uruguay. We were blessed with five more children in the ensuing years, born to us in various countries of South America. Our children have been raised in the Spanish-speaking countries of the world, and each one has a deep appreciation for the diversity in their cultural and linguistic heritage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/care-for-new-converts.p3" pid="rULfeovEAkWsUWVhM7Pyeg" hash="k-KGuw">In the past 22 years we have had a front row seat to watch the explosive unfolding of the Lord’s work in Latin America. Literally millions have joined the Church in these years, and we have seen it grow from a mere handful of stakes to over 700 at the present time. We have six functioning temples and five more under construction in these countries. What a tremendously exciting time to be alive and to be involved in this great work of blessing our Father’s children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/care-for-new-converts.p4" pid="tijsv5Cvl0a0qWixNdaizg" hash="yoEkkg">Yes, these past years have been incredibly exciting, challenging, and immensely enriching for us as a family, but we have learned much more than geography, culture, and language. We have learned new and deeper meanings for words like <span class="emphasis">love, joy, service,</span> and <span class="emphasis">sacrifice.</span> For example, we have watched families save for years and then travel for up to 72 hours on a cramped bus, with small children, over poor roads, just to be able to enjoy the blessings of the sacred ordinances of the temple. We have watched humble, devoted priesthood and auxiliary leaders strive to build the kingdom and to bless the lives of the Saints, but without having the advantages of telephones or personal vehicles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/care-for-new-converts.p5" pid="yhIE0FVd60-h8jQoDA5GDg" hash="H_FNDw">We have also learned that no one culture, people, or country has a corner on love, warmth, or kindness. As we would periodically return to the United States to visit family and friends, it would be our privilege to attend various wards in several different states. It wasn’t until our children became adolescents that we began to notice differences in the spirits of the various wards. Some wards our children loved to visit because they quickly found friends among the youth, and we all received a warm and hearty welcome. But there were other wards to which our children returned with less enthusiasm, and there was a noticeable absence of the warm and hearty welcome.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/care-for-new-converts.p6" pid="EZNoaTHQcEut1VP6OgnhGw" hash="UD7ooQ">We then began to observe that in some wards we visited in the United States as well as in Latin America, if we had been investigators or new members, we would not have felt very welcome. The Apostle Paul taught the Ephesians, “Ye are no more strangers and foreigners, but fellowcitizens with the saints, and of the household of God” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/2.19" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 2:19</a>). And yet, on occasion we felt like “strangers and foreigners” in the very Church of Jesus Christ to which we belonged.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/care-for-new-converts.p7" pid="-xuExvNkKEqS8-aZZ24Xvg" hash="wb4SUQ">These experiences helped us become aware of the discomfort that newcomers might occasionally feel in coming to our chapels, and these made us conscious of the need we <span class="emphasis">all</span> have to improve what we call our fellowshipping skills. We have occasionally observed wards in Latin America, Spain, and in the United States where humble new converts to the Church have <span class="emphasis">not</span> been received with open arms or warm <span class="emphasis">abrazos,</span> and so we have all seen a need to improve our retention of new converts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/care-for-new-converts.p8" pid="In0a_MWtyEm_pHh1WNCUxA" hash="mPvySg">Brothers and sisters, we have the richest blessings that God can give to His children. We have the fulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ. We ought to be the most open, friendly, happy, kind, considerate, thoughtful, loving people in the whole world. Now, we do pretty well at fulfilling callings, at going to meetings, at paying our tithing; but have we learned to truly live the second great commandment: “Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself”? (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.39" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:39</a>). This is not something that can be assigned to the elders quorum or to the visiting teachers; this has to spring from the heart of every true disciple of Christ, a person who will look automatically and without being asked for opportunities to serve, to uplift, and to strengthen his fellowman.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/care-for-new-converts.p9" pid="fyrAm93iaUu3WTCRCBMX0g" hash="b55d6A">We are reminded of the Savior’s words, “By this shall all men know that ye are my disciples, if ye have love one to another” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/13.35" class="scriptureRef">John 13:35</a>). Will nonmembers, new converts, and visitors to our chapels recognize us as His disciples by the warmth of our greeting, by the ease of our smiles, by the kindness and genuine concern that shine in our eyes?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/care-for-new-converts.p10" pid="ArA3UY2FYUOmVFNG0I6k-A" hash="nwVguw">Let us pay more attention to those who are new to our congregations. In the Sermon on the Mount, Jesus taught: “For if ye love them which love you, what reward have ye? … And if ye salute your brethren only, what do ye more than others?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.46-47" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:46–47</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/care-for-new-converts.p11" pid="cG1J2iLtY0WjWMEiBFEWOA" hash="gn4VLQ">In building the kingdom of God, every positive act, every friendly greeting, every warm smile, every thoughtful, kind note contributes to the strength of the whole. It is my prayer that we may be open and outgoing, friendly, and helpful to all who come among us. But let us give special care and concern for the new converts to the Church. When we detect a halting step or a stumble as they begin their journey on the gospel path, let us be there to lift and support with words of kindness and concern; let us be available to give gentle, loving counsel that will strengthen and sustain. Let us conscientiously look for occasions to show that love which the Savior admonished us to have when He said, “A new commandment I give unto you, That ye love one another” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/13.34" class="scriptureRef">John 13:34</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/care-for-new-converts.p12" pid="I6ud_l9PiE2nw5louTAYLw" hash="ElJNfQ">I testify that this is the Church of our Lord Jesus Christ, that He lives, that He directs this great work, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1997/10/care-for-new-converts</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1997-general-conference/1997-10-1040-elder-carl-b-pratt-64k-eng.mp3" length="3985453" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1997 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Blessings of a Proper Fast</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I fear … that too many of us are either not fasting on fast day or we are doing so in a lackadaisical manner.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030208_000_018" doc-version="2" hash="zqhhqg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="8KiWKjNgPUmTDz2zDmizOg" hash="g5SLjA">The Blessings of a Proper Fast</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="YaEWPqP7zEKmFIhX5pw4cw" hash="_8DQQg">Carl B. Pratt</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="OKm-tkmev0am1pI44wYSYA" hash="icMycQ">I fear … that too many of us are either not fasting on fast day or we are doing so in a lackadaisical manner.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-645.jpg" alt="Elder Carl B. Pratt" pid="blfbcJGockO2EpTssxfKAg" hash="TDG9Ww" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p1" pid="O1adLpuGS0WcZ5O9jDJKUA" hash="6EOlaw">Brethren, I hope you noticed this morning, as President Hinckley prepared to announce the names of two new Apostles, he spoke of fasting and praying to know the Lord’s will.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p2" pid="JTiezWUyV0m3Oc1YLClukw" hash="pst9IA">Fasting has always been a practice among God’s people. In our day it is a commandment given by the Lord to all members of the Church. In addition to occasional special fasts that we might have for personal or family reasons, we are expected to fast once a month on the first Sunday. We are taught that there are three aspects to a proper fast day observance: first, abstaining from food and drink for two consecutive meals or, in other words, 24 hours; second, attending fast and testimony meeting; and third, giving a generous fast offering.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p3" pid="5AC5wpm4dEaOXKSw4nc62Q" hash="n1NO5g">For the Pratt family our regular fasts have always been from the Saturday noon meal to the Sunday noon meal. That way we fast for two meals, Saturday evening and Sunday morning meals. Although there is no Church standard for fasting, except that it should be for 24 hours and two meals, we have found a spiritual advantage in attending fast and testimony meeting toward the end of the fast.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p4" pid="YSsriNs5bke2p2tiWVXURg" hash="eyQx5Q">For those who are physically able, fasting is a commandment. Speaking of our monthly fast day, President Joseph F. Smith said: “The Lord has instituted the fast on a reasonable and intelligent basis. … Those who can are required to comply … ; it is a duty from which they cannot escape; … it is left with the people as a matter of conscience, to exercise wisdom and discretion. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p5" pid="u6ydU47Q3kOIUAQx4Fu4KQ" hash="2AG57w">“But those should fast who can. … None are exempt from this; it is required of the Saints, old and young, in every part of the Church” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Doctrine,</span> 5th ed. [1939], 244).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p6" pid="gS-nttsog0ab3hgFMl95yQ" hash="754HnA">I fear, brethren, that too many of us are either not fasting on fast day or we are doing so in a lackadaisical manner. If we are guilty of taking our fast day for granted or simply fasting Sunday morning instead of making it two complete meals—24 hours—we are depriving ourselves and our families of the choice spiritual experiences and blessings that can come from a true fast.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p7" pid="vgtCNYM500KXvpcrCD9jmQ" hash="fYNdDw">If all we do is abstain from food and drink for 24 hours and pay our fast offering, we have missed a wonderful opportunity for spiritual growth. On the other hand, if we have a special purpose in our fasting, the fast will have much more meaning. Perhaps we can take time as a family before beginning our fast to talk about what we hope to accomplish by this fast. This could be done in a family home evening the week before fast Sunday or in a brief family meeting at the time of family prayer. When we fast with purpose, we have something to focus our attention on besides our hunger.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p8" pid="8PPiR64fpUWQBGROglqeWw" hash="KRrTOQ">The purpose of our fast may be a very personal one. Fasting can help us overcome personal flaws and sins. It can help us overcome our weaknesses—help them become strengths. Fasting can help us become more humble, less prideful, less selfish, and more concerned about the needs of others. It can help us see more clearly our own mistakes and weaknesses and help us be less prone to criticize others. Or our fast may have a focus on a family challenge. A family fast might help increase love and appreciation among family members and reduce the amount of contention in the family, or we might fast as a couple to strengthen our marriage bonds. A purpose of our fast as priesthood holders might be to seek the Lord’s guidance in our callings, as President Hinckley has demonstrated, or we might fast with our home teaching companion to know how to help one of our families.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p9" pid="gZhAZTWTjE-iJVDNZWgIXQ" hash="8dmU5A">Throughout the scriptures the term <span class="emphasis">fasting</span> is usually combined with prayer. “Ye shall continue in prayer and fasting from this time forth” is the Lord’s counsel (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.76" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:76</a>). Fasting without prayer is just going hungry for 24 hours. But fasting combined with prayer brings increased spiritual power.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p10" pid="nclHsmv36UiynrBqaHEwwg" hash="yyJ-dQ">When the disciples were unable to cure a boy who was possessed of an evil spirit, they asked the Savior, “Why could not we cast him out?” Jesus responded, “This kind goeth not out but by prayer and fasting” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/17.19,21" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 17:19, 21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p11" pid="uvtw_p0ozk-QdFlImDa0bw" hash="IvkpRg">Let us begin our fasts with prayer. This could be kneeling at the table as we finish the meal with which we begin the fast. That prayer should be a natural thing as we speak to our Heavenly Father concerning the purpose of our fast and plead with Him for His help in accomplishing our goals. Likewise, let us end our fasts with prayer. We could very appropriately kneel at the table before we sit down to consume the meal with which we break our fast. We would thank the Lord for His help during the fast and for what we have felt and learned from the fast.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p12" pid="mAt-aDlpGUiOw7b0e_7U_w" hash="mTjtOg">In addition to a beginning and ending prayer, we should seek the Lord often in personal prayer throughout the fast.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p13" pid="hgNTZBcWcEyh5vkPiiEuaw" hash="JC29vg">We should not expect our young children to fast for the recommended two meals. But let us teach them the principles of fasting. If fasting is discussed and planned in a family setting, the small children will be aware that their parents and older siblings are fasting, and they will understand the purpose of the fast. They should participate in the family prayers to begin and end the fast. This way, when they reach the proper age, they will be eager to fast with the rest of the family. In our family, we have done this by encouraging our children between 8 and 12 years of age to fast for one meal; then as they have turned 12 and received the Aaronic Priesthood or entered Young Women, we have encouraged them to fast for two complete meals.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p14" pid="B8VDBty8DEK4BXoKg7qZcA" hash="j01B-Q">After chastising ancient Israel for fasting improperly, the Lord, through the prophet Isaiah, speaks in beautiful poetic language of a proper fast:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p15" pid="bmEG2yHKWE-j2xp6bN8YNw" hash="DuAujw">“Is not this the fast that I have chosen? to loose the bands of wickedness, to undo the heavy burdens, and to let the oppressed go free, and that ye break every yoke?” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/58.6" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 58:6</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p16" pid="Vzo_NzxOhEym3j5BCQBAAg" hash="FCnboA">If we fast and pray with the purpose of repenting of sins and overcoming personal weaknesses, surely we are seeking to “loose the bands of wickedness” in our lives. If the purpose of our fast is to be more effective in teaching the gospel and serving others in our Church callings, we are surely striving to “undo the heavy burdens” of others. If we are fasting and praying for the Lord’s help in our missionary efforts, aren’t we desiring to “let the oppressed go free”? If the purpose of our fast is to increase our love for our fellow man and overcome our selfishness, our pride, and having our hearts set upon the things of this world, surely we are seeking to “break every yoke.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p17" pid="n9TmiH51OUCci6wOgFvoBw" hash="THrmqw">The Lord continues describing the proper fast:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p18" pid="Pvu4b2xewEK2XQJJPq08vg" hash="CQkZ6w">“Is it not to deal thy bread to the hungry, and that thou bring the poor that are cast out to thy house? when thou seest the naked, that thou cover him; and that thou hide not thyself from thine own flesh?” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/58.7" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 58:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p19" pid="8EOk8gruqEasuj2aN_bMOg" hash="3wH2iw">It is truly a wonderful thing that through our fast offerings today we can feed the hungry, shelter the homeless, and clothe the naked.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p20" pid="mb7wJZ1v9UCbKDGFymUVqw" hash="6GIMOg">If we fast properly the Lord promises:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p21" pid="BmezSkGslE6xmaptegEzFw" hash="4wr6iQ">“Then shall thy light break forth as the morning, and thine health shall spring forth speedily: and thy righteousness shall go before thee; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p22" pid="bvKrD_2Bn0ivOpOKWlIc5Q" hash="V8g9uQ">“Then shalt thou call, and the Lord shall answer; thou shalt cry, and he shall say, Here I am. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p23" pid="N8M--CnB3EGAG6YBBHPfrw" hash="OOgyqg">“And if thou draw out thy soul to the hungry, and satisfy the afflicted soul; then shall thy light rise in obscurity, and thy darkness be as the noonday:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p24" pid="7denoofMAkqtRITrcC1g8Q" hash="MH3OHA">“And the Lord shall guide thee continually, and satisfy thy soul in drought, … and thou shalt be like a watered garden, and like a spring of water, whose waters fail not” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/58.8-11" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 58:8–11</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast.p25" pid="cQhrDLAKwUSASBK3_4bmuw" hash="TigbAg">It is my prayer that we can improve our fasts so that we can enjoy these beautiful promised blessings. It is my testimony that as we “draw near” to the Lord through our fasting and prayer, He will “draw near” to us (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.63" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:63</a>). I testify that He lives, that He loves us, and that He wants to draw near to us. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2004/10/the-blessings-of-a-proper-fast</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2004-general-conference/2004-10-3020-elder-carl-b-pratt-64k-eng.mp3" length="4799848" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2004 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lord’s Richest Blessings</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As we pay our tithing faithfully, the Lord will open the windows of heaven and pour out upon us His richest blessings.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50028768_000_5030" doc-version="2" hash="1gA8LQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.head1">
    <h1 class="title" pid="JZX3DixNIUqmom2JxtzIcQ" hash="3ARnlA">The Lord’s Richest Blessings</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="K517hIwlZUuiSmJRiHDIiw" hash="_8DQQg">Carl B. Pratt</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="9tPkunKtFUqTFqAlH4YKHg" hash="2QxZnA">As we pay our tithing faithfully, the Lord will open the windows of heaven and pour out upon us His richest blessings.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p1" pid="l8WxUkdm80ekJbiJGojizA" hash="-Ez1nA">I am grateful for righteous ancestors who taught the gospel to their children in the home long before there were formal family home evenings. My maternal grandparents were Ida Jesperson and John A. Whetten. They lived in the small community of Colonia Juárez, Chihuahua, Mexico. The Whetten children were taught by precept and by observing the examples of their parents.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p2" pid="OwXgvFRVj06qmGjksuf37g" hash="FUF50A">The early 1920s in Mexico were hard times. The violent revolution had just ended. There was little cash circulating, and most of it was in silver coins. People often conducted their business through barter, or exchange of goods and services.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p3" pid="KkuFMt2t_UinBk96NERTaA" hash="I3S73g">One day toward the end of summer, Grandpa John came home, having completed a trade and having received as part of the deal 100 pesos in silver coins. He gave the money to Ida with instructions it was to be used to cover the upcoming school expenses of the children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p4" pid="-UUhuiJRtk2iL6Dzbt_xbw" hash="mUfr0A">Ida was grateful for the money but reminded John that they had not paid any tithing all summer long. They had had no cash income, but Ida reminded him that the animals had provided meat, eggs, and milk. Their garden had provided an abundance of fruits and vegetables, and they had made other trades for goods not involving cash. Ida suggested they should give the money to the bishop to cover their tithing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p5" pid="aLTxTkc4DEiPoCJVnxXA9Q" hash="bgkWgw">John was a little disappointed, as the cash would have helped a great deal toward the children’s schooling, but he readily agreed they needed to pay their tithing. He carried the heavy bag to the tithing office and settled with the bishop.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p6" pid="TMkj9_RJDEC8wourgLLgZA" hash="6VmHEQ">Shortly afterward he received word that a wealthy businessman from the United States, a Mr. Hord, would arrive the next week with several men to spend a few days in the mountains hunting and fishing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p7" pid="yp09v-39l0Wd7uI1RKYr5Q" hash="ZmCRGA">Grandpa John met the party of men at the railroad station not far from Colonia Juárez. He had the string of saddle horses and the necessary pack animals ready to transport the baggage and camp equipment into the mountains. The following week was spent guiding the men and caring for the camp and the animals.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p8" pid="UpAcDrI99UeubKFGgxpI9Q" hash="nqD3UQ">At the end of the week, the men returned to the railroad station to take the train back to the United States. John was paid that day for his work and was given a bag of silver peso coins to cover the other expenses. Once John and his men had been paid, John returned the balance of money to Mr. Hord, who was surprised, as he had not expected any money to be left over. He quizzed John to make sure all costs had been covered, and John answered that all the expenses for the trip had been met, and this was the balance of the funds.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p9" pid="iNcomW8EwkeqWpUPnRrmCA" hash="ViCy6A">The train whistled. Mr. Hord turned to go and then turned back and tossed the heavy bag of coins to John. “Here, take this home for your boys,” he said. John caught the bag and headed back to Colonia Juárez.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p10" pid="HtuwKXVKhEq1dtbuSkKkrw" hash="cC1WRg">That evening as the family gathered around after supper to hear the stories of the trip, John remembered the bag and brought it in and set it on the table. John said he didn’t know how much was in the bag, so for fun the bag was emptied onto the table—it was quite a pile—and when it was counted, it came to exactly 100 pesos in silver. Of course it was deemed a great blessing that Mr. Hord had decided to make that trip. John and his boys had earned good wages, but the 100 pesos left over was a reminder of the exact same amount of tithing paid the week before. To some, that might be an interesting coincidence, but to the Whetten family, it was clearly a lesson from the Lord that He remembers His promises to those who faithfully pay their tithing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p11" pid="2Qb5xCXYG0-cEQY-c-Pbbg" hash="2KVXTQ">As a child I loved that story because it was about a horseback camping trip into the mountains for hunting and fishing. And I loved it because it teaches that when we obey commandments we are blessed. There are several things we can conclude about tithing from this story.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p12" pid="AZFlToVXzU-XhLUcVUMnrg" hash="wjeCfA">First, you will notice that the payment of tithing in this case was not related to the amount of cash income. The Whettens decided to use their first cash income for tithing because they had lived well from their animals and their productive fruit and vegetable garden. They obviously felt indebted to the Lord for their blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p13" pid="HBuVkC7nWEm0dh5_t9tQXA" hash="940fQg">That is a reminder of the implication in the Lord’s words when He asks: “Will a man rob God? Yet ye have robbed me.” The people ask, “Wherein have we robbed thee?” And the Lord thunders back, “In tithes and offerings” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/3.8" class="scriptureRef">Malachi 3:8</a>). Yes, brothers and sisters, just as John and Ida Whetten realized that summer decades ago, we are all indebted to the Lord. Let us not be accused of robbing God. Let us be honest and pay our debts to the Lord. All He asks is 10 percent. Integrity in paying our debts to the Lord will help us be honest with our fellowmen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p14" pid="sfb5ViV8MUWEXHL-N6Qwng" hash="yDKXnA">The next thing I notice about that story is that my grandparents paid tithing regardless of the poor condition of their family finances. They knew the Lord’s commandment; they likened the scriptures unto themselves (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/19.23-24" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 19:23–24</a>) and obeyed the law. This is what the Lord expects of all His people. He expects us to pay tithing not from our abundance nor from the “leftovers” of the family budget but, as He commanded anciently, from the “firstlings” of our income, be it scarce or abounding. The Lord has commanded, “Thou shalt not delay to offer the first … fruits” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/22.29" class="scriptureRef">Exodus 22:29</a>). It has been my personal experience that the surest way to pay tithing faithfully is to pay it as soon as I receive any income. In fact, I’ve found it to be the only way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p15" pid="RQa1OoMZB0ODwXwXTG1qKQ" hash="WanFyg">We learn from my Whetten grandparents that tithing is not a matter of money, really; it is a matter of faith—faith in the Lord. He promises blessings if we obey His commandments. Clearly, John and Ida Whetten showed great faith in paying their tithing. Let us show our faith in the Lord by paying our tithing. Pay it first; pay it honestly. Teach our children to pay tithing even on their allowance or other income, and then take them with us to tithing settlement so they know of our example and our love for the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p16" pid="WTpLbDaYf0uU4IZjaTCqxw" hash="R8YQQQ">There is a possibility of misinterpretation in this story from my grandparents. We might conclude that since we pay tithing with money, the Lord will always bless us with money. I tended to think that way as a child. I have since learned it doesn’t necessarily work that way. The Lord promises blessings to those who pay their tithing. He promises to “open … the windows of heaven, and pour … out a blessing, that there shall not be room enough to receive it” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/3.10" class="scriptureRef">Malachi 3:10</a>). I testify that He fulfills His promises, and if we faithfully pay our tithing, we will not lack for the necessities of life, but He does not promise wealth. Money and bank accounts are not His richest blessings. He blesses us with wisdom to manage our limited material resources, wisdom that enables us to live better with 90 percent of our income than with 100 percent. Thus, faithful tithe payers understand provident living and tend to be more self-reliant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p17" pid="vrX60QTvuUKXHtaRYTShgg" hash="cK5mig">I have come to understand that the Lord’s richest blessings are spiritual, and they often have to do with family, friends, and the gospel. He often seems to give the blessing of a special sensitivity to the influence and guidance of the Holy Spirit, especially in marriage and family matters like raising children. Such spiritual sensitivity can help us enjoy the blessings of harmony and peace in the home. President James E. Faust suggested that the payment of tithing is “an excellent insurance against divorce” (“Enriching Your Marriage,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> Apr. 2007, 5; <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Apr. 2007, 7).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p18" pid="u6dfFb_whkqf4p6Mk-xm_Q" hash="CGqo0A">The payment of tithing helps us develop a submissive and humble heart and a grateful heart that tends to “confess … his hand in all things” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:21</a>). Tithe-paying fosters in us a generous and forgiving heart and a charitable heart full of the pure love of Christ. We become eager to serve and bless others with an obedient heart, submissive to the Lord’s will. Regular tithe payers find their faith in the Lord Jesus Christ strengthened, and they develop a firm, abiding testimony of His gospel and of His Church. None of these blessings are monetary or material in any way, but surely they are the Lord’s richest blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings.p19" pid="AEREDDqcxkeoYUpLOmSGSw" hash="YCX3gQ">I testify that as we pay our tithing faithfully, the Lord will open the windows of heaven and pour out upon us His richest blessings. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/04/the-lords-richest-blessings</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2011-general-conference/2011-04-5030-elder-carl-b-pratt-64k-eng.mp3" length="5079127" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
