<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Carlos E. Asay</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Carlos E. Asay.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Carlos%20E.%20Asay.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Carlos E. Asay.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1976 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>A Missionary Opportunity</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/04/a-missionary-opportunity?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My brethren, I needn’t tell you how frightened I am. My heart is pounding, and I feel a need for the Spirit to support me as I bear you my testimony. As you can well imagine, I have been humbled by this call, and all of my deficiencies and weaknesses</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-missionary-opportunity" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03070_000_018" doc-version="2" hash="Q0esbQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-missionary-opportunity.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ljhNuPw-DkWDTtIWLx1Ffw" hash="4vBSww">A Missionary Opportunity</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="wVtbX-rMjEeqxW1NROIR5g" hash="pDE4zw">Carlos E. Asay</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-missionary-opportunity.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-29c2.jpg" alt="Elder Carlos E. Asay" pid="yXwP2xdlWEelhvi4vyQ0Nw" hash="8VRGKQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-missionary-opportunity.p1" pid="HmkOFSfBS0aRFSGIxpUnww" hash="ehmDDg">My brethren, I needn’t tell you how frightened I am. My heart is pounding, and I feel a need for the Spirit to support me as I bear you my testimony. As you can well imagine, I have been humbled by this call, and all of my deficiencies and weaknesses seem to be magnified as I begin to look forward to my new responsibilities. I want you to know that I do have a testimony of the gospel of Jesus Christ. With all my heart I know that God lives, that Jesus is the Christ, that Joseph Smith was a prophet, and that we have a living prophet directing the affairs of the kingdom today. I know that to be true.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-missionary-opportunity.p2" pid="uyIEoON_qUyUjk55VkHKzA" hash="_LLwKg">I want to express my gratitude to my dear wife, to my family, to the Presiding Bishopric whom I love dearly, and to all the others who have helped prepare me for this responsibility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-missionary-opportunity.p3" pid="NxQaMJ26qEmnbJy_SZVVPQ" hash="M3f4Rw">As I elaborate a bit on my testimony, perhaps an experience might help. While serving as a mission president, I had occasion to discuss the gospel and to discuss missionary work with a Protestant minister. He was troubled because he had received a call to preside over a mission for his church, and because he had had a prior poor experience, he was seeking help. He came to my office in Dallas and said that he really didn’t want to accept the mission call, but he felt he had to. He said he knew that we had the best missionary program in the world, and he wanted to know why it was that we were so successful. I think he was looking for some organizational hints or something of that sort, but I knew that wasn’t the answer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-missionary-opportunity.p4" pid="NDhr5XFVvUOPJPLHLGawbA" hash="Rn42UA">After I had collected my thoughts, I told the man that there were four basic reasons why the Lord’s program succeeds. I said, first of all, we succeed because we are led by a living prophet, a man who is the mouthpiece for God on the earth, a man who receives inspiration—revelation—on behalf of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-missionary-opportunity.p5" pid="YEzjrMQwaEaIWr1dXrnDOQ" hash="yK7IeA">Second, we succeed because we work under the power and authority of the holy priesthood. We don’t assume that authority, we don’t take it upon ourselves, but it is given to us by the laying on of hands, and we are duly delegated to go out and preach the gospel. We have the priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-missionary-opportunity.p6" pid="_gy0rUjq3Ei2q4PjR9iwqQ" hash="Ff-MaA">Third, I said, we succeed because we are teaching the fulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ as restored in this day. We don’t play, as Elder Packer has taught, on one key; we play the entire keyboard. We know why we’re here, we know what we’re supposed to prepare for, and we know where we’ve been.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-missionary-opportunity.p7" pid="xJmA-3Giqkma0F_1agWfaw" hash="oM9kCA">And fourth, we succeed because we do what we do on the strength and power of personal testimony. Our young people go out and teach, not because of some promise of remuneration, but because they have a testimony; they forego college or delay it and put other personal plans aside so that they can go out and share their testimonies with the world. I said, when your church can conduct a program with a prophet directing under the power of the priesthood, teaching the fulness of the gospel, and on the strength of personal testimonies, you can do exactly what we are doing. I said, there is no need for you to go to that trouble, though. We already have it going; why don’t you join us? He didn’t accept my invitation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-missionary-opportunity.p8" pid="sUAMa37okkOUTX9W8YtVIw" hash="2xQXWQ">It’s true. And, oh, how happy I am that I have been given an opportunity to take an active role again in missionary work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-missionary-opportunity.p9" pid="waBPsrnmDU6dE55t9uN_Jw" hash="X42AOA">Perhaps I can conclude by making reference to something that Nephi said. He said: “My soul delighteth in the scriptures.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/4.15" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 4:15</a>.) Mine does. He said: “My soul delighteth in proving unto my people the truth of the coming of Christ.” My soul delights in that also. He said: “My soul delighteth in the covenants of the Lord which he hath made to our fathers; yea, my soul delighteth in his grace, and in his justice, and power, and mercy in the great and eternal plan of deliverance from death.” My soul delights in that too. And he said: “My soul delighteth in proving unto my people that save Christ should come all men must perish.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/11.4-6" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 11:4–6</a>.) I know this to be fact.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-missionary-opportunity.p10" pid="DPLzvaML_0iAGPSgpff9RA" hash="geQaWA">I pray the Lord will bless me and make me capable and equal to the task ahead, that he will be patient with me and forgiving of all my sins and shortcomings. I sustain the prophet; I sustain the Brethren. I am humbled with the prospects of working with them. In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/04/a-missionary-opportunity</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1976-general-conference/1976-04-3030-elder-carlos-e-asay-64k-eng.mp3" length="14866372" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1976 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Spirit of Missionary Work</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I want to take this opportunity to express my love and appreciation to the members of the First Council of the Seventy who were released yesterday. I’ve appreciated so much their leadership and support these past six months. I also sustain the new me</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03076_000_019" doc-version="3" hash="tTHc_g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="UM67aLP5pkSevhsEFB1w_A" hash="KBaM-g">The Spirit of Missionary Work</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="PV1tofKxpk-iJKuI_qLhqQ" hash="pDE4zw">Carlos E. Asay</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-29c2.jpg" alt="Elder Carlos E. Asay" pid="-Wjy41ZXeECbQpfT-4ti_w" hash="8VRGKQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p1" pid="o9zgbUxJk0iX2uvwC05m6Q" hash="pqDE8g">I want to take this opportunity to express my love and appreciation to the members of the First Council of the Seventy who were released yesterday. I’ve appreciated so much their leadership and support these past six months. I also sustain the new members, the new presidents of the First Council, and pledge my full support.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p2" pid="nzMEzjjJu0SN2R2dWRyQVA" hash="vXW50Q">A few years ago, in a mission presidents seminar, President Hugh B. Brown said: “If God would grant me one wish—just one—it would be this: that each missionary felt and enjoyed the spirit of his calling.” He also stated that if all missionaries were blessed to feel this spirit, miraculous things would occur in the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p3" pid="LaTzKLR86U6cnZTLYGfXiw" hash="YMhJ7A">If I were granted one wish, it would be similar to President Brown’s. My wish, however, would apply to all members of the Church, not just the full-time missionaries. Within my heart is the compelling desire that all members of the Church, young and old, be influenced and motivated by that special spirit which accompanies the sharing of the gospel of Jesus Christ. Would that all Latter-day Saints had intimate and continuous association with the missionary spirit!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p4" pid="NhW66Le4aUOq9yhGs8_TIA" hash="_zFe4w">The spirit of which I speak is best understood by reading the accounts of great missionaries such as the sons of Mosiah. It was their desire that they might impart the word of God to their brethren, the Lamanites. Note the depth of their feelings:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p5" pid="lZQyDOBQ4kmjaAW2UVuS2Q" hash="_o3y1Q">“Now they were desirous that salvation should be declared to every creature, for they could not bear that any human soul should perish; yea, even the very thoughts that any soul should endure endless torment did cause them to quake and tremble.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p6" pid="HFHUupdnEk6UnZxyxINRVw" hash="t2TXAQ">“And thus did the Spirit of the Lord work upon them.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/28.3-4" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 28:3–4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p7" pid="ZTAITsqbsUKtplDXawyfCw" hash="5nuIOA">This and other scriptures describe a marvelous phenomenon which occurs among men when the light of the gospel illuminates their lives. Almost instinctively, it seems, that light of truth sparks a desire to share. When our minds are expanded by new knowledge, we want others to know; when our spirits are elevated by heavenly influence, we want others to feel; and when our lives are filled with goodness, we want others, particularly those whom we love, to enjoy similar experiences.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p8" pid="HlYSYZiQmUirD0Oeck1TVg" hash="gslbXA">You will recall that in Lehi’s dream he “beheld a tree, whose fruit was desirable to make one happy.” So he went forth, partook of the fruit, and was filled with joy. Then, according to the record, he “began to be desirous that his family should partake of it also; for,” he said, “I knew that it was desirable above all other fruit.” This fruit motivated Lehi to beckon to his family and “with a loud voice” invite them to come to him and partake. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/8.10-12,15" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 8:10–12, 15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p9" pid="J-NNYqKX4k2JyrPOG2LpgA" hash="wxmJXw">Not too long ago, I heard the testimony of a new convert—a young man obviously touched by the Spirit. Among other things, he indicated that it was his great desire to share the restored gospel with his family and friends. With tears in his eyes and a quiver in his voice, he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p10" pid="K-Arf2XMiUCy5RvoECcPoA" hash="7sA3eA">“I want them <span class="emphasis">to know</span> what I know.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p11" pid="C1MGauvBOEOYkUgXMnYBmw" hash="cu9sqw">“I want them <span class="emphasis">to feel</span> what I feel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p12" pid="HMYfl6J7S0e9e-Zp9y5EqQ" hash="pWhW2Q">“I want them <span class="emphasis">to do</span> what I have done.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p13" pid="8DCf8LM73Ey4JwpT1jo1Sg" hash="9XVzjQ">There <span class="emphasis">is</span> a missionary spirit—a spirit which urges us to live outside ourselves and to be concerned for the welfare of others. And anyone who has ever served an honorable mission, assisted in the conversion of a friend, supported a son or daughter in the mission field, or enjoyed close associations with missionaries will testify of its reality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p14" pid="qivbMKbv0kW4FHzBQs6giA" hash="0oPG0A">One of the beautiful dimensions of the proselyting effort is that both parties involved, the teacher and the student, feel of the Spirit and are edified by what takes place. As revealed through the Prophet Joseph Smith, “He that preacheth and he that receiveth, understand one another, and both are edified and rejoice together.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/50.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 50:22</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p15" pid="0XKBe-pXJEa2k1DCmlc9MQ" hash="HluMsw">Listen to what one missionary wrote about teaching and testifying by the power of the Spirit:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p16" pid="rgytcpQ47Uu47jw-V_Xllg" hash="zI4a6Q">“Friday night I had the opportunity of bearing my testimony to an elderly couple and their son. I looked them straight in the eyes and said, ‘I know Joseph Smith received an answer to his prayer in the grove.’ My heart was filled with that burning feeling. … The lesson plan is great and so is [the language], but to bear testimony and have investigators feel of the Spirit is what really matters.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p17" pid="woAXY3EhaEqWgapz2m6-Bg" hash="xeRCmQ">Permit me to share an experience which I believe illustrates further this edifying process.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p18" pid="pSf4bYy3N0GbAyEShZJung" hash="4HXgew">A few years ago, some missionaries referred me to a lovely couple to whom they had been teaching the gospel. These people had been taught a number of lessons and had attended church on several occasions. But they were having some difficulty in recognizing a developing testimony.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p19" pid="f9qq6RXoukiL-ydQH2Lxww" hash="QtEGqw">After some silent praying, I was impressed to ask the husband, “Was prayer an important part of your life before you met the missionaries?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p20" pid="L8KJxxeMmEWrQFOkOpz-fw" hash="UPEYvA">“No,” he replied. “Until recently I seldom prayed.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p21" pid="pqOSBbff2EO3KOEVkUc9bA" hash="X0Yw9A">I then inquired, “Do you pray now?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p22" pid="52nlEqSTE0y7f-sZQn9vOQ" hash="iKVezg">“Oh yes,” he said. “We pray all the time. We bless the food before each meal; we have family prayers; and I pray frequently about my work.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p23" pid="ki5zgasi80Gs3_3eWF-O0g" hash="Pi3HVQ">I commended him for cultivating this habit and invited him to read with me this scripture: “For if ye would hearken unto the Spirit which teacheth a man to pray ye would know that ye must pray; for the evil spirit teacheth not a man to pray.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/32.8" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 32:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p24" pid="Mw2l7AF9p0GVgJhI9j5R4Q" hash="N7wT4g">My friend quickly admitted that he had been listening to the right spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p25" pid="14VO40tzA0u97jeHrz_wxA" hash="dENRew">I then asked the investigator about his knowledge of Christ’s teachings, and without hesitation he explained that before his contact with the missionaries his knowledge was very limited. He seemed eager, however, to let me know that the missionaries had taught him some significant things, including the plan of salvation. Once more, I invited him to read with me: “Now, we will compare the word unto a seed. … If ye give place, that a seed may be planted in your heart, behold, if it be a true seed, or a good seed, if ye do not cast it out by your unbelief, that ye will resist the Spirit of the Lord, behold, it will begin to swell within your breasts; and when you feel these swelling motions, ye will begin to say within yourselves—It must needs be that this is a good seed, or that the word is good, for it beginneth to enlarge my soul; yea, it beginneth to enlighten my understanding.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.28" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p26" pid="TQj7Xb6vAUaK7F_Hzrq6uA" hash="oG_Iyw">It required little persuasion for my friend to acknowledge that the word was true and good, and that he had felt the Spirit of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p27" pid="jDj3T6xgkkKsrPf9Ur9GrA" hash="5DKksQ">The third question I directed to his wife. It was: “What kind of companion and father was your husband prior to meeting the missionaries?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p28" pid="u_y3ymVnP0et9fqby9iR-Q" hash="1yA8RA">Somewhat reluctantly she answered, “He could have been better—he had a tendency to take me for granted and to neglect the children.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p29" pid="R6Ou2uzapUSPyX4txuvsag" hash="CZdeRw">I expressed thanks for her honest answer and suggested that we read together the following: “But he that believeth these things which I have spoken, him will I visit with the manifestations of my Spirit. … For because of my Spirit he shall know that these things are true; for it persuadeth men to do good.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/4.11" class="scriptureRef">Ether 4:11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p30" pid="GvV0P2ZLFkCkm4XVdearJA" hash="ESbHsw">She, too, was willing to testify that a new spirit had entered their home and that this same spirit had changed her husband’s life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p31" pid="lPS75_6gZkyY63ElZ-XsBQ" hash="xwEwQw">Finally, I spoke again to the man and asked about his faith in Christ. He confessed that before his meetings with the missionaries, his faith had wavered and that he had entertained serious doubts concerning the Savior. He pointed out that recently his faith had been strengthened because of the teachings and testimonies of the missionaries. I then requested that we read: “For behold, the Spirit of Christ is given to every man, that he may know good from evil; wherefore, I show unto you the way to judge; for everything which inviteth to do good, and to persuade to believe in Christ, is sent forth by the power and gift of Christ; wherefore ye may know with a perfect knowledge it is of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.16" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p32" pid="yw3DCsQRpUq70RbYYiCVgA" hash="9e8_jQ">Our discussion concluded with an open acknowledgment by my investigator friends that a new and precious spirit had entered their lives. The influence of prayer, the expanded knowledge, the tendency toward goodness, and the rediscovered faith had given them a new perspective and a new purpose for living.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p33" pid="KCFaRJijJUS7M3-iQm7NOw" hash="r-ZbCw">And, as the teacher in this case, I also benefited from the experience. My heart burned within me as I realized that the Spirit had assisted me in recalling relevant scriptures and had prompted me in determining what to say.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p34" pid="6qPG0OVMuEW0omFnQ1etvg" hash="YASzYA">I can attest that there is a lifting spirit associated with missionary service. I’m convinced that each time we walk our roads to Emmaus with nonmember friends, talking and opening up the scriptures to them, our eyes are opened to added truths and our hearts burn brighter. I’m convinced that each time we extend the right hand to the lame in body and spirit at our gates Beautiful and lift people up, we walk a little straighter and praise God with greater fervor. I’m convinced that each time we visit our Jacob’s wells and invite friends to drink of living waters, our thirst is quenched and we draw closer to the Savior of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p35" pid="cCmhXznZokmxxEyd6zxsTQ" hash="1b_YGA">Last week I boarded a plane to attend a stake conference in the East. My spirit was sagging and my mood less than desirable. I took my assigned seat, opened my briefcase, and began to work on some materials which were quite pressing. The seat adjacent to mine was vacant, and I found myself hoping that it would not be taken. I wanted to travel undisturbed by conversation and other distractions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p36" pid="jn8uLNqyQkK8fTkxAbz65g" hash="wF5vvQ">Just before the boarding gate was closed, a very hairy and unkempt young man rushed through the door and took the only remaining seat—the one next to mine. I must admit that this annoyed me. He appeared worldly, smelled worldly, and seemed eager for conversation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p37" pid="ihuP9Yh50EuWEceGyr80aA" hash="u04_Ng">I ignored him and continued with my writing. A short distance into the air, my unwelcomed traveling companion turned to me and said, “I feel that I offend you, and I want to make an explanation.” He continued, “I’m from Canada, and I’ve been attending a mechanics seminar in Utah. The seminar concluded with a workshop, and I’ve been deep in grease and grime all day. And as you can see and smell, I didn’t have time to shower or change clothes before catching the plane. I hope you will forgive me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p38" pid="7SlIRO11tEKfXZvF-CnZLg" hash="bRA5ag">Oh, how ashamed I was! Ashamed that I had been so selfish; ashamed that I had prejudged.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p39" pid="x2vHVJIXhEqnYgfJu7mplw" hash="GJbK5A">I repented of my feelings and apologized for my thoughts. Then, after a brief introduction, a beautiful gospel conversation ensued. Before we landed in Chicago, we were reading the scriptures together and conversing like old friends. We parted with a warm handshake and the promise that he would receive our missionaries.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p40" pid="i8Xq4RckrUuIp8CKPYIElw" hash="_-52rA">I relate this experience to remind myself and you that when we live outside ourselves and attempt to share the gospel, we invite the presence of a beautiful spirit—a spirit which accompanies fervent testimony, scripture reading, and a genuine concern for the souls of men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p41" pid="LpSY1ZOx-kS3M2_SuWaU0g" hash="bODJeA">Yes, if I were granted one wish, it would be that people everywhere—member, nonmember, missionaries, and friends alike—would feel and enjoy the missionary spirit. Would that all of us felt as Alma and had the yearning desire to cry, “O that I were an angel, and could have the wish of mine heart, that I might go forth and speak with the trump of God, with a voice to shake the earth, and cry repentance unto every people!” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/29.1" class="scriptureRef">Alma 29:1</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work.p42" pid="tLaz5wRbxkib0Fz7zxX_KA" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/10/the-spirit-of-missionary-work</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1976-general-conference/1976-10-3030-elder-carlos-e-asay-64k-eng.mp3" length="6781729" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 1976 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Look to God and Live”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I knew of a man who never looked up; consequently, he never lived—he just existed. Over a period of years this man became a slave to alcohol. Drink by drink he accumulated all the miserable habits and characteristics of a drunkard. He walked the stre</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03102_000_026" doc-version="2" hash="Pqwv5g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="r0-d6op98kukDOikActxZw" hash="j326qA">“Look to God and Live”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ec4Cc6Xvh0C_bo5rw9Px4Q" hash="pDE4zw">Carlos E. Asay</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-29c2.jpg" alt="Elder Carlos E. Asay" pid="wFPpannpGUC65DrS-61Slw" hash="8VRGKQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p1" pid="82Y-wGHl2USDbNbgjks-Vw" hash="apQDBA">I knew of a man who never looked up; consequently, he never lived—he just existed. Over a period of years this man became a slave to alcohol. Drink by drink he accumulated all the miserable habits and characteristics of a drunkard. He walked the streets in a stupor of mind and with an unsteady step. When greeted by friends passing by, his response was a feeble wave of the hand or an almost inaudible grunt. Physically, he was a wreck.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p2" pid="yl8TaTAY3UmdYVWpayo9Fg" hash="gG6daw">To avoid people and conversation, this alcoholic would stagger off the path or into the gutter, for that was the direction of his look. He seemed oblivious to the people, the things, and the events around him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p3" pid="HazsdmYlgUG56dVnqGi47g" hash="R7OSKA">Many pitied this man who had lost health, pride, purpose, family love, and other blessings. They observed his shackled condition but did little or nothing to remove or help him remove the shackles. Others, without compassion ridiculed him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p4" pid="2aZvqJUDs0O_fpXuN09tFA" hash="dzjQ3w">After many years of suffering, some unselfish people helped this man work a miracle. These friends invested countless hours of loving care, much kindly persuasion, many fervent prayers, and all else required to reform the man. In the process of repentance, (1) he allowed the written word of God to nourish his impoverished soul; (2) he fixed his eyes upon a living prophet and tuned his ears to the prophet’s teachings; and (3) he also rekindled faith in himself by exercising faith in Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p5" pid="buujxpkuz0Cf2Q8Pot7l_g" hash="MQC1Vg">In time he gained the confidence and strength to walk with steady stride on the sidewalk. He was successful in breaking Satan’s bonds. He straightened his shoulders, looked people in the eye, and began to converse with others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p6" pid="_n3bOt75NEKBQ6moBvhdqQ" hash="gRLdzg">More important, he assumed his rightful role as a loved husband and respected father. I’m told that when this man—this new man—stood in church and bore his testimony, he expressed these thoughts:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p7" pid="kn0GrzD5_EyaPShGm9o5dg" hash="Gu8ilw">“You’ll never know how wonderful it is to recognize people by the smiles on their faces rather than the dust on their shoes.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p8" pid="jcZ1bNGgrkCL-ISS_xQNlw" hash="IhjQhQ">“You’ll never know how wonderful it is to gaze upward at a blue sky rather than downward at darkened ground.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p9" pid="66Cj6BVP70-8LPIYh1RKwQ" hash="QRTjDA">“You’ll never know how wonderful it is to return home from work and have your children run toward you with love, rather than away from you with fear.”</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="8Pf7vqNVo06FN2Kg4-kCCA" hash="RFusuw">No Isolated Case</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p10" pid="wuKSQP6z9UuVcJZsE1Tyxg" hash="SAHGjA">I have not described an isolated or bizarre case. The story which I have shared with you, without the happy ending, is common. Every day men, women, and youth around us are permitting strong drink and other forms of sin to drag them down and to bend their look. How terribly wrong and serious it is when men allow themselves to become burdened with sin and error and are rendered unable to look up and live! On the other hand, how wonderful it is:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p11" pid="IjF8sBoNnUGgxNcdBdJvpQ" hash="RrqefQ">—When men look to God through the scriptures and allow divine truths to nourish their souls.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p12" pid="vpfnk1vsc0GnNHamBYLElQ" hash="SRLYrA">—When men look to God through a living prophet and permit the counsel of an inspired man to guide their steps.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p13" pid="lgbRJwXHzUKXKt977PAAwQ" hash="AQWS9Q">—When men look to Christ and place themselves in a position to claim the blessings of his atonement.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="XW0kKymaQkOjAvrmdSra6w" hash="y2d4Qw">Hear the Voice of God</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p14" pid="AEMjA32lmEGCM9m9ZpF6WQ" hash="N2y63w">Some years ago I supervised a young man who was having difficulty in understanding and appreciating his church assignment. I tried very hard to point out the importance of his duties. I also appealed to his sense of honor. The conversation seemed to have little effect upon my listener. Finally, after some inner strugglings, I asked: “What will it take to convince you that you must successfully complete your calling?” He did not answer. So I added: “Are you waiting to see a burning bush? to receive an angelic visitation? or to hear a voice directly from heaven?”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p15" pid="p0ygmEZAm0e2pvJWxlkzYw" hash="HKjHlA">His response was immediate: “That’s what I need. I need to hear the voice of God.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p16" pid="qRwsxPsU6UmM44NFDScW7w" hash="A3MRZw">At first I wondered if the young man was serious. However, the look on his face and the tone of his voice convinced me that he was. I then invited him to read with me this scripture: “And I, Jesus Christ, your Lord and your God, have spoken it.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p17" pid="odjfFa0_TkWJUNh1hFrB9A" hash="c5wi1g">“These words are not of men nor of man, but of me; wherefore, you shall testify they are of me and not of man;</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p18" pid="08T6W8o7AUWRSbEqVulFpw" hash="-bfXUA">“For it is my voice which speaketh them unto you; for they are given by my Spirit unto you, and by my power you can read them one to another; and save it were by my power you could not have them;</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p19" pid="r5bgWa7QOkCXvQ02mmCaaw" hash="p3zG5A">“Wherefore, you can testify that you have heard my voice, and know my words.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.33-36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:33–36</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p20" pid="yG5hQb4OYkO2jFHQ0rdwBw" hash="iycAPA">My associate began to understand that the scriptures are the will, the mind, the word, and the voice of the Lord. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:4</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p21" pid="Rwa_wh2V6kajuN6TVqg8_w" hash="xr_fOw">I encouraged the young man to look to God through the scriptures. I requested that he regard his daily study period as a personal interview with the Lord. And I made the promise that he would find purpose and enthusiasm for his calling—if he was faithful in his reading and pondering of the scriptures.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="TlT9aTOSn02L_op-RQBkUA" hash="MdTlAQ">Words of Christ—a Compass</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p22" pid="lbm5ifE2tka8ZO8OL_e7hw" hash="5557JA">In the Book of Mormon we read of a people who had an instrument called a ball or director. This compasslike instrument was prepared by the Lord and worked according to the people’s faith in God. When they were righteous and exercised faith, the spindles would point the way they should go. When their faith or diligence in keeping the commandments was lacking, the instrument would not work. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/16.title" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 16</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/18.12" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 18:12</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p23" pid="tuNFwqit-kGS7x-nB7jh3w" hash="KJF4jg">One writer stated that the compass and its operation was “not without a shadow” or type of things spiritual. He wrote:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p24" pid="6Fv5k0jzCEOrhrv9iyayPA" hash="SuujMQ">“For behold, it is as easy to give heed to the word of Christ, which will point to you a straight course to eternal bliss, as it was for our fathers to give heed to this compass, which would point unto them a straight course to the promised land.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p25" pid="bOzXDK_2QESQPHKOOjM0cQ" hash="ITUXvg">“And now I say, is there not a type in this thing? For just as surely as this director did bring our fathers, by following its course, to the promised land, shall the words of Christ, if we follow their course, carry us beyond this vale of sorrow into a far better land of promise.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p26" pid="fBMhaa1WV0Wi0yzhGIQIzQ" hash="Vw5Gsw">“… do not let us be slothful because of the easiness of the way; for so was it with our fathers; for so was it prepared for them, that if they would look they might live; even so it is with us. The way is prepared, and if we will look we may live forever.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p27" pid="na3ICL5fEUic-vX5m8i-lA" hash="DGwdpw">“… see that ye look to God and live.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.43-47" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:43–47</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p28" pid="GnT2zwWrkUCDXGtNlhww0Q" hash="7WxlWw">I fear that many of us rush about from day to day taking for granted the holy scriptures. We scramble to honor appointments with physicians, lawyers, and businessmen. Yet we think nothing of postponing interviews with Deity—postponing scripture study. Little wonder we develop anemic souls and lose our direction in living. How much better it would be if we planned and held sacred fifteen or twenty minutes a day for reading the scriptures. Such interviews with Deity would help us recognize his voice and enable us to receive guidance in all of our affairs.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p29" pid="zIO9Hab0iUuan1gg955Tgw" hash="N9BK4w">We must look to God through the scriptures.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="kUoT2Ce2CECQsFR6cUE1WQ" hash="mjgi4A">Conversion Story</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p30" pid="Nj3eUCRxf0C06IsvkphZGg" hash="BkGRPg">Near the turn of the century two missionaries approached a mountain village in one of the Hawaiian Islands. A man standing near his hut saw them coming and said to his children who stood nearby, “Run down the hill and tell those men to go back. We are not interested in what they are preaching.” The children obeyed their father.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p31" pid="xX4fX2JF2kaQVq-XUBFmtA" hash="bU6fsw">The missionaries, however, continued up the hill. Upon reaching the crest, they walked to the father and said, “We do not mean to be rude. But we have traveled many miles to tell you that there is a living prophet on the earth today.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p32" pid="Ex738XLBeU68qvCALcFSRQ" hash="cOnGag">A look of excitement swept over the man’s face. “What did you say?” he asked.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p33" pid="CSE8GLHCGEWmOCjgb4SCMA" hash="8JscOg">The missionaries repeated their testimony: “There is a living prophet on the earth today, and we want to share with you his message.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p34" pid="T1H--4wt7EedKDoy3TMo-g" hash="5DsgWg">Turning to his children, the man exclaimed, “Quickly, run and get mother, and call together your brothers and sisters. Tell them that there is a living prophet.” A short time later this family accepted the gospel and was baptized. (Related to Elder Asay by Tom Kaleo of Hawaii, about his own father.)</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.t6">
        <h3 class="title" pid="bdFz_s0gakSO3lxvZIYl7Q" hash="ulhBxQ">Role of Prophets</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p35" pid="OrB7eUIRZUamsJjw9MnIaA" hash="Zi0rLQ">Since ancient times the Lord has made his will known through prophets. Such men are specially prepared and called to receive and teach truth. It is their mission to serve as God’s mouthpiece.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p36" pid="0hBYLwVfRUqP8J_F_Z4p6g" hash="6DUTOg">Amos declared: “Surely the Lord God will do nothing, but he revealeth his secret unto his servants the prophets” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/amos/3.7" class="scriptureRef">Amos 3:7</a>). Was Amos speaking only of his day and age? Of course not. He knew that God is no respecter of persons. He knew that God’s love for his children is the same in all generations. He knew the need for continuing revelation.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p37" pid="W9UR_zFPGUOKornS-eraSg" hash="bMxsMA">Through a modern prophet these words were spoken:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p38" pid="S0RWMRdVDUW01yewDIqqhA" hash="BaM6XQ">“Wherefore the voice of the Lord is unto the ends of the earth. …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p39" pid="eP5ovJ4KIk-yAtAeIhC_9w" hash="a1j7wA">“And the day cometh that they who will not hear the voice of the Lord, neither the voice of his servants, neither give heed to the words of the prophets and apostles, shall be cut off from among the people.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.11,14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:11, 14</a>.)</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.t7">
        <h3 class="title" pid="9ymDXvD0VUGch3s2ud8ZwQ" hash="OV2cOg">Marching Orders</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p40" pid="G9uUK2W35E--sHmoEHg3XA" hash="hLb7Ng">How foolish it is to suppose that an army can march or fight effectively without instructions from the commanding officer. How inconsistent it is to think that yesterday’s strategies and maneuvers will win today’s battles. It may be true that the principles of warfare remain somewhat unchanged from one generation to another; however, weapons change, battlefields differ, the foe becomes wiser, and many other conditions develop which require continuous commands from the leader.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p41" pid="DHOxb_EKXUGVgEPhDkMffw" hash="P3QYTw">Christ, as the head of his Church and general of his royal army, has in times past and will in times future call the cadence for his loyal followers. He gives the commands to move forward through his prophet leaders; he gives the commands to halt through his prophet leaders. Eventually, victory will be the prize of those faithful soldiers who heed his instructions and remain steadfast within the ranks.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p42" pid="IgBelymZv0mqE1ZVNP4EaQ" hash="K2NIIg">We thank God for a living prophet. And we sing praises to the heavens for the privilege of receiving through that prophet commands and counsel fitted to meet our eternal needs.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p43" pid="ORxSowKyf0yIWMcNXDTw3g" hash="tPPsJQ">Oh, how we have need to look to God through his living prophet and live.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.t8">
        <h3 class="title" pid="Eg8ujxiyDkuQejINzWFGsA" hash="m8keJA">Fiery Serpents</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p44" pid="todDblWyxEq19gDY_WL4cg" hash="UAjvdg">As the children of Israel journeyed in the wilderness toward the land of Edom, they became discouraged and spoke against God and Moses, their leader. So “the Lord sent fiery serpents among the people,” and they bit the complainers and many died. In time, the people recognized their folly and pleaded with Moses, saying: “We have sinned … against the Lord, and against thee; pray unto the Lord, that he take away the serpents from us” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/num/21.6-7" class="scriptureRef">Num. 21:6–7</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p45" pid="G7lspEV-x0yf8ok9DqdB6Q" hash="g2_56w">Moses did pray in behalf of his followers, and in answer to his prayer the Lord instructed: “Make thee a fiery serpent, and set it upon a pole: and it shall come to pass, that every one that is bitten, when he looketh upon it, shall live” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/num/21.8" class="scriptureRef">Num. 21:8</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p46" pid="5LNQP7mOrE6McHf9uGqGfw" hash="iA8gaA">Moses again did as the Lord instructed.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p47" pid="mLt7hpb3ckqraCK5hOMxtw" hash="7wDBhg">Left at this point, one wonders what happened. How many were obedient? How many were not? Did anyone look and live? Answers to these questions are found in the Book of Mormon. One prophet explained: “He [the Lord] sent fiery flying serpents among them; and after they were bitten he prepared a way that they might be healed; and the labor which they had to perform was to look; and because of the simpleness of the way, or the easiness of it, there were many who perished” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.41" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:41</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p48" pid="UsJzYT72D0ODJrUZPHUH2g" hash="HbLXQw">The type raised up in the wilderness, the serpent on the pole, symbolized Christ upon the cross. Jesus himself taught this truth. Many times he forecast his cruel form of death; and on at least one occasion, he made reference to Moses and the wilderness incident. Note these words of the Master:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p49" pid="7NzYPnKh_EuvHFpZJuzNAw" hash="X8-34w">“And as Moses lifted up the serpent in the wilderness, even so must the Son of man be lifted up:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p50" pid="LKzm78Wn8kC7fYZ9YVjHIQ" hash="B1aMtg">“That whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have eternal life” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.14-15" class="scriptureRef">John 3:14–15</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p51" pid="1rTEIkdVC0-OkCIYaU25dA" hash="sGhD8w">We, like Israel of old, must rivet our eyes and minds upon the cross of Christ if we hope to gain eternal life, because through his resurrection we will gain the victory over physical death. And his atonement opens up to us a way to overcome our sins, a way to spiritual rebirth, and a way back to the presence of God.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p52" pid="mMRO-MD5jk2OlM_R6abXuQ" hash="JdITJA">Oh, how we must look to Christ and live.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p53" pid="PMV-qAgcCEmTKiFwoGYEsA" hash="d7tH1w">The direction of our look is critical. From the rooftop King David “saw a woman washing herself; and the woman was very beautiful to look upon” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/2-sam/11.2" class="scriptureRef">2 Sam. 11:2</a>). He looked across the way, and his heart was filled with lust. He looked; he fell.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p54" pid="g8eFtz48ZE2rQxtSsb_kGw" hash="zjKg6g">Judas Iscariot fixed his eye upon thirty pieces of silver. Greed overcame his righteous desires. His misplaced look cost his life, his soul, and the thirty coins. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/27.3-10" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 27:3–10</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p55" pid="tB5MZYTnCEC9LwD7a_9KuA" hash="L9KOPw">Our looks must not be allowed to wander across the way or to become fixed upon the perishable things of the world. The eye, “the light of the body” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.22" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 6:22</a>), must be trained to look upward. We must look to God and live!</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p56" pid="nzSk4rkCXkCAqecPPpVJLg" hash="eaZ7bw">We invite all men everywhere—the young, the older, the rising generation—</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p57" pid="k0NJirFNYEqZJBlS7SZ9kw" hash="ieNcbA">To look to God through the scriptures, for they testify of him;</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p58" pid="8PBREkFsmkOTC_PmX5cgLA" hash="acddMQ">To look to God through a living prophet, for he teaches us of that God whom President Tanner spoke about. We testify and invite people to look to Christ.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live.p59" pid="lB_7qGxB7E-Us3vUA_c-VQ" hash="9xXuwg">I testify that we can hear the voice of Deity through the scriptures; I testify that there is a living prophet among us; and I testify that Christ is the name whereby salvation is extended to all of us. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1978/10/look-to-god-and-live</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1978-general-conference/1978-10-4030-elder-carlos-e-asay-64k-eng.mp3" length="7235308" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 1978 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salt of the Earth: Savor of Men and Saviors of Men</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I hold in my hand a test tube filled with salt. Salt, as you know, contains two elements—sodium and chlorine—and is known chemically as sodium chloride.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03122_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="dnQhpQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="6cOufaPQuU6D3jZNVMht_g" hash="yf8SAg">Salt of the Earth:</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="kir91w60bUOMqDTpmH8c_g" hash="_zghJw">Savor of Men and Saviors of Men</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="cqIRKysS1E-SOynK5mrjnw" hash="pDE4zw">Carlos E. Asay</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-29c2.jpg" alt="Elder Carlos E. Asay" pid="ktFkxxjJvEq6YAwt0ImSyg" hash="8VRGKQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p1" pid="vd8-H3-Bc0-WKM8aY1HfVA" hash="hWAdTA">I hold in my hand a test tube filled with salt. Salt, as you know, contains two elements—sodium and chlorine—and is known chemically as sodium chloride.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p2" pid="8ljjwoNUaU6neCqs8Yz36g" hash="X-Zung">This white substance occupies an important place in our lives. It is essential to health; body cells must have salt in order to live and work. It has antiseptic, or germ-killing, properties. It is a preservative. It is an ingredient in many foods and products. And it is estimated that there are more than fourteen thousand uses for salt.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p3" pid="6BdEs4fTcE6PkXm2eGsPUg" hash="U4UFBg">According to the historians, “Salt at one time had religious significance, and was a symbol of purity. … Among many peoples, salt is still used as a sign of honor, friendship and hospitality. The Arabs say ‘there is salt between us,’ meaning ‘we have eaten together, and are friends’” (<span class="emphasis">The World Book Encyclopedia,</span> 1978, 17:69).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p4" pid="SHsVOCGpVU2yLk4u-eIA5w" hash="kq3A_A">The Organizer and Creator of this world understood perfectly the nature and importance of salt. More than thirty-five references to this substance are found in the scriptures. In the Old Testament mention is made of a “covenant of salt” (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/lev/2.13" class="scriptureRef">Lev. 2:13</a>; <a href="/scriptures/ot/num/18.19" class="scriptureRef">Num. 18:19</a>; <a href="/scriptures/ot/2-chr/13.5" class="scriptureRef">2 Chr. 13:5</a>). In the New Testament the Savior referred to his disciples as the “salt of the earth,” and charged them to retain their savor (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.13" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:13</a>). He repeated this charge to his chosen disciples on the American continent:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p5" pid="isSYHrKPTkaY-0UzzOpgVQ" hash="jSI_Vw">“Verily, verily, I say unto you, I give unto you to be the salt of the earth; but if the salt shall lose its savor, wherewith shall the earth be salted? The salt shall be thenceforth good for nothing, but to be cast out and to be trodden under foot of men” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/12.13" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 12:13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p6" pid="xHZ-s-r7Z06jEFnaZo4J6Q" hash="QpdMAw">How many times have we read, or heard others read, this scripture? Yet, do we understand fully the “salt of the earth” message? Are we conversant with the analogy? Are we responding properly to its implications?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p7" pid="HV99DO-Sz06EoaVU7Pr4Rg" hash="jjdwCw">Permit me to speak of the “savor” and “savior” roles which we have been called to fulfill as members of the priesthood and as the salt of the modern world.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="Tc-hAukvLECMT8Afwva-Xg" hash="41Fr8w">Savor of men</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p8" pid="dJFTeqsUZEGoOUeZ_9GVVg" hash="fHPPtA">In 1833 Joseph Smith received a revelation which included these instructions: “When men are called into mine everlasting gospel, and covenant with an everlasting covenant, they are accounted as the salt of the earth and the savor of men;</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p9" pid="SA9mlJtRCEm7W3524gLpAA" hash="xGuX3A">
          <span class="emphasis">“They are called to be the savor of men” </span>(<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/101.39-40" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 101:39–40</a>; italics added).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p10" pid="Y7QDQP7X1E-l4jdrG7PKWQ" hash="sekzlQ">The word <span class="emphasis">savor </span>(<span class="emphasis">s-a-v-o-r</span>) denotes taste, pleasing flavor, interesting quality, and high repute.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p11" pid="54-iXrMh10KeCT62d1uapw" hash="9cpg4Q">The salt in container A, which I am holding in my right hand, has savor. That is, it is clean, pure, uncontaminated, and useful. In this state or condition, salt will preserve, flavor, heal, and perform other useful functions.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p12" pid="rHDzMYs7V0CHZ1clua-IaA" hash="JwBNeA">The salt in container B, however, is salt that has lost its savor. It has lost its savor because it has been mixed with things of bad taste. In fact, it has taken on some of the color and appearance of other substances.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p13" pid="cIyYAXzA80Gv8t5ljuRcMQ" hash="FifYZw">When the Lord used the expression “savor of men,” he was speaking of those who represent him. He was referring to those who have repented, who have been washed clean in the waters of baptism, and who have covenanted to take upon them his name and his cause. Moreover, he was speaking of those who would share by covenant his priesthood power. He was speaking of you and me.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p14" pid="oN7A5DPsFUOeYP6sx3VaGQ" hash="gdVoBQ">A world-renowned chemist told me that salt will not lose its savor with age. Savor is lost through mixture and contamination. Similarly, priesthood power does not dissipate with age; it, too, is lost through mixture and contamination.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p15" pid="KT4B38Ur0kSE2I4HGATeiw" hash="6B7qWQ">When a young man or older man mixes his thoughts with pornographic literature, he suffers a loss of savor.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p16" pid="WVi6jVF3jk--pyCf_SjZ-g" hash="kSJxgA">When a priesthood bearer mixes his speech with lies or profanity, he suffers a loss of savor.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p17" pid="Nn47PlB6_UOxHti881LUqg" hash="sTACVQ">When one of us follows the crowd and becomes involved in immoral acts and the use of drugs, tobacco, alcohol, and other injurious substances, he loses savor.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p18" pid="NMlWAfmr9kugy_ZQ1xZ0wg" hash="9UWzfg">Flavor and quality flee a man when he contaminates his mind with unclean thoughts, desecrates his mouth by speaking less than the truth, and misapplies his strength in performing evil acts. King Benjamin cautioned, “Watch yourselves, and your thoughts, and your words, and your deeds, and observe the commandments of God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.30" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:30</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p19" pid="850Mei1NvEmf685j-0p-nw" hash="DP3smQ">I would offer these simple guidelines, especially to the young men, as the means to preserve one’s savor: If it is not <span class="emphasis">clean,</span> do not think it; if it is not <span class="emphasis">true,</span> do not speak it; if it is not <span class="emphasis">good,</span> do not do it (see Marcus Aurelius, “The Meditations of Marcus Aurelius,” in <span class="emphasis">The Harvard Classics,</span> Charles W. Eliot, ed., New York: P. F. Collier and Son, 1909, p. 211).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p20" pid="nXO2Uie7ZUeMmxV04oue6w" hash="Lh4wkg">Cleanliness, truth, and goodness have always been and will ever be the watchwords of men with savor. It is said that sixty-five percent or more of our communications are non verbal. If this is so, who we are and what we are is most important. A living prophet has declared: “No greater service can be given to the missionary calling of the Church than to exemplify positive Christian virtues in our lives” (Spencer W. Kimball, <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1978, p. 6).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p21" pid="wNhrq-ZDOUi74NFy7y5JVQ" hash="ECMA2w">We must fight daily to retain our savor, our purity. We must press forward, clinging to our standards of holiness, remembering all the while that we are called to be the savor of men.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="hss6Lxehg02Pwx6-8BKrdg" hash="YoDM6Q">Saviors of men</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p22" pid="7-KugvtHrEyr3EFuK2D8jA" hash="3nE26g">The Prophet Joseph Smith received these instructions from the Lord:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p23" pid="CpZaKAdxH0eEmtLU-_KsHQ" hash="Vu8fmg">“For they were set to be a light unto the world, and <span class="emphasis">to be the saviors of men;</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p24" pid="64i-HfjjR0u50fk4p4M_6w" hash="MjPEUg">“And inasmuch as they are not the saviors of men, they are as salt that has lost its savor” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/103.9-10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 103:9–10</a>; italics added).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p25" pid="wroAmoSxkEKDriTJTlrSFg" hash="IpW_iw">One is impressed with the depth of meaning associated with the words “saviors of men,” when they are studied in companionship with a complete definition of the priesthood: “The priesthood is the power and authority of God delegated to man on earth to act in all things pertaining to the salvation of men. It is the means whereby the Lord acts through men to save souls” (Spencer W. Kimball, <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> June 1975, p. 3).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p26" pid="xzmar52l5Umm9JS3b0GsSw" hash="Gd46aQ">Priesthood is God’s power. It is to be used in saving souls. It is not shared with young men or older men simply to sit on or to hold in name only. It is shared with the expectation that the receiver will exercise it in behalf of himself and others. The priesthood is to be honored, and callings within the priesthood are to be magnified.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p27" pid="HrMQHIi0OkqDG8hwVI5HJw" hash="hTuWnA">One of the grandest concepts in the gospel of Jesus Christ is the concept that men can and should be more than passive observers in the cause of saving souls. One Church leader taught: “In our preexistent state … we made a certain agreement with the Almighty. … We agreed … to be not only saviors for ourselves but measurably, saviors for the whole human family. We went into a partnership with the Lord. The working out of the plan became then not merely the Father’s work, and the Savior’s work, but also our work” (John A. Widtsoe, <span class="emphasis">Utah Genealogical and Historical Magazine,</span> Oct. 1934, p. 189).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p28" pid="mt-QTC9BmEaQjQq0y5xwDQ" hash="46NqgA">I know of a young priest who was asked by his bishop to fellowship an inactive quorum member. The bishop indicated that others had failed in their attempts to recover the boy. The final words of the bishop’s commission were: “Please save _________.” After many tries and failures, the miracle was wrought—the inactive returned to full activity in the quorum. It was thrilling for me to hear the hero in this experience bear testimony of the joy which he received as a result of his soul-saving efforts.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p29" pid="oQtqI2evQk60u7LjvM-bSQ" hash="dDG1Pw">Less than a month ago, two missionaries visited a widowed lady who had expressed interest in the Church. She was ill and had been advised by her physician that a kidney was to be removed. The elders comforted the woman, heeded the whisperings of the Spirit, and pronounced a blessing. Another miracle happened. The operation was cancelled, and the missionaries began teaching their friend the gospel. A baptismal date has already been set. This particular woman will never forget the blessing and teachings of the elders. They will be held in cherished memory and regarded as “saviors of men.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p30" pid="G4loCumWPE6ioVV1nJeIBw" hash="6spnVg">One of our priesthood brothers tells of how he was guided by the Spirit in locating thousands of names on one of his father’s ancestral lines. When the necessary research was completed, he and his wife and others completed the appropriate temple ordinances. In summarizing his experience, he said:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p31" pid="ur-P8Af1kUCgjI4lUMLlcw" hash="3EJeTg">“It taught me that if a person will put forth the effort to search, the way will be opened up and he will obtain the spirit of Elijah. …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p32" pid="ZHEJegkT3UKv5OylIB_7qg" hash="SsF0JA">“I firmly believe that in the preexistence we made a commitment … to be a savior to these people, doing all the necessary research and having the temple work done for them” (Jacob Suess, “Twice Rescued,” in <span class="emphasis">Links of Forever,</span> comp. by Connie Rector and Diane Deputy, Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1977, p. 120).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p33" pid="Okfvj6YKXEegU9gS2TWQfw" hash="bbvO-A">There should be salt between us and all men. We should extend honor, friendship, and hospitality to all of our brothers and sisters. To the inactives we extend the hand of fellowship; to the nonmembers we extend the divine invitation “come and see”; with the fathers of yesteryear we establish links which weld fathers to children and children to fathers. In all of this, we advance the purposes of the Master and assist in the reconciliation of men to the God who gave them life. And, in the process, we not only preserve our savor but we save ourselves.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p34" pid="nbc-cjbqeU2-A1PoFtK30g" hash="Yz5e_A">I count it significant that the headquarters of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is located in <span class="emphasis">Salt</span> Lake City. From this center of the Church flows the message of salvation to all the world. To this city of salt, men and women gather from all corners of the earth to receive instruction and edification. Such instruction, if accepted and practiced, will enable men to retain their <span class="emphasis">savor</span> and assist them in becoming <span class="emphasis">saviors of men.</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p35" pid="4KWyYbIJvU6uqELaG3rNOA" hash="-xOseQ">I pray that all of us will appreciate more perfectly the words of the Savior: “Ye are the salt of the earth.” I pray that we will carry this designation faithfully and honorably.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p36" pid="fXyp9vT0yUijq4X2nL5lHQ" hash="mkHIUw">Please remember that men—like salt—lose their savor through contamination; remember also that men who fail to use their priesthood power in behalf of others are like salt without savor.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men.p37" pid="FQ0JvqtPFECvD4WoGbAGRw" hash="EmwYkA">I testify that an abiding and exalting relationship with the Master is established as we live to be men with savor and saviors of men. This I declare, adding my witness that He lives and directs his church today, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1980/04/salt-of-the-earth-savor-of-men-and-saviors-of-men</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1980-general-conference/1980-04-3040-elder-carlos-e-asay-64k-eng.mp3" length="5705445" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 1980 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opposition to the Work of God</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god?lang=eng</link>
      <description>While pondering a theme for this conference assignment, I had occasion to conduct some business over the telephone with a member of the Council of the Twelve. In that conversation I asked, “Would you help me select a suitable subject for my conferenc</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03141_000_026" doc-version="2" hash="Go4P8g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="-hHWOV0CMkWhwMF0bTQCHA" hash="N0rvpw">Opposition to the Work of God</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="61craqbl0Uec5Hm7MVps_A" hash="pDE4zw">Carlos E. Asay</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-29c2.jpg" alt="Elder Carlos E. Asay" pid="Gkek6hCrY0WC9FD_y9g5qw" hash="8VRGKQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p1" pid="8SR-pwT3A0SvUOwWS26vkg" hash="rmOvfg">While pondering a theme for this conference assignment, I had occasion to conduct some business over the telephone with a member of the Council of the Twelve. In that conversation I asked, “Would you help me select a suitable subject for my conference assignment?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p2" pid="n_Uq9urQIUaRDbVfhuujWA" hash="Ncokyw">He said, “Yes,” in a very reassuring voice. And then he said, “Carlos, pray.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p3" pid="QdyYvHnWTUmON3ejHiuS_A" hash="ebChUQ">I therefore share with you the results of many prayers, and I do so prayerfully and obediently and very humbly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p4" pid="tJtMlBSenk-vqKG1OoYTPQ" hash="A8Axsg">On November 1, 1857, Elder George A. Smith delivered a memorable discourse, which included this old Chinese fable:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p5" pid="nMDPE62CNkqEc-V8dJi-bQ" hash="sYgvfA">“A man travelling through the country came to a large city, very rich and splendid; he looked at it and said to his guide, ‘This must be a very righteous people, for I can only see but one little devil in this great city.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p6" pid="HEi19yotmUqlxp8AizOnUQ" hash="4PWRWg">“The guide replied, ‘You do not understand, sir. This city is so perfectly given up to wickedness … that it requires but one devil to keep them all in subjection.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p7" pid="JK5pkq1lI0WUv6zFg2_lKQ" hash="_OgnbQ">“Travelling on a little farther, he came to a rugged path and saw an old man trying to get up the hill side, surrounded by seven great, big, coarse-looking devils.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p8" pid="ZG2Lmp6Os0ChKBESpnEhxw" hash="aVnpaw">“‘Why,’ says the traveller, ‘this must be a tremendously wicked old man! See how many devils there are around him!’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p9" pid="KUCbUhA53UiE7pTxsFhYYg" hash="Ei9f6Q">“‘This,’ replied the guide, ‘is the only righteous man in the country; and there are seven of the biggest devils trying to turn him out of his path, and they all cannot do it.’” (<span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses,</span> 5:363–64.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p10" pid="CJS2v-SAw0qgBhRkz6QjHQ" hash="q42y6w">After relating the fable, Elder Smith added that “the devil has the world so perfectly at his disposal that it requires few devils to keep it in subjection” and that “the whole legion of devils has nothing to do but look after the ‘Mormons’ and stir up the hearts of the children of men to destroy them—to put them out of existence.” (<span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses,</span> 5:364.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p11" pid="NiWxwgwElECDOyIh7ySZew" hash="-Dm_ZA">The evil one has attempted on many occasions in all dispensations to put out of existence, if you will, many of God’s children. Sometimes he, himself, has assumed the deluder’s role. Other times he has worked through those who have stepped to his side of the line. For instance, in the Book of Mormon, we read of three anti-Christs. Each was deceived, each preached against those who believed in Christ, and each sought openly to destroy the church of God. Their patterns of deceit were similar. They taught false doctrines, spread lies, referred to prophecies as foolish traditions, accused Church leaders of perverting the right way of God, and baited the people by referring to their faith as a foolish and vain hope. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/7.title" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 7</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/1.title" class="scriptureRef">Alma 1</a>; and <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/30.title" class="scriptureRef">Alma 30</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p12" pid="1bDJS99MYkC9vCNfErzx7w" hash="3JYRWQ">When we read about the anti-Christs of former days, we marvel at how perverted their thinking became and we marvel at how successful they were in deceiving men and women. We also wonder why some of the people were so gullible—so easily misled. And with all this marveling and wondering, we tend to niche the anti-Christs in some corner of ancient history and go about our unguarded ways. This is dangerous. It could result in loss of faith; and, in a spiritual sense, it could put us out of existence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p13" pid="CLuHfFqJ2ECkdkTPIZAyqQ" hash="qaS19Q">Since the spring of 1820, Lucifer has led a relentless attack against the Latter-day Saints and their leaders. A parade of anti-Christs, anti-Mormons, and apostate groups have appeared on the scene. Many are still among us and have released new floods of lies and false accusations. These faith-killers and testimony-thieves use personal contacts, the printed word, electronic media, and other means of communication to sow doubts and to disturb the peace of true believers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p14" pid="2OAtzHEIUE-lmwlq9ZJoeg" hash="-_R6Dw">Two months ago we received a tender letter from a bishop. He informed us that he had been involved in an excommunication of a recent convert. The new convert had fallen under the influence of a very dedicated apostate who was successful in destroying the convert’s testimony. It seems that, to discredit Joseph Smith and subsequent prophets, the apostate cited changes made in Church publications over the years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p15" pid="ch0KUfxORk-hveorb07csg" hash="DTxQxg">The approach used by the apostate is common among those who are more interested in shadows than in light. Their logic, if followed, would have them burning the New Testament because Luke’s account of the gospel is not exactly like Matthew’s or because the book of Acts reports two differing versions of Paul’s vision on the road to Damascus. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/9.1-9" class="scriptureRef">Acts 9:1–9</a> and <a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/22.4-11" class="scriptureRef">Acts 22:4–11</a>.) Belief in modern prophets and continuous revelation is absent in the lives of many apostates. They would pin their hopes for salvation upon things other than those related to living prophets and living faith.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.f2">
	<p pid="RmEWPHs0WkeoeFug15fGig" hash="hBpL6w">The questions follow: How do we respond to such malicious and evil designs? Do we strike back? Allow me to suggest a course of action—one which is in harmony with the teachings of the Savior, and one which, if followed, will be in harmony with the wise counsel of prophets past and present:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="wTzShLXjGUGZFPJJNs9KXA" hash="Z0sGuA">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="YyYooJ2wwUi07t6nvT4w-Q" hash="g4Rc2Q">
            <span class="emphasis">Avoid those who would tear</span>
            <span class="emphasis">down your faith.</span> Faith-killers are to be shunned. The seeds which they plant in the minds and hearts of men grow like cancer and eat away the Spirit. True messengers of God are builders—not destroyers. We send our missionaries into the world to teach and to assist people in receiving truth line upon line until the fulness of the gospel is received. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/98.112" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 98:112</a>.) As one new convert testified: “My previous church provided me the chapter on mortality. The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints added two more chapters pertaining to the premortal and postmortal existences.”</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="QY9v7nAQjEO2r-NB15ayKg" hash="5Q9rVQ">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="fXl4CdqdgEWcEyPWZFdgWw" hash="kL5eJg">
            <span class="emphasis">Keep the commandments.</span> President Brigham Young promised, “All we have to do is to go onward and upward, and keep the commandments of our Father and God; and he will confound our enemies.” (<span class="emphasis">Discourses of Brigham Young,</span> sel. John A. Widtsoe, Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1957, p. 347.) If we obey holy laws, we will take upon ourselves “the whole armour of God” and we will be able to stand against the wiles of the devil. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/6.11-18" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 6:11–18</a>.) Moreover, obedience ensures us of the guidance and protection of the Holy Spirit.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Jd-lVRj0-UqUzh0IssUeJw" hash="qCManA">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="I4G1GKQcJkmoqQp1SaUNxg" hash="DYgfhA">
            <span class="emphasis">Follow the living prophets, as we have just been admonished.</span> One Church leader taught: “Always keep your eye on the President of the Church, and if he ever tells you to do anything, and it is wrong, and you do it, the Lord will bless you for it. … But you don’t need to worry. The Lord will never let his mouthpiece lead the people astray.” (Heber J. Grant, quoted by Marion G. Romney in Conference Report, Oct. 1960, p. 78.) We walk in uncharted mine fields and place our souls in jeopardy when we receive the teachings of anyone except he that is ordained of God. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/43.2-7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 43:2–7</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/52.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 52:9</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="jgpS5lLK3kyBBjfuBv2DPw" hash="kgHCDw">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="pTs02SzYBEmLLdZ9OC-ofQ" hash="N-CoyA">
            <span class="emphasis">Do not contend or debate over points of doctrine.</span> The Master warned that “the spirit of contention is not of me, but is of the devil.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.29" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:29</a>.) We are inconsistent if we resort to Satanic tactics in attempting to achieve righteous ends. Such inconsistency results only in frustration, loss of the Spirit, and ultimate defeat. Remember, “We claim the privilege of worshiping Almighty God according to the dictates of our own conscience, and allow all men the same privilege.” (Eleventh Article of Faith.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="cGHDQVaWV02s9e5VIYWa6Q" hash="YbeAzw">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p pid="pd6jWnGPW0WzLWN5QnJFpA" hash="V48byA">
            <span class="emphasis">Search the scriptures.</span> Few of us would go astray or lose our way if we regarded the scriptures as our personal guide or compass. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.44" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:44</a>.) The iron rod <span class="emphasis">is</span> the word of God, and if held to, we will not fall.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="rlyRhZ49MUSdvPUvpbOhgw" hash="dbkG7A">
          <span class="label">6.</span>
          <p pid="UIKqGXykxUuAHZPmTMubWw" hash="5Xsdzg">
            <span class="emphasis">Do not be swayed or diverted from the mission of the Church.</span> There are those who would draw you off course and cause you to waste time and energies. Satan used a diversion ploy when he tempted Christ in the wilderness. The Savior’s decisive response, “Get thee hence, Satan” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/4.10" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 4:10</a>), is a proper example for all of us.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="lkDkG8hf6UKKn4JFMYWXhQ" hash="pDgirw">
          <span class="label">7.</span>
          <p pid="cBJftUHNzkmGRQFxQLb3mg" hash="ERWblw">
            <span class="emphasis">Pray for your enemies.</span> Christ said to the Nephites, “Love your enemies, bless them that curse you, do good to them that hate you, and pray for them who despitefully use you and persecute you.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/12.44" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 12:44</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.44" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:44</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/12.10-12" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 12:10–12</a>.) While on the cross, the Savior pled, “Father, forgive them; for they know not what they do.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/23.34" class="scriptureRef">Luke 23:34</a>.) There are many who are kept from the truth—not because they don’t want it, but because they know not where to find it.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="brQt9oi_n0GmqKQzDeUuTg" hash="jYC3nA">
          <span class="label">8.</span>
          <p pid="ojwoEpiQXEaLXsuPHdfGfw" hash="ueS6jw">
            <span class="emphasis">Practice “pure religion.”</span> Involve yourself in Christian service. Succor the needs of the sick and poor; visit the fatherless and widows, and be charitable to all whether in the Church or out of the Church. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.27" class="scriptureRef">James 1:27</a> and <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/1.30" class="scriptureRef">Alma 1:30</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="vrVB1izbi0ua5dpP8Wbusw" hash="dHYtFw">
          <span class="label">9.</span>
          <p pid="Bf7AqXIPuUetZQ5kFJyLkw" hash="iuxLnw">
            <span class="emphasis">Remember that there may be many questions for which we have no answers and that some things have to be accepted simply on faith.</span> An angel of the Lord asked Adam, “Why dost thou offer sacrifices unto the Lord?” He answered, “I know not, save the Lord commanded me.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/5.6" class="scriptureRef">Moses 5:6</a>.) There may be times when we are called upon to climb Mount Moriahs and to sacrifice our Isaacs without a full and prior explanation. Faith is the first principle of the gospel; it is a principle of progress.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p16" pid="2FvuPhR_UkCM2_NIAk2ByA" hash="uMpQGQ">I suspect that there are few who know better the reality of Satan and his henchmen than does the full-time missionary, for the missionary is exposed to the fiery darts of the adversary, which come whistling overhead as he or she labors in the front lines in our war against sin. However, I promise all missionaries—and all members—that if the nine actions just mentioned are followed consistently, victory will be yours and faith and testimony will be preserved.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p17" pid="xd1zjgV66EWVsNim0qPHQA" hash="dAu0og">At the same time—</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.f3">
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="UDdkO5JrAUO_7uvrSyoh7g" hash="uW16HA">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="NsiGUHGPM0S_smnuhpOMMA" hash="-9gXFw">I assure you that opposition to our cause testifies of its divinity. Would satanic powers combine against us if we were not posing a threat to such powers?</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="YiloBzase0mXO2GweuPsPw" hash="7Gd1hg">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="QRPEh60-I0KlNickKqyWNQ" hash="8rBo_g">I assure you that opposition, if met and overcome, has a refining influence upon our lives. A verse in one of our hymns reads:</p>
          
            <div class="stanza">
  <p class="line" pid="C354SN6gKk6OTCHhjnmqcw" hash="bjD38w">
    <span class="emphasis">When through fiery trials thy pathway shall lie,</span>
  </p>
  <p class="line" pid="m7clCkQGVkuGgF7URZsqwg" hash="mFaE3Q">
    <span class="emphasis">My grace, all sufficient, shall be thy supply.</span>
  </p>
  <p class="line" pid="XiSB020RwUGscNTDcC8MgA" hash="4XYHWg">
    <span class="emphasis">The flame shall not hurt thee; I only design</span>
  </p>
  <p class="line" pid="3VAfmGbX-kebb3Tb-Dc3gw" hash="ZsdLrg">
    <span class="emphasis">Thy dross to consume and thy gold to refine.</span>
  </p>
</div>
            <p class="citationInfo" pid="j5wU3wpP7U66Dd1LbX-0MA" hash="zTcnNg">(“How Firm a Foundation,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 66.)</p>
          
          <p pid="iBsTwG44okSDfvAc_i-2rA" hash="ODVZGQ">The Savior learned obedience by the things which he suffered. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/5.8" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 5:8</a>.) Joseph Smith’s oppositions gave him experience and worked for his good. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/122.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 122:7</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="zMK-nMdMX02FO2jnMJP3eQ" hash="Q4IRCw">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="DzmHOsJHZkCEKtObP-INlg" hash="SlNogQ">I assure you that the waters in which we are wont to swim are but little puddles when compared with the deep rivers of opposition in which the Prophet Joseph and others swam. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/127.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 127:2</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="kSe50pIWrkWvw5_HJGsfdA" hash="DIi2Kg">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="IT1EUauWHkO2sOX6GzYaiw" hash="ML1zug">I assure you that our cause is just and it will succeed, regardless of the opposition exerted against us. Earlier Saints were bolstered by these words: “As well might man stretch forth his puny arm to stop the Missouri river in its decreed course, or to turn it up stream, as to hinder the Almighty from pouring down knowledge from heaven upon the heads of the Latter-day Saints.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.33" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:33</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p18" pid="UD1fWl09CEOrHriAqiq4YA" hash="k1gCVA">President Brigham Young said: “Every time you kick ‘Mormonism’ you kick it upstairs; you never kick it downstairs. The Lord Almighty so orders it.” (<span class="emphasis">Discourses of Brigham Young,</span> sel. John A. Widtsoe, Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1941, p. 351.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p19" pid="mXY6ys6sZE-V3gc2XVT3cg" hash="mPDYfQ">With all my heart I implore those who are walking on the fringes of our faith to seek the safety of the center. This can be done best by counseling with your leaders and remaining within the fellowshipping circle of the Saints, and receiving nourishment from the good word of God. Do not permit faithless people to turn you out of the right way or to put you out of existence. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/6.title" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p20" pid="8eVF1_D1dUSlXv5ShIq4uQ" hash="uj5RlA">And I pray for those who deal in the highest form of larceny—that of stripping people of their precious testimonies. Such action, if continued, will lead only to the futility and emptiness of the dream of a night vision. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/27.3" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 27:3</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/5.33-39" class="scriptureRef">Acts 5:33–39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god.p21" pid="lQedW0ixTkeItA0M6QVNDQ" hash="C3doEA">God help us all in our war against sin. Though our numbers may be few and our dominions small, may we go forward “armed with righteousness and with the power of God in great glory” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/14.14" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 14:14</a>), is my prayer in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1981/10/opposition-to-the-work-of-god</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1981-general-conference/1981-10-5020-elder-carlos-e-asay-64k-eng.mp3" length="6289665" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 1981 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parent-Child Interviews</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Several years ago, I approached one of my daughters and said, “My dear, it’s time for an interview.” Her response was less than enthusiastic, and I determined within my own mind that I was boring her terribly. So instead of subjecting her to a formal</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03167_000_008" doc-version="2" hash="4JiCNg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="5jZD-cAOP06w7TyOETH0hA" hash="xZJDoQ">Parent-Child Interviews</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="MAtTLlDDw0Cc7YqB9kAHZA" hash="pDE4zw">Carlos E. Asay</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-29c2.jpg" alt="Elder Carlos E. Asay" pid="s35T9ZG1hUyjftHZYf72ww" hash="8VRGKQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p1" pid="8o6ZkC9XeESfrvXhGcLtPA" hash="nYOzpA">Several years ago, I approached one of my daughters and said, “My dear, it’s time for an interview.” Her response was less than enthusiastic, and I determined within my own mind that I was boring her terribly. So instead of subjecting her to a formal conversation, I invited her into the car and drove to the Dairy Queen where we both enjoyed a root beer float. All the way to and from the store, I asked questions, and she freely responded. She didn’t even realize that she was being interviewed—or at least that is what I thought. A few weeks later, I announced once again that I wanted to interview her. This time she promptly asked, “Wet or dry?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p2" pid="QzmM3OkacU6WvG0kS84mDQ" hash="o92FSw">I wonder if our conduct of good practices—even the conducting of interviews with our children—is sometimes done in a dry and deadening manner. Is it possible that in our drive to perform or fulfill a Church expectancy we collide with purpose? Can we not become so obsessed with form that we forget family? If so, perhaps we should ask ourselves whether within we are “full of dead men’s bones.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/23.27" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 23:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p3" pid="5jI7URl0AEqxVGUZYuilLg" hash="1byDtQ">When I think of dry performances, my mind turns to the ancients who altered the lesser law. They multiplied rituals, ceremonies, and symbols to the extent that the law itself was worshiped more than the Lord. In fact, the law was so abused that it pointed people away from, not forward to, the Messiah.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p4" pid="vBCWFGX8TUmAAgHqH4wiEQ" hash="wEeQpw">The acceptable performance, I feel, is made “wet” and given zest by the living waters which issue from Christ. It is a performance founded upon inspired teachings such as:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p5" pid="SYEQkRNn1kircmhOsCrgxA" hash="054MwQ">“[You] must have no other object in view … but to glorify God, and must not be influenced by any other motive than that of building his kingdom.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.46" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:46</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p6" pid="uOrH2XeVtkmFzWsTfEbYLQ" hash="LUkuWg">“He that is greatest among you shall be your servant.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/23.11" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 23:11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p7" pid="rdawVMfcjUaBH0DKMRdauw" hash="JCblOw">“For the letter killeth, but the spirit giveth life.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-cor/3.6" class="scriptureRef">2 Cor. 3:6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p8" pid="1hPBxptNn0CcVpqax-9ssw" hash="-vJpVA">“When thou doest alms, let not thy left hand know what thy right hand doeth.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.3" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 6:3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p9" pid="R-kknATsDU6jwpB95PCVFg" hash="J7E88g">Living performances are void of roteness and stiffness and self-centered tendencies. They are made by Saints who speak and act according to the feelings of their hearts and the Spirit of the Lord which is in them. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/4.12" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 4:12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p10" pid="ranQ0e8BTk2pNSgnO13mCQ" hash="FwtjLA">Alma’s interview with Helaman is a classic “wet” and refreshing performance. It is a short, three-question, forty-five-second exchange between father and son. According to the record, Alma was approaching the end of his ministry. He knew that he must select someone to assume prophetic and record-keeping responsibilities. Helaman was his choice. Therefore, Alma came to his son and asked: “Believest thou the words which I spake unto thee concerning those records which have been kept?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p11" pid="scsOW0D4nEGxFrkeSnUEYQ" hash="KyLKdQ">Without hesitation, Helaman answered: “Yea, I believe.” He might have said, “Yes, I believe in the scriptures; and yes, I believe all that you have taught me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p12" pid="1ybL510My0G56t83r38tlw" hash="pyCq0w">Alma’s second question was simply: “Believest thou in Jesus Christ, who shall come?” Again, without delay, Helaman stated: “Yea, I believe all the words which thou hast spoken.” (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/45.2-5" class="scriptureRef">Alma 45:2–5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p13" pid="gqlYiAONdEWP_Z_UujGlZA" hash="BECcvg">What a tribute to the father! He had talked of Christ, rejoiced in Christ, preached of Christ, and taught his son to know the source to which he might look for a remission of his sins. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/25.26" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 25:26</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p14" pid="5rPB7UcXw0WJHfCWDpzySw" hash="tuSJNw">Up to this point in the interview, the father’s questions were sampling the son’s basic beliefs. Now it was essential that those beliefs be tested and determined as being more than idle lip service. Alma’s capstone inquiry was, “Will ye keep my commandments?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p15" pid="uQ1V0KeqGU-YRk4-DpvD-g" hash="-yGgaQ">I am not certain what went through Helaman’s mind as he prepared to give his final response. He knew the necessity of honoring his parents and respecting priesthood authority. His previous actions had verified this fact. I like to think that Helaman’s reply was promoted by a heartfelt desire to be obedient rather than by a fear of authority. Deep love of God and father were reflected in his words: “Yea, I will keep thy commandments with all my heart.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p16" pid="84nkGbo0U0CNUh9DhyZ6NQ" hash="r_i1JQ">It is a marvelous thing when a father is able to make his commandments square perfectly with God’s expectations. Apparently, this condition was achieved by Alma, for Helaman was ready and willing to obey with all his heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p17" pid="DFYa3KqRP0WrfQy6nI3NFQ" hash="FDNH7A">This short, informative, and inspiring interview must have pleased Alma greatly. Not only had he communicated heart-to-heart and soul-to-soul with his son, but the son had openly declared his faith and pledged his devotion. To culminate the exchange, Alma, under the inspiration of the Spirit, prophesied and extended this blessing: “Blessed art thou; and the Lord shall prosper thee in this land.” (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/45.6-8" class="scriptureRef">Alma 45:6–8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p18" pid="mSXEHWbeKkCY5DNn83VlPA" hash="JNREAA">I wonder if our interviews with our children are as inspirational and building as the one between Alma and Helaman. I find it significant that the father came to the son; the son was not summoned to stand inspection or to give a report. I find it refreshing that the conversation was direct and without any verbal sparring; it was not labored or rehearsed. I find it exemplary that commitment was drawn without prying, wringing, or pressuring. And I find it most beautiful that the father concluded with a tender blessing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p19" pid="Gm5Ntr_Ny0WzQpQnMK_jlA" hash="QQfdVQ">Is this not a performance, or a pattern of communicating, that we should follow? And I refer to the principles involved, not necessarily to the form.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p20" pid="Sx1E3iccjkmEFImb0hJ6XA" hash="V5JV8Q">On one occasion when I arrived home late from an assignment, my wife expressed concern about one of our sons. She was worried that his mind was not riveted upon serving a mission, and she said as much to me. Her concerns certainly captured my attention, and I asked where the son was. She told me that he was in his room preparing to retire. Immediately I went to the room and sat on the edge of his bed. When I asked if I could speak with him a moment, he said, “Certainly.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p21" pid="P3bGYoyIgEaK9NXcKume_g" hash="cT6b8A">The hour was late. He was tired, and so was I. I, therefore, could see that nothing would be gained by a long conversation. And following the direct Alma-and-Helaman approach, the conversation went something like this:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p22" pid="E60KpaNER0KAaAzz_ieDPQ" hash="qx1Qpw">“Son, are you still planning on serving a mission?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p23" pid="BXDu1KMvmEmUAwMBsqv0Vw" hash="Nn0FxA">“Yes,” he answered. “I’ve always planned on serving, and I haven’t changed.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p24" pid="KvZzo_F3A0ePLXtnJM8ECA" hash="us1Z4w">“Son, do you know what qualifies a young man to serve a mission? Do you know what <span class="emphasis">worthiness</span> means?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p25" pid="6LTJC4Xud0CPwS1bCu47hg" hash="6XT1Jw">“Yes, Dad,” he said. “I understand the requirements and standards of worthiness that must be met.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p26" pid="mNY-9T7To0qDg-rBu70FKg" hash="gs_lIg">I said, “Thank you. I have one last question: Are you clean and worthy to serve? Could you accept a call if one were issued you today?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p27" pid="VExbGTCRAkqG66EDgj2V6A" hash="0_nJhg">There was a moment of reflective silence; then he declared: “It isn’t easy. Temptation is real and found everywhere. However, since you’ve asked, I am clean and I am worthy to serve.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p28" pid="m8_Sb--gEUm3yoEcEe2Acw" hash="B9W1Rw">This was a wonderful, beautiful, spontaneous, and sanctifying experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p29" pid="wgEa0PqRi0ie3A2QYFl3GQ" hash="xQMvow">I thanked my son, kissed him, assured him of my love, and bid him good night. I returned to my bedroom and told my wife that all was well and that she could go to sleep.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p30" pid="iWMNBswLzkSocbxKaVwbTw" hash="ML5T3Q">I do see great wisdom in the practices and performances which we encourage parents to follow in the Church. There is virtue in sponsoring family home evenings; in conducting family prayers, as Elder Perry has mentioned; in giving father’s blessings; and in holding parent-child interviews. All of these are important and have their place. However, the participation in such performances and the reporting of such activity must not become the end. They are means of involving, means of teaching, and means of blessing people. All should be engaged in for the purpose of saving and exalting souls.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews.p31" pid="7dWSSyHClkmjW5rdVgZXrQ" hash="EXOAQw">I thank God for my wife and my children; they make life so very meaningful. I thank God for the restored Church and living prophets who have provided me inspired programs for the benefit of those around me. And I’m grateful for the gospel which comes from the fountain of living waters—even Jesus Christ. But I pray humbly that I will be blessed not to confuse means and ends or become confused with performances at the expense of the spirit underlying all commandments. May our interviews, our prayers, our communications with our children be sanctifying and free of dryness and “dead men’s bones,” I pray, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1983/10/parent-child-interviews</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1983-general-conference/1983-10-1060-elder-carlos-e-asay-64k-eng.mp3" length="5271726" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 1983 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Oath and Covenant of the Priesthood</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Of all the holy agreements pertaining to the gospel of Jesus Christ, few, if any, would transcend in importance the oath and covenant of the priesthood. It is certainly one of the most sacred agreements, for it involves the sharing of heavenly powers</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03193_000_018" doc-version="2" hash="saTU4Q">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ZNPBwJ2fwkauDEcyc50tog" hash="elYmbw">The Oath and Covenant of the Priesthood</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="yZ6mSl9I20SFYWlHu9o27g" hash="pDE4zw">Carlos E. Asay</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-29c2.jpg" alt="Elder Carlos E. Asay" pid="YINOm8L0zESiVkD0RohiVA" hash="8VRGKQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p1" pid="PB9el_VYBU6OaE-oJyZRqA" hash="IKTvHg">Of all the holy agreements pertaining to the gospel of Jesus Christ, few, if any, would transcend in importance the oath and covenant of the priesthood. It is certainly one of the most sacred agreements, for it involves the sharing of heavenly powers and man’s upward reaching toward eternal goals. None of us can afford to be ignorant of the terms of this contract. To do so might cause us to miss the mark in our performance of duty and result in the forfeiture of promised blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p2" pid="yeHzPBp-8ECoD0ScHGhfjQ" hash="pZ_ZUA">A gospel covenant is a holy contract. “God in his good pleasure fixes the terms, which man accepts.” (Bible Dictionary, LDS ed., s.v. “covenant”.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p3" pid="cLtYkHcTlUO_mdxrJlg1jg" hash="PG8T6A">The two parties to the priesthood covenant are man and God. Man covenants to do certain things or meet certain conditions; God cites promises that he will give in return.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="zV03uukAdE6T7RyC2ZdX8g" hash="wU5tvA">Man’s Covenant</h3>
        <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.f2">
	  <ol class="number">
	    <li pid="3j-JSX36KkG8pKqU7UYmaw" hash="QBCGIw">
            <span class="label">1.</span>
            <p pid="m8RT48xbtkyIA5ZM3wQDzg" hash="D5Rd6g">Receive the Melchizedek Priesthood in Good Faith. When a man has the Melchizedek Priesthood conferred upon him, he is expected to receive it in good faith. The word receive is used generously in the Doctrine and Covenants verses that describe the oath and covenant of the priesthood:</p>
            <p pid="JDY3H_x_8E2xRBBdwYnFqQ" hash="M5GXOg">“All they who receive this priesthood receive me, saith the Lord; …</p>
            <p pid="dRQGXMNpFkeMmtVOireefw" hash="SuovCg">“And he that receiveth me receiveth my Father;</p>
            <p pid="5Tb3bwjah0mIQwCxkFwRAg" hash="yVN4aQ">“And he that receiveth my Father receiveth my Father’s kingdom.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.35,37-38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:35, 37–38</a>.)</p>
            <p pid="HHAvFRESHkqwpjiJiBDB2A" hash="X0TAgw">As people are confirmed members of the Church, those in authority lay hands upon their heads and command, “Receive the Holy Ghost.” Does not the same apply to the conferral of priesthood power? Several years ago, my father laid his hands upon my head to confer upon me the Melchizedek Priesthood and, as described in the Old Testament, to “put some of [his] honour upon [me] … and gave [me] a charge.” (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/num/27.18-23" class="scriptureRef">Num. 27:18–23</a>.) I knew that he had power to bestow, I knew that that power was real, and I knew the ultimate source of that power. So I received the holy priesthood in good faith.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="YJ4BHd3py0S3Tuozr5sLxw" hash="2jEaug">
            <span class="label">2.</span>
            <p pid="Oc2ndjfDI0et1oBMpTDSYg" hash="BDgw4Q">Magnify Callings. President Kimball defines priesthood, in part, as “the means whereby the Lord acts through men to save souls.” (Ensign, June 1975, p. 3.) This definition suggests action, not inaction. It implies that priesthood power is to be exercised in behalf of other people; it is not something to sit upon or to simply glory in. It suggests that priesthood callings are to be magnified.</p>
            <p pid="JMqV_xr0_UmX4XTA0xKraA" hash="IOo6wg">The transcendent blessings of the priesthood do not come by ordination alone. We are instructed:</p>
            <p pid="aNrSne4XJEywYpvjcnNILA" hash="AHR01A">“Ordination to the priesthood is a prerequisite to receiving [blessings], but it does not guarantee them. For a man actually to obtain them, he must faithfully discharge the obligation which is placed upon him when he receives the priesthood.” (Marion G. Romney, in Conference Report, Apr. 1962, p. 17.)</p>
            <p pid="TojtIHqMokOB2OVp6iJ16g" hash="npoy_A">What does it mean to magnify one’s calling? According to <span class="emphasis">Webster’s Third New International Dictionary,</span> “to magnify” is “to increase the importance of: cause to be held in greater esteem or respect … to make greater.” One magnifies a calling—</p>
            <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.f3">
		<ul class="bullet">
		  <li pid="qpwg7S3u-0WevXuRwel69g" hash="KzQWkw">
                <span class="label">•</span>
                <p pid="_Y70C0WLEE6HjO57rRMQuQ" hash="9A2vyQ">By learning one’s duty and executing it fully. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.99-100" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:99–100</a>.)</p>
              </li>
		  <li pid="OqxSdakhf02yhlfS5v9jug" hash="EThrow">
                <span class="label">•</span>
                <p pid="IdO7dspxG0iUwtTxql41RA" hash="XghxBg">By giving one’s best effort in assigned fields of labor.</p>
              </li>
		  <li pid="-aHDcBCE606w32dOOp_sIA" hash="O4Jz3A">
                <span class="label">•</span>
                <p pid="zR1kf5P10kqgRNqGVDztOg" hash="bt6ljg">By consecrating one’s time, talents, and means to the Lord’s work as called upon by our leaders and the whisperings of the Spirit. (See Spencer W. Kimball, <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Mar. 1985, p. 5.)</p>
              </li>
		  <li pid="7D_8VaioUE6eKtBOkZ1BOw" hash="J0gFaQ">
                <span class="label">•</span>
                <p pid="KdMs0OECtk-F2uD4YKj5Iw" hash="P8po7A">By teaching and exemplifying truth.</p>
              </li>
		</ul>
	      </div>
            <p pid="42SVjEHic0iFiJy2flQK4g" hash="Db0k5Q">Jacob, the Book of Mormon prophet, testified, “We did magnify our office unto the Lord, taking upon us the responsibility, … [teaching] them the word of God with all diligence; … [and] laboring with our might.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/1.19" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 1:19</a>.)</p>
            <p pid="x1Yv25l5fUCHOeUxoYUvzw" hash="foP7xQ">I underscore the words <span class="emphasis">taking responsibility, teaching the word of God,</span> and <span class="emphasis">laboring with might</span> in this inspired quotation. These are critical actions related to the exercise of priesthood power.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="GGAU15Sjo0OOQqByXg1tSw" hash="uH8drg">
            <span class="label">3.</span>
            <p pid="HUB9KWcP7Ua5YUzV7C8NYQ" hash="5FVbbg">Obey the Commandments. In the revelation on priesthood, we read, “And I now give unto you a commandment … to give diligent heed to the words of eternal life.” (D&amp;C 84:43.) “To give diligent heed,” I believe, includes to obey the commandments.</p>
            <p pid="mDUfo619ak6OIHWNF5KvGQ" hash="NDFAzw">No commandment or requirement of the gospel is nonessential. Each has its place, and all are to be respected. Not one is to be trifled with or placed aside as inconvenient.</p>
            <p pid="s4lZoqn_6UimiyW0uUrpSA" hash="weAZYA">A person who chooses to obey one commandment and ignore others is as foolish as the driver who adheres strictly to the posted speed limit but runs every stop sign and flaunts other rules of the road.</p>
            <p pid="lxRyDUq7lUWIM0S1SZBQ9g" hash="MII-xA">Let us remember that with every commandment, God has promised a blessing. If we expect to claim the blessing, we must keep the commandment. Otherwise, if we ignore or break the commandment, we are cursed by losing the blessing. (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/deut/11.26-28" class="scriptureRef">Deut. 11:26–28</a>.) It is a very simple but serious arrangement.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="8DXuu2lBw0qSv7_wnnd2eQ" hash="fi2ODg">
            <span class="label">4.</span>
            <p pid="FLpAxZbHIU-15RHjbs8JHQ" hash="dSKFiw">Live by Every Word of God. Addressing priesthood bearers, the Lord says, “For you shall live by every word that proceedeth forth from the mouth of God.” (D&amp;C 84:44; italics added.) This statement reinforces the need for obedience. It also suggests the need to know the word of the Lord.</p>
            <p pid="_z4R2fdVIkKIS0uIm6zPwQ" hash="PTn3uA">Words of eternal life come from one source: God. They are made available to us through the fountain of the holy scriptures and the fountain of living prophets and reconfirmed by personal revelation through the power of the Holy Ghost.</p>
            <p pid="nspZISjjhkKxRbOTQPmLZA" hash="MmyJgw">When we search the scriptures, we sit at the feet of prophets like Abraham, Isaiah, Peter, Paul, Nephi, Moroni, and Joseph Smith. These men received revelations in a former day and have much wisdom to share with us. Their counsel may be likened to a light positioned behind us. That light helps us understand things of the past and gives us partial vision for the future.</p>
            <p pid="dlr6lGXexEKqJVx9QXHskg" hash="7wh3bw">To receive added light, light positioned over and ahead of us, we must sit at the feet of living prophets, just as we are doing tonight. None of us need stumble along the way or depart from the path in the presence of such light. All we need to do is keep our eyes upon the prophets, heed their warnings, and live by their inspired words.</p>
            <p pid="g9MwXkxOpkqhAWHQvsaTeQ" hash="-3L8qQ">Men of the priesthood should burn these words into their minds:</p>
            <p pid="7R4qhBv6KUi0e8XrjjAd8g" hash="d9mtww">“What I the Lord have spoken, I have spoken, and I excuse not myself; … my word … shall all be fulfilled, whether by mine own voice or by the voice of my servants, it is the same.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:38</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.11-14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:11–14</a>.)</p>
            <p pid="QJ4kbrDvsUqFNBWVK05xNA" hash="cyPDNg">I have indicated that a man who receives the Melchizedek Priesthood agrees (1) to receive it in good faith, (2) to magnify callings given, (3) to obey all the commandments, and (4) to live by every word of God. These four expectations compose man’s covenant as applied to the oath and covenant of the priesthood.</p>
            <p pid="upqvwAYuNkmOHqjPXp9ZiQ" hash="IvFNoA">Next, let’s consider God’s promises and oath. You might ask, “If I fulfill my terms of the agreement, what has God promised in return?” Let us consider three promises:</p>
          </li>
	  </ol>
	</div>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="UB3U3VzyTkmv-no_YA-gRw" hash="oSmlvg">God’s Promises and Oath</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p4" pid="uZrG8sZMck62toOMH3FUnQ" hash="KZ4w6w">
          <span class="emphasis">Promise 1. We Will Be Sanctified by the Spirit.</span> Note these words:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p5" pid="FXYo-1bvfEeys0XGgaJ2Tw" hash="1RMAFg">“For whoso is faithful unto the obtaining these two priesthoods of which I have spoken [Aaronic and Melchizedek Priesthood], and the magnifying their calling, are sanctified by the Spirit unto the renewing of their bodies.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.33" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:33</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p6" pid="dNm7Ec5w30Gg2TJFLi__pw" hash="foBkKA">On one occasion, President Hugh B. Brown testified that President David O. McKay had been sanctified by the Spirit unto the renewing of his body. And, he added, “Some of the rest of us are better off today than we were many years ago so far as physical health is concerned—and we attribute that fact to [the Lord’s] blessing.” (In Conference Report, Apr. 1963, p. 90.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p7" pid="82m6XhVxKku58sDxUGHsaA" hash="ZWX6Bw">Many of us have felt the influence of this “renewal promise.” Without it, scores of our assignments might have gone unfinished.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p8" pid="vinaVdz9K0GcoVKY3LZBfA" hash="ecSiDw">
          <span class="emphasis">Promise 2: We Will Be Numbered with the Elect of God.</span> It is said of those who receive the holy priesthood and remain true to their covenants, “They become the sons of Moses and of Aaron and the seed of Abraham, and the church and kingdom, and the elect of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.34" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:34</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p9" pid="JMTsBGwEIU2qmbWTNgO5yA" hash="KtTs0g">Elder Bruce R. McConkie explains:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p10" pid="yuvwBpJSIk-6zb4p544SOQ" hash="5FHbCA">“These are the portion of church members who are striving with all their hearts to keep the fulness of the gospel law in this life so that they can become inheritors of the fulness of gospel rewards in the life to come.” (<span class="emphasis">Mormon Doctrine,</span> 2d ed., Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1966, p. 217.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p11" pid="ZSG2ZwkJiEanL0CG_lHS0g" hash="Vghesg">We do not become saints automatically by entering the waters of baptism. We become saints, in the true sense of the word, as we live saintly lives and cultivate Christlike attributes. Similarly, we do not become the elect of God instantaneously by receiving the priesthood. Such honor will come only so fast as we remember and perform according to the priesthood covenant.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p12" pid="PuShlaiRKEGmgfhCtoKWcw" hash="nPs29Q">
          <span class="emphasis">Promise 3: We Will Be Given All That God Has.</span> This all-encompassing promise is stated by Christ in these words: “All that my Father hath shall be given unto him.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:38</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p13" pid="tVzqGGG0ZEWX3bNzhKr71Q" hash="vUDPrw">Few of us, I suppose, can comprehend all that this promise means. Even though we know that it includes eternal life, or the inheritance of exaltation, still it is so great and so wonderful that it defies proper explanation. It is sufficient for me to know that God in heaven is my Father and that he will bless me with all he has to offer, if I prove myself to be a faithful son.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p14" pid="xm6vwZlliE2VtwqbREmYEA" hash="3DS3Yw">I stand in humble adoration of my Maker when I realize that he has sworn and confirmed his part of the agreement with an oath. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/6.13-17" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 6:13–17</a>.) He will never fall short of his promise, nor will he void it or compromise it in the slightest degree.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p15" pid="Vj653HcrJkmKpivANr1wCA" hash="FOg1zw">Perhaps I can place in clearer perspective all that I have said about the oath and covenant of the priesthood by relating a story based on a true experience.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p16" pid="LYd7JoOauE67FKj8VSHjwA" hash="0fTHxw">The son of a very wealthy man was called to serve a full-time mission. He entered the mission field and began his work. At first things went well; however, as he met rejections and as other challenges of finding and teaching surfaced, the young man’s faith wavered.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p17" pid="VfwgajC5vk65h7lyL44dVQ" hash="KWY7VQ">Mission associates gave encouragement, but it did not seem to help. One day the young man announced to the mission president that he was abandoning his call; he was returning home. The mission president did all within his power to dissuade the missionary. It was to no avail.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p18" pid="7RW7EphpCku3XFxNf9VASQ" hash="bjK8Lw">When word of the missionary’s decision reached the father, he obtained permission to visit his son in the mission field. In one of many tense conversations, the father said, “My son, I have lived for the day when you would serve a full-time mission. I did so because I love you and I love God. And I know that there is no work more essential than that of teaching truth to the peoples of the world.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p19" pid="e0tPhVFR4kWZdSNz77ATzg" hash="sXTt0Q">Somewhat sobered by his father’s words, the son meekly replied, “Dad, I didn’t realize that a mission meant so much to you.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p20" pid="4q_wGs4Hlk6tf-QSsJnYDw" hash="MMwgcw">“It means everything to me,” the father declared. Then he added with some emotion, “All my life I have worked and saved with one person in mind: you. And my one goal has been to provide you a decent inheritance.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p21" pid="Qh6kPQsaQ0eCDZ2XXqoANw" hash="02Qr-Q">“But Dad,” the son interjected, “the work is difficult and I don’t enjoy …”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p22" pid="1-XBdo7t1EW50kdxS7yj7w" hash="7DLeug">The father didn’t allow him to finish his sentence. Instead he asked, “How can I trust my businesses to your care if you cannot prove yourself by serving the Lord for two short years?”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p23" pid="g-AAL9r5AkO-m0WeOP0bag" hash="2JxaRA">There was an awkward pause as the son pondered the father’s question and studied his anxious countenance.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p24" pid="jG-W_rzZuk-As5iuvNvjRg" hash="U-qWRQ">Then with measured words, the father promised, “My son, my only heir, if you will be faithful in this calling and prove yourself worthy in every respect, all that I possess will be yours.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p25" pid="fdpijjb00EGjz27kTzqtLg" hash="5iZxQA">Noticeably touched by these earnest pleadings, the son rose to his feet, embraced his father, and sobbed, “I will stay.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p26" pid="THbekCeU4kO7FezWISCa8A" hash="eUA_VA">The son did stay in the mission field; he did serve faithfully from that day forward. And yes, in due time, he received from his father the promised inheritance, even all that his father had to share.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p27" pid="5uoW63kKck-ZhsyqbxxeUg" hash="UG93IA">My brethren, we are the sons of God. He has endowed us with his power, and he has called each of us to serve missions in a place called mortality. Our missions mean very much to him, and they should mean everything to us. In this mortal life, we are to prove ourselves worthy of his love and worthy of the inheritance he has offered.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p28" pid="pPud3vB1MkulEhW0l4j56A" hash="rOkUhw">What is that inheritance? It is all that he has, even eternal life. This blessed and promised gift will be ours only if we keep the covenants, particularly the covenant of the priesthood, and remain faithful to the end.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood.p29" pid="OVerFGEzN0-p4is2wQ1kWw" hash="x-gxCA">I pray that we will do so, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1985/10/the-oath-and-covenant-of-the-priesthood</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1985-general-conference/1985-10-3040-elder-carlos-e-asay-64k-eng.mp3" length="7178426" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 1985 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“One Small Step for a Man; One Giant Leap for Mankind”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I pray for the influence of the Holy Spirit as I discuss with you a most sacred subject—a subject that I hope will have special significance to those of you who may be investigating the Church. On July 20, 1969, astronauts landed on the moon, a plane</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_90905_000_028" doc-version="2" hash="lrKeeA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="FGmhSAdNqEmxmlPUYl0wpg" hash="-5mxhg">“One Small Step for a Man;</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="8dhk1d-O1EGEl0LnqTugXg" hash="rxUg_A">One Giant Leap for Mankind”</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="gjijYZFhHEehYobMirSiPQ" hash="pDE4zw">Carlos E. Asay</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1fa0.jpg" alt="Elder Carlos E. Asay" pid="7ppq3TIzO0SLVyoClpRF0w" hash="1B6PQA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p1" pid="GJPzFctRR0yXnnrRB5MSGQ" hash="pI-4qg">I pray for the influence of the Holy Spirit as I discuss with you a most sacred subject—a subject that I hope will have special significance to those of you who may be investigating the Church. On July 20, 1969, astronauts landed on the moon, a planet located some 239,000 miles from the earth. Millions of people the world over witnessed this historic event on television and stared in amazement as the lunar module came to rest on the moon’s surface. All were thrilled when Neil Armstrong exited from the space craft and announced: “One small step for a man; one giant leap for mankind.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p2" pid="peB-LTR1SU-eWYS49gxvdQ" hash="itewMA">The press coverage of this monumental achievement was broad. It occupied headlines and was the subject of feature stories for many days. After all, the moon-landing had opened new frontiers of space travel, revealed new knowledge about the universe, and represented a major investment of human resources. Some reporters declared that the moon landing was the greatest event in the history of mankind since the resurrection of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p3" pid="7t9spqMDUUuk07MmiXv4tQ" hash="01JuzA">I do stand in awe of the recent developments in space technology. My mind does not comprehend even a fraction of the miracles wrought by knowledgeable men of the world who have probed the universe. However, I take issue with those who believe that the placement of men upon the moon is the greatest occurrence of the last two thousand years. I do so because I know of an event wherein the Creator of the universe himself came to earth in answer to an obscure boy’s humble prayer and revealed pure theology.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p4" pid="8fyDK433I0GCTqd6cKOa1Q" hash="JboI7g">Greatness is measured by men in many ways. It is generally equated with size, cost, quantity, and position. God, however, has a better way, “for as the heavens are higher than the earth, so are [His] ways higher than [man’s] ways.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/55.9" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 55:9</a>.) In God’s eyes, greatness is equated with light, truth, goodness, and service. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:36</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/23.11" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 23:11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p5" pid="wInP7PMM5ke_0knMThRzfA" hash="x-TNIw">We are taught that eternal life is “the <span class="emphasis">greatest</span> of all the gifts of God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/14.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 14:7</a>; italics added), and that eternal life is to know “the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom [He has] sent.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17:3</a>.) Therefore, it is concluded that anyone who would introduce the only true God to mankind and unwrap the gift of eternal life, making it available to all, would be a partaker of greatness and be associated with great events.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p6" pid="JT6o0TJxG0uMuAJTFnfthg" hash="HnZTnA">The obscure young man of whom I speak, who introduced the true and living God to a benighted world, was not sponsored by an organization or trained by a group of professionals. At the time, he was no prophet, nor was he a prophet’s son. But like many who have been called in times past to perform a holy work, he was a common farm boy. (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/amos/7.14-16" class="scriptureRef">Amos 7:14–16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p7" pid="jUZ6j-fLb0GCqpCMFL64Bg" hash="bds9Xg">He was the product of a God-fearing family—a family that thirsted after righteousness and exercised a simple but deep faith in the Lord. His school was the home, his teachers were loving parents, and his textbook was the Holy Bible. Yet, at the tender age of fourteen, he demonstrated a type of faith which had power to thrust him into the presence of Deity. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/9.23" class="scriptureRef">Mark 9:23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p8" pid="cZDrM3eWqE-HrfN_WTKx2w" hash="FDz4ZQ">There were no cameras trained upon him when he stepped into that grove of trees in upper New York state. There were no cheering throngs or support personnel to provide him encouragement. Nor were there newspaper reporters on hand to describe his actions. He knelt alone under the gaze of his Heavenly Father and offered up the sincere desires of his heart with perfect confidence that his voice would be heard. He was unaware of the muted applause of unseen multitudes who had waited so patiently for the dawning of a new day and the restoration of the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p9" pid="kSlC4WcE90mhiHxmt-WAqA" hash="rG6DqQ">His investment in working the miracle was not money, machines, manpower, or even the trappings of science; his was an investment of living faith and an indomitable will.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p10" pid="AouX_LIH8Ea_isF1HX5NVQ" hash="Xz1FzQ">Joseph Smith’s prayer and first vision in 1820 were no small things, even though they began as “one small step for a [young] man.” Over the years they have proven to be “one giant leap for mankind”; for that act of supreme faith ended a long night of spiritual darkness, opened up a flood of unadulterated truths, and ushered in the dispensation of the fulness of times.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p11" pid="bD9WpDxjlUmTW4Myj1Yq5g" hash="888tqQ">We are told that the spin-off effects of the moon mission were many. Such benefits are reflected in all the materials about us. However, the consequences of Joseph Smith’s first vocal prayer and his probe into the unknown are infinitely greater and should be pondered seriously by all who are interested in “things as they <span class="emphasis">really</span> are, and of things as they <span class="emphasis">really</span> will be.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.13" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:13</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.f2">
	<p pid="zKn9bNqS3UqK-IoLFCBa6w" hash="_952FQ">Joseph did not emerge from the grove with lunar rocks in his pocket or with moon dust on his shoes. He emerged with a changed countenance and with a gold mine of truth lodged in his mind and heart:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="n9AxiqSwdkqNcIhZrZYbww" hash="5eHxMw">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="844f64AZuUqc2y_Yw5FwKQ" hash="hO2BgQ">Joseph learned that there are no winners in wars of words or tumults of opinion regarding religious matters. (See <a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.12" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:12</a>.) Such contention plays into the hands of Satan because he is the “father of contention.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.29" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:29</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Dw2wmscMVk-FlQYXAku-DA" hash="y6IP_A">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="jFyEJtizZ0Kb6c39hleEcA" hash="j0PJkA">Joseph learned of “the power of some actual being from the unseen world” which bound his tongue and enveloped him in thick darkness as he began to pray. (See <a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.16" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:16</a>.) This power was exerted by the evil one, who viewed Joseph Smith as a threat to his realm of sin and error.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="UWmYK-ESZ0CemEPKhMiuiw" hash="p8D_NQ">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="OZH_0th4ukaAyXGj1GqEmQ" hash="sCHatA">Joseph learned what Moses had learned years before about Satan’s darkness and nothingness, as compared with the light and liberty associated with God. (See <a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.10-15" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:10–15</a>.) Said Joseph:</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="0j3w6MV_okib0OKSdV3yFw" hash="K3CNIQ">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="YCVjoH_4OEeuNvgTdGkuTQ" hash="Lxs6Yw">Joseph learned that he was made in the image of God, exactly as the scriptures attest. In his own words:</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="1DvOHiz7VEmTH5GQ7ZDkqw" hash="JdhUPg">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p pid="PDjSpO8Fv0270lFyqxh0kQ" hash="X6Jmzw">Joseph learned that none of the churches of the day were right and that he should not join any of them. He recounts:</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="53lHhvURBU6QqsxaAeS5wg" hash="HnS-zQ">
          <span class="label">6.</span>
          <p pid="CtCp_iyHu06ZaEncOlngzQ" hash="Bd_LVg">Joseph learned why he must not align himself with an existing church. His words are:</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="P_qSIrJjd0-K0PVQQpANrg" hash="2L9pjg">
          <span class="label">7.</span>
          <p pid="NDR67kiGS0mCg52uxORG-g" hash="XWD4Vg">Joseph learned that “the testimony of James [was] true—that a man who lacked wisdom might ask of God, and obtain, and not be upbraided.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.26" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:26</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="IuapwLtn8kOhTCNVBDDphQ" hash="sSSTMA">
          <span class="label">8.</span>
          <p pid="F8rM1KhLOUafvOtE7x7a7w" hash="Wvq0hQ">Soon thereafter, Joseph learned “that God had a work for [him] to do” and that his name should be made known among all nations, kindreds, and tongues. (See <a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.33" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:33</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p12" pid="4fB8qNPAgkuEnMjZtTLOiQ" hash="1XZOwg">Such prophecy has been fulfilled as The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints has been established and as the fulness of the gospel has been preached in all the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p13" pid="qd75w3jwGUa6I-CBodQxtA" hash="aUs97w">Yes, it all started so quietly, so simply, and so very wonderfully. A believing boy took “one small step” and prayed. A loving Father in Heaven listened and responded. What has resulted is rightfully referred to as “one giant leap for mankind.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p14" pid="D7fNSD6qa0uzYVgpg41K9A" hash="O-rsUQ">All the towers ever built and all the spaceships ever launched pale in comparison with Joseph Smith’s first vision. Though men fly higher and higher into the heavens, they will not find God or see his face unless they humble themselves, pray, and heed the truths revealed through the Prophet of the Restoration.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p15" pid="JzwNpL0OvkusdRPzXJzBjg" hash="ugCtJQ">Some have foolishly said, “Take away Joseph Smith and his prayer in the grove and the First Vision and we can accept your message.” Such people would have us bury the treasure of saving truths already cited, and many more, and turn our backs to “the most important event that had taken place in all world history from the day of Christ’s ministry to the glorious hour when it occurred.” (Bruce R. McConkie, <span class="emphasis">Mormon Doctrine,</span> 2d ed., Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1968, p. 285.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p16" pid="Kcwq9Xpr1kmK8O9NRdpNAw" hash="JOhgLg">Joseph Smith “lived great” and “died great in the eyes of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/135.3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 135:3</a>.) He “has done more, save Jesus only, for the salvation of men in this world, than any other man that ever lived in it.” (135:3.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p17" pid="c3AKirdfSESYcKQou-wPRw" hash="knLdZw">His prayer was—</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.f3">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="f7062b2xh0CsoDr90WZI2Q" hash="uOOyrQ">
            <span class="emphasis">one small step for a [young] man, [but]</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="gcuU9fbyTU6mvSFA1CE-2Q" hash="rxUg_A1">
            <span class="emphasis">one giant leap for mankind.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="z8rRuqtInEu8FmbcfSGnzA" hash="nEM2fg">
            <span class="emphasis">[It proved that]</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="EIR9f8EgCkWCXKGUsQtzzw" hash="WGarZA">
            <span class="emphasis">There isn’t a thing that man cannot do,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="cO1L8Geq-keKkAG-y3pbVA" hash="8GSUwQ">
            <span class="emphasis">[if he has faith, trusts in the Lord, and]</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="KQZSueXPFE-NMwK4KqOiAA" hash="gL53kA">
            <span class="emphasis">If he takes one small step at a time.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p18" pid="EgffQA7940y9kKGiZCRWVg" hash="4OnlsA">Yes, “praise to the man who communed with Jehovah.” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> 1985, no. 27) and who was instrumental in translating the Book of Mormon, restoring the holy priesthood, organizing The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, and revealing the fulness of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind.p19" pid="1JtiUWycRUe_dNBy_Ym7VA" hash="R23Nbg">I know that Joseph Smith was a prophet, for the fruits of his labors are sweet and abiding, and the Holy Spirit has borne witness to my soul. I feel honored to blend my voice with the chorus of millions who testify of his greatness and divine calling. I also know that “the Lord God doth work by means to bring about his great and eternal purposes; and by very small means the Lord doth confound the wise and bringeth about the salvation of many souls.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.7" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:7</a>.) In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1990/04/one-small-step-for-a-man-one-giant-leap-for-mankind</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1990-general-conference/1990-04-4030-elder-carlos-e-asay-64k-eng.mp3" length="6758547" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 1990 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Men!</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1992/04/be-men?lang=eng</link>
      <description>A young man of deacon age reported: “I feel a lot of pressure from my friends to smoke and steal and things like that. … My best friends are really pushing me to do it. They call me a and a if I don’t. I really don’t like the idea of smoking but my g</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_92905_000_020" doc-version="2" hash="yVUN3g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="8h_VEyQOxEOMHFDomxtMew" hash="eUCTsA">Be Men!</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="NoVQMD1b80Ctvs1W_0cbLA" hash="pDE4zw">Carlos E. Asay</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1fa0.jpg" alt="Elder Carlos E. Asay" pid="MSJaEBlAJ0OZSYNO94fPBQ" hash="1B6PQA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p1" pid="L0JZ3Z1In0WhxuNs74NKwQ" hash="QF52EA">A young man of deacon age reported: “I feel a lot of pressure from my friends to smoke and steal and things like that. … My best friends are really pushing me to do it. They call me a <span class="emphasis">pansy </span>and a <span class="emphasis">mamma’s boy </span>if I don’t. I really don’t like the idea of smoking but my good friend Steve told me in front of some of my friends, ‘Kevin, you’re <span class="emphasis">an idiot </span>and <span class="emphasis">a chicken </span>wrapped up in one little body.’” (J. Santrock, <span class="emphasis">Adolescence,</span> New York: William C. Brown, 1987; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p2" pid="RXxcC3eyekKuJ4B_zeMdVg" hash="10msSQ">An eighteen-year-old priest recounted:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p3" pid="-DRLr4GIhEubEvdoIeIPFA" hash="NH49sw">“On one occasion, I was persuaded to join a group on a weekend excursion. I was told that the [plans] for the day included … sightseeing, a lunch, and a movie. I was promised that there would be no [inappropriate activities]. All … knew that I was a Latter-day Saint and … deeply committed to the moral standards of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p4" pid="q5Atlwr9R0afMQhsh5rYiw" hash="0fXvAg">“Upon reaching the city, we visited a place or two of historical significance and ate lunch. Then the inevitable happened—the group turned toward a bar and a house of [prostitution]. I refused to enter these dens of iniquity, and I openly expressed my anger over the broken promises of my associates.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p5" pid="uP9ZLDT2wE2axaoqTVBsdQ" hash="FsHZmA">“As I walked away … my companions taunted me by shouting, ‘When are you going to grow up?’ ‘When will you stop being a sissy and a religious fanatic?’ ‘When are you going to be a man?’” (Carlos E. Asay, <span class="emphasis">In the Lord’s Service, </span>Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1990, p. 46.)</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="6wSct7shT0q7WUOdGJYqTg" hash="oHao-A">Who Is a Man?</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p6" pid="w-K8uUgWXkm8h_25JMPGZg" hash="bUn63w">It seems that everyone at some time or another is invited by peers to smoke, drink, steal, or engage in other immoral acts, all under the pretense of manhood. And when someone refuses to participate, he is often ridiculed and called names like pansy, mamma’s boy, idiot, chicken, sissy, and religious fanatic. Such names are used by peers who equate manliness with the ability to drink liquor, blow tobacco smoke out of all the facial cavities, sow one’s wild oats like some animal on the street, and break moral laws without a twinge of conscience.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p7" pid="5qaNNv2GOUCmDS3s7x9vfg" hash="uy6_Pw">We see colorful advertisements on billboards, in magazines, and on the television screen promoting cigarettes, beer, and other vices. Those who use cunning tactics to peddle their wares disregard the souls of young people and love only their money. They would have us believe that a person with a cigarette or alcoholic beverage in hand is a man, when in reality he is nothing more than a slave to a destructive substance. They would have us believe that a person who engages in illicit sex is a man, when in reality he is nothing more than an abuser of those who are “tender,” and “chaste,” and “delicate.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/2.7" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 2:7</a>.) They would have us believe that brute force, or crude behavior, uncontrolled temper, foul language, and dirty appearance make a man, when in reality these characteristics are animalistic at best and the opposite of manhood at worst.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p8" pid="UVMORM-rnUKVQiAwQslBog" hash="Y-BI_g">We who bear the priesthood, must be on guard; we must not be influenced by barbarian voices in our quest to become men. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/14.8-11" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 14:8–11</a>.) We must remember that “God created man in his own image” and that man is expected to keep that image engraven upon his countenance. (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/1.27" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 1:27</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.14,19" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:14, 19</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p9" pid="I1jeb5lVk0GRi5AOhGYEbg" hash="ywfSAA">“What is man?” asked the psalmist. (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/8.4" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 8:4</a>.) The answer: “[God] made him a little lower than the angels, and hast crowned him with glory and honour.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/8.4-6" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 8:4–6</a>.) It is, therefore, our responsibility to climb ever upward and to wear God-given crowns honorably. Young men, especially those of a “chosen generation” and “royal priesthood,” must understand that they are the spiritual offspring of God and that no one becomes in truth a man until he reverences the Father of spirits and allows inner powers to control his thoughts, words, and actions. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-pet/2.9" class="scriptureRef">1 Pet. 2:9</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/17.28" class="scriptureRef">Acts 17:28</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/12.9" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 12:9</a>.)</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="PqjrefOF6E23vnvBIlH9dQ" hash="16bUAA">What Makes a Man a Man?</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p10" pid="2heQ5UFzGUOg7snghx1JgA" hash="0WfIJQ">What makes a man a man? This is a question used in a popular beer ad. The suggestion of that advertisement is that by drinking the beer the consumer becomes a man. How devious and how very stupid! Those who try to get you to drink alcoholic beverages and use drugs have total disregard for you, you who are the “temples of God.” Hence, they would have you defile your body and offend the Spirit of God that dwells within you. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/3.16-17" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 3:16–17</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p11" pid="DO1I4-ZkzkqMmfZPXe6_sA" hash="EfLnKA">What makes a man a man? Let’s turn to the Book of Mormon and Father Lehi for an answer. A short time before his death, Lehi gave this charge to his sons: “Arise from the dust, … and <span class="emphasis">be men.</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/1.21" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 1:21</a>; italics added.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p12" pid="04O7guyn_Uedbiz8hPLydQ" hash="efUlbw">“Awake from a deep sleep, yea, even from the sleep of hell, and shake off the awful chains by which ye are bound.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/1.13" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 1:13</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p13" pid="d-Y1ST0OEE6v6zUNkx8SHw" hash="o8Rylw">“Be determined in one mind and in one heart, united in all things.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/1.21" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 1:21</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p14" pid="1s0FM357k0WvdspJKRvzdA" hash="gwGEHw">“Put on the armor of righteousness. … Come forth out of obscurity. … Rebel no more.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/1.23-24" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 1:23–24</a>.)</p>
        <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.f2">
	  <ul class="bullet">
	    <li pid="yWM558UJMEuPzBWvX4SV-A" hash="lTXsFw">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="YHlQSEgWr0ymRIga2Gc7nw" hash="Eiz37Q">The challenge to “arise from the dust” means to overcome evil behaviors that destroy character and ruin lives. Physical appetites must be controlled.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="UgU6xDlKTUOGixI8SXNFgg" hash="C0Wyjw">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="RPYUFE8OiEmJ21kQIaL1AA" hash="Dc5j0Q">“Awake from a deep sleep, … even from the sleep of hell” suggests a process of learning and becoming aware of God’s holy purposes. No sleep is deeper or more deadly than the sleep of ignorance.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="rvCXdEjjqUi19nDaWVWqww" hash="7hk7Yg">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="R9KCoBzAUkSSWUaLl9_Tjw" hash="55PiiA">“Shake off the awful chains by which ye are bound” indicates the need to overcome bad habits, even the seemingly little habits that grow into strong “chains of hell.” (See 2 Ne. 26:22; Alma 5:7.)</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="pez1j1MGRES1Ow-kZDMCXw" hash="zDzl6w">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="gLkaO2YN4ECKfQntryAayw" hash="D8Tbkg">“Be determined in one mind and in one heart, united in all things” requires full commitment to righteousness and a singleness of purpose so that one’s will is made compatible with the will of God.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="iVfoSxGHA0WvoA6AOOM7_A" hash="20lRgQ">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="p0zTWQiA40qjwf2kolthYw" hash="gOg6fg">“Put on the armor of righteousness” reminds us of the need to wear the helmet of salvation, pick up the sword of truth, use the shield of faith, and accept the full protective coverings of the Lord. (See Eph. 6:11–18.)</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="ZyXWaS2Vy0CL4PJlU8o1aA" hash="d9TRHg">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="RqrgoCrYt02FrmpRTnKx2g" hash="AlDrJA">“Come forth out of obscurity” instructs one to model goodness and serve as a light to others. True men are living light fountains which are pleasant to be near. (See D&amp;C 103:9–10.)</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="Zgp3rnb83k6sr4SCMIxPuw" hash="5zXLVA">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="hwdEHL7130GChByWtKm0oQ" hash="5RNSiw">“Rebel no more” makes it perfectly clear that ignoring or willfully breaking commandments is a wasteful effort.</p>
          </li>
	  </ul>
	</div>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="26svKH7bF0q4N92q4PlpEQ" hash="F6-UoQ">Vicious Lie</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p15" pid="xm8ZOCJbvUa8v8V8kS3QGw" hash="JFowlg">There is a lie—a vicious lie—circulating among the Latter-day Saints and taking its toll among the young. And it is that a “balanced man” is one who deliberately guards against becoming too righteous. This lie would have you believe that it is possible to live successfully and happily as a “double-minded man” with one foot in Babylon and one foot in Zion. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.8" class="scriptureRef">James 1:8</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p16" pid="_R6DX9YXnUiZiHAk7jhjug" hash="GY7vwQ">I love this story of two young men who had been schooled in a monastery. One morning as they sought adventure, they passed a cathedral. The more righteous of the two remembered that they had not prayed that morning and said, “How can [we] hope for [God’s] blessing upon the day?”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p17" pid="QxXteVywQEmjUfH-d7x30Q" hash="f5KRXw">The less righteous one responded: “My friend, I have prayed so much during the last two months … that I feel that I have [somewhat] over-prayed myself.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p18" pid="OWlaNEUTuES3uHbjjA2fxw" hash="fPA27g">“How can a man have too much religion?” asked the first. “It is the one thing that availeth. A man is but a beast as he lives from day to day, eating and drinking, breathing and sleeping. <span class="emphasis">It is only when he raises himself, and concerns himself with the immortal spirit within him, that he becomes in [very] truth a man. </span>Bethink ye how sad a thing it would be that the blood of the Redeemer should be spilled to no purpose.” (A. Conan Doyle, “The White Company,” in <span class="emphasis">Works of A. Conan Doyle, </span>New York: Cosmopolitan Book Corporation, 1988, pp. 58–59; italics added.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p19" pid="B5WUn3VjPky5y7iztrUX2g" hash="TxvKmg">Can a man be too righteous? Too Christlike? Impossible! Can the so-called “balanced man” walk successfully the beam between good and evil? No. Each step is shaky, and eventually he will teeter and fall and break himself against the commandments of God.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p20" pid="Ne-36qbjzUy_DPzEQ5A8hA" hash="mSG4rA">Fleshliness never was manliness, and it never will be. A real man is one who yields to the enticings of the Holy Spirit and seeks to acquire Christlike virtues. A real man is one who allows the Spirit to direct the course and to call the cadence in his life. “Remember, to be carnally-minded is death, and to be spiritually-minded is life eternal.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/9.39" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 9:39</a>.)</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="ZPGyfaHY5U2gFYVVaOQAaQ" hash="3xRx2g">Examples of Manliness</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p21" pid="A62gAIbwNEqogiH_fQyMzA" hash="9iTFQQ">A man of Christ stood on October 1, 1959, before a crowd of 1,500 people in a church within the shadow of the Kremlin and boldly referred to Jesus as the great Redeemer. He said in an emotion-filled voice:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p22" pid="Yv4sNIh1Wke2el3yr8VmzQ" hash="vj1Y3Q">“I believe very firmly in prayer. It is possible to reach out and tap that unseen power which gives us such strength and such anchor in time of need. … Be not afraid. Keep His commandments. Love one another. Love all mankind. Strive for peace and all will be well. Truth will endure. Time is on the side of truth.” (Ezra Taft Benson, <span class="emphasis">Cross Fire: The Eight Years with Eisenhower, </span>Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday and Co., 1962, pp. 485–88.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p23" pid="KdmOd_fzrUOKAEoEXoN8HQ" hash="is7q6Q">People wept openly on that occasion, including newsmen who had reluctantly attended the worship service. One newsman, a former marine, ranked the experience as one of the two most spiritual and memorable of his life.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p24" pid="qxvKup-GXkKN5XKd-jeSCA" hash="vkaX1g">There was a man in that cathedral in Russia on that special day. His name, Ezra Taft Benson—he who now presides as the President, prophet of the Church.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p25" pid="WexWUv5wMk-6GdnBZ9ML6g" hash="sR1_TA">Parley P. Pratt provides us with a description of a real man in his account of his imprisonment in Richmond, Missouri, with Joseph Smith and others. On one of those awful nights in jail, Brother Pratt and his associates were exposed to the filthy language of their guards as they bragged of their deeds of rape, murder, robbery, and other crimes committed against the Mormons. When the Prophet Joseph could bear it no more, he rose to his feet and spoke with a voice of thunder:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p26" pid="M7bUTrjAgU-LSDep15TXSw" hash="ckWgxg">“SILENCE, ye fiends of the infernal pit. In the name of Jesus Christ I rebuke you, and command you to be still; I will not live another minute and bear such language. Cease such talk, or you or I die THIS INSTANT!”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p27" pid="5SCmkAEStEWPqcTBR4i2sA" hash="xrDjmg">Said Elder Pratt: “I have seen the ministers of justice, clothed in magisterial robes … in the Courts of England; I have witnessed a Congress in solemn session … ; I have tried to conceive of kings … ; and of emperors assembled to decide the fate of kingdoms; but dignity and majesty have I seen but <span class="emphasis">once, </span>as it stood in chains, at midnight, in a dungeon in an obscure village of Missouri.” (<span class="emphasis">Autobiography of Parley P. Pratt, </span>Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1985, pp. 179–80.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p28" pid="V5DzUUl5W0Kr1w5ey6aksg" hash="8Q37DQ">There was a man! Joseph Smith, the prophet of the Restoration.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p29" pid="3EOUjJJEUEayeUHLcHJThg" hash="sM1x_Q">The Savior, the perfect model of manliness, stood before his tormentors having been scourged, beaten, spat upon, and platted with a crown of thorns. Pilate admitted, “I find no fault in him.” Then he pronounced those irrefutable and piercing words: “Behold the man!” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/19.4-5" class="scriptureRef">John 19:4–5</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p30" pid="62a-uVej6EGTS9ylilyPrA" hash="0cEDcA">Jesus, our Savior, was <span class="emphasis">the </span>man among men, for he “increased in wisdom and stature, and in favour with God and man” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/2.52" class="scriptureRef">Luke 2:52</a>); he subjected the flesh to the Spirit and yielded not to temptation (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/15.1-8" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 15:1–8</a>); he learned obedience by the things which he suffered (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/5.8" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 5:8</a>); he grew from grace to grace (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.12-14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:12–14</a>); and, in the words of Shakespeare:</p>
        <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.f3">
          <div class="stanza">
            <p class="line" pid="xh2QFyEbJ0uR6tE9cfhhFw" hash="xVZtZQ">
              <span class="emphasis">His life was gentle, and the elements</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="ACFEeDFnXUOGuS_-Q-_XwA" hash="0dwGxA">
              <span class="emphasis">So mix’d in him that Nature might stand up</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="ydRzRXnfdECnudvoF9_CMQ" hash="t422Rg">
              <span class="emphasis">And say to all the world “This was a man!”</span>
            </p>
          </div>
        </div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p31" pid="Oex6H0kBe0a9nEEDCG7L_A" hash="n_l4Kw">Thus, he, the only sinless and perfect man who ever walked this earth, is qualified to state: “What manner of men ought ye to be? Verily I say unto you, even as I am.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.27" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 27:27</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p32" pid="sGky4dLX8U26wGJr9NPdug" hash="ZInK7Q">King David instructed his son Solomon, “Be thou strong … and shew thyself <span class="emphasis">a man;</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/be-men.p33" pid="iALoqeCGxEa8YaHzX1-zuw" hash="ZiQvoA">“And keep the charge of the Lord thy God, to walk in his ways, to keep his statutes, and his commandments, … that thou mayest prosper in all that thou doest.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-kgs/2.2-3" class="scriptureRef">1 Kgs. 2:2–3</a>; italics added.) I echo this charge—Be men! Be men of Christ! Be men of God! For this I pray, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1992/04/be-men</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1992-general-conference/1992-04-3020-elder-carlos-e-asay-64k-eng.mp3" length="6479880" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 1992 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“If a Man Die, Shall He Live Again?”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again?lang=eng</link>
      <description>A few years ago, I walked the halls of a care center. Most of the occupants were infirm individuals who were timeworn and anxious to go elsewhere. In passing one of the rooms, I heard a weak cry for help. The door was slightly ajar, so I entered with</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_94905_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="F-rPvQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="7ASGgbLl7EOd4muyQICqag" hash="QNOYxw">“If a Man Die, Shall He Live Again?”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="jV2Q5LN4pU6XE_00JezTIQ" hash="pDE4zw">Carlos E. Asay</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1fa0.jpg" alt="Elder Carlos E. Asay" pid="ivihsg5xBUyH3U_ESWRdyA" hash="1B6PQA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p1" pid="xZfmQif6m0q6UAMpt22IkQ" hash="yHEwMg">A few years ago, I walked the halls of a care center. Most of the occupants were infirm individuals who were timeworn and anxious to go elsewhere. In passing one of the rooms, I heard a weak cry for help. The door was slightly ajar, so I entered with the hope that I might help someone in distress. Once I was inside, my eyes were met by a pleading look from a sweet, elderly woman in a wheelchair. She stared at me for a moment and asked, “Can I die? Can I die?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p2" pid="lsyj5lBTMkKJJ4eDUILBHg" hash="_pejsg">Her tender look, soft voice, and delicate features melted my heart. The woman obviously was suffering physical pain and wanted to be released from a wasted body. She longed for the companionship of loved ones who had preceded her in death.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p3" pid="I0LF6ng3wEKo-ogirJRQkw" hash="S1C00Q">I don’t recall exactly what I said on that occasion. But I did attempt to reassure the woman that she could and would die in the Lord’s appointed time. I also tried to reassure her that she would live again, free of the infirmities that now troubled her.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="J2Jh7e2UZkG_JRvn059x5Q" hash="9jD91g">The Real Issue</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p4" pid="5LceNz45xE6iC1x2ovQDbQ" hash="ECkCxg">The real issue facing each of us is not <span class="emphasis">Can I die?</span> Physical death is one of life’s certainties. It occurs regularly and is evidenced by the printed obituary notices and the empty chairs at our tables. For just as the sun sets at the close of each day, in accord with the eternal rhythm of life, so will we experience a temporary separation of body and spirit, whereby our tabernacles of flesh will be placed “in the cold and silent grave” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/1.14" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 1:14</a>) and our spirits will be “taken home to that God who gave them life” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/40.11" class="scriptureRef">Alma 40:11</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p5" pid="RKvQU1G9sU6W3La2Sd553A" hash="TZZcSA">But rather, the real issue is, “If a man die, shall he live again?” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/job/14.14" class="scriptureRef">Job 14:14</a>). Will the grave seal our fate forever? Or is there a resurrection and another sphere of existence awaiting our souls?</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p6" pid="AWI05Z0vg0OEnNrJNJcGew" hash="sg-KEw">Those who believe that the grave is man’s final destiny live without hope of a better world and are inclined to embrace that fatalistic approach, “Eat, drink, and be merry, for tomorrow we die” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/28.7" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 28:7</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/15.32" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 15:32</a>). This approach often leads to wanton experimentation, immoral conduct, and all the other behaviors that reap misery and remorse of conscience (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/29.5" class="scriptureRef">Alma 29:5</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p7" pid="3AjP4AL2aEuZBY43O9kuXA" hash="9moj-w">Whereas, those who believe in a life after death are much more inclined to lead purposeful lives. Belief in a resurrection and related truths encourages one to obey the commandments, repent of sins, serve others, and do the other things that bring joy and happiness both here and hereafter. It seems, therefore, most appropriate that we address this real issue, <span class="emphasis">Shall I live again?</span> on the eve of Easter—a day when Christians the world over will commemorate the resurrection of the Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="0jV35i4QfUGGHf3S51dPDg" hash="ntf3Pw">Two Classes of Evidence</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p8" pid="X-3rM5CDkkyv_wXyg2xvqw" hash="44S_yA">A noted writer referred to Christ’s resurrection as “the <span class="emphasis">greatest miracle</span> and the most <span class="emphasis">glorious fact of history”</span> (James E. Talmage, <span class="emphasis">Jesus the Christ,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1979, p. 649; emphasis added).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p9" pid="WAq5zVZ3e0CNqghZEKy4zg" hash="Q-T5Bg">Miracles are “manifestations of divine or spiritual power” (Bible Dictionary, p. 732). They are not simply sleight-of-hand tricks or actions contrived by clever men. They are acts wrought by individuals with powers beyond those of mortals. What could possibly be greater than the act of laying one’s body down in death and picking it up again in a resurrected state as did Jesus? Only by the use of godly powers and only through the grace of God could such a marvelous thing occur.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p10" pid="vRvxL-ljhkOcPC5t20EbKQ" hash="eOtgRw">What about the claim that the Resurrection was “the most glorious fact of history”? The facts of the Resurrection may be placed in two groups or classes. One is the cloud of witnesses who saw the resurrected Christ; the other is the army of believers, both present and past, who on the strength of personal testimonies declare with conviction, “The grave hath no victory, and the sting of death is swallowed up in Christ” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/16.8" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 16:8</a>). Both classes of evidence are significant and worthy of our review.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="LtYFJzaJn02KLBoJA1LiZg" hash="CPCRoQ">Cloud of Witnesses</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p11" pid="q-MGpJHYVUKaRR4xwLRyrA" hash="Zk9O8w">In the Acts of the Apostles it is recorded: “To whom also he shewed himself alive after his sufferings by many <span class="emphasis">infallible proofs,</span> being seen of them forty days, and speaking of the things pertaining to the kingdom of God” (<a href="/scriptures/jst/bible-jst-acts/1.3" class="scriptureRef">JST, Acts 1:3</a>; emphasis added).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p12" pid="9WYAM6Z-i0KNza85GFNDvA" hash="ofqVXg">Included in the cloud of witnesses or among the “infallible proofs” were hundreds of followers who saw the risen Lord on multiple occasions.</p>
        <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.f2">
	  <ul class="bullet">
	    <li pid="DROHXg_jmki5ZzNHXJ_b8Q" hash="Aar5Ew">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="gzdQ0Npvd0-4H30LeZlQ-w" hash="wHzpAg">“He appeared first to Mary Magdalene” (Mark 16:9). She saw him and heard his voice.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="oaF_Ni1S6k6Ck4LnLZfgDA" hash="a8xzCg">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="LJJrHWFMeU6nlZZpxH24Dw" hash="rGJujA">He appeared to Joanna, Mary (the mother of James), “and other women that were with them” (Luke 24:10). They “held him by the feet, and worshipped him” (Matt. 28:9).</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="Z1GH8ipQ5U-QR1pNksVuyg" hash="OK_nwQ">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="QDvKnc6MWECQR6Ypn2r6Rg" hash="ZmDRNQ">He appeared to Peter—the one who had denied him thrice (see Luke 24:34).</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="vC2s7D5CsE2OwGWKoMZfvA" hash="eBNfew">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="mCdAkRlPsE2k2EUdvBcbAw" hash="Ybez6A">He appeared to two disciples as they went into the country (see Luke 24:13–32).</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="JGJvEFCj9kSdqtGeQZXuBw" hash="dNWKUw">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="FxovoPJhPkydXgI6it1SVw" hash="pZnXIQ">He appeared to his beloved Apostles at least four times.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="BdUgGZ2gFUOa30qQJhdAiA" hash="Ymv1vg">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="3cGMfaJNsku-hCmyU09ULA" hash="gFpBVg">He was seen after the Crucifixion by “above five hundred brethren at once” (1 Cor. 15:6), according to Paul’s account.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="oCQ20yJmN0eQk0DY2e_8Yw" hash="79tfYg">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="BxrcDqFgk0qzb2e6NlwQ_A" hash="ujaFPA">Moreover, “the graves were opened; and many bodies of the saints which slept arose,</p>
          </li>
	  </ul>
	</div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p13" pid="E8roRC773EWXYvf15gNXkA" hash="6thY-g">Even after all of these eyewitnesses, there were the skeptics. Some regarded the words of the women as “idle tales” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/24.11" class="scriptureRef">Luke 24:11</a>). Jesus chided the two disciples by saying, “O fools, and slow of heart to believe all that the prophets have spoken” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/24.25" class="scriptureRef">Luke 24:25</a>). And he upbraided some “because they believed not them which had seen him [earlier] after he was risen” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/16.14" class="scriptureRef">Mark 16:14</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p14" pid="ATXjcZjUdUKdI26rRhwE3Q" hash="GGLyhA">One wonders how anyone could doubt the actuality of the Resurrection after reading the several accounts of his appearances to the women, the disciples, and the Apostles. What greater evidence would one want than the documentation of fact provided in holy writ?</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p15" pid="Uk7EhSjkBUGOVY9igHf9zw" hash="WzfABQ">But there is more. Wrote John, “The testimony of two men is true” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.17" class="scriptureRef">John 8:17</a>). If this is a valid statement, then surely the testimony of Christ’s escape from the tomb provided by a second nation must not be overlooked. I refer, of course, to the Book of Mormon record of Christ’s postmortal appearances on the Western Hemisphere.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p16" pid="pPFSgk7UhkObLr2zKRf0-A" hash="f9G-HA">Near a temple in the land called Bountiful some 2,500 people heard a small, piercing voice declare: “Behold my Beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased, in whom I have glorified my name—hear ye him” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.7" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:7</a>). They stood in awe and experienced a change of heart upon hearing God, the Eternal Father, introduce his Only Begotten Son—his means of extending the gifts of immortality and eternal life to all of his children (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.16" class="scriptureRef">John 3:16</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p17" pid="e-AgMqjG6kWTRJWdb6uTQQ" hash="zlmJQQ">The multitude saw a man descending out of heaven. They heard him announce, “Behold, I am Jesus Christ, whom the prophets testified shall come into the world” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.10" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:10</a>). Then he invited the people to come forth one by one and see with their eyes and feel with their hands the prints of the nails in his hands and in his feet (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.14-17" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:14–17</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p18" pid="RKainhjANkCfoqPaG8Mdhg" hash="Z6Hl2Q">A cloud of people on two continents were eyewitnesses of the risen Christ. Thus, it can be said about this glorious fact of history, “The resurrection … is attested by evidence more conclusive than that which rests our acceptance of historical events in general” (James E. Talmage, <span class="emphasis">Jesus the Christ,</span> p. 699).</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="FXC_4RmK1k6vanMMQyjECA" hash="uUXQTQ">Personal Testimony</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p19" pid="oavDtH5QQ0OJMfeAEsVRrw" hash="QSDp-g">“Infallible proofs” of spiritual matters, such as Christ’s resurrection, are not of the hand, but of the heart. They are not seen with the naked eye; they are seen through the “eye of faith” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.19" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:19</a>). Nor are they established by a touch of a finger. The reality of spiritual matters is confirmed by feelings stirred through the spoken or written words of God (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.45" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:45</a>). I say this because “the Spirit speaketh the truth and lieth not. Wherefore, it speaketh of things as they really are, and of things as they really will be” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.13" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:13</a>). The Holy Spirit deals with facts, not with fancied happenings.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p20" pid="cRQ9dN1fyU2MNZRDwOhMhw" hash="ux05rw">You will recall that the two disciples who walked and talked with Christ on the road to Emmaus did not recognize him at first. Later, however, “their eyes were opened, and they knew him,” when they reflected, “Did not our heart burn within us, while he talked with us by the way, and while he opened to us the scriptures?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/24.31-32" class="scriptureRef">Luke 24:31–32</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p21" pid="DobBHpUo0U2thd2a-bYOOg" hash="9MmwZg">You will also recall that Jesus said to Thomas, “Be not faithless, but believing. …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p22" pid="TbxHBxLv7U2ljiyCwEaLYw" hash="s1RPtA">“Because thou hast seen me, thou hast believed: blessed are they that have not seen, and yet have believed” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/20.27,29" class="scriptureRef">John 20:27, 29</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p23" pid="lU4pXdMTqkuwIIWfEYPBCA" hash="c760Ag">Our “eyes of faith” will also be opened, and we shall know of a surety that he lives and that we shall live again, if we believe and accept the divine invitation “Walk with me” (see <a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/6.34" class="scriptureRef">Moses 6:34</a>).</p>
        <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.f3">
	  <ul class="bullet">
	    <li pid="1iCMcuW-OkSMIFqwO-5i6w" hash="M-OdOg">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="8_HzAkdbFE6Rl01xeJt4iQ" hash="VdKplw">Yes, we walk with him in the desert and feel his presence when we fast, pray, and withstand temptation.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="8yCJn3_zJUmhcY5yEUwfEA" hash="jP5gSA">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="3rmzwMAekESi7mQcfcE3ZA" hash="QPvPTA">We walk with him to Jacob’s well and our hearts burn within us when we study the scriptures and drink living waters.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="_2MFTnObsUW84W1W6tVn1g" hash="ds4a6g">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="FbM4Is61g0SMHfotAODNGQ" hash="dJtwmQ">We walk with him to Galilee when we teach and live the truth.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="-d7n-f-b5kOLxVsp3h0_jA" hash="bCrqoA">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="Y2E6CuQzTESzDk8abHnWzw" hash="-Xsyfg">We walk with him in Gethsemane when we assume the burdens of others.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="o75XlfxQAE6Jh1g1mqpN_Q" hash="eNnJjw">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="jRe6JNhwoEqmPS21JcQ6PA" hash="8yr7lQ">We walk with him to Calvary when we take up our cross by denying ourselves of all ungodliness, and every worldly lust (see JST, Matt. 16:26).</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="UCcJ1lMQwkmXDS5TGaBMfg" hash="j159Fg">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="EU2hcA58M0y3q6FAxqyLVw" hash="kJjPYA">We suffer with him on Golgotha when we sacrifice our time, talents, and means in building up the kingdom of God.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="6C2SojM-nkO08SBUKf8Iaw" hash="_WcdOw">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="6YbIOPscaEqwiuFh0fLqvA" hash="c5UBnA">We rise with him to a newness of life when we seek a spiritual rebirth and strive to become his sons and daughters.</p>
          </li>
	  </ul>
	</div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p24" pid="RSLVY4S9sUyxvaq_ghSjBw" hash="039sng">And in the process of following in his footsteps (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-pet/2.21" class="scriptureRef">1 Pet. 2:21</a>), we gain the personal conviction or infallible proof that he lives, that he is the Son of the living God, and that he is our Redeemer.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.t6">
        <h3 class="title" pid="mT2Pq-pi0kCVuobdC8RuuA" hash="JZFLeA">Conclusion</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p25" pid="9UjvIZELnE-yNe3iS1W-5A" hash="sh7hqQ">I cannot go back to that sweet old woman in the wheelchair who begged, “Can I die?” She has already crossed the bridge between earth and heaven—the bridge we call death. She now knows better than I that dying and living again are established facts. She knows of a certainty that “death is not a period but a comma in the story of life” (Amos John Traver), for she has gone back home and is cradled in the arms of God’s love (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/1.15" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 1:15</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p26" pid="dIj1SZFWW0608BJ6UmrJ0w" hash="Exzz4w">Whether young or old, we need not “look upon death with any degree of terror, for [our] hope and views of Christ and the resurrection; therefore, death [is] swallowed up to [us] by the victory of Christ over it” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/27.28" class="scriptureRef">Alma 27:28</a>). He is our Redeemer; he is “the resurrection, and the life” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/11.25" class="scriptureRef">John 11:25</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again.p27" pid="VaBv2lVEsE-kMYankZQ1fg" hash="lLybnA">I bear solemn testimony that <span class="emphasis">we shall live again!</span> Such testimony is founded upon the words of eyewitnesses, including modern prophets who have seen and heard the living God and the living Christ (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.22-24" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:22–24</a>; <a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.17" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:17</a>), and upon personal and sacred experiences of the Spirit gained in attempting to walk with God. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1994/04/if-a-man-die-shall-he-live-again</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1994-general-conference/1994-04-1030-elder-carlos-e-asay-64k-eng.mp3" length="5854848" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 1994 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stay on the True Course</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We of the Seventy extend a warm welcome to the nine men who joined our ranks yesterday. We also extend to them hands of fellowship and the promise of support in the months and years ahead.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_96905_000_024" doc-version="2" hash="-46hSQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="y-7yUQfDx0SAGk0Gw2Vm6g" hash="FZsKMg">Stay on the True Course</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Kg-7M4QE6kuwmmV9tnTMvA" hash="pDE4zw">Carlos E. Asay</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1fa0.jpg" alt="Elder Carlos E. Asay" pid="ivE8ini0PEyAzpuCa_UAuA" hash="1B6PQA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p1" pid="EM4SjkDHLUuFR7Eh_qYm6A" hash="wM2qQg">We of the Seventy extend a warm welcome to the nine men who joined our ranks yesterday. We also extend to them hands of fellowship and the promise of support in the months and years ahead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p2" pid="UmKgI58FjUeWNBNKB_q3Ig" hash="jpLTQQ">On this beautiful and sacred Easter morning, one’s thoughts center in Christ. And one’s inclination is to speak of His Atonement and the “hope for a better world” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.4" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:4</a>). However, “the [full] merits, and mercy, and grace of the Holy Messiah” are not claimed by thoughts or words alone; they are the reward of those who are sure, steadfast, and always abounding in good works (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.8" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p3" pid="zDetDOPdoUqZloW2riy-0A" hash="MfSioQ">I do, therefore, choose to speak with you concerning the imperative need to stay on the true course leading to eternal life. Such steadiness of direction requires three continuing actions: (1) the reaffirmation of the desired goal, (2) an assessment of current position, and (3) the initiation of needed course corrections. These actions harmonize with the renewal of life associated with Christ’s Resurrection and the fresh beginnings linked to this season of the year when the woes of wintertime are melted by the sunshine of spring.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p4" pid="NDNJgyqeSU2pYeylOymV7w" hash="tB5Kng">These actions are also in harmony with the Apostle Paul’s admonition, “Examine yourselves, whether ye be in the faith” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-cor/13.5" class="scriptureRef">2 Cor. 13:5</a>). Many of us receive an annual physical checkup and see our dentists twice a year. Some of us try to watch our diet, get the proper amount of rest, and exercise daily. All of this is done so that we might lengthen our days in mortality and enjoy a fulness of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p5" pid="oKdRvMcnRUeKWZdQsVwWLA" hash="V28K9A">I wonder, however, if we are paying sufficient attention to the spiritual aspects of our lives. Are we conducting frequent “spiritual checkups” to assess our standing before God and to determine whether we are on the path leading to eternal life? Alma asked: “Have ye walked, keeping yourselves blameless before God? Could ye say, if ye were called to die at this time, within yourselves, that ye have been sufficiently humble?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.27" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:27</a>). These and other questions might be used to obtain readings of our spiritual temperature and pulse rate.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="PlzK0DDrVUG2hviEA6vpSQ" hash="3BrPnA">A Reaffirmation of Goals</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p6" pid="gQaw3sZzhEimfaJq1J8d2Q" hash="xHDgrg">The ultimate goal of every clear-thinking person is to live after the manner of happiness in this world and, following death and resurrection, “dwell with God in a state of never-ending happiness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.41" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2:41</a>). “Happiness,” said the Prophet Joseph Smith, “is the object and design of our existence; and will be the end thereof, if we pursue the path that leads to it; and this path is virtue, uprightness, faithfulness, holiness, and keeping all the commandments of God” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith,</span> sel. Joseph Fielding Smith [1976], 255–56).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p7" pid="la3la536CUak9Li5wy7L0A" hash="jMpmbA">It must be remembered that “wickedness never was happiness” and never will be. Those who seek happiness in doing iniquity are seeking something “contrary to the nature of God” and “contrary to the nature of happiness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/41.10-11" class="scriptureRef">Alma 41:10–11</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p8" pid="t8RQ54YoiEeQaMJAMIUAYg" hash="_91tdg">The need to remain focused on eternal goals is illustrated in the biblical account of Jesus walking on the sea and Peter’s desire to do the same. Peter progressed over the water so long as he looked to Christ. But when he diverted his gaze away from the Master and allowed fear and doubt to enter in, he began to sink.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p9" pid="hBVkL0kju0usTHmxk2EP6g" hash="mK9LWw">If we, like Peter, keep our eyes fixed on Jesus and our eternal destination, we, too, may “walk triumphantly over the swelling waves of disbelief, and unterrified amid the rising winds of doubt” (Frederic W. Farrar, <span class="emphasis">The Life of Christ</span> [1994], 313; see also <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/14.24-31" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 14:24–31</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p10" pid="URRyeWZNXU2b4Qsiy8lmag" hash="KZ_-0w">We must not allow the things of the world to blinker our vision of the eternal destination. Nor must we permit the “voices in the world” to lead us off course (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/14.10" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 14:10</a>). Rather, we must allow the hope of Christ’s glory and of eternal life to rest in our minds forever (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/9.25" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 9:25</a>). We must reaffirm the goal that matters most and press toward it “looking forward with an eye of faith” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.40" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:40</a>).</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="xTeHtO-Nf0aNB-hWjCcw9Q" hash="tQ80-Q">An Assessment of Position</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p11" pid="8EUupKGg7E2cMtDyLpaFnA" hash="SFM5lw">Once we have reaffirmed our goal and focused our eyes and hearts upon it, we must make an assessment of our current position. At a critical time in United States history, when a famed debate raged in Congress, Daniel Webster said:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p12" pid="lHnRfAc5tk2_NoKTzo9fEA" hash="DQatSg">“Mr. President, when the mariner has been tossed about for many days in thick weather on an unknown sea, he naturally avails himself of the first pause in the storm, the earliest glance of the sun to take his latitude and ascertain how far the elements have driven him from his true course. Let us imitate this prudence and before we float on the waves of this debate refer to the point from which we departed, that we may at least be able to conjecture where we now are” (quoted in Conference Report, Oct. 1961, 78).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p13" pid="bXDVygMrokqHMtZdnaWXJw" hash="jKm1Uw">Mariners obtained their bearings by using a sextant. This instrument enabled men to measure the angular distance of the sun or the stars from the horizon, in finding the position of a ship. Those who failed to look up and make needed course corrections often perished in deep waters, whereas, the wise seaman who used the sextant in fixing position according to the light from celestial sources usually reached safe harbors.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p14" pid="EkFX_kYErkyk7OUEUeRIWg" hash="qAkgKw">The storms of life beat consistently against our “hulls.” Therefore, from time to time we, too, must take our latitude and ascertain how far the elements have driven us off the true course.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p15" pid="tZdsYnFGzk-FTyD6MrczUQ" hash="lY7OzQ">In 1916, Elder Joseph Fielding Smith declared: “The world is drifting. … Many things are tolerated today that would not have been tolerated for a moment twenty years ago. New problems have arisen with which we must now contend that we never dreamed of even in the days of my youth” (in Conference Report, Oct. 1916, 71).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p16" pid="i5NBOci9zkez2SQEfK95hQ" hash="pJik2g">Eighty years later, the slippage from traditional Christian moorings continues. Today we speak of the moral drift from gospel standards. We hear of some who belittle marriage, call divorce good, and promote relationships without natural affections. We observe some who are “tossed to and fro, and carried about with every wind of doctrine” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/4.14" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 4:14</a>). Has any of this caused us to relax rules or compromise the commandments? If so, what is it doing to us, our children, and the people around us?</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p17" pid="gB3ra1J0QkydIwE9wXni2Q" hash="L9ZiIQ">Said one insightful man, “If the temperature of the bath water rises one degree every fifteen minutes, how will the bather know when to scream?” (Marshall McLuhan). Failure on our part to fix position and take a firm stand in terms of rules, covenants, and expectations will result in a gradual float into dangerous waters and a conditioning to the rising heat of wickedness around us, and eventually all of us, especially our children, will get burned.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p18" pid="HongKksZaU2P715glMQjlA" hash="ec9F1w">We need not and must not flounder on the sea of popular opinions or drift with the waves of immorality. God is among us, and He has provided us with precious sextants to assess our spiritual latitude.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p19" pid="7uUR9JnqnEKgea9FURhV2w" hash="SjSzpA">One sextant was described by Elder Boyd K. Packer in these words: “Each of us has a sextant in our minds infinitely more refined and precise than that of any mariner. It functions on the principle of light from celestial sources as well. If we will set that sextant in our mind to the words <span class="emphasis">ordinance</span> and <span class="emphasis">covenant,</span> and then look up, light will come through. Then you will know how to fix your position and plot your course” (Regional Representatives’ seminar, 3 Apr. 1987).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p20" pid="RhQ_leCTXUODpND9BEctxg" hash="YOImDw">Alma spoke of another sextant. He suggested the need to focus our minds and hearts on the word of Christ, and then look to God. By so doing we will not only find the right latitude but also set our course toward “a far better land of promise”—even eternal life. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.44-47" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:44–47</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p21" pid="Bh1eiWBLxkudP9G7e5JZww" hash="BYSbqQ">A third sextant provided us by a loving Father in Heaven comes in the form of living prophets. A prophet issues warnings, proclaims the truth, boldly calls people to repentance, and invites all to live more fully the gospel of Christ.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p22" pid="x5NbRdItR0Ch6O3HZhTPrg" hash="gQORsw">There is the warning: “They who will not hear the voice of the Lord, neither the voice of his servants, neither <span class="emphasis">give heed to the words of the prophets and apostles,</span> shall be cut off from among the people” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:14</a>; emphasis added).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p23" pid="ZA1GPAPIA0e6CmERegTcBg" hash="i9EJfg">An assessment of one’s current position, in relationship to the ultimate goal of eternal life, can and must be obtained by looking toward the light which comes from God through personal revelation, the scriptures, and the words of living prophets.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p24" pid="qkfucI0wpUWddsZXofFH3g" hash="hNi8ow">The Psalmist said, “I thought on my ways, and turned my feet” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/119.59" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 119:59</a>). Of the prodigal son, it is written, “He came to himself” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15.17" class="scriptureRef">Luke 15:17</a>). We too must think on our ways, come to ourselves, and turn our feet toward God, who is our goal.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="60jBcEg-ikiX6ZazRcyWqQ" hash="bQVecA">Initiation of Course Corrections</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p25" pid="joTts6VsKk-HWzlKYySYsQ" hash="1uAzHw">If the assessment of current position reveals the slightest deviation from the right course leading to eternal life or the slightest drift from the mainstream of our faith, we must make immediate course corrections.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p26" pid="nZ0hbSmYCkCXHSFuFbWiXQ" hash="vIOP8g">One tormented soul cried out:</p>
        <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.f2">
          <div class="stanza">
            <p class="line" pid="n-RuA7KbTkOvndq-LF5-WA" hash="z_efgg">
              <span class="emphasis">I wish that there were some wonderful place</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="HGKQ3wHsEUC1Ilwr-i38nA" hash="XT4ykw">
              <span class="emphasis">Called the Land of Beginning Again,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="Bt_lKMzr_Eqy1iZjawNI0Q" hash="QOI23Q">
              <span class="emphasis">Where all our mistakes and all our heartaches</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="U6a0ydwPkUGVbETOhxkdug" hash="-vqPUQ">
              <span class="emphasis">And all of our poor selfish grief</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="z37Pnj2b_ESd6jjcLmNrTQ" hash="UyTelg">
              <span class="emphasis">Could be dropped like a shabby old coat at the door,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="62cAIxryEUOyVspSd8UdMQ" hash="QL9DDw">
              <span class="emphasis">And never be put on again.</span>
            </p>
          </div>
        </div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p27" pid="c1hdvPDKl0SvnhR7s0tg5w" hash="WlRKVw">There is a land of beginning again. It is the gospel of Jesus Christ. Course correction, along with a forgiveness of sins, is made possible to the repentant soul who comes unto Christ. But it requires faith, courage, and high resolve.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p28" pid="y1pP9EueS0m2FLke_a7OLA" hash="LBIkYQ">Mortality is not a pleasure cruise on some luxury liner. It is a voyage fraught with challenges and constant buffetings of winds and waves. As James A. Michener wrote: “A ship, like a human being, moves best when it is slightly athwart the wind, when it has to keep its sails tight and attend its course. Ships, like men, do poorly when the wind is directly behind, pushing them sloppily on their way so that no care is required in steering or in the management of sails; the wind seems favorable, for it blows in the direction one is heading, but actually it is destructive because it induces a relaxation in tension and skill. What is needed is a wind slightly opposed to the ship, for then tension can be maintained, and juices can flow and ideas can germinate, for ships, like men, respond to challenge” (<span class="emphasis">Chesapeake</span> [1978], 445; see also <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/123.16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 123:16</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p29" pid="FH6ORRwQdUixd2RQcmAGcg" hash="7N06ZQ">Whoever you are, wherever you live, and whatever you are doing, there will be challenges, for this is a time of testing. However, you must stay on the true course if you want to obtain happiness here and reach the safe harbor hereafter. There is no slight or insignificant deviation from the right way. One degree off latitude in the beginning becomes many degrees off course in the end.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p30" pid="u8DUf7YopUqhuh4g9N0wug" hash="57FdSg">If a “large ship is benefited … by a very small helm in the time of a storm, by being kept workways with the wind and the waves,” so are we benefited by keeping our hands on the wheels, resisting ill winds, and steering our course toward the desired port of eternal life (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/123.16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 123:16</a>). Such is done by reaffirming our goal, assessing our current position, and making needed course corrections.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p31" pid="IYFKjusGb06JPb9sudf4Cw" hash="k0C1uQ">This is the season of renewal and fresh beginnings. It is a time when our tears for the crucified Christ are wiped away by the sure knowledge of the resurrected Savior of all mankind. It is a time when “we talk of Christ, … rejoice in Christ,” and remind ourselves “that it is by grace that we are saved, <span class="emphasis">after all we can do</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/25.23,26" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 25:23, 26</a>; emphasis added).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p32" pid="YyCA2F5fFUGxhlLZ5vXHxw" hash="Z7Yg2A">Therefore, we must “be up and doing” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/60.24" class="scriptureRef">Alma 60:24</a>) and make an honest appraisal of ourselves as members of family units, members of the Church, and professed Christians. The living Christ invites us to come unto Him and to become more like Him. Is this not the object and essence of the holy Atonement?</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p33" pid="Xh4UZUwVNU6nhermV2zFSw" hash="llV31Q">Let us worship Him in spirit and in truth and celebrate His triumph over sin and death by looking to God and following the straight course to eternal happiness with even greater resolve and steadfastness.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course.p34" pid="cnZSzbp5AUWs75NWQzmZ4A" hash="Cz3I4Q">For this I pray, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1996/04/stay-on-the-true-course</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1996-general-conference/1996-04-4030-elder-carlos-e-asay-64k-eng.mp3" length="6701877" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 1996 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
