<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Carol F. McConkie</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Carol F. McConkie.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Carol%20F.%20McConkie.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Carol F. McConkie.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Live according to the Words of the Prophets</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Carol F. McConkie testifies of the divine role of prophets and the blessings that come from living by the counsel God gives us through them.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10991_000_43mcconkie" doc-version="5" hash="UNWxxg">
			
			<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.head1">
				<h1 class="title" pid="7-YlMwJ-tkOVicF8_jaEcw" hash="AJ-jhg">Live according to the Words of the Prophets</h1>
				<div class="byline">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p2" pid="e6xWUAcRFU2Mkl5LTUKthQ" hash="iZQJog">By Carol F. McConkie</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p3" pid="8a_ACT2h-UOZBPhD-oA6MA" hash="krXTEA">First Counselor in the Young Women General Presidency</p>
					<a href="gl://image/?pid=GESAS37o00mmQh2ahylPlw"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255554/907e1a6ae0a64f0581ed473dc5a66cbe/100x137.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x68="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255554/907e1a6ae0a64f0581ed473dc5a66cbe/50x68.jpg" data-src-100x137="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255554/907e1a6ae0a64f0581ed473dc5a66cbe/100x137.jpg" data-src-200x274="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255554/907e1a6ae0a64f0581ed473dc5a66cbe/200x274.jpg" data-src-320x439="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255554/907e1a6ae0a64f0581ed473dc5a66cbe/320x439.jpg" data-src-460x631="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255554/907e1a6ae0a64f0581ed473dc5a66cbe/460x631.jpg" data-src-640x879="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255554/907e1a6ae0a64f0581ed473dc5a66cbe/640x879.jpg" data-src-1024x1406="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255554/907e1a6ae0a64f0581ed473dc5a66cbe/1024x1406.jpg" data-src-2048x2813="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255554/907e1a6ae0a64f0581ed473dc5a66cbe/2048x2813.jpg" altText="Carol F. McConkie" pid="GESAS37o00mmQh2ahylPlw" hash="35kfng"></img></a>
				</div>
				<p class="kicker" pid="-mYgSvTG0U-PeM_7tDp1xg" hash="EoMuPA">To be in harmony with heaven’s divine purposes, we sustain the prophet and choose to live according to his words.</p>
			<p class="authorName" pid="bgSHDKevxEi9-VzrQo5ESA" hash="iZQJog1">By Carol F. McConkie</p></div>
			<div class="bodyBlock">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p5" pid="_N9C-mD-gUmrknv5UsCPiQ" hash="8Igi1g">Our Father in Heaven loves all of His children and desires that they know and understand His plan of happiness. Therefore, He calls prophets, those who have been ordained with power and authority to act in God’s name for the salvation of His children. They are messengers of righteousness, witnesses of Jesus Christ and the infinite power of His Atonement. They hold the keys of the kingdom of God on earth and authorize the performance of saving ordinances.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p6" pid="l0B7apIpdkGHF-uU1q91Gw" hash="N6Ks-g">In the Lord’s true Church, “there is never but one on the earth at a time on whom this power and the keys of this priesthood are conferred.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> We sustain President Thomas S. Monson as our prophet, seer, and revelator. He reveals the word of the Lord to guide and direct our <span class="emphasis">entire</span> Church. As President J. Reuben Clark Jr. explained, “The President of the Church … alone has the right to receive revelations for the Church.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p7" pid="AmY7_4wqQ0SpUxSGNNnrBA" hash="lVRV8g">Concerning the living prophet, the Lord commands the people of His Church:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p8" pid="JRkrYMD5ok6c-gBPTH1maw" hash="JGG_ag">“Thou shalt give heed unto <span class="emphasis">all</span> his words and commandments which he shall give unto you as he receiveth them, walking in all holiness before me;</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p9" pid="E8Ru09M2pUytMnMg7JmFbw" hash="uUD4iA">“For his word ye shall receive, as if from mine own mouth, in all patience and faith.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p10" pid="I78P7-Dsjk62D49anbtH6Q" hash="kUbtDw">“For by doing these things the gates of hell shall not prevail against you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p11" pid="ZrO2L2WOXEqUxtGxKEahdw" hash="EoMuPA1">To be in harmony with heaven’s divine purposes, we sustain the prophet and choose to live according to his words.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p12" pid="HFxnchzjwEOuuGyQpgjkKg" hash="mm0OhQ">We also sustain President Monson’s counselors and the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles as prophets, seers, and revelators. “They have the right, the power, and authority to declare the mind and will of [the Lord] … , subject to … the President of the Church.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> They speak in the name of Christ. They prophesy in the name of Christ. They do all things in the name of Jesus Christ. In their words we hear the voice of the Lord and we feel the Savior’s love. “And whatsoever they shall speak when moved upon by the Holy Ghost shall be scripture … and the power of God unto salvation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> The Lord Himself has spoken: “Whether by mine own voice or by the voice of my servants, it is the same.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p13" pid="TOiEHrmfaUe-gMQ3AP2gHw" hash="viKg2g">We are grateful for a church “built upon the foundation of the apostles and prophets, Jesus Christ himself being the chief corner stone.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> The Lord’s house is a house of order, and we need never be deceived about where to look for answers to our questions or uncertain about which voice to follow. We need not be “tossed to and fro, and carried about with every wind of doctrine.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> God reveals His word through His ordained servants, “for the perfecting of the saints, for the work of the ministry, for the edifying of the body of Christ: till we all come in the unity of the faith, and of the knowledge of the Son of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> When we choose to live according to the words of the prophets, we are on the covenant path that leads to eternal perfection.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p14" pid="SLdycBFCqkGOWoBr7pXBFA" hash="LSFrwA">From a single mother struggling to survive a season of famine, we learn what it means to sustain a prophet. The Lord instructed the prophet Elijah to go to Zarephath, where he would find a widow woman whom God had commanded to sustain him. As Elijah approached the city, he saw her gathering sticks. He called to her, “Fetch me, I pray thee, a little water in a vessel, that I may drink.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p15" pid="-02EWxPqCkm76Xd5BWPrwA" hash="2HV5cA">“And as she was going to fetch it, he called to her [again], and said, Bring me, I pray thee, a morsel of bread in thine hand.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p16" pid="JfKsPJHC0kCcKJKV16djLA" hash="Qj4kvg">“And she said, As the Lord thy God liveth, I have not a cake, but an handful of meal in a barrel, and a little oil in a cruse: and, behold, I am gathering two sticks, that I may go in and dress it for me and my son, that we may eat it, and die.”</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p17" pid="7-20ox-OU0WdeZinp-FXLA" hash="8DQ6TQ">Elijah responded, “Fear not; go and do as thou hast said: but make me thereof a little cake <span class="emphasis">first,</span> and bring it unto me, and after make for thee and for thy son.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p18" pid="pfwQC7yKlEigyb6uVPzl1w" hash="k2bnuw">Imagine for a moment the difficulty of what the prophet was asking a starving mother to do. Certainly, God Himself could have provided food for His faithful servant. But, acting in the name of the Lord, Elijah did as directed, which was to ask a beloved daughter of God to sacrifice that which she had in order to sustain the prophet.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p19" pid="gS8i5qBGQkm8ag-JMdJ-bw" hash="8LjqUw">But Elijah also promised a blessing for obedience: “For thus saith the Lord God of Israel, The barrel of meal shall not waste, neither shall the cruse of oil fail.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> The Lord gave the widow the opportunity to choose to believe and obey the words of the prophet.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p20" pid="glK3rbsBTEy7V46Oi9ZSzw" hash="FeJYQg">In a world threatened by a famine of righteousness and spiritual starvation, we have been commanded to sustain the prophet. As we give heed to, uphold, and affirm prophetic word, we witness that we have the faith to humbly submit to the will, the wisdom, <span class="emphasis">and</span> the timing of the Lord.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p21" pid="Q4mfS_UfFk6uaI7IXCHW2Q" hash="M9rACg">We heed prophetic word even when it may seem unreasonable, inconvenient, and uncomfortable. According to the world’s standards, following the prophet may be unpopular, politically incorrect, or socially unacceptable. But following the prophet is always right. “For as the heavens are higher than the earth, so are my ways higher than your ways, and my thoughts than your thoughts.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> “Trust in the Lord with all thine heart; and lean not unto thine own understanding.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p22" pid="2rfZMTaEuEe1mTzJEWGuTg" hash="f-APRw">The Lord honors and favors those who will heed prophetic direction. For the widow of Zarephath, obedience to Elijah saved her life and ultimately the life of her son. As the prophet had promised, “she, and he, and her house, did eat many days … according to the word of the Lord, which he spake by Elijah.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p23" pid="aK1Jxn3c70WBvSoI7ww-Yw" hash="VSK-zQ">The Lord “will feed those who trust Him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> The words of the prophets are like manna to our souls. When we partake, we are blessed, protected, and preserved both temporally and spiritually. When we feast upon their words, we learn how to come unto Christ and live.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p24" pid="lZ5lQFuvMEye9HgpbqWeQw" hash="1swObQ">Elder Bruce R. McConkie wrote that through the prophets “the Lord reveals the truths of salvation, … the salvation that is in Christ; and he charts … the course leading to eternal life. … In every age the Lord gives his people the direction they need at the moment of their peril and danger. And surely in the days ahead there will be times when nothing but the wisdom of God, descending from heaven and flowing forth from prophetic lips, will be able to save his people.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p25" pid="rvZ_fRvqrkihwBEiubiUcQ" hash="xjy5qQ">For me, the words of prophets taught by my Laurel teacher gave me a vision of what a covenant marriage relationship should look like. The words of the prophets gave me the faith and hope that I could prepare for and obtain a happy home. Consistently studying the teachings of the prophets, both ancient and modern, sustained me during the strenuous and often exhausting years of bearing, teaching, and nurturing seven children. The words of the prophets in the scriptures and taught from this pulpit are words of comfort, love, strength, and good cheer that embrace us all.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p26" pid="y8pA-FzjxEyUVs9lgBYW5A" hash="2rIUlQ">When we heed the words of the prophets, we build our homes and our lives upon an eternally sure foundation, “the rock of our Redeemer, who is Christ, the Son of God, … that when the devil shall send forth his mighty winds, yea, his shafts in the whirlwind, yea, when all his hail and his mighty storm shall beat upon you, it shall have no power over you to drag you down to … misery and endless wo.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p27" pid="njopG9bfYkOxhqUg9BztiQ" hash="t8bMdQ">We have a choice. We may choose to ignore, trifle with, trample upon, or rebel against the words of Christ spoken by His ordained servants. But the Savior taught that those who do so will be cut off from His covenant people.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p28" pid="696Z8Wamw06JvBl3mZvSzQ" hash="XJe5Wg">As we prayerfully read and study sacred prophetic word with faith in Christ, with real intent, the Holy Ghost will speak truth to our minds and hearts. May we open our ears to hear, our hearts to understand, and our minds that the mysteries of God may be unfolded to our view.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets.p29" pid="-ZvMzYu7SEulNppCqJ2Eig" hash="DTZTcQ">I bear my witness that Joseph Smith was and is the prophet called of God to restore the gospel of Jesus Christ and His priesthood to the earth. And I testify that in President Monson we are led by a true prophet of God today. May we choose to stand with the prophets and live according to their words until we become unified in faith, purified in Christ, and filled with the knowledge of the Son of God. In the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div>
			
		</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/10/live-according-to-the-words-of-the-prophets</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2014-general-conference/2014-10-4030-carol-f-mcconkie-64k-eng.mp3" length="5151777" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here to Serve a Righteous Cause</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sister Carol F. McConkie invites girls and women of all ages to serve a righteous cause as we help to build the kingdom of God.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13768_000_13mcconkie" doc-version="6" hash="oXQP1g">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="2ehGoD8ON0agFC3wHg5H6g" hash="N0RiCw">Here to Serve a Righteous Cause</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p2" pid="7Gvv9-wJREiKPSV6YiHB4Q" hash="iZQJog">By Carol F. McConkie</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p3" pid="ZUD9-gQ0pEG3hv4ZUgkuXw" hash="krXTEA">First Counselor in the Young Women General Presidency</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=Dl1b7LBf6k2ZPvrkI7vVUA"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" alt="Carol F. McConkie" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255554/907e1a6ae0a64f0581ed473dc5a66cbe/100x137.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x68="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255554/907e1a6ae0a64f0581ed473dc5a66cbe/50x68.jpg" data-src-100x137="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255554/907e1a6ae0a64f0581ed473dc5a66cbe/100x137.jpg" data-src-200x274="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255554/907e1a6ae0a64f0581ed473dc5a66cbe/200x274.jpg" data-src-320x439="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255554/907e1a6ae0a64f0581ed473dc5a66cbe/320x439.jpg" data-src-460x631="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255554/907e1a6ae0a64f0581ed473dc5a66cbe/460x631.jpg" data-src-640x879="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255554/907e1a6ae0a64f0581ed473dc5a66cbe/640x879.jpg" data-src-1024x1406="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255554/907e1a6ae0a64f0581ed473dc5a66cbe/1024x1406.jpg" data-src-2048x2813="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255554/907e1a6ae0a64f0581ed473dc5a66cbe/2048x2813.jpg" pid="Dl1b7LBf6k2ZPvrkI7vVUA" hash="35kfng"></img></a></div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="Z99yWM5hskq8VzQrx87ryA" hash="7csKQA">May we choose to serve a righteous cause as valiant emissaries of our Lord Jesus Christ.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="7rOyauOkAEWtDRwu03PuVQ" hash="rgS84w">Carol F. McConkie</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p5" pid="uHog6p63_k-w-cK_oQxurQ" hash="JZhRFQ">I am grateful that we may gather together with faithful women such as Lisa—the sister in the video—who are pure in heart, who love the Lord and serve Him, even amid their own trials. Lisa’s story reminds me that we must love one another and see in one another the beauty of the soul. The Savior taught, “Remember the worth of souls is great in the sight of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Whether we are age 8 or 108, each of us is “precious in [His] sight.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> He loves us. We are daughters of God. We are sisters in Zion. We have a divine nature, and we each have a glorious work to do.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p6" pid="8PO9Q63o10iWkFDVvUSAuQ" hash="Ds7RXA">Over the summer I visited with a lovely young mother of daughters. She shared with me her feeling that our young women need a cause, something to help them feel valued. She knew that we may discover our individual and eternal worth by acting in accordance with our divine purpose in mortality. Tonight, this beautiful and remarkable choir sang words that teach our purpose. Through test and trial, even through fear and in the midst of despair, we have valiant hearts. We are resolved to do our part. We are here to serve a righteous cause.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Sisters, in this cause we are all valued. We are all needed.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p7" pid="TODEbSH40UuwZOLE9VbJzw" hash="7aQciA">The righteous cause we serve is the cause of Christ. It is the work of salvation.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> The Lord taught, “This is my work and my glory—to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> We are the cause for which Jesus Christ suffered, bled from every pore, and in perfect love gave His life. His cause is the good news, “the glad tidings, … that he came into the world, even Jesus, to be crucified for the world, and to bear the sins of the world, and to sanctify the world, and to cleanse it from all unrighteousness; that through him all might be saved.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> Our Savior has “marked the path and led the way.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> I testify that as we follow His example, love God, and serve one another with kindness and compassion, we may stand in purity, “blameless before God at the last day.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> We choose to serve the Lord in His righteous cause that we may become one with the Father and with the Son.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p8" pid="9U7p2xvrq0-77H0tHfj1IQ" hash="IsfVjw">The prophet Mormon boldly declared, “For we have a labor to perform whilst in this tabernacle of clay, that we may conquer the enemy of all righteousness, and rest our souls in the kingdom of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> The early Church leaders and pioneers of the past pressed forward with heroic courage and determined faithfulness to establish the restored gospel and build temples where ordinances of exaltation could be performed. The pioneers of the present, meaning you and me, also press forward in faith, “to labor in [the Lord’s] vineyard for the salvation of the souls of men.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> And, as President Gordon B. Hinckley taught, “How magnificent will be the future as the Almighty rolls on His glorious work … through the selfless [service] of those whose hearts are filled with love for the Redeemer of the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> We join with faithful sisters of the past, of the present, and of the rising generation when we join together in the work of salvation!</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p9" pid="Vg5zgVZ78U6G9cnGLI6CcA" hash="ItCRZA">Before we were born, we accepted our Heavenly Father’s plan “by which [we] could obtain a physical body and gain earthly experience to progress toward perfection and ultimately realize [our] divine destiny as heirs of eternal life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> Of this premortal covenant, Elder John A. Widtsoe explained: “We agreed, right then and there, to be not only saviors for ourselves but … saviors for the whole human family. We went into a partnership with the Lord. The working out of the plan became then not merely the Father’s work, and the Savior’s work, but also our work. The least of us, the humblest, is in partnership with the Almighty in achieving the purpose of the eternal plan of salvation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p10" pid="VHvEOml5jUeedt_D2R6FcA" hash="xMN8oA">Here in mortality we have again covenanted to serve the Savior in the work of salvation. By participating in sacred priesthood ordinances, we pledge that we will embark in the service of God with heart, might, mind, and strength.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> We receive the Holy Ghost and seek His promptings to guide our efforts. Righteousness emanates out to the world when we understand what God wants us to do and then we do it.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p11" pid="ZemK2ULXw06FvLuAei9l5Q" hash="rp_P1A">I know a Primary child who said to a friend while standing at the bus stop, “Hey! You ought to come to church with me and learn about Jesus!”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p12" pid="9MYtyRKLDEuS3d9YgVsbDQ" hash="khW1Fg">I saw the girls in a Young Women class link arms together and make a commitment to minister to one another and then plan an appropriate way to help a young woman who was struggling with an addiction.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p13" pid="a0FyLsJbc0-YLIl-1UdAJw" hash="LYT2KQ">I have seen young mothers give everything of their time, their talents, and their energies to teach and exemplify the principles of the gospel so that their children, like the sons of Helaman, may stand courageously and faithfully through trial, temptation, and adversity.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p14" pid="ba3pAympv0CuaPbtVk8NTA" hash="o0KUsA">But perhaps most humbling to me was to hear a single adult sister declare with the fire of pure testimony that the most important work we can do is to prepare for marriage and family. Although this is not her experience, she knows that family is the very heart of the work of salvation. “The divine plan of happiness enables family relationships to be perpetuated beyond the grave.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> We honor the Father’s plan and glorify God when we strengthen and ennoble those relationships in the new and everlasting covenant of marriage. We choose to live pure and virtuous lives so that when the opportunity comes, we are prepared to make that sacred covenant in the house of the Lord and keep it forever.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p15" pid="ggOjW_7DAUOdKO_U4XR4Xg" hash="HJgOXQ">We all experience times and seasons in our lives. But whether we are at school, at work, in the community, or especially in the home, we are the Lord’s agents and we are on His errand.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p16" pid="loTEt-KUkEe_fND02Gmh0A" hash="8ErM0A">In the work of salvation, there is no room for comparison, criticism, or condemnation. It is not about age, experience, or public acclaim. This sacred work is about developing a broken heart, a contrite spirit, and a willingness to use our divine gifts and unique talents to do the Lord’s work in His way. It is having the humility to fall on our knees and say, “O my Father, … not as I will, but as thou wilt.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p17" pid="-O7Dk3aPeUKthUH2JV61qA" hash="je-b3w">In the strength of the Lord, we “can do all things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> We continually seek His guidance in prayer, in the scriptures, and in the whisperings of the Holy Ghost. One sister, faced with an overwhelming assignment, wrote, “Sometimes I wonder if the sisters in the early history of the Church didn’t, like us, put their heads on their pillows at night and pray, ‘Whatever tomorrow brings, will Thou help me through it?’” Then she wrote, “One of the blessings is [that] we have each other and we are in this together!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> Whatever our circumstances, wherever we are along the path toward salvation, we unite as one in our commitment to the Savior. We sustain one another in His service.</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=maT_Ni8tIkaB4LFIuxMEYQ"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572880/f5e6ceae94ba4f6d8c5c18250f3ddb91/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572880/f5e6ceae94ba4f6d8c5c18250f3ddb91/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572880/f5e6ceae94ba4f6d8c5c18250f3ddb91/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572880/f5e6ceae94ba4f6d8c5c18250f3ddb91/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572880/f5e6ceae94ba4f6d8c5c18250f3ddb91/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572880/f5e6ceae94ba4f6d8c5c18250f3ddb91/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572880/f5e6ceae94ba4f6d8c5c18250f3ddb91/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572880/f5e6ceae94ba4f6d8c5c18250f3ddb91/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572880/f5e6ceae94ba4f6d8c5c18250f3ddb91/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572880/f5e6ceae94ba4f6d8c5c18250f3ddb91/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Ella Hoskins completes Personal Progress" pid="maT_Ni8tIkaB4LFIuxMEYQ" hash="mRGhzw"></img></a>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p18" pid="4iRcXpmkuEKJTnDoYUi2Ng" hash="SwZXPw">Recently, you may have read about Sister Ella Hoskins, who at 100 years old was called to help the young women in her ward with Personal Progress.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> About two years later, at 102, Sister Hoskins earned her Young Womanhood Recognition award. The young women, the ward and stake Young Women and Relief Society presidencies, and family members gathered together to celebrate her accomplishment. Boundaries of age, organization, and marital status faded away in faithful service. Young women expressed gratitude for Sister Hoskins, for her teaching, and for her righteous example. They want to be like her. Afterward, I asked Sister Hoskins, “How did you do it?”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p19" pid="saCaemTWdUqUE5nQn9vm_g" hash="ObsVRA">She promptly responded, “I repent every day.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p20" pid="n0nMXCv-gUCZ1oVuhDHYnQ" hash="grhrtg">From a gentle lady, so full of the Spirit of the Lord that she glowed with pure light, I was reminded that to shine with the beauty of holiness, to stand with the Savior, and to bless others, we must be clean. Purity is possible through the grace of Christ as we deny ungodliness and choose to love God with might, mind, and strength.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> The Apostle Paul taught, “Flee … youthful lusts: … follow righteousness, faith, charity, peace, with them that call on the Lord out of a pure heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> None of us is perfect. We have all made mistakes. But we repent so that we may be better and “retain the name [of Christ] written always in [our] hearts.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> When we serve in the name of the Lord, with purity of heart, we reflect the Savior’s love and give others a glimpse of heaven.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause.p21" pid="7bOxwD6iwkqcTRIl0JSOuA" hash="T61asg">May we choose to serve a righteous cause as valiant emissaries of our Lord Jesus Christ. Let us stand together and “with a song in [our] heart[s] move forward, living the gospel, loving the Lord, and building [His] kingdom.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> I testify that in this glorious work, we may know the pure love of God. We may receive true joy and obtain all the glories of eternity. In the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/10/here-to-serve-a-righteous-cause</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2015-general-conference/2015-09-0050-carol-f-mcconkie-64k-eng.mp3" length="5569004" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Soul’s Sincere Desire</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sister McConkie teaches that our prayers involve all three members of the Godhead: we pray to the Father in the name of Christ by the power of the  Holy Ghost.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60001311_000_23mcconkie" doc-version="1" hash="h5GTLQ">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="Eu7CauPYlEi4tLC0X_55pg" hash="hsB1RA">The Soul’s Sincere Desire</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p2" pid="Les_lzXgVUitt1q3hK_hVg" hash="iZQJog1">By Carol F. McConkie</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p3" pid="6R5a3qTpZki1TghqvkayeQ" hash="krXTEA">First Counselor in the Young Women General Presidency</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="kidCh8FY0UG7cs9UMf2RRA" hash="BgIBXg">Every moment of precious prayer can be holy time spent with our Father, in the name of the Son, by the power of the Holy Ghost.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="nabGQAc3o0uVasySoVYXKw" hash="iZQJog">By Carol F. McConkie</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p5" pid="Cpd5NESMkUOfX5AC-GmJmw" hash="__NaZg">In the struggles of mortality, we are never left alone to accomplish our work, to fight our battles, to face adversity or unanswered questions. Jesus Christ taught with a parable “that men ought always to pray, and not to faint.” He told of a judge who did not honor God and did not have any regard for mankind. Repeatedly, a widow came before him, pleading to be avenged of her adversary. For a while, the judge would offer her no relief. But as a result of her faithful, consistent pleading, the judge finally thought, “Because this widow troubleth me, I will avenge her, lest by her continual coming she weary me.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p6" pid="PYieuj7uBEu2xKuWPSRPeg" hash="nj2PcQ">Then Jesus explained:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p7" pid="IAo4Y7q_RUe76xFlAOrJHw" hash="a2WJrQ">“Shall not God avenge his own elect, which cry day and night unto him … ?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p8" pid="gJObmTjSDEu0fmSCekxr3w" hash="mF_wMw">“I tell you that he will avenge them speedily.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p9" pid="x8o2wPofh0u4XBpbA4aTTQ" hash="98O62g">And then the Lord asks this question: “Nevertheless when the Son of man cometh, shall he find faith on the earth?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p10" pid="qghU8ByrvkK9zEEZNLd0hg" hash="88Akww">Prayer is essential to developing faith. When the Lord comes again, will He find a people who know how to pray in faith and who are prepared to receive salvation? “For whosoever shall call upon the name of the Lord shall be saved.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> We are children of a loving Heavenly Father, and we may enjoy personal communion with Him when we pray “with a sincere heart, with real intent, having faith in Christ”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> and then act in accordance with the answers we receive by the promptings of the Holy Ghost. In faith we pray, we listen, and we obey, that we might learn to become one with the Father and the Son.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p11" pid="ch_b5ZKukkiAD-lcj7TUwg" hash="0vtAvA">A prayer of faith opens the way to receive glorious heaven-sent blessings. The Savior taught:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p12" pid="arpTs0JTGkOeonPD6pllAQ" hash="OMaxbA">“Ask, and it shall be given you; seek, and ye shall find; knock, and it shall be opened unto you:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p13" pid="CoC1OQtFbUWi3C_fVkIAqg" hash="zZBS2w">“For every one that asketh receiveth; and he that seeketh findeth; and to him that knocketh it shall be opened.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p14" pid="EXLpoeWEZ0KT-AjMLn4UvQ" hash="zbIMWw">If we expect to receive, we must ask, seek, and knock. In his search for truth, Joseph Smith read from the scriptures, “If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask of God, that giveth to all men liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> In answer to his prayer of faith, the heavens were opened. God the Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, descended in glory and spoke to Joseph Smith, ushering in the dispensation of the fulness of times. For us, miraculous healing, powerful protection, divine knowledge, liberating forgiveness, and precious peace are among the answers that come when we offer up a “soul’s sincere desire”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> in faith.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p15" pid="xprlsCPKH0emElv_je6R2Q" hash="cTr63g">We pray to our Father in the name of Jesus Christ, by the power of the Holy Ghost, thus engaging all three members of the Godhead in our utterances.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p16" pid="slMcxYnNsUeskf8jaTKbZg" hash="vlD6Xg"><span class="strong">We pray to our Heavenly Father</span> and Him only because He is “God in heaven, who is infinite and eternal, from everlasting to everlasting … , the framer of heaven and earth, and all things which are in them.” As our Creator, He gave commandments that we “should love and serve him, the only living and true God, and that he should be the only being whom [we] should worship.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p17" pid="u2eOXIQXeEK7D-K8zNvskA" hash="v67mGQ">As you pray to Heavenly Father in faith, “he will console you in your afflictions, … [and ye may] feast upon his love.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> President Henry B. Eyring shared that his father’s prayers during a losing battle with cancer taught him the deeply personal relationship between God and His children:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p18" pid="Wh09zPdUl0ifCM9aIqKRhQ" hash="KL8cBw">“When the pain became intense, we found him in the morning on his knees by the bed. He had been too weak to get back into bed. He told us he had been praying to ask his Heavenly Father why he had to suffer so much when he had always tried to be good. He said a kindly answer came: ‘God needs brave sons.’</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p19" pid="JLIXmlIYmkOQGEN9sXEpnw" hash="OMY_mg">“And so he soldiered on to the end, trusting that God loved him, listened to him, and would lift him up. He was blessed to have known early and to never forget that a loving God is as close as a prayer.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p20" pid="byWDsf3rw0OUIuBvhXvfUg" hash="4P7DXw"><span class="strong">We pray in the name of Jesus Christ </span>because our salvation is in Christ, and “there is none other name under heaven given among men, whereby we must be saved.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> We come unto the Father in the sacred name of Jesus Christ<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> because He is our Advocate with the Father and He does plead our cause.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> He suffered, bled, and died to glorify His Father, and His merciful petition on our behalf opens the way for each of us to obtain peace in this life and everlasting life in the world to come. He does not want us to suffer longer or endure more trials than needed. He does want us to turn to Him and allow Him to ease our burdens, to heal our hearts, and to cleanse our souls through His purifying power. We never want to take His name in vain with rote and repetitious words. Sincere prayers offered in the holy name of Jesus Christ are an expression of our devoted love, our eternal gratitude, and our steadfast desire to pray as He prayed, to do as He did, and to become as He is.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p21" pid="IQBsRg1AT0mWfFHBRO1UUQ" hash="gUXmfQ"><span class="strong">We pray by the power of the Holy Ghost</span> because “he that asketh in the Spirit asketh according to the will of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> When we pray with faith, the Holy Ghost can guide our thoughts so that our words harmonize with the will of God. “Ask not, that ye may consume it on your lusts, but ask with a firmness unshaken, that ye will yield to no temptation, but that ye will serve the true and living God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p22" pid="rZSbYeL8XUKnOJ1oYV63qg" hash="gW5iHw">“It is not only important that we shall know how to pray, but it is equally important that we shall know how to receive the answer to our prayer, to be discerning, to be alert, to be able to see with clear vision and understand with clear intention God’s will and purpose concerning us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p23" pid="OAX_BVBSDU-rl2Ely2Hupg" hash="1rt3NQ">President Eyring shared: “I have had prayers answered. Those answers were most clear when what I wanted was silenced by an overpowering need to know what God wanted. It is then that the answer from a loving Heavenly Father can be spoken to the mind by the still, small voice and can be written on the heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=TkJIPe4B3U-ugVaLuyvZhw"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813767/59b71143422448c2a811aa69eaa4f791/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813767/59b71143422448c2a811aa69eaa4f791/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813767/59b71143422448c2a811aa69eaa4f791/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813767/59b71143422448c2a811aa69eaa4f791/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813767/59b71143422448c2a811aa69eaa4f791/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813767/59b71143422448c2a811aa69eaa4f791/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813767/59b71143422448c2a811aa69eaa4f791/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813767/59b71143422448c2a811aa69eaa4f791/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813767/59b71143422448c2a811aa69eaa4f791/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813767/59b71143422448c2a811aa69eaa4f791/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Christ with the Apostles" pid="TkJIPe4B3U-ugVaLuyvZhw" hash="RN880g"></img></a>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=jSlrjBeoJUaupjYHDMAUcA"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813783/bd12ea9266764b919500b3810f174c2e/200x129.png" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813783/bd12ea9266764b919500b3810f174c2e/50x32.png" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813783/bd12ea9266764b919500b3810f174c2e/100x64.png" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813783/bd12ea9266764b919500b3810f174c2e/200x129.png" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813783/bd12ea9266764b919500b3810f174c2e/320x206.png" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813783/bd12ea9266764b919500b3810f174c2e/460x296.png" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813783/bd12ea9266764b919500b3810f174c2e/640x412.png" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813783/bd12ea9266764b919500b3810f174c2e/1024x660.png" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813783/bd12ea9266764b919500b3810f174c2e/2048x1321.png" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813783/bd12ea9266764b919500b3810f174c2e/2790x1800.png" altText="Christ in Gethsemane" pid="jSlrjBeoJUaupjYHDMAUcA" hash="fFAbLg"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p24" pid="BQAV3G9O4kOQqXAFr8NaiA" hash="UP8lVA">As the Savior entered the Garden of Gethsemane, His soul was exceedingly sorrowful, even unto death. In His agony, the only one He could turn to was His Father. He pleaded, “If it be possible, let this cup pass from me.” But He added, “Nevertheless not as I will, but as thou wilt.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> Though sinless, the Savior was called upon to “[suffer] pains and afflictions and temptations of every kind,” including the sicknesses and infirmities of His people. “[He] suffereth according to the flesh that he might take upon him the sins of his people, that he might blot out their transgressions according to the power of his deliverance.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> Three times He prayed, “Father, thy will be done.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> The cup was not removed. In humble, faithful prayer He was strengthened to go forward and fulfill His divine mission to prepare for our salvation, that we might repent, believe, obey, and obtain the blessings of eternity.</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=uTIi5VrBsUa58oqzzlkljA"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813785/f4f593a1dba043428886002cfbf20912/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813785/f4f593a1dba043428886002cfbf20912/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813785/f4f593a1dba043428886002cfbf20912/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813785/f4f593a1dba043428886002cfbf20912/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813785/f4f593a1dba043428886002cfbf20912/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813785/f4f593a1dba043428886002cfbf20912/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813785/f4f593a1dba043428886002cfbf20912/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813785/f4f593a1dba043428886002cfbf20912/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813785/f4f593a1dba043428886002cfbf20912/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813785/f4f593a1dba043428886002cfbf20912/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Christ praying in Gethsemane" pid="uTIi5VrBsUa58oqzzlkljA" hash="Dnxi-Q"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p25" pid="K0O-MQ_VWEW3MRIVEIy08Q" hash="4Epxdg">The answers we receive in prayer may not be what we would desire. But in times of trouble, our prayers become a lifeline of love and tender mercy. In our pleading, we may be strengthened to go forward and fulfill all that we have been ordained to do. To His Saints living in perilous times, the Lord says, “Let your hearts be comforted … ; for all flesh is in mine hands; be still and know that I am God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p26" pid="Jz_trf9LsU6YJM1-MO2ADA" hash="tHzTEA">Whether we pray privately, with our families, at church, in the temple, or wherever we are; whether we pray with broken hearts and contrite spirits seeking forgiveness, heavenly wisdom, or simply the strength to endure, we pray <span class="emphasis">always</span> with full hearts, drawn out unto God continually for our welfare and the welfare of those around us. Sincere desires offered in a spirit of gratitude for abundant blessings and gratitude for the lessons of life instill in our hearts steadfast faith in Christ, a “brightness of hope, and a love of God and of all men.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire.p27" pid="Z07nSuxf5E-B3lp2u3jOYA" hash="bSmVBQ">Prayer is a gift from God. We need never feel lost or alone. I testify that every moment of precious prayer can be holy time spent with our Father, in the name of the Son, by the power of the Holy Ghost. In the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/10/the-souls-sincere-desire</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2016-general-conference/2016-10-1030-carol-f-mcconkie-64k-eng.mp3" length="5601340" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Beauty of Holiness</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sister McConkie encourages sisters to live up to their divine heritage of holiness by keeping covenants, following the Spirit, and relying on Jesus Christ.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60003501_000_12mcconkie" doc-version="1" hash="MwqIIw">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="wcSHF1EC6EuagL6BTe93YQ" hash="yMXKhA">The Beauty of Holiness</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p2" pid="35QJRKyYxkugjS2np7OJDQ" hash="iZQJog1">By Carol F. McConkie</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p3" pid="iLyQ_i0FgUCbMX9E-UL7Fw" hash="krXTEA">First Counselor in the Young Women General Presidency</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="UGnoPTx9m0ujjvKhehxWkg" hash="vQ5DnA">Our Father in Heaven has provided for us all that is required so that we can become holy as He is holy.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="26lEWaEy0Ue4RGxvVenfHA" hash="iZQJog">By Carol F. McConkie</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p5" pid="bAb7OWOJA0SwfWaPIlazLw" hash="ugPL8g">As I have prepared for this meeting, my heart has turned to the many faithful sisters whom I have met, near and far. For me, they are best described in a psalm of thanksgiving by King David: “Give unto the Lord the glory due unto his name: bring an offering, and come before him: worship the Lord in the beauty of holiness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p6" pid="zXGLk3SLXEGPubgB5HdxYw" hash="jZ8-4Q">I see the beauty of holiness in sisters whose hearts are centered on all that is good, who want to become more like the Savior. They offer their whole soul, heart, might, mind, and strength to the Lord in the way that they live every day.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Holiness is in the striving and the struggle to keep the commandments and to honor the covenants we have made with God. Holiness is making the choices that will keep the Holy Ghost as our guide.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Holiness is setting aside our natural tendencies and becoming “a saint through the atonement of Christ the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> “Every moment of [our lives] must be holiness to the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p7" pid="Ds13pd1ya0OGFgnHbhLO8w" hash="gjlkPg">The God of heaven commanded the children of Israel, “For I am the Lord your God: ye shall therefore sanctify yourselves, and ye shall be holy; for I am holy: neither shall ye defile yourselves.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p8" pid="t3dMLKEeUkGitM8ui3vLOw" hash="I6PJAA">Elder D. Todd Christofferson has taught: “Our Heavenly Father is a God of high expectations. … He proposes to make us holy so that we may ‘abide a celestial glory’ (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:22</a>) and ‘dwell in his presence’ (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/6.57" class="scriptureRef">Moses 6:57</a>).”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span><span class="emphasis"> Lectures on Faith</span> explains, “No being can enjoy his glory without possessing his perfections and holiness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Our Father in Heaven knows us. He loves us, and He has provided for us all that is required so that we can become holy as He is holy.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p9" pid="7p7HVqwtcUu1dvI19LzWmw" hash="bcn4Mg">We are daughters of Heavenly Father, and each of us has a divine heritage of holiness. Our Father in Heaven has declared, “Behold, I am God; Man of Holiness is my name.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> In the premortal world, we loved our Father and worshipped Him. We desired to be like Him. Out of perfect paternal love, He gave His Beloved Son, Jesus Christ, to be our Savior and Redeemer. He is the Son of Man of Holiness.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> His “name is Holy,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> “the Holy One of Israel.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p10" pid="P7FQRFM7CEeC3v3ytMDBSA" hash="Ti5FDQ">Our hope for holiness is centered in Christ, in His mercy and His grace. With faith in Jesus Christ and His Atonement, we may become clean, without spot, when we deny ourselves of ungodliness<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> and sincerely repent. We are baptized by water for the remission of sins. Our souls are sanctified when we receive the Holy Ghost with open hearts. Weekly, we partake of the ordinance of the sacrament. In a spirit of repentance, with sincere desires for righteousness, we covenant that we are willing to take upon us the name of Christ, remember Him, and keep His commandments so that we may always have His Spirit to be with us. Over time, as we continually strive to become one with the Father, the Son, and the Holy Ghost, we become partakers of Their divine nature.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.t1">
				<h2 pid="CN0lRMHr50WjwyYBKzwrPQ" hash="5qcl-A">Holiness Is Keeping Our Covenants</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p12" pid="KgQmjYICrEykZbmLupedtw" hash="M9Lbbg">We recognize the multitude of tests, temptations, and tribulations that could pull us away from all that is virtuous and praiseworthy before God. But our mortal experiences offer us the opportunity to choose holiness. Most often it is the sacrifices we make to keep our covenants that sanctify us and make us holy.</p>
				<a href="gl://image/?pid=4CgtpOgC3ku97dv7iy59qg"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908452/edb1806951a9491dbd2396b6fff30f9d/100x123.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x61="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908452/edb1806951a9491dbd2396b6fff30f9d/50x61.jpg" data-src-100x123="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908452/edb1806951a9491dbd2396b6fff30f9d/100x123.jpg" data-src-200x246="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908452/edb1806951a9491dbd2396b6fff30f9d/200x246.jpg" data-src-320x394="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908452/edb1806951a9491dbd2396b6fff30f9d/320x394.jpg" data-src-460x567="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908452/edb1806951a9491dbd2396b6fff30f9d/460x567.jpg" data-src-640x789="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908452/edb1806951a9491dbd2396b6fff30f9d/640x789.jpg" data-src-1024x1262="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908452/edb1806951a9491dbd2396b6fff30f9d/1024x1262.jpg" data-src-1460x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908452/edb1806951a9491dbd2396b6fff30f9d/1460x1800.jpg" altText="Evangeline, a young woman in Ghana" pid="4CgtpOgC3ku97dv7iy59qg" hash="AAAAAA1"></img></a>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p13" pid="3LV3uwSPIkyNy2M1CrRb2A" hash="FExd9g">I saw holiness in the countenance of Evangeline, a 13-year-old girl in Ghana. One of the ways she keeps her covenants is by magnifying her calling as the Beehive class president. She humbly explained that she goes to the homes of her friends, the less-active young women, to ask their parents to allow them to come to church. The parents tell her that it is difficult because on Sunday the children must do household chores. So Evangeline goes and helps with the chores, and by her efforts her friends are often permitted to come to church.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p14" pid="b__LFBY1qEeWIZf0pDnHjQ" hash="I3RRog">If we will keep the associated covenants, the sacred priesthood ordinances will change us, sanctify us, and prepare us to enter the presence of the Lord.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> So we bear one another’s burdens; we strengthen one another. We retain a remission of sins when we give spiritual and temporal relief to the poor, the hungry, the naked, and the sick.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> We keep ourselves unspotted from the world when we keep the Sabbath day and worthily receive the sacrament on the Lord’s holy day.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p15" pid="hS4HfTB79Eym5GAcTZBC_A" hash="bbMCtQ">We bless our families and make our homes holy places. We bridle our passions so that we may be filled with pure and lasting love.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> We reach out to others in kindness, with compassion, and stand as witnesses of God. We become a Zion people, of one heart and one mind, a pure people who dwell together in unity and righteousness.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> “For Zion must increase in beauty, and in holiness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p16" pid="q7Vvm45B_kefjEw9KFmIBQ" hash="oCF_Nw">Sisters, come to the temple. If we are to be a holy people prepared to receive the Savior at His coming, we must arise and put on our beautiful garments.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> In strength and honor, we forsake the ways of the world and keep our covenants, that we may be “clothed with purity, yea, even with the robe of righteousness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span></p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.t2">
				<h2 pid="Yrv7TOGZ9UClM7Qk_1U0eQ" hash="C1fN8A">Holiness Is Taking the Holy Ghost as Our Guide</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p18" pid="8_NCYWLpFkq_XKulBwjx1A" hash="_3BHdA">Holiness is a gift of the Spirit. We accept this gift when we choose to do those things that will increase the sanctifying power of the Holy Ghost in our lives.</p>
				<a href="gl://image/?pid=t3yi6KJ80kSOXQYqIHq1Mg"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908481/bb74fe0639714b4dbff5207af04e4a96/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908481/bb74fe0639714b4dbff5207af04e4a96/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908481/bb74fe0639714b4dbff5207af04e4a96/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908481/bb74fe0639714b4dbff5207af04e4a96/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908481/bb74fe0639714b4dbff5207af04e4a96/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908481/bb74fe0639714b4dbff5207af04e4a96/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908481/bb74fe0639714b4dbff5207af04e4a96/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908481/bb74fe0639714b4dbff5207af04e4a96/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908481/bb74fe0639714b4dbff5207af04e4a96/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908481/bb74fe0639714b4dbff5207af04e4a96/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Mary heard the Savior’s words" pid="t3yi6KJ80kSOXQYqIHq1Mg" hash="AAAAAA"></img></a>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p19" pid="sVBnv2KovEGgT8MgQOcPcg" hash="7sXBwA">When Martha received Jesus Christ into her home, she felt a tremendous desire to serve the Lord to the best of her ability. Her sister, Mary, chose to sit “at Jesus’ feet” and to hear His word. When Martha felt burdened about serving without any help, she complained, “Lord, dost thou not care that my sister hath left me to serve alone?”</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p20" pid="Y-7gbCQgH0SWeq_eYVxqSQ" hash="pRvrZQ">I love the words of the most gentle rebuke that I can imagine. With perfect love and infinite compassion, the Savior admonished:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p21" pid="dWhu-OWhB0mYSF8Be3eSIw" hash="MwG5rw">“Martha, Martha, thou art careful and troubled about many things:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p22" pid="78e5ePjobk-AIAC_7gkR4Q" hash="fqBaSA">“But one thing is needful: and Mary hath chosen that good part, which shall not be taken away from her.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p23" pid="8AUXK2ASck-oq5vGw3diig" hash="wIStog">Sisters, if we would be holy, we must learn to sit at the feet of the Holy One of Israel and give time to holiness. Do we set aside the phone, the never-ending to-do list, and the cares of worldliness? Prayer, study, and heeding the word of God invite His cleansing and healing love into our souls. Let us take time to be holy, that we may be filled with His sacred and sanctifying Spirit. With the Holy Ghost as our guide, we will be prepared to receive the Savior in the beauty of holiness.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span></p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.t3">
				<h2 pid="2tL8SnqyWEKix5uIan4rjQ" hash="-No1Bw">Holiness Is Becoming a Saint through the Atonement of Jesus Christ</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p25" pid="UiiPt23bsECCx-2WJDcnnQ" hash="7GNkdQ">According to the inspired words of King Benjamin, those who become saints through the Atonement of Jesus Christ are those who are submissive, meek, humble, patient, and full of love, as the Savior is.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span> He prophesied that Jesus Christ, “the Lord Omnipotent who reigneth, who was, and is from all eternity to all eternity, shall come down from heaven among the children of men, and shall dwell in a tabernacle of clay.” He came to bless the sick, the lame, the deaf, and the blind and to raise those who had died to life. And yet He suffered “more than man can suffer, except it be unto death.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26">26</span> And though He is the only one through whom salvation comes, He was mocked, scourged, and crucified. But the Son of God rose from the grave, that we may all overcome death. He is the one who will stand to judge the world in righteousness. He is the one who will redeem us all. He is the Holy One of Israel. Jesus Christ is the beauty of holiness.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p26" pid="KpY3BEXzsU6Nbgi-l6_WBA" hash="dS8esg">When King Benjamin’s people heard his words, they fell to the ground, so great was their humility and reverence for the grace and the glory of our God. They recognized their carnal state. Do we see our utter dependence on the grace and mercy of Christ, our Lord? Do we recognize that every good gift, temporal and spiritual, comes to us through Christ? Do we remember that according to the Father’s eternal plan, peace in this life and the glories of eternity are ours only in and through His holy Son?</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p27" pid="Rm3INKlyEEW9gwqogQknQA" hash="S37e0w">May we join with the people of King Benjamin as they cried aloud with one voice, “O have mercy, and apply the atoning blood of Christ that we may receive forgiveness of our sins, and our hearts may be purified; for we believe in Jesus Christ, the Son of God, who created heaven and earth, and all things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_27">27</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p28" pid="HOXKX84JskCxm5fhbKrftQ" hash="tubw-w">I testify that as we come unto the Holy One of Israel, His Spirit will come upon us, that we may be filled with joy and receive a remission of sins and peace of conscience.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness.p29" pid="kxrZ__0HWkiQezkPXyyD8g" hash="IPV44w">Heavenly Father has given each of us the capacity to become holy. May we do our best to keep our covenants and take the Holy Ghost as our guide. With faith in Jesus Christ, we become saints through His Atonement, that we may receive immortality and eternal life and give God our Father the glory due His name. May our lives ever be a sacred offering, that we may stand before the Lord in the beauty of holiness. In the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2017/04/the-beauty-of-holiness</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2017-general-conference/2017-03-0020-carol-f-mcconkie-64k-eng.mp3" length="5918020" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
