<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Carol B. Thomas</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Carol B. Thomas.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Carol%20B.%20Thomas.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Carol B. Thomas.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Mar 1998 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 1998 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Our True Identity</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1998/04/understanding-our-true-identity?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Long ago you and I were born as daughters in our Heavenly Father’s family. … Each one of you was a valiant and noble woman in your premortal life.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/understanding-our-true-identity" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_98905_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="EkdSig">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/understanding-our-true-identity.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="r_LBE1i6I0yjaoeQHnJYTA" hash="CcTw7g">Understanding Our True Identity</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="vuw4EL7MykiI5XOoCCSpnQ" hash="jTox9A">Carol B. Thomas</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="2R-eJiLsBU-9V4ojHKi_ag" hash="_PvlTA">Long ago you and I were born as daughters in our Heavenly Father’s family. … Each one of you was a valiant and noble woman in your premortal life.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/understanding-our-true-identity.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1d68.jpg" alt="Carol B. Thomas" pid="flR26tWMX023VACoK5-EHA" hash="0aznWQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/understanding-our-true-identity.p1" pid="j8FZccuMnES4ZayO_Oa7TA" hash="bDcXyg">Family—what a sacred name for those we love the most. If someone asked you to name the greatest thing about your family, what would it be? I know that most families, including mine, are not perfect, but every day we are trying to be more kind and thoughtful to each other. This past month my father died. I learned many lessons from my dad. He had such great faith. He said, “Dying is just like walking into another room.” The day he died, I thought: <span class="emphasis">My dad died today! This was his last day on earth! He has just walked into another room.</span> It was such a sweet, sacred experience for my family and me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/understanding-our-true-identity.p2" pid="aKtK8jFhQk6jg4rhui6Y6A" hash="33W-VQ">It was my father who taught me about the premortal life. He explained that long ago you and I were born as daughters in our Heavenly Father’s family. We made sacred decisions there that have influenced what we are doing now. When I was younger, my grandfather gave me a blessing. He blessed me that I would “continue my ministry here that I had so nobly performed there.” Now, if I had a ministry in the premortal existence, then so did you. It is not by chance that you were born now, in this season of the world’s history. Each one of you was a valiant and noble woman in your premortal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/understanding-our-true-identity.p3" pid="arxYUy6UukmbIn9JUpCywQ" hash="rJCUeg">Abraham said, “Now the Lord had shown unto me, Abraham, the intelligences that were organized before the world was; and among all these … were many of the noble and great ones” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.22" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:22</a>). Do you know that he was talking about you? You are each noble and great, born to live at this time on the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/understanding-our-true-identity.p4" pid="hbDA9NXcmEmjX9w-1a5gVQ" hash="xKseYQ">We all come from many different kinds of families. Some of you are doing hard things, and you are doing them so very well. Some of you may worry about your relationships with your mother or father as you learn together how to live in families. You are learning that sometimes the Savior calms the storm. Sometimes He lets the storm rage and calms you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/understanding-our-true-identity.p5" pid="RFWO19GLHUWa-fVQDD7KDQ" hash="aHyB-g">Paraphrasing what Elder Jeffrey R. Holland once said, “The [home] is not a monastery for perfect people”; sometimes it is a hospital where we nurse and take care of those we love (see “‘He Hath Filled the Hungry with Good Things,’” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1997, 66).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/understanding-our-true-identity.p6" pid="1AH40IzQPE-Q6KUZfMy4dQ" hash="CywVXw">One young woman wrote: “Every person in my family has hard times, but I try to be there for them and help them out. … We want to be together for all eternity.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/understanding-our-true-identity.p7" pid="UfLTsmYqrE-tyHpRfDGpCg" hash="GLqeMQ">We are so impressed that each of you young women is turning your heart to your family. One young woman scatters sunshine wherever she goes. She writes: “I help my family by making them laugh. When they are sad, I try to make them happy again.” Another young woman said: “Since I live in a family of nonmembers, myself included, I think that my service is being an example of a young woman trying to live the gospel. I bring to my house, little by little, the blessings and the good feelings that I receive from the one true church.” In Africa, two young women from Ghana who are sisters sing the beautiful songs of Zion, bringing a spirit of peace to their own family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/understanding-our-true-identity.p8" pid="VDSfGXlJlEWGmT6FEPW7rQ" hash="2Z_2aA">Sometimes young women have special challenges when the family isn’t complete. Last summer in Alaska, I met a Young Women president whose mother had died when she was three. She had been raised by her father, joining the Church at age 14. I asked her how she had learned to do all the feminine things, like fixing her hair and setting a pretty table. She said: “I watched my Young Women leaders! When I saw one of them who knew how to cook, I thought, <span class="emphasis">I want to be just like her.</span> Now, every time I clean my house, I think of my Laurel adviser.” So even if your own families are less than perfect, you can think about and plan for your own future family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/understanding-our-true-identity.p9" pid="3uCwr_aAP0-iZMgnYWNXug" hash="fI6z_g">As each one of you practices being a homemaker, you are doing exactly what the Lord wants you to do. In every young woman’s heart is a deep yearning to someday be a wife and a mother. These feelings were nurtured in your soul long before you came to this earth. President Hinckley has said, “Women, for the most part, see their greatest fulfillment, their greatest happiness in home and family” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of Gordon B. Hinckley</span> [1997], 387).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/understanding-our-true-identity.p10" pid="OEvGiKj6t063zqFdPGOfeA" hash="R3HShA">Turning hearts to the family! The 1998 Worldwide Celebration suggests so many ways you can turn your hearts to your families, including to your ancestors. The Spirit of Elijah is with young women. Throughout the world, there are Family History Centers™, places where you can find your ancestors and your roots. Young women love doing this. One young woman writes: “When we first went to the Family History Center, we didn’t want to go. It sounded so boring. But I got excited when I found the name of my great-great-grandmother on the computer.” As you search for your ancestors and desire to do their temple work, you know the power that comes from attending the house of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/understanding-our-true-identity.p11" pid="CtpOKgTZAEyM7gHcTXB7jA" hash="GGdDFA">Martha Milanes, a Young Women leader from Colombia, wrote: “Our temple will soon be dedicated, and what a glorious experience it will be to watch all of our young women doing the [baptismal] work for their ancestors. [The celebration] is so inspired that I am also willing to turn my own heart to my family. This will be our offering to the Lord at His temple here in Colombia.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/understanding-our-true-identity.p12" pid="hcbbAxg1wEq5QIIg66djRQ" hash="vkewsw">Thank you, young women, for all you offer. As you continue to enjoy this worldwide celebration, you will feel strengthened by the power of the Spirit. As you pray and read your scriptures and keep the commandments, the Holy Ghost will whisper to you that you belong to Heavenly Father’s royal family and that He loves you very much. Of this I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1998/04/understanding-our-true-identity</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/1998-general-young-women-meeting/1998-03-0020-carol-b-thomas-64k-eng.mp3" length="6991998" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 1998 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spiritual Power of Our Baptism</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism?lang=eng</link>
      <description>How can we apply the spiritual power of our baptism to the principle of modesty? We hope one of the things that makes you different from the world is the way you dress.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_99260_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="PUxhZQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="NZddYLKMA0uVwRxzWXGPPQ" hash="3Y4VIA">Spiritual Power of Our Baptism</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ubxjA5cBs0yCdW89HE4Wpw" hash="jTox9A">Carol B. Thomas</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="WCN8MAzlGU6zu3LtR4dOFg" hash="xJozyg">How can we apply the spiritual power of our baptism to the principle of modesty? We hope one of the things that makes you different from the world is the way you dress.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-ee3.jpg" alt="Carol B. Thomas" pid="uScH0hje6EOwZl3luxlRxw" hash="lVbTWw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p1" pid="Eyi1ocyAi0yibbJUSyZHLQ" hash="6gP58g">My dear young friends, how we love you. What a blessing it is to be here with you tonight. Not too long ago Elder Robert D. Hales, one of the members of the Quorum of the Twelve, asked the question, “Do our young women know what their baptismal covenants mean?” And then he said, “I wish you would teach them.” I remember thinking to myself, <span class="emphasis">Do I fully understand the importance of my own baptismal covenants?</span> So tonight, let’s talk for a few minutes about what it really means to become a member of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and how our baptism can bless our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p2" pid="Q6ubgmmH-kmyXQV1d_g9YA" hash="2bpHSA">The Savior has likened our baptism to being reborn. I want you to think about two of the greatest moments in your life: the day you were born and the day of your baptism, two very essential births in this lifetime. None of us can remember the day we were born. You can only imagine that your mother held you close in her arms and dreamed of what you would become.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p3" pid="dEyTSKr2hkOv9lzp-FN-OQ" hash="6zmPcQ">Now, it’s probably not as hard to remember the day you were baptized—your second birth. Listen to what Lan-Ting, a Beehive girl from the Philippines, wrote about her baptism: “I felt like I had been born again. What an extraordinary feeling of cleanliness, sinlessness! My mother’s tears flowed like a fountain of pearls, and I could tell these were tears of joy! My mother told me sincerely, ‘Lan-Ting, today I am relieved to say I can turn you over to the Lord. I trust He will accompany you along the roads of your life’” (letter in possession of Young Women office).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p4" pid="sHlcpSKKikuWdLl1ESZ61Q" hash="yM7Y_g">Baptism is our spiritual rebirth. It cleanses us from head to toe and allows us the companionship of the Savior through the gift of the Holy Ghost. He will accompany each of us along the road of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p5" pid="4TJE9R3q5USMWs4QEKX2UQ" hash="1bJwtg">Four things happen when we are baptized and confirmed: (1) we become members of Christ’s Church and commit to follow Him; (2) we have our sins forgiven; (3) it allows us entrance to the celestial kingdom; and (4) it is the doorway to personal sanctification (see Bible Dictionary, “Baptism,” 619). We might say we are “made holy.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p6" pid="23tcS1qhBEu9RcpMxgjWTw" hash="DKsw6w">The first three points are quite obvious. Tonight let’s focus on the fourth point: becoming holy. What does it mean to become holy? Because you have received the Holy Ghost, you are changed. You are a different person. It means you cannot be part of the world anymore; you can never go back. Elder Hales has said, “Help our young women to understand that when they are baptized, they are taken ‘out of the world’ and ‘into the kingdom’” (notes from General Young Women Board meeting, 5 Dec. 1997). You are taken out of the dark and into the light of Christ. It is the beginning of a whole new life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p7" pid="PGe7uv-ks0KfW_NMDzm7ig" hash="XBEvbw">Elder Henry B. Eyring, another member of the Quorum of the Twelve, remembers when he was baptized. On the way home, all he could think of was, “Uh-oh, the free ride is over.” And it’s true. After our baptism, each of us has the blessing of being responsible for every action in our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p8" pid="iGYAHX_2v0OIZRqwG9E3ug" hash="MOVZug">A story is told of the son of King Louis XVI of France. As a young man, he was kidnapped by evil men when they dethroned the king. For six months he was exposed to every filthy and vile thing that life had to offer, yet he never buckled under the pressure. This puzzled his captors, and they asked him why he had such great moral strength. His reply was simple: “I cannot do what you ask, for I was born to be a king” (see Vaughn J. Featherstone, “The King’s Son,” <span class="emphasis">New Era,</span> Nov. 1975, 35). You were born to be daughters of a King. By being baptized, you have been promised the blessings of royalty as you sanctify yourselves and become holy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p9" pid="S0a6kkp3oUyCKyIP-Etx1w" hash="iBr6Qw">So how do we do it? How can we become more holy so we may claim our royal heritage? Christ has said, “Follow me, … do the things which ye have seen me do” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.12" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p10" pid="E9agGxCqwEeg6V4QYkSogA" hash="6zdR5A">Share a few stories with me of young women who are following in the light of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p11" pid="-e8v0Zwkd0-jwoc8Uxz4LA" hash="RhUo8Q">A Laurel from Arizona writes: “It was October and our high school homecoming was fast approaching, but I was only 15 and a half when a guy asked me to the dance. I thought about saying yes and meeting him at the dance. My parents wouldn’t know. But then I realized it didn’t matter that my parents didn’t know—Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ always know, and they are the ones who really count. I didn’t go to the dance. Instead I had my girlfriends over. I felt so happy and free and full of life” (letter in possession of Young Women office).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p12" pid="gTWSdLwZb0S-bwnXNUrpZg" hash="0miKgA">A Beehive girl named Rebecca shared this journal entry: “Sometimes I think junior high is really hard. There is this one kid in my class who swears a lot. So I say a little prayer to help me not pay attention to him and to help it not get stuck in my mind. And it works. If you pray, it can solve even your littlest problems” (letter in possession of Young Women office).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p13" pid="Hv1TZLGHoEGrzqB9ee2Ckw" hash="cGNVMA">Still another young woman said: “This past year I haven’t had many friends, but it hasn’t gotten me down because the peace of the Spirit has filled my soul. … Even in those times when I feel lonely or awkward around people, the Lord has been there for me” (letter in possession of Young Women office).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p14" pid="gjmF1T-KPUuMMgeBgzwckw" hash="f9DwPg">A Mia Maid from Utah wrote: “This past year I had some personal challenges. I lost track of the Spirit, and then something incredible happened. I went to my bishop. I can’t remember ever feeling so scared. But the Lord was with me in that room, holding my trembling hand. I knew I could be forgiven. It’s been a hard road—humbling, repenting, and learning to pray all over again. But He was there. He never left me for a minute. I’ve been on both sides, and the light side is definitely the place to be” (letter in possession of Young Women office).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p15" pid="kgl0_keWx0CivzRlfWEJ0g" hash="jFP_qA">Thank you, thank you, young women, for your desire to follow the light of the Savior. All of you have difficult situations in your lives, but you know the source of your spiritual strength. Every time you pray or bear testimony or stand for the right, you shut down the powers of evil in your life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p16" pid="wgLfWm-lTEi2hxty7BnXfg" hash="cJ6k6w">When you walk down the halls at school and see all the other students, do you think to yourself, <span class="emphasis">I am different</span>? You are not <span class="emphasis">better</span> than they are, but your knowledge of and your commitment to the Savior make you different, and that difference can be an advantage, a blessing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p17" pid="3qh0BwT7NUWj31bSMWlIsQ" hash="Y9e2Fg">One of the hardest things for many of you is modesty. How can we apply the spiritual power of our baptism to the principle of modesty? We hope one of the things that makes you different from the world is the way you dress. Marcie Matthews, a Laurel from Chicago, Illinois, shares her story:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p18" pid="ztVMThji6kedjRvERONJTw" hash="aScYNw">“1998 was a year that I was able to see the results of many Young Women lessons, talks, and advice come into play. I am an average Mormon girl. Being able to keep my life this steady and strong has not been easy. I make goals all the time to help strengthen my testimony and my standards.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p19" pid="ObDI6lAOb0u9mpcyLBAb-w" hash="fEzxlg">“Recently we had a Mutual activity on the importance of modesty. Every lesson before I felt like I was a modest dresser, but I knew there was still something I could change—my shorts and the length of my skirts. It was the one weakness that I knew I had but had placed far behind in my head. Everyone wore short shorts, Daisy Dukes, and miniskirts, and I had bought mine with my own money. Then I heard the lesson on modesty. I went home wanting to go straight to my closet and throw away everything that was not modest so it wouldn’t be there to tempt me. After, I told my parents. I guess I was looking for them to tell me that there was no problem in the way I dressed and then let me go.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p20" pid="nuCKLJ1WEUSRUvZPngPU4g" hash="wiDbaQ">“Later that night my dad told me he was proud of me and that he would like to buy me a couple of knee-length dresses for church. The next step was to go through all my clothes and give away everything. It was hard for me to part with my favorite skirts and the shorts that I loved so much, but I did. <span class="emphasis">You will never see me in short shorts or short skirts again.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p21" pid="P3veil0NqUyDkFhbr1TO5w" hash="UWNnOA">“I have never felt better about myself. I love being able to walk into the temple and church and feel like I am a child of God and am representing Him … by the clothes that I wear.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p22" pid="bi_W-KRbe0GZaxLbR56iGA" hash="oOS2_g">“I challenge every young woman to take this step. It will help you find out who you are and what you stand for. When we have to give up something that is a part of us, the blessings will pour in more than you can imagine” (letter in possession of Young Women office).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p23" pid="ICmWX-bIlEaHgKPVixGq5Q" hash="bYPPbg">Marcie’s great example epitomizes our Young Women theme. You know, the part that says, “We stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things”—and in all <span class="emphasis">prom dresses.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p24" pid="8Wp7oHZwbkCNmZ_K07Hz8g" hash="C-CUPQ">We have talked about the spiritual power of our baptism. We can renew that power every week as we worthily partake of the sacrament. “There is no more eloquent expression in the English language than the sacramental prayers. We invite you to learn by heart the covenants and promises in the prayers on the bread and water” (Elder Dallin H. Oaks, notes in author’s possession). Ponder their meaning that they may bless your life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism.p25" pid="UrYlJ9qMoUSuY3KbzvN9Rg" hash="5Xgydw">I pray that you will tend and take care of your baptismal covenants. As you say your prayers, especially each Saturday night, ask Heavenly Father to prepare you to take the sacrament so the spiritual power of your baptism will be present in your life. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1999/04/spiritual-power-of-our-baptism</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/1999-general-young-women-meeting/1999-03-0020-carol-b-thomas-64k-eng.mp3" length="5558941" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 1999 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparing Our Families for the Temple</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Our greatest challenge is to prepare our families for the temple. Parents have the primary responsibility, but grandparents, aunts and uncles, even brothers and sisters all may teach the family.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_99260_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="Q2XoTQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="_mO-cW485kCVUaF_pmeQ9A" hash="lAMDjQ">Preparing Our Families for the Temple</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="N819T0GvNkWiwLLiVA0XLw" hash="jTox9A">Carol B. Thomas</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="hn9hgb4nG0iTYRxCXtl57g" hash="WNKK1Q">Our greatest challenge is to prepare our families for the temple. Parents have the primary responsibility, but grandparents, aunts and uncles, even brothers and sisters all may teach the family.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-ee3.jpg" alt="Carol B. Thomas" pid="D1wcr5JTa0WCJtcYzVI3Jw" hash="lVbTWw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.p1" pid="Rkw6SX1eMkCPpJhQ9aNWhg" hash="Ve-tVA">Brothers and sisters, I <span class="emphasis">think</span> I am happy to be here today. My assignment with the Young Women presidency puts me in many happy situations. One month ago a training assignment took me to Guayaquil, Ecuador. I arrived at the hotel after dark. The next morning I opened my curtains, and there across the valley was a beautiful granite building standing majestically on the Santa Ana Hills. Its stunning beauty was evident, but it wasn’t until I saw the angel Moroni on top that I, with tears in my eyes, realized that here was a temple, a symbol of the glorious blessings that will come to the members of the Church in that part of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.p2" pid="y0cah83zwUmfIrBRkWUE3w" hash="MQHSHQ">“Temples are unique among all buildings. … They are places of covenants and promises. At their altars we kneel before God our Creator and are given promise of his everlasting blessings” (Gordon B. Hinckley, <span class="emphasis">Teachings of Gordon B. Hinckley</span> [1997], 632–33). Wherever we went, we found that temples are being built, temples that will lift the Saints of God and change the face of countries, whether in South America or throughout the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.p3" pid="5cb7tOD83U-hC4m5JBQJcw" hash="IuOxMQ">Has it only been one year since our beloved prophet announced the building of 32 more temples? President Gordon B. Hinckley has said, “This is the greatest era of temple building in all the history of the world” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings,</span> 629).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.p4" pid="h83I2PM0n0uT8QHLY3FWPg" hash="JQ4tfw">Our youngest son, Spencer, now serving a mission in Mongolia, wrote that his mission president was addressing the missionaries and members concerning their duty in building up the Church there. “As President Cox opened the discussion for questions, the first response was, ‘When is Mongolia going to have a temple?’ These people,” Spencer said, “are hungering for the gospel to play a greater part in their lives. They don’t even have a Book of Mormon yet, and they want a temple.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.p5" pid="DrpAM_8srUicOSyhCEgLjw" hash="9_VZ5Q">Why all this fuss about temples? Simply put, the purpose of temples “is to redeem all mankind who are obedient to the laws and commandments of God. The gospel in its fulness was revealed to Adam. … [And] Saints of all ages have had temples in one form or another” (David B. Haight, “Personal Temple Worship,” Ensign, May 1993, 23–24).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.p6" pid="SqZEHY6XmEyH2rXuV3_doQ" hash="ceqeRg">Joseph Smith said, “The greatest responsibility in this world that God has laid upon us is to seek after our dead” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 6:313). If this is true, then as parents and family members our greatest challenge is to prepare our families for the temple. Parents have the primary responsibility, but grandparents, aunts and uncles, even brothers and sisters all may teach the family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.p7" pid="gVsjf5epa0OL9ZN8uuD5-g" hash="pBiwhA">When my husband and I were married in the temple, we understood the importance of never discussing the temple outside the temple, not because the ceremonies were secret but because they were sacred. “They are kept confidential lest they be given to those who are unprepared” (Boyd K. Packer, <span class="emphasis">The Holy Temple</span> [booklet, 1982], 2). But in a family setting, there are many precious truths that, with sensitivity and common sense, will help prepare our children for the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.p8" pid="1Lk-cmJG-kSKrSaQsuRtHg" hash="55LBiA">Consider:</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.f2">
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="enX95Jyn8Uq10wJ1D6LfRQ" hash="PmNSbw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="sxOt3aQmtUeo2YCMw4FXrw" hash="C3BGGA">
            <span class="emphasis">The sacred nature of the temple clothing.</span> In the temples all are dressed in white. White is the symbol of purity.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="t-sITDF8fEGGX8P6eVSugw" hash="6moP4Q">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="JPJxhh9clUqQF8Yha3CYKQ" hash="Y0j_zg">
            <span class="emphasis">The temple is the Lord’s classroom. </span>President Hinckley has said, “[The temple] becomes a school of instruction in the sweet and sacred things of God” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings, </span>635).</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="9iVvfMP3bESsohdsojA1AQ" hash="WWk8Zg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="t0Yk6APOFEqPY05JZZBSPg" hash="FozFHA">
            <span class="emphasis">What it means to be worthy for the temple.</span> Can we teach our children that receiving one’s endowment and the wearing of the sacred garment will not require a change of wardrobe or lifestyle if the principles of temple worthiness are understood and lived in their earlier years? A young woman who wears knee-length skirts will not have to buy a new wardrobe after she receives her endowment in the temple. A young man who anticipates going to the temple will respect the Church’s moral standards in his social behavior.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="vfPxEPtyj02CJ5e8mKfY3g" hash="WcGgjg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="zgFL_RcOV0etKgiVkQWJSg" hash="-MF5Hg">
            <span class="emphasis">Understanding gospel language.</span> What do the words <span class="emphasis">endowment, ordinances, sealings,</span> and <span class="emphasis">keys</span> really mean? The story is told of a little boy who overheard his parents discussing doing temple sealings. He asked, “Are you going to do the walls next week?”</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.p9" pid="61nNgvz-qEOJn8aOvh9obw" hash="XUZyug">Where may we teach our children? Family home evening is the formal setting, but there are so many more places where we may talk about our spiritual feelings for the temple. One of my favorite times was when my children were in bed at night. Occasionally I would lie on their bed and tell them of spiritual things. There in the peace and the quiet, the sweet Spirit can bear testimony to their heart and soul that the things you are saying are true.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.p10" pid="nHGf0SjpjEimKP7tgj7f9A" hash="HuFa2A">We may assume that Joseph and Mary taught their family about the temple. As Elder Perry has discussed, when the Savior was a 12-year-old boy, His parents took Him to the Feast of the Passover in Jerusalem. When Jesus was left behind, He was not found in places or entertainments for a boy His age. His parents found Him in the temple. Perhaps when Mary tucked Him in bed at night, she shared her testimony of these sacred and precious truths.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.p11" pid="-0lbpaxjOUGArgCPtIWydw" hash="kxkYAg">My first memory of temples was when I was a little girl. I knew the temple must be a pretty wonderful place because my parents faithfully attended, and they always came home together in such a good mood. I understood the sacred nature of the temple clothing by the way my mother spoke about it with love and respect.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.p12" pid="sm5FLDGWaUWFYcTZYTFKCQ" hash="1uxScA">President Howard W. Hunter has said: “Let us share with our children the spiritual feelings we have in the temple. And let us teach them more earnestly and more comfortably the things we can appropriately say. … Keep a picture of a temple in your home that your children may see it” (“A Temple-Motivated People,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Feb. 1995, 5). I noticed every home I visited in Africa had a picture of a temple hung simply and beautifully on the wall.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.f3">
	<p pid="CzS48D0zZk-4sT2m3kfAgw" hash="D_usmA">New understanding comes as we prepare our families for the temple. May I share a few things I have learned:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="DBSFBWWu_0uYkzCJ5lmUNA" hash="N01_Yg">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="P-gP6xb4pEWJiv1peo913w" hash="NqFwTQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Going to the temple often provides balance in our lives. </span>After returning home, we have an increased sense of well-being; the influence of the Spirit can shield us from the frustrations of the world. Listen to this promise by President Hinckley: “If there were more temple work done in the Church, there would be less … selfishness, less … contention, less … demeaning [of] others. The whole Church would increasingly be lifted to greater heights of spirituality, love for one another, and obedience to the commandments of God” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings,</span> 622).</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Db2U2-wqw02_kmeCSBun2A" hash="gkrN1Q">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="Ma5k8b_mw0OmrrilIGj7qA" hash="2k2KFg">
            <span class="emphasis">The spiritual atmosphere of the temple curbs our appetite for worldly things.</span> When we attend frequently, we no longer have such a need to wear the latest fashion, and we are not so easily drawn to the entertainment of the world.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="M4ZTroVrJ0OrSuiWg6FAKg" hash="0pe1FQ">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="6np7TrdSTkmwRJ-Ibgp3zQ" hash="hYFdaw">
            <span class="emphasis">The temple is a place of revelation.</span> Many years ago I was walking into the temple and in my mind I heard the words, <span class="emphasis">Learn public speaking.</span> I thought to myself, <span class="emphasis">When will I ever have need for public speaking?</span> Over several months’ period of time I tried very inadequately to conjure up some enthusiasm to obey the prompting I had received. I even checked out a tape from the local library by a public speaker who admitted that his goal was to someday speak in the Mormon Tabernacle. I thought at the time, <span class="emphasis">I’ll never be speaking in the Tabernacle!</span></p>
          <p pid="jKzWxSI6AU2SRSLQad7_SQ" hash="26IpiA">Elder John A. Widtsoe has said, “At the most unexpected moments, in or out of the temple will come to [us], as a revelation, the solution of the problems that vex [our lives]. … It is a place where revelations may be expected” (“Temple Worship,” <span class="emphasis">Utah Genealogical and Historical Magazine,</span> Apr. 1921, 63–64).</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="zliuLicwtEiMBFUf1m7PjA" hash="JG0T1w">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="yAfGNb4ShE6-IOh7FYvdCg" hash="sZYaog">
            <span class="emphasis">One of the biggest lessons I have learned is that Satan will try to keep us from going to the temple.</span> During a discussion with friends once, they shared with me that whenever they attend, they don’t tell anybody they are going. They just jump into their cars and go, because if they don’t something is sure to happen to keep them away.</p>
          <p pid="qQO5u8pGkUOWIpL7M8fSUg" hash="l_GDtw">I remember reading of a warning given by the president of the Logan Temple that Satan and his followers will “whisper in the ears of the people persuading them not to go to the Temple” (“Genealogical Department,” <span class="emphasis">Church News,</span> 12 Dec. 1936, 8). “Temple work brings so much resistance because it is the source of so much spiritual power to the Latter-day Saints” (Boyd K. Packer, “The Holy Temple,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Feb. 1995, 36).</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="nzgCHSsPqUuP-DbObBB3vw" hash="Jt8k8Q">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p pid="pSNa--J8LEGBRO0dz9jmLA" hash="a-rP7A">
            <span class="emphasis">The Spirit of Elijah is brooding in the land.</span> As we work with youth of the Church, we see they are being drawn to their temples.</p>
          <p pid="_eS3lI0DeUOI5mIT-kN5xA" hash="UkxNtg">In Nicaragua, Central America, a group of 49 young women and their leaders took 2,000 names to the Guatemala City Temple. It took each girl a year to save enough money to go. These faithful young women rode a bus almost two days’ journey through three country borders and spent two or three days at the temple before returning home.</p>
          <p pid="brvsanEag0iBlaJMWRaUEw" hash="8J35DA">In another ward, young people have located the names of 10,000 ancestors as they have turned their hearts to their families. Where temples are available, we see youth doing baptisms for the dead, sometimes on an individual weekly basis.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="8aN4Z6yZUE-VnDGyvwNFDg" hash="vTqMbw">
          <span class="label">6.</span>
          <p pid="IQHkkrzyT0m5k8D9BTkRSg" hash="LNIquQ">
            <span class="emphasis">In the temple the Spirit of the Lord provides comfort and peace, especially during moments of despair. </span>Recently I met a 35-year-old woman in the temple. As we visited, I asked if her husband was with her. With a look of tenderness in her eyes, she shared with me that he had died of a brain tumor three months ago. The temple is her anchor; the Spirit found in the temple gives her comfort and peace, and perhaps her husband was there.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.p13" pid="edQt2GUh80-ryiF_cBXT8w" hash="2ToLaw">Each of us may ask ourselves, “How often should I attend the temple?” Our leaders will never tell us how often we should attend, because it is different for every person. Many women of various ages who live close to a temple try to go once a week. When one of my friends worked full time, she spent one day a month in the temple, attending several sessions. These women are obedient, but they also understand the strength of priesthood power that comes into their lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.p14" pid="1M9knUpgXU6zjDFzRABq8g" hash="tfAWBg">For young parents, attending the temple may be a once-a-month date. President Packer has said: “Perhaps you will understand … we are trying to establish family history as … a ‘cottage industry.’ … Couples raising little children should not feel inadequate or guilty … if they cannot afford the time or money to attend a distant temple frequently. Mother makes a contribution by noting important events, collecting pictures, bits of memorabilia, … all as it fits into the schedule of a busy mother” (“A Plea to Stake Presidents,” leadership training meeting, 1 Apr. 1988).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.p15" pid="MS_D4kPq3kaAxPmNiItvrg" hash="tuzGRA">My own mother didn’t do scrapbooks, but she gave me a love for my heritage. She told me story after story about my ancestors as she taught me to love them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.p16" pid="kMGwU670AUKnRei4Eg8K_w" hash="aGRDaQ">President Packer continues: “Father and mother can speak of ordinances and covenants. By the inflection of their voices, they can italicize the word ‘temple’ every time they say it. … In proper season, family obligations will be a bit less and income a bit more. Then members can and should give more to this sacred [temple] work” (“A Plea to Stake Presidents”).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.p17" pid="Btk_aEhI3ECFPrc1A4b0JA" hash="9ttkrA">We plead with you mothers and fathers to teach your sons and daughters the meaning of the temple covenants. Teach them that “wearing the garment is a sacred privilege. … [It] is an outward expression of an inner commitment to follow the Savior Jesus Christ” (First Presidency letter, 5 Nov. 1996).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple.p18" pid="WS1hW5wox0W69TlPK9rNsg" hash="UvZYFA">Brothers and sisters, as servants of the living God, we shall press forward in this sacred temple work. May we teach our children that as they spiritually prepare themselves for the temple, they may stand in the presence of the Lord, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1999/04/preparing-our-families-for-the-temple</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1999-general-conference/1999-04-1040-carol-b-thomas-64k-eng.mp3" length="6853740" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1999 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrity</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2000/04/integrity?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Integrity makes you whole and complete.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10033256_000_038" doc-version="2" hash="ZgW4-w">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ctTexyCwSkiUXY1lztc9BA" hash="itWiFA">Integrity</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="-BRmGuttQUqQHGSR42EdPw" hash="jTox9A">Carol B. Thomas</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="M7jlpgag4UG7HE9CPp7i9w" hash="rntNxg">Integrity makes you whole and complete.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-ee3.jpg" alt="Carol B. Thomas" pid="pecMJqszQEmM6WL68azloA" hash="lVbTWw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p1" pid="CwlnwBDihEmk041QhPgN6g" hash="3umTew">It is exciting to meet with you tonight as we step across the threshold into this new millennium. It is a sacred time for you to be alive. Whether you are 12 or 15 or 17 years old, what you are doing now really matters as you prepare for your future roles as women, mothers, and builders of the kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p2" pid="p2SFRP7xz0u6V0H97iCLZw" hash="JBztMg">One summer when I was 16, I remember sitting down and writing in my journal all the qualities I wanted in a future husband—testimony, good looks, sense of humor, money, education. I thought these were all good qualities. But when my oldest daughter, Becky, was 16, she came to me and asked, “What is the most important quality to look for in a husband?” By then I had been married for many years. I knew the answer to that question. I believe the most important quality we can possess is integrity. How I love the value of integrity!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p3" pid="VeenqkNnIE289cX1Xy4FJw" hash="YfwdnQ">What is this most important principle? Integrity means to <span class="emphasis">do</span> what you say you will do; you keep promises to yourself. The Young Women program defines integrity as: “I will have the moral courage to make my actions consistent with my knowledge of right and wrong.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p4" pid="5_hL1T1lHUemePrLGVMOGA" hash="9K-W_g">“We can easily spot … someone with integrity. They’re honest. They do the right thing when nobody is watching. They keep their word and they keep our confidences. They repay their debts, and they clean up their own messes. They accept responsibility for their actions” (“The Wholeness of Integrity,” <span class="emphasis">Church News,</span> 26 June 1999, 16).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p5" pid="yFVxIsdvUk2ag74OShQDiA" hash="waHQOA">Everyone comes into this world with different levels of integrity. Have you ever wondered what qualified Jesus to be given the role as Savior of the world? He was the Firstborn of the Father, chosen from the beginning. But what really made Him perfect? It was His total dedication and desire to please our Father in Heaven. The Savior was capable of sinning, but His desire for “honesty [was] an armor against temptation” (James E. Talmage, <span class="emphasis">Jesus the Christ,</span> 3rd ed. [1916], 134). The Savior said, “I do always those things that please [the Father]” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.29" class="scriptureRef">John 8:29</a>). We know that throughout His life, He consistently made right choices. He had the moral courage to make His actions consistent with His knowledge of right and wrong.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p6" pid="iI_ER8rg4EyjxS4Hvm_erg" hash="gHZswA">President Hinckley has said: “In all this world there is no substitute for personal integrity. It includes honor. It includes performance. It includes keeping one’s word. It includes doing what is right regardless of the circumstances” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of Gordon B. Hinckley</span> [1997], 270).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p7" pid="QUNBWUvpNkislOXiiATzuQ" hash="5-x-Xw">Let’s look at a few examples of young women who are learning to love integrity. They have chosen to do what is right regardless of the circumstances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p8" pid="7f_piLaKJkmk_Ls4GioTHg" hash="qKXlYg">A young woman named Brooke writes: “This past summer I had the opportunity of attending a leadership conference. It only took a couple of hours to find out that the LDS kids were in the minority there. I ended up [rooming] with two girls who were very nice but definitely didn’t have the same standards. At night when I read my scriptures they stared at me like I was some kind of weirdo. While they were talking about their drinking parties, I was talking about [parties] with punch and cookies. They laughed but were always curious.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p9" pid="Q1WixJCEiUWC80ON_7QoJA" hash="V4Ipqw">“Although I was scared sometimes, I never failed to stand up for what I believe in. At the end of the conference, one of my roommates [said], ‘I guess Mormons can be cool,’ and that she would think about our religion and maybe even learn about it. I [learned] that I could make a difference by simply standing up for what I believe.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p10" pid="DOpFJ8Nvg0Ge3U3x3ahQkA" hash="aD3YEw">Cari shares this experience:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p11" pid="G3dRoyMfzkSOzCnoTZO1jw" hash="4YEIfw">“I have always known what was right, but I thought I could choose my own path. After being on that path, I started to feel lost and confused. Finally I prayed with a humble heart and asked Heavenly Father what I should do. The first step was to change friends. That wasn’t easy, being in the “popular” group. But I took the challenge and did just that.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p12" pid="e-Nn8wpMNkqGdHklaawnAQ" hash="l-oDXA">“We liked to hang out on the weekend and watch R-rated movies. I had made up my mind never to watch R movies again. It was the beginning of a new school year, and a guy asked me to watch a movie. I told him that I didn’t watch rated R movies. He said, “That’s cool, we can watch a different one.” This has happened more than once. I have left parties, sat home on weekends, and turned down [dates] because I don’t watch R-rated movies. This has been the greatest blessing in my life. Now it’s easier for me to stand up for what I believe in many other ways.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p13" pid="d0KjtU7ivECqoD2yI-djyA" hash="fGd_QQ">Kristen, a Laurel, writes:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p14" pid="w4mTe1H1SEeiMeLFKRe7iQ" hash="6cCM1w">“I try to stand as a witness of God every day. It’s the little things—being nice to everyone I talk with, not laughing at a crude joke, not gossiping about someone, being patient. Sometimes it’s these small things that are the hardest to do, … but I constantly strive to do better. Scripture study and prayer have given me power—the courage to stand and share with the Savior my testimony of Him. The scriptures give me the power to change for the better.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p15" pid="WWISeADoLkaVqVPPRE5aOw" hash="I5n4mQ">Now listen to Salina’s letter:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p16" pid="jEz_wzEFP0mMTXEEcYLEyA" hash="VuHOkw">“Last year in seminary we were taught about Joseph Smith. Towards the end of the year, we had a spiritual lesson that has impacted the rest of my life. Through all of his experiences, he never once failed to stand as a witness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p17" pid="lAanzVkXb0S_SZlptDghew" hash="SYXzgw">“As I sat listening, I asked myself over and over if I could be that strong. My testimony was strengthened that day as the Spirit manifested to me that the Church was true and Joseph Smith was a true prophet. If I was faced with trials as he was, with the Lord’s help I could be just as strong. So I made a commitment that day that I would always stand as a witness. If Joseph Smith could do it, so can I!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p18" pid="e7RBAdr1LUKe1e04fXALeQ" hash="RkDL9A">These young women are learning the value of integrity. There is a common thread which runs through all of these stories. Do you recognize it? You’ve heard it a thousand times before. Reading your scriptures and saying your prayers invites the Spirit to be with you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p19" pid="9TB6VT_tHk6xNdMjixTZyQ" hash="aTFzPA">When President Spencer W. Kimball was 15 years old, he attended stake conference and heard a speaker ask everyone who had read the entire Bible to raise their hands. I heard President Kimball say, “I cared not what others were thinking. I knew that I had not read it and I was filled with shame.” After the meeting was over, he ran home as fast as he could, grabbed the Bible off the shelf, and climbed the stairs to the attic. His brothers teased him, saying, “Why try? You’ll never finish it.” But he did. Almost a year later he finished reading the Bible. The integrity he had as a 15-year-old boy was one of the things that made him a great prophet of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p20" pid="CMuwhhpiD0yfrc8azRubKQ" hash="kYnYGA">Dear young women, you too can develop a love for integrity as you discipline yourselves through daily prayer and scripture study. The Holy Ghost can inspire you with a greater desire for honesty and integrity. Make a decision tonight that you will read your scriptures and say your prayers every day for the rest of your life. You see, scriptures and prayer go together like peanut butter and jelly. They will help you stay close to the Church and close to the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p21" pid="Aq5UHK5HIEGMPNCxMmHoaA" hash="JCK_Zw">And remember this: as you develop your integrity you can be more beautiful. Integrity makes you whole and complete. Integrity will bring a twinkle to your eye and a look of confidence that will magnetically draw people to you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p22" pid="Bk0tMoV3fE2CuSQBilJpDA" hash="IGYtOw">President Hinckley has said, “There is nothing more beautiful in this world than a … young woman who is clean in thought and word and deed” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of Gordon B. Hinckley,</span> 384).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p23" pid="SFpx1wMxe0avHQg1_lGUZw" hash="gvFhGg">Just like my daughter Becky, someday you will be looking for a young man with integrity. And a young man who holds the priesthood of God will also want to marry a young woman of integrity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p24" pid="8jGynMuefkmCMhq8z75zWA" hash="O6xzAA">President Hinckley was right. “There is no substitute for personal integrity. It includes honor, … performance, … keeping one’s word, … doing what is right regardless of the circumstances” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of Gordon B. Hinckley,</span> 270).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/integrity.p25" pid="Pj9F4mlyJk-HQf9ijP-p4Q" hash="ba37xg">As servants of the Lord Jesus Christ, we can do it! Our honest effort to improve our integrity allows God to increase our power to do it. Let me repeat that: Our honest effort to improve our integrity allows God to increase our power to do it. I promise you, as you read your scriptures and say your prayers—that’s the magic formula—the Holy Ghost will help you in your noble quest to strengthen and develop your integrity. Of this I testify, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2000/04/integrity</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2000-general-young-women-meeting/2000-03-0020-carol-b-thomas-64k-eng.mp3" length="5146733" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2000 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing Our Talent for Spirituality</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Spirituality is learning how to listen to the Spirit and then letting it govern our lives.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029247_000_038" doc-version="2" hash="zkAsLQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="tRLF6XmC00WBV36yWYsyzQ" hash="O7leQg">Developing Our Talent for Spirituality</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="MBs19wFmC0qvCd-rNtFO2Q" hash="jTox9A">Carol B. Thomas</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="y9-cr-0TTEe7vEkNGBS_EQ" hash="mnhPuw">Spirituality is learning how to listen to the Spirit and then letting it govern our lives.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-ee3.jpg" alt="Carol B. Thomas" pid="l2odWAUzIUiJhfq5T4uoBA" hash="lVbTWw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p1" pid="rP6G5wTt9EujFnpVWspgAg" hash="I9IzLA">How many of you have ever wanted to develop a new talent? Have you ever taken piano or soccer lessons? Tonight I want to talk to you about developing a talent—not just any talent, but one very special talent I bet you have never even thought about. I would like to talk to you about developing your talent for spirituality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p2" pid="iRz7hidc2UqdpP1LstVn3A" hash="_ltLCw">Did you know that spirituality is a talent? Elder Bruce R. McConkie of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles once said, “Above all talents … , chief among all endowments—stands the talent for spirituality” (<span class="emphasis">The Millennial Messiah</span> [1982], 234). Spirituality is learning how to listen to the Spirit and then letting it govern our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p3" pid="eFP7G0F-c0qRf-5p5yrOrA" hash="4hGFCQ">So how do we learn to listen to the Spirit? Well, first of all, we need to understand what the Spirit is. Second, we’ll look at young women who have learned how to recognize the Spirit. As members of the Church, we are given two spiritual gifts: the Light of Christ given to all men at birth and the special gift of the Holy Ghost given after our baptism. It allows us “to live by the power of the Holy Ghost, which is the power of revelation, and … testimony” (Bruce R. McConkie, <span class="emphasis">Doctrines of the Restoration: Sermons and Writings of Bruce R. McConkie,</span> ed. Mark L. McConkie [1989], 93). Once we know what the Spirit is, how do we recognize it when we feel it? That’s the hardest part.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p4" pid="HdHkPPEA-0eRYPhA62QFnA" hash="20AVhA">When I was 14, I remember realizing what the Spirit was for the very first time. I loved going to church, especially sacrament meeting. I always felt so warm and peaceful. This was the Spirit. I’m not sure I knew how important it was. I just knew it made me feel good. As an adult, I’ve learned that it not only makes us feel good, it teaches and testifies and cleanses us from sin. It can warn us of danger and help us remember things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p5" pid="_7Z0ajJbMEK2l3PZzEK_WA" hash="lYtISw">Some young women struggle to identify the Spirit. One girl wrote: “I haven’t really had any experiences with the Holy Ghost, and that’s mostly my fault for not living like I should. But I’m trying harder, and hopefully I will have a chance soon to feel the [comforting influence of the] Holy Ghost” (letter on file in the Young Women office).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p6" pid="vkBoy8M2E0K5VdgViyunjQ" hash="4xjtTw">These feelings are normal. This young woman may not know it, but the Holy Ghost is giving her a desire to feel His influence. The Spirit doesn’t always give us warm, fuzzy feelings. Most of the time, the voice of inspiration is a quiet voice, a still, small voice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p7" pid="mmNKXEZ5h0m7TE9YLNsDbw" hash="-D-ilQ">I remember what the Savior said to the faithful Nephites when He visited the New World: “I perceive that ye are weak, that ye cannot understand all my words. … Go … [into] your homes, … ponder upon the things which I have said, and ask … the Father … that ye may understand” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.2-3" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:2–3</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p8" pid="T0rpqK8Yb0eBzGegZzWiGQ" hash="nrRNgA">The Savior’s words were written for us. It’s OK if we’re weak, as long as we don’t stay weak, as long as we do something about it. Katie is a young woman who did just that. Let me share her story with you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p9" pid="F-8LzGmmi0STYzbskgoQPg" hash="IpwOxA">“All my life I have wanted to be good, but I got to the point where I wondered, ‘How can anyone really know if the Church is true?’ I took Moroni’s challenge and for five months prayed and read my scriptures every day. One night I sat on my bed almost in tears, giving up. I decided to pray. I said, ‘Heavenly Father, help me to please just know you are there. I’ve done what Thou hast asked according to the Church and I just really need to know.’ Immediately I felt like someone had wrapped their arms around me. I didn’t hear a loud voice or see an angel, but I felt Heavenly Father telling me, ‘Sweet Katie, you’ve known all along.’ It was like a kind and loving father comforting his little girl” (letter).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p10" pid="HkelWYEBc0uMBo7hFn4-vg" hash="8b9cSQ">One of the main functions of the Holy Ghost is to testify of truth. The Spirit testified to Katie that the gospel is true. Katie had paid the price. As the Savior said, she went to her home, studied His words, and prayed—for five whole months. Katie is developing her talent for spirituality. She can use this gift to govern her life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p11" pid="LF_Ru8UAskG9gDas4umDbQ" hash="sziNEg">Talents are meant to be shared. As you learn to play the piano, you can bless others with your music. As you develop your talent for spirituality, you can use this gift to bless your family. Did you know you have some responsibility for the happiness in your family? It isn’t just your mom’s or dad’s job to keep the family happy. You can help too. Listen to what Brooke did as she shared her talent for spirituality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p12" pid="upCxT1gUB0i6Im70wNzZGQ" hash="WBLRTg">“My eight-year-old sister was scared of strangers coming into the house. One night she came into my room, and I tried to explain to her that she wasn’t hearing anyone walking around. I remembered my seminary teacher challenged us to always try to have Heavenly Father’s Spirit with us. So I prayed in my heart that I would get help to not be frustrated. A verse came instantly into my head. I opened the scriptures and told her to read it to me. Then I was bearing testimony to her about the Holy Ghost and how if she wanted peace to get down and pray and the Spirit would come. She gave me a hug and kiss and went off to bed. Then I remembered my 10-year-old sister on the top bunk. She told me she never knew that if you wanted something like that you could pray and the Spirit would bring you peace. I know the Holy Ghost was inspiring me to say that” (letter).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p13" pid="q73rue09T0iPU3mixcyGJg" hash="kxtjMg">There are lots of ways you can bless your family. Brooke did three important things: she bore her testimony, she prayed for her sister, and she was an example to her other sister on the top bunk. This strengthened her own spirituality as well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p14" pid="W44f1LL3wk-CXGJn_-KLHw" hash="0MRYJg">The Savior invites us to bear testimony. He has said, “Go ye into all the world, preach the gospel to every creature” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p15" pid="XRdw9QAgbkG20iVj_84HEg" hash="L-K8Wg">Many of you love bearing testimony at camp. Well, you don’t have to wait for camp. You can bear your testimony to your family often in simple ways.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p16" pid="Ouil1RfBCEuPf5HjfBcC9g" hash="SdNnzw">When my grandchildren visited me and we saw a picture of President Hinckley, I said, “I love President Hinckley. I am so grateful to have a living prophet on the earth today.” It took about 10 seconds, but it taught my grandchildren and helped us feel the Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p17" pid="210F58sJckqoG0rh_L-48w" hash="53pyow">We bear testimony every single day by our example. Just last month when I was writing this talk, my daughter Jill came home, happily fixed dinner, and washed the dishes. The sweet spirit she carries in her heart blesses our home. I know she loves Jesus by the way she shows her love for me. Another way we show our love for Jesus is through prayer. President Hinckley has said, “Let every family in this Church have prayer together” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of Gordon B. Hinckley</span> [1997], 216). “Your daily conversations with [H]im will bring peace into your hearts and a joy into your lives that can come from no other source” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of Gordon B. Hinckley,</span> 216).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p18" pid="Vut7BDXb4EevxZVbBNJ_Vw" hash="hun0Bg">You can help your family remember to pray. Prayer is like an umbrella in the storms of life. When I was a busy mom with seven children at home, I was so grateful when one of my children would say, “We forgot to have family prayer.” Sometimes we would stand by the back door and pray as the children ran off to school. It always strengthened the spirituality in our home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p19" pid="Zi7NxcvPaUKHhy6c70P9Mg" hash="VQBKPg">And you can pray for your family. If there is contention, pray for a spirit of peace. No matter what, Heavenly Father will bless you with peace in your heart. Prayer is a miracle; it can help develop the spirituality in your home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p20" pid="JJWYyGMIjUCSCsC1WpL49g" hash="H_GTYQ">Recently, our prophet, President Hinckley, prayed for the youth of the Church. It was a never-to-be-forgotten experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p21" pid="gWOLEX6kk0eG5Ba4S99cmA" hash="fCooRw">Can you even imagine how wonderful it would be to know that Jesus prays for us? When He was among the Nephites, “he … knelt upon the earth; and … prayed unto the Father. … No one can conceive of the joy which filled our souls at the time we heard him pray for us unto the Father” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.15,17" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:15, 17</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p22" pid="k-icoSJ9J02OOPS8wypENg" hash="Bjm0pA">Could it be with you as it was with the Nephite children? As the Savior ministered to them, “he did loose their tongues, and they did speak … great and marvelous things, even greater than he had revealed unto the people” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/26.14" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 26:14</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p23" pid="2jnUXcWzW025CQbZ_Kj8Ow" hash="Nm2mFQ">With the power of the Spirit, you too can speak great and marvelous things in your own family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p24" pid="WM1EaDJhv0mwSI3tSmywGQ" hash="eajGXg">These children “saw angels descending out of heaven as it were in the midst of fire; and they came down and encircled those little ones about … ; and the angels did minister unto them” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.24" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:24</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p25" pid="AVyPPfoz_E6GRCMD-R3tHw" hash="Gbfd1g">You may never see angels descending out of heaven, but I can promise you as you bear testimony and pray in your families, unseen angels will minister to you. As you share your talent for spirituality, you will feel the warmth and power of the Spirit governing your life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p26" pid="Do4OziftnE6o9NxUXLFQDw" hash="brsRKQ">The prophets are right. You young women “are part of the greatest generation we have ever had” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of Gordon B. Hinckley,</span> 718). You can be a strong influence on your family. It is a true principle that the Lord operates through families.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality.p27" pid="99lsv7_lOESoB3TX1MFpOQ" hash="EZ4iFQ">Now that you have learned how the Spirit works and how you as young women can use it to bless your families, it is our prayer that you will let spirituality become you. Heavenly Father is eager to unleash this great power. May the Spirit bless you as you develop your talent for spirituality, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2001/04/developing-our-talent-for-spirituality</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2001-general-young-women-meeting/2001-03-0020-carol-b-thomas-64k-eng.mp3" length="5350239" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2001 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sacrifice: An Eternal Investment</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sacrifice is an amazing principle. … It can develop within us a profound love for each other and our Savior, Jesus Christ.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029247_000_027" doc-version="2" hash="3KVcGw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="JQMrGXNZwUmfds2kNeHFog" hash="vY_iGQ">Sacrifice:</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="gSS6-BDLI0aiyzgIFB2uOQ" hash="4Cv3gQ">An Eternal Investment</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ElWnjk7PsE-n-OtAyfrMLg" hash="jTox9A">Carol B. Thomas</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="Q8URC8QQgUqzVicS-fIwnA" hash="8FT_5Q">Sacrifice is an amazing principle. … It can develop within us a profound love for each other and our Savior, Jesus Christ.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-ee3.jpg" alt="Carol B. Thomas" pid="xTgewXrGDUSJDb3aVHK1TQ" hash="lVbTWw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p1" pid="7cRF15ShG0y2dgxXenTs5w" hash="OcFdNw">As a mother, I think one of the most heart-wrenching stories in the Old Testament is that of Abraham, asked by the Lord to offer his young son Isaac as a sacrifice. Sarah must have been at least 100 years old when Isaac was taken to the mountain. Out of kindness to her, I think Abraham might not have told her what he intended to do, and that meant he had to bear this great test of faith alone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p2" pid="OGkKTyATZk-ILchRnPXABg" hash="6KRDAg">President Lorenzo Snow once said, “No mortal man could have done what Abraham did … except he were inspired and had a divinity within him to receive that inspiration” (<span class="emphasis">The Teachings of Lorenzo Snow,</span> ed. Clyde J. Williams [1984], 116).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p3" pid="xpFF3yKBUUmJ9hyT_O3icQ" hash="tU-Dbw">Beginning with Adam, all Old Testament prophets have kept the law of sacrifice. Sacrifice is integral to the celestial law, pointing us to the most glorious sacrifice of all: our Savior Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p4" pid="b0cjMQDD0kGa7sABnvbKug" hash="WAtVnQ">President Gordon B. Hinckley defined sacrifice so beautifully when he said: “Without sacrifice there is no true worship of God. … ‘The Father gave his Son, and the Son gave his life,’ and we do not worship unless we give—give of our substance, … our time, … strength, … talent, … faith, … [and] testimonies” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of Gordon B. Hinckley</span> [1997], 565).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p5" pid="T4wFyGW-40KiURDah8j8rA" hash="W9SR1g">Brothers and sisters, the law of sacrifice is one of the things that sets us apart from the rest of the world. We are a covenant people, blessed with opportunities to worship and to give; but are we fully converted to the principle of sacrifice? I’m reminded of the wealthy young man, taught by the Savior, who asked, “What do I still lack in my life?” (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/19.20" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 19:20</a>). Jesus said to him, “If thou wilt be perfect, go and sell [all] that thou hast … and come and follow me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/19.21" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 19:21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p6" pid="G-qZuk1j80aeN2C4KEa_Xw" hash="PSsKHQ">Let’s discuss three ways that sacrifice can help us follow the Savior: teaching our families, giving to the poor and needy, and sharing ourselves in missionary work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p7" pid="IcYMQgZnBkilo6LytzA7UA" hash="cxp5WA">First, how can we teach our families to sacrifice? My grandfather Isaac Jacob was a great example to me. Grandpa was a sheep rancher who sent four sons on missions. During the Depression, it became my mother’s opportunity to serve, and she received her call to Canada.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p8" pid="yzJbhmKuvkqPBKv9G-g-4Q" hash="HXzl4A">Grandpa’s situation became critical when he was called in by his bank and asked just what was the $50 a month going out for Mom’s mission. He had taken out a loan and was paying a high rate of 12 percent interest. The bankers were not satisfied and told him to bring Mom home from her mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p9" pid="JBFGFPJ6gki66uiOBjFoeg" hash="yh2gsA">The following day Grandpa gave his answer: “If that girl comes home, the sheep are yours—and I’ll bring them right up to your door.” This caught the bankers by surprise. They were already using Grandpa to care for other sheep outfits which they had acquired, and they would have no one else to take care of all those sheep. Mom completed her mission, and Grandpa’s example taught his family the importance of sacrifice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p10" pid="OjxRDUlw7kaKkGKTbxWRrA" hash="IJCu9Q">As we teach our families to sacrifice, we should also teach them to deny themselves. The story is told of the Civil War general Robert E. Lee, who, when asked by a woman for advice in raising her child, said, “Teach [your child] to deny himself” (see Joseph Packard, <span class="emphasis">Recollections of a Long Life</span> [1902], 158).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p11" pid="JnZyN-zUi0qCDAJpxt_BXw" hash="5eo8RA">We must avoid saturating our children with material things. We may deprive a child of enjoyment when we give him too much. If we never allow him to want something, he will never enjoy the pleasure of receiving it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p12" pid="BPvhFXMVdEuwtfEqSx7-Wg" hash="oQCVNg">Are we encouraging our children to sacrifice by giving their time and resources, such as helping a lonely neighbor or befriending someone who needs it? As they concentrate on the needs of others, their own needs become less important. True joy comes from sacrificing for others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p13" pid="SzsFP2eWrkK3xkFEKtidLQ" hash="uEmG0Q">Second, we can give more generously to the poor and needy. As I visit with Church members, I am overwhelmed with the goodness of faithful Latter-day Saints. A young man in Colombia, raised by his grandmother, owned several shoe repair shops and served as the custodian in his ward. When he was called on a mission, he had saved not only enough money to pay for his own mission but also contributed extra funds to support another missionary.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p14" pid="uXYbYyOVDECRpWZ6rQ2vaw" hash="tYJzAA">What about sharing our food, clothing, and furniture? The Lord commands that we not covet our own property (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/19.26" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 19:26</a>). In many places we are blessed to have Deseret Industries. We can teach our children to go through their closets regularly and share their clothing while it is still in style, allowing others to dress fashionably too.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p15" pid="9i1bGfMt3E6nw_U0khSwDA" hash="sjf1CA">Many rewards come from sharing our material possessions. King Benjamin reminds us of this when he says, “For the sake of retaining a remission of your sins from day to day, that ye may walk guiltless before God … impart of your substance to the poor, … such as feeding the hungry, clothing the naked, visiting the sick and administering to their relief” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.26" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:26</a>). We can all be searching for the many opportunities in our lives to give—to share.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p16" pid="IlqdLnwif0ONVfqvuS0ruA" hash="NEUF9Q">The third area of sacrifice is missionary work. As part of our assignment in visiting wards and branches throughout the Church, we see the tremendous need for senior missionaries. You can’t imagine what a great good they do as they love the missionaries and teach the local members the doctrine and culture of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p17" pid="Xl_ChTI9wkyBPaSIggArKA" hash="KnL9mA">Recently President Hinckley visited a stake conference in an affluent area where only four older couples were serving missions. Hoping to inspire more members to serve, he promised them that their children and grandchildren would not even miss them while they’re gone. With the invention of e-mail, friendly letters can be sent and received by senior missionaries just about any day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p18" pid="BJWpDEs6D0G8iai56NksbA" hash="wptQMA">Your years of experience will bless others, and you’ll discover how wonderful people really are. The missions of the world need you! Pray for that spirit of adventure and a desire to serve a mission. You’ll enjoy more excitement than motor-home travel or rocking chairs.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p19" pid="4nAX5-21NE-jupHxLqTaSA" hash="sVjVZQ">Young people, we hope you are excited about missionary work. Just last week each young woman in the Church was invited to bring one other young woman into full activity. How great it would be if the young men would join us in this effort!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p20" pid="EdRzl27W3UiVaiX1vQVEDg" hash="KvYeYg">Many of you are doing remarkable things. Megan, a young woman, prayed many months for two friends who were not members of the Church, arranging for one friend to sign up for seminary and inviting the other to be taught by the missionaries. Recently these two young women were baptized. The Church needs you. President Hinckley cannot walk down the halls of your school and teach your friends, but you can, and the Lord is counting on you. We’re so proud of the courage you have as you share your love for the gospel with your friends.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p21" pid="MTUmvucHRUiSWsyzgBQ6Yg" hash="mGcKBQ">Sacrifice is an amazing principle. As we willingly give our time and talents and all that we possess, it becomes one of our truest forms of worship. It can develop within us a profound love for each other and our Savior, Jesus Christ. Through sacrifice our hearts can be changed; we live closer to the Spirit and have less of an appetite for things of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p22" pid="mCwSqnLuZ0W9Yj4arlyC0Q" hash="XbrnEA">President Hinckley taught a grand truth when he said: “It is not a sacrifice to live the gospel of Jesus Christ. It is never a sacrifice when you get back more than you give. It is an investment, … a greater investment than any. … Its dividends are eternal and everlasting” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of Gordon B. Hinckley,</span> 567–68).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment.p23" pid="SqxHOSnSQkKO2pQ0coBxmA" hash="GgqHTw">How comforting to know that we are not expected to make this investment alone. Like Abraham of old, we have a divinity within us to receive inspiration through the powers of heaven. Brothers and sisters, I pray that by doing these things we will come to love the principle of sacrifice, that this great principle will bring us closer to our Savior, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2001/04/sacrifice-an-eternal-investment</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2001-general-conference/2001-04-4040-carol-b-thomas-64k-eng.mp3" length="4656009" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strengthen Home and Family</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Three principles that will help you strengthen your home and family are nurturing, sacrifice, and prayer.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029598_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="QerMVw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="AVcZr-MnB0atBG-o-Pr30Q" hash="3tQ1xg">Strengthen Home and Family</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="kpV-CFOBSUyISwdXnZ4TDg" hash="jTox9A">Carol B. Thomas</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="QduhuMdPe0q93r0XHFNM1g" hash="7MhDqQ">Three principles that will help you strengthen your home and family are nurturing, sacrifice, and prayer.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-ee3.jpg" alt="Carol B. Thomas" pid="TgrLmsx6O02T3uYxLCj_-A" hash="lVbTWw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p1" pid="MMgfEnjHS0mOeo43_tuz5g" hash="2tldNg">As we watched the 2002 Winter Olympics draw to a close, we couldn’t help but remember those individuals who took home the gold. So many athletes with years of preparation came together to compete, hoping to win. As young women in the Church, you too are preparing and competing for a medallion as the Spirit burns brightly within you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p2" pid="lkQRucmcL068NrMzv4PYmg" hash="gqHZfQ">The Young Women program can provide a wonderful training ground to help each of you reach your goals, and the Young Women theme is a constant reminder that we are not alone in the competition. We are on the Lord’s team, and He will always be there for us to help us bring home the gold.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p3" pid="GZFK9WjofUq6H2Xkm3SLtg" hash="TzbVNg">As daughters of God, some of you may have great athletic ability, but all of you have been blessed with many talents and gifts. One of the most meaningful gifts is your ability to “strengthen [your] home and family,” a new phrase which has been added to the Young Women theme. Do you recognize these words? One of the assignments given us as girls and women in the kingdom is to love and strengthen our families.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p4" pid="14NBS0ik1ECY9w-CFkLBKw" hash="NyYtKw">Tonight it is my prayer that the Spirit will burn within you, that you will have a greater desire to strengthen your family now and prepare for your future family. The scriptures are filled with ways to teach us how to strengthen our families. There is no greater teacher than the Savior. As you study His teachings and follow His example, you can make your family life better. Let’s talk about three principles that will help you strengthen your home and family:</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.f2">
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="OR7OUbnzIEeu-I7Ui7UtwQ" hash="PgwcPw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="lyqVDJakRk2c2povwhTlRA" hash="J4dyIw">Nurturing</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="4Hth98rKIEuv2zHi-bsnng" hash="7g-_VA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="gWCfA-NHJEqiKklUikq7Ow" hash="vY_iGQ">Sacrifice</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="1yRkHBjwJk2pIq9xkwHShw" hash="PQRFwA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="GPcG0rC9AkigU-4nJ70yTA" hash="7ButCA">Prayer</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="3ym25_tqF0CfYgfjBZPKdQ" hash="J4dyIw1">Nurturing</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p5" pid="zaYyadP7HUuGg-BIk5zirg" hash="rMbgEQ">Who doesn’t enjoy playing with a small child or holding a newborn baby in their arms? As women, we were born with a natural ability to love and nurture others. To nurture means to support each other, to encourage each other, to nourish and love each other. Are we doing this in our families?</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p6" pid="IJws5ri-yk2OOdSwqdeIaA" hash="6rRoGg">The Savior Himself taught us to nurture. Many times He said, “How oft have I gathered you as a hen gathereth her chickens under her wings, and have nourished you” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/10.4" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 10:4</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p7" pid="OhtKJZUKwke6LzoQcG7wpQ" hash="7Tob1g">As you gather together in your family, you can do so much to invite a spirit of unity. When was the last time you put your arms around your mom or dad and thanked them for all they do? Parents do most of the nurturing, but they need to be nurtured too.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p8" pid="qEX7DxkTok24EYN5W-abdQ" hash="ox3vSw">As women, we can gather our little chickens under our wings with love and tenderness. Recently I watched a young mother talk to her two-year-old child. When she was crying and the mother couldn’t understand what she wanted, the mother said, “Don’t cry. Use your words. Tell me what’s bothering you.” She had shown such respect for this two-year-old baby that the baby stopped crying and “used her words.” This young mother is learning how to nurture.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p9" pid="XsFIvI9zV02pbrrKnxsOLA" hash="amMw0w">When our Father in Heaven introduced the Savior to the world, He demonstrated good nurturing by using a soft voice. The language of the scripture says, “They heard a voice as if it came out of heaven; … and it was not a harsh voice, neither was it a loud voice; … notwithstanding it being a small voice it did pierce them that did hear to the center” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.3" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:3</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p10" pid="otJCKojnDkCRnr4OxCtp8g" hash="pO0l6w">In our homes, this can be a model for the way we talk to our family members. Let us not use a loud voice but a soft voice when we talk to those we love. This is the way Heavenly Father speaks to His children.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="KSb7tvUq30GOf_aP6SiQyA" hash="vY_iGQ1">Sacrifice</h3>
        <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.f3">
	  <p pid="fTtQ4EbBPkWelXVxHR947Q" hash="5d90Tg">The second principle is sacrifice. As young women, you are learning to sacrifice every day. We are so impressed with all the good things you are doing:</p>
	  <ul class="bullet">
	    <li pid="jJlEwiDNJkOAYHHuayP_lw" hash="nOPkXA">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="x5CBJKWRg0ezeIVhZdDyQg" hash="at7ykA">You tend after school when your mothers need to work. You help fix dinner and put babies to bed.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="XaLmzwKRLUSfkFSEUc6KIw" hash="KUBmlQ">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="wsCt7Cdb00OHzlZdzkra4g" hash="7K6eVA">You stay home from parties on weekends because you won’t watch inappropriate movies regardless of the rating.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="QL1uOVt2fk22pbhADEnsAA" hash="Ten_ig">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="9aR1bY8qy0WVpl9OYOgTpA" hash="9ypVYQ">Thousands of you get up at five o’clock each morning to attend early-morning seminary before going off to school.</p>
          </li>
	  </ul>
	</div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p11" pid="aLmfSA2ekEyN7cFs242jjQ" hash="GozkCw">The Savior is so proud of you. He knows what you’re going through. He understands how hard it is for you to make sacrifices. The Savior taught us to sacrifice. He sacrificed His life for all mankind.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p12" pid="wfso73mYoEW_ODVy6JPGjg" hash="YiDNAg">After He was resurrected, the first thing He taught the Nephites was how He had sacrificed. He said: “I have drunk out of that bitter cup which the Father hath given me. … I have suffered the will of the Father in all things” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.11" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:11</a>). He had done what Heavenly Father wanted Him to do.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p13" pid="heUfgoVqxU6NW3XrX1yLuQ" hash="g_AFnQ">Heavenly Father wants us to create a righteous family. Becoming a wife and mother may limit your career opportunities, but it can be so rewarding. As a young mother, I remember playing a song for my little girls while they danced around the room. It may sound a little silly, but it says it all:</p>
        <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.f4">
          <div class="stanza">
            <p class="line" pid="kKY3w9l1D0meYKDtFBJ9uA" hash="zzDVcw">
              <span class="emphasis">When I grow up, I want to be a mother and have a family:</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="-KJ7Nxy_YkuLPZojbUWt3Q" hash="yqN6KQ">
              <span class="emphasis">one little, two little, three little babies of my own.</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="NUTloN9bvEGoctHXBPP6KQ" hash="VnonXA">
              <span class="emphasis">Of all the jobs for me, I’ll choose no other.</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="Qj2ftriPT0uGf7-YTnKWJg" hash="3iQejw">
              <span class="emphasis">I’ll have a family. … </span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="6ULtpqnrxkuWIqYKNINaMQ" hash="f7CSNg">
              <span class="emphasis">And I will love them all day long</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="9GJjjl90bUaVp20doVioDQ" hash="J_wbmA">
              <span class="emphasis">and give them cookies and milk and yellow balloons,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="QtHOYF82UUOGyTKe6s1gxw" hash="z3WMKg">
              <span class="emphasis">And cuddle them when things go wrong,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="YUPG_gQF_E-awkItafHzuA" hash="eYDCnQ">
              <span class="emphasis">and read them stories and sing them pretty tunes.</span>
            </p>
          </div>
        </div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p14" pid="BXASe9j24Uu5piSa81Uvcw" hash="L2D8vg">Well, you get the idea. Being a mother is a great blessing, not a sacrifice.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="IrBDI2qVNkGPvPrlCin7dQ" hash="7ButCA1">Prayer</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p15" pid="rOWKTZMQyky9bcjFJv6K0g" hash="fi96aA">Third, the Savior teaches us to pray.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p16" pid="bAjuvIN5NkuweLqiCA2khQ" hash="Gcxd7g">As you help strengthen your family, prayer must be a consistent, daily part of your life. Prayer will protect you from the adversary, give you peace, and help your families love each other more.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p17" pid="iV7OXhP7_kSEjGXdTVUF1Q" hash="ldbH8Q">When the Savior visited the Nephites, He had only a few days to teach them the fulness of the gospel. During much of that time, He focused on prayer. Did you know that in chapters 17 through 20 of Third Nephi, prayer is mentioned about 44 times? Many times He commanded the people to pray. He knelt on the ground and prayed for them. He taught them how to pray. He blessed the little children and prayed unto the Father for them. He commanded them to always pray in their hearts.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p18" pid="X-JtM9x7skCgdYyGjJy-DQ" hash="O5ruqw">Perhaps during a Mutual activity you could bring your scriptures, read those four chapters aloud, and underline when the word <span class="emphasis">prayer</span> is mentioned—sharing stories and testimonies on the power of prayer. I promise that you will feel the Spirit of the Lord and develop a stronger testimony of prayer.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p19" pid="MyLIMrPiHkmoM-DzluLKDA" hash="g89RvQ">Our prophets have said that they don’t worry about the youth who pray twice a day. Now, if they don’t worry about us, then we don’t need to worry about ourselves, as long as we sincerely pray twice a day.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p20" pid="Aa7L4GPXkUCi_thp8Z5-vw" hash="i12UJA">Listen to a wonderful story by the mother of the Prophet Joseph Smith about the night he went to get the gold plates. She writes: “[That night] I sat up very late. … About twelve o’clock Joseph came to me and asked me if I had a chest with a lock and key. … And not having one I was greatly alarmed. … But Joseph … said, ‘Never mind, I can do very well … without it—be calm—all is right.’”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p21" pid="YTK-8ORJHEmxCzwyyP_G_Q" hash="LOsJNw">Shortly after, Joseph and Emma left, taking a horse and wagon. Now listen to what his mother says: “I spent the night in prayer and supplication to God, for the anxiety of my mind would not permit me to sleep.” The pleadings of a mother, a righteous daughter of God, comforted the Prophet and protected the gold plates. Over the years, her constant prayers helped strengthen her home and family (see Lucy Mack Smith, <span class="emphasis">History of Joseph Smith, </span>ed. Preston Nibley [1979], 102).</p>
        <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.f5">
	  <p pid="T49QEZcxe0mtDLJ1tcG8Yg" hash="KDjCKQ">How can you use prayer to strengthen your family? Because Heavenly Father loves you so, He wants you to talk to Him. Whatever struggles you may have, you can pray about anything:</p>
	  <ul class="bullet">
	    <li pid="fYiDLQrTG0udM7fgM0RPvg" hash="LR5vKw">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="baduHCAc5ECV3GpwS202uw" hash="lFcblQ">You can pray for help in keeping family rules, such as coming home on time.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="smrDfL0CIUK1fE617WOVOQ" hash="4qGI-A">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="71CDPMW4EEaH4vGVIYoodQ" hash="tgFUrw">You can pray that your family will have a desire to study the scriptures together.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="QEM0wfz_QkijEE6zH1t0SQ" hash="FQ77_g">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="CLRoqNaKEEiLmf_ScQ_KXQ" hash="Xz3OYA">You can pray that you will have better communication with your mom or your dad.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="badlgyum8UWxCchMq_8ZAg" hash="wPVaKA">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="O10SYw9Fo0G0BGTuPbl2fA" hash="Ein6sw">You can pray that you will be more patient with a sister or brother, helping them solve their problems.</p>
          </li>
	  </ul>
	</div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p22" pid="RDxyp-7rbE6XfxjKe0mz7A" hash="wcQN6w">Pray over problems that worry you! Don’t give up. Heavenly Father can and will answer your prayers. I have had many prayers that have been answered. I also have prayers that have not been answered yet. Our prayers will be answered in the Lord’s time when we are ready.</p>
        <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.f6">
	  <p pid="cb2xXZ26k0qL7m8ASBsMZA" hash="zottsw">Tonight I have talked about three principles to help you strengthen your home and family:</p>
	  <ul class="bullet">
	    <li pid="Qjq9h07V3UW_Z9kvePMlrQ" hash="PgwcPw1">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="gpI0bUcNWky4Y96aBAdCiQ" hash="J4dyIw2">Nurturing</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="Fco2EXNDGUu37chmFC1zDA" hash="7g-_VA1">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="3GeY_D2we0OAR0eTNFP_kQ" hash="vY_iGQ2">Sacrifice</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="rS7ysI6RnkeWnkP4Cso1ZQ" hash="PQRFwA1">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="xjChPZQ7Gki0Si6LDbzz5g" hash="7ButCA2">Prayer</p>
          </li>
	  </ul>
	</div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family.p23" pid="sx9bLHSmlU-j3f6Zvw84OQ" hash="Ex0-Sw">The Savior, our Redeemer and friend, has shown us the way. As you practice His teachings, you may never win the Olympic silver or gold, but earning your Young Womanhood medallion can bring a much greater reward and help keep the fire of the Holy Ghost burning brightly within each one of you. As you study and develop a love for the scriptures, I pray that you will find other meaningful ways to strengthen your home and family. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2002/04/strengthen-home-and-family</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2002-general-young-women-meeting/2002-03-0020-carol-b-thomas-64k-eng.mp3" length="5074293" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2002 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
