<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Cecil O. Samuelson Jr.</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Cecil O. Samuelson Jr..</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Cecil%20O.%20Samuelson%20Jr..jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Cecil O. Samuelson Jr..</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2004 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2004 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Perilous Times</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times?lang=eng</link>
      <description>How grateful I am, in these perilous times, for the protection and guidance given to us by the sacred assurance that Jesus Christ lives today.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030208_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="kFu17w">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="R1rwc1fNukGLe_x-2_eWdA" hash="Q5piwA">Perilous Times</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="OeHk-h8htkuMi4ihawLnxA" hash="LBErHQ">Cecil O. Samuelson Jr.</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="DrKldija60a8giAuVDEyzQ" hash="zW-B9w">How grateful I am, in these perilous times, for the protection and guidance given to us by the sacred assurance that Jesus Christ lives today.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-647.jpg" alt="Elder Cecil O. Samuelson Jr." pid="80eYXjXoM02NxpWeEwYLtg" hash="nRjwHw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p1" pid="OOB3SFylwUG0ciuJzybI-A" hash="oJQFkA">Brethren, it is both comforting and potentially worrisome to know that we live in an age and a time that was not only foreseen by the prophets of previous dispensations but was also clearly a focus of their concerns and their aspirations. The Apostle Paul said, “In the last days perilous times shall come” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/3.1" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 3:1</a>), and then he went on to catalog and describe with remarkable accuracy much that we currently see daily in the media, in advertisements for entertainment, and almost everywhere in the world around us. As careful as we might and should be, absolute avoidance of much of the peril which is seemingly enveloping us is at best difficult and often near impossible to avoid.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p2" pid="wy_4sCR2FU-ujiGIWHA9uQ" hash="bKcGuQ">Happily, we are not left without hope or spiritual sustenance as we strive individually and as families to accomplish the sacred purposes of mortal life for which we came to this earthly probation. Each of our circumstances is unique. We come literally from the four corners of the earth, and we also come from tremendously different families, backgrounds, challenges, opportunities, experiences, triumphs, and disappointments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p3" pid="gid8PrUkvUazNgWbSCfxdQ" hash="610WEQ">Likewise, in common with all of the human family—everyone being the progeny of our loving Heavenly Father—we share vast congruence in our DNA or genetic physical makeup, as well as the universally possible and promised blessings and characteristics that identify our divine parentage and spiritual potential. It is this special blending of our common origins and characteristics and also of our unique attributes, experiences, and specialized challenges that makes each of us who and what we are. While we may have differences in what constitutes special peril for us individually, we share much that establishes the apt description of “perilous times” for all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p4" pid="6ZB6CSA2qEu-e2ugXeipJQ" hash="MC4kBg">Paul, in describing our “perilous times,” did not promise that things would necessarily get easier or necessarily better. He did give counsel to those seeking comfort and assurance in the face of the deteriorating conditions of our day. Just as his prophecies or predictions were clearly accurate, so is his direction to us remarkably relevant as well. Said he, “Continue … in the things which thou hast learned and hast been assured of, knowing of whom thou hast learned them” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/3.14" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 3:14</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p5" pid="UPZeNJOcYEqP2GcmAEc2ww" hash="-rYZvQ">In this general conference, consistent with the pattern covering the entire history of the Church, we have learned and will learn of the Restoration of the gospel in our day; of the remarkable clarity and testimony of the Lord Jesus Christ found in the Book of Mormon; of the mission and contributions of the Prophet Joseph Smith and his successors in the Presidency of the Church, including especially President Gordon B. Hinckley, who teaches and testifies with such power, spirituality, and lucidity; and of the strength, comfort, and blessings that accrue from the presence of other living apostles and prophets in our midst. Not only do we learn these things, but we are assured that they are true, knowing, as Paul said, “of whom [we have] learned them.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p6" pid="U5o-fAh8zUu_vx_v4OCJAw" hash="_VBTsA">Another who was authorized to assure those to whom he ministered was Alma. As he expressed his pleasure at the privilege of teaching and testifying to the people of Gideon, he was forthright, clear, and direct in his witness of the Lord Jesus Christ, who was yet to come in His earthly ministry. He expressed his delight at the general faith and faithfulness of this group of good people and promised them that they would be the recipients of “many things to come” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/7.7" class="scriptureRef">Alma 7:7</a>). In the midst of his discourse, describing things yet to come, he said, “There is one thing which is of more importance than they all— … the time is not far distant that the Redeemer liveth and cometh among his people” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/7.7" class="scriptureRef">Alma 7:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p7" pid="6SPO9VGvPUCUPPHMInxUzQ" hash="lTVHwQ">Alma was speaking in his time specifically of the events of a few decades hence when the Savior would be born into mortality. Centuries have passed and Alma’s prophecies have been largely fulfilled, but the central fact of his estimation of the thing more important than all else is still absolutely true, completely relevant, and fundamentally essential for us today as well. It is that “the Redeemer liveth.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p8" pid="i7Qe1O_y10eGfVJ_-q3huA" hash="f1VUgA">As Alma and “all the prophets who have prophesied ever since the world began” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/13.33" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 13:33</a>) have taught and testified of the coming of the Messiah and His mission to redeem His people, so do we join in bearing testimony of Him and His sacred work “to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>). Surely when we begin to understand the magnitude of His sacrifice and service to us individually and collectively, we then cannot consider anything else to be of more importance or to approach His significance in our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p9" pid="3LnYjdc2XkmSNHNi5cZltQ" hash="yMNmmg">For most of us, this understanding does not come all at once and likely will not be fully complete during our mortal sojourn. We do know, however, that as we learn line upon line, our appreciation for the Savior’s contributions will increase and our knowledge and assurance of their truthfulness will grow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p10" pid="HVZMvgxYw0KV1TnLeNZhKQ" hash="FQBe6g">The Apostle Paul was forceful and candid in much of his teaching and preaching. Listen to these familiar words that may describe most of us in our efforts and progression and yet provide the counsel, encouragement, and witness that we so badly need:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p11" pid="h6aN1MmRTE2lS5ldDUJCGQ" hash="v96aEA">“When I was a child, I spake as a child, I understood as a child, I thought as a child: but when I became a man, I put away childish things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p12" pid="Mvi7tQe890-SG7d6ZYQcHA" hash="VPDv9w">“For now we see through a glass, darkly; but then face to face: now I know in part; but then shall I know even as also I am known” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/13.11-12" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 13:11–12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p13" pid="rgWxLmKa7kKrjGDsvpv7Aw" hash="qCkzAw">Many years ago, President James E. Faust gave this counsel to those still struggling to become fully convinced in their testimonies of Jesus Christ and His sacred mission and promises. Said he:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p14" pid="ugVOUjNomk-0ILisM7NVPQ" hash="3q_dyw">“For those who have honest doubts, let us hear what eyewitnesses had to say about Jesus of Nazareth. The ancient apostles were there. They saw it all. They participated. No one is more worthy of belief than they. Said Peter: ‘For we have not followed cunningly devised fables, when we made known unto you the power and coming of our Lord Jesus Christ, but were eyewitnesses of his majesty.’ (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-pet/1.16" class="scriptureRef">2 Pet. 1:16</a>.) Said John: ‘For we have heard him ourselves, and know that this is indeed the Christ, the Saviour of the world.’ (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/4.42" class="scriptureRef">John 4:42</a>.) Modern-day witnesses, Joseph Smith and Sidney Rigdon, declared: ‘For we saw him, even on the right hand of God; and we heard the voice bearing record that he is the Only Begotten of the Father.’ (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:23</a>.)” (“A Personal Relationship with the Savior,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1976, 59).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p15" pid="Vfa30vvDJ0mQ54tZ_m69qw" hash="RhRQaQ">In our own day, we have been promised that the Lord has many gifts in store for “those who love [Him] and keep all [His] commandments” and also those “that seeketh so to do” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/46.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 46:9</a>). While not every gift of God is pledged to every person, we have been assured that “to every [person] is given a gift by the Spirit of God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/46.11" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 46:11</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p16" pid="_8AHrMOTC0Kx6Eko3LfH2g" hash="XHVWtQ">Listen to these words from the 46th section of the Doctrine and Covenants that address the question of the thing or gift of more importance than any other:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p17" pid="kpZaxLZChkuTdNGYbsot3g" hash="hZBp8A">“To some it is given by the Holy Ghost to know that Jesus Christ is the Son of God, and that he was crucified for the sins of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p18" pid="I7URSzNNF0eOtev-u1Fn6A" hash="ZuKVgw">“To others it is given to believe on their words, that they also might have eternal life if they continue faithful” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/46.13-14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 46:13–14</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p19" pid="lIQueI7itEu2S2Gf2pVhIw" hash="jie_GQ">It is this knowledge and testimony of the living Christ that allows us to be continually responsive to the advice and counsel of Peter, who said that we must “be ready always to give an answer to every man that asketh you a reason of the hope that is in you” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-pet/3.15" class="scriptureRef">1 Pet. 3:15</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p20" pid="4-4hdLu310OsBA_xIvL9Gw" hash="meEtSw">When we begin to really sense that this hope is real and is actually centered in Jesus, being made possible because of His love for us and especially His love of His Father, then we can gratefully and individually proclaim, using the words of a favorite hymn, “I stand all amazed at the love Jesus offers me” (“I Stand All Amazed,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 193). Likewise, as our understanding unfolds, we are led to exclaim, “Then sings my soul, my Savior God, to thee, How great thou art! How great thou art!” (“How Great Thou Art,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 86).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times.p21" pid="HQoo9oF6B0C8EMMPCATpaA" hash="jbrX5w">How grateful I am, in these perilous times, for the protection and guidance given to us by the sacred assurance that Jesus Christ lives today, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2004/10/perilous-times</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2004-general-conference/2004-10-3030-elder-cecil-o-samuelson-jr-64k-eng.mp3" length="4250203" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2004 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testimony</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/04/testimony?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The fundamentals of gaining and retaining a testimony of the gospel of Jesus Christ are straightforward, clear, and within the capacity of every person.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50028768_000_2070" doc-version="2" hash="OaDbxQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.head1">
    <h1 class="title" pid="i5oWZOaBIEexSSyOQXpSQw" hash="w8s8fg">Testimony</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="cXaznsUBUk2RBomA5ww2rQ" hash="LBErHQ">Cecil O. Samuelson Jr.</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="7SfxXlw5jEmGtjcrU4GEnw" hash="dEtBJA">The fundamentals of gaining and retaining a testimony of the gospel of Jesus Christ are straightforward, clear, and within the capacity of every person.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p1" pid="9YObNTVrrkKZeeslqimpKw" hash="g579UQ">One of the great blessings of my life over many years has been the opportunity to be surrounded by and work with the young people of the Church. I consider these associations and friendships to be among the sweetest and most valuable of my life. They also are much of the basis for the optimism I have for the future of the Church, society, and the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p2" pid="fnxuyzOHTUy9WOG_P5Zgsw" hash="ffkezQ">During these interactions I have also had the privilege of conferring with some who have had various doubts or challenges with their testimonies. While the specifics have been varied and occasionally unique, many of the questions and causes for confusion have been quite similar. Likewise, these are issues and concerns not restricted to any demographic or age-group. They may trouble those who are multigenerational Church members, relatively new Church members, and also those just becoming familiar with The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. Their questions are usually the result of honest inquiry or curiosity. Because the implications are so significant and serious for each of us, it seems appropriate to consider the matter of our testimonies. In our Latter-day Saint context, we refer to our testimonies as our sure witness of the truthfulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ, which is obtained by revelation through the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p3" pid="S_UYCFlgZUCVB2IeRu3gfg" hash="0cgpkA">While a testimony is simple and clear in this defining declaration, arising from this declaration are several potential questions, such as: Who is entitled to have a testimony? How does one obtain the necessary revelation? What are the steps in obtaining a testimony? Is gaining a testimony an event or an ongoing process? Each of these queries and others have their own subsets, but the fundamentals of gaining and retaining a testimony of the gospel of Jesus Christ are straightforward, clear, and within the capacity of every person.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p4" pid="IESgBjUcIkGNZzpjyKghDA" hash="MKxxQA">Let me briefly respond to these possible uncertainties and then refer to some insights that have been shared recently by trusted young adult friends who have had personal experience in gaining their testimonies. They have also had opportunities to minister to others having challenges or difficulties with some aspects of their faith and beliefs.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p5" pid="-LFPJBNQAkuVSWEHT95IAw" hash="8Ngurg">First, who is entitled to have a testimony? Everyone who is willing to pay the price—meaning keeping the commandments—may have a testimony. “Wherefore the voice of the Lord is unto the ends of the earth, that all that will hear may hear” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.11" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:11</a>). A fundamental reason for the Restoration of the gospel is so “every man might speak in the name of God the Lord, even the Savior of the world; that faith also might increase in the earth” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.20-21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:20–21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p6" pid="zuZOJDTxlEa2otrVll0x4w" hash="TBuusg">Second, how does one obtain the necessary revelation, and what are the fundamental steps to achieve it? The pattern has been clear and consistent throughout the ages. The promise given for obtaining a testimony of the Book of Mormon also applies generally:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p7" pid="v4KmoxsDvEqXcr3KZWN6_Q" hash="uWMPqw">“And when ye shall receive these things”—meaning you have listened, read, studied, and pondered on the question at hand—“ask God, the Eternal Father, in the name of Christ, if these things are not true”—meaning you will pray thoughtfully, specifically, and reverently with a firm commitment to follow the answer to your prayer—“and if ye shall ask with a sincere heart, with real intent, having faith in Christ, he will manifest the truth of it unto you, by the power of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p8" pid="IbBd0fNU50aFUdz_Aqqk8Q" hash="_uMWZw">“And by the power of the Holy Ghost ye may know the truth of all things” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.4-5" class="scriptureRef">Moroni 10:4–5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p9" pid="yWNjmHV3UUyt8piTIgPovw" hash="j-GyaQ">Third, is gaining a testimony an isolated event or an ongoing process? A testimony is similar to a living organism that grows and develops when treated properly. It needs constant nourishment, care, and protection to thrive and prosper. Likewise, neglect or deviance from the pattern of living that a testimony clarifies can lead to its loss or diminishment. The scriptures warn that transgressing or breaking the commandments of God can result in the loss of the Spirit and even to one denying the testimony he or she once possessed (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:23</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p10" pid="Rp6i0U-v0ke9B7yrHieaOA" hash="jz1wlQ">Let me now share 10 of the observations and suggestions of my valued and faithful young friends. The ideas they share have a commonality in their thinking and experience; thus, they likely will not be surprising to any of us. Unfortunately and especially at times of our own struggle and distress, we may temporarily forget or discount their applicability to us personally.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p11" pid="7pDkrIyY40y5aLfjkhBseg" hash="2kaWqw">First, everyone has worth because we are all children of God. He knows us, loves us, and wants us to succeed and return to Him. We must learn to trust in His love and in His timing rather than in our own sometimes impatient and imperfect desires.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p12" pid="WmvIhQGVykaMhTieypWq6w" hash="RkMrxQ">Second, while we believe fully in the mighty change of heart described in the scriptures (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/5.2" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 5:2</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.12-14,26" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:12–14, 26</a>), we must understand it often occurs gradually, rather than instantaneously or globally, and in response to specific questions, experiences, and concerns as well as by our study and prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p13" pid="zr36F5UeVU2sT62_VUgvHg" hash="bHolfw">Third, we need to remember that a fundamental purpose of life is to be tested and stretched, and thus we must learn to grow from our challenges and be grateful for the lessons learned that we cannot gain in an easier way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p14" pid="aSMlB0Vu_UO7sDnuvhMMCA" hash="PznmLw">Fourth, we must learn to trust the things that we believe in or know to sustain us in times of uncertainty or with issues where we struggle.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p15" pid="Ocrir45gZk6P1XBc86klfA" hash="je0Rzg">Fifth, as Alma taught, gaining a testimony is usually a progression along the continuum of hoping, believing, and finally knowing the truth of a specific principle, doctrine, or the gospel itself (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p16" pid="pc_AHQIxAUCjc8G2vJkeEQ" hash="bCo9NA">Sixth, teaching someone else what we know strengthens our own testimony as we build that of another. When you give someone money or food, you will have less. However, when you share your testimony, it strengthens and increases for both the bearer and the hearer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p17" pid="eTmrRVIGFUyGkxqWuKXD3Q" hash="AROV3A">Seventh, we must do the little but necessary things daily and regularly. Prayers, scripture and gospel study, attendance at Church meetings, temple worship, fulfilling visiting teaching, home teaching, and other assignments all strengthen our faith and invite the Spirit into our lives. When we neglect any of these privileges, we place our testimonies in jeopardy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p18" pid="GsrmGlX530uHKz8aM54ZAw" hash="loYqvQ">Eighth, we should not have higher standards for others than we do for ourselves. Too often we may let the mistakes or failures of others, especially leaders or Church members, influence how we feel about ourselves or our testimonies. Other people’s difficulties are not an excuse for our own deficiencies.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p19" pid="B5PL0jW9tUqOda4YEmU_kA" hash="xkVxmQ">Ninth, it is good to remember that being too hard on yourself when you make a mistake can be as negative as being too casual when real repentance is needed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p20" pid="pyMIbzoRJkOmr7bT6EZcDQ" hash="kMaYMg">And tenth, we must always be clear that the Atonement of Christ is fully and continuously operative for each of us when we allow it to be so. Then everything else fits into place even when we continue to struggle with certain details, habits, or seemingly missing parts in the mosaic of our faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p21" pid="YD6pwIUpSk6XFijfDeSLHg" hash="gRUiKA">I am grateful for the insights, strengths, and testimonies of so many of my exemplary young friends and associates. When I am with them, I am strengthened, and when I know that they are with others, I am encouraged with the knowledge of the good that they are doing and the service that they are rendering in behalf of the Master they worship and strive to obey.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p22" pid="Mh0igGsha0SRGKmQwswBqw" hash="B7aH9w">People do good and important things because they have testimonies. While this is true, we also gain testimonies because of what we do. Jesus said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p23" pid="KQtsM6pPCUCLWlTeUO2zLw" hash="PvjNRg">“My doctrine is not mine, but his that sent me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p24" pid="cqWkOA8DrUu6S_xUPFVZMQ" hash="q24zug">“If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it be of God, or whether I speak of myself” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/7.16-17" class="scriptureRef">John 7:16–17</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p25" pid="00YLnoPDUUOy9E2Rs8J7fw" hash="mMahqg">“If ye love me, keep my commandments” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.15" class="scriptureRef">John 14:15</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p26" pid="6TpmcbTEZkez-RhkaLHRAw" hash="M7h2nw">Like Nephi and Mormon of old, “I do not know the meaning of all things” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/11.17" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 11:17</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/bofm/w-of-m/1.7" class="scriptureRef">Words of Mormon 1:7</a>), but let me tell you what I do know.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/testimony.p27" pid="CNB-z9D8JUWKyfZrxyYTjw" hash="bJm11w">I know God our Heavenly Father lives and loves us. I know His uniquely special Son, Jesus Christ, is our Savior and Redeemer and the head of the Church, which bears His name. I know Joseph Smith experienced all that he has reported and taught with respect to the Restoration of the gospel in our day. I know we are led by apostles and prophets today and President Thomas S. Monson holds all of the keys of the priesthood necessary to bless our lives and advance the work of the Lord. I know we are all entitled to this knowledge, and if you are struggling, you can rely on the truthfulness of the testimonies you hear from this pulpit at this conference. These things I know and bear testimony of in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/04/testimony</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2011-general-conference/2011-04-2070-elder-cecil-o-samuelson-jr-64k-eng.mp3" length="4231094" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
