<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Charles A. Didier</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Charles A. Didier.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Charles%20A.%20Didier.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Charles A. Didier.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>My Gratitude</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/10/my-gratitude?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, I suppose that everybody knows, even if it is not yet Church doctrine, that French is the language of heaven. Yes. And if you didn’t know it, I think there is still time to repent before the next conference.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-gratitude" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03063_000_025" doc-version="3" hash="WgXrXw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-gratitude.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="-n5bE91B2UOOV6zSuNG_qw" hash="w_IXRQ">My Gratitude</h1><p class="authorName" pid="w0p02MAYKEeBt_B_jTrDIQ" hash="10p2Yg">Charles A. Didier</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-gratitude.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2bca.jpg" alt="Elder Charles A. Didier" pid="9P2bm6aqp0SG3NfO0vR-Qw" hash="rXJsfQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-gratitude.p1" pid="O0LKk9MifkagwSIWWXV51g" hash="chPp0Q">My dear brothers and sisters, I suppose that everybody knows, even if it is not yet Church doctrine, that French is the language of heaven. Yes. And if you didn’t know it, I think there is still time to repent before the next conference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-gratitude.p2" pid="rHbiS-vWPkitL-Azx3Ds-A" hash="vWekAA">My dear brothers and sisters, if I am here today, I owe it to hundreds of hands which pushed me, pulled me, helped me, sustained me to be here today; in fact, to be a member of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-gratitude.p3" pid="3Ut3os69Gk-gQmWkKZc43Q" hash="545qcg">And what I want to share today with you is simply a message of gratitude: First to thank my wife, my dear wife, for what she has done for me, for the faith that she had in me and her constant effort to be a loving mother to two boys.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-gratitude.p4" pid="uNLeJxr_6E2CMew2o1Rp6g" hash="g8jeeQ">To my mother, now deceased, but who had the courage to lead the family to the Church, to see that the children of the family were taught in the principles of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-gratitude.p5" pid="bfEc7FAMvEKeMwXU1ENP7w" hash="s8tyng">To my father, still not a member, but for what he taught me—to always select quality in life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-gratitude.p6" pid="zq7ckDCTB0SyHRpDPBKKPw" hash="kIl3-A">To the missionaries, the missionaries who came knocking on my door to bring me the message of the restoration of the gospel, to those who taught me, who baptized me, to those with whom I had the great pleasure to work in the France-Switzerland Mission, missionaries whom I respect for their dedication, their sacrifice, and their example.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-gratitude.p7" pid="2-3C-Hn5v0W9V5RulF_43Q" hash="V16cAw">Thank you to you great people of America, for you, your fathers, and your grandfathers who gave your lives to give freedom to my country two times in forty years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-gratitude.p8" pid="aGNz8PTMxkiNdIAAC7nwRw" hash="JyW69Q">Thank you to the leaders of the Church, to the managers who have helped me to be a constant practicer of the gospel of Jesus Christ. Thank you also to the prophet of the Lord, President Kimball, whom I love and admire because he’s here to lead us, to guide us in very difficult times.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-gratitude.p9" pid="hpRVn_igQEe-ASCtsvtR3A" hash="jqR3JA">Thank you to my Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ, for his sacrifice. Thank you to my Father in heaven who gave me the possibility to learn about the beauty of his gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-gratitude.p10" pid="ScCvjbmMa0OkPbmUGzGaBQ" hash="wAXRaw">I would like to share with you my testimony, that I know that God lives, that I know that Jesus is the Christ, as well as I know that the Holy Ghost can murmur and whisper in your ear the same testimony that I have today about the veracity of the Book of Mormon and all the principles that exist in the church of Jesus Christ on earth today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-gratitude.p11" pid="QA1uPYNOdkOS24b_ORyzMw" hash="t9HhYw">And this I bear solemn witness to you, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/10/my-gratitude</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1975-general-conference/1975-10-4040-elder-charles-a-didier-64k-eng.mp3" length="3705841" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Value of People</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, as we shared yesterday the great “spirit of 76 North Main,” of the Relief Society, I would like to share with you the “spirit of ’76” of the Europe West Area, and bring to you the message of love, of testimony, from the </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03070_000_040" doc-version="2" hash="O8htNA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ow_LXKqRcEqLx9UqAahBRw" hash="SqwbxQ">The Value of People</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="5kdi5pAbeEyhWZJ9abzImA" hash="10p2Yg">Charles A. Didier</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2bca.jpg" alt="Elder Charles A. Didier" pid="8MnbYA4B60SlxOcqZjMWyQ" hash="rXJsfQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p1" pid="vc-D4l6t6Euy9CGRme7otw" hash="DGqKpg">My dear brothers and sisters, as we shared yesterday the great “spirit of 76 North Main,” of the Relief Society, I would like to share with you the “spirit of ’76” of the Europe West Area, and bring to you the message of love, of testimony, from the people of Belgium, France, Italy, the Netherlands, Spain, and Switzerland.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p2" pid="XQIHPdhWKE-_5TTJZSgAJw" hash="2aWl8w">During my last move, and going through what is called the elimination process, I found one of my former students’ notebook of international law. I had written in big capital letters on the front cover a quotation from Aristide Briand, winner of the Nobel Prize for Peace and one of the animators of the former League of Nations. It read, “The institutions are worth what the individuals are worth.” During the years I had pondered many times about this truth as I studied or worked with different institutions like companies, governments, or even churches. And I thought that by the same analogy I could say that the value of a country depends upon the value of its people and that it will rise or decline according to the desires of its people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p3" pid="jnw3J1v_GECrtP49yVoAeg" hash="sPyq4g">One people, one country, has done more for the world than any other nation in history because of the righteous desires of its people. May I today celebrate with you the bicentennial of the creation of this country—a country that has a divinely inspired constitution—and praise the Lord with you for what its inhabitants were, what they are, and what they will be?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p4" pid="tme9nKkd00GfaZ1KU6m2Mg" hash="gmbdGg">I remember as a child the stories about the generosity of the American people as they were told by my grandfather as I sat on his lap. With a gentle and broken voice, he explained how our people were saved from starvation at the end of the First World War. My own first vision of this charity came when I saw my first American soldier on his Bren gun carrier the day we were liberated. He handed me a large piece of something to put in my mouth. (I found out much later that this something was called “corned beef”!)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p5" pid="cg8keBvGKk-25BU3SNeANQ" hash="rgLj0Q">I remember as a teenager reflecting on the sacrifices of the American people as I rode on my bicycle through the cemeteries not far from my home and looked silently at the thousands of white crosses in orderly lines, marking the graves of those who gave their lives so that I could live in freedom. I remember as a student learning how our countries of Europe kept their economical freedom thanks to General Marshall’s plan; how our countries kept their independence; how so many countries in the world, struck by natural disasters, were rescued and helped.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p6" pid="DYHGedi45EG6bppVGM3SvQ" hash="avDNxg">I remember as a young man receiving in my home two young men. (Strangely enough, they had the same first name: Elder!) They showed our family the Book of Mormon, a divine evidence of the Lord’s care and love for his children. They declared to our family the message of the restoration of the gospel, the divine sonship of Christ, the divine mission of Joseph Smith, and the divinity of this church. Their message and their willingness to follow the prophet’s call changed our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p7" pid="1hKI-fqU7kmyBMAUzhUv3g" hash="H_aBcA">I remember as a father, as a priesthood holder, as a mission president, how, thanks to your examples of charity, of sacrifice, of love, of dedication, of work, I learned a lesson—that the source of all blessings is God, through obedience to his commandments. Now I see the fruits of the seeds you planted as I tour the missions and stakes of Europe, and I would like to share some of them with you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p8" pid="qtTxs0ugC0myZlGP5GoNmA" hash="UMUJIw">I saw the fruits of sharing the gospel and calling every young man as a missionary as I watched a young local Spanish missionary bearing his testimony in Italy. Another elder just recently called from the Paris Stake told his mission president, with tears in his eyes, that he and his companion had taught five discussions the previous evening in a language that he did not speak three weeks ago.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p9" pid="6CYL4K7yG0ONnkx4d1sO6A" hash="cGV_zQ">I saw the fruits of loving the message of an inspired prophet of the Lord to lengthen our stride when I listened to a branch mission leader in Brussels, Belgium, telling his priesthood companions that he was thrilled to know that fifteen families were ready to find new families and invite them into their homes to be taught by the missionaries.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p10" pid="R_5ig1Y6RkmYMpq2iTs8IA" hash="EZ5kgw">I saw the fruits of sacrifice as I listened to district presidents striving to get better activity, attendance, and results to be qualified to grow into stakes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p11" pid="wu-67_NWHU-DKTPfgu0sNw" hash="xbaAbA">I saw the fruits of work and dedication as I watched hundreds of members going to the temple, preparing for the coming area conferences, building the kingdom with a renewed spirit of service to their fellowmen. The complete list of the fruits would be too long, but you should know that your seeds fell into good ground and are bringing forth more and more good fruit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p12" pid="wSWS9PrmwUOfFcJIN_48fA" hash="4ynAxQ">Yes, I remember what you have done and so do millions of people who looked for the light of example and truth. Today is already the past for many, and tomorrow wears a mask of fear. Today can still change tomorrow, but what kind of society are we building? What kind of a country will we have if we, as one people, do not defend ourselves against the assaults of evil? Was it not Moroni who took a piece of his garment and wrote on it, in order to keep his people from slavery, “In memory of our God, our religion, and freedom and our peace, our wives, and our children.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/46.12" class="scriptureRef">Alma 46:12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p13" pid="PJ276LQsakmzAw42uMzXPA" hash="JA-mXw">I said in the beginning that the value of a country rests upon the values of its people. For the people of God, for the people who want peace, for their women and their children, there is only one way, one church, and one Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p14" pid="Z2c1CaDqFEW0wIBzpfg_lA" hash="o5Cs-A">The way is to repent and obey the commandments of the Lord and be examples to the rest of the nations by listening to a living prophet. The church is The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, restored by the Prophet Joseph Smith. The Lord is the Lord Jesus Christ, of whom it is said, “For there is none other name under heaven given among men, whereby we must be saved.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/4.12" class="scriptureRef">Acts 4:12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p15" pid="Yo3oRA9pF0C3jMXgFuxpLg" hash="bSUnng">This is eternal truth, and “whatsoever is more or less than this is the spirit of that wicked one who was a liar from the beginning.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.25" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p16" pid="KdlBElaH_kGDl7OdRBcimQ" hash="ACwg5g">Today at school, at work, or wherever we may be, the choice between truth and evil will be presented to us in many different ways. It could be by papers, posters, individuals, radio, television, conversations. A mental choice has to be made concrete by accepting or refusing, by dictating or obeying, by counseling or dissuading.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p17" pid="HFVsqFrQGEaKmhCbC2zP6A" hash="yi4Ljw">What are the feelings that will determine this daily choice? Love, passion, fear, courage, pride, laziness, or will? Are these feelings in accordance with our faith and testimony? The key to the righteous answer is given by a loving Father:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p18" pid="GfMccjyxr0a0vEU0SxPL1A" hash="PZYJQQ">“He that keepeth his commandments receiveth truth and light, until he is glorified in truth and knoweth all things.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p19" pid="Rtavkv-zWkGXsbTLwHvrJw" hash="xpWYtw">Obedience to the commandments must be the sole and essential condition determining our choices and thus determining our eternal life. Alma expressed it in a very clear way:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p20" pid="zRagxS6USUCBbNJsYnYzdg" hash="ZQ7zPw">“I ought not to harrow up in my desires, the firm decree of a just God, for I know that he granteth unto men according to their desire, whether it be unto death or unto life; yea, I know that he allotteth unto men according to their wills, whether they be unto salvation or unto destruction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p21" pid="pmb_otx_w06TE97anR77Ig" hash="T1P5wA">“Yea, and I know that good and evil have come before all men; he that knoweth not good from evil is blameless; but he that knoweth good and evil, to him it is given according to his desires, whether he desireth good or evil, life or death, joy or remorse of conscience.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/29.4-5" class="scriptureRef">Alma 29:4–5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p22" pid="3V0k_khslU29RWSyQbPYMQ" hash="raXtUA">May we remember together to “make a joyful noise unto the Lord, all ye lands.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people.p23" pid="ewhvkP4D6kurtr8-asQnJQ" hash="vhYdyQ">“Serve the Lord with gladness: … know ye that the Lord he is God: It is he that hath made us, and not we ourselves; we are his people, and the sheep of his pasture.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/100.1-3" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 100:1–3</a>.) The future of the world is in the hands of the people, and following a living prophet today will determine our salvation. It is my prayer that, thanks to a great conference, we will make new resolutions so that we will be remembered forever and ever as one people who wanted to serve the Lord. In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/04/the-value-of-people</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1976-general-conference/1976-04-6060-elder-charles-a-didier-64k-eng.mp3" length="12435862" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1976 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter to a Returned Missionary</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, I would like to dedicate the following words to a certain category of men and women in the Church. We do not talk too much about them, maybe because they don’t say too much, maybe because there is a bridge too far. You c</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03089_000_027" doc-version="2" hash="2N0nNg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="txi5ulIOYk-7N46B1uHOGg" hash="0xHRLg">Letter to a Returned Missionary</h1><p class="authorName" pid="UULAw-G4rUiWG0LrBcWpcg" hash="10p2Yg">Charles A. Didier</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2bca.jpg" alt="Elder Charles A. Didier" pid="WREpm0_yY0ywkMas-__n0w" hash="rXJsfQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p1" pid="W1fxhwIl1Eq-lk9xdn0KeA" hash="GFcBzA">My dear brothers and sisters, I would like to dedicate the following words to a certain category of men and women in the Church. We do not talk too much about them, maybe because they don’t say too much, maybe because there is a bridge too far. You can and will meet some of them today, tomorrow, and every day of your life. They live among us. Just now we have about 50,000 parents, 100,000 grandparents, and many thousands of brothers, sisters, cousins, and friends who will be concerned with them soon. In fact, we are all concerned with this group. We call them returned missionaries.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p2" pid="nNirQzE7q0OOuq8amYvt6w" hash="odeoAQ">I have a letter here with me that I was going to mail to one of them. May I share it with you as a tribute to missionary work but especially as a reminder of our responsibilities towards our returned missionaries. Before I read it, you should know that the personages of this letter, as well as their characters, are not imaginary, and that after all their resemblance with anyone real, living or dead—with many other returned missionaries—could well be a coincidence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p3" pid="mnzEBl2KKEC84SqanXGnEA" hash="FlWiuw">Dear Elder Brown,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p4" pid="ujPqaocGUEq51-htt2zRAA" hash="iqhcdg">You will certainly not mind if I still call you elder, will you? This is the name under which I started to know you, and it will be associated that way in my mind forever. Do you remember? It was that hot summer afternoon. You and your companion were pushing your bicycles towards the hill where we lived. We admired how you could put up with the heat with your white shirts and your ties. For two or three days we had noticed how you literally flew down the hill, and when you rang the bell of our home, all of us, the four children, rushed to the door to know who those young foreigners were and what they were doing in the neighborhood. You came in, and when we offered you some ice-cold tea, you refused politely by saying that you were not thirsty. What a pious excuse for missionaries, as I learned later who you were and the purpose of your visit. It took us some time to realize what you were talking about. First the strong American accent and then what you showed us to start with: pictures of Indians, pictures of ruins in South America, and even some handmade copper plates bound with three rings. We felt quite like Christopher Columbus when he discovered the New World, a strange but exciting discovery.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p5" pid="wR5fVLH06USmbJMg-CjdBA" hash="kKjwZA">We rapidly became good friends as your visits became more frequent. You were preaching the message of the restoration of the gospel, and we were learning English in school. We both had our personal motivations to see each other! It was not difficult to also teach us some English and especially how to say “I love you.” You were a living example with your companion. We loved you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p6" pid="pEzwqMhwGEeYYyi5SgTvfA" hash="gBpGDw">One day we learned that you were leaving the city. This you called a transfer. It was the right word; we had to transfer our love to a new companion. Soon we followed his teachings and example, but you were the first, and you remained so in our minds. We also learned that your mission was for two years, and of course, you promised when you left that you would send us news. Indeed, we received one short letter two months later. There was also a picture with it. All was well, but it took us a little time to recognize you. Oh, not because of the horse that you were riding instead of your bicycle in the mission fields, not because of the clothes, but rather because of the sideburns and the length of your hair. We smiled about this as we thought that perhaps you were trying to re-create the legend of Buffalo Bill. We did not know that leaving the mission field also meant that you abandoned some of the characteristics that made you so special to us and were some of the reasons why we invited you into our home. You were so different from the world. Why was it so difficult to remain different?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p7" pid="H62K6-7PskutvLycWYRSVQ" hash="SFQbkQ">We were anxious to receive the next letter. We grew in the Church, were baptized one after the other, and learned very soon of the importance of temple marriage. Some wedding cards arrived in the meantime from some of your companions. We rejoiced every time just looking at their pictures, and we could feel their happiness. Yours never came. We did not dare ask you why.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p8" pid="ehqR6GSm5UO_kwFwLtGSCw" hash="I3aRhw">Some time passed; I had my first opportunity to come to Salt Lake. I was finally going to see all the things you had been talking about, or should I say, <span class="emphasis">bragging</span> about. That’s another word of vocabulary that I learned from you. Would you believe me if I told you that I was not surprised when I saw the city? You revealed so much and with such an enthusiasm about the valley, the Tabernacle, the temple, and the members that I already had a vision in my mind of what to expect. I had envisaged even Brigham Young entering the valley and saying, “This is the place.” Now the vision became reality in the same way that you explained the first vision of Joseph Smith and what it meant for the world and for myself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p9" pid="WFsh5EplfkCSVGZeGMWzIw" hash="LRY2lQ">Of course, we wanted to visit with you. We still had a vision of you, Elder, smiling and testifying with tears in your eyes: “I know what I say is true because I asked my Heavenly Father and I received a personal answer. There are no doubts any more. I have peace in my mind. I know that Jesus is the Christ, that Joseph Smith is a Prophet, and that this Church, The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, is the only true and living church upon the face of the whole earth.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p10" pid="39smo7Voo0aGSckzef2qdQ" hash="-JIZ7A">I could not resist or deny your testimony because of the Book of Mormon. You spoke to my heart by the power of the Holy Ghost. I did not tell you how I felt that day. These are things we sometimes do not like to talk about because of the sacredness of our feelings, but it was the beginning of a new life for me, with new objectives, and a sure knowledge of the Church and of the truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p11" pid="5szKzjdRYkKIv5CEOocF3w" hash="-8tNhA">Yes, that day we arrived in Salt Lake we wanted to tell you, the same way you told us, that we also knew. We wanted to say: “Thank you, Elder. Thank you for what has happened in our lives because of your testimony. You prepared the way of the Lord. You made his paths straight. Now, listen, the gospel rolls forth into the cities of your old mission. Zions are established in Europe. Well done, thou good and faithful servant. Let us share this joy together.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p12" pid="pc_k2qeQc0KDaD1beNRQAA" hash="zyd_Dw">We first met one of your former companions; we asked after you. There was a kind of hesitation in his voice, and he seemed embarrassed but finally he admitted that you were working in a gas station and that you would probably not be coming to general conference or even listening to it. You were not, as we say in the Church, “very active,” meaning that you were no longer living the principles that you preached to us some years ago. We decided immediately to see you. We drove in front of the gas station and stopped.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p13" pid="yuO51Jj0Dk-EW_dY5wenwQ" hash="H3j5DA">We were looking for you, and as you saw us and realized who we were, there was a kind of hesitation. I could detect panic on your face, and I smiled as you were trying desperately to hide a cigarette that started to burn your fingers. We shook hands, asked about your wife, your children, your life, your future. Something was missing. You knew it and we knew it. We left. A last look through the window, a last wave of the hand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p14" pid="YaPWQl_QxUKvE2kPxVMGaw" hash="WZ5qjA">Today I am in Salt Lake again, and I am writing this letter with the hope of reaching you. I do not know where you are. I drove in front of the gas station, but you were not there anymore. Where are you, my brother?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p15" pid="_r8NpEwhskej0W8njEjdzQ" hash="yCEHiw">I hope that you will not mind if I have recalled some of the souvenirs of what you always referred to as the best time of your life. Why can’t it be the same way today? Why should the “best time” always refer to yesterday instead of tomorrow? The gospel of Jesus Christ is not a gospel made of souvenirs. It is a gospel presented to us so that we may live it today in order to know where we will be tomorrow. Alma bore his testimony of it in these words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p16" pid="D5gdK1NbdUqbwgn0YJjLOA" hash="wa9P0g">“For behold, this life is the time for men to prepare to meet God; yea, behold the day of this life is the day for men to perform their labors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p17" pid="Hd7iHCGN6EiAa0f93lIrJg" hash="Cfx4bg">“And now, as I said unto you before, as ye have had so many witnesses, therefore, I beseech of you that ye do not procrastinate the day of your repentance until the end; for after this day of life, which is given us to prepare for eternity, behold, if we do not improve our time while in this life, then cometh the night of darkness wherein there can be no labor performed.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/34.32-33" class="scriptureRef">Alma 34:32–33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p18" pid="je8fnYayQ0uU8ayTszYUKQ" hash="0kiQBA">Dear Elder, you said one day in a conference that mothers can give birth to children, but missionaries can give eternal life to people. I recorded this as well as your testimony that day. The words of our Savior Jesus Christ are also recorded that we may not forget, that because of his sacrifice, we may repent of our errors. Didn’t he declare to the Nephites: “Behold, I am the law, and the light. Look unto me, and endure to the end, and ye shall live; for unto him that endureth to the end will I give eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p19" pid="VEN0HVdCF0GNrMdReus3Hw" hash="-p3AUg">“Behold, I have given unto you the commandments; therefore keep my commandments. And this is the law and the prophets, for they truly testified of me.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/15.9-10" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 15:9–10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p20" pid="y3a3dfWW_UKjqZ4XB1latw" hash="5et1wA">You have opened the gate to many. Why, why do you close it for yourself? May I put my foot in the door, as you once did in mine? Reach out your hand while there is still time, and let us tell you that we love you. Your bishop is waiting for you; your home teachers are caring for you; your missionary companions do not forget you; but more than that, we, we need you. Come as you are—our arms are open. We’re waiting for you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary.p21" pid="1R7hZtVrMk-nKUEt2tZn6w" hash="8lR0TQ">Now the time has come to leave, but you should know that what you once were you can be again. May my testimony help you as yours did me some years ago. I know by the power of the Holy Ghost, the spirit of revelation. I know in my mind and in my heart that God lives, that Jesus is the Christ, our Redeemer, and that we have a living prophet today, Spencer W. Kimball, and that by following his directions and advice we can come closer to our Heavenly Father and repent of our sins. My prayer is that you may realize this again in your own life and make a new decision to be one of His disciples, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1977/10/letter-to-a-returned-missionary</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1977-general-conference/1977-10-5030-elder-charles-a-didier-64k-eng.mp3" length="6917677" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 1977 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
