<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Cheryl A. Esplin</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Cheryl A. Esplin.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Cheryl%20A.%20Esplin.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Cheryl A. Esplin.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Our Children to Understand</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Teaching our children to understand is more than just imparting information. It’s helping our children get the doctrine into their hearts.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10485_000_13espli" doc-version="2" hash="moJZCQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="R7kkllbPT0e9jPT09ujPOA" hash="OsrB2A">Teaching Our Children to Understand</h1><p class="authorName" pid="DgJwwOUrrkGfHJ56CKvhvw" hash="d_eh1w">By Cheryl A. Esplin</p><p class="kicker" pid="mn1BPFSbpUqRwnFpr3ktMQ" hash="2NLdSg">Teaching our children to understand is more than just imparting information. It’s helping our children get the doctrine into their hearts.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" pid="LEPf_2IZAkSyP_7-WMI2Hw" hash="0L1bzw">
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p5" pid="Td72THLTGEK_Lhvw64MgXw" hash="1JdK8w">
      <span class="pageBreak" page-number="10"></span>As years pass, many details in my life are becoming more and more dim, but some of the memories that remain most clear are the births of each of our children. Heaven seemed so near, and if I try, I can almost feel those same feelings of reverence and wonder I experienced each time one of those precious infants was placed in my arms.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p6" pid="SX2_tRCsTEG9DDqD5I6zug" hash="KniqRw">Our “children are an heritage of the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/127.3" class="scriptureRef">Psalm 127:3</a>). He knows and loves each one with perfect love (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/8.17" class="scriptureRef">Moroni 8:17</a>). What a sacred responsibility Heavenly Father places upon us as parents to partner with Him in helping His choice spirits become what He knows they can become.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p7" pid="TvUY8u1sQE6-LGCAUcM2tQ" hash="d4s6Dw">This divine privilege of raising our children is a much greater responsibility than we can do alone, without the Lord’s help. He knows exactly what our children need to know, what they need to do, and what they need to be to come back into His presence. He gives mothers and fathers specific instruction and guidance through the scriptures, His prophets, and the Holy Ghost.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p8" pid="NQ7wiOLRjEm-FAagsUvF1g" hash="FUE1VA">In a latter-day revelation through the Prophet Joseph Smith, the Lord instructs parents to teach their children to <span class="emphasis">understand</span> the doctrine of repentance, faith in Christ, baptism, and the gift of the Holy Ghost. Notice the Lord doesn’t just say we are to “teach the doctrine”; His instructions are to teach our children to “<span class="emphasis">understand</span> the doctrine.” (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.25,28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:25, 28</a>; emphasis added.)</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p9" pid="0fu0wGI7-k2cGjVH2T2p1w" hash="TGhB3A">In Psalms we read, “Give me understanding, and I shall keep thy law; yea, I shall observe it with my whole heart” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/119.34" class="scriptureRef">Psalm 119:34</a>).</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p10" pid="8wM2O-7HakmCaW1pwIUYpQ" hash="RIQmmA">Teaching our children to understand is more than just imparting information. It’s helping our children get the doctrine into their hearts in a way that it becomes part of their very being and is reflected in their attitudes and behavior throughout their lives.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p11" pid="V9zyqbHLtU2PGMKjyeNlmA" hash="82Cpxw">Nephi taught that the role of the Holy Ghost is to carry the truth “unto the hearts of the children of men” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/33.1" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 33:1</a>). Our role as parents is to do all we can to create an atmosphere where our children can feel the influence of the Spirit and then help them recognize what they are feeling.</p>
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p12" pid="qb8TBU27UUOtH8XcZtjQOQ" hash="UNob-g">I’m reminded of a phone call I received several years ago from our daughter, Michelle. With tender emotion she said, “Mom, I just had the most incredible experience with Ashley.” Ashley is her daughter who was five years old at the time. Michelle described the morning as being one of constant squabbling between Ashley and three-year-old Andrew—one wouldn’t share and the other would hit. After helping them work things out, Michelle went to check the baby.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p13" pid="9NQOq2gZGEqxYiM4Z7yLSw" hash="fY-tvA">Soon, Ashley came running in, angry that Andrew wasn’t sharing. Michelle reminded Ashley of the commitment they had made in home evening to be more kind to each other.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p14" pid="5G2rGaF1zE2IVmyHAoXcpg" hash="9LNLjg">She asked Ashley if she wanted to pray and ask for Heavenly Father’s help, but Ashley, still very angry, responded, “No.” When asked if she believed Heavenly Father would answer her prayer, Ashley said she didn’t know. Her mother asked her to try and gently took her hands and knelt down with her.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p15" pid="DFn2jgLpzEagqjb_PTCwrg" hash="Gf-rEw">Michelle suggested that Ashley could ask Heavenly Father to help Andrew share—and help her be kind. The thought of Heavenly Father helping her little brother share must have piqued Ashley’s interest, and she began to pray, first asking Heavenly Father to help Andrew share. As she asked Him to help her be kind, she began to cry. Ashley ended her prayer and buried her head on her mother’s shoulder. Michelle held her and asked why she was crying. Ashley said she didn’t know.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p16" pid="RwMtLkcPkkmg-9g3zAvBjQ" hash="s0y8ZA">Her mother said, “I think I know why you’re crying. Do you feel good inside?” Ashley nodded, and her mother continued, “This is the Spirit helping you feel this way. It’s Heavenly Father’s way of telling you He loves you and will help you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p17" pid="z1EpldLQ2kSuwy29UPyo-A" hash="zJcaJw">She asked Ashley if she believed this, if she believed Heavenly Father <span class="pageBreak" page-number="11"></span>could help her. With her little eyes full of tears, Ashley said she did.</p>
    </span>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p18" pid="39fw4ScIM0K24L0jws92mw" hash="W3fPaw">Sometimes the most powerful way to teach our children to understand a doctrine is to teach in the context of what they are experiencing right at that moment. These moments are spontaneous and unplanned and happen in the normal flow of family life. They come and go quickly, so we need to be alert and recognize a teaching moment when our children come to us with a question or worry, when they have problems getting along with siblings or friends, when they need to control their anger, when they make a mistake, or when they need to make a decision. (See <span class="emphasis">Teaching, No Greater Call: A Resource Guide for Gospel Teaching</span> [1999], 140–41; <span class="emphasis">Marriage and Family Relations Instructor’s Manual</span> [2000], 61.)</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p19" pid="JZ7jkJKq5EqzhrJ20Fm57g" hash="Xgc5xA">If we are ready and will let the Spirit guide in these situations, our children will be taught with greater effect and understanding.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p20" pid="WI9Ib1o4pE6JOxQC7dK9FQ" hash="ecy2-A">Just as important are the teaching moments that come as we thoughtfully plan regular occasions such as family prayer, family scripture study, family home evening, and other family activities.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p21" pid="DMXskBnAokiRWgTMxr7UeQ" hash="9GveoQ">In every teaching situation all learning and all understanding are best nurtured in an atmosphere of warmth and love where the Spirit is present.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p22" pid="hzE2KNO4rE-7h4ZFiSRBzg" hash="pPhnvQ">About two months before his children turned eight years old, one father would set aside time each week to prepare them for baptism. His daughter said that when it was her turn, he gave her a journal and they sat together, just the two of them, and discussed and shared feelings about gospel principles. He had her draw a visual aid as they went along. It showed the premortal existence, this earth life, and each step she needed to take to return to live with Heavenly Father. He bore his testimony about each step of the plan of salvation as he taught it to her.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p23" pid="rESwXm_vsEis3Mcv7kOQGw" hash="VIcHSw">When his daughter recalled this experience after she was grown, she said: “I will never forget the love I felt from my dad as he spent that time with me. … I believe that this experience was a major reason I had a testimony of the gospel when I was baptized.” (See <span class="emphasis">Teaching, No Greater Call,</span> 129.)</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p24" pid="eChhhqHMikiBSWfVDfGdsw" hash="IKQk1w">Teaching for understanding takes determined and consistent effort. It requires teaching by precept and by example and especially by helping our children live what they learn.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p25" pid="0c344dANe06ninctT-8zNg" hash="OVqGiA">
      <span class="pageBreak" page-number="12"></span>President Harold B. Lee taught, “Without experiencing a gospel principle in action, it is … more difficult to believe in that principle” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of Presidents of the Church: Harold B. Lee</span> [2000], 121).</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p26" pid="6-i8fpdfx0-gbFvw-oOezg" hash="AdnjIg">I first learned to pray by kneeling with my family in family prayer. I was taught the language of prayer as I listened to my parents pray and as they helped me say my first prayers. I learned that I could talk to Heavenly Father and ask for guidance.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p27" pid="0KUs_3wJvUiHEi5nMfY1zA" hash="FDe_7w">Every morning without fail, my mother and father gathered us around the kitchen table before breakfast, and we knelt in family prayer. We prayed at every meal. In the evening before bed, we knelt together in the living room and closed the day with family prayer.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p28" pid="bm1x2ZXYm0qtpea1b9bnuw" hash="B7VJwg">Although there was much I didn’t understand about prayer as a child, it became such a part of my life that it stayed with me. I still continue to learn, and my understanding of the power of prayer still continues to grow.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p29" pid="izwAmmocHEqQhkNby8sbKQ" hash="O0f7kA">Elder Jeffrey R. Holland said, “We all understand that the success of the gospel message depends upon its being taught and then understood and then lived in such a way that its promise of happiness and salvation can be realized” (“Teaching and Learning in the Church” [worldwide leadership training meeting, Feb. 10, 2007], <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> June 2007, 57; <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> June 2007, 89).</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p30" pid="-PjK5eadrkGlVF-elHOKcA" hash="WoTNyQ">Learning to fully understand the doctrines of the gospel is a process of a lifetime and comes “line upon line, precept upon precept, here a little and there a little” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/28.30" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 28:30</a>). As children learn and act upon what they learn, their understanding is expanded, which leads to more learning, more action, and an even greater and more enduring understanding.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p31" pid="UpZLQ1MYDEuSxT5_cdbacA" hash="tNG9PQ">We can know our children are beginning to understand the doctrine when we see it revealed in their attitudes and actions without external threats or rewards. As our children learn to understand gospel doctrines, they become more self-reliant and more responsible. They become part of the solution to our family challenges and make a positive contribution to the environment of our home and the success of our family.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p32" pid="nmC45rbhF0u2KFKzfGpZ0w" hash="Cnmz5g">We will teach our children to understand as we take advantage of every teaching situation, invite the Spirit, set the example, and help them live what they learn.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p33" pid="MnayOgS6t0ylknZ8cVpf7w" hash="C0XK5g">When we look into the eyes of a tiny infant, we are reminded of the song:</p>
    <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.f1">
      <div class="stanza">
        <p class="line" pid="kCPhYh5PJEebmKdtbATOlg" hash="Sxrctg">I am a child of God,</p>
        <p class="line" pid="PdjRWZiobkqYiA3WhG_QTA" hash="trRcsw">And so my needs are great;</p>
        <p class="line" pid="LtOgIfrVRUqNOiNHGEwjjg" hash="Y8zvPw">Help me to <span class="emphasis">understand</span> his words</p>
        <p class="line" pid="_awsQpRq3kaIK3FJr6ZGiA" hash="qg4zmQ">Before it grows too late.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="stanza">
        <p class="line" pid="1mRlR6bN5E2egOJM84Y3AA" hash="-on1eA">Lead me, guide me, walk beside me,</p>
        <p class="line" pid="cFXDkAE5Q0yfjXnpruoJ3g" hash="wkwinw">Help me find the way.</p>
        <p class="line" pid="e-pXZrbIKUaDtM6SKee_Tg" hash="bt_CJw">Teach me all that I must do</p>
        <p class="line" pid="2yz7L8vgPEGqJDZr02iUVA" hash="wPuYEw">To live with him someday.</p>
      </div>
      <p class="citationInfo" pid="uTgj2i4y4Eu_VHyUk-EwqQ" hash="hE1RbQ">(“I Am a Child of God,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 301; emphasis added)</p>
    </div>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand.p43" pid="ALvPW_cJakict2ooHFU3NA" hash="6C6E2Q">May we do so. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2012/04/teaching-our-children-to-understand</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2012-general-conference/2012-04-1030-cheryl-esplin-64k-eng.mp3" length="4858030" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sacrament—a Renewal for the Soul</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sister Cheryl A. Esplin teaches how Jesus Christ can renew our souls through the sacrament and discusses how to better prepare for this ordinance.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10991_000_14esplin" doc-version="6" hash="aqAezg">
			
			<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.head1">
				<h1 class="title" pid="MYAEr_Kpgkymbt44zayeog" hash="HCY4Ow">The Sacrament—a Renewal for the Soul</h1>
				<div class="byline">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p2" pid="5GR1ULEYHUC4fUqkBF9DDw" hash="d_eh1w">By Cheryl A. Esplin</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p3" pid="Va6xjsjN_kye-sPLc9Momg" hash="7MgrIA">Second Counselor in the Primary General Presidency</p>
					<a href="gl://image/?pid=5xt2YIUHdU6HasiQD68Htg"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/100x137.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x68="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/50x68.jpg" data-src-100x137="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/100x137.jpg" data-src-200x275="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/200x275.jpg" data-src-320x440="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/320x440.jpg" data-src-460x633="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/460x633.jpg" data-src-640x881="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/640x881.jpg" data-src-1024x1410="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/1024x1410.jpg" data-src-2048x2820="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/2048x2820.jpg" altText="Cheryl A. Esplin" pid="5xt2YIUHdU6HasiQD68Htg" hash="mQSRbw"></img></a>
				</div>
				<p class="kicker" pid="_Mw1Bcc9OUCo-WaFQKW-pQ" hash="7g__3A">The Spirit heals and renews our souls. The promised blessing of the sacrament is that we will “always have his Spirit to be with [us].”</p>
			<p class="authorName" pid="IFyifBaErky-tj3SjAgQgQ" hash="d_eh1w1">By Cheryl A. Esplin</p></div>
			<div class="bodyBlock" pid="4qLywY6OjUCGG59rEWSktg" hash="yIRcdA">
				<span class="story">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p5" pid="wBD9mHNL0k-0yIsBFPIYDQ" hash="Ltmj-A">A group of young women once asked me, “What do you wish you had known when you were our age?” If I were to answer that question now, I would include this thought: “I wish when I was your age I had understood the significance of the sacrament better than I did. I wish I had understood the sacrament in the way that Elder Jeffrey R. Holland described. He said, ‘One of the invitations inherent in the sacramental ordinance is that it be a truly spiritual experience, a holy communion, a renewal for the soul.’<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span>”</p>
				</span>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p6" pid="gB7B181cLkWc7PtcXSnv8w" hash="tq-_lA">How can the sacrament “be a truly spiritual experience, a holy communion, a renewal for the soul” each week?</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p7" pid="BxxQF1336kqxIivKhAO7_A" hash="cRBaCg">The sacrament becomes a spiritually strengthening experience when we listen to the sacrament prayers and recommit to our covenants. To do this, we must be willing to take upon us the name of Jesus Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Speaking of this promise, President Henry B. Eyring taught: “That means we must see ourselves as His. We will put Him first in our lives. We will want what He wants rather than what we want or what the world teaches us to want.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p8" pid="4BRk-yPGg06FiEp1IFQfTA" hash="XryqAQ">When we take the sacrament, we also covenant to “always remember”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Jesus Christ. On the night before He was crucified, Christ gathered His Apostles around Him and instituted the sacrament. He broke bread, blessed it, and said, “Take, eat; this is in remembrance of my body which I give a ransom for you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Next He took a cup of wine, gave thanks, gave it to His Apostles to drink, and said, “This is in remembrance of my blood … , which is shed for as many as shall believe on my name.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p9" pid="ecXFbMrBl0WOwNGB75M5qA" hash="kMf7-g">Among the Nephites and again at the Restoration of His Church in the latter days, He repeated that we are to take the sacrament in remembrance of Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p10" pid="6aRhEq4PuUCins29r0s_Sw" hash="P3sjCQ">As we partake of the sacrament, we witness to God that we will remember His Son always, not just during the brief sacrament ordinance. This means that we will constantly look to the Savior’s example and teachings to guide our thoughts, our choices, and our acts.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p11" pid="VDxSMxsObkuXT8_Nm_AcxA" hash="lXRfuw">The sacrament prayer also reminds us that we must “keep his commandments.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p12" pid="TDjXfgjtxUOYFmOE7pTiAA" hash="BIaZ9w">Jesus said, “If ye love me, keep my commandments.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> The sacrament gives us an opportunity for introspection and an opportunity to turn our heart and will to God. Obedience to the commandments brings the power of the gospel into our lives and greater peace and spirituality.</p>
				<span class="story">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p13" pid="63AqJ2TwC0-QRE3fRGmQtA" hash="GlSZaQ">The sacrament provides a time for a truly spiritual experience as we reflect upon the Savior’s redeeming and enabling power through His Atonement. A Young Women leader recently learned about the strength we receive as we strive to thoughtfully partake of the sacrament. Working to complete a requirement in Personal Progress, she set a goal to focus on the words in the sacrament hymns and prayers.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p14" pid="5LMd3QmuYEKd5-JxBhjA-A" hash="rp4hkw">Each week, she conducted a self-evaluation during the sacrament. She recalled mistakes she had made, and she committed to be better the next week. She was grateful to be able to make things right and be made clean. Looking back on the experience, she said, “I was acting on the repentance part of the Atonement.”</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p15" pid="dPdDW7jCe0mvw9F8CBMN8w" hash="SGH7Ew">One Sunday after her self-evaluation, she began to feel gloomy and pessimistic. She could see that she was making the same errors over and over again, week to week. But then she had a distinct impression that she was neglecting a big part of the Atonement—Christ’s enabling power. She was forgetting all the times the Savior helped her be who she needed to be and serve beyond her own capacity.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p16" pid="Lb_ysz2s1Uizp1qtiYtfOw" hash="4GHJmA">With this in mind, she reflected again on the previous week. She said: “A feeling of joy broke through my melancholy as I noted that He had given me many opportunities and abilities. I noted with gratitude the ability I had to recognize my child’s need when it wasn’t obvious. I noted that on a day when I felt I could not pack in one more thing to do, I was able to offer strengthening words to a friend. I had shown patience in a circumstance that usually elicited the opposite from me.”</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p17" pid="cfKaMOfqr02qCFJ7B9De9w" hash="gLXpyA">She concluded: “As I thanked God for the Savior’s enabling power in my life, I felt so much more optimistic toward the repentance process I was working through and I looked to the next week with renewed hope.”</p>
				</span>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p18" pid="CoeVCh97TU--IyJPBNrZ4A" hash="SecYiQ">Elder Melvin J. Ballard taught how the sacrament can be a healing and cleansing experience. He said:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p19" pid="DXKUzVxS1UmOUNdlogfhjw" hash="ovZ1rQ">“Who is there among us that does not wound his spirit by word, thought, or deed, from Sabbath to Sabbath? We do things for which we are sorry and desire to be forgiven. … The method to obtain forgiveness is … to repent of our sins, to go to those against whom we have sinned or transgressed and obtain their forgiveness and then repair to the sacrament table where, if we have sincerely repented and put ourselves in proper condition, we shall be forgiven, and spiritual healing will come to our souls. …</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p20" pid="M4I8--ZfUUm8GrT2aYZ2gQ" hash="CsEJ1A">“I am a witness,” Elder Ballard said, “that there is a spirit attending the administration of the sacrament that warms the soul from head to foot; you feel the wounds of the spirit being healed, and the load being lifted. Comfort and happiness come to the soul that is worthy and truly desirous of partaking of this spiritual food.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p21" pid="bIy2PdzYbEWYq14e1EpCsQ" hash="MjmdRw">Our wounded souls can be healed and renewed not only because the bread and water remind us of the Savior’s sacrifice of His flesh and blood but because the emblems also remind us that He will always be our “bread of life”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> and “living water.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p22" pid="J98olvyy3UqrH8ovc-MZ2A" hash="eRKiuA">After administering the sacrament to the Nephites, Jesus said:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p23" pid="r5-YvuUbQEiI5tJkEyAU8g" hash="4C0W1A">“He that eateth this bread eateth of my body to his soul; and he that drinketh of this wine drinketh of my blood to his soul; and his soul shall never hunger nor thirst, but shall be filled.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p24" pid="ecvHdsVdQE2gl-zZkpJWYw" hash="4dmPhA">“Now, when the multitude had all eaten and drunk, behold, they were filled with the Spirit.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p25" pid="dQguxRoyqUCGlQS_erIBDQ" hash="L_rm4w">With these words, Christ teaches us that the Spirit heals and renews our souls. The promised blessing of the sacrament is that we will “always have his Spirit to be with [us].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p26" pid="IP9mgfmIh0acJYZI4VfgxQ" hash="w9hG6g">When I partake of the sacrament, I sometimes picture in my mind a painting that depicts the resurrected Savior with His arms outstretched, as if He is ready to receive us into His loving embrace. I love this painting. When I think about it during the administration of the sacrament, my soul is lifted as I can almost hear the Savior’s words: “Behold, mine arm of mercy is extended towards you, and whosoever will come, him will I receive; and blessed are those who come unto me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p27" pid="fARBPjLcr0qNb6RFdUbwHQ" hash="jbBgtg">Aaronic Priesthood holders represent the Savior when they prepare, bless, and pass the sacrament. As a priesthood holder extends his arm to offer us the sacred emblems, it is as if the Savior Himself were extending His arm of mercy, inviting each one of us to partake of the precious gifts of love made available through His atoning sacrifice—gifts of repentance, forgiveness, comfort, and hope.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
				<span class="story">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p28" pid="jsCEwnw4MkiY9ZbilJjlfA" hash="zb5KQg">The more we ponder the significance of the sacrament, the more sacred and meaningful it becomes to us. This was what a 96-year-old father expressed when his son asked, “Dad, why do you go to church? You can’t see, you can’t hear, it’s hard for you to get around. Why do you go to church?” The father replied, “It’s the sacrament. I go to partake of the sacrament.”</p>
				</span>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p29" pid="lA1tWirg6EGuBsyhK0Y63Q" hash="3fprsg">May each of us come to sacrament meeting prepared to have “a truly spiritual experience, a holy communion, a renewal for [our] soul.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul.p30" pid="IB7yjIHvzkuxV7VC9x0I8A" hash="CZ8l8Q">I know that our Heavenly Father and our Savior live. I am grateful for the opportunity the sacrament provides to feel of Their love and to partake of the Spirit. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div>
			
		</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-a-renewal-for-the-soul</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2014-general-conference/2014-10-1040-cheryl-a-esplin-64k-eng.mp3" length="5129216" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filling Our Homes with Light and Truth</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_12565_000_61esplin" doc-version="8" hash="bZAHNQ"&gt;
	
	&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.head1"&gt;
		&lt;h1 class="title" pid="ySl68QdH00WtBbuGVIkmSA" hash="i6Y3dQ"&gt;Filling Our Homes with Light and Truth&lt;/h1&gt;
		&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p2" pid="R_aW7AgYakSrwoHlE2FpoQ" hash="d_eh1w"&gt; By Cheryl A. Esplin &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p3" pid="7BsDJnD_jEyYcraM6OL5Vg" hash="7MgrIA"&gt;Second Counselor in the Primary General Presidency&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=2LGEN8m4_06QPwLGzEAYxA"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" type="jpg" uri="cheryl-a-esplin-10.jpg" translate="no" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/100x137.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x68="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/50x68.jpg" data-src-100x137="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/100x137.jpg" data-src-200x275="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/200x275.jpg" data-src-320x440="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/320x440.jpg" data-src-460x633="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/460x633.jpg" data-src-640x881="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/640x881.jpg" data-src-1024x1410="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/1024x1410.jpg" data-src-2048x2820="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/2048x2820.jpg" pid="2LGEN8m4_06QPwLGzEAYxA" hash="5gANhA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="kicker" pid="WtVzkk3OEUqoaXVZZpGWaQ" hash="07l1nQ"&gt;In order for us and our families to withstand the pressures of the world, we must be filled with light and gospel truth.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="authorName" pid="OAl4vnIA3U2g7qcOmC6OyA" hash="d_eh1w1"&gt; By Cheryl A. Esplin &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class="bodyBlock" pid="KRvZdxzFYkS6l65r8ikN6g" hash="fqQNDQ"&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p5" pid="5Ol_GFZNKkOqaPdsczQ7Fw" hash="g1GrNQ"&gt; My heart filled with the Spirit as I listened to these families teach that sacred truth: “The family is of God.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; Inspiring music is just one of the many ways we can feel the Spirit whisper to us, filling us with light and truth. &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;span class="story"&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=hajwkSmV3UibCJFePu7B9Q"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445728/468ab4e4f3ac4f37b77f1cee2a53ceb0/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445728/468ab4e4f3ac4f37b77f1cee2a53ceb0/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445728/468ab4e4f3ac4f37b77f1cee2a53ceb0/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445728/468ab4e4f3ac4f37b77f1cee2a53ceb0/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445728/468ab4e4f3ac4f37b77f1cee2a53ceb0/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445728/468ab4e4f3ac4f37b77f1cee2a53ceb0/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445728/468ab4e4f3ac4f37b77f1cee2a53ceb0/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445728/468ab4e4f3ac4f37b77f1cee2a53ceb0/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445728/468ab4e4f3ac4f37b77f1cee2a53ceb0/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445728/468ab4e4f3ac4f37b77f1cee2a53ceb0/2790x1800.jpg" altText="" pid="hajwkSmV3UibCJFePu7B9Q" hash="wjpGAw"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p6" pid="1nOH57xur0G4_70X8AGxjw" hash="38GDFg"&gt;The concept of being filled with light and truth became particularly important to me because of an experience I had many years ago. I attended a meeting where members of the Young Women general board taught about creating spiritually strong families and homes. To visually demonstrate this, a Young Women leader held up two soda cans. In one hand she held a can that was empty and in the other hand a can that was unopened and full of soda. First, she squeezed the empty can; it began to bend and then collapsed under the pressure. Next, with her other hand, she squeezed the unopened can. It held firm. It didn’t bend or collapse like the empty can—because it was filled.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p7" pid="bMa3Yi59oUyDR-h2A_b7ig" hash="AFuKOA"&gt;We likened this demonstration to our individual lives and to our homes and families. When filled with the Spirit and with gospel truth, we have the power to withstand the outside forces of the world that surround and push against us. However, if we are not filled spiritually, we don’t have the inner strength to resist the outside pressures and can collapse when forces push against us.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p8" pid="mYMiSu5XKU2jYwrLpaQyqQ" hash="VMtc8g"&gt;Satan knows that in order for us and our families to withstand the pressures of the world, we must be filled with light and gospel truth. So he does everything in his power to dilute, distort, and destroy the truth of the gospel and to keep us separated from that truth.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p9" pid="TCE_NAVwiU-ePEi7lmJERA" hash="RQiSNQ"&gt; Many of us have been baptized and have received the gift of the Holy Ghost, whose role it is to reveal and teach the truth of all things.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; With the privilege of that gift comes the responsibility to seek truth, to live the truth we know, and to share and defend the truth. &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p10" pid="4x-ffaff20yX8Pxh469N-A" hash="mv6EGA"&gt; One place where we best seek to be filled with light and truth is in our own homes. The words in the chorus of the song we heard remind us, “God gave us families to help us become what He wants us to be.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; Families are the Lord’s workshop on earth to help us learn and live the gospel. We come into our families with a sacred duty to help strengthen each other spiritually. &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p11" pid="tPWIhsUbk0mYZgNV2iEPLg" hash="HW2fhw"&gt;Strong eternal families and Spirit-filled homes do not just happen. They take great effort, they take time, and they take each member of the family doing his or her part. Every home is different, but every home where even one individual seeks for truth can make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p12" pid="CL26hntux0qAg2EGTndXfg" hash="OJk0hw"&gt; We are continually counseled to increase our spiritual knowledge through prayer and through studying and pondering the scriptures and the words of the living prophets. In his general conference talk about receiving a testimony of light and truth, President Dieter F. Uchtdorf said: &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p13" pid="mJOMyFct1U2mTLweuqYMIQ" hash="fR1qcg"&gt;“The Everlasting and Almighty God … will speak to those who approach Him with a sincere heart and real intent.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p14" pid="VdfNeMgwvkeRvvoseTTUyg" hash="r858KQ"&gt;“He will speak to them in dreams, visions, thoughts, and feelings.”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p15" pid="8tmg6It86kmpkxiSkDAskg" hash="Gzi5Uw"&gt; President Uchtdorf continued: “God cares about you. He will listen, and He will answer your personal questions. The answers to your prayers will come in His own way and in His own time, and therefore, you need to learn to listen to His voice.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p16" pid="sPzgR5Cy2UuTtTeN6HEqAQ" hash="gprPrQ"&gt;A short family history story illustrates this counsel.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;span class="story"&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p17" pid="smpsjr54GkWxIIGdn0kqiA" hash="YSpNYA"&gt;Several months ago I read the testimony of my great-grandfather’s sister Elizabeth Staheli Walker. As a child, Elizabeth immigrated to America from Switzerland with her family.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p18" pid="ChwoA-17aEyrBHnyAC2sKg" hash="Cok4oA"&gt;After Elizabeth married, she and her husband and children lived in Utah near the Nevada border, where they ran a mail station. Their home was a stopping place for travelers. All day and all night they had to be ready to cook and serve meals for travelers. It was hard, exhausting work, and they had little rest. But the greatest thing that concerned Elizabeth was the conversation of the people they associated with.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p19" pid="dabTCXf47U-JqaN5bzUWlQ" hash="6IVy5g"&gt;Elizabeth said that up to this time she had always taken for granted that the Book of Mormon was true, that the Prophet Joseph Smith had been authorized of God to do what he did, and that his message was the plan of life and salvation. But the life she was experiencing was anything but what would strengthen such a belief.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p20" pid="6gWzAXqJ2EOFxHXsnKbBnA" hash="pfENXw"&gt;Some of the travelers who stopped were well-read, educated, smart men, and always the talk around her table was that Joseph Smith was “a sly fraud” who had written the Book of Mormon himself and then distributed it to make money. They acted as if to think anything else was absurd, claiming “that Mormonism was bunk.”&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p21" pid="myRJLYM8iUa3kAZ6cc38fw" hash="fJhRLQ"&gt;All this talk made Elizabeth feel isolated and alone. There was no one to talk to, no time to even say her prayers—although she did pray as she worked. She was too frightened to say anything to those who ridiculed her religion. She said she didn’t know but what they were telling the truth, and she felt she could not have defended her belief if she had tried.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=7HFrdCjOQEmeaiFkURPnIA"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445727/080bc79bff48444889fe22484ccdd467/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445727/080bc79bff48444889fe22484ccdd467/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445727/080bc79bff48444889fe22484ccdd467/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445727/080bc79bff48444889fe22484ccdd467/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445727/080bc79bff48444889fe22484ccdd467/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445727/080bc79bff48444889fe22484ccdd467/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445727/080bc79bff48444889fe22484ccdd467/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445727/080bc79bff48444889fe22484ccdd467/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445727/080bc79bff48444889fe22484ccdd467/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445727/080bc79bff48444889fe22484ccdd467/2790x1800.jpg" altText="" pid="7HFrdCjOQEmeaiFkURPnIA" hash="7HXv7w"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p22" pid="k4tfAeTWwkyR7jT487Zcww" hash="-58JTQ"&gt;Later, Elizabeth and her family moved. Elizabeth said she had more time to think and was not so distracted all the time. She often went down in the cellar and prayed to Heavenly Father about what was troubling her—about the stories those seemingly smart men had told about the gospel being bunk and about Joseph Smith and the Book of Mormon.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p23" pid="sHnLtxHlIEuehfgBvrlfZA" hash="klKL3A"&gt;One night Elizabeth had a dream. She said: “It seemed I was standing by a narrow wagon road, which led around by the foot of a low rolling hill; halfway up the hill I saw a man looking down and speaking, or seemed to be speaking, to a young man who was kneeling and leaning over a hole in the earth. His arms were stretched out, and it looked as if he was reaching for something from in the hole. I could see the lid of stone that seemed to have been taken off from the hole over which the boy was bending. On the road were many people, but none of them seemed to be at all interested in the two men on the hillside. There was something that came along with the dream that impressed me so strangely that I woke right up; … I could not tell my dream to anyone, but I seemed to be satisfied that it meant the angel Moroni [instructed] the boy Joseph at the time he got the plates.”&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p24" pid="MTv85KGq3ECjGYBWGSnKHw" hash="JyEslQ"&gt;In the spring of 1893, Elizabeth went to Salt Lake City to the dedication of the temple. She described her experience: “In there I saw the same picture [that] I had seen in my dream; I think it was [a] colored-glass window. I feel satisfied that if I saw the Hill Cumorah itself, it would not look more real. I feel satisfied that I was shown in a dream a picture of the angel Moroni giving Joseph Smith the [gold] plates.”&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=skheb-mp_Eaasvincl0OKw"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445731/c509d3ba4aa741d6835cd4bbae205842/100x191.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x95="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445731/c509d3ba4aa741d6835cd4bbae205842/50x95.jpg" data-src-100x191="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445731/c509d3ba4aa741d6835cd4bbae205842/100x191.jpg" data-src-200x383="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445731/c509d3ba4aa741d6835cd4bbae205842/200x383.jpg" data-src-320x614="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445731/c509d3ba4aa741d6835cd4bbae205842/320x614.jpg" data-src-460x882="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445731/c509d3ba4aa741d6835cd4bbae205842/460x882.jpg" data-src-640x1228="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445731/c509d3ba4aa741d6835cd4bbae205842/640x1228.jpg" data-src-938x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1445731/c509d3ba4aa741d6835cd4bbae205842/938x1800.jpg" altText="" pid="skheb-mp_Eaasvincl0OKw" hash="RowljQ"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p25" pid="0QU9j075zkm8uP8eQruC1w" hash="aS03kQ"&gt; Many years after having this dream and several months before she died at nearly age 88, Elizabeth received a powerful impression. She said, “The thought came to me as plain … as if someone had said to me, … ‘Do not bury your testimony in the ground.’”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p26" pid="oruT6cb-Gk-LRtmVtKpkww" hash="ptAsbw"&gt;Generations later, Elizabeth’s posterity continues to draw strength from her testimony. Like Elizabeth, we live in a world of many doubters and critics who ridicule and oppose the truths we hold dear. We may hear confusing stories and conflicting messages. Also like Elizabeth, we will have to do our best to hold on to whatever light and truth we currently have, especially in difficult circumstances. The answers to our prayers may not come dramatically, but we must find quiet moments to seek greater light and truth. And when we receive it, it is our responsibility to live it, to share it, and to defend it.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p27" pid="IzyDNFaHWEukDrfWZel_6Q" hash="ASDZmw"&gt;I leave you with my testimony that I know as we fill our hearts and homes with the Savior’s light and truth, we will have the inner strength to withstand in every circumstance. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth.p28" pid="XHeVqC9pvk-HLKTdHCkn4w" hash="saqqqw"&gt;
			&lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;Note: On April 4, 2015, Sister Esplin was released as second counselor in the Primary general presidency and sustained as first counselor.&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/04/filling-our-homes-with-light-and-truth</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2015-general-conference/2015-03-0010-cheryl-a-esplin-64k-eng.mp3" length="5005990" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>He Asks Us to Be His Hands</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13285_000_11esplin" doc-version="5" hash="Ab6LKQ"&gt;
	
	&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.head1"&gt;
		&lt;h1 class="title" pid="nkUldk4RZEiBTj3Bd4bFLQ" hash="occy5g"&gt;He Asks Us to Be His Hands&lt;/h1&gt;
		&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p2" pid="s8xpUNaRMkmYo3njzNJnWA" hash="d_eh1w1"&gt;By Cheryl A. Esplin&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p3" pid="nYpHs3rUbk6XSy_cwO3fXg" hash="Iy-2ig"&gt;First Counselor in the Primary General Presidency&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=83CFMcGbJEOR5ZkbUgPaVw"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" altText="Cheryl A. Esplin" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/100x137.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x68="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/50x68.jpg" data-src-100x137="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/100x137.jpg" data-src-200x275="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/200x275.jpg" data-src-320x440="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/320x440.jpg" data-src-460x633="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/460x633.jpg" data-src-640x881="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/640x881.jpg" data-src-1024x1410="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/1024x1410.jpg" data-src-2048x2820="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255523/125c1c19635845879f6775eaf1379184/2048x2820.jpg" webURL="cheryl-esplin-primary-second-counselor_1255523.jpg" pid="83CFMcGbJEOR5ZkbUgPaVw" hash="AAAAAA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="kicker" pid="_QbN9b12w0C1ucNQtR0bCA" hash="uvKPoA"&gt;True Christlike service is selfless and focuses on others.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="authorName" pid="GK7YyKbzIUKfF-TsZibxNw" hash="d_eh1w"&gt;By Cheryl A. Esplin&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class="bodyBlock"&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p5" pid="EdoPoSgK-U2jMK_YKcpHkQ" hash="FKb82w"&gt;“Love one another; as I have loved you.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; These words, sung by this remarkable choir, were spoken by Jesus just hours before His great atoning sacrifice—a sacrifice Elder Jeffrey R. Holland described as “the most majestic manifestation of pure love ever to be demonstrated in the history of this world.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p6" pid="yFwLl1MJqkKfjBPe-RXwlA" hash="0evT2A"&gt;Jesus not only taught us to love, but He also lived what He taught. Throughout His ministry, Jesus “went about doing good”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; and “entreated all to follow His example.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; He taught, “For whosoever will save his life shall lose it: but whosoever will lose his life for my sake, the same shall save it.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p7" pid="bWhponThHEubPAYTSVCr-A" hash="JoqssQ"&gt;President Thomas S. Monson, who has understood and lived the admonition to love, said: “I believe the Savior is telling us that unless we lose ourselves in service to others, there is little purpose to our own lives. Those who live only for themselves eventually shrivel up and … lose their lives, while those who lose themselves in service to others grow and flourish—and in effect save their lives.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p8" pid="ER6q9WRmjk2h4Xl--e_mMg" hash="iSBJDA"&gt;True Christlike service is selfless and focuses on others. One woman who took care of her invalid husband explained, “Don’t think of your task as a burden; think of it as an opportunity to learn what love really is.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p9" pid="tYVeuz62F0aIJBp6HADS8g" hash="pkJFjw"&gt;Speaking at a BYU devotional, Sister Sondra D. Heaston asked: “What if we could really see into each other’s hearts? Would we understand each other better? By feeling what others feel, seeing what others see, and hearing what others hear, would we make, and take, the time to serve others, and would we treat them differently? Would we treat them with more patience, more kindness, and more tolerance?”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p10" pid="ipBPn9a3YUabsVDb7rW4pg" hash="Pprf3w"&gt;Sister Heaston shared an experience from when she served at a Young Women camp. She said:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p11" pid="8Q3Q47A-S0akKyKxu4xWzw" hash="YwdSXQ"&gt;“One of our … devotional speakers … taught us about ‘becoming.’ One of her statements … was, ‘Be someone who reaches out to know and serve others—throw away the mirrors and look through the window.’&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=px8wep4LCkmToc_MONG7Tg"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705722/f0e44b4edef7421898ce46aac425c821/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705722/f0e44b4edef7421898ce46aac425c821/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705722/f0e44b4edef7421898ce46aac425c821/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705722/f0e44b4edef7421898ce46aac425c821/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705722/f0e44b4edef7421898ce46aac425c821/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705722/f0e44b4edef7421898ce46aac425c821/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705722/f0e44b4edef7421898ce46aac425c821/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705722/f0e44b4edef7421898ce46aac425c821/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705722/f0e44b4edef7421898ce46aac425c821/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705722/f0e44b4edef7421898ce46aac425c821/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Conversation between a young woman and a leader is difficult when looking into a mirror" pid="px8wep4LCkmToc_MONG7Tg" hash="UjvGsA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p12" pid="vNRUeWHy5EKW5m9IQd_l8Q" hash="IgVS8w"&gt;“To demonstrate this, she called up one of the young women and asked that young woman to stand facing her. [She] then pulled out a mirror and put it between the young woman and herself so that she, [the speaker], was looking into the mirror while she tried to talk with the young woman. Not surprisingly, it didn’t even begin to be an effective or heartfelt conversation. This was a powerful object lesson that illustrated how difficult it is to communicate with and serve others if we are too worried about ourselves and see only ourselves and our needs. [She] then put away the mirror, pulled out a window frame, and put it between her face and the young woman’s face. … We were able to see that the young woman had become [her] focal point and that true service requires that we focus on the needs and emotions of others. Ofttimes we are so worried about ourselves and our own busy lives—as we look in mirrors while trying to look for opportunities to serve—that we do not see clearly through the windows of service.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8"&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=mzXgdiRvU0-nzadnPYtKHw"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705723/5f3d3fb5ad524393868c0811e40a4012/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705723/5f3d3fb5ad524393868c0811e40a4012/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705723/5f3d3fb5ad524393868c0811e40a4012/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705723/5f3d3fb5ad524393868c0811e40a4012/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705723/5f3d3fb5ad524393868c0811e40a4012/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705723/5f3d3fb5ad524393868c0811e40a4012/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705723/5f3d3fb5ad524393868c0811e40a4012/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705723/5f3d3fb5ad524393868c0811e40a4012/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705723/5f3d3fb5ad524393868c0811e40a4012/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705723/5f3d3fb5ad524393868c0811e40a4012/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Conversation between a young woman and a leader is easy when looking through a window" pid="mzXgdiRvU0-nzadnPYtKHw" hash="2moGJA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p13" pid="lW4OlVsZ4k2cHgozi-36PA" hash="ISEE3A"&gt;President Monson has often reminded us that we are “surrounded by those in need of our attention, our encouragement, our support, our comfort, our kindness—be they family members, friends, acquaintances, or strangers.” He said, “We are the Lord’s hands here upon the earth, with the mandate to serve and to lift His children. He is dependent upon each of us.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9"&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=U-wGS8h3hEqUmOgWlV2DGg"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705519/982136261d0f4c958af37f64114238e2/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705519/982136261d0f4c958af37f64114238e2/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705519/982136261d0f4c958af37f64114238e2/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705519/982136261d0f4c958af37f64114238e2/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705519/982136261d0f4c958af37f64114238e2/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705519/982136261d0f4c958af37f64114238e2/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705519/982136261d0f4c958af37f64114238e2/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705519/982136261d0f4c958af37f64114238e2/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705519/982136261d0f4c958af37f64114238e2/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705519/982136261d0f4c958af37f64114238e2/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Children are invited to serve and be the Lord’s hands" pid="U-wGS8h3hEqUmOgWlV2DGg" hash="YI_dww"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p14" pid="mPmiGLfp4UurQMLQNovsYg" hash="PYva2w"&gt;Last year in January, the &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;Friend&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;Liahona&lt;/span&gt; magazines invited children all around the world to follow the counsel of President Monson—to be the Lord’s hands. Children were invited to perform acts of service—large and small. They were then encouraged to trace their hand on a piece of paper, cut it out, write on it the service they did, and send it to the magazines. Many of you listening tonight might be some of the thousands of children who did a loving service and sent it in.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=i67bOhMl6k-tfyybm5mMKg"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705528/660b2efcf154461a88b9ba23d63987c3/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705528/660b2efcf154461a88b9ba23d63987c3/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705528/660b2efcf154461a88b9ba23d63987c3/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705528/660b2efcf154461a88b9ba23d63987c3/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705528/660b2efcf154461a88b9ba23d63987c3/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705528/660b2efcf154461a88b9ba23d63987c3/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705528/660b2efcf154461a88b9ba23d63987c3/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705528/660b2efcf154461a88b9ba23d63987c3/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705528/660b2efcf154461a88b9ba23d63987c3/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705528/660b2efcf154461a88b9ba23d63987c3/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Children recorded acts of service on cutout hands" pid="i67bOhMl6k-tfyybm5mMKg" hash="F9sCAw"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=sUsan9mLw0a54xAO6dZJsw"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705487/ea7b26ab29804d6b8727fcc88f0715ec/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705487/ea7b26ab29804d6b8727fcc88f0715ec/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705487/ea7b26ab29804d6b8727fcc88f0715ec/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705487/ea7b26ab29804d6b8727fcc88f0715ec/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705487/ea7b26ab29804d6b8727fcc88f0715ec/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705487/ea7b26ab29804d6b8727fcc88f0715ec/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705487/ea7b26ab29804d6b8727fcc88f0715ec/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705487/ea7b26ab29804d6b8727fcc88f0715ec/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705487/ea7b26ab29804d6b8727fcc88f0715ec/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705487/ea7b26ab29804d6b8727fcc88f0715ec/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Thousands of children sent a record of their acts of service to the magazines" pid="sUsan9mLw0a54xAO6dZJsw" hash="RBctMA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p15" pid="O7JlWpEiF0uW_9f5Cmsijw" hash="0tvoYg"&gt;When children learn how to love and serve others when they are young, they set a pattern of service for the rest of their lives. Often children teach the rest of us that showing love and service doesn’t have to be big and grandiose to be meaningful and make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p16" pid="Ix759goYCkiUsc_Ufr4B3Q" hash="892ntw"&gt;A Primary teacher shared the following example. “Today,” she said, “our five- and six-year-old class made love necklaces. Each child drew pictures on strips of paper: one of themselves, one of Jesus, and some of members of their family and loved ones. We glued the strips into circles that looped through each other to make a chain that we turned into love necklaces. As they were drawing, the children talked about their families.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p17" pid="eE_5366gqEO8f4gVCyTWeA" hash="Soqx9Q"&gt;“Heather said, ‘I don’t think my sister loves me. We are always fighting. … I even hate myself. I have a bad life.’ And she put her head in her hands.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p18" pid="bOTmR1UiMkSfFxPA6pYm9g" hash="REmltg"&gt;“I thought about her family circumstances and felt that maybe she did indeed have a hard life. But after Heather had said this, Anna, down at the other end of the table, responded, ‘Heather, I am putting you in my necklace between me and Jesus because He loves you and I love you.’&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p19" pid="F_K-IWbUqkSrcPaMyeNUJA" hash="o8FTfQ"&gt;“When Anna said that, Heather crawled under the table to get to Anna and threw her arms around her.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p20" pid="Jo2P1eWRRkm5Y7oo4BGpGg" hash="hniwow"&gt;“At the end of class, when her grandmother came to pick her up, Heather said, ‘Guess what, Grandma? Jesus loves me.’”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p21" pid="nl5uh-uU3kS1QsxLSXFDjw" hash="CUkH1g"&gt;When we reach out in love and service even in the smallest ways, hearts are changed and softened as others feel the love of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p22" pid="ZEwyCA1AcEStvwiw4WHdxw" hash="oQ1Plg"&gt;Sometimes, however, because of the countless people all about us who need help and relief from burdens, it can be difficult to meet the many pressing needs.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p23" pid="trpwX_9urkG8rulnZ9Sv5Q" hash="b4Byaw"&gt;Sisters, some of you listening may feel stretched to capacity ministering to the needs of family members. Remember, in those routine and often mundane tasks, you are “in the service of your God.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11"&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p24" pid="ZmponQUnNE-cDKIRAzoKGw" hash="D8d8WQ"&gt;Others of you might be feeling an emptiness that could be filled as you look into your neighborhood or community for opportunities to help ease another’s burdens.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p25" pid="-4QdLmDa0EOXtN7hvz1RPQ" hash="AF8hyw"&gt;All of us can incorporate some service into our daily living. We live in a contentious world. We give service when we don’t criticize, when we refuse to gossip, when we don’t judge, when we smile, when we say thank you, and when we are patient and kind.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p26" pid="A0BVxfIGiUuuC1z-Eji2XQ" hash="Lc_jkA"&gt;Other kinds of service take time, intentional planning, and extra energy. But they are worth our every effort. Perhaps we could start by asking ourselves these questions:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;ul class="bullet"&gt;
			&lt;li pid="41pHuFRNsE6LR9E0NXucTg" hash="AnHqMw"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p27" pid="GxDZpKSJ_0iGq1JibuV-2Q" hash="tA9TXA"&gt;Who in my circle of influence could I help today?&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="QZRXKrPYykyx5pJ_LgyU6A" hash="foJ4Lw"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p28" pid="eEzBAPWBxUanz5LI1pbBvg" hash="4E0nww"&gt;What time and resources do I have?&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="Qpyp3LEmW0mUPt6so_K24Q" hash="enEx7A"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p29" pid="H3dL9vnmXEqR4QmF1q_bCQ" hash="583tXg"&gt;In what ways can I use my talents and skills to bless others?&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="GnzMrEpBYEGrgKsfr6hDlA" hash="qp0aQg"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p30" pid="DudctXO8B027U_h7HpD5jw" hash="ZM7BTw"&gt;What might we do as a family?&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p31" pid="HjtfW6psE0yOP3uRn7ghjQ" hash="v_xBRg"&gt;President Dieter F. Uchtdorf taught:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p32" pid="rzFbkWtIREyYSGZ024J6bw" hash="5FTDYw"&gt;“You must do … what disciples of Christ have done in every dispensation: counsel together, use all resources available, seek the inspiration of the Holy Ghost, ask the Lord for His confirmation, and then roll up your sleeves and go to work.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p33" pid="UroK_V3Ilkaj86tMmm9edg" hash="ddmfxg"&gt;“I give you a promise,” he said. “If you will follow this pattern, you will receive specific guidance as to the &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;who, what, when, &lt;/span&gt;and &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;where&lt;/span&gt; of providing in the Lord’s way.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12"&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p34" pid="i9BZxxn-9ECBfOLRvXXZ5A" hash="6XwyvA"&gt;Whenever I wonder what it will be like when the Savior comes again, I think of His visit to the Nephites when He asked:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p35" pid="GGaPZXoQFUCdN6-M3GYkKQ" hash="xalAzQ"&gt;“Have ye any that are sick among you? Bring them hither. Have ye any that are lame, or blind, or halt, or maimed, or leprous, or that are withered, or that are deaf, or that are afflicted in any manner? Bring them hither and I will heal them, for I have compassion upon you; my bowels are filled with mercy. …&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p36" pid="FSY6vHw8gEOXoIJ1z3fpHA" hash="swab5A"&gt;“… [The Savior] did heal them every one.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p37" pid="cJq370Q36U2mWuCPii7UpA" hash="1daS4Q"&gt;For now, He asks us to be His hands.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p38" pid="-a3TZ9fqJUWGo7qOjliz2w" hash="g3vglQ"&gt;I have come to know that it is the love of God and neighbor that gives meaning to life. May we follow our Savior’s example and His admonition to reach out to others with love.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p39" pid="uP45HxQfBUeDs1F-eiRHjQ" hash="9O7gxQ"&gt;I testify to the reality of President Henry B. Eyring’s promise “that if [we’ll] use [our] gifts to serve someone else, [we’ll] feel the Lord’s love for that person. [We’ll] also feel his love for [us].”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14"&gt;14&lt;/span&gt; In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands.p40" pid="C79W6g0n5kiCtUkPvgDINQ" hash="cN8K1A"&gt;
			&lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;Note: On April 2, 2016, Sister Esplin was released as first counselor in the Primary general presidency.&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/04/he-asks-us-to-be-his-hands</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2016-general-conference/2016-03-0020-cheryl-a-esplin-64k-eng.mp3" length="4952648" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
