<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Christoffel Golden Jr.</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Christoffel Golden Jr..</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Christoffel%20Golden%20Jr..jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Christoffel Golden Jr..</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2001 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2001 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Our Father’s Plan</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan?lang=eng</link>
      <description>[Our Heavenly] Father’s desire is to provide all of us with the opportunity to receive a fulness of joy, even the fulness that He possesses.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029371_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="lTHWZQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="qtIGl6fQakyivtrzUvGA7w" hash="zkW6MQ">Our Father’s Plan</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="2ACiABYZcEiYBw0ops_INw" hash="AxoRLw">Christoffel Golden Jr.</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="8D6rnv8Blk-EaDywFAf9Ww" hash="4VIwpw">[Our Heavenly] Father’s desire is to provide all of us with the opportunity to receive a fulness of joy, even the fulness that He possesses.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-af9.jpg" alt="Elder Christoffel Golden Jr." pid="bAidj2_DPkSo1wLu1TWUzg" hash="EMxTtQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.p1" pid="QMnHu0lVqEyhwua-BTcKdA" hash="oCTezw">In a revelation given to the Prophet Joseph Smith sometime in June 1830, we are told of our Heavenly Father’s declared intention: “For behold, this is my work and my glory—to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> According to this decree, the Father’s desire is to provide all of us with the opportunity to receive a fulness of joy, even the fulness that He possesses in His perfected and glorified state.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.p2" pid="KL2pAHF-dkeqFCsLRUPUeg" hash="r07caQ">During these momentous latter days, we declare that God our Eternal Father lives. We testify that we existed in His presence, prior to this life, as His spirit children. During our premortal existence, we were tutored in conditions which provided us with the opportunity to develop our talents and abilities. In that blessed, premortal abode, we were “left to choose good or evil.” Alma states that we chose good by exercising “great faith” and performing “good works.” Thus, we kept our first estate, while our Father, in turn, foreordained us to receive certain privileges in this lifetime.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.p3" pid="4VhiLm1T1UCAdWME6E1tPQ" hash="DeJ6uw">Likewise, latter-day revelation reveals that our Heavenly Father ordained a great plan of happiness for all of His spirit children who had kept their first estate.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> It embraced the prospect that we could one day become like our Father in Heaven and possess all of the attributes and rights He now enjoys. The Apostle Peter reminded the Saints that our Lord’s “divine power hath given unto us all things that pertain unto life and godliness,” so that “by these ye might be partakers of the divine nature.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Peter’s statement may be considered bold, and we admit that it would take a lifetime, and more, to accomplish; nevertheless, his thoughts find resonance in the Savior’s charge, “Be ye therefore perfect, even as your Father which is in heaven is perfect.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.p4" pid="y9MP4yPGokaoovah_mGExg" hash="7yfVwQ">The Father’s plan also required all who had kept their first estate to be tried and tested in a mortal or second estate. In this environment, we are required to act for ourselves and prove to ourselves and to God whether we would keep all of His commandments and overcome sin and opposition.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.p5" pid="-kmlFR6H5UiVrP-Di2wmQQ" hash="zHG7tw">Since the Fall of Adam and because of the nature of mortal mankind, man developed a predisposition to violate the laws of God and thereby become enslaved to the demands of justice. Nevertheless, because of our Heavenly Father’s foreknowledge and through the great plan of happiness, He devised a plan of mercy. It furnished a way for the exacting requirements of justice to be appeased through an infinite Atonement.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.p6" pid="WhoL3oshVUiTci0oXtmQvQ" hash="pWmDpQ">Jesus Christ, as the chosen of the Father from the beginning,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> possessed all the qualifications and attributes required to harmonize the laws of justice and mercy through His Atonement.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.p7" pid="cB4ZNvJmwECdchL2zInmQQ" hash="XnQEOw">The Atonement, King Benjamin taught, allows man to put off the natural man as we yield to the enticings of the Holy Spirit.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> Consequently, it is our testimony that all who come unto Christ by obedience to the laws and ordinances of the gospel are able to exercise faith unto “everlasting salvation and eternal life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.p8" pid="yA4DR9XwaEGyxokBfynnmg" hash="9gEC1Q">We also testify that compliance with all of the conditions of the great plan of happiness, after the Great Apostasy, was not possible until our Heavenly Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, reestablished the gospel through the Prophet Joseph Smith.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.p9" pid="w7-rjsNUjUiy7RDqLkLGZQ" hash="QJp6Yg">Our beloved prophet, President Gordon B. Hinckley, declared, “The Prophet Joseph’s account of these events is true, that the Father bore witness of the divinity of His Son, that the Son instructed the boy prophet, and that there followed a train of events which led to the organization of ‘the only true and living church upon the face of the whole earth.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.p10" pid="tfp7g2UjEE6Q662MSPSdSA" hash="pqbFMA">It is the heartfelt desire of all the faithful to keep their second estate. We are not left alone to find our way back home. The Lord has set up His kingdom on the earth wherein the elect of God can be gathered.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.p11" pid="kmJphZMmCkCurq45D9ftJA" hash="FegaMw">In the Lord’s loving care, He has provided us with all of the essential resources required to forge our way through the many pitfalls placed before us by the evil one.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.p12" pid="RMGzLuj2TkG3DZdCaEZh_w" hash="DAYtuw">These indispensable resources include the ordinances and covenants of the gospel, in which the power of the Atonement is manifest.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> We also have the holy scriptures, which provide us with a standard to discern truth from error.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.p13" pid="X7MI6zA5CUiBBLC_8TQzYA" hash="osgeSg">Importantly, we live in a blessed day in which the Lord has placed His watchmen, even the living apostles and prophets, in our midst. They hold all the necessary keys and authority which are essential to administering the ordinances of salvation and exaltation.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.p14" pid="wKxN004hYE6gSbLUtr0_1A" hash="g8i1zg">Above all, as baptized members of the church of Christ, we have the incomparable gift of the Holy Ghost. The Savior, on the eve of His suffering for our sins, told His disciples, that the “Spirit … will guide you into all truth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.p15" pid="5fjga8zvKkeoTRjVodAH2A" hash="0QKXcg">John the Revelator, in heavenly vision, saw the fulfillment of our Father’s plan and recorded the condition of those who had come out of great tribulation and had washed their robes white in the blood of the Lamb. He saw how they who had overcome the world stood before the throne of God and served Him in His temple. The Lord was in their midst, while the faithful hungered and thirsted no more, and God wiped away all the tears from their eyes.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.p16" pid="utx64LV1PEetaYF5ctkn1w" hash="AQxmSw">We need not fear but with faith follow our Heavenly Father’s great plan of happiness. Our call to all is to come and receive of the grace and mercy of the Lord, for He is mighty to save and will never forsake us!<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan.p17" pid="vyP_OFIcqEq5CA8kxHIwxA" hash="zYks9Q">May the Lord bless us in this great endeavor, I pray, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2001/10/our-fathers-plan</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2001-general-conference/2001-10-2050-elder-christoffel-golden-jr-64k-eng.mp3" length="3845544" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2001 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small and Simple Things</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things?lang=eng</link>
      <description>May we discover anew the divine power of daily prayer, the convincing influence of the Book of Mormon, and true devotion when partaking of the sacrament.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008332_000_029" doc-version="2" hash="9nicbA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="AL5HcmivQUSpfAmbM9vPAw" hash="0NS5pw">Small and Simple Things</h1><p class="authorName" guid="4674c91b-88fd-4388-a7d3-4c5988821127" pid="aP4XOjqFrU2VvGfsYG1KAg" hash="AxoRLw">Christoffel Golden Jr.</p><p class="kicker" pid="9dFoiwjsXEGxqv7A7MwsJw" hash="d5yKYg">May we discover anew the divine power of daily prayer, the convincing influence of the Book of Mormon, and true devotion when partaking of the sacrament.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="81131b79-4b17-4537-a073-30e88428f72f">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/GOLDENC_01.jpg" alt="Elder Christoffel Golden Jr." guid="edf88cd4-da83-4c9f-8c8f-3873d9107aec" pid="4mX7lRjI3k-1WhM--Ee-xQ" hash="9MOm8g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.p" pid="1nk7T6Vstk6LY-XqtA6_Yg" hash="3Sof7w">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="78"></span>Everyone who will live the gospel of Jesus Christ daily and endure to the end will gain eternal life—this is the promise of the Lord.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> In its essentials, the gospel is simple and easy to understand and adapted to the capacity of the weakest.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Alma, the Book of Mormon prophet, aptly remarked, “Now ye may suppose that this is foolishness in me; but … by small and simple things are great things brought to pass; … and by very small means the Lord doth confound the wise and bringeth about the salvation of many souls.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.p" pid="g-CM9w9X5EivfVphkwPbnw" hash="KiXFrw">Quite recently, I was privileged to observe this process in the life of a brother named Stan, who had been less active for some 45 years. He had lived a good life and supported both his wife and son in their activity as faithful members in the Church. Yet for personal reasons he chose to remain outside the fellowship of the Church. Even so, each month he welcomed the home teachers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.p" pid="sXVGQ4CNT0Gi9iPczJ4Lkg" hash="8eg6_A">During February 2006, Stan received new home teachers. Their first visit was pleasant enough, although Stan showed no real interest in the gospel or in any matters remotely associated with spiritual things. Their next visit did little to alter their initial observations, even though Stan was a little warmer and friendlier. On their third visit, however, there was a visible change in Stan’s countenance and demeanor. To their utmost surprise and even before they were able to present their message, Stan interrupted them with a number of thoughtful questions. In the ensuing discussion he also recounted his experiences during the past month, in which he and his wife had commenced reading one chapter a day from the Book of Mormon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.p" pid="h0nEDPiMJES1zGVIyc9o1A" hash="ZJ3c0w">Elder Bruce R. McConkie eloquently described the type of reawakening Stan experienced: “Here is a man who gains a copy of this blessed <span class="pageBreak" page-number="79"></span>book, begins to read it, and continues … until, having read it all, his famished soul is filled with the bread of life. He cannot lay it aside or ignore its teachings. It is as though the waters of life are flowing into the barren deserts of his soul, quenching the arid, empty feeling that theretofore separated him from his God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.p" pid="M7ifQxMUUkS0wRN4VbKs3A" hash="l28H4Q">The home teachers were reminded of the remarkable power of the Book of Mormon and how very real the influence of the Spirit of the Lord is when we turn to its sacred pages. They also more fully understood the Prophet Joseph Smith’s declaration “that the Book of Mormon [is] the most correct of any book on earth, … and a man would get nearer to God by abiding by its precepts, than by any other book.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.p" pid="kgI316jlEk2CSvk9w-tGmw" hash="ulOBEg">Stan’s thirst for learning and rediscovery of the restored gospel soon expanded his reading beyond one chapter a day, accompanied by deep soul-searching and fervent prayer. To those who sometimes are concerned whether the Lord will actually hear their prayers, the Savior reminds us:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.p" pid="Rn9zTTJdLEO223ZoocViUA" hash="Rp0I2A">“If a son shall ask bread of any of you that is a father, will he give him a stone? or if he ask a fish, will he for a fish give him a serpent? …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.p" pid="M7SE5OcmykKGpI_KApVUqA" hash="0qD43g">“If ye then, being evil, know how to give good gifts unto your children: how much more shall your heavenly Father give good gifts, through the Holy Spirit, to them that ask him?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.p" pid="RJFdq7WIeE2CixHPkakBgQ" hash="XoU89Q">Our beloved prophet, President Gordon B. Hinckley, also counseled: “You can’t do it alone. … You need the help of the Lord … and the marvelous thing is that you have the opportunity to pray, with the expectation that your prayers will be heard and answered. … He stands ready to help.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.p" pid="hciZyBBDIkCqND2FW5UxoA" hash="O8hx5Q">During August of 2006, Stan ventured alongside his ever-faithful wife into his ward sacrament meeting—his first in 45 years. There, with a humble and prayerful heart, he listened to the simple sacramental prayers offered by the youthful priests. Feeling unworthy and sensing something of the depth and the meaning of this most holy ordinance, he reflected deeply and painfully without partaking of the bread or the water for a number of weeks.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.p" pid="xbXrQt7Qb0eQ8NKfl18i0g" hash="qZminA">President Joseph Fielding Smith, in a tender testimony many years ago, said: “In my judgment the sacrament meeting is the most sacred, the most holy, of all the meetings of the Church. When I reflect upon the gathering of the Savior and his apostles on that memorable night when he introduced the sacrament … my heart is filled with wonderment and my feelings are touched. I consider that gathering one of the <span class="pageBreak" page-number="80"></span>most solemn and wonderful since the beginning of time.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.p" pid="uW4-ShD2NESlCCangzVYcQ" hash="U2mVrg">Stan continued studying, praying, attending church, and receiving appropriate counsel and encouragement from his home teachers. Then the day arrived when, joyfully, he felt he was ready to put forth his hand to partake of the precious sacrament. When we partake worthily, thoughtfully, and reverently of the holy sacrament, we are enabled to become “partakers of the divine nature”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> because of the Atonement of Christ and the power of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.p" pid="9K828SX7VkCX2QSIUOKrhA" hash="H2FtJQ">As Stan returned to activity in the Church, he received a calling and, some months later, was ordained an elder. In July 2007, Stan and his wife knelt across the altar in a house of the Lord and, by the authority and eternal law of God, were married for time and for all eternity.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.p" pid="6tGmmnfENUG-tLFMPVXUXA" hash="EOeUIw">Brothers and sisters, may we discover anew the divine power of daily prayer and the convincing influence of the Book of Mormon and the holy scriptures. On Sundays, when partaking of the sacrament, may we do so in the spirit of true devotion to Him who is the giver of all things.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.p" pid="qxL7gPYnSUSm--bVt3Dfhw" hash="aKYXEg">In the wake of our best and very limited efforts and because of the Lord’s infinite goodness, “great things [are] brought to pass” by the “small and simple things.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.p" pid="4S6tVUfOzUi7oNs08pBA6Q" hash="nF1iug">Finally, as to these sacred things, may I add my personal witness and assurance in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things.f1"><title>Notes</title><ol class="number" guid=""><li guid="57a10ecb-90c1-4806-8701-3958db4380cd" pid="T9pRawrqv0mif3IgrIcmMQ" hash="pwNxaA1">
        <span class="label">1.</span>
        <p guid="d910e0c2-f6b7-4678-8912-890d0f7ac23c" pid="TDon5uvqT0W0o95Nn_5tDw" hash="B7uwDw">See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.13-18" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 27:13–18</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/14.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 14:7</a>.</p>
      </li><li guid="231d6088-4fe5-4ca8-b8bf-b330369d1ec1" pid="iH1AtYuvv0WYLq8McMarcw" hash="1cQutA1">
        <span class="label">2.</span>
        <p guid="b1230bd7-cf61-4d28-8a42-04538a77d84d" pid="L77MIwwQ2kifzfYgITE5eA" hash="GU5l-w">See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/11.28-30" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 11:28–30</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.14" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:14</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.44" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:44</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/133.57-58" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 133:57–58</a>.</p>
      </li><li guid="ede84d5d-1398-4da7-b9bd-1f94b97730d1" pid="NRssSA27l0uJ6uFS6UK1hw" hash="n4Gzog1">
        <span class="label">3.</span>
        <p guid="0710859a-ea1a-4ab8-bd40-ec72f0293442" pid="AmP-6hPxFUim-n6DgsC6-Q" hash="dNOnnQ">
          <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.6-7" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:6–7</a>.</p>
      </li><li guid="825f351e-3c40-4a80-852a-4dc55920da33" pid="XPd5A-hn_0SkYq8E1aRD8A" hash="Se6SUg1">
        <span class="label">4.</span>
        <p guid="37883d9c-6a18-47ab-9006-d78b8c00b844" pid="GcmkkVI6nkeJ9rJyFmFuBQ" hash="i_l-vw">
          <span class="emphasis">A New Witness for the Articles of Faith</span> (1985), 414.</p>
      </li><li guid="5117d04a-074d-4c17-9091-e4f2fbebac70" pid="VqgSjQni4Ui5yg5WvxD-Ng" hash="PKGxGQ1">
        <span class="label">5.</span>
        <p guid="f3c9630d-5747-4243-a65d-8c52c250007d" pid="YKQsUEiYfkWIso3TcFrMEg" hash="AFLvCg">
          <span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 4:461.</p>
      </li><li guid="2d6780a1-eb13-4ffa-9b44-d8f4ef4d1f6f" pid="rMa-nG4b1064PGMed-uxew" hash="qNTdXQ1">
        <span class="label">6.</span>
        <p guid="75ee6694-4d5b-49b2-8e85-898f564a8ce1" pid="RTf2D3gU1E-SJFwwUhf_4w" hash="ru9rww">
          <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/11.11,13" class="scriptureRef">Luke 11:11, 13</a>; see Joseph Smith Translation in footnote 13<span class="emphasis">a.</span></p>
      </li><li guid="c0d68f1a-306f-4394-be68-6aded49d51c7" pid="PklpnDZn80WvNCacn2lckg" hash="6EqKgQ1">
        <span class="label">7.</span>
        <p guid="12215b06-1eec-43ba-8a30-ef5e49d3fd39" pid="q4sGw4-osUG836k63O6UWg" hash="bqDwqg">
          <span class="emphasis">Teachings of Gordon B. Hinckley</span> (1997), 468.</p>
      </li><li guid="73732e27-7ec6-45a4-8824-48360815f174" pid="7oVM_QPOQk6KPyhzMUe3iA" hash="Zc0Gyw1">
        <span class="label">8.</span>
        <p guid="700224a5-93da-4201-b3a0-54641e702088" pid="PA23IxAYlEaIEtTuY7qxbQ" hash="Tia18w">In Conference Report, Oct. 1929, 60–61.</p>
      </li><li guid="aa831ae7-16f6-4118-b160-539a8d528a92" pid="I8c-C8gXz0e_J_UJurqjug" hash="LS_yzQ1">
        <span class="label">9.</span>
        <p guid="3049ac8d-fed4-4d38-8a1c-3e5add57099b" pid="P_VZnP37pkS68E_-892R5g" hash="WpZFvw">
          <a href="/scriptures/nt/2-pet/1.4" class="scriptureRef">2 Peter 1:4</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.1-14" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 18:1–14</a>.</p>
      </li><li guid="ef05d2fc-c143-4354-898b-6ff57ad379e0" pid="qJhXc9elmkqseUkpjTziQQ" hash="EJaoIg1">
        <span class="label">10.</span>
        <p guid="6eaea703-7bc7-4f17-b667-7a49633a8ae3" pid="QWA3OZDn9k2tv5ShpxLOdg" hash="H-jrvA">See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/19.3-6" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 19:3–6</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/131.1-4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 131:1–4</a>.</p>
      </li><li guid="a0f7cb5f-2ef4-4d5b-a928-0fb80ea27ec2" pid="EOZiCTGg-kasHCEzieKExA" hash="Xu2ykQ1">
        <span class="label">11.</span>
        <p guid="4eee1d15-7895-442c-bd12-76745053623b" pid="ej83zIdrckapUyZOj6_4YQ" hash="mmcC4Q">See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/6.title" class="scriptureRef">Moroni 6</a>.</p>
      </li></ol></div>
    <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/GOLDENC_01.jpg" alt="Elder Christoffel Golden Jr." guid="edf88cd4-da83-4c9f-8c8f-3873d9107aec" pid="bJ9Eu-SUfEiXd5JmpZwYWA" hash="9MOm8g1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="edf88cd4-da83-4c9f-8c8f-3873d9107aec"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/10/small-and-simple-things</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2007-general-conference/2007-10-4050-elder-christoffel-golden-jr-64k-eng.mp3" length="3884427" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2007 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Father and the Son</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son?lang=eng</link>
      <description>At the heart of the gospel of Jesus Christ and its power to save is a correct understanding of the Father and the Son.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10785_000_53jr" doc-version="2" hash="NZD2tQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="hW0e4dlgXk2ZLSBUIrRJeQ" hash="Uz0o4Q">The Father and the Son</h1><p class="authorName" pid="kbodZ-nIFk6M3mkdydQJrg" hash="ar7OFQ">By Elder Christoffel Golden Jr.</p><p class="kicker" pid="9nwPKCDd8UmgJ8OKEY80Ng" hash="fkxyiA">At the heart of the gospel of Jesus Christ and its power to save is a correct understanding of the Father and the Son.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p5" pid="NIJ-MuQ8KEWAh1Z5g3PcgA" hash="pXwAbA"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="99"></span>My beloved brothers and sisters, I am grateful to address you this afternoon in the setting of this inspiring general conference!</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p6" pid="iKapjHGPiUOpAOML5ovB2g" hash="vUA5hQ">In addressing a topic that to my mind is most sacred, I wish first to acknowledge with gratitude the devotion of so many Christians throughout the ages, including my ancestry of French Protestants and Irish Catholics. Because of their faith and worship of God, many of them sacrificed position, possessions, and even their lives in defense of their God and their faith.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p7" pid="RBzWt8SgkEWq3r3ZOPwxbQ" hash="6ycPtw">As Latter-day Saints and as Christians, we likewise have a strong and deep faith in God the Eternal Father and His Son, Jesus Christ. Devotion to God ever remains a sacred and personal matter between each of us and our Maker.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p8" pid="heuBx8K3LESeOobDfHOG4w" hash="G4ABUw">Our quest for eternal life is nothing other than a quest to understand who God is and for us to return to live with Him. The Savior prayed to His Father, “And this is life eternal, that they might <span class="pageBreak" page-number="100"></span>know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p9" pid="xgkAVzz1WUKsPgl9jOSAsQ" hash="6y_c9g">Even in the light of this declaration by our Savior Himself, the prevailing view of the nature of the Father and the Son throughout the many centuries and among much of mankind is clearly inconsistent with the teachings of the holy scriptures.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p10" pid="7Vtw4HLrCku_Snl-bujpVw" hash="kuZ3Mw">We respectfully submit that at the heart of the gospel of Jesus Christ and its power to save is a correct understanding of the Father and the Son.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p11" pid="YmCFbfsMzECnZkpkSQf_WQ" hash="vpL1Lg">The importance of this most fundamental principle of the gospel of Jesus Christ is confirmed by the First Vision of the Prophet Joseph Smith in 1820. The Prophet wrote: “I saw two Personages, whose brightness and glory defy all description, standing above me in the air. One of them spake unto me, calling me by name and said, pointing to the other—<span class="emphasis">This is My Beloved Son. Hear Him!</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p12" pid="j2bBrCDUqUa3nqrsq9GGkA" hash="XxKLjA">This experience by the boy Joseph, followed by many other visions and revelations, reveals that God actually exists; the Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, are two separate and distinct beings; man is created in the image of God; our Heavenly Father is literally the Father of Jesus Christ; God continues to reveal Himself to man; God is ever near and interested in us; and He answers our prayers.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p13" pid="_l4XMhTvjUCjB7GaCuhmQQ" hash="odSwQg">Even though similar appearances of the Father and the Son in holy writ are relatively rare, the remarkable fact of the First Vision is that it agrees so well with other recorded events in the holy scriptures.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p14" pid="nfBS_ZnhCEuMlhdC__En1A" hash="Lnbqvg">In the New Testament, for example, we read of Stephen’s final testimony at his martyrdom. Said he, “Behold, I see the heavens opened, and the Son of man standing on the right hand of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p15" pid="z3ZtxmGaqUiOgep2qkDiIw" hash="DK9kbw">While in mighty vision on the Isle of Patmos, the Apostle John sees the “Lord God Almighty”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> as well as the Lamb of God, who “redeemed us … by [His] blood.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p16" pid="nwnscR0TAkOSn-L5mviKFw" hash="TLsRdA">In the Book of Mormon, the doctrine of the Father and the Son stands in majestic testimony alongside the Holy Bible. The Book of Mormon records the visitation of our Savior to the Nephites, in which the voice of the Father, in the presence of some 2,500 Nephites, introduces the risen Christ: “Behold my Beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased, in whom I have glorified my name—hear ye him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p17" pid="JgTu0rvqakq-0sYmLH1k3Q" hash="BySZsg">In the four Gospels, Christ Himself refers to His Father in Heaven 160 times, while during His brief three-day ministry among the Nephites, as recorded in the Book of Mormon, He mentions His Father 122 times.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p18" pid="Ac3-KxQD6UaXtQrPf3CD8g" hash="2lRxzA">For example, in Matthew, Jesus says, “Not every one that saith unto me, Lord, Lord, shall enter into the kingdom of heaven; but he that doeth the will of <span class="emphasis">my Father</span> which is in heaven.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p19" pid="pmGTzdQ-hkWKOOe2bGDqJQ" hash="KTNywg">In John, He testifies, “The Son can do nothing of himself, but what he seeth <span class="emphasis">the Father</span> do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p20" pid="wQNOxYM4AEG1Eu1G2A2CXw" hash="BFAIyA">And in Luke, He exclaims, “<span class="emphasis">Father,</span> into thy hands I commend my spirit.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p21" pid="S-fNsZrPrkyWVRDtgI34Gg" hash="n1QzBw">Every time our Lord refers to His Heavenly Father, He does so with the utmost reverence and submissiveness.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p22" pid="ce35bCLRuUm25iQWaLkZRg" hash="34enyQ">In saying this, I hope there will be no misunderstanding. Jesus Christ is the great Jehovah, the God of Israel, the promised Messiah, and because of His infinite Atonement, He is our Savior and the Redeemer of the world. Of Him the Apostle Paul declared, “Then cometh the end, when [Christ] shall have delivered up the kingdom to God, even the Father; when [Christ] shall have put down all rule and all authority and power.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p23" pid="9S9pzU_IREyuVH0kBcqzrA" hash="jiVD4Q">On the eve of the Savior’s Atonement, He offered up His great Intercessory Prayer to His Father. He prayed:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p24" pid="BI2xbXRZCUOBqqoFThQFyg" hash="00akfg">“Neither pray I for these [in other words, His Apostles] alone, but for them also which shall believe on me through their word;</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p25" pid="jfoLn4wfOkqKuEbDCer58Q" hash="6tQyVQ">“That they all may be <span class="emphasis">one;</span> as thou, Father, art in me, and I in thee, that they also may be <span class="emphasis">one in us:</span> that the world may believe that thou hast sent me.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p26" pid="q-4w7hHTK0ezqfFukEW9NQ" hash="8oxtjg">“And the glory which thou gavest me I have given them; that they may be one, even as we are one.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p27" pid="DmBdGqlxhEaVWHnvFkLAng" hash="v2B4ag">The Father and the Son are distinctly separate beings, but They are perfectly united and one in power and purpose. Their oneness is not reserved for Them alone; rather, They desire this same oneness for everyone who will, with devotion, follow and obey Their commandments.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p28" pid="jNQAfFFPuEmLUtA7vEPkxw" hash="Co0naA">How is the earnest seeker of God able to become acquainted with the Father and the Son? Our Savior promised, “But the Comforter, which is the Holy Ghost, … shall teach you all things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p29" pid="SlrmFCN7_EaGagWuDvQicw" hash="BO0z-w">In the Book of Mormon, Nephi, when speaking of the doctrine of Christ, declared that the Holy Ghost <span class="pageBreak" page-number="101"></span>“witnesses of the Father and the Son.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p30" pid="z8QJluh9AkG5VB2VCRz7pg" hash="jSOO5Q">It is true that the power or influence of the Holy Ghost may on occasion be felt, according to the will of the Lord, by any person irrespective of that person’s religious persuasion. But the full measure, or gift, of the Holy Ghost comes only after a person has received, with “a broken heart and a contrite spirit,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> the ordinances of baptism and the gift of the Holy Ghost<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> by the laying on of hands. These and other sacred ordinances may be performed only under the direction and power of the priesthood of God. In this regard, we are taught:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p31" pid="LzNgPOuIkEmZGj8Dnkc_kQ" hash="NeXx6A">“And this greater priesthood administereth the gospel and holdeth the key of the mysteries of the kingdom, even the key of the knowledge of God.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p32" pid="kWGhbq05PUu28z_6IcIzqg" hash="R_FCIg">“Therefore, in the ordinances thereof, the power of godliness is manifest.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p33" pid="yi6dKAacoUWmxbbcGCdmSg" hash="pLiVWQ">Seen in its true light, the doctrine of the Father and the Son is the doctrine of the eternal family. Every human being has existed previously as a spirit child with heavenly parents,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> with Christ being the Firstborn of the Father in this heavenly family.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p34" pid="pWohjc_Rm0Gl-2MSO6ivvw" hash="tlIsow">So it is with all of us. We are the children of our Heavenly Father.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p35" pid="Qo1tRuKfTUS7ezh_HQ_Syw" hash="abtAog">President Ezra Taft Benson with prophetic insight said, “Nothing is going to startle us more when we pass through the veil to the other side than to realize how well we know our Father [in Heaven] and how familiar his face is to us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son.p36" pid="t6BygQdQpkWLSpLprRauig" hash="xvL9_g">I have learned that it is not possible to convey in the language of man those things which are made known only by the Holy Ghost and power of God. It is in this spirit that I bear my solemn witness and testimony of the reality, nearness, and goodness of our Eternal Father and His holy Son, Jesus Christ. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2013/04/the-father-and-the-son</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2013-general-conference/2013-04-5030-elder-christoffel-golden-jr-64k-eng.mp3" length="5328917" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
