<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Claudio D. Zivic</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Claudio D. Zivic.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Claudio%20D.%20Zivic.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Claudio D. Zivic.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2007 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2007 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>After All We Can Do</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We, as members of the Church of Jesus Christ, have chosen not to be ordinary men and women.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008332_000_036" doc-version="2" hash="wZ1h_A"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="yUQaJYQ89EKe1zV5qy195w" hash="KnGm3w">After All We Can Do</h1><p class="authorName" guid="b8b38e44-f151-4c03-96f6-1a54569e8f5d" pid="xvG-774hQUaEYXPgleylAA" hash="04wHxg">Claudio D. Zivic</p><p class="kicker" pid="ckTDyFILRESZAmH3zrInyQ" hash="5uuQ4A">We, as members of the Church of Jesus Christ, have chosen not to be ordinary men and women.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="0b731299-9191-410c-a344-b82fcc59cd1e">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/ZivicCD_07.jpg" alt="Elder Claudio D. Zivic" guid="dcfaa788-fa57-4856-82b3-2fb3b114240b" pid="BAjjTHsSQUSbDoiCAwbbJA" hash="ugSLhg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="EmyHgabv_UedcQpu5nsq3g" hash="xcruFg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="98"></span>I have heard that no one has ever died giving a talk in a general conference. If that is the case today, I sincerely apologize.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="wKl5ZJroeki2eDeoADkkkw" hash="jS6_6Q">While serving in the required military service in Argentina, I read a book whose author I do not remember. He wrote: “I choose not to be an ordinary man; it is my right to be someone out of the ordinary, if I am able.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="fyabQ_ACPka8s9NC2eRn_A" hash="vXh6eg">To be someone out of the ordinary means to be successful, unique, and outstanding.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="VdHQ9_imn0yDI2fgOyuRVw" hash="AhpMrQ">That phrase has remained written in my mind and heart. My feelings were and are that we, as members of the Church of Jesus Christ, have chosen not to be ordinary men and women. The last words, “if I am able,” made me think that it is not enough to go through the motions of being baptized and confirmed, but rather we have to fulfill and honor the commitment that we made with the Lord on that memorable day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="RvWutEY3qEqx5Cp75uTkVQ" hash="dBVMdw">Lehi taught his son Jacob, saying: “Wherefore, men are free according to the flesh; and all things are given them which are expedient unto man. And they are free to choose liberty and eternal life, through the great Mediator of all men, or to choose captivity and death, according to the captivity and power of the devil; for he seeketh that all men might be miserable like unto himself” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.27" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 2:27</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="2sMoW1SreEacEaPxuZ6mGA" hash="rP4Wdw">Undoubtedly, freedom and eternal life are what we seek. We tremble at the very thought of dying and being captives of the devil.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="H6lO1GWh6E6_48ArZ7E_tA" hash="Itkt9g">Nephi taught us clearly what we ought to do. He said, “For we know that it is by grace that we are saved, after all we can do” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/25.23" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 25:23</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="OkMdYZyOwkCfX1-Bk6RThw" hash="qZgqOw">I believe that the first thing we have to keep in mind in doing “all we can” is to repent of our sins. We will never be able to reach our divine potential if we remain in our sins.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="N3lMTHpf0kun8xURKHCWVw" hash="FxxJ2Q">I have fond memories of the day of my baptism when I was eight years old. It was performed in the Liniers Branch, the first chapel of the Church built in South America. After my baptism, as I was returning home along with my family, my oldest brother started wrestling with me, as he often did. I exclaimed, “Do not touch me! I cannot sin!” As the days passed, I realized that it was not possible to remain sinless for the rest of my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="r_OLYlF_90-mARHPGbm9aA" hash="LxTDPQ">It is difficult to bear the sufferings that are inflicted upon us, but the real torment in life is to suffer the consequences of our own shortcomings and sins which we inflict upon ourselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="3Jovyk-tpEGL89lzgq1f8A" hash="_lPOBw">There is only one way to rid ourselves of this suffering. It is by means of sincere repentance. I learned that if I could present unto the Lord a broken heart and a contrite spirit, feeling a godly sorrow for my sins, humbling myself, being repentant of my faults, He, through His miraculous atoning sacrifice, could erase those sins and remember them no more.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="VfM3bh2tK0WUDocgXissgw" hash="_7TDkg">The Argentine poet José Hernández, in his famous book <span class="emphasis">Martín Fierro,</span> wrote:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.f1" guid="cc349eb4-a1e5-4c10-9041-bbe0ae34ca8d">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="aZMSom5NAkitKuNJKQMlcQ" hash="uexwfQ">
            <span class="emphasis">A man loses a lot of things</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="7ttE-DLbwE25gsr9VUayLQ" hash="vd1Gtw">
            <span class="emphasis">and sometimes finds them again,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="QuY3qwVGS0qWguiz0vOAhg" hash="XKCPCg">
            <span class="emphasis">but it’s my duty to inform you,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Q2rQTUi6G0aCzkCTAH3Bgw" hash="X-o98Q">
            <span class="emphasis">and you’ll do well to remember it,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="UZIAT0PCvky-qjCDkgWxxw" hash="-wR9ug">
            <span class="emphasis">if once your sense of shame gets lost</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="hld8TMiKQEuffqrUTjFBbA" hash="B1PE5g">
            <span class="emphasis">it will never again be found.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="hJAHzpwwkEm5wfD-zbC1sA" hash="HBlmMg">If we don’t experience the godly sorrow that results from our sins or unrighteous actions, it will be impossible for us to remain on the way of outstanding people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="RRf4Z8Rt90yM7YusPrWk7Q" hash="6wHd7g">Another important principle to remember in doing “all we can do” is to look for and develop the opportunities that life within the gospel constantly offers us and recognize that the Lord has given us all that we have. He is responsible for all that is good in our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="toeWwX1MT0q7Cyx0bVJ7gw" hash="H3n_YQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="99"></span>Another thing that must be our permanent responsibility is to do “all we can do” to share the gospel of happiness with all mankind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="kZyN6cdlN0-TGvB_5-Om2g" hash="WxU8yQ">Some time ago I received a letter from Brother Rafael Pérez Cisneros of Galicia, Spain, telling me about his conversion. Part of his letter said the following:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="OMLFfCdxrkydmyrBXg6jag" hash="VF9hgg">“I had no concept of the purpose of life or what the family really is. When I finally allowed the missionaries to come into my home, I told them, ‘Give me your message, but I warn you that nothing is going to make me change religions.’ On this first occasion my children and my wife were listening attentively. I felt separated from the group. I felt afraid, and without thinking I went to my bedroom. I closed the door and began to pray from the depths of my soul like I had never prayed before. ‘Father, if it is true that these young men are Your disciples and have come to help us, please make it known to me.’ It was in that very moment that I began to cry like a small child. My tears were abundant, and I felt happiness like I had never before experienced. I was absorbed in a sphere full of joy and happiness that penetrated my soul. I understood that God was answering my prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="6wC-4YAbqEWwFIN3ioEG6A" hash="kp36Mw">“All of my family was baptized, and we had the blessing of being sealed in the Swiss Temple, making me the happiest man in the world.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="XY-bl6BAikeNAHVVB2Y_YQ" hash="T4eT9g">I think this story should motivate us to do “all we can do” to share the blessings of joy that come from living the gospel of happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="oimdJx7QY0yeODB2MC-jPg" hash="LKFIMg">The final concept I want to share is that we should do “all we can do” until the end of our mortal probation. Without question, we have living examples like President Gordon B. Hinckley and many other men and women who continue to faithfully serve at ages that others may consider inconvenient.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="PiRfdVa-RkSC1LqEQHMbIA" hash="jNAjfw">When I served as president of the Spain Bilbao Mission, I was impressed with the quality of members and missionaries that I met, who moved the work forward with great ability and love, as do many faithful members of the Church in other parts of the world. To all of them, I express my sincere respect and admiration.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="zBbZJf-HzEyE7h4x4YbxUQ" hash="C0GGfA">The Lord has said that He is “delight[ed] to honor those who serve me in righteousness and in truth unto the end.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="BM3rtRXJekK9H5cTClMtqA" hash="mGE8gg">“Great shall be their reward and eternal shall be their glory” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.5-6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:5–6</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="uY7oUcQFxkGbvDkI52GSKQ" hash="uYGLsQ">May we always have in our minds and hearts the words of Nephi:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="CQJBnCFLQEyG_gAOi3XXvg" hash="WgfKTw">“Awake, my soul! No longer droop in sin. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="jtMuv27lgUGds_g9pqdiVQ" hash="zv5wdg">“… My soul will rejoice in thee, my God, and the rock of my salvation” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/4.28,30" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 4:28, 30</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do.p" pid="TgWXTDj_Dki_tJKV2I75Dw" hash="OeabBw">It is my humble prayer that the Lord may bless us to do “all we can do” in this “out of the ordinary” path that we have chosen, which I testify to be true, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/ZivicCD_07.jpg" alt="Elder Claudio D. Zivic" guid="dcfaa788-fa57-4856-82b3-2fb3b114240b" pid="WAiwxpCKuE20TAzENyF-bw" hash="ugSLhg1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="dcfaa788-fa57-4856-82b3-2fb3b114240b"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/10/after-all-we-can-do</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2007-general-conference/2007-10-5050-elder-claudio-d-zivic-64k-eng.mp3" length="3885678" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2007 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Not Take the Wrong Way</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Claudio D. Zivic counsels us to stay on the gospel path by keeping the commandments and to repent when we need to get back on the right path.
		</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10985_000_27zivic" doc-version="3" hash="mFKZ1A">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="oU87VzdmoEqwY-uXGvEuiw" hash="UGPd7Q">Let’s Not Take the Wrong Way</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p" pid="0Cvd1v86u0ewosD8Yz9Zow" hash="Q2Qf6g">By Elder Claudio D. Zivic</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p" pid="MlZST5LvlkWxstYtMrBGhg" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
		</div>
		<img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/leaders/claudio-d-zivic.jpg" altText="Elder Claudio D. Zivic" pid="2jpmBjvle0yvkr-t5M3vLg" hash="TrCz5A" />
		<p class="kicker" pid="VrRCd_wy-0-SSRDvi7H_-A" hash="faUzxw">I pray that we will not lose sight of the way so that we may always be connected with the heavens.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="suQPqJGVZ0WeTxkSnlM9vw" hash="Q2Qf6g1">By Elder Claudio D. Zivic</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="6NzglnAYtkqGRy7KDyxwfg" hash="2U54aQ">
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p5" pid="_EmK-OC7MUeC22KBDn6NAg" hash="1fB54A">
				<span class="pageBreak" page-number="39"></span>A little boy was practicing the piano, and a salesman, upon seeing him through the window, asked, “Is your mother home?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p6" pid="6TKCVbsadUGVAzNodYgCmQ" hash="n7LaCA">To which the child replied, “And … what do you think?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p7" pid="8gWwLliLGUW9P5VlIjyuLg" hash="DbIvXw">Our five dear children play the piano, thanks to the motivation of my wife! When the teacher arrived at our home, our son Adrián would run and hide in order to skip his lesson. But one day something marvelous occurred! He began to love music so much that he continued practicing on his own.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p8" pid="ch_uA3ZkYkWnJsWW-WJhYw" hash="C1W34w">If we could reach that point in the process of our conversion, it would be marvelous. It would be wonderful to have a desire deep in our hearts to keep the commandments without anyone constantly reminding us and to have a firm conviction that if we follow the right path, we will have the blessings promised in the scriptures.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p9" pid="8H9HaJPAA0ajBGqbFtRwog" hash="Gd97PQ">Several years ago I went to Arches National Park with my wife; our daughter, Evelin; and a family friend. One of the most famous arches there is called Delicate Arch. We decided to walk about 1.5 miles (2 km), climbing the mountain in order to reach the arch.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p10" pid="pauY5avggUu7C-GLXxQ8HQ" hash="p1K2_A">We started off on our pathway with great enthusiasm, but after walking a short stretch, the others needed to rest. Because of my desire to get there, I decided to continue on alone. Without paying attention to the path I ought to take, I followed a man in front of me who seemed to be moving forward with great surety. The pathway became more and more difficult, and I had to jump from one rock to another. Because of the difficulty, I was sure the women in my group would never make it. Suddenly I saw Delicate Arch, but to my great surprise, I saw that it was in an area inaccessible to me.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p11" pid="rNj9STedCEy7zXuXpb1svg" hash="yr2INQ">With great frustration, I decided to go back. I waited impatiently until we met up again. My immediate question was “Did you reach Delicate Arch?” They happily told me that they had. They explained that they had followed the signs showing the way, and with care and effort, they had reached their destination.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p12" pid="dZxIwg3IbkW7ApRDPrrqhA" hash="ZybTKA">Unfortunately, I had taken the wrong way. What a great lesson I learned that day!</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p13" pid="iRXpdS3JmEyklodZ241HwQ" hash="cThUcA">How often do we make a mistake about the right way, letting ourselves be led along by the trends of the world? We need to continually ask ourselves if we are being doers of the words of Jesus Christ.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p14" pid="WSoQp_nbAU2_6cthDxB2RA" hash="lXY3eQ">A marvelous teaching is found in the book of John:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p15" pid="3fZv5gFUvUeqg-xgPQ-xfQ" hash="rC0b2A">“Abide in me, and I in you. As the branch cannot bear fruit of itself, except it abide in the vine; no more <span class="pageBreak" page-number="40"></span>can ye, except ye abide in me.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p16" pid="c_WmMmKLuUqpqPRKwzN4LA" hash="TSdOBg">“I am the vine, ye are the branches: He that abideth in me, and I in him, the same bringeth forth much fruit: for without me ye can do nothing” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/15.4-5" class="scriptureRef">John 15:4–5</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p17" pid="ytuVxIywykOtbYspmYWRPA" hash="xs10hA">Using this analogy, we can see the very close, transcendent relationship we have with Jesus Christ and the importance He places on each one of us. He is the root and the trunk that conducts the living water to us, the sap that will allow us to be nourished so that we can produce much fruit. Jesus Christ taught us in such a way that as branches—or beings dependent upon Him—we would never underestimate the value of His teachings.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p18" pid="ntgIoDtWOUSV3lig2wwz6w" hash="9Hp-3A">There are some mistakes that may be serious, and if we do not correct them in time, they can permanently lead us off the right path. If we repent and accept correction, these experiences will allow us to humble ourselves, change our actions, and once again draw closer to our Heavenly Father.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p19" pid="M_bXVihTYEqOQ0mdNvZbgw" hash="cRgWEg">I want to give an example of this concept by making reference to one of the most dramatic moments that the Prophet Joseph Smith experienced. Through this experience, the Savior has given us invaluable teachings regarding principles that we ought to keep in mind throughout our lives. It happened when Martin Harris lost the 116 translated pages of the first part of the Book of Mormon.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p20" pid="YfhvJwxIN06okNjhLaT5fA" hash="ciWCLg">After repenting for not following God’s counsel, the Prophet received the revelation that is found in <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/3" class="scriptureRef">section 3</a> of the Doctrine and Covenants (see <span class="emphasis">Teachings of Presidents of the Church: Joseph Smith</span> [2007], 69–71). From what is written in <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/3.1-10" class="scriptureRef">verses 1 to 10</a>, I wish to highlight three principles that we should always remember:</p>
		<div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.f1">
			<ol class="number" guid="">
				<li pid="qaL1ACnrtkeC2wZgtE3ITg" hash="1JcPEw">
					<span class="label">1. </span>
					<p pid="8yeXxkqRpke5Qs1XdJ8O4Q" hash="oDejuQ">The works and the purposes of God cannot be frustrated.</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="xfA1gIH7Ikuk-owfCxPGnQ" hash="K8aqDw">
					<span class="label">2. </span>
					<p pid="lnFlZGBWl0aruRmqt7D0rQ" hash="0gMRgg">We must not fear man more than God.</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="ZOka3jkfFE2PvwQzMq0dzw" hash="_FY3FA">
					<span class="label">3. </span>
					<p pid="L9TUZm2eOE24-jua_-Zu8w" hash="PnSqJw">There is a need of constant repentance.</p>
				</li>
			</ol>
		</div>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p24" pid="Y_EZNQrm9UesmQDankQcBg" hash="KvSqcg">In <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/3.13" class="scriptureRef">verse 13</a>, the Lord teaches us four actions that we should never do:</p>
		<div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.f2">
			<ol class="number" guid="">
				<li pid="BPFLMTFcpkOwaZOfERVqgQ" hash="qtqhKQ">
					<span class="label">1. </span>
					<p pid="s_vto8DlyEeVqTfUaxhnPA" hash="g1Xj1A">Set at naught the counsels of God.</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="t7gJRYlpD0S5SRtUftx-wA" hash="TrICMg">
					<span class="label">2. </span>
					<p pid="UdRxYSI8REGYMMBkGxybIA" hash="DzBQsg">Break the most sacred promises made before God.</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="6H-JwJCSbEmd5AVYNjbLBg" hash="zhrGEQ">
					<span class="label">3. </span>
					<p pid="ih-wJB-UsEycvyeBYrb4BQ" hash="N-Za6w">Depend upon our own judgment.</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="FXRTLSMrIk2YA3EDSnIOdA" hash="Ymyqrg">
					<span class="label">4. </span>
					<p pid="RmMxFwH_80SbkIzCNGJOyQ" hash="70Q4SA">Boast in our own wisdom.</p>
				</li>
			</ol>
		</div>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p29" pid="dK3aIYMV3k2SgJpabpmgXA" hash="r4D4fw">I pray that we will not lose sight of the way so that we may always be connected with the heavens, so that the currents of the world do not sweep us away.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p30" pid="hL35HgM3jk2rD39oZhlyDw" hash="kPjclg">If any one of you reaches the point of abandoning the Lord’s way—at any point along that way—with great <span class="pageBreak" page-number="41"></span>remorse you will feel the bitterness of having set at naught the counsels of God, of having broken the most sacred promises made before God, of having trusted in your own judgment, or of having boasted in your own wisdom.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p31" pid="4cgCRTaFcE6EIZbc4pkrEw" hash="3okm2w">If this is the case, I exhort you to repent and come back to the right way.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p32" pid="Hy1itDcItky1Dk9fmB0dMw" hash="fT1Q1g">One time a grandchild called his grandfather to wish him a happy birthday. He asked him how old he was. He said that he had reached 70 years. His grandson thought for a moment and then asked, “Grandpa, did you start all the way back at 1?”</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p33" pid="_6obmWtOUE2On8J2Nj4aJA" hash="hDn3Lw">During childhood and youth, people think they will never become old; the idea of death never takes root—that is for very, very old people—and reaching that point is still an eternity away. As time goes on, months and seasons go by until the wrinkles begin to appear, energy is reduced, the need for doctor visits becomes more frequent, and so on.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p34" pid="cq3ko0spXEeyNl8hFwX85Q" hash="Mk95cQ">The day will come in which we shall again meet up with our Redeemer and Savior, Jesus Christ. I plead that on that sacred and sublime occasion we can recognize Him because of the knowledge we have of Him and because of having followed His teachings. He will show us the marks in His hands and feet, and we will join together in a lasting embrace, weeping for joy at having followed His way.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way.p35" pid="JyiqiTiTpUeDWWFD85HljQ" hash="UheOwA">I testify to the four ends of the earth that Jesus Christ lives. He exhorts us, “Hearken, O ye nations of the earth, and hear the words of that God who made you” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/43.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 43:23</a>). May we have the capacity to grasp, give heed to, comprehend, and correctly interpret the message of “that God who made [us]” so as not to stray from His way, I plead in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/04/lets-not-take-the-wrong-way</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2014-general-conference/2014-04-2070-elder-claudio-d-zivic-64k-eng.mp3" length="4476970" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2014 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
