<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Coleen K. Menlove</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Coleen K. Menlove.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Coleen%20K.%20Menlove.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Coleen K. Menlove.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Living Happily Ever After</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Savior, Jesus Christ, showed us the way to happiness and told us everything we need to do to be happy.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10033256_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="QPUwIg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="TNZBuLjWjkuYAq26K6UgZw" hash="1eUm1w">Living Happily Ever After</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Rb5Z89l5GEKdDHUOMm8wRg" hash="LnvmLg">Coleen K. Menlove</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="WZ0hGHmDK0-1JznjeBfYig" hash="sZx80A">The Savior, Jesus Christ, showed us the way to happiness and told us everything we need to do to be happy.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-cd.jpg" alt="Coleen K. Menlove" pid="ciAfSTcDUEqNHbjMo5D86w" hash="DRVclA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p1" pid="BJGlcAT3vUG9ulpAgSZ6Vw" hash="7viOcQ">Children love stories. As a child, I was immediately drawn into stories that started with the words “Once upon a time.” These stories often ended with “They lived happily ever after.” I have a feeling that children are not the only ones who are intrigued by those phrases. We each long to have the “once upon a time” of our lives filled with so much happiness that it becomes the “happily ever after” of our hopes and dreams.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p2" pid="7FXq-HzobkmfTDKRZbIHwA" hash="5EU1jQ">We are living in our “once upon a time.” We are experiencing a mortal probation now during our turn on earth. In our premortal existence, “all the sons of God shouted for joy” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/job/38.7" class="scriptureRef">Job 38:7</a>) as we accepted the great eternal plan of happiness. We happily anticipated coming to earth to experience opportunities to grow spiritually. “Men are, that they might have joy” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.25" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:25</a>). The opportunity is here and now to obtain happiness that extends beyond our earth life; however, we need to know what it is and where to find it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p3" pid="tiH-JF33xU-g3Pgq0pd2yA" hash="rMweSA">In the Book of Mormon, Lehi explained to his son Jacob that happiness is a result of obedience. He told Jacob that eternal laws have both punishments and opportunities for happiness attached to them. When we disobey God’s laws, we suffer the punishments, but when we obey, we reap the happiness (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.10" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:10</a>). Part of what creates happiness is the absence of regret, guilt, and sin.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p4" pid="4xxtkNR5N0SgwOwgO6zjuQ" hash="AFl7QQ">The Prophet Joseph Smith taught, “Happiness is the object and design of our existence; and will be the end thereof, if we pursue the path that leads to it; and this path is virtue, uprightness, faithfulness, holiness, and keeping all the commandments of God” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith,</span> sel. Joseph Fielding Smith [1976], 255–56).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p5" pid="lXCy1IHbUE2j275uQxgeDQ" hash="SmVJqg">A young friend named Emily discovered this for herself. Emily did not yet have a testimony of the gospel and was contemplating whether to remain active in the Church or try to find happiness elsewhere. As she searched for answers, she began to notice that the people and families around her who were the happiest were the ones who were active in the Church. After that discovery, she determined that even if she didn’t yet have a complete testimony of the truthfulness of the gospel, she wanted to be part of something that helped people to be so happy. The word <span class="emphasis">gospel</span> means “good news,” and, as Emily discovered, the good news is that the gospel can make us very happy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p6" pid="9HLs5ZMZPEu7XtiaC-MubA" hash="28x5sg">But, you may be thinking, even within the Church there are people who aren’t happy or people who are usually happy but who experience intermittent times of stress, worry, challenge, and discouragement. That, too, is part of the great plan of happiness. Mortality is a time of testing and trial, which means that there must be times when we feel pain and emotional discomfort. However, by patiently trusting in the eternal plan, we can experience daily happiness and have hope for “ever-after happiness.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p7" pid="SjAorTEe6k-TKnwq-rFk8A" hash="rWZoAQ">Elder Boyd K. Packer explained: “It was meant to be that life would be a challenge. To suffer some anxiety, some depression, some disappointment, even some failure is normal. Teach our members that if they have a good, miserable day once in a while, or several in a row, to stand steady and face them. Things will straighten out. There is great purpose in our struggle in life” (<span class="emphasis">“That All May Be Edified”</span> [1982], 94).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p8" pid="t7mieeYCUE2GLdWVo6rpxQ" hash="QlKMDQ">The story of our search for happiness is written in such a way that if we continue to trust in God and follow His commandments through the challenging times, even those times will bring us closer to the happiness we are seeking. The Savior said, “In the world ye shall have tribulation: but be of good cheer; I have overcome the world” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/16.33" class="scriptureRef">John 16:33</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p9" pid="xaWg3hRY7UqxarkjTSEN2Q" hash="YhH0PQ">The Savior, Jesus Christ, showed us the way to happiness and told us everything we need to do to be happy. As we study the teachings of the Savior and thereby understand the purpose of our existence, we feel and express our happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p10" pid="O5e6Jpu2UEW6Po-G0kghEg" hash="be4IZg">In the Doctrine and Covenants, the Lord said that we should worship Him “with a glad heart and a cheerful countenance” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.15" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:15</a>). We can experience a speedier and more sure course to our “ever-after happiness” by developing certain habits and attitudes that encourage happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p11" pid="mP3xDegIGUOpuE-STbMKHg" hash="FORrNA">Our prophet, President Gordon B. Hinckley, is the very essence of a glad heart. He has written: “I am an optimist! … My plea is that we stop seeking out the storms and enjoy more fully the sunlight. I am suggesting that as we go through life, we ‘accentuate the positive’” (<span class="emphasis">Standing for Something</span> [2000], 101).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p12" pid="p2_VVFAi3Ee6P_aM671muQ" hash="vduMzA">Children are usually good examples of attitudes of “a glad heart and a cheerful countenance.” They have a sense of happiness and optimism that invites others to rejoice with them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p13" pid="-ziGD-f17Euxj4UH5rZsKQ" hash="LkyGFQ">My husband and I took our grandson to lunch for his fourth birthday. After lunch, we buckled him in the backseat for the drive home. In the front seat, we began to discuss the schedule of the day, but I heard this four-year-old talking to himself. He was saying over and over, “I am such a lucky boy. I am such a lucky boy.” He was expressing his joy to anyone who would listen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p14" pid="v23fDLDCeE2_7L05R87LNw" hash="S7q2ng">We can learn how simple joy can be from these little ones. I would like to share some comments from Primary children that teach us what happiness is and where we can find it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p15" pid="2q41s7JC6UOCG2rPdqp-8w" hash="B6kZcA">One child observed, “Happiness looks like a smile that you can see in people’s eyes so that you know they really are happy.” This child knows happiness is as simple as a smile.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p16" pid="YI25hyK7NE2_kP1bEMlmcA" hash="XUjXVg">Recently I stopped at a grocery store to quickly pick up a few things for dinner. As I turned the corner, I came face to face with an older gentleman. I smiled, as I was relieved that we hadn’t collided. He smiled and said, “Thank you for your smile. I needed it.” I also needed his smile. Smile—it will make a difference for you and for others. What would life be like if we couldn’t give and receive smiles?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p17" pid="_C413clwhEej4fCHtllbtg" hash="pYI76w">Happiness is not only simple, but it is here for us to experience each day. Happiness is all around us. It can be as immediate as now. Some children said, “Happiness is a big word with flowers all around it.” Another said it looks like “a rainbow.” “It looks like the sun.” We need to remember that despite all of life’s challenges, our time to be happy is now.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p18" pid="-zTibSU7nUCZQIAmmR_QJw" hash="BoTRMQ">A few months ago I had an opportunity to take a morning walk on a mountain trail with four of my grandchildren. We each brought a bag so we could collect treasures from nature. As we looked for pieces to put in our collection, we found many different colors, designs, and textures in the leaves and rocks. It was hard to choose. I soon noticed that the children’s bags were filling up. Each leaf the children selected was unique, but because it was late fall, most of the leaves had dark weathered spots, irregular shapes, or faded and discolored parts. Because of this, I was reluctant to add things to my bag. I was looking for a leaf that showed the brightest colors and had no flaws. If it wasn’t perfect, I wasn’t going to treasure it. But this meant that my bag had very little in it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p19" pid="s3ecB_ejwkuh9mH35XNoYg" hash="v3WJ9g">Later, as I thought about this experience, I realized that I had cheated myself of much delight and happiness that could have been mine. I didn’t appreciate the uniqueness of the objects because I was looking for what I had deemed perfection. My grandchildren had been wiser than I had been. They had savored the odd shapes and spots on the leaves. They giggled at and enjoyed the brittle crispness of the dying leaves, and they delighted in the soft, faded colors. They filled their bags with happy treasures to take home. We can fail to see and enjoy the unique happiness and beauty in each day if we are so focused on our desire for what we want instead of what the Lord has designed for us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p20" pid="CJp2lmB2E0O2VUY6R96JCw" hash="BS2fMw">Happiness is knowledge of the gospel of Jesus Christ. One child said, “Happiness looks peaceful like Jesus and Heavenly Father.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p21" pid="6Mk0mbMgw02l4C4al8apog" hash="N_QTpw">Recently I attended a Primary and was holding a 14-month-old child on my lap when she looked up and saw a picture of the Savior on the wall. Her little face beamed as she said with her newly acquired language skills, “Jesus.” Perhaps this little one understands the joy of knowing the Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p22" pid="ueCmNRaB8k6P2g0GwU4B8Q" hash="raICZA">It is knowing and feeling the pure love of Christ that brings exquisite joy to our souls. It is knowing that forgiveness for our mistakes is possible. It is through the Atonement of the Savior, who satisfied the demands of justice and offers us mercy, that hope and joy are possible. As we draw near to the Savior, we are free from doubt and confusion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p23" pid="aWR2y-H7Gk-6lz8Ahmi0Ww" hash="2hXvUA">Elder Richard G. Scott said: “Your joy in life depends upon your trust in Heavenly Father and His holy Son, your conviction that their plan of happiness truly can bring you joy” (“Finding Joy in Life,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1996, 24).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p24" pid="U43e061zG0m7v2VVKV9rtg" hash="yf0FCw">Through the Savior we can find our way back to God. We can find peace and happiness in this life and eternal joy in the world to come. That thought, in and of itself, warms my heart and makes me smile.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after.p25" pid="v7iatk2tDk6XQd0yj-0Ogw" hash="odDN2Q">As we come to understand the great plan of happiness, we will radiate, for all the world to see, a glad heart and a cheerful countenance. We will show that we know the gospel of Jesus Christ is a simple, ever-present source of true happiness today and ever after in eternity. It is living the gospel of Jesus Christ that is our guarantee of living “happily ever after.” Of this I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2000/04/living-happily-ever-after</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2000-general-conference/2000-04-1040-coleen-k-menlove-64k-eng.mp3" length="5926246" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Voice of Gladness for Our Children</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children?lang=eng</link>
      <description>This is our charge, this is our opportunity, to diligently teach and testify to our children of the truthfulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029898_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="VJg6gQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="kwVbLNTnkE2iRoqeFvdaAA" hash="X_C3Ug">A Voice of Gladness for Our Children</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="7yeAi-Dqk0So572c64VJ8A" hash="LnvmLg">Coleen K. Menlove</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="0LCZkwgydE6PUxvrTbW5MQ" hash="k91pBA">This is our charge, this is our opportunity, to diligently teach and testify to our children of the truthfulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-cd.jpg" alt="Coleen K. Menlove" pid="wkyzjI0950qfjyCvdEOWBQ" hash="DRVclA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p1" pid="IkocZ3BDFEaP_xQ8V7Ju4w" hash="gx6kYQ">I like exclamation marks! I use them often when writing notes to myself and to others. It is a way to show enthusiasm and commitment. One of my favorite scriptures is punctuated with an exclamation mark:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p2" pid="eVSTcjvZCUKvhuzaGUdBZA" hash="ma8Q5g">“Now, what do we hear in the gospel which we have received? A voice of gladness!” There are 14 more exclamation marks in the rest of the verse and the next four verses that follow. They read in part:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p3" pid="P9SFpa1fMkqbSKSjB-EWug" hash="c84Z8w">“A voice of mercy from heaven; and a voice of truth out of the earth … a voice of … glad tidings of great joy. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p4" pid="Wt-dqUPEREmNU8LMdK6jvw" hash="SKCo5w">“… Glorious is the voice we hear from heaven, proclaiming in our ears, glory, and salvation … !”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span>—with an exclamation mark.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p5" pid="O6wjEKIDbkm8WBQq3VctCA" hash="0XJOJg">We can hear a voice of gladness that brings exclamations of hope and joy into our lives. The joy of our testimonies of the Savior can punctuate every aspect of our lives as we seek to come unto Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p6" pid="AMp_XWh4UEuKBDAZxmrWHQ" hash="D2PPwA">What about our children? Do they hear exclamations of joy and hope in the gospel? After a Primary lesson about Joseph Smith’s First Vision, the class was asked to draw pictures to take home and share with their families. The children had been taught about the darkness Joseph experienced before the appearance of the Father and the Son. A six-year-old girl picked up a black crayon and started to draw. She colored the bottom and up one side of the page as dark as she could. When her teacher asked her about the picture, she said she was drawing Joseph Smith in the darkness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p7" pid="y3ZHfoK_lEGA6pGF4v0wdg" hash="yS_EwQ">Her teacher inquired: “Do you know that when Heavenly Father and Jesus appeared, all the darkness had to leave? Heavenly Father and Jesus are always more powerful than Satan, and They will protect you.” The child turned back to her paper. In the top corner, she drew an outline of two figures; and then, trading her black crayon for a bright yellow one, she filled the rest of the page with light.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p8" pid="BOIF_5JJQEeg_C7lUaLQaA" hash="xuy4jw">It is this light, the light of the restored gospel—a “voice of gladness”—that parents can help their children come to know. The adversary is real, but children can feel the peace and the joy that come as they exercise faith in Jesus Christ. Our children will not experience this light unless we teach them the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p9" pid="vkEa_U8KrE-Bcv8QucwF2w" hash="2e8d0Q">The Lord directed parents to “bring up [their] children in light and truth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> He also instructed us to teach our children “to pray, and to walk uprightly before the Lord,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> and “to understand the doctrine of repentance, faith in Jesus Christ, … and of baptism and the gift of the Holy Ghost.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> We help tune their ears, minds, and hearts to recognize “a voice of gladness” and desire to be worthy to obtain eternal joy when we teach the truths of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p10" pid="qIqLVAl7REK1Mp6vLQtr5Q" hash="gTX6AQ">This is exemplified in the Book of Mormon. Enos’s father taught him “in the nurture and admonition of the Lord.” This great blessing caused Enos to proclaim, “Blessed be the name of my God for it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Enos then explains, “The words which I had often heard my father speak concerning eternal life, and the joy of the saints, sunk deep into my heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p11" pid="RofgXKQ9ekqR3YZvjZqPNA" hash="66hLwg">A friend shared an experience she had as a small child in a branch of the Church where she was the only child of Primary age. Week after week, her mother held home Primary on the same day and at the same time. She eagerly anticipated sitting on the sofa with her mother and learning the gospel of Jesus Christ and how to live it. Minutes carefully recorded by her mother in a notebook revealed the home Primary meetings always included prayers, songs, and a lesson.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p12" pid="VY7gOWGrrEmVK6DAdyVYKQ" hash="F9XuMw">The desire of this mother’s heart was for her little daughter to develop a testimony of Jesus Christ and to feel the joy of the gospel. She provided her daughter with what had been so important to her as a child. This little girl, now a woman of faith and covenant, looks back on her childhood with deep appreciation for her mother’s enthusiasm and commitment to teach her of the Savior. This mother’s diligence became her daughter’s delight—with an exclamation mark.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p13" pid="UZMpNODDcUatzyx7McMgBg" hash="nbA-2Q">Living prophets are clear regarding our sacred duty to teach our children.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> In a letter issued by the First Presidency, we are instructed “to give highest priority to family prayer, family home evening, gospel study and instruction, and wholesome family activities. However worthy and appropriate other demands or activities may be, they must not be permitted to displace the divinely-appointed duties that only parents and families can adequately perform.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p14" pid="GyYICwNo30GLWFcqtablGw" hash="7S0sfA">Yes, life can be fast-paced for parents and is becoming so for children. It would be easy to say there is not enough time to fit everything in. Looking back at a time that passed all too quickly, I can now see that each day was filled with precious little moments full of opportunity to help our children hear the “voice of gladness” in the gospel. Children are always learning from us. They are learning what is important by what we choose to do as well as what we choose not to do. Casual, infrequent family prayers, scripture study, and family home evenings will not be enough to fortify our children. Where will children learn the gospel and standards such as chastity, integrity, and honesty if not at home? These values can be reinforced at church, but parents are the most capable and most effective in teaching them to their children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p15" pid="GaM6-Rnl0E6bWvZHGd870g" hash="OvpFfg">Understanding who these children are and their potential in God’s kingdom can help us have a greater desire to meet the challenges more patiently—more lovingly. The Lord will help us teach our children if we will do all that is within our power. Families are forever, and the Savior wants us to succeed. As we seek the Spirit, we can receive the comfort, guidance, and reassurance we need to fulfill the responsibilities and receive the blessings of parenthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p16" pid="ANURa8PObESlA_v5AdwDTg" hash="ZTQe_A">The divinely inspired programs of the Church and those called to minister to our children can help us. My husband and I are grateful for bishops, priesthood and auxiliary leaders, and home and visiting teachers who helped strengthen our family. Whether we have children in our own home or not, each of us can play an important part in assisting parents.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p17" pid="Gg_pEuyChEOuOmGP3H5pqA" hash="fLFeaw">Children are so capable of learning the significant things of the kingdom. As we listen to them we can better understand how they are applying what they are learning about the gospel. A father explained to his four-year-old daughter that the family had spent most of the day cleaning the house and every room was clean except one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p18" pid="dNdXL4nz2UaPY6eX1E3CfQ" hash="TvwBBg">“Do you know which room is not clean?” he asked her.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p19" pid="6MffgpWzh0u5pIhGeU9glQ" hash="FMx-YA">“Mine,” she quickly replied.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p20" pid="Ms8ggG99D0aONCSocyndzw" hash="HqaJhw">“Do you know anyone who could help clean your room?” he asked, expecting her to answer that she could.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p21" pid="rK_G4EkXJEeySjhz0B6F4w" hash="oUDiHA">Instead she replied, “Well, Daddy, I know that any time you are scared, worried, or need help, you can get down on your knees and ask Heavenly Father to help.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p22" pid="4u1ftba-GUe6I1SE3KfY9A" hash="Am0K0g">It is interesting to note that as we listen to our children, they can also teach us. A father shared an experience he had with his eight-year-old daughter. He said: “While I was contemplating remarks for my sacrament meeting talk on ‘Becoming like Little Children,’ I asked my daughter why we needed to become like little children. She responded, ‘Because we are all little children compared to Jesus, and because little children have a good imagination.’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p23" pid="qe4ESrkiXUKCwbZWAZd99w" hash="o90CkQ">Surprised by the last part of her answer, he asked why we need a good imagination. She replied, “So we can imagine Jesus in the Garden of Gethsemane and on the cross, and when we take the sacrament we can think about Him.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p24" pid="D2RWQwi8lESJ2UtqW2E55w" hash="8uh_Bw">As in all things, the Savior set the example for us in how we should love and teach our children. When He appeared to the Nephites on this hemisphere, the scriptures tell us that as He spoke to the people, “he wept, … and he took their little children, one by one, and blessed them, and prayed unto the Father for them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p25" pid="C3PgD6Bwd0qxTVvDk6z_qA" hash="wtW8tQ">Referring to this occasion, President Gordon B. Hinckley said, “There is no more tender and beautiful picture in all of sacred writing than this simple language describing the love of the Savior for little children.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p26" pid="VZQxu9lX40GD678sugeNNw" hash="SKA9qA">The key to accomplishing effective gospel teaching in the home is to invite the Spirit of the Lord to be with us. Some of the best counsel my husband and I received during some turbulent times of raising our children was to do all that is possible to invite and keep the Spirit in our home. Children cannot learn spiritual things and have spiritual feelings without the guidance of the Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p27" pid="Y73SnTErvUq87OXMEpKH1A" hash="89uMmQ">As parents, we can share our testimony of Jesus Christ with our children often. The bearing of testimony, whether during family home evening or in a teaching moment, will invite the Spirit. President Boyd K. Packer also instructs us to “teach our young people to bear testimony—to bear testimony that Jesus is the Christ, that Joseph Smith is a prophet of God, that the Book of Mormon is true.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p28" pid="WnRwn81S4EuqZCbzw6EMYA" hash="FkZtrA">President Hinckley reassures us: “Of all the joys of life, none other equals that of happy parenthood. Of all the responsibilities with which we struggle, none other is so serious. To rear children in an atmosphere of love, security, and faith is the most rewarding of all challenges.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children.p29" pid="G1uQpe_opEyGPzWJSnTjEQ" hash="UA65Vw">I know—with an exclamation mark—that children can receive a witness by the Spirit that brings conviction and commitment to their hearts! I bear witness that this is our charge, this is our opportunity, to diligently teach and testify to our children of the truthfulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ, that they might also hear the “voice of gladness.” In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2002/10/a-voice-of-gladness-for-our-children</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2002-general-conference/2002-10-1040-coleen-k-menlove-64k-eng.mp3" length="5940260" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2002 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All Thy Children Shall Be Taught</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Children need to know that having faith in the Savior and following Him will help them receive peace in this troubled world.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10032029_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="jEkbQw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="e0hmE_u4BkmumRKKGX3xSA" hash="tfP2qA">All Thy Children Shall Be Taught</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="cc276Uvnn0-E4pG9SPxmAg" hash="LnvmLg">Coleen K. Menlove</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="OKjvaEW3hUGuskOxBFdnNA" hash="bqR1aQ">Children need to know that having faith in the Savior and following Him will help them receive peace in this troubled world.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-cd.jpg" alt="Coleen K. Menlove" pid="6V1vnFSgC0Gdh0UNOOH-Og" hash="DRVclA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p1" pid="x10Lm5Sukky3zUtXFZB_nQ" hash="nLAVQw">Recent disasters around the world have touched our hearts. The suffering children, who are innocent victims, weigh particularly heavy upon us. We have seen children without family members to provide, protect, and love them. Our hearts desire to reach out and help in some way—any way that would relieve their suffering and bring hope to their lives. We are grateful for the opportunities we have to give assistance. We are encouraged by the efforts of many who are helping these children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p2" pid="XE4SV9c4PUSkNn3wljYQ0Q" hash="sbqJEQ">However, we do not need to look far to find children who live in different yet challenging circumstances. Unknowingly, we may look beyond the children in our own midst. Are we really aware of the perilous circumstances surrounding our own children? We can usually determine if their physical needs are met, but what about their spiritual needs? Do they know of the light and peace of the gospel of Jesus Christ? The scriptures teach, “All thy children shall be taught of the Lord; and great shall be the peace of thy children.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p3" pid="W5GroBjNl0aeLl6-v_i01Q" hash="8PVVhg">Children need the peace that comes from knowing they have a loving Heavenly Father, who sent His Son, Jesus Christ, to bring light and hope into the world. It is up to us as adults to direct children to that peace and light.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p4" pid="AQm25l_8vEmETE559_memw" hash="ky0yVA">The spiritual plight of some children in the world today is depicted in a painting by the Danish artist Carl Bloch. This painting beautifully illustrates a scriptural account found in John, chapter 5. Christ, the healer and comforter, is the focus of the painting. He is lifting a covering from a man who has had infirmities since birth. The man is waiting for the miracle of healing in the pool of Bethesda, but he has no one to assist him. As the man waits, hoping for a miracle, Christ stands in his presence with the power to heal him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p5" pid="1WygiLMMUE-lLHOi8OOGlA" hash="I9dyYg">The painting includes several figures in the background, none of whom are looking directly at Christ. The Lord is in their midst, yet only one man sees Him as such. All the others appear to be going about their daily business, oblivious to the great power of Jesus and the miracle about to occur in their presence. A young child and a woman, perhaps his mother, are in view of Jesus; yet like the others, their eyes are focused elsewhere. In the very presence of the Savior, this woman fails to direct the child to the Savior. I wonder, would we, too, have missed this opportunity to come unto Christ? Are life’s experiences distracting us and dulling our spiritual view so we are not focusing on that which matters most? I wonder, do we miss opportunities to learn of the Lord and feel His love? Do we miss opportunities to share with others—especially children—that which matters most, the gospel of Jesus Christ? We have all seen children and youth standing in the crowds confused and wanting to know what matters most.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p6" pid="MJ8OQtr7_ES2KYHMHeKmXA" hash="NaNBPw">I can almost hear this child and other children crying out the words so many of us have sung, “Teach me to walk in the light.” Remember the words:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="-FfbLucTcUe6ZHboRgCkFw" hash="NZTYMw">
            <span class="emphasis">Teach me to walk in the light of his love;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="tPm2dBh6xUams-ZOzo2V_w" hash="JX6Tfw">
            <span class="emphasis">Teach me to pray to my Father above;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="EhTb8HDuOEqGGIKODjn3fg" hash="aPUjeA">
            <span class="emphasis">Teach me to know of the things that are right;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="9Oh2YjHCKEm7GzxPH5GprQ" hash="hVO35g">
            <span class="emphasis">Teach me, teach me to walk in the light.</span>
            <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p7" pid="22h2s_Yj50irMUS_UaUSAQ" hash="QJYuVg">Are we teaching our children to know, feel, and rejoice in the beauty, power, and miracles of the gospel of Jesus Christ? President Gordon B. Hinckley has counseled: “Let us nurture our children concerning Him whom we call the Lord Jesus Christ. Let us teach our children the grand saving principles of the gospel.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Children need to know that having faith in the Savior and following Him will help them receive peace in this troubled world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p8" pid="50L08rXl3EaxpiDYJN476Q" hash="xa9R4w">How do we teach our children? We can follow the example of the Savior. In the Book of Mormon we read of the resurrected Savior’s appearance to those in the Western Hemisphere. While teaching the people, He gathered the children to Him. He knelt and prayed with the children and for them. He blessed the children one by one. He felt the joy of their presence and opened the heavens that the children might be taught from on high.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p9" pid="EkxawB1PFE6-Mh_YfL_zRw" hash="1DzDzQ">As you include children at your family dinner table, as you involve them in daily family prayer and scripture study and in family home evening, you are following the example of the Savior by loving and teaching them. As you do this, let them know that together your family is striving to keep the commandments and to be worthy to be an eternal family. It may be during the informal one-on-one times that the Spirit will prompt us to ask just the right questions or to say just the right thing to help our children know and feel the light of the Lord. If we make the opportunities, the Spirit will guide us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p10" pid="wlgN1pPNKE-n9_uJd74Hzg" hash="voQjfQ">We have wonderful, capable children in our midst. We can help them find peace in this life and in the life to come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p11" pid="tOfmga-2NUKEOy-RSLCOAQ" hash="sO76qg">Children need to experience the Light of Christ so they can choose the light and resist the darkness. Moses had a miraculous experience when he was transfigured and beheld God with his spiritual eyes. After Moses had been taught of God and had beheld His glory and work, Satan came to Moses with darkness and confusion. Because Moses had experienced the light and glory of God, he knew the difference. He stood boldly against Satan saying, “Who art thou? For behold I am a son of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p12" pid="W5wlY_cPvECossS7z8RTnw" hash="Av2XwA">Children need to be filled with the light of the gospel so when temptation comes they can say: “I know who I am. I am a child of God. I know what I am to do. I am to be baptized, receive the Holy Ghost, and keep the commandments.” Then children can say: “I know who I can become. I can become a righteous young woman,” or, “I can become a righteous young man and receive the priesthood of God.” Children filled with this knowledge and light can make the decision to reject darkness and turn to the light and peace of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p13" pid="2xJ0LwyiSE6nYJgYkojI9Q" hash="SaMkmQ">Children who have the gospel tucked into their hearts recognize the hand of the Lord in their lives. Children know more than we sometimes suppose and can do more than we sometimes think. I have learned that children who have the light of the gospel are believing. They do not doubt. Samantha, age 11, said, “I know the gospel is true because I can feel it.” Three-year-old Benjamin said, “I know Heavenly Father hears and answers my prayers because He loves me.” Children who have the light of the gospel say, “I know the Holy Ghost is directing my life because I feel happy when I choose to follow its promptings.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p14" pid="NiALgdjm-0q_naXzYx4Pfg" hash="ZhCIAQ">Sam is beginning to understand the feelings that come from the Holy Ghost. When his mother asked, “Who is the Holy Ghost?” he said, “It is a warm feeling inside me.” Sam also understood that when his little two-week-old brother was sick, it was the Holy Ghost encouraging him to pray for the Lord’s help.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p15" pid="h-lQajwO7kOKx2XJI0lw6Q" hash="rFTlcQ">Can you feel the peace of these children?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p16" pid="wkzNY1nsb0mjxxGy7pf1mw" hash="V85PKA">Teaching children requires more than desire. It requires diligence on our part. Earlier I mentioned the song “Teach Me to Walk in the Light,” written by Clara McMaster. Sister McMaster shared with me that while serving on the Primary general board she received the assignment to write a song about teaching children. She found this an especially daunting task and prayed to know how to begin and complete this assignment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p17" pid="jJNofsee1kqrDnKXJ-3TgA" hash="aOC13g">After much effort she submitted her work, only to be told that it was not yet right. She was not told what to change, only to continue the effort until it was right. She was spiritually exhausted, not knowing how to proceed. She again sought guidance from the Lord, made changes, and submitted another edition. This process continued three times until at last she was told it was perfect and she was not to change anything.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p18" pid="dRoGJL0_v0SVt2IXDb6wSA" hash="Q2O3Sg">Even though there were many times that Sister McMaster wanted to give up, she diligently worked at what she had been asked to do and what she hoped would bless the lives of children. Her inspired music has been sung by adults and children in many lands and in many languages. This song represents the desire of my heart—that all children will learn to walk in the light of the gospel of Jesus Christ. This song begins with a plea from a child, “Teach me to walk in the light,” and ends with a commitment, “Gladly, gladly we’ll walk in the light.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p19" pid="88sd8fASQkCEV5Cm883f_g" hash="ySyhgQ">It will take time and effort to teach children, but we must not become distracted or give up. Our children so need the fulfillment of the promise “and great shall be the peace of thy children.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> Let no child wonder if he or she is loved by Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ. Let all children know who they are, what they are to do, and who they can become.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p20" pid="NergJ9hvEEyazYW4eAlcgw" hash="BpkpQw">I am grateful to all who reach out to children, who love them and teach them that regardless of their earthly circumstances, they can feel peace in the light of the gospel and receive the promises of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p21" pid="lrT9hUf9f0KyeDmwlKfLPQ" hash="_A-2Ug">I would like to speak especially to the children around the world. I have met some of you here and some of you in places such as Africa, the Philippines, Korea, and most recently in Ukraine and Russia. I have visited you in Primaries and even in children’s hospitals. I hope you know how much you are loved by your family, your Primary teachers, and, most importantly, by Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p22" pid="Y869Ej5Vp0633V_XTA8XEw" hash="vE9f1Q">Never settle for less than the privileges and blessings God offers you. The standards you keep in your dress, your language, and your behavior are outward signs of your inward commitment to follow Heavenly Father’s plan for you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught.p23" pid="635g1IaajU-QtXd6282mxQ" hash="YUyezg">Your influence upon me is greater than you can imagine. Thank you for the joy and hope you bring into my heart and the hearts of your Primary leaders and especially your parents. Please remember to express your thanks to those who love and teach you. I know, and I want you to know, you are a child of God, Heavenly Father loves you, and you can pray to Him anytime, anywhere. Try always to remember and follow Jesus Christ, and this will bring light and peace into your lives now and give you hope for the eternities. Of this I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2005/04/all-thy-children-shall-be-taught</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2005-general-conference/2005-04-1040-coleen-k-menlove-64k-eng.mp3" length="6691118" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2005 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
