<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Craig C. Christensen</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Craig C. Christensen.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Craig%20C.%20Christensen.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Craig C. Christensen.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2003 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2003 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Seek, and Ye Shall Find</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As we engage our faith and commit our energy to draw closer to Jesus Christ, we begin to understand more fully who He really is.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030371_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="BEUWHg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="tMZylnBINkGK1gH1h2ieJA" hash="ZOiQrQ">Seek, and Ye Shall Find</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ipU12Hh3C0WLyuke1hQE0Q" hash="1JurUg">Craig C. Christensen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="vQC2G0WZzkeDkpDx5LhOig" hash="uZ7Wig">As we engage our faith and commit our energy to draw closer to Jesus Christ, we begin to understand more fully who He really is.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-a97.jpg" alt="Elder Craig C. Christensen" pid="7RGvirKpkE60JOYU0SHPnQ" hash="nmX8Vw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p1" pid="OlSQGH6g-k6og2RgpjgB3Q" hash="qots5Q">My dear brothers and sisters, I pray that I may be guided by the Spirit of the Lord as I share with you my personal feelings and testimony.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p2" pid="eWWEINqGmEmQ_Fv5DrBtdA" hash="0jstiA">One of the most compelling invitations and profound promises given by the Savior is found in the simple phrase “seek, and ye shall find.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p3" pid="36jVRzB9BkWFp900jG89xA" hash="v2cSBg">Although the process of seeking includes prayer and supplication, it goes much deeper than that. Seeking is more of a journey than a single event. I liken it to taking a long, cross-country vacation. Although we know what our ultimate destination is, the rich experiences and real learning come day by day as we progress toward our goal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p4" pid="LpItlXQXL0qhdg73gXb4cg" hash="QzHnxg">As we seek the things of God, we must humble ourselves before Him, remembering that it is by His grace that we receive them, and focus our thoughts and our prayers, our faith and our desires, even all of the energy of our hearts that we might receive light and understanding directly from a loving Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p5" pid="o_WzjA-jtUKDG2c4rOLPSw" hash="jL-7Yg">The pattern for seeking answers from God is simple to explain yet much more personal when applied. To begin, we are invited to study in our minds and ponder in our hearts those things that we most desire of Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> This process of reflection brings clarity and inspiration to our souls. We are then instructed to present our thoughts and desires directly to Heavenly Father in humble prayer with the promise that, if we ask Him in the name of Christ, if what we are seeking is right, and if we “ask with a sincere heart, with real intent, having faith in Christ, he will manifest the truth of it unto [us], by the power of the Holy Ghost,” for it is “by the power of the Holy Ghost” that we “know the truth of all things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p6" pid="hLpOyNMfME-q5N8FNwCB9Q" hash="8QMgHw">And what should we seek?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p7" pid="NZ6eSDDgi0yPD7_jwBYCzw" hash="QBO0yw">The scriptures teach us that we should “seek … earnestly the [very] best gifts,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> that we should seek wisdom and understanding and to “prepare every needful thing.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> We are admonished to lose ourselves in the service of others<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> and to seek those things that are “virtuous, lovely, or of good report or praiseworthy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p8" pid="yPDbttJvEU6yQ52ndXYT5Q" hash="0Zy6tQ">At the same time, we are cautioned not to seek the unclean things of the world.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> President Gordon B. Hinckley has said: “There is so much evil, enticing evil, in the world. Shun it, my brothers and sisters. Avoid it. It is as a dangerous disease. It is as a poison that will destroy you. Stay away from it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> In the book of Amos we read, “Seek good, and not evil, that ye may live: and so the Lord, the God of hosts, shall be with you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p9" pid="mfWH2_VDC0ixy2C43JPawQ" hash="NMIUZA">What we seek first and foremost, above all other things, is “the kingdom of God, and his righteousness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> We seek to know “the only true God and Jesus Christ whom [He has] sent.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p10" pid="Gzz0uBrnQkyvyOwRD9ci8A" hash="f_NSKA">In a very personal version of the invitation to seek and find, the Savior said, “Draw near unto me and I will draw near unto you; seek me diligently and ye shall find me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p11" pid="j-Co0bVFbkaDF0LSoRwI-Q" hash="Q9qA8Q">And what does it mean to find Him?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p12" pid="9HIsCOAQREGRJHrtJoHloQ" hash="j_wWZA">As we engage our faith and commit our energy to draw closer to Jesus Christ, we begin to understand more fully who He really is. As we seek Him diligently, we gain a deep and abiding testimony of His matchless love, His perfect life and example, and the blessings of His great atoning sacrifice. As we draw nearer to Him, we truly begin to find Him and to recognize Him as the Creator of the earth, the Redeemer of mankind, the Only Begotten of the Father, the King of kings, the Prince of Peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p13" pid="bTsZGRg8P0mgHDW8jwK7bQ" hash="ZX1pIg">The deeper we seek, the more we begin to appreciate His role as the Great Jehovah of the Old Testament and the Holy Messiah of the New Testament. We begin to understand more fully His eternal message of salvation and exaltation. We find that He continues to beckon us to come and follow Him, that His teachings are certain and are as applicable today as they were throughout all previous generations of time. We begin to know, with more profound appreciation, what occurred in Gethsemane and on Calvary. Although He was erroneously convicted and sentenced, He gave His life willingly; and in fulfillment of His own prophetic words, He was resurrected on the third day. This priceless gift brings immortality to all and eternal life to the obedient and faithful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p14" pid="duwlHkPP-EG34_YUuz8RFw" hash="hIJ8zQ">As we begin to realize that His message was and is for all mankind everywhere, we accept, with great enthusiasm, the scriptural account of His visit to the ancient inhabitants of the American continent. We delight in the coming forth of the Book of Mormon as a second witness—indeed another testament—of His messianic mission as the Savior and the Redeemer of the world. We acknowledge that a man can get closer to Him by searching and praying about the Book of Mormon than by studying any other book.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p15" pid="o-y3niM3Qk2sITrzrdZejg" hash="u9quZQ">As we seek to find Him, we receive a witness of His personal visit, together with His Father, to the boy prophet, Joseph Smith, ushering in the long-awaited “dispensation of the fulness of times.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p16" pid="fgC3dLDrUUGgaDeyfXQ5pg" hash="FkS65A">As we seek Him, we recognize that He has restored His Church to the earth, The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, that within His Church, He has bestowed the power and authority to provide essential ordinances that will permit us to return and live with Him once again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p17" pid="6TBTaq6vA0WrxxyIgNgLfw" hash="narb5w">As we seek Him, we find that He continues to guide His Church through His living prophet, President Gordon B. Hinckley, and that the organization of His Church is built upon the foundation of apostles and prophets, “Christ himself being the chief corner stone.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p18" pid="bYJYDuGiXE2HyLA_P9rlPQ" hash="NplRIQ">As we seek Him diligently, we feel His love for us and understand more clearly the answers to our prayers. We acknowledge that through His Spirit, we find “wisdom and great treasures of knowledge, even hidden treasures”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> and gain a greater desire to live our lives in accordance with His commandments and direction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p19" pid="odMCdoM50EaghfYuRv38IA" hash="isVmHw">As we seek Him, we find that He is “the light and the life of the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> As we seek Him, brothers and sisters, we shall indeed find Him and experience the inner peace He has promised us. I so testify, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2003/04/seek-and-ye-shall-find</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2003-general-conference/2003-04-2060-elder-craig-c-christensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="3432238" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2003 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Book with a Promise</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I pray that we will continue to use the Book of Mormon: Another Testament of Jesus Christ to share the gospel message with family and friends.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00009475_000_038" doc-version="2" hash="NSwINQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="1i7_Di6wnUSFurXba-BlQw" hash="x-h9nA">A Book with a Promise</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="v5EVzBpsrkaCWv2-8L16Mg" hash="4lelQg">Elder Craig C. Christensen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="TGo_lpI0p0CtpmdLLWC2mg" hash="JnswBQ">I pray that we will continue to use the Book of Mormon: Another Testament of Jesus Christ to share the gospel message with family and friends.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.p1" pid="3q1nwdMSh0SQbzBHk_HvSw" hash="4Tg2gg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="105"></span>My dear brothers and sisters, it has been a sacred privilege to join with you in sustaining President Thomas S. Monson, his counselors in the First Presidency, and the Twelve Apostles as prophets, seers, and revelators. I testify that prophets “speak as they are moved upon by the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.p2" pid="qVHO0PAXr0OLcUhcUvD1OA" hash="zw8LBg">“And whatsoever they shall speak when moved upon by the Holy Ghost shall be scripture, shall be the will of the Lord, … and the power of God unto salvation” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.3-4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:3–4</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.p3" pid="WLLcKeXHL0uFOBgNLEEFLQ" hash="IRBIUQ">As members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, we have the benefit and blessing of living scripture as declared by those sustained as prophets, as well as canonized scripture found in the Bible, the Book of Mormon, the Doctrine and Covenants, and the Pearl of Great Price. The prophet Nephi wrote, “My soul delighteth in the scriptures, and my heart pondereth them, and writeth them for the learning and the profit of my children” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/4.15" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 4:15</a>). Written scripture, especially the Book of Mormon, brings us to believe in God and “be reconciled unto him through the atonement of Christ, his Only Begotten Son” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.11" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:11</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.p4" pid="AYl2H1XJtk2AxBy9yx1Ewg" hash="o5ry1w">Several months ago a friend and I had the opportunity of presenting a set of scriptures to an associate who is not a member of the Church. Knowing that this might be a life-changing event for him—and for us—we took the time to have his name embossed on each volume. As we presented these sacred records to him, we could tell he was deeply moved by the significance and sincerity of our offering. For several minutes he examined each book without speaking, rubbing his hand on the cover and turning some of the pages.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.p5" pid="8smuzHDBWUeUApaHM5CJQA" hash="8CcG8Q">Recognizing the importance of the moment, we helped him turn to the title page of the Book of Mormon and began to explain that the Book of <span class="pageBreak" page-number="106"></span>Mormon was another testament, or witness, of Jesus Christ. He then asked a question that all missionary-minded members are anxious to hear: “Why do we need additional witnesses of Jesus Christ other than the Bible?” Rather than responding quickly, we asked him why he thought this might be important. His answer seemed even more inspired than his question. He suggested that since there appeared to be so many variations of the Bible and its teachings, we needed some kind of clarifying voice, something that would help us understand the Bible better. His observation opened the door for us to share our feelings and testimonies regarding both the Bible and the Book of Mormon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.p6" pid="S9r1gn1-qU2xJ8oQmfawwA" hash="Whe5Dw">We began by expressing our devotion and deep conviction to the doctrines and teachings of the Bible, especially the New Testament. Being able to read many of the Savior’s words as He taught the gospel during His earthly ministry strengthens us, helps us come to know Him, and teaches us that we can become more like Him. We then declared that, like the Bible, the Book of Mormon is additional evidence that God loves all of His children and has provided a way for us to return and live with Him once again. We spent the next hour or so reviewing many aspects of the Book of Mormon, including its history and divine origin. Allow me to share a few of the things we discussed.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="SNtV27MZ8kCb7VZAz8M1IA" hash="x-h9nA1">A Book with a Promise</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.p7" pid="VYF4QLiMi06W_t1doGIrsQ" hash="30Cofw">We first explained that the Book of Mormon is a book with a promise. Although its history is compelling by itself, it is a book of scriptural significance that should be received and read under the influence of the Holy Ghost. All who study and ponder its teachings are given a promise found in the last chapter of Moroni (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.3-4" class="scriptureRef">Moroni 10:3–4</a>) as well as in the introduction to the Book of Mormon, where we read: “We invite all men [and women] everywhere to read the Book of Mormon, to ponder in their hearts the message it contains, and then to ask God, the Eternal Father, in the name of Christ if the book is true. Those who pursue this course and ask in faith will gain a testimony of its truth and divinity by the power of the Holy Ghost.” We then spent several minutes teaching about prayer and how the Holy Ghost can speak to our hearts and confirm that the Book of Mormon is true.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="zlr85skk-02b5XmBxSFeqw" hash="QPylmg">A Book with a Purpose</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.p8" pid="TyA_MsyKTEGHCDBS3L9vcA" hash="jvo3Vg">Next we stated that the Book of Mormon is a book with a purpose. From the title page we read that the Book of Mormon was “written by way of commandment” and “by the spirit of prophecy and of revelation” to “come forth by the gift and power of God” to the convincing of each of us <span class="pageBreak" page-number="107"></span>“that Jesus is the Christ, the Eternal God.” In a personal expression of this purpose, Nephi, as one of the authors of the Book of Mormon, wrote, “The fulness of mine intent is that I may persuade men to come unto the God of Abraham, and the God of Isaac, and the God of Jacob, and be saved” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/6.4" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 6:4</a>).</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="rSiRIwVOyEmzSpgGAceIAw" hash="Vi5RrA">A Book That Teaches the Great Plan of Happiness</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.p9" pid="sRRJvhzIOk6FzipjB5AZ2g" hash="YH_bCw">Additionally, we explained that the Book of Mormon is a book that teaches “the great plan of happiness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/42.8" class="scriptureRef">Alma 42:8</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/42.5,13,31" class="scriptureRef">vv. 5, 13, 31</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/9" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 9</a>). In profound yet understandable terms, the Book of Mormon teaches the purpose of life, from whence we came, and what happens when we die. We learn of faith in Jesus Christ and His atoning sacrifice, of repentance, of the importance of baptism by immersion, and of the gift and power of the Holy Ghost. By studying and feasting upon the doctrines of the Book of Mormon, we gain “a perfect brightness of hope, and a love of God and of all men,” with a desire to “endure to the end” that we may “have eternal life” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.20" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 31:20</a>).</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="5wyWlqbx_U69Pa8OJchfBg" hash="Ue7MzA">A Book That Testifies That Jesus Is the Christ</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.p10" pid="_7orhC6e00G2_HawXKurTA" hash="DRcnzQ">Most importantly, we declared that the Book of Mormon is a book that testifies that Jesus is the Christ, the Savior of the world. Great prophets throughout the Book of Mormon have borne solemn witness that Jesus Christ is the Creator of the earth (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/3.8" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 3:8</a>), the Redeemer of mankind (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/5.9-12" class="scriptureRef">Helaman 5:9–12</a>), the Only Begotten of the Father (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/11.18-21" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 11:18–21</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.11" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:11</a>). These Book of Mormon prophets knew Him, as Abraham and Moses did, and received and taught His everlasting gospel. As we read and study their words, we gain a deeper understanding of the Savior’s matchless love, His perfect life and example, and the blessings of His great atoning sacrifice.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.t6">
        <h3 class="title" pid="1dRvLgSef0mOZ8UsMLXONw" hash="OeCnXw">A Book That Authenticates the Prophetic Mission of Joseph Smith</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.p11" pid="chzuxt1KrU-Cc41oGGiqeA" hash="dvCWxQ">We then testified that the Book of Mormon is tangible evidence that Joseph Smith was chosen by the hand of the Lord to restore the Church of Jesus Christ to the earth in these latter days. As stated in the introduction to the Book of Mormon, “Those who gain [a] divine witness from the Holy Spirit [of the divinity of the Book of Mormon] will also come to know by the same power that Jesus Christ is the Savior of the world, that Joseph Smith is his revelator and prophet in these last days, and that The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is the Lord’s kingdom once again established on the earth.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.p12" pid="cws2-2HDLUeHJ94KNBH2mg" hash="Ao580g">Ever since Samuel Smith set out to preach the gospel with a few first-edition copies, the Book of Mormon has blessed the lives of millions around the world. I pray that we will continue to use the Book of Mormon: Another Testament of Jesus Christ to share the gospel message with family and friends. If we do this, as was the case with our dear friend, many will respond with great interest to know more about the life and mission of the Savior and His great plan of happiness for each of us.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise.p13" pid="jhEkOJ0LjEGXquMnYDdBCQ" hash="B5NXlA">I express my solemn witness that the Book of Mormon is true. It is a book that has brought about a mighty change in my life. I know that God lives. Jesus is the Christ. His gospel has been restored to the earth. President Thomas S. Monson is His prophet and living oracle at this time. The Spirit I feel as I daily read, ponder, and pray about the Book of Mormon strengthens my understanding and testimony of these things and reaffirms to me that they are true. I humbly share this testimony and my personal witness with you in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2008/04/a-book-with-a-promise</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2008-general-conference/2008-04-5070-elder-craig-c-christensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="4077417" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Unspeakable Gift from God</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Holy Ghost works in perfect unity with Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ, fulfilling many important roles and distinct responsibilities.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10491_000_14christensen" doc-version="2" hash="Gq6-jg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="UwKL8CI_c0yUHTDX8edYZQ" hash="1QQ8ww">An Unspeakable Gift from God</h1><p class="authorName" pid="PUVCuA078ESKrJN9TcjR3A" hash="x8SLUA">By Elder Craig C. Christensen</p><p class="kicker" pid="UK6nrWSJGEyWV4eItcuopA" hash="A35urA">The Holy Ghost works in perfect unity with Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ, fulfilling many important roles and distinct responsibilities.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" pid="FgxzQZpOcEGoOanTcbGBlA" hash="4p30Tg">
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p5" pid="qY51n3L3akqReIihlBZXDQ" hash="dC4tQA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="12"></span>In 1994, President Howard W. Hunter invited all members of the Church to “establish the temple … as the great symbol of [our] membership.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Later that same year, construction on the Bountiful Utah Temple was completed. Like many, we were anxious to take our young family to the open house prior to the dedication. We labored diligently to prepare our children to enter the temple, praying earnestly that they would have a spiritual experience so that the temple would become a focal point in their lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p6" pid="G8dv2ha5IUeUPiNfnyMgSw" hash="UyXpNQ">As we reverently walked through the temple, I found myself admiring the magnificent architecture, the elegant finishes, the light shining through towering windows, and many of the inspiring paintings. Every aspect of this sacred building was truly exquisite.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p7" pid="DPYHBjOAL02PC9SppYPbrA" hash="Z-Kgdw">Stepping into the celestial room, I suddenly realized that our youngest son, six-year-old Ben, was clinging to my leg. He appeared anxious—perhaps even a little troubled.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p8" pid="eVGWHxel0UWv9vWRJWPovg" hash="3PQvnA">“What’s wrong, Son?” I whispered.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p9" pid="RdmQm6OoRUebcIZiJ3Tpvw" hash="TVgwIw">“Daddy,” he replied, “what’s happening here? I’ve never felt this way before.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p10" pid="2XYGRtOrvUqPmAc0ZzW0og" hash="MkCqvQ">Recognizing that this was likely the first time our young son had felt the influence of the Holy Ghost in such a powerful way, I knelt down on the floor next to him. While other visitors stepped around us, Ben and I spent several minutes, side by side, learning about the Holy Ghost together. I was amazed at the ease with which we were able to discuss his sacred feelings. As we talked, it became clear that what was most inspiring to Ben was not what he <span class="emphasis">saw</span> but what he <span class="emphasis">felt</span>—not the physical beauty around us but the still, small voice of the Spirit of God within his heart. I shared with him what I had learned from my own experiences, even as his childlike wonder reawakened in me a deep sense of gratitude for this unspeakable gift from God—the gift of the Holy Ghost.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
    </span>
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.t1">
      <h2 class="title" pid="NYs_x0_lDUCKlw3vSRXNqA" hash="xZrA5w">Who Is the Holy Ghost?</h2>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p12" pid="wFZXaIOTSkiaRuWECPJ8aw" hash="3z55EQ">The Holy Ghost is the third member of the Godhead, and, as such, like God the Father and Jesus Christ, He knows our thoughts and the intents of our hearts.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> The Holy Ghost loves us and wants us to be happy. Since He knows the challenges we will face, He <span class="pageBreak" page-number="13"></span>can guide us and teach us all things we must do to return and live with our Heavenly Father once again.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p13" pid="cb_3jmqzv0uqfcu72WXJEQ" hash="5WrwBw">Unlike Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ, who have glorified bodies of flesh and bones, the Holy Ghost is a personage of spirit who communicates to our spirits through feelings and impressions.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> As a spirit being, He has the unique responsibility of being an agent through which personal revelation is received. In scripture, the Holy Ghost is often referred to as the Holy Spirit, the Spirit of the Lord, the Holy Spirit of Promise, or simply the Spirit.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
    </div>
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.t2" pid="Tb5VDuZEa0KjUI5NNRGezA" hash="Pw3OnA">
      <h2 class="title" pid="R7cKZGrYDEiOlGWEthhftw" hash="FKYniw">What Is the Mission of the Holy Ghost?</h2>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p15" pid="TyR5zWG2iEyxxA_eLAIUCQ" hash="A_K1mw">The Holy Ghost works in perfect unity with Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ, fulfilling many important roles and distinct responsibilities. The primary purpose of the Holy Ghost is to bear witness of God the Father and of His Son, Jesus Christ,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> and to teach us the truth of all things.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> A sure witness from the Holy Ghost carries far more certainty than a witness from any other source. President Joseph Fielding Smith taught that “the Spirit of God speaking to the spirit of man has power to impart truth with greater effect and understanding than the truth can be imparted by personal contact even with heavenly beings.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p16" pid="b_kOEupvikOHpfprQJ0oIA" hash="4y8oIA">The Holy Ghost is also known as the Comforter.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> During times of trouble or despair or simply when we need to know that God is near, the Holy Ghost can lift our spirits, give us hope, and teach us “the peaceable things of the kingdom,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> helping us feel “the peace of God, which passeth all understanding.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <span class="story">
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p17" pid="Cq4caLo7DEa-aV-ywp5WlA" hash="2tSrRg">Several years ago as our extended family gathered for a holiday dinner, my father began playing games with many of his grandchildren. Suddenly and without warning, he collapsed and quickly passed away. This unexpected event could have been devastating, especially for his grandchildren, raising questions that are difficult to answer. However, as we gathered our children around us, as we prayed and read the words of Book of Mormon prophets about the purpose of life, the Holy Ghost comforted each of us personally. In ways that are difficult to describe with words, the answers we sought came clearly into our hearts. We felt a peace that day that truly surpassed <span class="emphasis">our</span> understanding, yet the witness from the Holy Ghost was certain, undeniable, and true.</p>
      </span>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p18" pid="zsJH92oFr0-1Pt-4JXHP2g" hash="lCpFIg">The Holy Ghost is a teacher and a revelator.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> As we study, ponder, and pray about gospel truths, the Holy Ghost enlightens our minds and quickens our understanding.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> He causes the truth to be indelibly written in our souls and can cause a mighty change to occur in our hearts. As we share these truths with our families, with fellow members of the Church, and with friends and neighbors in our community, the Holy Ghost becomes their teacher as well, for He carries the message of the gospel “unto the hearts of the children of men.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p19" pid="ZAXDGswib0WBZ0x0zPTHBQ" hash="VrqvTg">The Holy Ghost inspires us to reach out to others in service. For me, the most vivid examples of heeding the promptings of the Holy Ghost in the service of others come from <span class="pageBreak" page-number="14"></span>the life and ministry of President Thomas S. Monson, who said: “In the performance of our responsibilities, I have learned that when we heed a silent prompting and act upon it without delay, our Heavenly Father will guide our footsteps and bless our lives and the lives of others. I know of no experience more sweet or feeling more precious than to heed a prompting only to discover that the Lord has answered another person’s prayer through you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
      <span class="story">
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p20" pid="um74lqZlqk-3cFQS2YoDlg" hash="dZDbHQ">I share just one tender experience. While President Monson was serving as a bishop, he learned that a member of his ward, Mary Watson, was in the hospital. As he went to visit her, he learned that she was staying in a large room with several other patients. When he approached Sister Watson, he noticed that the patient in a neighboring bed quickly covered her head.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p21" pid="U2AHqdxT7kqhTZKlkJ6L8A" hash="h-MtWQ">After President Monson had visited with Sister Watson and given her a priesthood blessing, he shook her hand, said good-bye, and prepared to leave. Then a simple but amazing thing happened. I quote now from President Monson’s own recollection of this experience:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p22" pid="kXpxH2jUZ0S-kH1i63VNow" hash="FqLs8g">“I could not leave her side. It was as though an unseen hand [was] resting on my shoulder, and I felt within my soul that I was hearing these words: ‘Go over to the next bed where the little lady covered her face when you came in.’ I did so. …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p23" pid="G0AvjXeTA0qux_IVTAi8yg" hash="9YYQjA">“I approached the bedside of the other patient, gently tapped her shoulder and carefully pulled back the sheet which had covered her face. Lo and behold! She, too, was a member of my ward. I had not known she was a patient in the hospital. Her name was Kathleen McKee. When her eyes met mine, she exclaimed through her tears, ‘Oh, Bishop, when you entered that door, I felt you had come to see me and bless me in response to my prayers. I was rejoicing inside to think that you would know I was here, but when you stopped at the other bed, my heart sank, and I knew that you had not come to see me.’</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p24" pid="j_1Rkn-oaEqvOmqbFt7myw" hash="ibTszw">“I said to [Sister] McKee: ‘It does not matter that I didn’t know you were here. It is important, however, that our Heavenly Father knew and that you had prayed silently for a priesthood blessing. It was He who prompted me to intrude on your privacy.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
      </span>
    </div>
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.t3">
      <h2 class="title" pid="LeAyX38PrkSvED0Jxh1sFA" hash="qzXhKg">How Does the Holy Ghost Speak to Us?</h2>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p26" pid="bD2_q7YQVE6LjjecoWTX2g" hash="1I8nKA">We all have experiences with the Holy Ghost, even though we may not always recognize them. As inspired thoughts come into our minds, we know them to be true by the spiritual feelings that enter into our hearts. President Boyd K. Packer has taught: “The Holy Ghost speaks with a voice that you <span class="emphasis">feel</span> more than you <span class="emphasis">hear.</span> … While we speak of ‘listening’ to the whisperings of the Spirit, most often one describes a spiritual prompting by saying, ‘I had a <span class="emphasis">feeling</span> …’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> It is through these sacred feelings from the Holy Ghost that we come to know what God would have us do, for this, as stated in scripture, “is the spirit of revelation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
    </div>
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.t4">
      <h2 class="title" pid="0OHl-ybkOEqhp0hdLXgLdw" hash="vzM8Zg">What Does It Mean to Receive the Gift of the Holy Ghost?</h2>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p28" pid="BmO6_02pvEOOYULSCTRyig" hash="TUE4tw">In teaching our six-year-old son, Ben, I thought it important to differentiate between what he was feeling, which was the influence of the Holy Ghost, and the gift of the Holy Ghost, which he would receive after baptism. Before baptism, all honest and sincere seekers of truth can feel the influence of the Holy Ghost from time to time. However, the opportunity to receive the constant companionship of the Holy Ghost and the <span class="emphasis">fulness</span> of all the associated blessings is available only to worthy, baptized members who receive the gift of the Holy Ghost by the laying on of hands through those holding the priesthood authority of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p29" pid="7OpAvQNAJEa_ZjSGDQdgvw" hash="G5ZKFg">Through the gift of the Holy Ghost, we receive added capacity and spiritual gifts, increased revelation and protection, steady guidance and direction, and the promised blessings of sanctification and exaltation in the celestial kingdom. All of these blessings are given as a result of our personal desire to receive them and come as we align our lives with the will of God and seek His constant direction.</p>
    </div>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p30" pid="6yQI2Kz1iECeeRZkHqQi8w" hash="pNxxcw">As I reflect back on my experience with Ben in the Bountiful Utah Temple, I have many sweet feelings and impressions. One clear recollection is that while I was absorbed in the grandeur of what I could see, a small child near my side was recognizing the powerful feelings in his heart. With a gentle reminder, I was <span class="pageBreak" page-number="15"></span>invited not only to pause and kneel down but also to heed the Savior’s call to become as a little child—humble, meek, and ready to hear the still, small voice of His Spirit.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god.p31" pid="5OvnenXcS0yJ71AjGLUNOw" hash="4mFDsw">I bear witness of the living reality and divine mission of the Holy Ghost and that by the power of the Holy Ghost, we may know the truth of all things. I testify that the gift of the Holy Ghost is Heavenly Father’s precious and unspeakable gift to all who will come unto His Son, be baptized in His name, and receive the Holy Ghost through confirmation in His Church. Of these sacred truths I bear personal witness in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2012/10/an-unspeakable-gift-from-god</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2012-general-conference/2012-10-1040-elder-craig-c-christensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5259688" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Know These Things of Myself</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Craig C. Christensen encourages priesthood holders to develop their own testimony of the gospel of Jesus Christ and of the Restoration.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10991_000_32christensen" doc-version="6" hash="ejgGcA">
			
			<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.head1">
				<h1 class="title" pid="A_aGCf-B70miRrSi8rSC5w" hash="gcXUrg">I Know These Things of Myself</h1>
				<div class="byline">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p2" pid="r7iUcMgUqU-ysjJD5YfL8Q" hash="x8SLUA">By Elder Craig C. Christensen</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p3" pid="bsMQma9T5EK0AV9kyQC6Hg" hash="hptprg">Of the Presidency of the Seventy</p>
					<a href="gl://image/?pid=jbL1B09XiEuvNLAKxhnQHg"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255504/00263332f5ca4d05b2928c2b71d6fe4f/100x125.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x62="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255504/00263332f5ca4d05b2928c2b71d6fe4f/50x62.jpg" data-src-100x125="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255504/00263332f5ca4d05b2928c2b71d6fe4f/100x125.jpg" data-src-200x251="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255504/00263332f5ca4d05b2928c2b71d6fe4f/200x251.jpg" data-src-320x401="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255504/00263332f5ca4d05b2928c2b71d6fe4f/320x401.jpg" data-src-460x577="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255504/00263332f5ca4d05b2928c2b71d6fe4f/460x577.jpg" data-src-640x803="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255504/00263332f5ca4d05b2928c2b71d6fe4f/640x803.jpg" data-src-1024x1286="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255504/00263332f5ca4d05b2928c2b71d6fe4f/1024x1286.jpg" data-src-2048x2572="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255504/00263332f5ca4d05b2928c2b71d6fe4f/2048x2572.jpg" data-src-3717x4669="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255504/00263332f5ca4d05b2928c2b71d6fe4f/3717x4669.jpg" altText="Elder Craig C. Christensen" pid="jbL1B09XiEuvNLAKxhnQHg" hash="3lf_9A"></img></a>
				</div>
				<p class="kicker" pid="jFHG4aIiuEKHOu7KvYDwzg" hash="9jgo6Q">Learning for ourselves that the restored gospel of Jesus Christ is true can be one of the greatest and most joyful experiences in life.</p>
			<p class="authorName" pid="Gse2TFuJdUKeY7cDmmWt4w" hash="x8SLUA1">By Elder Craig C. Christensen</p></div>
			<div class="bodyBlock">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p5" pid="oQsWoKyOuE2DP-72Y7QYyg" hash="MLoZHA">My dear brethren, we are continually inspired by the personal example and priesthood service of President Thomas S. Monson. Recently, several deacons were asked, “What do you admire most about President Monson?” One deacon recalled how President Monson, as a child, gave his toys to needy friends. Another mentioned how President Monson cared for the many widows in his ward. A third noted that he was called as an Apostle at a very young age and has blessed people all around the world. Then one young man said, “The thing I admire most about President Monson is his strong testimony.”</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p6" pid="y_R5BnR5O0CUal39UbhW_g" hash="C06Xxg">Indeed, we have all felt our prophet’s special witness of the Savior Jesus Christ and his commitment to always follow the promptings of the Spirit. With each experience he shares, President Monson invites us to live the gospel more fully and to seek for and strengthen our own personal testimonies. Remember what he said from this pulpit just a few conferences ago: “In order for us to be strong and to withstand all the forces pulling us in the wrong direction … , we must have our own testimony. Whether you are 12 or 112—or anywhere in between—you can know for yourself that the gospel of Jesus Christ is true.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p7" pid="C0_n6qR9-E6des6mrJEc3w" hash="RqOq0g">Although my message tonight is directed to those who are closer to 12 than 112, the principles I share apply to everyone. In response to President Monson’s statement, I would ask: Does each of us know for ourselves that the gospel is true? Can we say with confidence that our testimonies are truly our own? To quote President Monson again: “I maintain that a strong testimony of our Savior and of His gospel will … protect you from the sin and evil around you. … If you do not already have a testimony of these things, do that which is necessary to obtain one. It is essential for you to have your own testimony, for the testimonies of others will carry you only so far.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
				<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.t1">
					<h2 pid="Rx2APUWICEedA4Sl8vUxUw" hash="gcXUrg1">I Know These Things of Myself</h2>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p9" pid="apyFUG1Uy0SMnmMHZMbLFA" hash="o1VMnA">Learning for ourselves that the restored gospel of Jesus Christ is true can be one of the greatest and most joyful experiences in life. We may have to begin by relying on the testimonies of others—saying, as the stripling warriors did, “We do not doubt our mothers knew it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> This is a good place to start, but we must build from there. To be strong in living the gospel, there is nothing more important than receiving and strengthening our own testimony. We must be able to declare, as Alma did, “I … know these things of myself.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p10" pid="nbmO23s3BkScyOfiAqS-mQ" hash="QOplbg">“And how do ye suppose that I know of their surety?” Alma continued. “Behold, I say unto you they are made known unto me by the Holy Spirit of God. Behold, I have fasted and prayed many days that I might know these things of myself. And now I do know of myself that they are true.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
				</div>
				<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.t2">
					<h2 pid="yKzLqHAG7UKwMk1Ngvf9Jw" hash="Zck7Zg">I Desire to Behold the Things Which My Father Saw</h2>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p12" pid="-ezhCuVAYUOkpRGr4MJRTg" hash="UXDL5Q">Like Alma, Nephi also came to know the truth for himself. After listening to his father speak of his many spiritual experiences, Nephi wanted to know what his father knew. This was more than simple curiosity—it was something he hungered and thirsted after. Even though he was “exceedingly young,” he had “great desires to know of the mysteries of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> He yearned to “see, and hear, and know of these things, by the power of the Holy Ghost.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p13" pid="_Exo99Nf5U-MOHVZLi6CCA" hash="YSnv7g">As Nephi “sat pondering in [his] heart,” he was carried “away in the Spirit … into an exceedingly high mountain,” where he was asked, “What desirest thou?” His response was simple: “I desire to behold the things which my father saw.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Because of his believing heart and his diligent efforts, Nephi was blessed with a marvelous experience. He received a witness of the forthcoming birth, life, and Crucifixion of the Savior Jesus Christ; he saw the coming forth of the Book of Mormon and the Restoration of the gospel in the last days—all as a result of his sincere desire to know for himself.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p14" pid="NMX7r1-Nx0uaeUDoVkgO7Q" hash="tckLLg">These personal experiences with the Lord prepared Nephi for the adversity and challenges he would soon face. They enabled him to stand strong even when others in his family were struggling. He could do this because he had <span class="emphasis">learned</span> for himself and he <span class="emphasis">knew</span> for himself. He had been blessed with his own testimony.</p>
				</div>
				<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.t3">
					<h2 pid="JGs0AeFdj0yvx_g2hnq6gw" hash="ACbakw">Let Him Ask of God</h2>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p16" pid="nDC1EzePTUyrqgeqmWYoaQ" hash="A18EWQ">Similar to Nephi, the Prophet Joseph Smith was also “exceedingly young” when his “mind was called up to serious reflection” about spiritual truths. For Joseph, it was a time of “great uneasiness,” being surrounded by conflicting and confusing messages about religion. He wanted to know which church was right.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Inspired by these words in the Bible, “If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask of God,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> he acted for himself to find an answer. On a beautiful morning in the spring of 1820, he entered a grove of trees and knelt in prayer. Because of his faith and because God had a special work for him to do, Joseph received a glorious vision of God the Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, and learned for himself what he was to do.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p17" pid="DX90BBXscEC0JWyqv23kbg" hash="W02PEg">Do you see in Joseph’s experience a pattern you could apply in gaining or strengthening your own testimony? Joseph allowed the scriptures to penetrate his heart. He pondered them deeply and applied them to his own situation. He then acted on what he had learned. The result was the glorious First Vision—and everything that came after it. This Church quite literally was founded on the principle that anyone—including a 14-year-old farm boy—can “ask of God” and receive an answer to his prayers.</p>
				</div>
				<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.t4">
					<h2 pid="Kv5n6MWX0Ui4E-jD5MJYjA" hash="mL1MgQ">So What Is a Testimony?</h2>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p19" pid="m7p35yvIgEm55VYvUPLzfQ" hash="4RuB2A">We often hear members of the Church say that their testimony of the gospel is their most prized possession. It is a sacred gift from God that comes to us by the power of the Holy Ghost. It is the calm, unwavering certainty we receive as we study, pray, and live the gospel. It is the feeling of the Holy Ghost bearing witness to our souls that what we are learning and doing is right.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p20" pid="n8Z7vb1RDEiHGfam-n6vgQ" hash="QQFN_g">Some people speak of a testimony as if it were a light switch—it’s either on or off; you either have a testimony, or you do not. In reality, a testimony is more like a tree that passes through various stages of growth and development. Some of the tallest trees on earth are found in Redwood National Park in the western United States. When you stand at the base of these massive trees, it is amazing to think that each one grew from a tiny seed. So it is with our testimonies. Although they may begin with a single spiritual experience, they grow and develop over time through constant nourishment and frequent spiritual encounters.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p21" pid="yBi09wCxsEirG7fpoOn5Tg" hash="W-f2sA">It’s not surprising, then, that when the prophet Alma explained how we develop a testimony, he spoke of a seed growing into a tree. “If ye give place,” he said, “that a seed may be planted in your heart, behold, if it be a true seed, or a good seed, if ye do not cast it out by your unbelief, … it will begin to swell within your breasts; and when you feel these swelling motions, ye will begin to say within yourselves—It must needs be that this is a good seed, or that the word is good, for it beginneth to enlarge my soul; yea, it beginneth to enlighten my understanding, yea, it beginneth to be delicious to me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p22" pid="IjesVZmrLUOTfVc28agjTQ" hash="sem08g">This is often how a testimony begins: with sacred, enlightening, assuring feelings that demonstrate to us that the word of God is true. However, as wonderful as these feelings are, they are only the beginning. Your work to grow your testimony is not done—any more than the work of growing a redwood tree is done when the first tiny sprout pokes out of the ground. If we ignore or neglect these early spiritual promptings, if we do not nurture them by continuing to study the scriptures and pray and by seeking more experiences with the Spirit, our feelings will fade and our testimonies will diminish.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p23" pid="mAMau4JpC0WFrKgX_lR6wQ" hash="TfBz8A">As Alma put it: “If ye neglect the tree, and take no thought for its nourishment, behold it will not get any root; and when the heat of the sun cometh and scorcheth it, because it hath no root it withers away, and ye pluck it up and cast it out.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p24" pid="JJrQ7tFn20Ks75IMaF6fJA" hash="HQXbuw">In most cases, our testimonies will grow the same way a tree grows: gradually, almost imperceptibly, as a result of our constant care and diligent efforts. “But if ye will nourish the word,” Alma promised, “yea, nourish the tree as it beginneth to grow, by your faith with great diligence, and with patience, looking forward to the fruit thereof, it shall take root; and behold it shall be a tree springing up unto everlasting life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
				</div>
				<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.t5">
					<h2 pid="OCf6AWFfPUyvpqfFBM5BMw" hash="B1cNOw">Now Is the Time; Today Is the Day</h2>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p26" pid="-ZvWrP2ZZEi5KEGP3TT8Rw" hash="Iq38hA">My own testimony began as I studied and pondered the teachings found in the Book of Mormon. As I knelt down to ask God in humble prayer, the Holy Ghost testified to my soul that what I was reading was true. This early witness became the catalyst for my testimony of many other gospel truths, for, as President Monson taught: “When we know the Book of Mormon is true, then it follows that Joseph Smith was indeed a prophet and that he saw God the Eternal Father and His Son, Jesus Christ. It also follows that the gospel was restored in these latter days through Joseph Smith—including the restoration of both the Aaronic and Melchizedek Priesthoods.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> Since that day, I have had many sacred experiences with the Holy Ghost that have reaffirmed to me that Jesus Christ is the Savior of the world and that His restored gospel is true. With Alma, I can say with certainty that I know these things of myself.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p27" pid="mIgIJN0DdEWGsERMuzFLrw" hash="_75kzg">My young friends, now is the time and today is the day to learn or reaffirm for ourselves that the gospel is true. Each of us has an important work to do. To accomplish that work, and to be protected from worldly influences that seem to be constantly looming, we must have the faith of Alma, Nephi, and young Joseph Smith to obtain and develop our own testimony.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself.p28" pid="YCwCT8CXhEuViYYS3xY7AA" hash="phTsMw">Like the young deacon I spoke of earlier, I admire President Monson for his testimony. It is like a towering redwood, yet even President Monson’s testimony had to grow and develop over time. We can come to know for ourselves, just as President Monson has, that Jesus Christ is our Savior and the Redeemer of the world, that Joseph Smith is the prophet of the Restoration, including the restoration of the priesthood of God. We bear that holy priesthood. May we learn these things and know them for ourselves is my humble prayer in the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
				</div>
			</div>
			
		</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/10/i-know-these-things-of-myself</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2014-general-conference/2014-10-3020-elder-craig-c-christensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5728516" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“A Choice Seer Will I Raise Up”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Christensen reminds us that through Joseph Smith’s foretold mission as Prophet of the Restoration, we enjoy the fruits and blessings of the Restoration.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60001311_000_24christensen" doc-version="1" hash="AReJuQ">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="URctGlvq1kG1C2_8KKBHdg" hash="Z_4Wmw">“A Choice Seer Will I Raise Up”</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p2" pid="Mw41ZtIfjU-P75pR2nMCDA" hash="x8SLUA1">By Elder Craig C. Christensen</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p3" pid="FLEBgOhyk0uwc9_SR1v_1g" hash="hptprg">Of the Presidency of the Seventy</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="z8N5r9wyL0qj9dG3fvh1JQ" hash="eL0y0w">Because Joseph was a prophet, we have more than a window into heaven—the very doorway to the eternities is open to us.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="Utua25CONUuH9zkaNQayZA" hash="x8SLUA">By Elder Craig C. Christensen</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p5" pid="ZcegI1AhukuouUlIxPLvYw" hash="DxCM6g">When Moroni first came to Joseph Smith, he warned that Joseph’s “name should be had for good and evil among all nations.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> We have seen the fulfillment of that prophecy. In the war between good and evil, the Restoration of the gospel through the Prophet Joseph Smith has both inspired believers who follow him and also provoked antagonists who fight furiously against the cause of Zion and against Joseph himself. This battle is not new. It began soon after young Joseph walked into the Sacred Grove and continues today with added visibility on the internet.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p6" pid="_Ijvu0p3zU-ORVC7Sw1UYg" hash="ShnrXw">The Lord personally declared to Joseph Smith:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p7" pid="upKoS9E38E2zIecCFOMJbg" hash="T8LrmQ">“The ends of the earth shall inquire after thy name, and fools shall have thee in derision, and hell shall rage against thee;</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p8" pid="dKfv_o83mECndRbkqVc3qQ" hash="thXcow">“While the pure in heart, and the wise, and the noble, and the virtuous, shall seek counsel, and authority, and blessings constantly from under thy hand.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p9" pid="FDtzaOm4XUSbMwPUu8PA7w" hash="cC0Dxg">Today I offer my testimony to all who seek to better understand the sacred mission of Joseph Smith Jr., the Prophet of the Restoration.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p10" pid="eodlrGZG802uLhe-6_oxjQ" hash="fRaVdQ">We need not be timid about testifying of Joseph’s mission as prophet, seer, and revelator, for the Lord has always worked through prophets.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Because of the truths restored through Joseph Smith, we know much more about our Heavenly Father and the Savior Jesus Christ. We know of Their divine attributes, Their relationship to each other and to us, and the great plan of redemption that allows us to return to Their presence.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p11" pid="LBZRjiWwe0qs8ePiYJurhg" hash="v2adIA">Of Joseph, President Brigham Young declared: “It was decreed in the councils of eternity, long before the foundations of the earth were laid, that he should be the man, in the last dispensation of this world, to bring forth the word of God to the people and receive the fullness of the keys and power of the Priesthood of the Son of God. The Lord had his eye upon him … [for he] was foreordained in eternity to preside over this last dispensation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p12" pid="eGQao-rMR0K6e1CmIjONLQ" hash="z6adBA">In preparation for this great work, Joseph Smith was born into a loving family who experienced many of the everyday burdens and trials of life. As Joseph began to mature, his feelings toward God “were deep and often poignant,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> yet he was confused by conflicting religious ideas taught by the preachers of his day. Fortunately, young Joseph did not let his questions paralyze his faith. He sought answers in the Bible and found this counsel: “If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask of God, that giveth to all men liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p13" pid="ucOdhpGMSkGfbk1uYWrvTQ" hash="fF5Crg">Joseph recalled: “Never did any passage of scripture come with more power to the heart of man than this did at this time to mine. It seemed to enter with great force into every feeling of my heart. I reflected on it again and again.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p14" pid="-49ItBbAyEWZtSF9cita8Q" hash="iTQ5pg">With simple faith, Joseph acted on these spiritual feelings. He found a secluded place, knelt down, “and began to offer up the desires of [his] heart to God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> There is great power in Joseph’s description of what happened:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p15" pid="7lMeqbfZDEWkrRlmUD6ndg" hash="U_btDw">“I saw a pillar of light exactly over my head, above the brightness of the sun, which descended gradually until it fell upon me.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p16" pid="qP-h-u84I06e8kOaZEK09w" hash="-yaiEQ">“… When the light rested upon me I saw two Personages, whose brightness and glory defy all description, standing above me in the air. One of them spake unto me, calling me by name and said, pointing to the other—<span class="emphasis">This is My Beloved Son</span>.<span class="emphasis"> Hear Him!</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p17" pid="ZRAhgNsQF0Oc4uEIIq0e_w" hash="j5IjRg">Joseph Smith saw God, the Eternal Father, and Jesus Christ, the Savior and Redeemer of the world. This was Joseph’s <span class="emphasis">First</span> Vision. In the years that followed, Joseph translated the Book of Mormon by the gift and power of God. Numerous other heavenly beings visited him, restoring truths and authority that had been lost for centuries. These divine communications to Joseph Smith opened the windows of heaven and the glories of eternity to our view. Joseph’s life stands as a testimony that if any of us lack wisdom, we can ask God in faith and receive answers—sometimes from heavenly beings but more often by the power of the Holy Ghost, who speaks to us through inspired thoughts and feelings.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> It is through the Holy Ghost that we can “know the truth of all things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p18" pid="RkYDgyq6_0a_Albz6mTdrg" hash="cY0c3g">For many of us, a witness of the Prophet Joseph Smith begins as we read the Book of Mormon. I first read the Book of Mormon from cover to cover as a young early-morning seminary student. With my vivid boyish imagination, I decided to read as if I were Joseph Smith, discovering the truths in the Book of Mormon for the very first time. It had such an impact on my life that I continue to read the Book of Mormon in that way. I often find that doing so deepens my appreciation for the Prophet Joseph and for the truths restored in this precious book.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p19" pid="2pl8WzsXdECcUXYacUseLw" hash="tOhvZg">For example, imagine Joseph’s feelings as he translated passages about baptism for the remission of sins. Joseph, who had been told not to join any of the existing churches, naturally had questions about this saving ordinance. His questions led him, once again, to pray, and that prayer led to a visit from John the Baptist, who restored the Aaronic Priesthood and the authority to baptize.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p20" pid="W8P2t7f3jkGjkirdWunWVQ" hash="1kW5lQ">Or consider how Joseph might have felt when he learned for the first time that Jesus Christ visited the people of the Western Hemisphere—that He taught them, prayed for them, healed their sick, blessed their children, conferred priesthood authority, and administered the sacrament unto them.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> Joseph may not have realized it at the time, but what he learned about the ordinances and organization of Christ’s ancient Church prepared him to later assist the Lord in restoring that same Church to the earth.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p21" pid="pxu_Hi8VYEef4k-zcimP5Q" hash="5WwDsw">During the translation of the Book of Mormon, Joseph and his wife Emma mourned the death of their infant son. In those days preachers commonly taught that children who died without baptism would be condemned forever. With this in mind, imagine how Joseph must have felt as he translated these words from the prophet Mormon: “Little children need no repentance, neither baptism. … [For] little children are alive in Christ, even from the foundation of the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p22" pid="RB2yPO90s0ilkT8bNL8OcA" hash="P640Ow">Perhaps the most stunning passage in the Book of Mormon to young Joseph may have been the <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/3" class="scriptureRef">third chapter of 2 Nephi</a>. This chapter contains an ancient prophecy about a “choice seer” whom the Lord would raise up in the latter days—a seer named Joseph, named after his father. This future prophet would be “esteemed highly” and would do a work “of great worth” unto his people. He would “be great like unto Moses” and would be given “power to bring forth [God’s] word.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> Consider how Joseph Smith must have felt as he realized that this prophecy was about <span class="emphasis">him</span>! He was not just translating history; he was translating a vision of the last days, of the miraculous Restoration of the gospel of Jesus Christ—<span class="emphasis">and Joseph himself would help fulfill it!</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p23" pid="gF8-Gk-LL0SmS_6fm8uxaQ" hash="vlY6rQ">Today, almost 200 years later, it’s easy to see how this prophecy has been realized. We know about the great things Joseph accomplished as the Lord’s prophet. But remember that when Joseph translated this prophecy, he had done few of the things the prophets foretold. He was still a young man in his early 20s. The Church had not yet been organized. There were no wards or branches, no missionaries, and no temples. Hardly anyone had heard of Joseph Smith, and some of those who had, actively opposed him. Now look at the great work the Lord has wrought by the hand of His servant Joseph, notwithstanding the opposition against him. Is not the fulfillment of this prophecy compelling evidence of the prophetic calling of Joseph Smith?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p24" pid="krTdSyy2P0645aZLRDbKnA" hash="8AG55Q">To any who may be questioning their testimony of Joseph Smith or are struggling with erroneous, misleading, or superficial information about his life and ministry, I invite you to consider the fruits—the many blessings that have come to us through the miraculous mission of Joseph Smith, the Prophet of the Restoration.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p25" pid="9Hv_CPYrT02BH_hXgq-0Qg" hash="VOR_ew">Because Joseph was a prophet, revelations and prophets are no longer a thing of the past. The “day of miracles”—of visions, healings, and ministering of angels—has not ceased.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p26" pid="XKR8QRDUHkOovVQmqvmDYA" hash="-AbbZQ">Because Joseph was a prophet, each of us has access to the power and blessings of the holy priesthood, including baptism, the gift of the Holy Ghost, and the sacrament.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p27" pid="WerXfs2UWUSBc1xVjtdXAA" hash="qm_yPQ">Because Joseph was a prophet, we have the blessings and ordinances of the temple that bind us to God, make us His people, and manifest to us “the power of godliness,” making it possible one day to “see the face of God, even the Father, and live.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p28" pid="QxQQQLJREkW5UTxJna4XDA" hash="Xp_Jyg">Because Joseph was a prophet, we know that marriage and family are an essential part of God’s plan for our happiness. We know that through temple ordinances and covenants, our cherished family relationships can endure eternally.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p29" pid="lki67zRp_0CMLVwgrkR5mg" hash="z54iIQ">Because Joseph was a prophet, we have more than a window into heaven—the very doorway to the eternities is open to us. We can know “the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom [He has] sent.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> Eternal life can be ours.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up.p30" pid="8Pam2y1WQkmyB-bPEoXhXA" hash="qshaGA">Most of all, because Joseph was a prophet, we have witness upon witness, testimony upon testimony, that Jesus Christ is the Son of God and Savior of the world. We have an unbroken chain of special witnesses of Jesus Christ, including our prophet today, President Thomas S. Monson; the counselors in the First Presidency; and the members of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles. To their witnesses, I add my humble yet certain testimony: Jesus Christ lives and leads His Church. Joseph Smith was and is the Prophet of the Restoration. The priesthood and authority of God are again on the earth. May we fearlessly declare our witness and our gratitude for this wonderful prophet, seer, and revelator of the Lord is my prayer in the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/10/a-choice-seer-will-i-raise-up</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2016-general-conference/2016-10-1040-craig-c-christensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5772945" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
