<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Craig A. Cardon</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Craig A. Cardon.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Craig%20A.%20Cardon.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Craig A. Cardon.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Moving Closer to Him</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The priesthood, through the workings of the Spirit, moves individuals closer to God through ordination, ordinances, and refinement of individual natures.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006562_000_036" doc-version="2" hash="LRJRkQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="xDrUN8CEHka7CDHnclUBLQ" hash="wpRXEQ">Moving Closer to Him</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="z1I7V8-q50Kt890krrTY2Q" hash="s7LK1A">Craig A. Cardon</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="fE9UbR2Phk--PBSV3_G7Nw" hash="duBFFQ">The priesthood, through the workings of the Spirit, moves individuals closer to God through ordination, ordinances, and refinement of individual natures.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/CardonCA_06.jpg" alt="Elder Craig A. Cardon" pid="jkcOJrHEu02ci7ENZVdySg" hash="wEj0bw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p1" pid="Sjp-GBjAVUaXYq1xzKpfQA" hash="GeQA0A">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="94"></span>Years ago our young family moved into a home on what was then the edge of development in our community, which afforded a view of the mountains to the east. One Monday morning, just as I finished dressing and was ready to rush out the door to work, our six-year-old son, Craig, came bringing his four-year-old brother, Andrew, into the room by the hand. With determination Craig looked up at me and said, “Dad, yesterday in Primary my teacher told us that if you hold the priesthood, you can move mountains. I told Andy this, and he doesn’t believe me. You hold the priesthood, right, Dad?” Then turning his little body and pointing out the window, he looked back at me and said, “See those mountains over there? Show him, Dad!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p2" pid="3SmUZsg4P06kfnRXhZX8lg" hash="jnY9rg">What followed was a sweet experience. How grateful I was for young sons who were beginning a lifetime of learning about the priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p3" pid="vlGIJKZVhk6dm8pZnYIlow" hash="1ur-KA">While the Lord truly taught those to whom He had given the priesthood that by faith mountains would move<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span>—and there are recorded instances of such<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span>—my hope is to bring greater understanding to that aspect of the doctrine of the priesthood which <span class="emphasis">moves individuals</span> closer to God, affording them the opportunity to become like Him and live eternally in His presence. This doctrine involves both the sons and the daughters of God. Accordingly, I pray that what I share will be of help to both.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p4" pid="KkozZnt_4UaCFQBoE8CPbQ" hash="FqkldQ">In 1823 the angel Moroni appeared to Joseph Smith and quoted several scriptures, including the following from Malachi: “Behold, I will reveal unto you the Priesthood, by the hand of Elijah the prophet.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> This first recorded reference to priesthood in this dispensation anticipated a process that would unfold in the decades to come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p5" pid="CRYKcDdIEUShNHCFS81anQ" hash="a7bWrQ">In 1829 John the Baptist restored the Aaronic Priesthood,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> followed <span class="pageBreak" page-number="95"></span>shortly thereafter by Peter, James, and John restoring the Melchizedek Priesthood.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p6" pid="nEh6QaThdUCQo5hXagprsA" hash="LEPzag">In 1836 Moses and Elias restored the keys of the gathering of Israel and of the dispensation of the gospel of Abraham,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> followed then by Elijah restoring the keys of sealing. The revelation then concludes with Elijah telling the Prophet Joseph, “Therefore, the keys of this dispensation are committed into your hands.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p7" pid="JE_iRfyeqEGMmIiAlZijUw" hash="3AxUDw">With all priesthood authority, offices, and keys again on earth, in 1841 the Lord emphasized to the Prophet the importance of building temples where the Lord could make available to His children priesthood ordinances by which His sons and daughters would be prepared to return to His presence.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p8" pid="nQKYKbHRzki0B_SxSgFZzQ" hash="orrC8Q">He declared: “Let this house be built … that I may reveal mine ordinances therein unto <span class="emphasis">my people;</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p9" pid="IjPFQZzgnUekm7VTkl6xow" hash="Mq4zJw">“For I deign to reveal … things that pertain to the dispensation of the fulness of times.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p10" pid="TzaISbmC5kqRA2N-xl9x-A" hash="-oE7Ig">Earlier in Kirtland the Lord had taught the Prophet Joseph about the oath and covenant of the priesthood, explaining the conditions by which promised blessings are realized.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> In Nauvoo understanding grew as to the eternal scope and power of the priesthood<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> in blessing all His faithful children, whether in this life or the next.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> While the priesthood is given to worthy sons of God, His daughters are also a part of His people to whom He reveals His priesthood ordinances. And the promised blessing of “all that [the] Father hath”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> is available to both men and women who exercise faith in Jesus Christ, receive the ordinances, and endure in faith to the end. “Therefore, in the ordinances [of the Melchizedek Priesthood], the power of godliness is manifest.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p11" pid="GRvkUtw6HUagfpqkZ_3HNg" hash="Pa_HcQ">The crowning temple ordinance is available only to a man <span class="emphasis">and</span> a woman when they are sealed together, forming an eternal family unit. It is by virtue of this and all other priesthood ordinances that the families of the earth shall be blessed.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> This sealing ordinance is so central to the Lord’s purposes that He has promised to the faithful who are not sealed in this life through no fault of their own this blessing in the life to come.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> No other doctrine in all of religion better confirms God’s commensurate love for both His sons <span class="emphasis">and</span> His daughters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p12" pid="tRdJwbE_DEizu1MQY0YbUw" hash="NYP0Ag">The priesthood also has the power to change our very natures. As Paul wrote, “All those who are ordained unto this priesthood are made like unto the Son of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> This likeness is not only in ordination and ordinance but also in the perfecting of individual hearts, something that occurs “in process of time”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> as we “[yield] to the enticings of the Holy Spirit, and [put] off the natural man.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> When a man is ordained to the Melchizedek Priesthood, he enters into an “order”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> by which he may be refined through service to others, especially his own family, and blessed by the constant companionship of the Holy Ghost.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p13" pid="EipZ2WfXhUKreMji0wtuZA" hash="OlaJhw">The Lord instructed all of us when He taught that for priesthood bearers, <span class="pageBreak" page-number="96"></span>unrighteousness brings an end to heavenly power or influence, while righteousness strengthens them. He identified qualities that “greatly enlarge the soul” as “persuasion, … long-suffering, … gentleness[,] … meekness, … love unfeigned[,] … kindness, and pure knowledge.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> He then added these instructive words: “Let thy bowels also be full of charity towards all men, and to the household of faith, and let virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly; then shall thy confidence wax strong in the presence of God; and the doctrine of the priesthood shall distil upon thy soul as the dews from heaven.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p14" pid="vEugwh6SsUynUecyfY3UwQ" hash="IQVGOw">It is significant that after inviting us to have charity toward “all men,” the Lord added the phrase “and to the household of faith.” Why? Doesn’t “all men” include the household of faith? Consider the implications when this added phrase is understood to mean more specifically “your very own household of faith.” Unfortunately, there are a few within the Church who exhibit greater charity toward nonfamily members than toward their own spouses and children, siblings and parents. They may show feigned kindness publicly while privately sowing and cultivating seeds of contention, demeaning those who should be closest to them. These things should not be.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p15" pid="tRMcxjdlNE-8gc-7_tdbhQ" hash="D2-cTg">The Lord then spoke of thoughts that are garnished—embellished and guarded—by virtue unceasingly. Such thoughts abhor sin.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> They allow our communications to be “Yea, yea; Nay, nay,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span> unencumbered by guile. They see the good and the potential in others, undeterred by the inevitable imperfections in others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p16" pid="IPK0Cs5rsk2e7Ja7VgE5-A" hash="Hi1Klg">The verse concludes with a beautifully instructive reference to a distilling process. To better understand the application of these principles in the refinement of our personal lives, consider two glasses of water, each with the same outward appearance, placed in a room with high humidity. After a period of time, water begins to condense on one of the glasses because it is at a different temperature, occasioned by prior preparation not obvious initially, while the other glass remains dry and unaffected. Without compulsory means, the humidity is able to “flow unto”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26">26</span> the one glass while the other receives nothing. In a similar way, qualities that greatly enlarge the soul; charity toward others, especially our families; and thoughts garnished with virtue adjust our spiritual temperatures to allow the doctrine of the priesthood to distil upon our souls.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p17" pid="YDP2Qt9GZEuMhrakoat4Qg" hash="BMsnzw">So it is that the priesthood, through the workings of the Spirit, moves individuals closer to God through ordination, ordinances, and refinement of individual natures, thus affording God’s children the opportunity to become like Him and live eternally in His presence—a work more glorious than moving mountains.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_27">27</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p18" pid="B10F_yA17E2bZhQKR1l7nw" hash="W4MZwg">I conclude by joining my prayer with that of Thomas Kelly, in words edited by Parley P. Pratt:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="2XGsEKfsAE6UmFcr8pBD1Q" hash="tT6XtQ">
            <span class="emphasis">As the dew from heav’n distilling</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="oT4YS_YVPUiu155ZOE-mCw" hash="al9XQQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Gently on the grass descends</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="SnxzGj8IjUWFLvknZopb3A" hash="fNmU8Q">
            <span class="emphasis">And revives it, thus fulfilling</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="V6unTqyLZUKBlBwvSBgpGw" hash="OkgQPA">
            <span class="emphasis">What thy providence intends,</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="rm7qKGpE7kWpAUKkQYGplw" hash="VZ2DUw">
            <span class="emphasis">Let thy doctrine, Lord, so gracious,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="n21SIuDUF0m9AvVJLgvEvA" hash="qGu8kQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Thus descending from above,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="3ijk-BoRSkyhhCDavzLP_g" hash="5QwFRw">
            <span class="emphasis">Blest by thee, prove efficacious</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="XD6DNDSBY0S0MnVjKwuu8Q" hash="S2jwug">
            <span class="emphasis">To fulfill thy work of love.</span>
            <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_28">28</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him.p19" pid="yOHxECoQ5kOPw6U5I4oq3w" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/10/moving-closer-to-him</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2006-general-conference/2006-10-5040-elder-craig-a-cardon-64k-eng.mp3" length="4519197" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Savior Wants to Forgive</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Lord loves us and wants us to understand His willingness to forgive.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10785_000_15cardon" doc-version="2" hash="jejcsQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="gV8arhwmyEmV4TuRdElk5A" hash="3dj1yA">The Savior Wants to Forgive</h1><p class="authorName" pid="spyn1-MCaUC5ADuYbv92wA" hash="i4gv4g">By Elder Craig A. Cardon</p><p class="kicker" pid="KMjo1cWlcUCq2ywE1sjDuQ" hash="9E3YiQ">The Lord loves us and wants us to understand His willingness to forgive.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p5" pid="Y0nyxpKNPUGzNskPnqypxg" hash="OyxyLQ"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="15"></span>During the time of our Savior’s mortal ministry, many followed after Him, including scribes and Pharisees “out of every town of Galilee, … Judaea, and Jerusalem.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> A bedridden, paralyzed man desiring to be healed was brought to a large gathering, but unable to get him close to the Savior, his friends took him to the roof of the house where the Savior was and lowered him down. Seeing this demonstration of faith, with a great purpose not yet known to His listeners, the Savior declared, “Man, thy sins are forgiven thee.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p6" pid="zwydC_4pYkiJhk75h44Low" hash="5ZdW9A">This must have surprised the man, and although the scriptures say nothing of his reaction, he may have wondered if the Savior really understood why he had come.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p7" pid="rsX42Y8EZkqrF2uEf3Zf3Q" hash="-xQJcg">The Savior knew that many people followed Him because of His mighty miracles. Already He had turned water to wine,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> cast out unclean spirits,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> and healed the nobleman’s son,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> a leper,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> Peter’s mother-in-law,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> and many others.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p8" pid="L8FbMLivGk23z3Wq35-qcw" hash="PmfvAQ">But with this paralyzed man, the Lord chose to give evidence to both disciple and detractor of His unique role as Savior of the world. Hearing the Savior’s words, the scribes and Pharisees had begun to reason among themselves, ignorantly speaking of blasphemy while concluding that only God can forgive sin. Perceiving their thoughts, the Savior addressed them, saying:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p9" pid="o-G_2Pik6EGc25D4lIwTKQ" hash="9OcMmw">“What reason ye in your hearts?</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p10" pid="f77ouvPffE-FQYImoSOLgw" hash="ganktA">“Whether is easier, to say, Thy sins be forgiven thee; or to say, Rise up and walk?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p11" pid="ickauBtv6kKoOj3ls8DANQ" hash="CIo8ag">Not waiting for their response, the Savior continued, “But that ye may know that the Son of man hath power <span class="emphasis">upon earth</span> to forgive sins, [He then turned to the paralyzed man] I say unto thee, Arise, and take up thy couch, and go into thine house.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> And he did!</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p12" pid="u0jZOIZimEebjkOBCtJOIg" hash="somWDw">By this miraculous physical healing, the Savior confirmed to all of us this infinitely more powerful spiritual truth: the Son of Man forgives sins!</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p13" pid="ccdUwc1jOU2ONmVDhhCsGw" hash="ASjX-w">While this truth is readily accepted by all believers, not so easily acknowledged is the essential companion truth: the Savior forgives sins “upon earth” and not just at the Final Judgment. He does not excuse us <span class="emphasis">in</span> our sins.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> He does not condone our return to past sins.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> But when we repent and obey His gospel, He forgives us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p14" pid="z3dmBjSzQUeOVGev-AVKWg" hash="3ENzwQ">In this forgiveness we see the enabling <span class="emphasis">and</span> the redeeming power of the Atonement harmoniously and graciously applied. If we exercise faith in the Lord Jesus Christ, the enabling power of His Atonement <span class="emphasis">strengthens</span> us in our moment of need,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> and His redeeming power <span class="emphasis">sanctifies</span> us as we “[put] off the natural man.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> This brings hope to all, especially to those who feel that recurring human weakness is beyond the Savior’s willingness to help and to save.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p15" pid="RVEvjwlKDka09_XdLyV0zw" hash="CiwIxA">Providing an opportunity for the Savior to enlighten our understanding,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> Peter once inquired how many times he should forgive his brother and then asked, “Till seven times?” Surely that would be more than enough. But the Savior’s response opened wide the door to <span class="emphasis">His</span> merciful heart: “I say <span class="emphasis">not</span> unto thee, Until seven times: but, Until seventy times seven.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p16" pid="Jol88d2zF0KoELuXKf5cJA" hash="vxEDZw"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="16"></span>The Lord loves us and wants us to understand His willingness to forgive. On more than 20 occasions in the Doctrine and Covenants, the Lord told those to whom He was speaking, “Thy sins are forgiven thee,” or similar words.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> On about half of those occasions, the Lord’s words were directed specifically to the Prophet Joseph Smith, sometimes addressing him alone, sometimes with others.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> The first of these was recorded in 1830, the last in 1843. Thus, over a span of many years, the Lord told Joseph repeatedly, “Thy sins are forgiven thee.”</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p17" pid="T4ByKOSwm0qjFsUVeHrt3w" hash="3RaH-Q">While Joseph was not “guilty of any great or malignant sins,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> we do well to remember that with very few exceptions, the Lord’s “seventy times seven” does not limit forgiveness according to the seriousness of the sin.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p18" pid="uIp2AZv_JkqVtKjsnGKTEA" hash="sNkTkA">While speaking to elders assembled in Kirtland, the Lord said, “I will that ye should overcome the world; <span class="emphasis">wherefore</span> I will have compassion upon you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> The Lord knows our weakness and the eternal consequences of “the world” upon imperfect men and women.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> The word <span class="emphasis">wherefore</span> in this verse is His affirmation that it is only by virtue of His compassion that we may ultimately “overcome the world.” How is that compassion made manifest? To these same elders in Kirtland, He said, “I have forgiven you your sins.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span><span class="emphasis"> The Savior wants to forgive.</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p19" pid="bgnRAaEWGUGNCAafeNPh6w" hash="2KEV-g">No one need suppose that this forgiveness comes without repentance. Indeed, the Lord has declared, “I, the Lord, forgive sins unto those who confess their sins before me and ask forgiveness,” and then He adds the cautionary qualifier “who have not sinned unto death.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> While the Lord “cannot look upon sin with the least degree of allowance,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span> yet He differentiates the relative gravity of some sins. He stipulates there will be no forgiveness for “blasphemy against the Holy Ghost.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26">26</span> He declares the gravity of murder<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_27">27</span> and emphasizes the seriousness of sexual sin such as adultery.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_28">28</span> With regard to repeated serious sexual sin, He makes known the increased difficulty of receiving His forgiveness.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_29">29</span> And He has said that “he who sins against the greater light shall receive the greater condemnation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_30">30</span> Yet, in His mercy, He allows for improvement over time rather than demanding immediate perfection. Even with the multitude of sins occasioned by the weakness of mortality, as often as we repent and seek His forgiveness, He forgives again and again.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_31">31</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p20" pid="jXALErlsuUSpWh_xuaMyfw" hash="rf_Q9g">Because of this, all of us, including those struggling to overcome addictive behaviors such as substance abuse or pornography and those close to them, can know that the Lord will recognize our righteous efforts and will lovingly forgive when repentance is complete, “until seventy times seven.” But this does not mean one may <span class="emphasis">willingly</span> return to sin with impunity.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_32">32</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p21" pid="0Fm6bOg3bU69lCqOh2nifw" hash="muecpg">The Lord is always interested in our hearts,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_33">33</span> and rationalized false faith does not justify sin.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_34">34</span> In this dispensation the Lord warned one of His servants against such rationalization by declaring, “Let [him] be ashamed of the Nicolaitane band and of all their secret abominations.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_35">35</span> The Nicolaitans were an ancient religious sect that claimed license to commit sexual sin by virtue of the Lord’s grace.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_36">36</span> This is not pleasing to the Lord.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_37">37</span> His compassion and grace do not excuse us when “[our] hearts are not satisfied. And [we] obey not the truth, but have pleasure in unrighteousness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_38">38</span> Rather, after we do all we can do,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_39">39</span> His compassion and grace are the means whereby “in process of time”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_40">40</span> we overcome the world through the enabling power of the Atonement. As we humbly seek this precious gift, “weak things become strong unto [us],”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_41">41</span> and by <span class="emphasis">His</span> strength, we are made able to do that which we could never do alone.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p22" pid="L-f36d1hwUu2WIb9wskYoQ" hash="aMZVXw">The Lord looks upon the light we have received,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_42">42</span> the desires of our hearts,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_43">43</span> and our actions,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_44">44</span> and when we repent and seek His forgiveness, He forgives. As we consider our own lives and the lives of our loved ones and acquaintances, we should be equally willing to forgive ourselves and others.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_45">45</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p23" pid="3jtyh-uH0066iukVhnpNMw" hash="ZoFvbA"><span class="emphasis">Preach My Gospel</span> speaks of the difficulty in overcoming addictive behavior and encourages priesthood <span class="pageBreak" page-number="17"></span>leaders and members to “not be shocked or discouraged” if investigators or new members continue to struggle with such problems. Rather, we are counseled to “show confidence in the individual and not be judgmental … [treating] it as a temporary and understandable setback.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_46">46</span> Could we do less with our own children or family members who struggle with similar problems, having temporarily strayed from the path of righteousness? Surely they merit our steadiness, patience, and love—and yes, our forgiveness.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p24" pid="e5mL_nwiA0WrkuYK3UDang" hash="LztGJw">In general conference just last October, President Monson counseled:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p25" pid="V88BEGCuF0SSw1SWcaG1BQ" hash="2Lg2oQ">“We need to bear in mind that people can change. They can put behind them bad habits. They can repent from transgressions. …</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p26" pid="V41QZy-7vUmUlcPBC7AQ_Q" hash="nTBNBA">“… We can help them to overcome their shortcomings. We must develop the capacity to see men <span class="emphasis">not</span> as they are at present but as they may become.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_47">47</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p27" pid="FMKH2Bm880-MTxEvKpZvog" hash="1c8yMA">At an early conference of the Church, similar to this conference, the Lord told the members:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p28" pid="oqvZVLNyV0madQ1X91AO2w" hash="nX_PRQ">“Verily I say unto you, ye are clean, but not all; …</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p29" pid="dK6qrTAJYEqjEF2r9usHmQ" hash="R0xGkQ">“For <span class="emphasis">all flesh</span> is corrupted before me. …</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p30" pid="c5TDbVMeR0WuQfW5gFCvmQ" hash="2kwN_g">“… For verily some of you are guilty before me, <span class="emphasis">but I will be merciful unto your weakness.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_48">48</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p31" pid="kwd_4nV7o0ueAB4X9FvI9w" hash="jkZStw">His message is the same today.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p32" pid="8VNgZGops0y1lZLXPmguzg" hash="PhDxXQ">Our Heavenly Father knows what we are facing, that we all sin and “come short of the glory of God”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_49">49</span> again and again. He sent His Son, who “knoweth the weakness of man and how to succor them who are tempted.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_50">50</span> His Son teaches us to “pray always that [we] enter <span class="emphasis">not</span> into temptation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_51">51</span> We are told to “cry unto [God] for <span class="emphasis">mercy;</span> for he is mighty to save.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_52">52</span> The Savior commands us to repent<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_53">53</span> and to forgive.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_54">54</span> And although repentance is not easy, as we strive with all our hearts to obey His gospel, He gives this promise: “Verily I say unto you, notwithstanding [your] sins, <span class="emphasis">my bowels are filled with compassion towards [you].</span> I will not utterly cast [you] off; <span class="emphasis">and in the day of wrath I will remember mercy.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_55">55</span> The Savior wants to forgive.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p33" pid="RWdoLIFRaUirf1tKmo9tcw" hash="Y8otsQ">Each week the Mormon Tabernacle Choir begins its inspiring broadcast with the uplifting words of William W. Phelps’s familiar hymn “Gently Raise the Sacred Strain.” Not as familiar are the comforting words of the fourth verse:</p>
				<div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.f1">
					<div class="stanza">
						<p class="line" pid="27_-yRnhIUm5tp7LmxisoQ" hash="qYDWfQ">Holy, holy is the Lord.</p>
						<p class="line" pid="pRwYETdFBEuvJcm2XpWo8g" hash="iYHKOQ">Precious, precious is his word: …</p>
						<p class="line" pid="1c0wuhoxF0KYAp7Q2GpuXg" hash="eNPXlg">Repent and live;</p>
						<p class="line" pid="FU4J3L7wtkaxarWOM2pS2Q" hash="tLUf3w">Tho your sins be crimson red,</p>
						<p class="line" pid="9jaAWTX4R06kwB_24gZ4rQ" hash="GwNNQg">Oh, repent, and he’ll forgive.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_56">56</span></p>
					</div>
				</div>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive.p39" pid="OGCSAuRP5U-x3F9MEBPgjw" hash="EJlvOw">I invite you to remember and believe the words of the Lord and to exercise faith in Him unto repentance.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_57">57</span> He loves you. He wants to forgive. I so testify in the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2013/04/the-savior-wants-to-forgive</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2013-general-conference/2013-04-1050-elder-craig-a-cardon-64k-eng.mp3" length="5369344" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
