<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Cree-L Kofford</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Cree-L Kofford.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Cree-L%20Kofford.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Cree-L Kofford.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Oct 1991 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 1991 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Inheritance—An Allegory</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Standing at this historic pulpit with memories of those men and women who have stood here before me filling my thoughts, I am reminded of the admonition given to Moses when he was told, “Put off thy shoes from off thy feet, for the place whereon thou</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_91911_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="-ddl8Q">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="VFxrj1Z7uEudnL-QZjO8YQ" hash="rsccGA">The Ultimate Inheritance—</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="qUW3lgLH7UGdVF8asxSABA" hash="w39aNA">An Allegory</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="G2pWp-S7bk-ZCepSzuGSwA" hash="aejHwA">Cree-L Kofford</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-21f0.jpg" alt="Elder Cree-L Kofford" pid="Q2MZb92fAkWyj7YeN6VHGw" hash="Pbk22A" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p1" pid="HdxqOBPja02UovVxFj8DPw" hash="YDoevw">Standing at this historic pulpit with memories of those men and women who have stood here before me filling my thoughts, I am reminded of the admonition given to Moses when he was told, “Put off thy shoes from off thy feet, for the place whereon thou standest is holy ground.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/3.5" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 3:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p2" pid="xZQ6T71mCEqanjm5J4TN6w" hash="kt32Nw">I pray that as I stand upon this holy ground I may do so with my shoes from off my feet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p3" pid="sim_82Ql4Ua-8ZL48ACgMA" hash="wB9X6Q">I desire to teach you concerning matters of eternal significance. In doing so I shall speak allegorically, which simply means that I will teach by using a story which has symbolic meanings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p4" pid="JoZYY9ylD0y9ASJD7F7AQg" hash="nmQY4Q">In an allegorical sense, I am here today as a member of the trial team assembled by your chief advocate. We have now received the legal action in which each of you has been named as a party defendant. I and others of the trial team have reviewed the pleadings carefully and have confirmed that the real purpose of opposing counsel is to prove that you are <span class="emphasis">not</span> eligible to receive your ultimate inheritance. Our adversary’s trial team is even now working tirelessly to assemble the facts necessary to bring about your defeat.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p5" pid="atKjQvlZsUqnrGl2o50LLA" hash="86uAiQ">By virtue of motions made, heard, and previously decided, we have been compelled to produce, on behalf of each of you, all records relating to your business and personal transactions. These include a schedule of your neighbors, friends, and business acquaintances. Additionally, full disclosure concerning your spouse, your children, your parents, and members of your extended family has been made.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p6" pid="AwGCOCRNJEqvy7DdyiFxNg" hash="OtUa3A">You should know that our adversary is prepared to spend such time, effort, and money as is necessary to deprive you of your inheritance. They have already expended untold millions of dollars in preparing their case against each of you. They have hired gifted, talented, and experienced people to work for them. They intend to win!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p7" pid="8zH79FHRzEK6yD1MAAjsLw" hash="68exxg">Fortunately, you are represented by the <span class="emphasis">most</span> skilled, capable, and diligent counsel I have ever seen. It’s amazing to watch him as he argues on your behalf before the Supreme Judge.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p8" pid="z-5MJjpHR0SK3-wTiqNCKQ" hash="5KrhrQ">For example, our adversary brought a motion seeking an order that some of you have already forfeited your rights to your ultimate inheritance and therefore a summary judgment should be entered against you. I must admit he was brilliant in his presentation. For a time it seemed to me that he would prevail. Many of the court personnel were nodding their heads in seeming agreement with him. His argument was powerful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p9" pid="zJf65wiNOUOpyNP3NHk1ig" hash="7dhK6A">Citing several of you by name, he said, “If these defendants have lived this long and have not yet taken serious steps to qualify for their ultimate inheritance, why should we waste further time of the court? Let us simply enter judgment against them now and be done with it.” So powerful was his presentation that many in the public gallery applauded when he concluded.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p10" pid="3ScfcrYeEEeCQxuQ9mxpFw" hash="I9ml2w">You could have heard a pin drop when your chief advocate arose. The suspense in the courtroom was electrifying. What arguments could he possibly make that would overcome those just presented? I wish you could have been there.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p11" pid="FEZOCvDT-ESjowOXWOSOBw" hash="uBFLHA">In contrast to the bombastic and cynical arguments of opposing counsel, your advocate began your defense as a trickle and built to the force of a mighty river. Humbly, softly, meaningfully, and compellingly, he pled your case. I knew the impact he was having when I saw tears streaming down the cheeks of many in the courtroom. I don’t remember all of his arguments and logic, but I do remember him saying that man is a little lower than the angels (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/8.5" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 8:5</a>) and that the worth of souls is great (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:10</a>). In one of the most majestic moments, his eyes filled with compassion and his voice quivering with indignation, he admonished, “He that is without sin among you, let him first cast a stone.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.7" class="scriptureRef">John 8:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p12" pid="Y-ionnt8FUytrb319mLLtA" hash="5WOT6w">He went on to argue that “this life is the time for men to prepare to meet God” (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/34.32" class="scriptureRef">Alma 34:32</a>) and closed with a breathtaking summary in which he said no one has the right to judge the sum total of a man’s life until that life has been lived.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p13" pid="ox63_u0mCUSovfRL8tvJJw" hash="kBYbbA">There was silence in the room when he finished, silence broken only by the voice of the Supreme Judge announcing his decision: “Motion of counsel for the plaintiffs is denied. The issues sought to be summarily decided here are better left until trial of this matter on the merits,” he said.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p14" pid="kaiJjQgzx0CLC8tAPuzFiw" hash="mad6Cg">Now, in preparation for your appearance on the witness stand, you should be advised that, in the law, we have what are known as threshold questions. These are simply questions that are the point of beginning, or the starting place. The threshold question in your trial is, Do you love the Lord God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind? (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.37" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:37</a>.) If the answer is no, there will be a motion for judgment against you. That motion will be granted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p15" pid="hL6LuIlrekq9EwgegjDm_w" hash="2tWwTw">On the other hand, if you answer yes, opposing counsel will immediately test the validity of your answer with the question, Do you keep his commandments? (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.15" class="scriptureRef">John 14:15</a>.) A negative response will reveal your fraud, and you will stand judged by your own testimony. If your answer is in the affirmative, there will then follow hours, perhaps days, of questions, each designed to prove that you do not, in fact, keep his commandments. Among those questions will be the following:</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.f2">
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="vqn8Xvi7a0-zJvMmAPRJBw" hash="GyFK8g">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="w3Arw89iJEGCnJoff5pMug" hash="9CGHmA">Do you love your neighbor as yourself? (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.39" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:39</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="abms8LYV3k2EdPbvi8BLoQ" hash="pa_77w">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="96NXqLguuUi-R7CMnG0GZg" hash="4fK48Q">Do you place worldly pursuits or personal pleasures above your service to God? (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.3" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:3</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="SLKFY0P-0kGYxHKFxJRoYg" hash="giiACA">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="zcHpdTQk4E-Tn4gkjmaN_Q" hash="uAfLvw">Do you take the name of the Lord God in vain? (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.7" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:7</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="0meqQOzIXkOSCvJnbu4YVQ" hash="0ehJ8Q">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="VcUfOwHYGUSfJxH3Vnzxow" hash="m7cjbw">Do you keep the Sabbath day holy? (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.8" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:8</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="YESZOrnjGUGNO_3O4O-4HQ" hash="PxSRpg">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p pid="S3K9GZHd_kq0xMdPEcU57A" hash="Za88bA">Do you honor your father and mother? (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.12" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:12</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="bo3BQenGHE2aj0Ev8PbL6A" hash="xqvwjA">
          <span class="label">6.</span>
          <p pid="etdlGCMCs0S2JNiD8Q32qQ" hash="BMI34Q">Do you commit adultery or fornication? (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.14" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:14</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="ULl8TfasoEqVo2TOcss7GA" hash="SnyhAg">
          <span class="label">7.</span>
          <p pid="y1bTaXJn-0WJkQE2DhcW-w" hash="a4so2Q">Do you steal? (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.15" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:15</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Y44xhY12EkOEKwVc8hDQBA" hash="I3dTEQ">
          <span class="label">8.</span>
          <p pid="3ajRPHn2kUG1hORUasz3xQ" hash="WZ8j7Q">Do you bear false witness? (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.16" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:16</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="TdHKflnFOEe5p6pYhovqMQ" hash="6Rs-Dg">
          <span class="label">9.</span>
          <p pid="xC37Aymzi0u4NKKA72NsLw" hash="Vr12WQ">Do you covet? (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.17" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:17</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p16" pid="WgmoqQDFuUOyegrV1q5JrQ" hash="fAofHA">Remember, opposing counsel and his trial team will be fully conversant with your conduct and behavior. Witnesses will have been subpoenaed by them to testify against you. Your neighbors will present their testimony concerning your conduct with them. Those who have observed your Sabbath day activity will be called to the stand. On each point where you are vulnerable, witnesses will be produced to contradict your sworn testimony.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p17" pid="7sZtHqAN2UecunO4xv_Dfg" hash="p6EtoA">As your counsel we will, of course, be equally well prepared. Your chief counsel will produce every witness favorable to you and elicit from them every fact which may be used on your behalf.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p18" pid="skrpCpHkFky_ruIOqvALdQ" hash="i8QSkw">However, one thing is clear—the ultimate outcome of your case is dependent upon the facts which you provide. There’s an old adage among trial lawyers that says, “We don’t make the facts, we only present them.” The facts which represent your life are the facts that will ultimately determine your victory or your defeat.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p19" pid="V0XXoMnjyU6a4l9WSRxERQ" hash="lZrtzg">That is one of the reasons I have come today. I have been asked to see that you are clearly informed concerning this matter and to urge you, where necessary, to create facts which will allow the Supreme Judge to find on your behalf. Fortunately for you, your life’s facts <span class="emphasis">can</span> still be created. No matter how long you have lived, no matter how many mistakes you have made, your life’s story <span class="emphasis">can</span> still be changed. It <span class="emphasis">can</span> still be written. It is not too late. Please, I plead with you, help him to help you win your ultimate inheritance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p20" pid="9VGUiV0rd0mprVMz1r-xcA" hash="p7oraA">Now before closing, I should like to express my deep love to Ila, who is my sweetheart and my heartbeat. I honor her and the womanhood which she so elegantly represents. I love our five children, who are my best friends, and our twelve grandchildren, who regularly teach me the joy of unconditional love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory.p21" pid="v7IzpP0JgUaQbmBh28bqbg" hash="lL-Tjw">In the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1991/10/the-ultimate-inheritance-an-allegory</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1991-general-conference/1991-10-2050-elder-cree-l-kofford-64k-eng.mp3" length="4853108" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 1991 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Name Is Safe in Our Home</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home?lang=eng</link>
      <description>There are those among us who would recoil in horror at the thought of stealing another person’s money or property but who don’t give a second thought to stealing another person’s good name or reputation.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_99260_000_034" doc-version="2" hash="zhgjkg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="8gqcN96DgUat0lgUAt6hXA" hash="vyg57A">Your Name Is Safe in Our Home</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="WWcfHYUWDEmXwDA4--4ihg" hash="XLWc4A">Elder Cree-L Kofford</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="kNJHK82sbUW5IkZC0_T2ag" hash="funUQA">There are those among us who would recoil in horror at the thought of stealing another person’s money or property but who don’t give a second thought to stealing another person’s good name or reputation.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1b21.jpg" alt="Elder Cree-L Kofford" pid="iVR26tdh0k6iMYmY3m2g7w" hash="OCcEOw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p1" pid="C8SMPGl1f0q84XSVlsvnsA" hash="R880kg">I wonder if you have any idea how easy you are to love and how much I love you. Just before this session started, some of our grandchildren stopped by our hotel room. They had obviously been talking about Elder Marlin Jensen’s talk of this morning. One of them said, “Are you scared, Grandpa?” I lied and said, “Not very.” Another one said, “Don’t worry, Grandpa, if you mess up, we’ll still love you.” But then reality came back into the room when someone added, “But, Grandpa, it would be very embarrassing.” So I am going to try very hard not to mess up.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p2" pid="uGF2roc8uUubqpbc3H33Pw" hash="YfJXqA">On June 26, 1858, what I believe to be the largest standing army in the history of the United States up to that date began its prearranged entry into Salt Lake Valley. They had come to quell a nonexistent rebellion. Almost anyone remotely familiar with the history of the Church can tell you that they marched in relative silence within a few yards of where this building now stands, through a city described by one writer as “deserted,” and encamped some distance to the west. What followed is far less well known. In due course the army moved approximately 40 miles south of Salt Lake City to the village of Fairfield, a small farming community in Cedar Valley, home to what is estimated to have been less than 200 people. Their local spiritual leader was John Carson, my great-grandfather.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p3" pid="xPdJAzEp4ESib0VOL1AWnw" hash="c7To5A">Imagine how this small congregation must have felt. After all, how would you like to wake up some morning and find that several thousand soldiers, together with over 3,000 wagons, 10,000 oxen, and 12,000 mules, had moved into your ward? The challenges were immediate. From our oral family history, and subject to all of the romanticizing and inaccuracies of such histories, we learn that Bishop Carson was gravely concerned about the welfare of the people over whom he presided. All of the challenges that attended army encampments of that time descended upon Fairfield almost overnight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p4" pid="wGzd9Wf6yESvGHFaVzl9IA" hash="7DBjWg">To protect the members of the congregation as much as possible, Bishop Carson met with the commander of the fort, who often dined at his hotel and with whom he developed a good relationship based upon mutual respect. The two leaders surveyed the situation and then by agreement drew a line upon the ground. No army personnel would cross into the civilian community without specific approval of their superiors. And members of the congregation would not cross into the fort without specific approval from Bishop Carson. The line on the ground represented an unspoken command: “Over this line you may not cross.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p5" pid="9BTXb7EhjEeFCPJ-5ZsVRQ" hash="_Xkcyw">When we were children, a line on the ground had special significance. Whenever boyhood tempers caused disagreement, the time-honored solution called for a line on the ground. The antagonists stood on opposite sides of the line, attempting to act as intimidating as possible. Someone would say, “Step over the line and you’ll be sorry,” though they usually didn’t say it in those genteel words. In those moments I learned the great value of a line on the ground and the consequences of stepping over it. In the years that have followed, I have come to understand that figurative lines on the ground are placed there by a loving Heavenly Father who seeks to protect us from Lucifer’s army.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p6" pid="3S449VoiKkiZdtC90SUIxA" hash="OcLG6g">While each of us may have dozens of lines on the ground in our life today, I would like to discuss just one of them—the line that says, “Keep each person’s name safe in your home.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p7" pid="ybfY_EDmRkCwSmUH48e4Jg" hash="rdDfoQ">During the early years of my service as a General Authority, I was privileged to be in company with Elder Marion D. Hanks on one occasion when he related the following story. I use it here with his permission:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p8" pid="XMj1PLo-O0KLk_-D9rzt_g" hash="Re9q-w">Oscar Kirkham was one of the great men of the Church and among the Church’s most respected Scouters. He served in the First Council of the Seventy and was a significant presence wherever he went. Often in meetings he would rise to a “point of personal privilege” and then, when recognized, would proceed to say something good about someone. Near the end of his life, he spoke briefly at Brigham Young University on the theme “say the good word.” On the morning that Elder Kirkham died, Elder Hanks was invited to the Kirkham family home. There he was handed a small, inexpensive notebook in which Elder Kirkham had kept his notes. The last two entries were: “Say the good word” and “Your name is safe in our home” (see Marion D. Hanks, foreword to <span class="emphasis">Say the Good Word,</span> by Oscar A. Kirkham [1958], 4).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p9" pid="yFn3hQ4pfkqEEB4aMrYThQ" hash="mxO_vQ">What a blessing it would be if all of us could follow that counsel, if each of our names truly could be safe in the home of others. Have you noticed how easy it is to cross over the line and find fault with other people? All too often we seek to be excused from the very behavior we condemn in others. Mercy for me, justice for everyone else is a much too common addiction. When we deal with the name and reputation of another, we deal with something sacred in the sight of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p10" pid="f-7AIs5TzEWxOuvFtXJYCg" hash="funUQA1">There are those among us who would recoil in horror at the thought of stealing another person’s money or property but who don’t give a second thought to stealing another person’s good name or reputation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p11" pid="691DY6TLg0abs59ePmYW2g" hash="pyjwtA">The old adage “Never judge another man until you have walked a mile in his footsteps” is as good advice today as it was the day it was first uttered. Someone once said,</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="vAUs_eE9Tkq5adHTxSwYIg" hash="dCiAgw">
            <span class="emphasis">There is so much good in the worst of us,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="sQnIxvPtJU2KryIaM8MUUQ" hash="QsX3pw">
            <span class="emphasis">And so much bad in the best of us,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="aFhwF8yD6UyiUzP6xCIgKg" hash="6tUdNA">
            <span class="emphasis">That it ill behooves any of us</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="QRIlJFu2IkeIuzPqWkdK8Q" hash="WbqDOw">
            <span class="emphasis">To find fault with the rest of us.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p12" pid="W2bbUeQcNU632eu9zNbMNw" hash="SpIUYw">The principle is not new, nor is it unique to our day and time. The book of Psalms from the Old Testament contains this urgent warning from the Lord: “Whoso privily slandereth his neighbour, him will I cut off” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/101.5" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 101:5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p13" pid="h2POHL_cKkGlnRaKpEFnDQ" hash="Xu5obA">James, a servant of the Lord in the meridian of time, repeated this eternal truth when he said: “Speak not evil one of another, brethren. He that speaketh evil of his brother, and judgeth his brother, speaketh evil of the law, and judgeth the law. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p14" pid="Dzqi1Fe5q0af1OtsLzQHTA" hash="KEIURw">“… Who art thou that judgest another?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/4.11-12" class="scriptureRef">James 4:11–12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p15" pid="4Vjs4zk0JUGhZE3oeIVaXg" hash="D8bOuQ">And in this latter day, the Lord renewed His long-taught command in a revelation given through the prophet Brigham Young: “Cease to speak evil one of another” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/136.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 136:23</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p16" pid="V7RC_SclFEyKWxP1wr_U-A" hash="m8Wc6Q">It is most significant to me that this simple commandment is set forth just a few verses from the Lord’s words on the penalty for disobedience: “Be diligent in keeping all my commandments, lest judgments come upon you, and your faith fail you, and your enemies triumph over you” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/136.42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 136:42</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p17" pid="mmmcFzr9B0uYau1B0Csf-A" hash="rAQBjw">To those who doubt the importance of the commandment, may I pose two simple questions: (1) How can you say you love your fellowman when behind his back you seek to diminish his good name and reputation? (2) How can you say you love your God when you cannot even love your neighbor?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p18" pid="BPmgRp_YtkS5lyZdeJrV0A" hash="GOhqeQ">Any feeble attempt to justify such conduct only brings more forcibly to mind those explosive words of the Savior found in the book of Matthew:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p19" pid="dMZArpLxXkKrM1bimMZwmA" hash="WbYKxA">“O generation of vipers, how can ye, being evil, speak good things? …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p20" pid="xgWDdaxz5kGPLjX2OYuSiw" hash="Ntcstg">“But I say unto you, That every idle word that men shall speak, they shall give account thereof in the day of judgment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p21" pid="wdSITvsQHkSUEwfwqijvCQ" hash="sIvAAw">“For by thy words thou shalt be justified, and by thy words thou shalt be condemned” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/12.34,36-37" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 12:34, 36–37</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p22" pid="8WT0GnIsdU2793BpMFNvWQ" hash="OULHQw">I would like to say a few words to the Primary children who may be listening. Children, I’ve been trying to teach your moms and dads something very important, but I need your help. I’ll make you a deal. If you will promise to listen very carefully, I promise not to talk very long.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p23" pid="d_3uSE4ZaU2-D2aEE6j4fw" hash="g4slNQ">Do you remember the story of Bambi, the little deer, and all of his friends in the forest? If you do, you will remember that one of Bambi’s good friends was a rabbit named Thumper. Thumper was about your age. He was a neat rabbit, but he had one problem. He kept saying bad things about people. One day Bambi was in the forest learning to walk, and he fell down. Thumper just couldn’t resist the temptation. “He doesn’t walk very good, does he?” Thumper blurted out. His mother felt very bad and said, “What did your father tell you this morning?” And then Thumper, looking down at his feet and kind of shifting his weight, said, “If you can’t say somethin’ nice, don’t say nothin’ at all.” That’s a good piece of advice that all of us need to follow. What I need you to do, young people, is this. If you hear anyone in your family start to say something bad about someone else, will you please just stamp your foot and say in a loud voice, “If you can’t say somethin’ nice, don’t say nothin’ at all.” Now, even though that isn’t correct English, everyone will understand exactly what you mean. Now, Moms and Dads, that ought to make it a little easier to live the commandment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p24" pid="61HIxATeBUqhFigv50fewQ" hash="idy14Q">I pray that the Lord will bless each of us that we may never cross over the line on the ground and that we may live so that it can be said, “Your name is safe in our home.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home.p25" pid="YMPhldEmz0-6UhmCi75TvQ" hash="al9aXQ">On this special Easter Day, I close with my solemn declaration, born of the Spirit, that Jesus Christ is indeed our Savior and our Redeemer and that salvation comes by and through His atoning sacrifice and in no other way. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1999/04/your-name-is-safe-in-our-home</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1999-general-conference/1999-04-5040-elder-cree-l-kofford-64k-eng.mp3" length="5026083" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1999 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
