<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Dale G. Renlund</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Dale G. Renlund.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Dale%20G.%20Renlund.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Dale G. Renlund.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2009 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2009 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Preserving the Heart’s Mighty Change</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change?lang=eng</link>
      <description>To endure to the end, we need to be eager to please God and worship Him with fervor.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50019113_000_033" doc-version="2" hash="pCIIww">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="1RX8KhKyvE20sTJprELQMA" hash="8E1_WQ">Preserving the Heart’s Mighty Change</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="fecbXOrDL0GEk1ro7jDW-w" hash="18jqNA">Dale G. Renlund</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="umRU2npt90WCemsKdrysRA" hash="9O2s7g">To endure to the end, we need to be eager to please God and worship Him with fervor.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p1" pid="F1s7Vz8yl0mXKFCk2axDxw" hash="kPtYsg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="97"></span>In December 1967 the first successful heart transplant was performed in Cape Town, South Africa. The dying man’s diseased heart was removed, and a healthy heart from a deceased donor was sewn in its place. Since then, over 75,000 heart transplants have been performed worldwide.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p2" pid="oaM28qafVU2PX4GVxwfxug" hash="8GOG8A">In each heart transplant recipient, the patient’s own body recognizes the new, lifesaving heart as “foreign” and begins to attack it. Left unchecked, the body’s natural response will reject the new heart, and the recipient will die. Medicines can suppress this natural response, but the medications must be taken daily and with exactness. Furthermore, the condition of the new heart must be monitored. Occasional heart biopsies are performed wherein small pieces of heart tissue are removed and then examined under a microscope. When signs of rejection are found, medications are adjusted. If the rejection process is detected early enough, death can be averted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p3" pid="FYsDVL_B2kqgnmzDRR68ow" hash="vad-bA">Surprisingly, some patients become casual with their transplanted hearts. They skip their medicines here and there and obtain the needed follow-up less frequently than they should. They think that because they feel good, all is well. Too often this shortsighted attitude puts the patients at risk and shortens their lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p4" pid="8UMPytzsXUGDjATigh-jCw" hash="3ioqBQ">A heart transplant can prolong life for years for people who would otherwise die from heart failure. But it is not “the ultimate operation,” as <span class="emphasis">Time</span> magazine called it in 1967.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> The ultimate operation is not a physical but a spiritual “mighty change” of heart.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p5" pid="h9CmwU8c3kubOtAUanpjmw" hash="JzMcnQ">Through the Atonement of Christ and by obedience to the laws and ordinances of the gospel, we undergo <span class="pageBreak" page-number="98"></span>this ultimate operation, this spiritual change of heart. As a result of our transgressions, our spiritual hearts have become diseased and hardened, making us subject to spiritual death and separation from our Heavenly Father. The Lord explained the operation that we all need: “A new heart also will I give you, and a new spirit will I put within you: and I will take away the stony heart out of your flesh, and I will give you an heart of flesh.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p6" pid="Ery9NimOS0W9fCjjAPXIHw" hash="ud8WXA">Just as with heart transplant patients, however, this mighty change of our spiritual hearts is just the beginning. Repentance, baptism, and confirmation are necessary but not sufficient. Indeed, equal, if not greater, care must be taken with a spiritually changed heart than with a physically transplanted heart if we are to endure to the end. Only by doing so can we be held guiltless at the time of judgment.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p7" pid="cgsNybQcXUyS1kKRKDWw4A" hash="eIabgQ">Enduring to the end can be challenging because the tendency of the natural man is to reject the spiritually changed heart and allow it to harden. No wonder the Lord cautioned to “even let those who are sanctified take heed.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p8" pid="X7qG0Xb5HU2pRssxQTsprg" hash="tiAKLQ">We all know of individuals who had this mighty change of heart but subsequently yielded to the natural man. They became casual in their worship and devotion to God, their hearts became hardened, and they thereby jeopardized their eternal salvation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p9" pid="S8m64tVyiUiaCZ7a5Wh6mA" hash="tu69kQ">The lives of the people who were converted by the preaching of the sons of Mosiah offer some insights as to how one avoids rejecting the mightily changed spiritual heart. Of them, we read that “as many as were brought to the knowledge of the truth, through the preaching of Ammon and his brethren, … and were converted unto the Lord, never did fall away.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p10" pid="oHz5rh3z7Uy0cds2DcsZXA" hash="yOOexw">How did they successfully endure to the end? We know that they were “distinguished for their zeal towards God, and also towards men; for they were perfectly honest and upright in all things; and they were firm in the faith of Christ, even unto the end.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p11" pid="cG9JI3wU3k6odSy6fq6EwQ" hash="BblJow">Their zeal towards God likely reflects an eagerness to please God and worship Him with fervor and passion. Their zeal towards men suggests an ardent interest in helping and serving others. Being perfectly upright and honest in all things suggests that they held their covenants firmly and did not rationalize their commitments to God or man. We further know that they taught their children the gospel in their homes. We know that they buried their weapons of war, distancing themselves from temptations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p12" pid="J4-EZES2IUO68dgNyDIaoQ" hash="GwfrMw">They must have frequently assessed the condition of their spiritually changed hearts. They did not simply assume that all was well. By figuratively examining their changed hearts, they could identify any early hardening or rejection and treat it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p13" pid="vbw8R1x85E6hHKfQ40YObQ" hash="y5rt4w">Alma the Younger poses a series of questions to contemporaries of the people of Ammon that figuratively biopsy spiritually changed hearts. Alma asks, “If ye have experienced a change of heart, and if ye have felt to sing the song of redeeming love, I would ask, can ye feel so now?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> He further asks if they have been sufficiently humble, free of pride and envy, and kind toward their fellowman.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> By honestly answering questions like these, we can correct early deviations from the strait and narrow path and keep our covenants with exactness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p14" pid="erG466KLYUq6WSdn78gKJw" hash="8nS7NA">In 1980 we moved as a family across the street from the hospital where I trained and worked. I worked every day, including Sundays. If I finished my Sunday work by 2:00 p.m., I could join my wife and daughter and drive to church for meetings that began at 2:30.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p15" pid="6O-1tEYGc0qyVrh8oTfoEw" hash="OXpHkw">One Sunday late in my first year of training, I knew that I would likely finish by 2:00. I realized, however, that if I stayed in the hospital just a little longer, my wife and daughter would depart without me. I could then walk home and take a needed nap. I regret to say that I did just that. I waited until 2:15, walked home slowly, and lay down on the couch, hoping to nap. But I could not fall asleep. I was disturbed and concerned. I had always loved going to church. I wondered why on this day the fire of testimony and the zeal that I had previously felt were missing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p16" pid="QdxC2tEHbUyrcsqIDXh81A" hash="UYAX4Q">I did not have to think long. Because of my schedule, I had become casual with my prayers and scripture study. I would get up one morning, say my prayers, and go to work. Often day blended into night and into day again before I would return home late the following evening. I would then be so tired that I would fall asleep before saying a prayer or reading the scriptures. The next morning the process began again. The problem was that I was not doing the basic things I needed to do to keep my mightily changed heart from turning to stone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p17" pid="ZhgUvHgbz0K9PXxbUjU_dw" hash="35M6cA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="99"></span>I got off the couch, got on my knees, and pleaded with God for forgiveness. I promised my Heavenly Father that I would change. The next day I brought a Book of Mormon to the hospital. On my to-do list that day, and every day since, were two items: praying at least morning and evening and reading in the scriptures. Sometimes midnight would come, and I would have to quickly find a private place to pray. Some days my scripture study was brief. I also promised Heavenly Father that I would always try to get to church, even if I missed part of the meeting. Over the course of a few weeks, the zeal returned and the fire of testimony burned fiercely again. I promised to never again fall into the spiritual death trap of being casual about these seemingly small actions and thereby jeopardizing things of an eternal nature, regardless of circumstances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p18" pid="b9OsewGl6Uu3npsB8bKvJQ" hash="quPbPw">To endure to the end, we need to be eager to please God and worship Him with fervor and passion. This means that we maintain faith in Jesus Christ by praying, studying the scriptures, partaking of the sacrament each week, and having the Holy Ghost as our constant companion. We need to actively help and serve others and share the gospel with them. We need to be perfectly upright and honest in all things, never compromising our covenants with God or our commitments to men, regardless of circumstances. In our homes we need to talk of, rejoice in, and preach of Christ so that our children—and we ourselves—will desire to apply the Atonement in our lives.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> We must identify temptations that easily beset us and put them out of reach—way out of reach. Finally, we need to frequently biopsy our mightily changed hearts and reverse any signs of early rejection.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p19" pid="O0HdxHGHL0SzAS9BM1dIwA" hash="j70HBA">Please consider the state of your changed heart. Do you detect any rejection setting in as a result of the tendency of the natural man to become casual? If so, find a place where you too can kneel. Remember, more than mortal years on this earth are at stake. Do not risk forfeiting the fruits of the ultimate operation: eternal salvation and exaltation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change.p20" pid="_7WHM8SRM0CIuRRZNAoO6w" hash="U8ZBmg">I pray that we may press forward with steadfast faith in Christ and endure joyfully to the end,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2009/10/preserving-the-hearts-mighty-change</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2009-general-conference/2009-10-5040-elder-dale-g-renlund-64k-eng.mp3" length="4868368" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2009 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latter-day Saints Keep on Trying</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Dale G. Renlund teaches that being a Saint means to keep trying and encourages us to do so while allowing others the same opportunity.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_12565_000_27renlund" doc-version="5" hash="XUgR5g">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="5LCXnjrwhEOU-ZyNzBNyjA" hash="6R7hNQ">Latter-day Saints Keep on Trying</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p2" pid="P5ehDcyQl06X7RsqyWrmFg" hash="0khSQw">By Elder Dale G. Renlund</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p3" pid="YI9FW8B45k-dWvx_NjJKWQ" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=uqy5zb2OuUmzb53U2jGX5g"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" type="jpg" uri="dale-g-renlund-10.jpg" translate="no" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x279="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/200x279.jpg" data-src-320x446="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/320x446.jpg" data-src-460x642="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/460x642.jpg" data-src-640x893="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/640x893.jpg" data-src-1024x1429="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/1024x1429.jpg" data-src-2048x2858="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/2048x2858.jpg" data-src-4041x5640="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/4041x5640.jpg" pid="uqy5zb2OuUmzb53U2jGX5g" hash="49lsIA"></img></a>
		</div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="NPJjglNe3U-6J4L0NM1q0A" hash="ERDRyw">As we try, persevere, and help others to do the same, we are true Latter-day Saints.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="BSOkxGDghUq2sItv4zSVBQ" hash="0khSQw1">By Elder Dale G. Renlund</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="JzI12mXFwEyHvYYbYQFi3w" hash="RNRs9A">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p5" pid="CGr0GmrrDUmo9-KSeRV-bQ" hash="R4FRXg">My dear brothers and sisters, in December 2013 the world mourned the death of Nelson Mandela. After 27 years of imprisonment for his role in the antiapartheid struggle, Mandela was the first democratically elected president of South Africa. His forgiveness of those who had imprisoned him was remarkable. He received widespread acclaim and praise.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Mandela frequently deflected accolades by saying, “I’m no saint—that is, unless you think a saint is a sinner who keeps on trying.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p6" pid="bEs_I1ShTUG6P1Vr8X5osw" hash="Vz9uLA">This statement—“a saint is a sinner who keeps on trying”—should reassure and encourage members of the Church. Although we are referred to as “Latter-day Saints,” we sometimes flinch at this reference. The term <span class="emphasis">Saints</span> is commonly used to designate those who have achieved an elevated state of holiness or even perfection. And we know perfectly well that we are not perfect.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p7" pid="8ZfJyZ67JUmgDe1xXeAHBA" hash="HExynA">Our theology does teach us, though, that we may be perfected by repeatedly and iteratively “relying wholly upon” the doctrine of Christ: exercising faith in Him, repenting, partaking of the sacrament to renew the covenants and blessings of baptism, and receiving the Holy Ghost as a constant companion to a greater degree. As we do so, we become more like Christ and are able to endure to the end, with all that that entails.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> In less formal terms, God cares a lot more about who we are and who we are becoming than about who we once were.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> He cares that we keep on trying.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p8" pid="6ijBmn0SH0WWdaCzX0OIZQ" hash="6C0IqQ">The comedy <span class="emphasis">As You Like It,</span> written by the English playwright William Shakespeare, depicts a dramatic change in a character’s life. An older brother attempts to have his younger brother killed. Even knowing this, the younger brother saves his wicked brother from certain death. When the older brother learns of this undeserved compassion, he is totally and forever changed and has what he calls a “conversion.” Later several women approach the older brother and ask, “Was’t you that did so oft contrive to kill [your brother]?”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p9" pid="fDIJHFMn9UmMl2m0hyWsRA" hash="Z0s8ew">The older brother answers, “’Twas I; but ’tis not I: I do not shame to tell you what I was, since my conversion so sweetly tastes, being the thing I am.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p10" pid="VDJp24aEG0KNrv8kNW2XWQ" hash="5U54ew">For us, because of God’s mercy and the Atonement of Jesus Christ, such a change is not just literary fiction. Through Ezekiel, the Lord declared:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p11" pid="oWn52Uyfb0qnlzfoXZrSWw" hash="PcqOXw">“As for the wickedness of the wicked, he shall not fall thereby in the day that he turneth from his wickedness. …</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p12" pid="qQmeB2N810C2FEfdZtR7Pw" hash="dUNoxg">“… If he turn from his sin, and do that which is lawful and right;</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p13" pid="_zJJSemRG069MF2WfMo_9Q" hash="L8N89A">“… Restore the pledge, give again that he had robbed, walk in the statutes of life, without committing iniquity; he shall surely live. …</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p14" pid="l5hG7nrAGE2apQP41ILdEQ" hash="GR55XA">“None of his sins that he hath committed shall be mentioned unto him: he hath done that which is lawful and right.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p15" pid="jphwm66ZIEmtD8I0dPwTyA" hash="N6FGDA">In His mercy, God promises forgiveness when we repent and turn from wickedness—so much so that our sins will not even be mentioned to us. For us, because of the Atonement of Christ and our repentance, we can look at our past deeds and say, “’Twas I; but ’tis not I.” No matter how wicked, we can say, “That’s who I was. But that past wicked self is no longer who I am.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p16" pid="3eF4m2P9jUiXo0WsEt7wqg" hash="ClI8ng">President Thomas S. Monson has taught, “One of God’s greatest gifts to us is the joy of trying again, for no failure ever need be final.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Even if we’ve been a conscious, deliberate sinner or have repeatedly faced failure and disappointment, the moment we decide to try again, the Atonement of Christ can help us. And we need to remember that it is not the Holy Ghost that tells us we’re so far gone that we might as well give up.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p17" pid="VpVLXIVkkU2vEpWJNMoU4g" hash="GcCmIw">God’s desire that Latter-day Saints keep on trying also extends beyond overcoming sin. Whether we suffer because of troubled relationships, economic challenges, or illnesses or as a consequence of someone else’s sins, the Savior’s infinite Atonement can heal even—and perhaps especially—those who have innocently suffered. He understands perfectly what it is like to suffer innocently as a consequence of another’s transgression. As prophesied, the Savior will “bind up the brokenhearted, … give … beauty for ashes, the oil of joy for mourning, [and] the garment of praise for the spirit of heaviness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> No matter what, with His help, God expects Latter-day Saints to keep on trying.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p18" pid="uzqA1rnv_Eep6mjDlvBRSg" hash="RUKnbQ">Just as God rejoices when we persevere, He is disappointed if we do not recognize that others are trying too. Our dear friend Thoba shared how she learned this lesson from her mother, Julia. Julia and Thoba were among the early black converts in South Africa. After the apartheid regime ended, black and white members of the Church were permitted to attend church together. For many, the equality of interaction between the races was new and challenging. One time, as Julia and Thoba attended church, they felt they were treated less than kindly by some white members. As they left, Thoba complained bitterly to her mother. Julia listened calmly until Thoba had vented her frustration. Then Julia said, “Oh, Thoba, the Church is like a big hospital, and we are all sick in our own way. We come to church to be helped.”</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p19" pid="JmheIuybSEKvwGNcm7ylyQ" hash="5iCOFw">Julia’s comment reflects a valuable insight. We must not only be tolerant while others work on their individual illnesses; we must also be kind, patient, supportive, and understanding. As God encourages us to keep on trying, He expects us to also allow others the space to do the same, at their own pace. The Atonement will come into our lives in even greater measure. We will then recognize that regardless of perceived differences, all of us are in need of the same infinite Atonement.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p20" pid="k1o1WXllekySoB8BkGhFpA" hash="zaBnsw">Some years ago a wonderful young man named Curtis was called to serve a mission. He was the kind of missionary every mission president prays for. He was focused and worked hard. At one point he was assigned a missionary companion who was immature, socially awkward, and not particularly enthusiastic about getting the work done.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p21" pid="QoVclIWrDUW6JWSwL5ngqw" hash="OLqTgA">One day, while they were riding their bicycles, Curtis looked back and saw that his companion had inexplicably gotten off his bike and was walking. Silently, Curtis expressed his frustration to God; what a chore it was to be saddled with a companion he had to drag around in order to accomplish anything. Moments later, Curtis had a profound impression, as if God were saying to him, “You know, Curtis, compared to me, the two of you aren’t all that different.” Curtis learned that he needed to be patient with an imperfect companion who nonetheless was trying in his own way.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p22" pid="ITBvpmly_0WaMGmIF8UuwQ" hash="eIdLQA">My invitation to all of us is to evaluate our lives, repent, and keep on trying. If we don’t try, we’re just latter-day sinners; if we don’t persevere, we’re latter-day quitters; and if we don’t allow others to try, we’re just latter-day hypocrites.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> As we try, persevere, and help others to do the same, we are true Latter-day Saints. As we change, we will find that God indeed cares a lot more about who we are and about who we are becoming than about who we once were.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying.p23" pid="iOxJXfQ9p0GNWNXa7NWLfQ" hash="5s0gtQ">I am deeply grateful for the Savior, for His infinite Atonement, and for latter-day prophets who encourage us to be Latter-day Saints, to keep on trying.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> I witness of the Savior’s living reality in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/04/latter-day-saints-keep-on-trying</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2015-general-conference/2015-04-2070-elder-dale-g-renlund-64k-eng.mp3" length="5032867" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Through God’s Eyes</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/10/through-gods-eyes?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Dale G. Renlund teaches that to truly serve others, we need to see them as Heavenly Father sees them.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/through-gods-eyes" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13768_000_53renlund" doc-version="2" hash="_T81DQ">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/through-gods-eyes.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="sc86lFAMGkyGaQcZ3ubFWw" hash="cpO7-A">Through God’s Eyes</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/through-gods-eyes.p2" pid="MQyZPAR0yU2BhzzM_YjcTA" hash="0khSQw">By Elder Dale G. Renlund</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/through-gods-eyes.p3" pid="7IVqiPSU6UiLMet9cHC1ZA" hash="F9R90A">Of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=uodNHIe_ZEqSc00USzyDEw"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" alt="Elder Dale G. Renlund" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x279="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/200x279.jpg" data-src-320x446="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/320x446.jpg" data-src-460x642="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/460x642.jpg" data-src-640x893="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/640x893.jpg" data-src-1024x1429="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/1024x1429.jpg" data-src-2048x2858="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/2048x2858.jpg" data-src-4041x5640="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255572/78dd5d9226b04058b3c3b72bcb03538f/4041x5640.jpg" pid="uodNHIe_ZEqSc00USzyDEw" hash="ucpXbQ"></img></a></div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="LxZ8TJPTVUSWSwcaVuZEvQ" hash="l00qxg">To effectively serve others, we must see them through a parent’s eyes, through Heavenly Father’s eyes.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="eCAE4_hOaEqIqitgAQSv2g" hash="18jqNA">Dale G. Renlund</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/through-gods-eyes.p5" pid="_x8KOocxo0O4OUD-nAK7rg" hash="dtXDMA">My dear brothers and sisters, thank you for sustaining me yesterday as a member of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles. It is hard to express how much that means to me. I was especially grateful for the sustaining vote of the two extraordinary women in my life: my wife, Ruth, and our dear, dear, dear daughter, Ashley.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/through-gods-eyes.p6" pid="TrieIMtU90ugiEXIkXsw9w" hash="sk8VrA">My call gives ample evidence to the truthfulness of the Lord’s statement early in this dispensation: “That the fulness of my gospel might be proclaimed by the weak and the simple unto the ends of the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> I am one of those weak and simple. Decades ago, when I was called to be the bishop of a ward in the eastern United States, my brother, slightly older and much wiser than I, called me on the phone. He said, “You need to know that the Lord hasn’t called you because of anything you have done. In your case, it is probably in spite of what you have done. The Lord has called you for what He needs to do through you, and that will happen only if you do it His way.” I recognize that this wisdom from an older brother applies even more today.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/through-gods-eyes.p7" pid="8sm_yB9dG0CYkgd9-6vMfA" hash="sQsNBQ">Something wonderful happens in a missionary’s service when he or she realizes that the calling is not about him or her; rather, it is about the Lord, His work, and Heavenly Father’s children. I feel the same is true for an Apostle. This calling is not about me. It’s about the Lord, His work, and Heavenly Father’s children. No matter what the assignment or calling is in the Church, to serve capably, one must serve knowing that everyone we serve “is a beloved spirit son or daughter of heavenly parents, and, as such, … has a divine nature and destiny.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/through-gods-eyes.p8" pid="9zbbOz0-fkm-bt7z3iU1uA" hash="DcZ0WQ">In my past profession, I was a cardiologist specializing in heart failure and transplantation, with many patients who were critically ill. My wife jokingly says that it was a bad prognostic sign to become one of my patients. All teasing aside, I saw many people die, and I developed a kind of emotional distance when things went poorly. That way, feelings of sadness and disappointment were tempered.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/through-gods-eyes.p9" pid="bWkcGDyw-UmWhNpcQcr9gA" hash="juLpeA">In 1986 a young man named Chad developed heart failure and received a heart transplant. He did very well for a decade and a half. Chad did all he could to stay healthy and live as normal a life as possible. He served a mission, worked, and was a devoted son to his parents. The last few years of his life, though, were challenging, and he was in and out of the hospital frequently.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/through-gods-eyes.p10" pid="-H5P-7UUYUCCz00Die355Q" hash="cviOug">One evening, he was brought to the hospital’s emergency department in full cardiac arrest. My associates and I worked for a long time to restore his circulation. Finally, it became clear that Chad could not be revived. We stopped our futile efforts, and I declared him dead. Although sad and disappointed, I maintained a professional attitude. I thought to myself, “Chad has had good care. He has had many more years of life than he otherwise would have had.” That emotional distance soon shattered as his parents came into the emergency room bay and saw their deceased son lying on a stretcher. In that moment, I saw Chad through his mother’s and father’s eyes. I saw the great hopes and expectations they had had for him, the desire they had had that he would live just a little bit longer and a little bit better. With this realization, I began to weep. In an ironic reversal of roles and in an act of kindness I will never forget, Chad’s parents comforted me.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/through-gods-eyes.p11" pid="Nci94q7wf0C7t0GU2SZsOg" hash="VWVhiQ">I now realize that in the Church, to effectively serve others we must see them through a parent’s eyes, through Heavenly Father’s eyes. Only then can we begin to comprehend the true worth of a soul. Only then can we sense the love that Heavenly Father has for all of His children. Only then can we sense the Savior’s caring concern for them. We cannot completely fulfill our covenant obligation to mourn with those who mourn and comfort those who stand in need of comfort unless we see them through God’s eyes.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> This expanded perspective will open our hearts to the disappointments, fears, and heartaches of others. But Heavenly Father will aid and comfort us, just as Chad’s parents comforted me years ago. We need to have eyes that see, ears that hear, and hearts that know and feel if we are to accomplish the rescue so frequently encouraged by President Thomas S. Monson.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/through-gods-eyes.p12" pid="LnSlqB4tAke9RzMfWbg1lw" hash="5Nu-JQ">Only when we see through Heavenly Father’s eyes can we be filled with “the pure love of Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Every day we should plead with God for this love. Mormon admonished, “Wherefore, my beloved brethren, pray unto the Father with all the energy of heart, that ye may be filled with this love, which he hath bestowed upon all who are true followers of his Son, Jesus Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/through-gods-eyes.p13" pid="-DjopgsuEECP_oFoUOGSTw" hash="hakC2w">With all my heart I want to be a true follower of Jesus Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> I love Him. I adore Him. I witness of His living reality. I witness that He is the Anointed One, the Messiah. I am a witness of His incomparable mercy, compassion, and love. I add my testimony to that of the Apostles who, in the year 2000, stated “that Jesus is the Living Christ, the immortal Son of God. … He is the light, the life, and the hope of the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/through-gods-eyes.p14" pid="zvRUsbpdYkCJHaphqoqbnQ" hash="C-LaWg">I testify that on a day in 1820 in a grove in upstate New York, the risen Lord appeared, along with God, our Heavenly Father, to the Prophet Joseph Smith, just as Joseph Smith said They did. Priesthood keys are on earth today to enable saving and exalting ordinances. I know it. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/10/through-gods-eyes</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2015-general-conference/2015-10-4040-elder-dale-g-renlund-64k-eng.mp3" length="3345707" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“That I Might Draw All Men unto Me”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13285_000_27renlund" doc-version="3" hash="nTl2jQ"&gt;
	
	&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.head1"&gt;
		&lt;h1 class="title" pid="m8AmEmBo5U-ZnUgLcHaBQQ" hash="wPCVvg"&gt;“That I Might Draw All Men unto Me”&lt;/h1&gt;
		&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p2" pid="hNgmhGvQTkmE2nV-3GkfWw" hash="0khSQw1"&gt;By Elder Dale G. Renlund&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p3" pid="ivW8J7JGbk6Q6XHiBzY-PA" hash="F9R90A"&gt;Of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles&lt;/p&gt; 
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=zGfLGgjquky1HHDyrO4Qhw"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" altText="Elder Dale G. Renlund" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1658854/f6838dbffca6469c841b97cab319324e/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1658854/f6838dbffca6469c841b97cab319324e/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1658854/f6838dbffca6469c841b97cab319324e/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x279="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1658854/f6838dbffca6469c841b97cab319324e/200x279.jpg" data-src-320x446="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1658854/f6838dbffca6469c841b97cab319324e/320x446.jpg" data-src-460x642="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1658854/f6838dbffca6469c841b97cab319324e/460x642.jpg" data-src-640x893="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1658854/f6838dbffca6469c841b97cab319324e/640x893.jpg" data-src-1024x1429="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1658854/f6838dbffca6469c841b97cab319324e/1024x1429.jpg" data-src-2048x2858="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1658854/f6838dbffca6469c841b97cab319324e/2048x2858.jpg" data-src-4041x5640="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1658854/f6838dbffca6469c841b97cab319324e/4041x5640.jpg" webURL="dale-renlund-portrait-apostle_1658854.jpg" pid="zGfLGgjquky1HHDyrO4Qhw" hash="AAAAAA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="kicker" pid="p4YDjKssCkG8s08zyVsyEA" hash="1Hik4w"&gt;As we draw closer to God, the enabling power of the Atonement of Jesus Christ will come into our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="authorName" pid="M9ZzLAa7dEGRpD5GcC3oqw" hash="0khSQw"&gt;By Elder Dale G. Renlund&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class="bodyBlock"&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p5" pid="5D7qhKJm70yBkpjZzYmjxA" hash="ZhWIDg"&gt;My dear brothers and sisters, while living in Africa, I sought advice from Elder Wilford W. Andersen of the Seventy about helping Saints who live in poverty. Among the remarkable insights he shared with me was this: “The greater the distance between the giver and the receiver, the more the receiver develops a sense of entitlement.”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p6" pid="tyk92oANOk2wQkvvl1rXBA" hash="9mSQsw"&gt;This principle underlies the Church’s welfare system. When members are not able to meet their own needs, they turn first to their families. Thereafter, if necessary, they can also turn to their local Church leaders for assistance with their temporal needs.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; Family members and local Church leaders are closest to those in need, frequently have faced similar circumstances, and understand best how to help. Because of their proximity to the givers, recipients who receive help according to this pattern are grateful and less likely to feel entitled.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p7" pid="fOaWWgtO5kWCebKwHPaMLQ" hash="2ISYiQ"&gt;The concept—“the greater the distance between the giver and the receiver, the more the receiver develops a sense of entitlement”—also has profound spiritual applications. Our Heavenly Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, are the ultimate Givers. The more we distance ourselves from Them, the more entitled we feel. We begin to think that we deserve grace and are owed blessings. We are more prone to look around, identify inequities, and feel aggrieved—even offended—by the unfairness we perceive. While the unfairness can range from trivial to gut-wrenching, when we are distant from God, even small inequities loom large. We feel that God has an obligation to fix things—and fix them right now!&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p8" pid="Im-eIeTxa0aAdBzJohvatA" hash="M8c-Sw"&gt;The difference made by our proximity to Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ is illustrated in the Book of Mormon in the stark contrast between Nephi and his older brothers Laman and Lemuel:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;ul class="bullet"&gt;
			&lt;li pid="R6WC5MAen0mXPd1i3r9gvg" hash="EDzjAg"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p9" pid="NcJ1zXiIYUm42gCS4Wqa_w" hash="i6CNqg"&gt;Nephi had “great desires to know of the mysteries of God, wherefore, [he] did cry unto the Lord,” and his heart was softened.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; On the other hand, Laman and Lemuel were distant from God—they did not know Him.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="ov076UoOYUCnrnajhtu5hQ" hash="KM0cXQ"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p10" pid="iMvJy6DqQEKML4-AsXF1lg" hash="LxFkCg"&gt;Nephi accepted challenging assignments without complaint, but Laman and Lemuel “did murmur in many things.” Murmuring is the scriptural equivalent of childish whining. The scripture records that “they did murmur because they knew not the dealings of that God who had created them.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="Bxpf-Gg1QkmNC1oP0Dvviw" hash="7v8I9w"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p11" pid="F0xVOYAHF0mBnLVPczMxfQ" hash="bls82g"&gt;Nephi’s closeness to God enabled him to recognize and appreciate God’s “tender mercies.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; In contrast, when Laman and Lemuel saw Nephi receiving blessings, they “were wroth with him because they understood not the dealings of the Lord.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; Laman and Lemuel saw the blessings that they received as their due and petulantly assumed that they should have more. They seemed to view Nephi’s blessings as “wrongs” committed against them. This is the scriptural equivalent of disgruntled entitlement.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="7u0t43LpgEeMfDLd9GeCFA" hash="AyZCVA"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p12" pid="auxAJBBSj0u_Zp1SdBLoLw" hash="J_DFbQ"&gt;Nephi exercised faith in God to accomplish what he was asked to do.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; In contrast, Laman and Lemuel, “being hard in their hearts, … did not look unto the Lord as they ought.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt; They seemed to feel that the Lord was obligated to provide answers to questions that they had not posed. “The Lord maketh no such thing known unto us,” they said, but they did not even make the effort to ask.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8"&gt;8&lt;/span&gt; This is the scriptural equivalent of derisive skepticism.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p13" pid="NA1fjsPLuU2uu_JhXuLq5Q" hash="wyTcUw"&gt;Because they were distant from the Savior, Laman and Lemuel murmured, became contentious, and were faithless. They felt that life was unfair and that they were entitled to God’s grace. In contrast, because he had drawn close to God, Nephi must have recognized that life would be the most unfair for Jesus Christ. Though absolutely innocent, the Savior would suffer the most.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p14" pid="7D5ZjvWbjkuo2DzC4lQ9cQ" hash="11I04g"&gt;The closer we are to Jesus Christ in the thoughts and intents of our hearts, the more we appreciate His innocent suffering, the more grateful we are for grace and forgiveness, and the more we want to repent and become like Him. Our absolute distance from Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ is important, but the direction we are heading is even more crucial. God is more pleased with repentant sinners who are trying to draw closer to Him than with self-righteous, faultfinding individuals who, like the Pharisees and scribes of old, do not realize how badly they need to repent.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9"&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p15" pid="Q4vI4bvINUuZd2zoClYtrg" hash="hFYrww"&gt;As a child, I sang a Swedish Christmas carol that teaches a simple but powerful lesson—drawing near to the Savior &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;causes&lt;/span&gt; us to change. The lyrics go something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;div class="poetry"&gt;
			&lt;div class="stanza"&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p16" pid="J-ZhhcSebUyhaZKl9Q1LKQ" hash="1hOs3Q1"&gt;When Christmas morning gleams&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p17" pid="qFkN100nmEq2XKbbCXPP6g" hash="2KBdcw1"&gt;I want to go to the stable,&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p18" pid="Koqm8ZKpYkiNiRRuDBbXZQ" hash="w33xag"&gt;Where God in the nighttime hours&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p19" pid="GmD5tzEkbkWSaApzxq_gWg" hash="2V2uiQ"&gt;Already rests upon the straw.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;div class="stanza"&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p20" pid="_KsEY_ZwykC7ezo_2_3JXw" hash="TVC9rA1"&gt;How good Thou wast to desire&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p21" pid="ZthQOY6pwEaA3vFbBU4lMw" hash="mEg97A1"&gt;To come down to the earth!&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p22" pid="9XjASCcZD02r7E_vNXfaSw" hash="yCr2CQ"&gt;Now, I do not wish to waste&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p23" pid="TRCPEvzlIU2scHS_WJHrdQ" hash="lM-LpQ"&gt;My childhood days in sin anymore!&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;div class="stanza"&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p24" pid="U9xsDP8SOkiuS9LqiyN13g" hash="wVV-zw"&gt;Jesus, we need Thee,&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p25" pid="dU9omgskmEak6osy-Z8JOA" hash="dDJaEA"&gt;Thou dear children’s friend.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p26" pid="R0ttlz0EKkCjW51qWbqgzg" hash="EroCEA"&gt;I no longer wish to grieve Thee&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p27" pid="ez2GsBwaRkW1u1opVzizFQ" hash="zJv05A"&gt;With my sins again.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p28" pid="HYc2GOrRnk2sWqdCRkcfnQ" hash="uQL5HA"&gt;When we figuratively transport ourselves to the Bethlehem stable, “where God in the nighttime hours already rests upon the straw,” we can recognize better the Savior as a gift from a kind, loving Heavenly Father. Rather than feeling entitled to His blessings and grace, we develop an intense desire to stop causing God further grief.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p29" pid="0RxWyX3JI02wQK0wInHQHg" hash="Cnw0Zw"&gt;Whatever our current direction or distance to Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ, we can choose to turn toward Them and draw closer to Them. They will help us. As the Savior told the Nephites following His Resurrection:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p30" pid="D0qGtVDE4ESQytyYloqd6w" hash="oDKAxw"&gt;“And my Father sent me that I might be lifted up upon the cross; and after that I had been lifted up upon the cross, that I might draw all men unto me, …&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p31" pid="HP_xh87NWUmSTWP00l7NZw" hash="nywCJA"&gt;“And for this cause have I been lifted up; therefore, according to the power of the Father I will draw all men unto me.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11"&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p32" pid="wPLoToSCEUCE9CKfX-GZVA" hash="a_Qorw"&gt;To draw closer to the Savior, we must increase our faith in Him, make and keep covenants, and have the Holy Ghost with us. We must also act in faith, responding to the spiritual direction we receive. All of these elements come together in the sacrament. Indeed, the best way I know of to draw closer to God is to prepare conscientiously and partake worthily of the sacrament each week.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p33" pid="k8RxRNpl6Ua2CvXYjC0Qag" hash="LpsGmg"&gt;A friend of ours in South Africa shared how she came to this realization. When Diane was a new convert, she attended a branch outside of Johannesburg. One Sunday, as she sat in the congregation, the layout of the chapel made it so that the deacon did not see her as the sacrament was passed. Diane was disappointed but said nothing. Another member noted the omission and mentioned it to the branch president after the meeting. As Sunday School began, Diane was invited to an empty classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p34" pid="2aop1mCAokeR-OqbmYMonQ" hash="pyR6Sw"&gt;A priesthood holder came in. He knelt down, blessed some bread, and handed her a piece. She ate it. He knelt down again and blessed some water and handed her a small cup. She drank it. Thereafter, Diane had two thoughts in rapid succession: First, “Oh, he [the priesthood holder] did this just for me.” And then, “Oh, He [the Savior] did this just for me.” Diane felt Heavenly Father’s love.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p35" pid="ERS_L411TEKF2c341w2xBA" hash="G3OS2g"&gt;Her realization that the Savior’s sacrifice was just for her helped her feel close to Him and fueled an overwhelming desire to keep that feeling in her heart, not just on Sunday but every day. She realized that although she sat in a congregation to partake of the sacrament, the covenants she made anew each Sunday were individually hers. The sacrament helped—and continues to help—Diane feel the power of godly love, recognize the Lord’s hand in her life, and draw closer to the Savior.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p36" pid="jNpjy2JpqkKYzZx3aScu9w" hash="_K8YGQ"&gt;The Savior identified the sacrament as indispensable to a spiritual foundation. He said:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p37" pid="DAFE-IThS0qjAMdNJrtAUw" hash="Sl0-0A"&gt;“And I give unto you a commandment that ye shall do these things [partake of the sacrament]. And if ye shall always do these things blessed are ye, for ye are built upon my rock.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p38" pid="nz6XMlvDsUKfE52zK-QGtQ" hash="oEn_qA"&gt;“But whoso among you shall do more or less than these are not built upon my rock, but are built upon a sandy foundation; and when the rain descends, and the floods come, and the winds blow, and beat upon them, they shall fall.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12"&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p39" pid="iK5lXKxrVUeRAErioH5HXw" hash="OWaBDA"&gt;Jesus did not say “&lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; rain descends, &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; floods come, and &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; winds blow” but “&lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;when.&lt;/span&gt;” No one is immune from life’s challenges; we all need the safety that comes from partaking of the sacrament.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p40" pid="fgE6vU4a_kmLbKBOH2_dkQ" hash="MKIvuA"&gt;On the day of the Savior’s Resurrection, two disciples traveled to a village called Emmaus. Unrecognized, the risen Lord joined them on the journey. As they traveled, He taught them from the scriptures. When they reached their destination, they invited Him to dine with them.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p41" pid="U1rbgsVqSE-e1nuTwBWd3g" hash="DM-LVQ"&gt;“And it came to pass, as he sat at meat with them, he took bread, and blessed it, and brake, and gave to them.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p42" pid="X6ZOwRUuNku6YQ6-LthBCw" hash="_OYLEQ"&gt;“And their eyes were opened, and they knew him; and he vanished out of their sight.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p43" pid="2mjZb9JLYECry1hMWdplvQ" hash="6MNxgA"&gt;“And they said one to another, Did not our heart burn within us, while he talked with us by the way, and while he opened to us the scriptures?&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p44" pid="njFs3CiDZUSs3ekFqdBrTw" hash="CFboJg"&gt;“And they rose up the same hour, and returned to Jerusalem, and found the eleven [Apostles] gathered together.”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p45" pid="u20pUD8CI0-kmKr0sIgMcQ" hash="zT_RIw"&gt;And then they testified to the Apostles that “the Lord is risen indeed. …&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p46" pid="gfzUQNL_202V-2Gt4DHjhg" hash="gRENQg"&gt;“And they told what things were done in the way, and how he was known of them in breaking of bread.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p47" pid="tnsw3f8XmUuCqbmulAJNFg" hash="PH6CFg"&gt;The sacrament truly helps us know our Savior. It also reminds us of His innocent suffering. If life were truly fair, you and I would never be resurrected; you and I would never be able to stand clean before God. In this respect, I am grateful that life is not fair.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p48" pid="AydfJOn9XEi4ufaFN0MSwg" hash="1p4puQ"&gt;At the same time, I can emphatically state that because of the Atonement of Jesus Christ, ultimately, in the eternal scheme of things, there will be no unfairness. “All that is unfair about life can be made right.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14"&gt;14&lt;/span&gt; Our present circumstances may not change, but through God’s compassion, kindness, and love, we will all receive more than we deserve, more than we can ever earn, and more than we can ever hope for. We are promised that “God shall wipe away all tears from [our] eyes; and there shall be no more death, neither sorrow, nor crying, neither shall there be any more pain: for the former things are passed away.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15"&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p49" pid="AuH360U-h0CzEe5beFl_Bg" hash="OYpfLg"&gt;No matter where you stand in your relationship to God, I invite you to draw nearer to Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ, the Ultimate Benefactors and Givers of all that is good. I invite you to attend sacrament meeting each week and partake of the holy emblems of the Savior’s body and blood. I invite you to feel God’s nearness as He is made known to you, as He was to the disciples of old, in the “breaking of [the] bread.”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me.p50" pid="NAbkW6zjvkidpaj0Zyh2Cg" hash="w_II5A"&gt;As you do, I promise that you will feel nearer to God. Natural tendencies to childish whining, disgruntled entitlement, and derisive skepticism will dissipate. Those sentiments will be replaced by feelings of greater love and gratitude for Heavenly Father’s gift of His Son. As we draw closer to God, the enabling power of the Atonement of Jesus Christ will come into our lives. And, as with the disciples on the way to Emmaus, we will find that the Savior has been nearby all along. I so witness and testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/04/that-i-might-draw-all-men-unto-me</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2016-general-conference/2016-04-1070-dale-g-renlund-64k-eng.mp3" length="6565653" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Repentance: A Joyful Choice</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Renlund teaches that repentance is a choice we can make because of the Savior’s Atonement and that repenting can lead to joy.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60001311_000_67renlund" doc-version="1" hash="yOyOlg">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="SOaMS0v9OUCwAsFA_RpOBw" hash="Ku3Lcg">Repentance: A Joyful Choice</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p2" pid="anDe5NfqWE6DDVvtzfYLXA" hash="0khSQw1">By Elder Dale G. Renlund</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p3" pid="5nTut4w69kWwdE00ACqR7A" hash="F9R90A">Of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="FPT6aC2dsUS-ZzKWorPgLA" hash="gTftsw">Repentance is not only possible but also joyful because of our Savior.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="ite6OXdlv0-UVCwtRmjetA" hash="0khSQw">By Elder Dale G. Renlund</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p5" pid="uxTNsNru00CyFCbjI7FYcA" hash="h984hA">My dear brothers and sisters, when I was 12 years old, my family lived in Göteborg, a coastal city in southern Sweden. By way of reference, it is the hometown of our dear associate Elder Per G. Malm,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> who passed away this summer. We miss him. We’re grateful for his nobility and his noble service and for the example of his absolutely adorable family. And we certainly pray God’s richest blessings to be theirs.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p6" pid="LSDTq732RUqX5w5Hgj5LfQ" hash="7MlVqQ">Fifty years ago, we attended church in a large remodeled home. One Sunday, my friend Steffan,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> the only other deacon in the branch, greeted me at church with some excitement. We went to the chapel’s adjacent overflow area, and he pulled from his pocket a large firecracker and some matches. In an act of youthful bravado, I took the firecracker and lit the long gray fuse. I intended to snuff out the fuse before it blew up. But when I burned my fingers trying to do so, I dropped the firecracker. Steffan and I watched in horror as the fuse continued to burn.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p7" pid="Jcnxvu5DWkGQw6gLmVgeGg" hash="ZGhlaA">The firecracker exploded, and sulfurous fumes filled the overflow area and the chapel. We hurriedly gathered up the scattered remnants of the firecracker and opened the windows to try to get the smell out, naively hoping that no one would notice. Fortunately, no one was hurt and no damage was done.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p8" pid="h_4dHeCOLU28j545jOWyvw" hash="sFgs4A">As members came to the meeting, they did notice the overpowering smell. It was hard to miss. The smell distracted from the sacred nature of the meeting. Because there were so few Aaronic Priesthood holders—and in what can only be described as dissociative thinking—I passed the sacrament, yet I did not feel worthy to partake of it. When the sacrament tray was offered to me, I took neither the bread nor the water. I felt horrible. I was embarrassed, and I knew that what I had done had displeased God.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p9" pid="UWvOmt9-UECe42pSPIkTSA" hash="xZIGjQ">After church, the branch president, Frank Lindberg, a distinguished older man with silver-gray hair, asked me to come to his office. After I sat down, he looked at me kindly and said he had noticed that I had not partaken of the sacrament. He asked why. I suspect he knew why. I was sure everyone knew what I had done. After I told him, he asked how I felt. Through tears, I haltingly told him I was sorry and that I knew I had let God down.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p10" pid="9hFvItDLl0-6y1VROVOo6w" hash="cRLbwA">President Lindberg opened a well-worn copy of the Doctrine and Covenants and asked me to read some underlined verses. I read the following out loud:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p11" pid="4v2Fs_w99kWjPYYKkGBL_A" hash="cVr-iw">“Behold, he who has repented of his sins, the same is forgiven, and I, the Lord, remember them no more.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p12" pid="SZZKzl7hC0GXZVf-XYez_A" hash="R0B3Nw">“By this ye may know if a man repenteth of his sins—behold, he will confess them and forsake them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p13" pid="We-JeNN4KUKyKaNrEQ955g" hash="8cxEAg">I will never forget President Lindberg’s compassionate smile when I looked up after I had finished reading. With some emotion, he told me that he felt it would be fine for me to resume partaking of the sacrament. As I left his office, I felt indescribable joy.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p14" pid="QNDg9wMmK0eTAL27eA31nA" hash="unX7_g">Such joy is one of the inherent results of repentance. The word <span class="emphasis">repent</span> connotes “to perceive afterwards” and implies “change.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> In Swedish, the word is <span class="emphasis">omvänd,</span> which simply means “to turn around.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> The Christian writer C. S. Lewis wrote about the need and the method for change. He noted that repentance involves “being put back on the right road. A wrong sum can be put right,” he said, “but only by going back till you find the error and working it afresh from that point, never by simply <span class="emphasis">going on.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> Changing our behavior and returning to the “right road” are part of repentance, but only part. Real repentance also includes a turning of our heart and will to God and a renunciation of sin.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> As explained in Ezekiel, to repent is to “turn from … sin, … do that which is lawful and right; … restore the pledge, … [and] walk in the statutes of life, without committing iniquity.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p15" pid="dS82Hr17zkOdMorSDDk7EQ" hash="cpUDhg">Yet even this is an incomplete description. It does not properly identify the power that makes repentance possible, the atoning sacrifice of our Savior. Real repentance must involve faith in the Lord Jesus Christ, faith that He can change us, faith that He can forgive us, and faith that He will help us avoid more mistakes. This kind of faith makes His Atonement effective in our lives. When we “perceive afterwards” and “turn around” with the Savior’s help, we can feel hope in His promises and the joy of forgiveness. Without the Redeemer, the inherent hope and joy evaporate, and repentance becomes simply miserable behavior modification. But by exercising faith in Him, we become converted to His ability and willingness to forgive sin.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p16" pid="HjMbX3Pne0evZ9b0o8w-eQ" hash="LC1rNQ">President Boyd K. Packer affirmed the hopeful promises of repentance in April 2015 at his last general conference. He described the power of the Savior’s Atonement to heal in what I consider the distillation of the wisdom gained in half a century of apostolic service. President Packer said: “The Atonement leaves no tracks, no traces. What it fixes is fixed. … It just heals, and what it heals stays healed.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p17" pid="05Wy3tLeIUaFPpQb-GA7Hw" hash="xQatOw">He continued:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p18" pid="05qA2ZC8zU2AWxCLifIDWA" hash="2eaGiQ">“The Atonement, which can reclaim each one of us, bears no scars. That means that no matter what we have done or where we have been or how something happened, if we truly repent, [the Savior] has promised that He would atone. And when He atoned, that settled that. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p19" pid="nuMiitwVt0iVBgVu8VPp3Q" hash="uudtdA">“… The Atonement … can wash clean every stain no matter how difficult or how long or how many times repeated.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p20" pid="gmYV0Gxub0SD9oH43Azr8Q" hash="7VNOLA">The reach of the Savior’s Atonement is infinite in breadth and depth, for you and for me. But it will never be imposed on us. As the prophet Lehi explained, after we “are instructed sufficiently” to “know good from evil,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> we “are free to choose liberty and eternal life, through the great Mediator of all men, or to choose captivity and death.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> In other words, repentance is a choice.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p21" pid="eRol5taRwEGk3KiHIH-T3A" hash="ssPJLA">We can—and sometimes do—make different choices. Such choices may not seem intrinsically wrong, but they prevent us from becoming truly penitent and thus preclude our pursuit of real repentance. For instance, we may choose to blame others. As a 12-year-old in Göteborg, I could have blamed Steffan. He was the one who brought the big firecracker and the matches to the church in the first place. But blaming others, even if justified, allows us to excuse our behavior. By so doing, we shift responsibility for our actions to others. When the responsibility is shifted, we diminish both the need and our ability to act. We turn ourselves into hapless victims rather than agents capable of independent action.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p22" pid="RwMqC06I6kaavAfTVvknCA" hash="wojPGw">Another choice that impedes repentance is minimizing our mistakes. In the Göteborg firecracker incident, no one was hurt, no permanent damage occurred, and the meeting was held anyway. It would have been easy to say that there was no reason to repent. But minimizing our mistakes, even if no immediate consequences are apparent, removes the motivation to change. This thinking prevents us from seeing that our mistakes and sins have eternal consequences.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p23" pid="MAAuhmwxfkyv_IJooWm09Q" hash="YPIDaQ">Yet another way is to think that our sins do not matter because God loves us no matter what we do. It is tempting to believe what the deceitful Nehor taught the people of Zarahemla: “That all mankind should be saved at the last day, and that they need not fear nor tremble, … and, in the end, all men should have eternal life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> But this seductive idea is false. God does love us. However, what we do matters to Him and to us. He has given clear directives about how we should behave. We call these commandments. His approbation and our eternal life depend on our behavior, including our willingness to humbly seek real repentance.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p24" pid="nvbIhmFICk2vtCXPw0zliQ" hash="K09M6A">Additionally, we forgo real repentance when we choose to separate God from His commandments. After all, if the sacrament were not sacred, it would not matter that the smell of the firecracker was disruptive to that Göteborg sacrament meeting. We should be wary of discounting sinful behavior by undermining or dismissing God’s authorship of His commandments. Real repentance requires recognizing the Savior’s divinity and the truthfulness of His latter-day work.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p25" pid="tWwdWSP6CEqru5Tj1qVioQ" hash="NZDJNw">Instead of making excuses, let us choose repentance. Through repentance, we can come to ourselves, like the prodigal in the parable,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> and reflect on the eternal import of our actions. When we understand how our sins can affect our eternal happiness, we not only become truly penitent but we also strive to become better. When faced with temptation, we are more likely to ask ourselves, in the words of William Shakespeare:</p>
			<div class="poetry">
				<div class="stanza">
					<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p26" pid="2k52F9YcJE-NQGQnrvq82w" hash="ywbe2A">What win I, if I gain the thing I seek?</p>
					<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p27" pid="YL4nuAeLhEyr2CBkAbz3EA" hash="ZrMkcA">A dream, a breath, a froth of fleeting joy.</p>
					<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p28" pid="oaVXGBuHmUOaLSH75TtAJg" hash="z7zmlg">Who buys a minute’s mirth to wail a week,</p>
					<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p29" pid="-2rlrV-WaUqyDCIDPTOGMw" hash="3kaXtQ">Or sells eternity to get a toy?<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
				</div>
			</div>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p30" pid="JBEOGyBtCkyXIiaaLhlXlA" hash="PcR0-A">If we have lost sight of eternity for the sake of a toy, we can choose to repent. Because of the Atonement of Jesus Christ, we have another chance. Metaphorically, we can exchange the toy we so ill-advisedly purchased in the first place and receive again the hope of eternity. As the Savior explained, “For, behold, the Lord your Redeemer suffered death in the flesh; wherefore he suffered the pain of all men, that all men might repent and come unto him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p31" pid="BGi2C1C5hkyrGqg9SnDZww" hash="82DTng">Jesus Christ can forgive because He paid the price for our sins.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p32" pid="4eI158SgjUWqrwbO2n1yHg" hash="JHI0cQ">Our Redeemer chooses to forgive because of His incomparable compassion, mercy, and love.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p33" pid="gGVgm84oME-_ktltHvkosg" hash="nt5gKA">Our Savior wants to forgive because this is one of His divine attributes.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p34" pid="5eRLlNZuQEK3h0DsapEFKg" hash="o0IuZA">And, like the Good Shepherd He is, He is joyful when we choose to repent.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p35" pid="NlxGt5QHekuvmJC7bqNtQg" hash="AtMe6A">Even as we feel godly sorrow for our actions,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> when we choose to repent, we immediately invite the Savior into our lives. As Amulek taught, “Come forth and harden not your hearts any longer; for behold, now is the time and the day of your salvation; and therefore, if ye will repent and harden not your hearts, <span class="emphasis">immediately</span> shall the great plan of redemption be brought about unto you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> We can feel godly sorrow for our actions and, at the same time, feel the joy of having the Savior’s help.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p36" pid="ffXEseKx9kOlAIPi2VZFTg" hash="AHZ-GQ">The fact that we can repent is the good news of the gospel!<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> Guilt can be “swept away.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> We can be filled with joy, receive a remission of our sins, and have “peace of conscience.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span> We can be freed from feelings of despair and the bondage of sin. We can be filled with the marvelous light of God and be “pained no more.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26">26</span> Repentance is not only possible but also joyful because of our Savior. I still remember the feelings that washed over me in the branch president’s office after the firecracker episode. I knew I had been forgiven. My feelings of guilt vanished, my gloomy mood lifted, and my heart felt light.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice.p37" pid="UIr9H5liOU2W9KG_x-aHlw" hash="33Y9UQ">Brothers and sisters, as we conclude this conference, I invite you to feel more joy in your life: joy in the knowledge that the Atonement of Jesus Christ is real; joy in the Savior’s ability, willingness, and desire to forgive; and joy in choosing to repent. Let us follow the instruction to “with joy … draw water out of the wells of salvation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_27">27</span> May we choose to repent, forsake our sins, and turn our hearts and wills around to follow our Savior. I testify of His living reality. I am a witness and repeated recipient of His incomparable compassion, mercy, and love. I pray that the redeeming blessings of His Atonement may be yours now—and again and again and again throughout your lives,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_28">28</span> as they have been in mine. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/10/repentance-a-joyful-choice</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2016-general-conference/2016-10-5070-dale-g-renlund-64k-eng.mp3" length="7567555" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Good Shepherd</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Renlund describes Jesus Christ as the Good Shepherd, who is compassionate despite our imperfections and finds joy in seeing His sheep heal.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60003501_000_24renlund" doc-version="1" hash="NCHHIQ">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="MtrjsY1gxUy5szY2WTCJQA" hash="CpX3gQ">Our Good Shepherd</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p2" pid="UeHt01tqSUamLZciYMH19w" hash="0khSQw1">By Elder Dale G. Renlund</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p3" pid="60lf7gw34EikZMxmmUl60g" hash="F9R90A">Of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="-OGNXT84PEKqjcbEdln-IA" hash="nMGVHw">Jesus Christ, our Good Shepherd, finds joy in seeing His diseased sheep progress toward healing.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="vOVdsDVlyUerFNLdD9sR_w" hash="0khSQw">By Elder Dale G. Renlund</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p5" pid="U7iaNvMXxkiNamve5JG0gA" hash="vMFu1A">We get a glimpse into our Heavenly Father’s character as we recognize the immense compassion He has for sinners and appreciate the distinction He makes between sin and those who sin. This glimpse helps us have a more “correct [understanding of] his character, perfections, and attributes”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> and is foundational to exercising faith in Him and in His Son, Jesus Christ. The Savior’s compassion in the face of our imperfections draws us toward Him and motivates us in our repeated struggles to repent and emulate Him. As we become more like Him, we learn to treat others as He does, regardless of any outward characteristic or behavior.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p6" pid="-PZrUiiLdE6ePz6oTDFOJw" hash="EYXjOA">The impact of distinguishing between the outward characteristics of an individual and the individual himself is central to the novel <span class="emphasis">Les Misérables,</span> by the French author Victor Hugo.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> As the novel opens, the narrator introduces Bienvenu Myriel, the bishop of Digne, and discusses a dilemma facing the bishop. Should he visit a man who is an avowed atheist and is despised in the community because of his past behavior in the French Revolution?<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p7" pid="4gPCjOJSbEiEE4AiiNQjjw" hash="LdduXg">The narrator states that the bishop could naturally feel a deep aversion for the man. Then the narrator poses a simple question: “All the same, should the scabs of the sheep cause the shepherd to recoil?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Answering for the bishop, the narrator provides a definitive answer, “No”—and then adds a humorous comment: “But what a sheep!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p8" pid="J65msisM4UmUhypK-i-Bqw" hash="GOYaYg">In this passage, Hugo compares the man’s “wickedness” with skin disease in sheep and compares the bishop with a shepherd who does not withdraw when faced with a sheep that is sick. The bishop is sympathetic and later in the novel demonstrates a similar compassion for another man, the main protagonist in the novel, a degraded ex-convict, Jean Valjean. The bishop’s mercy and empathy motivate Jean Valjean to change the course of his life.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p9" pid="amtjgXSiBEGjniT9zZ9JpA" hash="GN-clg">Since God uses disease as a metaphor for sin throughout the scriptures, it is reasonable to ask, “How does Jesus Christ react when faced with our metaphorical diseases—our sins?” After all, the Savior said that He “cannot look upon sin with the least degree of allowance”;<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> so how can He look at us, imperfect as we are, without recoiling in horror and disgust?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p10" pid="dLfG6bJMq0GHGT2hNrj9yQ" hash="gYWQrw">The answer is simple and clear. As the Good Shepherd,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> Jesus Christ views disease in His sheep as a condition that needs treatment, care, and compassion. This shepherd, our Good Shepherd, finds joy in seeing His diseased sheep progress toward healing.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p11" pid="5xMhidVaqEeqBrd_j3Oicg" hash="LR5rDg">The Savior foretold that He would “feed his flock like a shepherd,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> “seek [out] that which [is] lost, … bring again that which [is] driven away, … bind up that which [is] broken, and … strengthen that which [is] sick.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Though apostate Israel was depicted as being consumed with sinful “wounds, and bruises, and putrifying sores,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> the Savior encouraged, exhorted, and promised healing.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p12" pid="_VzucscHPE-SKV8Qpn-1YA" hash="ziF4Zg">The Savior’s mortal ministry was indeed characterized by love, compassion, and empathy. He did not disdainfully walk the dusty roads of Galilee and Judea, flinching at the sight of sinners. He did not dodge them in abject horror. No, He ate with them.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> He helped and blessed, lifted and edified, and replaced fear and despair with hope and joy. Like the true shepherd He is, He seeks us and finds us to offer relief and hope.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> Understanding His compassion and love helps us exercise faith in Him—to repent and be healed.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p13" pid="TzCmyzyw10SKcjLYEev91w" hash="9HebSA">The Gospel of John records the effect of the Savior’s empathy on a sinner. Scribes and Pharisees brought a woman caught in the very act of adultery to the Savior. The accusers implied that she should be stoned, in compliance with the law of Moses. Jesus, in response to persistent questioning, finally said to them, “He that is without sin among you, let him first cast a stone at her.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p14" pid="_MEM9Yp8wk2K7J89sa3QCw" hash="2t4U_w">The accusers departed, “and Jesus was left alone, and the woman standing in the midst.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p15" pid="Y9wLGy6uxkG8oRvCvjGuVA" hash="tSYDEg">“When Jesus … saw none but the woman, he said unto her, Woman, where are those thine accusers? hath no man condemned thee?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p16" pid="WudXhYt5FUacmSPokDD25Q" hash="CJu3zQ">“She said, No man, Lord. And Jesus said unto her, Neither do I condemn thee: go, and sin no more.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p17" pid="4Ya9Ca7Gw06-Yb6kxxmcFg" hash="rSHMzg">Surely, the Savior did not condone adultery. But He also did not condemn the woman. He encouraged her to reform her life. She was motivated to change because of His compassion and mercy. The Joseph Smith Translation of the Bible attests to her resultant discipleship: “And the woman glorified God from that hour, and believed on his name.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p18" pid="kPjej25z70GRRqZ1J1bYgw" hash="Y6qy6w">While God is empathetic, we should not mistakenly believe that He is accepting and open-minded about sin. He is not. The Savior came to earth to save us <span class="emphasis">from</span> our sins and, importantly, will not save us <span class="emphasis">in</span> our sins.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> A skilled interrogator, Zeezrom once tried to trap Amulek by asking: “Shall [the coming Messiah] save his people in their sins? And Amulek answered and said unto him: I say unto you he shall not, for it is impossible for him to deny his word. … He cannot save them in their sins.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> Amulek spoke a fundamental truth that to be saved from our sins, we must abide “the conditions of repentance,” which unleash the Redeemer’s power to save our souls.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p19" pid="mY6lg60kiUe-5vO4SmdCMg" hash="3pBWeA">The Savior’s compassion, love, and mercy draw us toward Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> Through His Atonement, we are no longer satisfied with our sinful state.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> God is clear about what is right and acceptable to Him and what is wrong and sinful. This is not because He desires to have mindless, obedient followers. No, our Heavenly Father desires that His children knowingly and willingly choose to become like Him<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> and qualify for the kind of life He enjoys.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> In doing so, His children fulfill their divine destiny and become heirs to all that He has.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> For this reason, Church leaders cannot alter God’s commandments or doctrine contrary to His will, to be convenient or popular.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p20" pid="ElENcfyc_k6PFsFgbRqzMA" hash="ljV0Sg">However, in our lifelong quest to follow Jesus Christ, His example of kindness to those who sin is particularly instructive. We, who are sinners, must, like the Savior, reach out to others with compassion and love. Our role is also to help and bless, lift and edify, and replace fear and despair with hope and joy.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p21" pid="h2g9QbQ1pE2XZa33zOdScQ" hash="Oo9WEg">The Savior rebuked individuals who recoiled from others they viewed as unclean and who self-righteously judged others as more sinful than they.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> That is the pointed lesson the Savior directed to those who “trusted in themselves that they were righteous, and despised others.” He spoke this parable:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p22" pid="rBI-5lJWY0-DdzluYscVhg" hash="3AAwWg">“Two men went up into the temple to pray; the one a Pharisee, and the other a publican.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p23" pid="eM6u-rVRrEWuqWfngbs3ew" hash="Fe_6zA">“The Pharisee stood and prayed thus with himself, God, I thank thee, that I am not as other men are, extortioners, unjust, adulterers, or even as this publican.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p24" pid="Ztfz_EOIbUWnmMcdDQizLw" hash="tNvVuw">“I fast twice in the week, I give tithes of all that I possess.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p25" pid="WkbPJ3QjcEe9UnDNHSvDCQ" hash="xnwvgw">“And the publican, standing afar off, would not lift up so much as his eyes unto heaven, but smote upon his breast, saying, God be merciful to me a sinner.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p26" pid="3oNGNjovzU2xVw75B5ywvg" hash="mfYnEA">Jesus then concluded, “I tell you, this man [the publican] went down to his house justified rather than the other [the Pharisee]: for every one that exalteth himself shall be abased; and he that humbleth himself shall be exalted.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p27" pid="ih1d6p0tlkqrRW_Er6kczA" hash="lgD-yQ">The message for us is clear: a repenting sinner draws closer to God than does the self-righteous person who condemns that sinner.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p28" pid="2mDj1Iztrk6xuu6mTnwsXA" hash="gQcz-Q">The human tendency to be self-righteous and judgmental was also present in Alma’s day. As the people “began to establish the church more fully … the church began to wax proud, … the people of the church began to be lifted up in the pride of their eyes, … they began to be scornful, one towards another, and they began to persecute those that did not believe according to their own will and pleasure.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26">26</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p29" pid="aCqTFl4DAE2qOd735MkzSA" hash="my4dHg">This persecution was specifically prohibited: “Now there was a strict law among the people of the church, that there should not any man, belonging to the church, arise and persecute those that did not belong to the church, and that there should be no persecution among themselves.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_27">27</span> The guiding principle for Latter-day Saints is the same. We must not be guilty of persecuting anyone inside or outside the Church.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p30" pid="WZql9YlGWkWnHchw27vesA" hash="DP9HzA">Those who have been persecuted for any reason know what unfairness and bigotry feel like. As a teenager living in Europe in the 1960s, I felt that I was repeatedly picked on and bullied because I was an American and because I was a member of the Church. Some of my schoolmates treated me as though I were personally responsible for unpopular U.S. foreign policies. I was also treated as though my religion were an affront to the nations in which I lived because it differed from state-sponsored religion. Later, in various countries across the world, I have had small glimpses into the ugliness of prejudice and discrimination suffered by those who are targeted because of their race or ethnicity.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p31" pid="U59gyRoa9UqagzFWxZ2qWQ" hash="Hjk62w">Persecution comes in many forms: ridicule, harassment, bullying, exclusion and isolation, or hatred toward another. We must guard against bigotry that raises its ugly voice toward those who hold different opinions. Bigotry manifests itself, in part, in unwillingness to grant equal freedom of expression.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_28">28</span> Everyone, including people of religion, has the right to express his or her opinions in the public square. But no one has a license to be hateful toward others as those opinions are expressed.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p32" pid="gtHY2iBOZkWa1l8snIHUoQ" hash="eLS3vQ">Church history gives ample evidence of our members being treated with hatred and bigotry. How ironically sad it would be if we were to treat others as we have been treated. The Savior taught, “Whatsoever ye would that men should do to you, do ye even so to them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_29">29</span> For us to ask for respect, we must be respectful. Furthermore, our genuine conversion brings “meekness, and lowliness of heart,” which invites “the Holy Ghost [and fills us with] perfect love,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_30">30</span> an “unfeigned love”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_31">31</span> for others.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p33" pid="Ln5EbVvzMEiFnYtuzNM9yQ" hash="WT3slA">Our Good Shepherd is unchanging and feels the same way today about sin and sinners as He did when He walked the earth. He does not recoil from us because we sin, even if He on occasion must think, “But what a sheep!” He loves us so much that He provided the way for us to repent and become clean so we can return to Him and our Heavenly Father.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_32">32</span> In doing so, Jesus Christ also set the example for us to follow—to show respect to all and hatred toward none.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd.p34" pid="vIlyDrSYLEOP65LD2c0Fzg" hash="8Du9NQ">As His disciples, let us fully mirror His love and love one another so openly and completely that no one feels abandoned, alone, or hopeless. I testify that Jesus Christ is our Good Shepherd, who loves and cares for us. He knows us and laid down His life for His sheep.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_33">33</span> He also lives for us and wants us to know Him and exercise faith in Him. I love and adore Him, and I am profoundly grateful for Him, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2017/04/our-good-shepherd</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2017-general-conference/2017-04-1040-dale-g-renlund-64k-eng.mp3" length="7349974" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
