<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Daniel L. Johnson</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Daniel L. Johnson.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Daniel%20L.%20Johnson.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Daniel L. Johnson.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2006 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2006 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Law of Tithing</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I invite you to put your trust in the Lord and, as He Himself said, “Prove me now herewith.”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006562_000_016" doc-version="2" hash="VDysjQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="gzjyv9av8EO9PtUDSB91tQ" hash="r8UIog">The Law of Tithing</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="uECdP3ElE0GR-u-IFLoQyA" hash="zWMG4A">Daniel L. Johnson</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="FZ-9YK7Ld02Qz-UcH6bhQA" hash="h9xfIg">I invite you to put your trust in the Lord and, as He Himself said, “Prove me now herewith.”</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/JohnsonDL_06.jpg" alt="Elder Daniel L. Johnson" pid="x9vtZkTwr0awpzb3j5EF8w" hash="vgUpug" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing.p1" pid="cGrb4vmjnUu46cZ3hx5GUA" hash="tDegRg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="35"></span>My remarks this afternoon are intended as an invitation to those who have not yet gained a personal testimony of the full payment of tithing. There are many reasons that are used to not pay tithing, such as medical emergencies, debts, car or home repairs, educational expenses, and insurance. These reasons and others like them are very real and are lived and dealt with every day by many, if not most, of us. These tax our limited financial resources and, if we are not wise stewards of these resources, may result in the inability to meet our tithing obligation to the Lord. A lack of compliance with this eternal law is not to be taken lightly and can not only seriously impair our spiritual growth and development, but it can also limit the physical and temporal blessings that we could otherwise enjoy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing.p2" pid="49vsXXvO-E-7NXGGuaOTFA" hash="ZiUuOg">As President Spencer W. Kimball once said: “The Lord herein makes clear that tithing is his law and is required of all his followers. It is our honor and privilege, our safety and promise, our great blessing to live this law of God. To fail to meet this obligation in full is to deny ourselves the promises and is to omit a weighty matter. It is a transgression, not an inconsequential oversight.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing.p3" pid="sM4licLkpEi6DMrJ4BRGtQ" hash="nxnA4Q">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">So what is a tithing?</span>
</span> The Lord has given us His definition: “And this shall be the beginning of the tithing of my people. And after that, those who have thus been tithed shall pay one-tenth of all their interest annually; and this shall be a standing law unto them forever.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Please note that the tithe is not just any freewill offering, nor is it a 20th or some other fraction of our annual interest or income.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing.p4" pid="UybM1W2xoUmGGQ451QQUlg" hash="B07jSw">President Howard W. Hunter stated it this way: “The law is simply stated as ‘one-tenth of all their interest.’ Interest means profit, compensation, increase. It is the wage of one employed, the profit from the operation of a business, the increase of one who grows or produces, or the income to a person from any other source. The Lord said it is a standing law ‘forever’ as it has been in the past.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing.p5" pid="5riFdgDO90OUrcqfhcE4RQ" hash="7EEtKw">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">How is tithing used?</span>
</span> Faithful members of the Church pay their tithing to a member of their branch presidency or ward bishopric. Under the direction of the Lord’s prophet, these funds are then gathered and used to fund the growth and development of the Church throughout the world. Examples of the use of tithing funds are the construction of temples, the financing of the worldwide missionary effort, the building and maintenance of meetinghouses, and other worthy purposes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing.p6" pid="mVvhbsUGWUKz0teHr_KQ5g" hash="ODdF3g">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">Why does the Lord require His people to pay tithing?</span>
</span> The Lord is our Father, and as our Father, He loves us. Because He loves us, He wants to bless us both temporally and spiritually. Listen to some of His statements as written in the scriptures: “Hearken and hear, O ye my people, saith the Lord and your God, ye whom I delight to bless with the greatest of all blessings.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> And another: “For thus saith the Lord—I, the Lord, am merciful and gracious unto those who fear me, and delight to honor those who serve me in righteousness and in truth unto the end.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing.p7" pid="_BqN2Ct6A0mvbc9KOWI0mA" hash="sVeD9w">In order to bestow His blessings on His children in a just and equitable manner, the Lord has instituted laws that govern those blessings that He wants all of us to enjoy. He has revealed this principle of laws to His prophet of the Restoration: “There is a law, irrevocably decreed in heaven before the foundations of this world, upon which all blessings are predicated—and when we obtain any blessing from God, it is by obedience to that law upon which it is predicated.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> And again: “I, the Lord, am bound when ye do what I say; but when ye do not what I say, ye have no promise.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing.p8" pid="UJtLM6WRdEmqwCiEGSXn5Q" hash="pdRAxQ">The Lord knew from the beginning that we, His children, would be faced with temporal and spiritual adversities during this mortal life. Indeed, these adversities are a vital part of this mortal probation. He knew that we would stand in need of His blessings throughout our lives in order to not only survive our individual trials, but also to enjoy a degree of comfort and even prosperity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing.p9" pid="S7rUuuYWYUeZQ8i9K9C84Q" hash="3f6AyQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="36"></span>Thus the law of tithing, which was instituted from the beginning. We know from the scriptures that Abraham was blessed through his obedience to this law, and we now have that same law as it was reiterated by the Savior during His visit to the inhabitants of the American continent almost 2,000 years ago:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing.p10" pid="2gzKOQCmfEy4NObKOU6JJw" hash="Pip9wg">“Bring ye all the tithes into the storehouse, that there may be meat in my house; and prove me now herewith, saith the Lord of Hosts, if I will not open you the windows of heaven, and pour you out a blessing that there shall not be room enough to receive it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing.p11" pid="DDwsoQGBGUmw_cd1GC6tgA" hash="AQ64Bw">“And I will rebuke the devourer for your sakes, and he shall not destroy the fruits of your ground; neither shall your vine cast her fruit before the time in the fields, saith the Lord of Hosts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing.p12" pid="8yoKtDo3_0mR0BW3ppfneA" hash="wd32qg">“And all nations shall call you blessed, for ye shall be a delightsome land, saith the Lord of Hosts.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing.p13" pid="bcDILnrdmkCyIATHymxOdg" hash="ix_VXA">What a marvelous law! He who has not only the power and the means to bless His children temporally and spiritually but also the desire to do so, has provided to us the key to those blessings that we both need and desire. This key is the law of tithing. Indeed, as stated by President James E. Faust: “Some may feel that they cannot afford to pay tithing, but the Lord has promised that He would prepare a way for us to keep all of His commandments. To pay tithing takes a leap of faith in the beginning. … We learn about tithing by paying it. Indeed, I believe it is possible to break out of poverty by having the faith to give back to the Lord part of what little we have.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> My brothers and sisters, we have but to obey the law.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing.p14" pid="uGPedNChkUmcqi6YKVxyEg" hash="mkD2bQ">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">Now the invitation:</span>
</span> To those who are not yet full-tithe payers, I invite you to begin today to pay your full tithing to the Lord through your local priesthood leader. I invite you to pay your tithing to the Lord first, before you meet any other financial obligations. I invite you to put your trust in the Lord and, as He Himself said, “Prove me now herewith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> As you do so and as you place your tithing obligation to the Lord as the first priority of all of your other financial obligations, you will indeed become a witness to the matchless power of the Lord as He opens the windows of heaven and pours out a blessing “that there shall not be room enough to receive it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> You will then have gained your own personal testimony of this very sacred law of tithing, and as you continue your obedience to this law, it will draw you ever closer to the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing.p15" pid="WR5HOz6fuUaYfNWIFZW3Kw" hash="0khVJQ">To those of you who are already tithe payers, I commend you for your faithfulness. You are already witnesses and have your own personal testimonies as to the fulfillment of the Lord’s promises to those who obey this commandment, and each time you pay your tithing, your personal commitment to the Lord increases.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing.p16" pid="QvvLw-oouEyZ7bhh6MyVNw" hash="gfeiow">I bear you my own personal witness of the law of tithing and of the reality of the promises that the Lord has given regarding this law. I know from personal experience that the blessings do indeed come, and for that I am most grateful. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/10/the-law-of-tithing</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2006-general-conference/2006-10-2060-elder-daniel-l-johnson-64k-eng.mp3" length="4131098" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2006 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a True Disciple</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As we obey His commandments and serve our fellowmen, we become better disciples of Jesus Christ.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10491_000_55johnson" doc-version="2" hash="yWImKQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="Etsfju9qL0-YnZdYH6f_Xg" hash="mc4VXw">Becoming a True Disciple</h1><p class="authorName" pid="CDNwfcXU6EWQdXxkpYvvfA" hash="HP4t1g">By Elder Daniel L. Johnson</p><p class="kicker" pid="Nwf-GXSlNEagnp1cpHS8cA" hash="d_9KOA">As we obey His commandments and serve our fellowmen, we become better disciples of Jesus Christ.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" pid="MS2Ndn_LpEaMW2w-W7XF_A" hash="2j8ruA">
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple.p5" pid="E5K7z38rBUOTgFLUSHNEmw" hash="zXztLw">
      <span class="pageBreak" page-number="101"></span>Those of us who have entered into the waters of baptism and received the gift of the Holy Ghost have covenanted that we are willing to take upon ourselves the name of Jesus Christ, or in other words, we declare ourselves to be disciples of the Lord. We renew that covenant each week as we partake of the sacrament, and we demonstrate that discipleship by the way that we live. Such discipleship was beautifully demonstrated in recent events in Mexico.</p>
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple.p6" pid="8DNpTRB5z0KkEOGvqbCBQg" hash="SkMzaw">It had been a beautiful spring for the fruit-growing communities in northern Mexico. The fruit trees were in full bloom, and expectations were high for a bounteous harvest. Plans were already being made to pay off loans, replace needed equipment and aging orchards, and meet personal commitments such as school tuition for family members. Plans were even being made for family vacations. There was a general air of optimism. Then, on a Monday afternoon in late March, a winter storm moved in, and it began to snow. It snowed until about three o’clock in the morning. Then, as the clouds moved out, the temperature plummeted. Throughout the night and early morning, every effort was made to save at least a part of the fruit crop. It was all to no avail. It simply got too cold, and the crop was totally frozen. There would be no fruit to be harvested and sold this year. Tuesday dawned with the sickening and disheartening loss of all those wonderful plans, expectations, and dreams of just the day before.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple.p7" pid="EiONAGO3JEKAnT10qMoEXA" hash="k_tIhA">I received an email regarding that terrible Tuesday morning from Sandra Hatch, the wife of John Hatch, then-first counselor in the presidency of the Colonia Juárez Chihuahua Temple. I quote portions of that email: “John got up early—about 6:30—to run up to the temple to see if we should cancel the session this morning. He came back saying that the parking lot and road were clear, so we decided to go ahead. We figured that maybe some of the workers who didn’t have orchards would come, and we could put all the workers into the session. … It was so inspiring to see the men come in, one after another. There they were, after no sleep at all, and figuring their crops were lost. … I was watching them during our preparation meeting, and they were having a hard time <span class="pageBreak" page-number="102"></span>staying awake. But instead of figuring they had a good excuse to not come, they were there. And there were 38 people in the session (a full session)! It was an uplifting morning for us, and we thanked Heavenly Father for good people who do their duty, no matter what happens. I felt a special spirit there this morning. I am sure He was pleased to know that we love His house and felt that it was a good place to be on such a difficult morning.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple.p8" pid="t0bR9T6Igkqw-jypV5qz7Q" hash="LoYAEA">The story does not end there and in fact is still ongoing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple.p9" pid="Qo4mIjEXQ06PtMTiwYyi4g" hash="QKGqew">Most of those who lost their fruit crop had some land available on which to plant alternative crops for the season, such as chili peppers or beans. These crops could provide at least some cash flow sufficient to survive on until next year’s fruit crop. However, there was one good brother with a young family who did not have additional land and was facing a year with no revenue at all. Others in the community, seeing the dire situation of this brother and acting on their own initiative and expense, arranged for a piece of property, used their own equipment to prepare the land, and provided the chili plants for him to plant.</p>
    </span>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple.p10" pid="_xl-0X8JrUubpb4BqIQwSA" hash="l0kM2A">I know the men about whom I have just spoken. Knowing them, I was not surprised at what they did. But those who do not know them will probably be asking two questions, both beginning with the word <span class="emphasis">why.</span> Why would they come to the temple to perform their duties and to serve after having been up all night long, only to realize that they had lost the greater part of their revenue for the whole year? Why would they use what were now scarce and very precious resources to help another in desperate need when they themselves were now in such dire financial straits?</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple.p11" pid="ltWZP2Nz0kKnsXF0r6t0nQ" hash="mPLgMw">If you understand what it means to be a disciple of Jesus Christ, then you will know the answer to these two questions.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple.p12" pid="brhatXJbHUKLZfAWhS_tGg" hash="Wqny2Q">Making the covenant to be a disciple of Christ is the beginning of a lifelong process, and the path is not always easy. As we repent of our sins and strive to do what He would have us do and serve our fellowmen as He would serve them, we will inevitably become more like Him. Becoming like Him and being one with Him is the ultimate goal and objective—and essentially the very definition of true discipleship.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple.p13" pid="2JhJXrkA20-f3cvIqoS4ZA" hash="kx6emw">As the Savior asked His disciples when He visited the American continent, “Therefore, what manner of men ought ye to be?” And then, answering His own question, He said, “Verily I say unto you, even as I am” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.27" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 27:27</a>).</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple.p14" pid="pI3ExWhlDkSRuRxof3ht5g" hash="C422LA">Becoming as the Savior is not an easy task, especially in the world in which we live. We face obstacles and adversity virtually every day of our lives. There is a reason for this, and it is one of the primary purposes of mortality. As we read in <a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.25" class="scriptureRef">Abraham 3:25</a>, “And we will prove them herewith, to see if they will do all things whatsoever the Lord their God shall command them.”</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple.p15" pid="JRfaxBRJK0WlOUmc3H6l_w" hash="X8INcQ">These tests or trials vary in nature and intensity. But no one will leave this mortal existence without passing through them. Mostly, we picture trials as the loss of a crop or a job; the death of a loved one; illness; physical, mental, or emotional incapacitation; poverty; or loss of friends. However, even the attainment of seemingly worthwhile objectives can bring their own dangers of unhelpful pride, where we aspire more to the honors of men than the approbation of heaven. These may include worldly popularity, public recognition, physical prowess, artistic or athletic talent, prosperity, and riches. Regarding these latter trials, some of us may have feelings similar to those expressed by Tevye in <span class="emphasis">Fiddler on the Roof:</span> If riches are a curse, “may [God] smite me with it. And may I never recover!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple.p16" pid="ppuQbPUWkEO2q1H2dc09eg" hash="dEYa1A">But these latter types of trials may be even more daunting and dangerous <span class="pageBreak" page-number="103"></span>and more difficult to overcome than the former. Our discipleship will be developed and proven not by the type of trials that we are faced with but how we endure them. As we have been taught by President Henry B. Eyring: “So, the great test of life is to see whether we will hearken to and obey God’s commands in the midst of the storms of life. It is not to endure storms, but to choose the right while they rage. And the tragedy of life is to fail in that test and so fail to qualify to return in glory to our heavenly home” (“Spiritual Preparedness: Start Early and Be Steady,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 2005, 38).</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple.p17" pid="YDLzLjZX8UGAR9at3DvttA" hash="GCEvmw">I am the proud grandfather of 23 grandchildren. They never cease to amaze me with their grasp of eternal truths, even in their very early and tender years. As I was preparing for this talk, I asked each of them to send me a very brief definition of what it meant to them to be a disciple or a follower of Jesus Christ. I received wonderful answers from all of them. But I would like to share with you this response from eight-year-old Benjamin: “Being a disciple of Jesus Christ means being an example. It means being a missionary and preparing to be a missionary. It means to serve others. It means you read the scriptures and say your prayers. It means you keep the Sabbath day holy. It means you listen to the promptings of the Holy Ghost. It means going to church and going to the temple.”</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple.p18" pid="VkLIvdrvAUGbXZBxjN9dzA" hash="Db4dOQ">I agree with Benjamin. Discipleship is all about doing and becoming. As we obey His commandments and serve our fellowmen, we become better disciples of Jesus Christ. Obedience and submission to His will bring the companionship of the Holy Ghost, along with those blessings of peace, joy, and security that always accompany this third member of the Godhead. And they can come in no other way. Ultimately, it is total submission to His will that helps us become as our Savior is. Again, becoming like Him and being one with Him is the ultimate goal and objective—and essentially the very definition of true discipleship.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple.p19" pid="jdoJ4uv6ek6tPuj2viMvoA" hash="XsWQjw">Discipleship is what I saw being practiced in the Colonia Juárez Temple and in its nearby fields as brothers and sisters in the faith reaffirmed their commitments to God and to each other despite heartrending adversity.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple.p20" pid="lMfA5dYwNkKi373JW1fQvQ" hash="TndPDA">I testify that as we obey His commandments, serve others, and submit our will to His will, we will, indeed, become His true disciples. I so testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2012/10/becoming-a-true-disciple</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2012-general-conference/2012-10-5050-elder-daniel-l-johnson-64k-eng.mp3" length="4933751" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
