<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By David E. Sorensen</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by David E. Sorensen.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/David%20E.%20Sorensen.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by David E. Sorensen.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1993 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1993 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Prayer</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1993/04/prayer?lang=eng</link>
      <description>When our oldest children were still small, we lived on a busy street here in Salt Lake City. My wife, Verla, and I were concerned about the danger that street presented to our children. We used every opportunity to reinforce the importance of staying</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_93905_000_016" doc-version="2" hash="ehhjEw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ext5RUe4T0Sq5R_-QsuuAg" hash="7ButCA">Prayer</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ecEQLpT4BkeGgCaPRr1AxA" hash="RxlkYw">David E. Sorensen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1dc0.jpg" alt="Elder David E. Sorensen" pid="IeACoXijl0-JlI7PUV4UCQ" hash="4xYnaQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p1" pid="DbfYa_-4PEyuehotYEu4hA" hash="wA1RYQ">When our oldest children were still small, we lived on a busy street here in Salt Lake City. My wife, Verla, and I were concerned about the danger that street presented to our children. We used every opportunity to reinforce the importance of staying away from the street. In addition, this was a time in our children’s lives when they were learning about temples and eternal families. So our children’s prayers regularly included this request: “Please help us to be married in the temple and stay out of the street.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p2" pid="EtAtts9KkkG2m6Hgi76ZGQ" hash="bDd7PQ">One day after some of our neighbor’s children had gone home after playing at our house, my wife received a call from their mother. One of her children had heard a prayer while he was visiting us and had offered this variation when he said his own prayer at home: “Please help us stay out of the temple and get married in the street.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p3" pid="BUn2GxGcbEae0I_frCiSMA" hash="A9P8zA">I trust that that particular prayer was not received exactly the way it was phrased, but I do have a strong testimony of the importance of prayer in shaping our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p4" pid="1MuYQLiprkCPrAtBWSNpxg" hash="eq8P1A">The Savior puts great emphasis on prayer in the Book of Mormon. He repeatedly and personally prayed with and for the Nephites. And after He did this, He asked them to follow His example:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p5" pid="Em1QU6HGLESw0LrbvqpfWA" hash="bDaSEQ">“Verily, verily, I say unto you, ye must watch and pray always, lest ye be tempted by the devil, and ye be led away captive by him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p6" pid="P8xS0EgeK0-Af-o2yYk4Ug" hash="TvFm5Q">“And as I have prayed among you even so shall ye pray in my church, among my people who do repent and are baptized in my name. Behold I am the light; I have set an example for you.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.15-16" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:15–16</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.24" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:24</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/19.17-34" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 19:17–34</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.21" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 27:21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p7" pid="RxB4EXS-kkKDZoaqcMTbJQ" hash="V2LlEA">In fact, Christ specifically exhorts the Nephites at least ten times to “pray unto the Father in [his] name.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.19" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:19</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/13.6-9" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 13:6–9</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/14.11" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 14:11</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.3" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:3</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.20-21,23" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:20–21, 23</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/20.31" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 20:31</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/21.27" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 21:27</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.2-7,9,28" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 27:2–7, 9, 28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p8" pid="7g2DJAFtXUyobS47be6pRQ" hash="6uBi5w">Christ taught that prayer is indispensable at each step of the perfection process, but especially at the very beginning. For example, He taught that one of the key reasons for the restoration of the gospel was so scattered Israel could pray to the Father in the name of Christ:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p9" pid="rqT8uhFXwEmzKN24aW-jTw" hash="3bw0LQ">“Yea, the work shall commence among all the dispersed of my people, with the Father to prepare the way whereby they may come unto me, that <span class="emphasis">they may call on the Father in my name.</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/21.27" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 21:27</a>; emphasis added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p10" pid="mHtv3egT2kmsSYZsxXY1Lw" hash="5GBqBA">Furthermore, He taught that we in the Church are to pray on behalf of those who are investigating the Church. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.23-30" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:23–30</a>.) He encouraged those who had heard His words to ponder them and to pray to the Father in His name for increased understanding. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.3" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:3</a>.) And, of course, He showed us that even perfected people, such as Himself, should pray constantly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p11" pid="n-7Be3YljUWXETVsDbTnQQ" hash="igeSvA">At each level of our progression toward becoming like our Heavenly Father, prayer is a necessary step. Once we have tasted of His goodness, Christ encourages us to pray often—in secret, in our families, in our churches, and in our hearts, continually asking specifically for the things which we need—telling us, “And whatsoever ye shall ask the Father in my name, which is right, believing that ye shall receive, behold it shall be given unto you.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.20" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p12" pid="hKfCqW4BYkG3J2ZTRRJcWw" hash="PaX0uA">Christ taught the Nephites that prayer is more than just a means to receive our Father in Heaven’s generosity; rather, prayer itself is an act of faith as well as an act of righteousness. Prayer is the defining act of the worshipper of God the Father and His Son Jesus Christ. This is because the act of prayer itself can change and purify us, both individually and as a group. As our Bible Dictionary states, “The object of prayer is not to change the will of God, but to secure for ourselves and for others blessings that God is already willing to grant, but that are made conditional on our asking for them.” (P. 753.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p13" pid="po3Mw5ffZE26gSKXBZlBQg" hash="KbGsjw">In other words, prayers bring our desires and the desires of our Father into harmony, thus bringing us both the blessing we are seeking and also the blessing of greater unity with the Father. This practice is key to the collective and individual salvation of women and men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p14" pid="r9Tv3iNuikq8UdK2NOk_4w" hash="JRGeNA">Elder Hyrum M. Smith expressed this idea well when he wrote, “The prayer of faith is the secret of the strength of the Church.” (Hyrum M. Smith and Janne M. Sjodahl, <span class="emphasis">The Doctrine and Covenants Commentary,</span> rev. ed., Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1972, p. 194.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p15" pid="lff_O5Na-k6MqkTP3y7s8Q" hash="910n8w">I have seen this verified in my own life. While we were living in California, one of our sons was seriously injured in an automobile accident. His skull was badly fractured, and doctors gave us very little encouragement that he would survive. Three days after he was admitted to the hospital, he contracted meningitis, and his condition worsened. Our family doctor and neighbor came to our home and said, “All we can do now is pray.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p16" pid="2FeRgztPzkyH1-oOM9SHJw" hash="DFVMpw">And pray we did. For several weeks our neighbors, friends, and business associates joined us in praying for our son and for our own strength. After almost a month, our son’s condition finally stabilized and then improved, and we were blessed to see him eventually recovered and smiling again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p17" pid="7sPjHvQadU6WZL-rRJgCeg" hash="CIInXA">I would not wish a similar experience on anyone, but that terrible, difficult period taught us the principle that President Thomas S. Monson has taught the Church. Said he, “Prayer is the passport to spiritual power.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1990, p. 47.) During our son’s illness, we saw and felt the spiritual power of prayer! Our ward had never prayed harder than it did then, and I don’t think the members had ever been closer to each other. Our family was sustained by the collective faith and prayers of our friends. And even as our hearts were breaking in fear that we might lose our son, we felt closer to our Heavenly Father and more aware of our dependency on Him than at almost any other time in our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p18" pid="gGZ-G5fuXUGT8tS1gSjKmw" hash="gcoScg">While the blessings we ask for and receive through prayer are undeniably magnificent, the greatest blessing and benefit is not the physical or spiritual blessings that may come as answers to our prayers but in the changes to our soul that come as we learn to be dependent on our Heavenly Father for strength.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p19" pid="ibOAcZET2kGhmGlnEkJmBg" hash="qtwzpQ">One mother told the following experience that helps to explain this idea. She said, “Sometimes while we are eating, one of my children will get my attention and signal to me while his mouth is full of food. Grunting and waving, he will try to motion for me to do something for him. I know perfectly well that what he wants is for me to pour him a glass of milk, but I will wait until he uses words to ask me before I will do it. It’s not that I can’t understand what he wants but that I feel it is important for him to learn how to communicate well.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p20" pid="ObcJIBQfVk-FjeMyFfoBKg" hash="2mvHTw">In much the same way that parents tutor their children in communication and courtesy, I believe that our Heavenly Father teaches us to pray because the very act of praying will improve us. We worship our Father in Heaven as all-knowing and all-powerful. Surely, as our Creator, He knows our cares, our worries, our joys, our struggles without our informing Him. The reason our Heavenly Father asks us to pray cannot be that we are able to tell Him something He does not already know. Rather, the reason He asks us to pray is that the process of learning to communicate effectively with Him will shape and change our lives as much as we are changed by learning to communicate as children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p21" pid="hoSnD1wRkUS7ElmDWiCRVQ" hash="deFsXQ">President Gordon B. Hinckley teaches it this way: “There is something in the very posture of kneeling that contradicts the attitudes described by Paul; ‘proud … heady, highminded.’ …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p22" pid="4ffcjOE5Mka9Gl_87sibeQ" hash="59QZdA">“There is something in the act of addressing Deity that offsets a tendency toward blasphemy and toward becoming lovers of pleasure more than lovers of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p23" pid="iYzNDXAo106zTo5dzVuPqQ" hash="TAYtVQ">“The inclination to be unholy, as Paul described it, to be unthankful, is erased as together family members thank the Lord for life and peace and all they have.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Feb. 1991, p. 4.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p24" pid="PmoODDL6LUytzKmT6AUkSw" hash="Iwyjew">Aside from participating in the ordinances of the gospel, there is no other time in our lives when we can renew our spiritual life and improve our understanding of our place before Heavenly Father the way we can when we pray. As we humble ourselves to approach our God and thoughtfully consider His grace and great love for us, we will become a more holy and reverent people, more able to receive the blessings He will willingly pour out on us. Truly, the prayer of faith is the secret of the strength of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/prayer.p25" pid="-2M43IrxKkyNgUH8uiASAA" hash="txm7bg">I testify that God lives, that Jesus is the Christ, that Joseph Smith was the Prophet of the Restoration. Ezra Taft Benson is our prophet. The Book of Mormon’s gold plates are a reality, as were the appearances of Moroni and many other angels who instructed the Prophet Joseph Smith in response to his prayers. The restoration of the priesthood is real and eternal. It is the binding force for such divine ordinances as baptisms and sealings as administered by the Church today. The First Presidency and the Twelve Apostles are prophets, seers, and revelators. I so testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1993/04/prayer</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1993-general-conference/1993-04-2070-elder-david-e-sorensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="4846941" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1993 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small Temples—Large Blessings</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The simple presence of a temple should serve as a reminder of covenants we have made, the need for integrity, and the fact that God is never far away.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_98911_000_025" doc-version="2" hash="CcZ-yw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="H_qOMUIB3kSP8MSJ0nr8rw" hash="_huv3Q">Small Temples—</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="QZ1v_Xe4hkah0nCadfceKQ" hash="20Ggtw">Large Blessings</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="iTRYAALAqku_5Nn9jsjGFQ" hash="RxlkYw">David E. Sorensen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="l9dQUXKjxESbgIRU7Xbbeg" hash="WgF5cg">The simple presence of a temple should serve as a reminder of covenants we have made, the need for integrity, and the fact that God is never far away.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1dc0.jpg" alt="Elder David E. Sorensen" pid="B9gJhvFOZE6_KhSEzMSUeA" hash="4xYnaQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p1" pid="8YVwTRWUGEKCxgC31wRinw" hash="Spp-mQ">Elder Maxwell, you are a great treasure to the Church and a blessing to the world at large. May God bless you and keep you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p2" pid="sgJeLmb-VU-x4JTd1z6D3Q" hash="MbKN1g">Brothers and sisters, it is a daunting experience to stand before you. When I was growing up, my family lived on a cattle ranch in south-central Utah, and I spent a lot of time in a saddle rounding up and caring for the cattle. I must confess there is a part of me right now that would be more comfortable dodging a charging bull than speaking here today; however, I know I am among friends, and I believe with all my heart in the importance of the work we are doing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p3" pid="PexWApIA10KgwxQ1X2D0kw" hash="Lre-zA">In the early days of the Church when there were just a few members, the Prophet Joseph Smith said to a group of men: “You know no more concerning the destinies of this Church and kingdom than a babe upon its mother’s lap. You don’t comprehend it. … It is only a little handfull of Priesthood you see here tonight, but this Church will fill North and South America—it will fill the world” (as quoted by Wilford Woodruff, in Conference Report, April 1898, 57). We are beginning to see a partial fulfillment of that prophecy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p4" pid="AlbM59xqS0OlNK9gX6j3qg" hash="_jbzZA">As Church membership has grown around the world, so has the need for temples. President Hinckley said 13 years ago, “The sacred and important work that goes on in temples must be accelerated, and for this to happen, it is necessary that temples be taken closer to the people rather than having the people travel so far to temples” (in Conference Report, Oct. 1985, 71; or <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1985, 54).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p5" pid="slofqwaZeUyhmslq4w7oYw" hash="csiorg">Let me share with you some numbers that show how far the Church has come in the effort to bring temples closer to the people:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p6" pid="4SP1NXfgOk6pAVExXH48qw" hash="7Po2jA">In the year 1900, there were just four operating temples—all of them in the state of Utah.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p7" pid="3hV5WfCGdEuLbr9dsN7XmA" hash="TXLNGA">In the next 50 years, from 1900 to 1950, four more temples were dedicated, for a total of eight. So in the first century, the Church built about one temple per decade.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p8" pid="prYSBlhcrESCmJ_6NTyt0A" hash="mqhyfg">In the 30 years between 1951 and 1980, another 11 temples were built, bringing the total to 19. This was a faster rate, but even still there were many members for whom a visit to a temple meant years of saving money and a long journey.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p9" pid="DbwR2HkiFUWFYpmXy4cdRA" hash="fZQLIA">In the 1980s, the Church began a more intensive temple building effort; by 1997, 32 more temples had been dedicated, or about two per year.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p10" pid="Dex6CzhM8k2el9lfoGtl-Q" hash="5wy-3Q">The Church has now entered the most committed era of temple building in its history. In 1998, two temples have been dedicated, with 15 more under construction and an additional 26 temple sites being prepared for groundbreaking. These 43 temples, plus those currently operating, bring the total to 94.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p11" pid="zxq7S8IsRk24pCu24BPb3Q" hash="U-ynDA">This is an extraordinary blessing for us as members of the Church. The Old Testament describes some of the joy that comes from people building these holy places: “And they sang together … in praising and giving thanks unto the Lord; … And all the people shouted with a great shout, when they praised the Lord, because the foundation of the house of the Lord was laid” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ezra/3.11" class="scriptureRef">Ezra 3:11</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/ot/ezra/3.10,12,13" class="scriptureRef">Ezra 3:10, 12, 13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p12" pid="nhrpFLJnXkqUw0DKEGVU5A" hash="qhnbeA">Watching these new temples being built, I believe that we too will have occasion to praise the Lord and weep for joy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p13" pid="bHVDMSHF5kCAHC22Z6L-cw" hash="hObC7Q">As we see the increased commitment President Hinckley and others have made to building new temples, we might pause and ask ourselves why temples are of such importance. Indeed, nonmembers of the Church may not even understand the distinction between our regular meetinghouses, of which there are many thousands, and these very special buildings we call temples.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p14" pid="XZhUUdXG3keNetamvn6V9A" hash="_oL9ag">President Hinckley explained the distinction this way: “These unique and wonderful buildings, and the ordinances administered therein, represent the ultimate in our worship. These ordinances become the most profound expressions of our theology” (in Conference Report, Oct. 1995, 72; or <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1995, 53). In other words, temples are of great value to us because they help us express our core theology, that of coming to Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p15" pid="boHQz0WYG0ynIYtVDMb6RA" hash="O8rCFQ">Temples do this in at least two ways. First, they symbolically and literally remind us and teach us about Christ and His Father. We know that Christ spent key parts of His ministry at the temple in Jerusalem (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/7.title" class="scriptureRef">John 7–8</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/21.title" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 21–23</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/11.title" class="scriptureRef">Mark 11–12</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/20.title" class="scriptureRef">Luke 20</a>), and drew frequently on temple symbolism in His teachings, often comparing Himself to symbols used in the temple, such as light and water (see, for example, <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/7.38" class="scriptureRef">John 7:38</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.12" class="scriptureRef">John 8:12</a>). Our temple worship today includes many symbolic references to Christ, from the spires on the outside that point our minds heavenward, to the white clothing we wear inside the temple to symbolize that, as the book of Revelation says, we have come “out of great tribulation, and have washed [our] robes, and made them white in the blood of the Lamb” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rev/7.14" class="scriptureRef">Rev. 7:14</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p16" pid="0xQIBIEFyUqxXzVZqS24zA" hash="z9VgKg">Temples stand as a constant physical reminder of the grace and the goodness of the Father. This helps communities of Saints strengthen themselves. President George Q. Cannon said: “Every foundation stone that is laid for a temple, and every temple completed … lessens the power of Satan on the earth, and increases the power of God and Godliness” (Logan Temple cornerstone ceremony, 19 Sept. 1877; quoted in Nolan Porter Olsen, <span class="emphasis">Logan Temple: The First 100 Years</span> [1978], 34).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p17" pid="a0avzqM5UUuvseadrAERlQ" hash="g-ITig">Temples have always symbolized being in the presence of the Lord. “Let them make me a sanctuary; that I may dwell among them,” said the Lord. “And there I will meet with thee, and I will commune with thee” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/25.8,22" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 25:8, 22</a>). There is a closeness to God that comes through consistent worship in the house of the Lord. We can come to know Him and feel welcome, “at home,” in His house.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p18" pid="cD1cD5UQQkGvYDD2nR7OTg" hash="jemm8w">With temples in so many places around the world, more of us will have them nearby to remind us of Christ and His sacrifice for us. The simple presence of a temple should serve as a reminder of covenants we have made, the need for integrity, and the fact that God is never far away.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p19" pid="M9V9Y_h710mwY6KQSVtXOQ" hash="Y8Z_ag">Beyond their physical presence and outward symbolism, temples can inspire us to come unto Christ in a second way—that is, by the ordinances we perform in them. All temple ordinances are centered in Jesus Christ and His divine mission, and they are performed by the authority of the Melchizedek Priesthood. Doctrine and Covenants 84 says, “And without the ordinances thereof, and the authority of the priesthood, the power of godliness is not manifest unto men in the flesh” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:21</a>). Each ordinance is calculated to reveal to us something about Christ and our relationship to God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p20" pid="cq8iYGA9Uk-igRHCbnfhog" hash="UK8lBg">While some ordinances in the temple seem easy to understand, such as eternal marriage, others require careful and lengthy spiritual preparation before their full impact becomes clear to us. In the first letter to the Corinthians, Paul described the need to have the Spirit of God with us in order to understand the things of God: “Now we have received, not the spirit of the world, but the spirit which is of God; that we might know the things that are freely given to us of God” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/2.12" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 2:12</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/2.11,14" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 2:11, 14</a>). As the Spirit of God helps us understand and know His plan for us, we will find not only greater knowledge but also a greater measure of peace and compassion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p21" pid="3qT6ctLYjki5C2-oCSoHHQ" hash="5-dTlQ">Temple ordinances also provide an opportunity to strengthen our families, something so much needed today. Strength can be provided through performing ordinances vicariously for our ancestors, thus forming a “welding link” between parents and children (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/128.18" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 128:18</a>). For example, in the temple we can be baptized vicariously for our ancestors who may not have had a chance to hear the gospel during their mortal lives (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/15.29" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 15:29</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p22" pid="FatMxRHWpkeOQ2kvcS9XJQ" hash="SV8Ypw">In Japan, I witnessed a 21-year-old man accept the gospel. After baptism, he was the only member of the Church in his family. He completed the family history work for his deceased grandfather so he could perform ordinance work vicariously for him, literally doing something for his grandfather that his grandfather could no longer do for himself. As this young man came up out of the baptismal font, he had tears in his eyes. He said, “Now I know and feel, I have a witness, that I am not the only member of this Church in my family.” These ordinances strengthened his relationship with his family and brought a new closeness into his life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p23" pid="cq-my3fd_kuIJOchACbWaA" hash="RPzIwg">At the dedication of the Manti Temple, President Lorenzo Snow prayed: “May this holy temple be to them as one of the gates of heaven, opening into the straight and narrow path that leads to endless lives and eternal dominion” (Manti Temple dedication, 21 May 1888).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings.p24" pid="gagTLstgwUiCWD1sBr2bxA" hash="QCxTSw">Brothers and sisters, the gates of heaven are open to us and the Lord Jesus Christ is inviting us to come unto Him, I humbly testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1998/10/small-temples-large-blessings</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1998-general-conference/1998-10-4030-elder-david-e-sorensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5344400" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 1998 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Can’t Pet a Rattlesnake</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Pornography, though billed by Satan as entertainment, is a deeply poisonous, deceptive snake that lies coiled up in magazines, the Internet, and the television.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029247_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="9AvPcA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="K_7OyllAakGgxqg6RK21sg" hash="3RZcmQ">You Can’t Pet a Rattlesnake</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="vKyznbATl0iV1nQ1rbfAXQ" hash="RxlkYw">David E. Sorensen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="USF1PrHeK0G08uiIdpKaew" hash="jzYT_Q">Pornography, though billed by Satan as entertainment, is a deeply poisonous, deceptive snake that lies coiled up in magazines, the Internet, and the television.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-e3.jpg" alt="Elder David E. Sorensen" pid="RKXvm1QhMk6eMh97FceYGg" hash="ypTUOg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p1" pid="zGFHU-wpqkq7Xaf_Bh9BiQ" hash="abZ7vA">Some years ago, Sister Sorensen and I had the privilege of visiting India. At one airport I remember walking across the landing strip and seeing some men sitting in front of wicker baskets, playing flutes. As they started to play the music, they would take the top off the basket and a cobra would appear! As the music continued, the snake would rise higher and higher, nearly reaching its full length until the cobra would collapse back into the basket. Once I noticed a cobra fall outside the basket. The man playing the flute reached over, petted the cobra, and carefully put it back into the basket. I was amazed that a man could handle such a dangerous creature apparently without being harmed. But our guide quickly told me that this was very risky and told us that a major cause of death in this province was indeed poisonous snakebite.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p2" pid="lEIy_LU8-0ypbkQ5uqLATQ" hash="bcRYNg">My mind raced back to the days of my youth on the farm. In the summertime one of our responsibilities was to haul hay from the fields into the barn for winter storage. My dad would pitch the hay onto a flatbed wagon. I would then tromp down the hay to get as much as possible on the wagon. One day, in one of the loose bundles pitched onto the wagon was a rattlesnake! When I looked at it, I was concerned, excited, and afraid. The snake was lying in the nice, cool hay. The sun was glistening on its diamond back. After a few moments the snake stopped rattling, became still, and I became very curious. I started to get closer and leaned over for a better look, when suddenly I heard a call from my father: “David, my boy, you can’t pet a rattlesnake!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p3" pid="5hMW9NdXRkKUtgnmwvSlBQ" hash="oOs_BA">Tonight I would like to talk to you about the dangers of petting poisonous snakes. The ones I refer to do not have long, slithering bodies but come in many other forms. Often the world makes these dangers look harmless—even exciting and interesting. But petting such snakes fills the mind with poison—poison that drives away the Holy Spirit.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p4" pid="6ISBsbI-vUqMEqv0KTxAPA" hash="y_0YVw">Brethren, today’s popular entertainment often makes what is evil and wrong look enjoyable and right. Let us remember the Lord’s counsel: “Woe unto them that call evil good, and good evil.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p5" pid="o6UrEr9c_Uy31mLAiOvdpQ" hash="GMrRlg">Pornography, though billed by Satan as entertainment, is a deeply poisonous, deceptive snake that lies coiled up in magazines, the Internet, and the television. Pornography destroys self-esteem and weakens self-discipline. It is far more deadly to the spirit than the rattlesnake my father warned me not to pet. The Bible records that King David was gifted spiritually, but he stood where he should not have stood. He watched what he should not have watched. Those obsessions became his downfall.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p6" pid="pJoaVoWwiUW3qQ-R5Idm2w" hash="2tiFvw">Resisting the temptations of today’s electronic media is not easy. It takes focused courage and effort. In the small town where I grew up, one had to drive at least an hour to find trouble. But today on the Internet, trouble is just a few mouse clicks away. To avoid such temptations, be like Captain Moroni of old; set up “fortifications” to strengthen your places of weakness. Instead of building walls of “timbers and dirt” to protect a vulnerable city, build “fortifications” in the form of personal ground rules to protect your priceless virtue.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> When you’re on a date, plan to be in groups and avoid being alone. I know men, young and old, who have simply determined not to turn on the TV or surf the Internet anytime when they are alone. Fathers, it is wise to keep computers and televisions in the family room or other high-traffic areas in your home—not in children’s bedrooms. I also know of fathers who, while on business trips, wisely choose not to turn on the hotel television.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p7" pid="twWo_hRYcESOUr834d0sEA" hash="xas3FA">Remember, such “fortifications” are not a sign of weakness. On the contrary, they show strength. The scriptures tell us Captain Moroni was so strong that if all men would be like him, “the very powers of hell would [be] shaken forever.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Remember Moroni’s “strongholds”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> were the key to his success. Creating your own “strongholds” will be the key to yours.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p8" pid="K56_IALRl0Wm0FwWa_3dFA" hash="aUExjg">One key fortification you can build is to decide now, before you face a challenge, where to draw the line. Our prophet teaches that if we decide now not to watch inappropriate media but instead to walk away, “the challenge is behind us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p9" pid="zvEAUTe_8EGBKRwJ5R0Viw" hash="nojYgQ">Recently my granddaughter Jennifer was invited to go with several of her school friends to a dinner and a movie. The girls all agreed on the movie they were going to see, and Jennifer was comfortable attending. However, the girl who left dinner to buy the movie tickets for the group returned with tickets to a different movie than was planned! She said, “It is a great show, and it’s R-rated.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p10" pid="oZLz2NukPEilMGqFSNzz1Q" hash="IQ0T2A">Jennifer, caught by surprise, couldn’t believe the situation had changed so quickly. But fortunately she had made up her mind before she ever found herself in this position that she would not watch R-rated movies. She was able to stand firm and say to her friends, “I can’t go see an R-rated movie. My parents would not approve.” To which the girls replied, “Oh, come on! Your parents will never know!” Confronted with this, Jennifer went on to say, “Well, actually it doesn’t matter whether my parents will know. I just don’t go to R-rated movies!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p11" pid="qKgQ102yy0qmeRm3eXRTJQ" hash="CVekmA">Her friends were upset and tried to get her to relent. They told her she “was ruining everything.” When she would not give in, they threw the ticket and change in her face and deserted her for the R-rated movie. It wound up being a lonely night full of rejection from her friends. But it was a great moment for Jennifer and our family.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> She gained confidence, self-worth, and spiritual power.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p12" pid="pVVVsat9V0eo_bcHwN031g" hash="4yf_Cw">Knowingly petting a poisonous spiritual snake is doubly dangerous.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Those who do remind me of the little boy who was overheard praying, “Heavenly Father, if you can’t make me a better boy, don’t worry about it. I’m having a real good time like I am.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p13" pid="YgCtn9IU2EWhTYXk-YVq4w" hash="nRq-PQ">Don’t be like that shortsighted boy. Those who plan to sin, thinking they can repent before they receive the sacred covenants and ordinances of the temple, risk losing their spiritual health. They find it is a painful process to come back to the right path.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p14" pid="X9GsBRdWT06ajC1jI9GrjQ" hash="KPU9mw">For those who suffer from a poisonous snakebite, there is a painful cleansing process. Where the bite was inflicted, a cut with a sharp knife is required. Then, someone must cleanse the infected blood from the wound. Often a stay in the hospital is required. My plea to you tonight, brethren, is to avoid petting that rattlesnake. It is much better not to commit the sin.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p15" pid="DSoe7LMQvk6dMfSrmv4VIg" hash="vqhjQQ">Some young men, as they advance in the priesthood, plan for a mission, or prepare to go to the temple, realize they suffer from a snakebite that has spiritually poisoned them. Sexual sins are among the most poisonous.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p16" pid="Nj9BnR_jWkK1GyUotCLFdw" hash="XECtJQ">If you or someone you know has been poisoned spiritually, there is a spiritual snakebite kit. It’s called repentance.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> And like the remedy for temporal snakebite, it is most effective if applied quickly and early. It can combat even the most venomous spiritual poisons. “For, behold, the Lord your Redeemer suffered death in the flesh; wherefore he suffered the pain of all men, that all men might repent and come unto him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> The miracle of forgiveness is real.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> Your repentance is honored of the Lord.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p17" pid="7tMlub6xSUWzDZkxfnckiw" hash="h9ZLxw">An important step in obtaining the cure for spiritual poison is to get on your knees and ask Heavenly Father to forgive you.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> Pray for the desire to do what is right. Pray for the courage to talk to your parents and the bishop if necessary.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> Regardless of your fears, they will continue to love you. You don’t have to do this alone. The path of repentance, though difficult, need not be traveled alone. Parents and leaders can provide valuable encouragement and support.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p18" pid="KSGs3BZZ5U-J16tDrs172Q" hash="8AG3Jg">The power and freedom of forgiveness is real. The Savior taught, “The truth shall make you free.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> Joy comes from living the way the Savior lived.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> He has asked us to keep our thoughts pure.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> He has asked us to maintain our self-respect. He has asked us to become a good influence on our family and our friends. We are to love them and to lift them toward the light. He said, “By this shall all men know that ye are my disciples, if ye have love one to another.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> He has promised He will help us live His standards. He has said: “Take my yoke upon you. … For my yoke is easy, and my burden is light.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p19" pid="CKgMDaolTEue6RhK63qfiw" hash="sDMs-g">Brethren of the priesthood, can you join me right here, right now, once again to commit and to take upon you the name of Christ? With this priesthood which you hold, can you rise up and wield the power of God to defend righteousness? Can you stand in holy places?<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p20" pid="4n7MNf5bsU20s4U9K4MrIw" hash="QP2mGw">We have all accepted the responsibility to pattern our life after the Master. He has committed the keys of the priesthood and of divine revelation to our living prophet, Gordon B. Hinckley. He counsels, “Stay away from pornography.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> “I plead with you to get it out of your life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake.p21" pid="dZbpD-X1xUajUHccZNdvXQ" hash="oFsDlw">Don’t allow the poison to touch your souls, brethren. Remember, “He that is righteous is favored of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26">26</span> I testify of this in the name of our Lord and Master, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2001/04/you-can-t-pet-a-rattlesnake</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2001-general-conference/2001-04-3020-elder-david-e-sorensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="4871676" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2001 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forgiveness Will Change Bitterness to Love</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Forgiveness means that problems of the past no longer dictate our destinies, and we can focus on the future with God’s love in our hearts.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030371_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="OUtZ1g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="6Z1UtUonIUiiuYF1Rio2cQ" hash="TELskA">Forgiveness Will Change Bitterness to Love</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Vyntpgsuukyoo7xa2HX5JA" hash="RxlkYw">David E. Sorensen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="E7UdjNijI0S4oXmTH885yg" hash="zOYAHQ">Forgiveness means that problems of the past no longer dictate our destinies, and we can focus on the future with God’s love in our hearts.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-e3.jpg" alt="Elder David E. Sorensen" pid="x60Rk0A1iUWnuJXxgH2hGg" hash="ypTUOg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p1" pid="7FU8J_aoOEWr8stSOhpr6g" hash="jQwUAg">Isn’t it amazing, the gifts of the Spirit that the Lord has given to Elder Nelson. His talents bless not only the Church, but the whole world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p2" pid="yLnIpNsozka_GsAVIM-jgA" hash="G_9mWQ">I’d like to speak today of forgiveness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p3" pid="9CJjvRKAbUKQUg6BiDKV8g" hash="mUOTJQ">I grew up in a small farming town where water was the lifeblood of the community. I remember the people of our society constantly watching, worrying, and praying over the rain, irrigation rights, and water in general. Sometimes my children chide me; they say they never knew someone so preoccupied with rain. I tell them I suppose that’s true because where I grew up the rain was more than a preoccupation. It was a matter of survival!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p4" pid="KeHO6Lq0v0qfCoY5_Rq2sA" hash="Lhd9yw">Under the stress and strain of our climate, sometimes people weren’t always at their best. Occasionally, neighbors would squabble over one farmer taking too long a turn from the irrigation ditch. That’s how it started with two men who lived near our mountain pasture, whom I will call Chet and Walt. These two neighbors began to quarrel over water from the irrigation ditch they shared. It was innocent enough at first, but over the years the two men allowed their disagreements to turn into resentment and then arguments—even to the point of threats.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p5" pid="411D473rmkGhWxEXz58gVg" hash="YgX0sA">One July morning both men felt they were once again short of water. Each went to the ditch to see what had happened, each in his own mind reckoning the other had stolen his water. They arrived at the headgate at the same time. Angry words were exchanged; a scuffle ensued. Walt was a large man with great strength. Chet was small, wiry, and tenacious. In the heat of the scuffle, the shovels the men were carrying were used as weapons. Walt accidentally struck one of Chet’s eyes with the shovel, leaving him blind in that eye.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p6" pid="50r2UbhALUqeQcyAX__ytg" hash="jOI7ew">Months and years passed, yet Chet could not forget nor forgive. The anger that he felt over losing his eye boiled inside him, and his hatred grew more intense. One day, Chet went to his barn, took down the gun from its rack, got on his horse, and rode down to the headgate of the ditch. He put a dam in the ditch and diverted the water away from Walt’s farm, knowing that Walt would soon come to see what had happened. Then Chet slipped into the brush and waited. When Walt appeared, Chet shot him dead. Then he got on his horse, went back to his home, and called the sheriff to inform him that he had just shot Walt.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p7" pid="E3Xv2wCkJUCL8gOrpnoIow" hash="fcQMYw">My father was asked to be on the jury that tried Chet for murder. Father disqualified himself because he was a longtime friend of both men and their families. Chet was tried and convicted of murder and sentenced to life in prison.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p8" pid="alO60FHMhkq3n51NOEPSXA" hash="bfhqxA">After many years, Chet’s wife came to my father and asked if he would sign a petition to the governor, asking for clemency for her husband, whose health was now broken after serving so many years in the state penitentiary. Father signed the petition. A few nights later, two of Walt’s grown sons appeared at our door. They were very angry and upset. They said that because Father had signed the petition, many others had signed. They asked Father to have his name withdrawn from the petition. He said no. He felt that Chet was a broken and sick man. He had suffered these many years in prison for that terrible crime of passion. He wanted to see Chet have a decent funeral and burial beside his family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p9" pid="gOlk8ryYjkCIeLzYPeQB9A" hash="8VMYBQ">Walt’s sons whirled in anger and said, “If he is released from prison, we will see that harm comes to him and his family.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p10" pid="aDygIv1DJEmeOhyujeSsqA" hash="ntdl2g">Chet was eventually released and allowed to come home to die with his family. Fortunately, there was no further violence between the families. My father often lamented how tragic it was that Chet and Walt, these two neighbors and boyhood friends, had fallen captive to their anger and let it destroy their lives. How tragic that the passion of the moment was allowed to escalate out of control—eventually taking the lives of both men—simply because two men could not forgive each other over a few shares of irrigation water.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p11" pid="6gFWFjfRwki-56Tq7R_z5A" hash="TXfqjQ">The Savior said, “Agree with thine adversary quickly, whiles thou art in the way with him,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> thus commanding us to resolve our differences early on, lest the passions of the moment escalate into physical or emotional cruelty, and we fall captive to our anger.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p12" pid="FwWMWE1U506Hl5hYSex9gQ" hash="SDSbCw">Nowhere does this principle apply more than in our families. Your specific concern may not be water, but each of us on earth, living under the stress and strain of this telestial climate, will have reason—real or perceived—to take offense. How will we react? Will we take offense? Will we find fault? Will we let the passions of the moment overcome us?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p13" pid="n6Tjx26s-0S44tuzCnk4DQ" hash="S1rnZg">President Brigham Young once compared being offended to a poisonous snakebite. He said that “there are two courses of action to follow when one is bitten by a rattlesnake. One may, in anger, fear, or vengefulness, pursue the creature and kill it. Or he may make full haste to get the venom out of his system.” He said, “If we pursue the latter course we will likely survive, but if we attempt to follow the former, we may not be around long enough to finish it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p14" pid="nNjH9BH1hUiZqboHe-0_vQ" hash="WFnK1w">Now let me take a moment here to note that we must take care in our families not to cause spiritual or emotional snakebites in the first place! In much of today’s popular culture, the virtues of forgiveness and kindness are belittled, while ridicule, anger, and harsh criticism are encouraged. If we are not careful, we can fall prey to these habits within our own homes and families and soon find ourselves criticizing our spouse, our children, our extended family members. Let us not hurt the ones we love the most by selfish criticism! In our families, small arguments and petty criticisms, if allowed to go unchecked, can poison relationships and escalate into estrangements, even abuse and divorce. Instead, just like we learned with the poisonous venom, we must “make full haste” to reduce arguments, eliminate ridicule, do away with criticism, and remove resentment and anger. We cannot afford to let such dangerous passions ruminate—not even one day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p15" pid="OHVDYm0eT0KTcmX1tbGppA" hash="29wTKw">Contrast Walt and Chet’s tragic story with the example of Joseph of Egypt. Joseph’s brothers jealously hated him. They plotted to take his life and finally sold him as a slave. Joseph was carried into Egypt and struggled for years to rise from slavery. During these challenging times, Joseph might have condemned his brothers and sworn revenge. He might have soothed his pain by scheming to get even someday. But he did not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p16" pid="4vLe1ZYw-USjift51GU00g" hash="lyqWpQ">In time, Joseph became ruler over all of Egypt, second in command only to Pharaoh. During a devastating famine, Joseph’s brothers traveled to Egypt for food. Not recognizing Joseph, they bowed down to him because of his high position. Surely at that moment Joseph had the power to exact revenge. He might have put his brethren in prison or sentenced them to death. Instead he confirmed his forgiveness. He said: “I am Joseph your brother, whom ye sold into Egypt. Now therefore be not grieved, nor angry with yourselves, that ye sold me hither. … And God sent me before you to preserve you a posterity … and to save your lives by a great deliverance. So now it was not you that sent me hither, but God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p17" pid="ptd5Vl5nCkiH7yATsdnxCA" hash="ScNqhw">Joseph’s will to forgive changed bitterness to love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p18" pid="4MuwnxWUsE-RVYqdjxLggw" hash="AN1xYA">I would like to make it clear that forgiveness of sins should not be confused with tolerating evil. In fact, in the Joseph Smith Translation, the Lord said, “Judge righteous judgment.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> The Savior asks us to forsake and combat evil in all its forms, and although we must forgive a neighbor who injures us, we should still work constructively to prevent that injury from being repeated. A woman who is abused should not seek revenge, but neither should she feel that she cannot take steps to prevent further abuse. A businessperson treated unfairly in a transaction should not hate the person who was dishonest but could take appropriate steps to remedy the wrong. Forgiveness does not require us to accept or tolerate evil. It does not require us to ignore the wrong that we see in the world around us or in our own lives. But as we fight against sin, we must not allow hatred or anger to control our thoughts or actions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p19" pid="6FWyfx9qekSiA78f32jDHA" hash="6ZjV-w">The Savior said, “Wherefore, I say unto you, that ye ought to forgive one another; for he that forgiveth not his brother his trespasses standeth condemned before the Lord; for there remaineth in him the greater sin.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p20" pid="OIGxyEn2CE2HSBuHd64FEg" hash="rVGmAw">This is not to say that forgiveness is easy. When someone has hurt us or those we care about, that pain can almost be overwhelming. It can feel as if the pain or the injustice is the most important thing in the world and that we have no choice but to seek vengeance. But Christ, the Prince of Peace, teaches us a better way. It can be very difficult to forgive someone the harm they’ve done us, but when we do, we open ourselves up to a better future. No longer does someone else’s wrongdoing control our course. When we forgive others, it frees us to choose how we will live our own lives. Forgiveness means that problems of the past no longer dictate our destinies, and we can focus on the future with God’s love in our hearts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love.p21" pid="XzviwV-D5EWnqNn17OKkLw" hash="poybdQ">May the seeds of unforgivingness that haunted my neighbors never be allowed to take root in our homes. May we pray to our Heavenly Father to help us overcome foolish pride, resentment, and pettiness. May He help us to forgive and love, so we may be friends with our Savior, others, and ourselves. “Even as Christ forgave you, so also do ye.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> In the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2003/04/forgiveness-will-change-bitterness-to-love</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2003-general-conference/2003-04-1030-elder-david-e-sorensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5649824" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2003 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faith Is the Answer</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Remember that faith and obedience are still the answers—even when things go wrong, perhaps especially when things go wrong.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10032029_000_026" doc-version="2" hash="MYkVgw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="2OeLKzlcBUW5VFDVfcXYjw" hash="qBU6LA">Faith Is the Answer</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="3ias0LVy1kqgBBcoNYYaxg" hash="RxlkYw">David E. Sorensen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="WV_yDtmZQUWUICKLU7jXtw" hash="268eCQ">Remember that faith and obedience are still the answers—even when things go wrong, perhaps especially when things go wrong.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-e3.jpg" alt="Elder David E. Sorensen" pid="-u6DMVABaUKPzlJgMyaV1Q" hash="ypTUOg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p1" pid="UzdfSZqPWU6vdEs7hQJECg" hash="nYe1qg">In the early 1950s the United States was at war on the Korean peninsula. Because of the draft policy of the government at that time, young men were not allowed to serve missions but instead required to join the military. Knowing this, I enrolled in the Army Reserve Officers’ Training Corps when I went to college. My goal was to become an officer like my oldest brother. However, during a visit home for the Christmas holiday, my home-ward bishop, Vern Freeman, invited me into his office. He advised me that a young Church leader by the name of Brother Gordon B. Hinckley had negotiated an agreement with the U.S. government permitting each ward in the Church in the United States to call one young man to serve a mission. This young man would receive an automatic deferment from the military during his mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p2" pid="PO4op6nUMEasRRTdSeV7wg" hash="SZfimA">Bishop Freeman said he had been praying about it and felt he should recommend me to serve as a full-time missionary representing our ward. I explained to him that I had already made other plans—I had enrolled in the Army ROTC and expected to become an officer! My bishop gently reminded me that he had been prompted to recommend me to serve a mission at that particular time. He said, “Go home and talk to your parents and come back this evening with your answer.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p3" pid="oHkV8zXGR0eG09nIOPeQfQ" hash="q6yQWQ">I went home and told my father and mother what had happened. They said the bishop was inspired, and I should happily accept the Lord’s invitation to serve. My mother could see how disappointed I was at the prospect of not becoming an army officer right away. She quoted:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p4" pid="dp794nfxDkeCYnrs6KHQcg" hash="FVxn3Q">“Trust in the Lord with all thine heart; and lean not unto thine own understanding.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p5" pid="vvcWLMxxfUq2_0s01Q-CAw" hash="59Al4w">“In all thy ways acknowledge him, and he shall direct thy paths.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p6" pid="cApR7p-5IU2c8q8UjeQaWw" hash="-Nktog">That night I went back to the bishop’s office and accepted his invitation. He told me to go to the Selective Service Office and advise them of my decision.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p7" pid="VAgruW2MJU2wJqywJrjUEw" hash="KzlOCg">When I did so, to my surprise the lady who was chairman of the Selective Service Office told me: “If you accept a mission call, you will receive your draft notice before you can reenter Army ROTC. You will serve as an enlisted man, not as an officer.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p8" pid="F-0Pv7JGsEmcsgXmRpnICA" hash="43c8VQ">Despite this unexpected change, my mission was wonderful. It changed the course of my life as it does for those who serve. But, true to their word, the government sent an induction letter drafting me into the U.S. Army about one month before my mission release.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p9" pid="t8qLNurSzUCIsLf6ekE27w" hash="7W2o6w">After boot camp and military police school, I found myself assigned to an army base to work as a military policeman. One night I was given an all-night assignment to escort a convoy of prisoners from one camp to another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p10" pid="uzpGUIFfakKEsmSlbRz9tQ" hash="LNkv4Q">During the night the convoy stopped at a halfway point for a rest. The commanding officer instructed us to go into the restaurant and drink coffee so we could stay awake the rest of the night. Right away he noticed that I declined. He said, “Soldier, you need to drink some coffee to stay awake the rest of this trip. I do not want any prisoners escaping or causing trouble on my watch.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p11" pid="FUs9bTOI1EyCfYqCjzC58A" hash="s6gFvQ">I said, “Sir, I respectfully decline. I am a Mormon, and I don’t drink coffee.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p12" pid="nJyxD1A64kOqtbfOBBc97Q" hash="6UVcVw">He didn’t care for my answer, and he again admonished me to drink the coffee.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p13" pid="4F8ivQibhk-GB9EvDbzHkw" hash="jOLAZw">Again, I politely refused. I took my place at the rear of the bus, my weapon in hand, praying in my heart that I would stay awake and never have to use it. The trip ended uneventfully.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p14" pid="6KT96eHodk-PXU0MbjLhSA" hash="OqO68g">A few days later the same commanding officer invited me into his office for a private interview. He told me that even though he had worried that I would not be able to stay awake during the all-night trip, he appreciated that I had stood by my convictions. Then to my amazement he said his assistant was being transferred and he was recommending me to be his new assistant!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p15" pid="ifsHmCYJDUi_1uic5mBB-A" hash="9_O8FA">For most of the next two years I had many opportunities for leadership and managerial assignments. As it turned out, the positive experiences during my military service were more than I had ever dreamed possible.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p16" pid="WL2Mm7rVH0eL7DpjvEtgNw" hash="_JtVHQ">From this simple story—and many more like it over the course of my life—I have learned faith and obedience are the answers to our concerns, cares, and suffering. Faith in the Lord Jesus Christ is truly the power that can change our lives and lead us to salvation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p17" pid="nW5OFaUkNU29GogCgyfcVQ" hash="wh2ILw">How can we build this faith? Through our actions. We must “go and do the things which the Lord hath commanded,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> just as Nephi counseled. We must trust in the Lord with all our hearts, as my mother so lovingly taught me. Gratefully, many times when we exercise faith to do the Lord’s will, we find that we are richly blessed for our obedience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p18" pid="cEQJp4OdT0-3LdGMyfSixQ" hash="_vOhyw">Sometimes, though, we find that even when we do our best to serve the Lord, we still suffer. You may know someone who faces these most challenging of circumstances: consider the parent whose child becomes ill, for whom everyone prays and fasts with all their heart and soul, but who ultimately dies. Or the missionary who sacrifices to go on a mission, then develops a terrible illness that leaves him or her severely disabled or in chronic pain. Or the woman who lives her life as faithfully and obediently as she can but is never able to have the children she hopes for. Or the wife who does her very best making a good home for her family and raising her children, but whose husband leaves her. The scriptures have many examples of people who were saved after showing great faith, such as Shadrach, Meshach, and Abed-nego in the fiery furnace. But the scriptures also have many examples of devout people who did not get divine intervention during a crisis. Abinadi was burned at the stake; John the Baptist was beheaded; Alma and Amulek’s followers were cast into the flames. To do well does not mean everything will always turn out well. The key is to remember that faith and obedience are still the answers—even when things go wrong, perhaps especially when things go wrong.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p19" pid="YkVbrKe4ekOTqo9JSHoU4A" hash="DD_ZcQ">Remember the Lord has promised that He will help us as we face adversity. He has particular compassion for those who suffer. It was He who said, “Blessed are they that mourn: for they shall be comforted.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p20" pid="oGVWPElZPECq9XO7So7pcg" hash="24tCtQ">As part of the Atonement, our Savior suffered all things. He knows physical and emotional pain; He knows the sorrow of loss and betrayal. But He showed us that ultimately love, patience, humility, and obedience are the path to true peace and happiness. Jesus said, “Peace I leave with you, my peace I give unto you.” But then, to warn us to look for more than just worldly comfort, Jesus added, “Not as the world giveth, give I unto you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> The world sees peace as the absence of conflict or pain, but Jesus offers us solace despite our suffering. His life was not free of conflict or pain, but it was free of fear and full of meaning. The Apostle Peter wrote: “If, when ye do well, and suffer for it, ye take it patiently, this is acceptable with God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p21" pid="yneFX0HZxkiiI0Fpfq_b1Q" hash="y9IFPQ">“For even hereunto were ye called: because Christ also suffered for us, leaving us an example, that ye should follow his steps: …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p22" pid="kDko1Fykd0OAxYfiBjldlg" hash="H1mAgg">“Who, when he was reviled, reviled not again; when he suffered, he threatened not; but committed himself to him that judgeth righteously.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p23" pid="wLI52T0ClkOg7iZwV8a0pQ" hash="Gnn4UQ">We who have accepted Jesus Christ as our Savior must rely wholly on the merits of Christ. He will save us after all we can do. When we courageously exercise our faith and when we go forward relying on the merits of Christ, He will bless us and guide us in all of our efforts. He will strengthen us and bring us peace in the time of our trials. “For we walk by faith, not by sight.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> I pray that each of us can better learn to put our trust in the Lord and to increase our faith in Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p24" pid="ebN-2Sz4QUGCbObRvVXOBg" hash="gGnQVg">Now, brothers and sisters, in closing I wish to mention one other topic. Over the past years I have been blessed to be able to observe President Hinckley closely, and I want to remind you that President Hinckley is not only a living prophet but also a living seer. He sees things that others do not see. He has the gift of discernment; he is an optimist and a realist. I wish to express my gratitude to the Lord for preserving President Hinckley’s life and permitting him and his noble counselors to lead the Church for these past 10 years. Through President Hinckley’s divine guidance, the Church has received many far-reaching blessings, many that are not obvious. I strongly encourage each of you to more closely follow his counsel and guidance, for truly “a seer hath the Lord raised up unto his people.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer.p25" pid="YaLOWJGZSk2gC4xQ6Q1SLA" hash="1Q2V4g">Jesus is the Christ. Joseph is the prophet of the Restoration. President Gordon B. Hinckley is our living prophet. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2005/04/faith-is-the-answer</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2005-general-conference/2005-04-4030-elder-david-e-sorensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5469148" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2005 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
