<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By David F. Evans</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by David F. Evans.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/David%20F.%20Evans.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by David F. Evans.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Your Mission Will Change Everything</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Come and be part of the greatest generation of missionaries the world has ever known.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006561_000_013" doc-version="3" hash="Z-fAjg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="u0-8YANcoE6W9oxdr7Hx_Q" hash="CG977Q">Your Mission Will Change Everything</h1><p class="authorName" uuid="43a13c96-a254-4bab-b30c-6bb9af09e55e" pid="MBWlYkFCw0GsS4jgHxELXA" hash="0scg5A">David F. Evans</p><p class="kicker" pid="dENlVKT4pUOMdBzNroUBcA" hash="d0tLSQ">Come and be part of the greatest generation of missionaries the world has ever known.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" uuid="c8dac751-0dc9-46ed-99c5-167808e980d6">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything.t1" uuid="">
      <img src="en2006lp.nfo-o-d3.jpg" alt="Elder David F. Evans" uuid="7c02e90f-f688-4dd0-9e04-7f9bf62a6784" pid="5DeZNInMjESnQzp82AmEiQ" hash="WLGjMw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything.p1" uuid="c954cb56-7feb-4c73-b60a-83123a371659" pid="Txq2TrzO3k6tQI1i610iVA" hash="P9Ct3w">It has been a year since I was sustained in general conference. I am grateful for this year and for all that I have experienced. I love the Lord and am so very grateful for His sacrifice and for His gospel. I love President Hinckley and sustain him as the Lord’s prophet on the earth. Together with faithful Saints everywhere, I testify of prophets and apostles in our time and pledge my life to His cause.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything.p2" uuid="93718995-cac1-44d2-b8de-a605d7086c8c" pid="XwITgvwV1k2KhH0_5ZX2CQ" hash="x2Jw8Q">A few years ago, I was interviewing missionaries. A winter storm was blowing in as missionaries came and went throughout the day. The storm changed from icy rain to snow and back again. Some missionaries arrived by train from nearby cities and walked to the church through the storm. Others rode their bicycles. Almost without exception they were cheerful and happy. They were the Lord’s missionaries. They had His Spirit and felt joy in His service regardless of their circumstances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything.p3" uuid="70bed30e-4e36-445b-9a5b-a0b2a6b9cd42" pid="bDPtSWO0qUu-fu0DPeYEOw" hash="SUsUBg">As each companionship concluded their interviews, I will never forget watching them go back out into the storm to preach the gospel and do what the Lord had called them to do. I could see their commitment and dedication. I could feel the love they had for the people and for the Lord. As I watched them leave, I felt an overwhelming love for them and for what they were doing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything.p4" uuid="45fea153-c921-4ac2-9ff2-4124ca4235e1" pid="iiuxYp57vES1X192HOeEHw" hash="DyYfRw">Later that night, I attended a priesthood meeting in the same city. The storm had continued and was now mostly snow. During the opening song, the branch president of the smallest and farthest branch and his two missionary counselors, Elder Warner and Elder Karpowitz, came into the chapel. As they got ready to sit down, these two wonderful missionaries took off their winter hats and gloves. They took off their outer coats. Then they each took off a second winter coat and sat down. Like the missionaries earlier in the day, despite the weather these missionaries were happy. They felt the Spirit of the Lord in their lives. Through service in the Lord’s cause, they felt a certain love and warmth and joy that are difficult to describe.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything.p5" uuid="39c7e6c6-4293-420a-b310-77a66de7f855" pid="dlH5ZZG2u0C8C95VsRBZrw" hash="3Ny-RA">As I watched these great young missionaries that evening, I had a remarkable experience. In my mind’s eye, I saw missionaries throughout the mission going out into that winter night. Some were knocking doors and facing rejection as they sought to teach the gospel of Jesus Christ. Some were in homes or apartments teaching individuals and families. In spite of the conditions they faced, they were doing what they could to teach the gospel of Jesus Christ to those who would listen, and they were happy. Into my heart came a feeling that I cannot fully explain.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything.p6" uuid="a31d8c3f-ee57-497d-82ed-29a0928116ca" pid="IwZ6NBRnMkSryHAESNtROA" hash="FIIeww">By a wonderful gift of the Spirit, I felt His love, the pure love of Christ that He has for faithful missionaries everywhere, and it changed me forever. I understood how precious each missionary is to Him. I caught a glimpse of what prophets would describe as the “greatest generation of missionaries” the world has ever known (see M. Russell Ballard, “The Greatest Generation of Missionaries,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 2002, 47). I began to understand why it was necessary to raise the bar so that missionaries everywhere would be entitled to the protection, direction, and happiness that accompany the Spirit of the Lord. I also began to understand why—as parents, bishops, stake presidents, and other leaders—we must do everything we can to help the young people of the Church become worthy of the blessings of missionary service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything.p7" uuid="3be39b13-d88e-47eb-9dbf-36bd35781121" pid="cPZiTxRFa0eaSDhTv70Hag" hash="8pZsrw">President Hinckley described what happens to the heart of every missionary who commits his or her life and work to the Lord when he talked about his own missionary experiences. It was early in his mission, and he was discouraged. The work was hard, and the people were not receptive. However, there came a time when discouragement turned to commitment. For him, the beginning was a letter from his father in which he read: “Dear Gordon, I have your letter. … I have only one suggestion: Forget yourself and go to work.” In describing what happened next, he said: “I got on my knees in that little bedroom … and made a pledge that I would try to give myself unto the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything.p8" uuid="a6a398da-08ff-4e40-8e2b-e1f21817e746" pid="Vk1VzPxkTUmhUtU_XRQWmg" hash="l-hxMw">“The whole world changed. The fog lifted. The sun began to shine in my life. I had a new interest. I saw the beauty of this land. I saw the greatness of the people. … Everything that has happened to me since that’s been good I can trace to that decision made in that little house” (in Mike Cannon, “Missionary Theme Was Pervasive during Visit of President Hinckley,” <span class="emphasis">Church News,</span> Sept. 9, 1995, 4).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything.p9" uuid="da5f78d3-3c9c-46d3-a0da-725293abbf60" pid="6x0DwR-6d0eVHTXH1a5QUQ" hash="ZNCeCg">President Hinckley continued by saying: “You want to be happy? Forget yourself and get lost in this great cause, and bend your efforts to helping people” (in <span class="emphasis">Church News,</span> Sept. 9, 1995, 4).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything.p10" uuid="a7c95c8b-3eac-4c7d-8647-d227b6ba2809" pid="bQ8n0WxhKUalYmucisUuLw" hash="JBMBGw">To every young man I would say, do you want to be happy? If so, come and join with us, 52,000 strong and counting, and serve your fellow man as a missionary for the Lord. Make the commitment to give two years of your life to the Lord. It will change everything. You will be happy. The fog will lift. You will come to love the culture and the people you are called to serve. The work will be difficult, but there will also be great satisfaction and joy as you serve. If you are faithful during your mission and thereafter, you will look back on your life and say with President Hinckley, “Everything that has happened to me since that’s been good I can trace to that decision to serve a mission and give my life to the Lord.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything.p11" uuid="a78eef25-587f-4166-bf04-cce153488596" pid="cVHTMm1idEKy5CoNZ1m5NQ" hash="b25LFw">President Hinckley has reminded us that it is not only young elders who are entitled to these blessings. Couples serve wonderfully and are needed so very much. While young sisters are not obligated to serve, the President has said: “We need some young women. They perform a remarkable work” (“To the Bishops of the Church,” <span class="emphasis">Worldwide Leadership Training Meeting,</span> June 19, 2004, 27). We also know that there are some who, for health or other reasons, are honorably excused from service. We love them and know that our Heavenly Father will provide compensating blessings in their lives as they serve in other ways and live faithfully.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything.p12" uuid="b30aaccc-6ace-441b-9b41-9113b519a128" pid="OXqdAoLxtk2XdV6JSVGPgA" hash="OlZo-g">A year ago, Elder Ballard asked that parents, bishops, and branch presidents work together and help at least one more young man, in addition to those who would normally be prepared to serve, become worthy and be called from each ward and branch of the Church (see “One More,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 2005, 71). Many have responded. As leaders, we should all recommit ourselves to following this inspired request.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything.p13" uuid="281aa021-506e-4acb-8165-c78f1fec2629" pid="EJlTHoqI5UKwe1ctDR05nQ" hash="7uKMgQ">Brothers and sisters, many good bishops have been doing for a long time what Elder Ballard asked. Thirty-six years ago, Bishop Matheson called my home and invited me to his office. Because of world circumstances, the number of missionaries any ward could send was limited, but an additional space had become available, and he had the responsibility to recommend one more missionary. He told me he and his counselors had been praying. He told me that he was impressed that now was the time that the Lord wanted me to serve my mission. I was stunned. Never before had anyone said to me that the Lord had something He wanted me to do. I felt the Spirit of the Lord testify to me that I should go and that I should go now. I said to the bishop, “If the Lord wants me to serve, then I will go.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything.p14" uuid="df25bcc6-7dce-4926-bd9e-58bd7f0981c4" pid="_aw6XsG0f0CsLoizfGgoVg" hash="4Dy1mA">For me, everything changed. The fog really did lift, and happiness and joy came into my life. In one way or another, every good thing that has happened to me since that day has come because of the commitment made to serve the Lord and His children and give two years of my life in His service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything.p15" uuid="b5f9d2c5-6a00-49b6-84ab-14da1993f915" pid="IuYhngZCvUecrNNkVxQHJA" hash="hVG-CQ">I say again: Come and join with us. Come and be clean. Come and be happy. Come and experience the very thing that the Lord has said is of “most worth” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/15.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 15:6</a>) to you at this time in your life. Come and be part of the greatest generation of missionaries the world has ever known.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything.p16" uuid="5c341554-b168-4d78-af83-8b324e7abd7b" pid="L05BhvOER0apwUmU-L5TsQ" hash="DXbkGA">This is the work of the Lord. Our Father in Heaven lives, and His Son, Jesus Christ, leads and directs this work today. Of this I testify, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/04/your-mission-will-change-everything</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2006-general-conference/2006-04-2060-elder-david-f-evans-64k-eng.mp3" length="3861931" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Was It Worth It?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The work of naturally and normally sharing the gospel with those we care about and love will be the work and joy of our lives.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10485_000_55evans" doc-version="2" hash="Ec_ytA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="pXbb_X6KwkORHF2dyKV1DQ" hash="Bn8Hjw">Was It Worth It?</h1><p class="authorName" pid="B2hAIXXJwUSKW22sX6QGNA" hash="S68EJw">By Elder David F. Evans</p><p class="kicker" pid="--HZWKbXL0-I9K1yzQBgCQ" hash="Xo4r-A">The work of naturally and normally sharing the gospel with those we care about and love will be the work and joy of our lives.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" pid="D2Ho-yjt6Uq3WRnvoAN4Hw" hash="izIX6g">
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p5" pid="slAA3ZQzhU2olTnAtP8KvQ" hash="Lx1XZw">
      <span class="pageBreak" page-number="106"></span>During this conference and in other recent meetings,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> many of us have wondered, what can I do to help build up the Lord’s Church and see real growth where I live?</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p6" pid="JI6aQTiw3UaEiPScP1saOw" hash="DwGClg">In this and every other important endeavor, our most important work is always within our own home and family.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> It is within families that the Church is established and real growth occurs.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> We are to teach our children the principles and doctrines of the gospel. We need to help them have faith in Jesus Christ and prepare them for baptism when they are eight years old.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> We must be faithful ourselves so that they can see our example of love for the Lord and His Church. This helps our children feel joy in keeping the commandments, happiness in families, and gratitude in service to others. Within our homes we should follow the pattern given by Nephi when he said:</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p7" pid="yvE_7zDIBUagc7JiL7Daeg" hash="OplXBw">“We labor diligently … to persuade our children … to believe in Christ, and to be reconciled to God. …</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p8" pid="psMbAp_o70uR0Qlyju_J3Q" hash="Otasaw">“… We talk of Christ, we rejoice in Christ, we preach of Christ, we prophesy of Christ, and we write according to our prophecies, that our children may know to what source they may look for a remission of their sins.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p9" pid="DwD8giv3LkOxRC1SSiLarA" hash="WtuAoQ">We labor diligently to bring these blessings to our children by attending church with them, holding family home evening, and reading the scriptures together. We pray daily with our family, accept callings, visit the sick and the lonely, and do other things that let our children know that we love them and that we love our Heavenly Father, His Son, and Their Church.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p10" pid="-NO4nfKZ90KFvqxHRt8dMg" hash="2ctODw">We talk and prophesy of Christ as we give a family home evening lesson or sit with a child and tell of our love for him or her and of our testimony of the restored gospel.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p11" pid="JqZWmfroUkaDQyMEgE4eoA" hash="822HEg">We can write of Christ by writing letters to those who are away. Missionaries serving, sons or daughters in the military, and those we love are all blessed by letters we write. Letters from home are not just quick e-mails. Real letters provide something tangible that can be held, thought about, and cherished.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p12" pid="KB78O74tq0qO7ojBniKnHw" hash="W9Lssg">We help our children rely on the Savior’s Atonement and know the forgiveness of a loving Heavenly Father by showing love and forgiveness in our own parenting. Our love and forgiveness not only draw our children closer to us but also build their faith in knowing that Heavenly Father loves them and that He will forgive them as they strive to repent and do better and be better. They trust this truth because they have experienced the same from their earthly parents.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p13" pid="OCcvD_aL8Ee-8tNBBlH69Q" hash="h2Ja0w">In addition to the work we will do within our own family, Nephi taught that “we labor diligently to … persuade our … brethren, to believe in Christ, and to be reconciled to God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> As members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, every one of us has the blessing and responsibility of sharing the gospel. Some of those who need the gospel in their lives are not yet members of the Church. Some were once among us but need to feel again the joy they felt when they embraced the gospel at an earlier time in their lives. The Lord loves both the person who has never had the gospel and the person who is returning to Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> To Him and to us, it doesn’t matter. It is all one work. It is the worth of souls, whatever their condition, that is great to our Heavenly Father, His Son, and to us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> The work of our Heavenly Father and His Son is “to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> of all His children, regardless of their current circumstances. Our blessing is to help in this great work.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p14" pid="ddVI0k3lb0C9lFx0br87VA" hash="_pYHHw">President Thomas S. Monson explained how we can help when he said: “Our missionary experiences have to be current. It is not enough to sit back and ponder former experiences. To be fulfilled, you have to continue to naturally and normally share the gospel.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p15" pid="i8gkHzTn9U20vmbC7JOzOg" hash="ndMZUw">The work of naturally and normally sharing the gospel with those we care about and love will be the work and joy of our lives. Let me tell you about two such experiences.</p>
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p16" pid="JtLZw9y3gkqDn_WJlM_Vuw" hash="PZ2ADA">Dave Orchard grew up in Salt Lake City, where most of his friends were <span class="pageBreak" page-number="107"></span>members of the Church. They were a great influence on him. In addition, Church leaders in his neighborhood constantly invited him to activities. His friends did the same. Even though he didn’t join the Church at that time, his growing-up years were blessed by the influence of good LDS friends and Church-sponsored activities. After he entered college, he moved away from his home, and most of his friends left on missions. He missed their influence in his life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p17" pid="4iIbVp9eZky0JDOw3xW_iQ" hash="1_qRjA">One of Dave’s high school friends was still home. This friend was meeting every week with his bishop in an effort to put his life in order and be able to serve as a missionary. He and Dave became roommates, and as would be both natural and normal, they talked about why he wasn’t then serving as a missionary and why he was meeting frequently with the bishop. The friend expressed his gratitude and respect for his bishop and the opportunity to repent and serve. He then asked Dave whether he would like to come to the next interview. What an invitation! But in the context of their friendship and circumstances, it was both natural and normal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p18" pid="K-JI-Dk8nkaGDJOWveS0wA" hash="Me2NZA">Dave agreed and was soon meeting with the bishop himself. This led to Dave’s decision to meet with the missionaries. He received a testimony that the gospel is true, and a date for his baptism was set. Dave was baptized by his bishop, and a year later, Dave Orchard and Katherine Evans were married in the temple. They have five beautiful children. Katherine is my little sister. I will be forever grateful to this good friend who, together with a good bishop, brought Dave into the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p19" pid="Y6BNr5cEgEiCT8-2Gpd5OQ" hash="y_xvfg">As Dave spoke of his conversion and bore his testimony regarding these events, he asked the question, “So, was it worth it? Was all the effort of friends and youth leaders and my bishop, over all the years, worth the effort to have just one boy be baptized?” Pointing to Katherine and his five children, he said, “Well, at least for my wife and our five children, the answer is yes.”</p>
    </span>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p20" pid="pL0cJYOS8UqCGZT4-qZ16Q" hash="850Y-Q">Whenever the gospel is shared, it is never “just one boy.” Whenever conversion happens or someone returns to the Lord, it is a family that is saved. As Dave and Katherine’s children have grown, they have all embraced the gospel. One daughter and two sons have served as missionaries, and one just received his call to serve in the Alpine German-Speaking Mission. The two oldest have married in the temple, and the youngest is now in high school, faithful in every way. Was it worth it? Oh yes, it was worth it.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p21" pid="UklkXUuKDEm5MqrGlX6xVQ" hash="bSOWDA">Sister Eileen Waite attended the same stake conference where Dave Orchard told of his conversion experience. Throughout the conference, all she could think of was her own family and particularly her sister, Michelle, who had long been away from the Church. Michelle was divorced and trying to raise four children. Eileen <span class="pageBreak" page-number="108"></span>felt impressed to send her a copy of Elder M. Russell Ballard’s book <span class="emphasis">Our Search for Happiness,</span> together with her testimony, which she did. The very next week a friend told Eileen that she too had felt that she should contact Michelle. This friend also wrote Michelle a note, sharing her testimony and expressing her love. Isn’t it interesting how often the Spirit works on several people to help one in need?</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p22" pid="_3Q0_f1seEKHdu09w1w26g" hash="CrLl1Q">Time passed. Michelle called Eileen and thanked her for the book. She said that she was beginning to recognize the spiritual void in her life. Eileen told her that she knew that the peace she was seeking could be found in the gospel. She told her that she loved her and wanted her to be happy. Michelle began to make changes in her life. Soon she met a wonderful man who was active in the Church. They married and a year later were sealed in the Ogden Utah Temple. Recently her 24-year-old son was baptized.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p23" pid="KmVyNOQTNEOjOThQll_RFg" hash="9_9ILA">To the others in Michelle’s family and all others who do not yet know that this Church is true, I invite you to prayerfully consider whether the Church is true. Allow your family and friends and missionaries to help. When you know that it is true, and it is, come join with us by taking the same step in your life.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p24" pid="fOHCYRTuCEK8xDQOcS8n-w" hash="Sa6A_w">The end of this story has not yet been written, but blessings have been given to this wonderful woman and her family as those who love her acted on a prompting and in a natural and normal way shared their testimony and invited her to come back.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p25" pid="XSO9Kc3hGEO8-fcZ65ul-Q" hash="RlrEdQ">I have thought a lot about these two experiences. One young man who was working to put his own life in order helped another young man who was seeking the truth. One woman shared her testimony and her faith with her sister who had been away from the Church for 20 years. If we will pray and ask Heavenly Father who we can help and promise to act on the promptings He gives us letting us know how we can help, He will answer our prayers and we will become instruments in His hands to do His work. Acting in love upon the promptings given by the Spirit becomes the catalyst.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p26" pid="GF2Y7ZEsUUOtAmIiAosWmw" hash="g5sI5g">As you have listened to these experiences of naturally and normally sharing the gospel with those you care about, many of you have had the same experience that Eileen Waite had. You have thought of someone to whom you should reach out and either invite to come back or share with him or her your feelings about the gospel of Jesus Christ. My invitation is to act, without delay, on that prompting. Talk to your friend or family member. Do it in a natural and normal way. Let them know of your love for them and for the Lord. Missionaries can help. My counsel is the same that President Monson has given so many times from this very pulpit: “Never delay a prompting.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> As you act on the prompting and do it with love, watch as our Heavenly Father uses your willingness to act to bring about a miracle in your life and in the life of the person you care about.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it.p27" pid="-vNfzEbOdEWfTR1QdR46Xw" hash="IZrFxA">My dear brothers and sisters, we can build up His Church and see real growth as we work to bring the blessings of the gospel to our family and to those we love. This is the work of our Heavenly Father and His Son. I know that They live and that They answer prayers. As we act on those promptings, having faith in Their ability to bring about a miracle, miracles will occur and lives will change. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2012/04/was-it-worth-it</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2012-general-conference/2012-04-5050-elder-david-f-evans-64k-eng.mp3" length="5256423" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
