<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By David M. McConkie</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by David M. McConkie.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/David%20M.%20McConkie.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by David M. McConkie.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Gospel Learning and Teaching</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching?lang=eng</link>
      <description>What matters most is the attitude or spirit by which the teacher teaches.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021411_000_1050" doc-version="2" hash="d0bSkg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="7QudkBPJLkKtpeKuVVFBOw" hash="f-_y9w">Gospel Learning and Teaching</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="J-uXb7mGSUiU3ClcmH7t4Q" hash="TB-Ztw">David M. McConkie</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="orq8aB2MAUqnEkJiLtIpCg" hash="JwKv5w">What matters most is the attitude or spirit by which the teacher teaches.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p1" pid="h-l2rmE6QUm4OcIJzq9-Zw" hash="b08KHg">As a member of the Sunday School general presidency, I feel I should begin my remarks this morning by saying, “Good morning, class.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p2" pid="GAOio5MxdUq0b0rBLcBPUQ" hash="HbN8kw">My message today is to all those who have been called to teach, in whatever organization you are serving and whether you are a recent convert to the Church or a teacher with years of experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p3" pid="aNfhqfWbm06ZbvGunxVlbQ" hash="ho0Hlw">I am not going to talk about the “how” of teaching but rather about the “how” of learning. There can be a significant difference between what a teacher says and what those in the class hear or learn.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p4" pid="oVDv4CH67UKzWtJgRMjNjw" hash="QfGETQ">Think for a moment of a teacher who really made a difference in your life. What was it about him or her that caused you to remember what was taught, to want to discover the truth for yourself, to exercise your agency and act and not just to be acted upon—in other words, to learn? What was it about this teacher that set him or her apart from the rest?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p5" pid="K4lB9VK_SE2G9tMHHfL2jA" hash="5t1HkA">A successful teacher and author said: “What matters most in learning is attitude. The attitude of the teacher.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p6" pid="4rV2FCwtskijEufGq8LlzQ" hash="ELjBzA">Note that what matters most in learning is not the number of years a teacher has been a member of the Church or how much teaching experience a person has or even the teacher’s knowledge of the gospel or teaching techniques. What matters most is the attitude or spirit by which the teacher teaches.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p7" pid="G8swDzQuGE2m2xs277XUpA" hash="HuYcZQ">In a worldwide leadership training meeting, Elder Jeffrey R. Holland told this story: “For many years, I have loved the story that President Packer has told about William E. Berrett’s boyhood Sunday School teacher. An elderly Danish brother was called to teach a class of rowdy boys. … He didn’t speak the language very well; he still had a heavy Danish brogue; he was much older, with big farm hands. Yet he was to teach these young, rambunctious 15-year-olds. For all intents and purposes, it would not have seemed like a very good match. But Brother Berrett used to say—and this is the part President Packer quotes—that this man somehow taught them; that across all those barriers, across all those limitations, this man reached into the hearts of those rowdy 15-year-old kids and changed their lives. And Brother Berrett’s testimony was ‘We could have warmed our hands by the fire of his faith.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p8" pid="gNW_UZvtc02pEQ1YHGoJSA" hash="QrR-cA">Successful gospel teachers love the gospel. They are excited about it. And because they love their students, they want them to feel as they feel and to experience what they have experienced. To teach the gospel is to share your love of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p9" pid="hWwJNFEcoUOWnDmLJr8zUA" hash="jB0kcw">Brothers and sisters, a teacher’s attitude is not taught; it’s caught.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p10" pid="8t-kXfc6hkys1tm-nwZmVQ" hash="4rhCZA">How, then, do we develop the attitude necessary to be a successful teacher? I would like to discuss four basic principles of gospel teaching.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p11" pid="c-dK67y6N02dAj5XJdOVcA" hash="dghp7w">First, immerse yourself in the scriptures. We cannot love what we do not know. Develop a habit of daily scripture study, separate and apart from your lesson preparation. Before we can teach the gospel, we must know the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p12" pid="RlKryA_Ar0Or8Jo9_r36Gg" hash="jLp1mQ">President Thomas S. Monson still treasures the memory of his boyhood Sunday School teacher. He said: “It was my experience as a small boy to come under the influence of a most effective and inspired teacher who listened to us and who loved us. Her name was Lucy Gertsch. In our Sunday School class, she taught us concerning the Creation of the world, the Fall of Adam, the atoning sacrifice of Jesus. She brought to her classroom as honored guests Moses, Joshua, Peter, Thomas, Paul, and, of course, Christ. Though we did not see them, we learned to love, honor, and emulate them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p13" pid="3ir5_Zshbk2R3pXix1fohw" hash="WWxnXQ">Lucy Gertsch was able to invite these honored guests into her classroom because she knew them. They were her cherished friends. Because of that, her class also learned to “love, honor, and emulate them.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p14" pid="QPEwKNCnr0ykNz_Ijoh30g" hash="Jn6efQ">The Lord said to Hyrum Smith, “Seek not to declare my word, but first seek to obtain my word.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> This admonition applies to each of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p15" pid="_smvyHLS60yAvqnpyufLPA" hash="2rINOw">The Lord has commanded us to search the scriptures,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> to feast upon them,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> and to treasure them up.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> As we earnestly search and ponder the word of the Lord, we will have His Spirit with us. We will become acquainted with His voice.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p16" pid="no-f_DnhiEyvl9pgsHSbRg" hash="-wEIkA">Soon after I was called to be a stake president, our stake presidency received training from an Area Seventy. During the training, I asked a question to which he responded, “That is a good question. Let’s turn to the <span class="emphasis">Church Handbook of Instructions</span> for the answer.” We then went to the handbook, and there was the answer to my question. A little later in our training, I asked another question. Once again he responded, “Good question. Let’s turn to the handbook.” I did not venture to ask any more questions. I thought it best to read the handbook.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p17" pid="1Rab-83E70ODOVD4rEXzWQ" hash="VHaBdQ">I have thought since that the Lord could give a similar response to each of us as we go to Him with concerns or questions. He could say, “That’s a good question. If you will review Alma chapter 5 or Doctrine and Covenants section 76, you’ll remember that I have already spoken to you about this.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p18" pid="AYiwvTrnUkq9GyxsgG1c6A" hash="bKqwBA">Brothers and sisters, it is contrary to the economy of heaven for the Lord to repeat to each of us individually what He has already revealed to us collectively. The scriptures contain the words of Christ. They are the voice of the Lord. Studying the scriptures trains us to hear the Lord’s voice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p19" pid="3NhUbCbDqkuAeK4ygDZT2g" hash="msd51g">Second, apply in your life the things that you learn. When Hyrum Smith desired to be a part of this great latter-day work, the Lord said to him, “Behold, this is your work, to keep my commandments, yea, with all your might, mind and strength.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Our work, first and foremost as teachers, is to keep the commandments with all of our might, mind, and strength.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p20" pid="Q4zwDyg4pEOykJ7HTNm_8Q" hash="EDpilg">Third, seek heaven’s help. Appeal unto the Lord for His Spirit with all of the energy of your heart. The scriptures state, “If ye receive not the Spirit ye shall not teach.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> This means that even if you use all the right teaching techniques and what you are teaching is true, without the Spirit real learning is not going to take place.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p21" pid="X4RlFrFrUUujLqEpWoUUyw" hash="AAvjXg">The role of the teacher is “to help individuals take responsibility for learning the gospel—to awaken in them the desire to study, understand, and live the gospel.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> This means that as teachers we should not focus so much on our performance as on how we help others learn and live the gospel.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p22" pid="kYxuR415h064zZgqi0-V0g" hash="ZVsAoA">When was the last time you knelt in prayer and asked the Lord to help you not just with your lesson but also to help you to know and to meet the needs of each student in your class? No class is so large that we cannot pray for inspiration regarding how to reach each student.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p23" pid="PrCRR6Llb0-Rxam3daiq0w" hash="bKxbGQ">It is natural for teachers to have feelings of inadequacy. You must understand that “age and maturity and intellectual training are not in any way or to any degree necessary to communion with the Lord and His Spirit.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p24" pid="APXn88N0XEK4vUqzm2phaQ" hash="2z1AUA">The promises of the Lord are certain. If you earnestly search the scriptures and treasure up in your minds the words of life, if you keep the commandments with all of your heart and pray for each student, you will enjoy the companionship of the Holy Ghost and you will receive revelation.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p25" pid="BxKrpgdaqkShBPRzcOkLvg" hash="7splDg">Fourth, brothers and sisters, it is of utmost importance that we exercise our agency and act, without delay, in accordance with the spiritual promptings we receive.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p26" pid="XKnfUhcyjUu0C4m3JVNu1A" hash="Thps8g">President Thomas S. Monson taught: “We watch. We wait. We listen for that still, small voice. When it speaks, wise men and women obey. Promptings of the Spirit are not to be postponed.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p27" pid="2FvvWQDK70Wh1FdfRDj38Q" hash="AXjY7Q">You must not be afraid to exercise your agency and act upon the thoughts and impressions that the Spirit of the Lord puts into your heart. You may feel awkward at first, but I promise you that the sweetest and most gratifying experiences you will have as a teacher will be when you submit to the will of the Lord and follow the promptings you receive from the Holy Ghost. Your experiences will strengthen your faith and give you greater courage to act in the future.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching.p28" pid="dLTphtY1XUaL2iLF0YdqkA" hash="L-1Tbw">Dear teachers, you are one of the great miracles of this Church. You have a sacred trust. We love you and have confidence in you. I know that if we will search the scriptures and live so that we are worthy to have the companionship of the Holy Ghost, the Lord will magnify us in our callings and responsibilities so that we may accomplish our errand from the Lord. That we may all do so is my prayer in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/10/gospel-learning-and-teaching</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2010-general-conference/2010-10-1050-david-m-mcconkie-64k-eng.mp3" length="4896391" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching with the Power and Authority of God</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Lord has provided the way for every worthy Latter-day Saint to teach in the Savior’s way.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10791_000_53mcconkie" doc-version="6" hash="xWTgDw">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="BgfuaQ93Ek27dXE-mLdt3A" hash="dqkWww">Teaching with the Power and Authority of God</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="3t41UReHsUSqGoypbtLjmw" hash="81HsEg">By David M. McConkie</p>
		<p class="kicker" pid="rI00o6Lo40CGO4inWDSvuQ" hash="OAlI4Q">The Lord has provided the way for every worthy Latter-day Saint to teach in the Savior’s way.</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p5" pid="ZJSDTHUCKEKZhCUfVmCWHA" hash="p8qjPg"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="96"></span>We are grateful beyond any measure of expression for teachers throughout the Church. We love you and have great confidence in you. You are one of the great miracles of the restored gospel.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p6" pid="O0ajciKDZUOsdQ0rjm7jbA" hash="D72jLw">There is indeed a secret to becoming a successful gospel teacher, to teaching with the power and authority of God. I use the word <span class="emphasis">secret</span> because the principles upon which a teacher’s success rests can be understood only by those who have a testimony of what took place on the morning of a beautiful, clear day, early in the spring of 1820.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p7" pid="UF1IGE2Ej0GVj8NVncsmCA" hash="iDtSRQ">In response to a 14-year-old boy’s humble prayer, the heavens were opened. God the Eternal Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, appeared and spoke to the Prophet Joseph Smith. The long-awaited restitution of all things had begun, and the principle of revelation was everlastingly established in our dispensation. Joseph’s message, and our message to the world, can be summarized in two words: “God speaks.” He spoke anciently, He spoke to Joseph, and He will speak to you. This is what sets you apart from all other teachers in the world. This is why you cannot fail.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p8" pid="bgnW4-OpU0WA2yK51C8vAw" hash="wzCGlA">You have been called by the spirit of prophecy and revelation and have been set apart by priesthood authority. What does this mean?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p9" pid="JBOxQwKawkKu36RR1Ap90g" hash="4QmoXw">First, it means that you are on the Lord’s errand. You are His agent, and you are authorized and commissioned to represent Him and to act on His behalf. As His agent, you are entitled to His help. You must ask yourself, “What would the Savior say if He were teaching my class today, and how would He say it?” You must then do likewise.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p10" pid="zR4WBxLTvEmYXIdQfGvDqQ" hash="vBG-8g">This responsibility may cause some to feel inadequate or even somewhat fearful. The pathway is not difficult. The Lord has provided the way for every worthy Latter-day Saint to teach in the Savior’s way.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p11" pid="CdELAsAD1Ea90Gw3scFH4w" hash="KdtlsA">Second, you are called to preach the gospel of Jesus Christ. You must not teach your own ideas or philosophy, even mingled with scriptures. The gospel is “the power of God unto salvation,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> and it is only through the gospel that we are saved.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p12" pid="_ah6uAUGrEKWaaSG8apuEw" hash="NVRvSg">Third, you are commanded to teach the principles of the gospel as they are found in the standard works of the Church, to teach the words of modern-day apostles and prophets, and to teach that which is taught you by the Holy Ghost.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p13" pid="yfctljgMH0y_T67T23yZfg" hash="z-V6uw">So where do we begin?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p14" pid="enn7TcPq3UCb4Dza4iii8g" hash="yyAlvQ">Our first and foremost responsibility is to live so that we can have the Holy Ghost as our guide and companion. When Hyrum Smith sought to become engaged in this latter-day work, the Lord said, “Behold, this is your work, to keep my commandments, yea, with all your might, mind and strength.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> This is the starting point. The counsel, provided by the Lord to Hyrum, is the same counsel He has provided to the Saints in every age.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p15" pid="HBt6EjIcc0-bXIruupejnw" hash="kPppWw">Speaking to teachers today, the First Presidency stated: “The most important part of your service will be your own daily spiritual preparation, including prayer, scripture study, and obedience to the commandments. We encourage you to dedicate yourself to <span class="pageBreak" page-number="97"></span>living the gospel with greater purpose than ever before.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p16" pid="2ANKfbVPzUqMqLL8ojIVkw" hash="QaPdTA">It is significant that the First Presidency did not say that the most important part of your service is to prepare your lesson well or to master various teaching techniques. Of course, you must diligently prepare for each lesson and strive to learn how you can teach so as to help your students exercise their agency and allow the gospel to enter into their hearts, but the first and most important part of your service is your personal, spiritual preparation. As you follow this counsel, the First Presidency has promised: “The Holy Ghost will help you to know what to do. Your own testimony will grow, your conversion will be deepened, and you will be strengthened to meet the challenges of life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p17" pid="YgAH5bjxckyyvZYFHfVKyw" hash="vzObKw">What greater blessings could a teacher desire?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p18" pid="cP7qNdXZVUGc0MYX4cgexA" hash="rZbhBg">Next, the Lord has commanded that before we seek to declare His word, we must seek to obtain it.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> You must become men and women of sound understanding by diligently searching the scriptures and by treasuring them up in your hearts. Then as you ask for the Lord’s help, He will bless you with His Spirit and His word. You will have the power of God unto the convincing of men.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p19" pid="QOhMsFydX0uWeZXVs45h2w" hash="kL9eOg">Paul tells us that the gospel comes to men in two ways, in word and in power.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> The word of the gospel is written in the scriptures, and we can obtain the word by diligently searching. The power of the gospel comes into the lives of those who so live that the Holy Ghost is their companion and who follow the promptings they receive. Some focus their attention only on obtaining the word, and they become experts in delivering information. Others neglect their preparation and hope that the Lord in His goodness will somehow help them get through the class period. You cannot expect the Spirit to help you remember the scriptures and principles you have not studied or considered. In order to successfully teach the gospel, you must have both the word and the power of the gospel in your life.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p20" pid="HSVnnVgzGEianoo5zBDU3w" hash="B4xEnQ">Alma understood these principles when he rejoiced in the sons of Mosiah and how they taught with the power and authority of God. We read:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p21" pid="FQGtHWN33kugI5ohv2jBUg" hash="Vl3fHQ">“They were men of a sound understanding and they had searched the scriptures diligently, that they might know the word of God.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p22" pid="-SnEHZailEyVbQC1coJwjA" hash="IOQnWg">“But this is not all; they had given themselves to much prayer, and fasting; therefore they had … the spirit of revelation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p23" pid="XLDUiWu8rUaKaWd2J3-5cg" hash="PxXSuA">Next, you must learn to listen. Elder Jeffrey R. Holland taught this principle to missionaries. I will quote from Elder Holland’s remarks but have taken the liberty of replacing the terms <span class="emphasis">missionaries</span> and <span class="emphasis">investigators</span> with the terms <span class="emphasis">teachers</span> and <span class="emphasis">students</span> respectively: <span class="pageBreak" page-number="98"></span>“Second only to the responsibility [teachers] have to listen to the Spirit, is the responsibility they have to listen to the [student]. … If we’ll listen with spiritual ears, … <span class="emphasis">[our students] will tell us</span> what lessons they need to hear!”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p24" pid="yk0HYD0GUkaXmOkRMxkWjQ" hash="e3hqBw">Elder Holland continued: “The fact of the matter is [teachers] are still too focused on delivering comfortable, repetitious lesson content rather than focusing on their [students] as individuals.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p25" pid="jUf0hK453U29gwmeOgBC5w" hash="7szVUg">After you have prepared yourself and your lesson to the very best of your ability, you must be willing to let go. When the quiet promptings of the Holy Ghost come, you must have the courage to set aside your outlines and your notes and go where those promptings take you. When you do this, the lesson you deliver is no longer your lesson, but it becomes the Savior’s lesson.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p26" pid="o9ADDaR9nk2oJu3iMf0SLw" hash="HaUTSA">As you dedicate yourself to living the gospel with greater purpose than ever before and search the scriptures, treasuring them up in your heart, the same Holy Ghost, who revealed these words to apostles and prophets anciently, will testify to you of their truthfulness. In essence, the Holy Ghost will reveal them anew to you. When this happens, the words that you read are no longer only the words of Nephi or Paul or Alma, but they become your words. Then, as you teach, the Holy Ghost will be able to bring all things to your remembrance. Indeed, “it shall be given you in the very hour, yea, in the very moment, what ye shall say.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> When this happens, you will find yourself saying something that you did not plan to say. Then, if you will pay attention, you will learn something from the things that you say when you teach. President Marion G. Romney said, “I always know when I am speaking under the inspiration of the Holy Ghost because I always learn something from what I’ve said.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Remember, a teacher is also a student.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p27" pid="ZJWeP-7XJUq8CgviU2PSBw" hash="JUKO_A">Finally, you must stand as an independent witness of the things you teach and not just be an echo of the words in a manual or the thoughts of others. As you feast upon the words of Christ and strive to live the gospel with greater purpose than ever before, the Holy Ghost will manifest unto you that the things you are teaching are true. This is the spirit of revelation, and this same spirit will carry your message into the hearts of those who desire and are willing to receive it.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god.p28" pid="5S1LTy4t102EmJGrGo-ANA" hash="wiQNxQ">Let us now end where we started—in the Sacred Grove. Because of what took place on that beautiful spring morning not so long ago, you are entitled to teach with the power and authority of God. Of this I bear my solemn and independent witness in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2013/10/teaching-with-the-power-and-authority-of-god</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2013-general-conference/2013-10-5030-david-m-mcconkie-64k-eng.mp3" length="5202686" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
