<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By David L. Beck</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by David L. Beck.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/David%20L.%20Beck.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by David L. Beck.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2010 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Magnificent Aaronic Priesthood</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood?lang=eng</link>
      <description>There is an urgency for you to fulfill your duty to God. I am confident that you will.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021388_000_024" doc-version="2" hash="dUTJ8g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="3LxPf2drTEyMshRrYmSsIg" hash="7gDy0Q">The Magnificent Aaronic Priesthood</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="N8veoFDSHEiofP-GvHyTvw" hash="k7-wdA">David L. Beck</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="n_AK45KR8U-fj053A5DCag" hash="OcunDQ">There is an urgency for you to fulfill your duty to God. I am confident that you will.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p1" pid="YGkYoatp00iIuPfri-WPIg" hash="Hvi17w">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="54"></span>I am honored tonight to speak to the amazing young men of the Church. I have been blessed to meet many of you throughout the world. Your enthusiasm is contagious.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p2" pid="aD-eF9RjJE-gxQY8vRokkw" hash="SVVLHw">You face your challenges with extraordinary strength and courage. I express my love to you and the confidence I have in you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p3" pid="zk-bsZETN0G-Ynbw5myimA" hash="Mm5sCQ">You inspire the people around you more than you can imagine. Listen to the words of a young man who is not of our faith, trying to describe his friend who holds the Aaronic Priesthood: “I do notice something different about Luis. … This guy is nothing like … other people. It’s just something you see in him. … I don’t even know what it is, but he’s different than all of them. It’s just something you feel; it’s not [something] … you see visually. You just feel it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p4" pid="8CLLU5WouE-bBh_1m4q_pg" hash="lOt2gQ">There is something very important that sets Luis and you apart from other young men. You have received the Aaronic Priesthood. It is a sacred gift, and many do not fully appreciate it. Tonight I will help you see how you can discover for yourselves the magnificence of the Aaronic Priesthood.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="WtVBqFxs0U22ZgbewQtopQ" hash="jU-0Ug">I. God Trusts You</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p5" pid="oAHbSBMew0yFk-HXBw2njQ" hash="RLPrcg">When God entrusts you with His sacred priesthood, He shows great confidence in you. He knows He can trust you to use the priesthood to serve others, just as He has trusted other young men to do some of His most important work.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p6" pid="01ujjO-21kekP_ZOAS5DdA" hash="TgCk5A">For example, the world would not have the Book of Mormon’s powerful witness of Jesus Christ if it had not been for two young men whom God trusted. Mormon, the prophet who compiled this sacred record, was just 10 years old when he was assigned to observe and later record the history of his people. At age 15, he was “visited of the Lord, and tasted and knew of the goodness of Jesus” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/morm/1.15" class="scriptureRef">Mormon 1:15</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p7" pid="OulXBTYR9UqlfZcaxwiVJw" hash="0Rte5w">The Book of Mormon was translated and published by Joseph Smith, who was called to his great work at age 14, when he was visited by Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p8" pid="7MDDfOZ_9UekS8-TkQnJig" hash="YqHU0A">President Thomas S. Monson has said: “Great things are expected of you. … Like a clarion call comes the word of the Lord to you, to me, and to priesthood holders everywhere: ‘Wherefore, now let every man learn his duty, and to act in the office in which he is appointed, in all diligence’” (“The Call for Courage,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 2004, 54, 57).</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="LNYODMOcF0ukBy0aDs_mzQ" hash="fAmh8Q">II. The New Duty to God Program</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p9" pid="zjYfa5XfgUieR5lWdpSVAQ" hash="pQH0bQ">To help you respond to that urgent call, the Church is introducing a new Duty to God program, as President Henry B. Eyring announced earlier today. I am excited about this program. Materials will be sent to your bishops and branch presidents beginning in June. You should begin using them as soon as you receive them.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p10" pid="ODWaZfIQNEKyFKFXY_Scsg" hash="QefqNA">As a deacon, teacher, and priest, you will participate in activities that will help you build spiritual strength and learn and fulfill your priesthood duties. Each activity follows this simple pattern:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p11" pid="k01k8hNayk2l4spCEkqOtw" hash="VQrsOg">First you <span class="strong">learn</span> about a gospel principle or a priesthood duty. You discover what Heavenly Father wants you to do, and you strive to gain a spiritual witness about why it is important.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p12" pid="D8JH-u4buke5syw1bUdCZg" hash="z5gW-A">Next you make plans to <span class="strong">act</span> on what you have learned. You are encouraged to base your plans on your own needs, circumstances, and opportunities to serve others. This is a wonderful chance to take responsibility for your own growth and develop spiritual self-reliance.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p13" pid="d1ZpMNx7HkyDdQKJ1DI9hA" hash="VHsVUQ">Then you <span class="strong">share</span> what you learn and experience with others. As you do so, you will strengthen your testimony and build faith in those around you. You will increase your ability to talk <span class="pageBreak" page-number="55"></span>about the gospel with others.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p14" pid="NtbwtrY4uUaLwaSWV9W11A" hash="vlyi3g">I am grateful to a young man who shared with me the following experience. He and another Aaronic Priesthood holder were assigned to administer the sacrament to a man who was homebound and very sick. They arrived at his home not realizing that recent medical treatments prevented him from eating any food—even a piece of the sacrament bread. After blessing the bread, the young man presented the sacrament to the frail man. He took a piece of the blessed bread, waited a moment, and then held it against his lips. The young man said when he saw this faithful brother express his reverence for the sacrament, he felt as though he were watching him kiss the feet of the Savior. He could tell that he loved Him.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p15" pid="M9aBk6_i-0mEG2Bpu4a12g" hash="cfVvyA">The significance of the sacrament was impressed upon that young man in an unforgettable way that day. You will have sacred experiences, just as this young man did.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p16" pid="El_6ZzOy6UqM-P5fxl2ulQ" hash="lISndA">Your parents, leaders, and quorum members play an important role in the Duty to God program. Your Sunday quorum meetings will provide regular opportunities to learn, act, and share. The new Duty to God program will guide you on your journey to fulfill your duty to God and discover the magnificence of the Aaronic Priesthood.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="8hqbiKiQzUmVRN9mRX0Svw" hash="_4z_kg">III. Fulfill Your Duty to God</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p17" pid="-IZGT7sztUSwS350_40-yA" hash="-F_tbw">During the past year I have been on a journey that has forever changed the way I view you and the Aaronic Priesthood. I am excited for you to discover for yourself what I have discovered. You will learn why the Aaronic Priesthood is so important in your life and how vital it is to the Church. You will appreciate why it is referred to as one of the “grand heads” of the priesthood (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:6</a>). You will understand better the meaning of priesthood keys, the ministering of angels, and the preparatory gospel (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/13" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 13</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.26" class="scriptureRef">84:26</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p18" pid="Rfs2QW5ad0OtlViXs6Iefw" hash="3vJuCg">Satan would have you think that you are too young or that there are too few of you to do significant things with the Aaronic Priesthood. None of that is true.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p19" pid="5PM7AVHrgkaTvvQdYhOrlw" hash="tEx0NA">God’s words to Moses are for you today: “Behold, thou art my son; … and I have a work for [you]” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.4,6" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:4, 6</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p20" pid="MzKvAcPcE02mVsI4-9i_ww" hash="84LEMA">He has given you His power to do great things. As you fulfill your duty to God, you will strengthen and bless your family. This is your greatest priesthood duty. Listen to a mother describe the impact her son has on his family: “Leo has the priesthood in our home, and it’s a huge blessing. He’s a good example to his siblings; … he makes sure they always pray. He passes the sacrament on Sundays. His little brother sees him. He helps … with family prayer. I know that he will continue to be a blessing as he gets older. He will be able to baptize his younger brother. It’s a comfort and a gift to us.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p21" pid="-6UBBXFeTUi-kRst9gxGnA" hash="3jrpRA">As you fulfill your duty to God, you will reach out to your friends who are not of our faith and help prepare them to join the Church. Like a true brother, you will watch over and strengthen them. You will lead out in the rescue of other young men who have lost their way.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p22" pid="eaKzv62Y8k6YojAmbUGrCg" hash="W4cRDQ">As you fulfill your duty to God, you will be a force for good at all times and in every circumstance. Your righteous example and your faithful priesthood service will be a powerful way to invite all who know you to come unto Christ.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p23" pid="5JIH2naWfkyNptrZQpdNtA" hash="i7qwMQ">In their most critical time, the Nephites looked to a young man, Mormon, for leadership and inspiration (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/morm/2.1-2" class="scriptureRef">Mormon 2:1–2</a>). Today, we look to you to be a great strength to the Church and a force for good on the earth. This is what the Lord expects.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="ashyoZLNHEKdzDQ8EcwaYA" hash="fFwdRA">IV. Become a Faithful Priesthood Man</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p24" pid="JcyBZ9cke02IQFknW1ssAQ" hash="-McyOA">
          <span class="pageBreak" page-number="56"></span>I testify that you will feel your heart changing as you become a faithful priesthood man. You will seek to be completely clean and administer the sacrament worthily. You will treat every young woman with kindness and respect. You will honor your parents. You will avoid offending the Spirit in what you think, say, or do. You will come to know the Lord, whom you serve, and you will ever strive to be like Him.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p25" pid="fRhHj-oobU-23Q-zxD5P1A" hash="HbY20g">I testify that your faithful service in the Aaronic Priesthood will change the lives of those you serve. There are people who need your priesthood service. Your family needs you. Your quorum needs you. The Church needs you. The world needs you.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p26" pid="kkfMOexNY0eBNiKbUUSa9w" hash="OcunDQ1">There is an urgency for you to fulfill your duty to God. I am confident that you will.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p27" pid="vdzYxn9NHk2VEuznxbvnGQ" hash="l6Vq-g">On a cold morning a few weeks ago, I jogged along the Tagus River in Lisbon, Portugal. I came to a monument dedicated to the Portuguese explorers from centuries past. I stopped as the sun rose and splashed its warm light on the imposing monument and on me. I was inspired as I looked at the determined faces of the explorers gazing out over the water. These were men who were willing to do things that very few had done. They left a familiar and comfortable world and courageously went out into the unknown ocean and discovered new lands. They changed the world.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p28" pid="MKk8hwNoLEuEbRw2J_xhSg" hash="F9pUYw">I see you when I think of that monument of courageous explorers. I see you on a personal journey that few in the world today choose to pursue. I see you fulfilling your duty to God.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood.p29" pid="-szt3jX8TUi8wQ3HLxnmQQ" hash="4nWpiQ">I pray that we may all understand the magnificent Aaronic Priesthood and trust, as God does, those who bear it. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/04/the-magnificent-aaronic-priesthood</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2010-general-conference/2010-04-3030-david-l-beck-64k-eng.mp3" length="5435212" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2010 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Sacred Duty to Minister</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister?lang=eng</link>
      <description>You received the power, the authority, and the sacred duty to minister the moment you were ordained to the priesthood.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10785_000_33beck" doc-version="2" hash="HJhUWQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="x4XfW93OP0iuvcnaN_pO1A" hash="YcpwVg">Your Sacred Duty to Minister</h1><p class="authorName" pid="-n82qZXWW0aP7aZhlroeiA" hash="Mqhwzw">By David L. Beck</p><p class="kicker" pid="cin2wNRE4ka_8gPJK4g6kQ" hash="-Y7YQQ">You received the power, the authority, and the sacred duty to minister the moment you were ordained to the priesthood.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
				<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.t1" pid="H6sDNVALh0aQ68JIAD7o5A" hash="HWC2HA">
					<h2 class="title" pid="nfPYNEsNaUGGKAwMnDd1aQ" hash="WWh-VQ">The Joy of Ministering</h2>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p6" pid="TsIsNfV-dEC3UrSSeWjIjA" hash="uKsK9w"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="55"></span>Young men of the Aaronic Priesthood, you are beloved sons of God, and He has a great work for you to do. To accomplish this work, you must fulfill your sacred duty to minister to others.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p7" pid="v_ZF1d-nSkCxS0byzd0wIw" hash="N8URWw">Do you know what it means to minister? Think about this question while I tell you about a girl named Chy Johnson.</p>
					<span class="story">
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p8" pid="RsSKL-xDY0e4AskQ3tr5XA" hash="65W-RA">When Chy started high school last year, she became the victim of cruel and thoughtless bullying. She was mistreated, shoved, and taunted as she walked to class—some students even threw garbage at her. You have probably seen people mistreated like this in your school too.</p>
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p9" pid="zjEAeF21EU2Ei9C5HxsNyw" hash="8EdSvg">For too many people, the teenage years are a time of loneliness and fear. It doesn’t have to be this way. Fortunately for Chy, there were young men at her school who understood what it means to minister.</p>
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p10" pid="ZsH4HjtCh0uknPgBICgqjA" hash="gE8QIw">Chy’s mother had asked teachers at the school to help stop the bullying, but it continued. She then contacted Carson Jones, an Aaronic Priesthood holder and the starting quarterback of the football team. She asked him to help her find out who was doing the bullying.</p>
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p11" pid="5GqIrXFUf0esZkRZAifb7w" hash="JkWPbg">Carson agreed to help, but in his heart he felt that he could do much more than just identify the bullies. The Spirit whispered to him that he needed to help Chy feel loved.</p>
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p12" pid="EyhaVg0Mok6uePrbYSH-cA" hash="ghDQfw">Carson asked some of his teammates to join him in ministering to Chy. They invited her to sit with them during lunch. They walked her to class to make sure she was safe. Not surprisingly, with football players as her close friends, no one bullied Chy anymore.</p>
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p13" pid="t-fky7s7PkuMwvsElgnOCw" hash="cOqiJg">This was an exciting season for the football team. But even with the thrill of an undefeated season, these young men did not forget about Chy. They invited her to join the team on the field after games. Chy felt loved and appreciated. She felt safe. She was happy.</p>
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p14" pid="GjzHJKuRGEqIuFX4hlICZA" hash="t4K-cA">The football team went on to win the state title. But something more important than a football championship happened at their school. The example of these young men has motivated other students to be more accepting, more friendly. They now treat each other with more kindness and respect.</p>
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p15" pid="98cja9M3a0iB7TeWL66Gdw" hash="u9-PWA">National news media found out what these young men had done and shared their story across the country. What began as an effort to minister to one is inspiring thousands of others to do the same.</p>
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p16" pid="YsM17yFMc02-fJLOPftQGw" hash="Q_ssvg">Chy’s mother calls these young men “angels in disguise.” Carson and his friends are quick to say that Chy has blessed their lives much more than they blessed hers. That’s what happens when you lose yourself in serving others—you find yourself.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> <span class="pageBreak" page-number="56"></span>You change and grow in ways that would not be possible otherwise. These young men have experienced the joy of ministering and continue to seek opportunities to bless others. They are anxious to extend their ministering in the coming months when they serve as full-time missionaries.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
					</span>
				</div>
				<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.t2">
					<h2 class="title" pid="bOs8jcEGrUOVvGRNlxmEZw" hash="BEaQNw">A Need and a Duty</h2>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p18" pid="BXEGDSFqKUahMV_-lcOs-g" hash="weXJ6w">There are thousands of Chy Johnsons throughout the world—people who need to feel Heavenly Father’s love. They are in your schools, in your quorums, and even in your family. Some come to mind quickly. Others have needs that are less obvious. Virtually everyone you know could be blessed in some way by your ministering. The Lord is counting on you to reach out to them.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p19" pid="JE1B6B5rgE6fwKx5xa7CEw" hash="MANe5w">You don’t have to be a star athlete to minister to others. You received the power, the authority, and the sacred duty to minister the moment you were ordained to the priesthood. President James E. Faust taught, “Priesthood is the authority delegated to man to <span class="emphasis">minister</span> in the name of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> The Aaronic Priesthood holds the keys of the ministering of angels.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p20" pid="WE0_evmua0qN57Ztvt8Zpg" hash="s-JLcw">As you love His children, Heavenly Father will guide you, and angels will assist you.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> You will be given power to bless lives and rescue souls.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p21" pid="NgVjg_LFZkGal-oBtyEkFg" hash="c5nAew">Jesus Christ is your example. He “came not to be ministered unto, but to minister.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> To minister means to love and care for others. It means to attend to their physical and spiritual needs. Put simply, it means to do what the Savior would do if He were here.</p>
				</div>
				<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.t3">
					<h2 class="title" pid="XjEPqvr52EqPfWR-HoiRgg" hash="yW6F3Q">Your Family</h2>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p23" pid="TwQlKOMkBU-9AryndoudtA" hash="iMNoDw">Start in your own home. This is where you can do your most important ministering.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p24" pid="MgUqwLqRg0iCfdrF3p4L-g" hash="uqdZiA">Do you want to try an interesting experiment? The next time your mother asks for your help around the house, say something like, “Thank you for asking, Mom. I would love to help.” Then watch her reaction. Some of you might want to brush up on your first aid skills before you try this. You may send her into shock. After you revive her, you’ll find a noticeable improvement in your relationship with her and an increase of the Spirit in your home.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p25" pid="ZIlp2PzsHUy2dBOYDjrHpg" hash="hxmWxg">That’s just one way to minister to your family; there are many others. You minister as you speak kind words to family members. You minister as you treat your siblings like your best friends.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p26" pid="FBI5SdQxnk2mG4v6wAJAiA" hash="8tvnjQ">Perhaps most important, you minister as you assist your father in his duties as the spiritual leader in your home. Give your full support and encouragement to family home evening, family prayer, and family scripture study. Do your part to ensure that the Spirit is present in your home. This will strengthen your father in his role and prepare you to be a father someday. If you do not have a father in your home, your responsibility to minister to your family is even more needed.</p>
				</div>
				<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.t4" pid="yZNcWot72EKryt24XaZ10A" hash="5dIprg">
					<h2 class="title" pid="u9mbU2FW10m5HVt3j3I9XQ" hash="u_-3sA">Your Quorum</h2>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p28" pid="sByhIwnblk2Mw_1FaXEbRw" hash="ROCK5Q">You also have a duty to minister in your quorum.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p29" pid="qZxp4CbfRUOZv9UhwsTqyQ" hash="-hLQYw">The priesthood is expanding across the world. Many of you are heeding President Monson’s call to rescue. There are more active Aaronic Priesthood holders today than ever before in the history of the Church. Yet there are still those who are not active and who need you.</p>
					<span class="story">
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p30" pid="yOxl5jRF8U6rEugvKMLlTQ" hash="d_EPMA">Last June, when a new branch was created in Bangalore, India, the only <span class="pageBreak" page-number="57"></span>young man in priesthood meeting was a recently ordained deacon named Gladwin.</p>
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p31" pid="BXa13wUSmEuStAUaT1BZ3g" hash="W3ZArg">Gladwin, along with the Young Men president and branch president, began calling the less-active young men and visiting them in their homes. Soon a second young man, Samuel, started coming to church again.</p>
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p32" pid="97lCZYQRaUCZLuReCeWMDQ" hash="yaLVjg">Each week Gladwin and Samuel called those who had not attended quorum meeting and shared what they had learned. They also called or visited them on their birthdays. One by one, the less-active young men became their friends and began to accept invitations to come to quorum activities, to attend quorum meetings, and eventually to do their own ministering. Today, all of the young men in the branch are active in the Church.</p>
					</span>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p33" pid="9TtsSFSepESoIkc1imtHGw" hash="mzFuLQ">The scriptures teach that Aaronic Priesthood quorums are to sit in council and edify—or build up and strengthen—one another.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> You edify as you teach gospel truths, share spiritual experiences, and bear testimony. The youth curriculum encourages these kinds of interactions in quorum meetings, but this can happen only when every member of the quorum feels loved and respected. Mocking and teasing have no place in a quorum meeting—especially when feelings are openly shared. Quorum presidencies must take the lead in ensuring that quorum meetings are a safe place for everyone to participate.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p34" pid="Bc4xvj9j_U6kv0HGYCczZA" hash="EQAuKg">The Apostle Paul admonished, “Let no corrupt communication proceed out of your mouth, but that which is good to the use of edifying, that it may minister grace unto the hearers.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p35" pid="1578DV4MsEWsBosddRLErA" hash="flq83w">Priesthood holders never use vulgar or filthy language. They never demean or hurt others. They always build up and strengthen others. This is a simple but powerful way to minister.</p>
				</div>
				<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.t5">
					<h2 class="title" pid="4HRJ95UMW0K8stvK9HxPnw" hash="iRcOlQ">At All Times</h2>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p37" pid="xKKSZC01yUGf_ZwBNWHE0A" hash="q1SJvA">The work of ministering is not confined to ordinances or home teaching visits or occasional service projects. We are always priesthood men—not just on Sunday and not only when we’re wearing white shirts and ties. We have a duty to minister wherever we stand. Ministering is not just something we do—it defines who we are.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p38" pid="lcWiN7fd8k6biWF7A3Yu-g" hash="_9Mgrg">Minister every day. Opportunities are all around you. Look for them. Ask the Lord to help you recognize them. You will find that most consist of small, sincere acts that help others become followers of Jesus Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p39" pid="Sb1Sb_GsCUmoLjl26pvbiw" hash="idjzeQ">As you strive to be worthy of the Spirit, you will recognize thoughts and feelings prompting you to minister. As you act on these promptings, you will receive more of them and your opportunities and ability to minister will increase and expand.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p40" pid="cCKKYCvCck-BY2ndbVaaCQ" hash="_Mb1pA">My young brethren, I testify that you have been given the authority and power of the magnificent Aaronic Priesthood to minister in God’s name.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p41" pid="ZiAS2ix2q0WvXKlgMdxO2A" hash="0KgKGA">I testify that as you do, you will be an instrument in God’s hands to help others. Your life will be richer and more meaningful. You will find greater strength to resist evil. You will find true happiness—the kind that is known only by true followers of Jesus Christ.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister.p42" pid="v2eFgRaT4kmNkmjZURLY5w" hash="odMgIA">May you experience the joy of fulfilling your sacred duty to minister, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
				</div>
			</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2013/04/your-sacred-duty-to-minister</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2013-general-conference/2013-04-3030-david-l-beck-64k-eng.mp3" length="4989384" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
