<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Dean L. Larsen</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Dean L. Larsen.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Dean%20L.%20Larsen.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Dean L. Larsen.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Oct 1976 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 1976 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>“I Am the Vine, Ye Are the Branches”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/10/i-am-the-vine-ye-are-the-branches?lang=eng</link>
      <description>This past week, as I read through some prospective material for the  magazine, I came to these lines of verse that reflect the reaction of a housewife after her first encounter with some Latter-day Saint missionaries:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-am-the-vine-ye-are-the-branches" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03076_000_006" doc-version="3" hash="TgPhgw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-am-the-vine-ye-are-the-branches.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="AQ0g_2INkUibHNSTx3nHOw" hash="hLFCYg">“I Am the Vine, Ye Are the Branches”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="tYpUehl800OzsvFlOAQ8Zg" hash="VXIyUA">Dean L. Larsen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-am-the-vine-ye-are-the-branches.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-246c.jpg" alt="Elder Dean L. Larsen" pid="_-hymjGcVUKCb8vlD5bMVA" hash="TC6x9Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-am-the-vine-ye-are-the-branches.p1" pid="4P1vilGTT06QNDl8wuHYSg" hash="MKvW6g">This past week, as I read through some prospective material for the <span class="emphasis">Ensign</span> magazine, I came to these lines of verse that reflect the reaction of a housewife after her first encounter with some Latter-day Saint missionaries:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-am-the-vine-ye-are-the-branches.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="LEo3P03Nyk-X0DGwZyMc3w" hash="xLeGMw">
            <span class="emphasis">The sun shone that afternoon and so did you</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="oEmuhV4wB0-EXqA-40pS9A" hash="rhArMw">
            <span class="emphasis">As I opened the door.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="8euHOd1OkkGkA4c2pK3vNQ" hash="z21doA">
            <span class="emphasis">Truth standing there and I concerned about my custard</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="KEVy45fRb0-efD5sU_a_ng" hash="3oLnAg">
            <span class="emphasis">And the kitchen floor.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="u-OjDRN6xUatu99wMnUoIA" hash="YRepfA">
            <span class="emphasis">You spoke, memories stirred and through the windows, darkly,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="ML54dAVkxES1pn3ZNRKn5g" hash="LXO90Q">
            <span class="emphasis">I watched the years</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="pWuaqkCNO0qWIrBbjrBW8g" hash="CNrSyA">
            <span class="emphasis">And wondered what it was I longed for</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="-vY_6woAikuZ0tLkzdXyzg" hash="DhisXw">
            <span class="emphasis">And why my tears.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="GekGclziIUe927UGvUKCJw" hash="1_7lhw">
            <span class="emphasis">You went on your way, but something lingered in the air,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Pn-I_PWqs0aOXaAs77hyjw" hash="1P8VPA">
            <span class="emphasis">Peace for my pain;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="0sVlyGw8OUSJikmP3DK4Sw" hash="0vq2kQ">
            <span class="emphasis">I picked up my mop, pretended that things could</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="tEUNr9Ya60mrJnTtUoNsnA" hash="MBCGVA">
            <span class="emphasis">Be the same again.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-am-the-vine-ye-are-the-branches.p2" pid="xyF9qE4deEa_5hg_M37__g" hash="b8oaaQ">Since receiving a phone call several days ago from President Kimball, in an attempt to maintain some equilibrium, I’ve been pretending that things would be the same again for me; I know they will not, and I desire with all my heart the sustaining influence of the Lord and the influence of your faith and prayers as I accept this new assignment. I have told the Lord that I am his to use however he sees fit. I have also made that pledge to President Kimball, and I am sustained in that by a loving, faithful wife and a loyal family. I have the consolation of these words of promise of the Lord to his earlier servants when he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-am-the-vine-ye-are-the-branches.p3" pid="cCF5-2z6w0aHXQhHoad-Kw" hash="fBcmBg">“Now ye are clean through the word which I have spoken unto you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-am-the-vine-ye-are-the-branches.p4" pid="GZplov1HnkqseyVj9TSo8Q" hash="rC0b2A">“Abide in me, and I in you. As the branch cannot bear fruit of itself, except it abide in the vine; no more can ye, except ye abide in me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-am-the-vine-ye-are-the-branches.p5" pid="BOCsylN21Eit--45o5qrDg" hash="oFoRuQ">“I am the vine, ye are the branches: He that abideth in me, and I in him, the same bringeth forth much fruit: for without me ye can do nothing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-am-the-vine-ye-are-the-branches.p6" pid="bI1LvByK4kSGGFEMvniFWA" hash="s6hXMQ">“If ye abide in me, and my words abide in you, ye shall ask what ye will, and it shall be done unto you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-am-the-vine-ye-are-the-branches.p7" pid="47UtMDnspEGOlbne15N6Aw" hash="YrXcQw">“Herein is my Father glorified, that ye bear much fruit; so shall ye be my disciples.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/15.3-5,7-8" class="scriptureRef">John 15:3–5, 7–8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-am-the-vine-ye-are-the-branches.p8" pid="mmkUyV6mM06afp2YmPPDSw" hash="Az-U3Q">I bear witness today, brothers and sisters, that the Lord Jesus Christ lives, that this is his work, that President Kimball is indeed the Lord’s prophet upon the earth. The Lord will come again to reign as King of kings and as Lord of lords. May we be worthy to be with those who serve and live with him when that time comes, I pray, and solemnly invoke his blessings upon us all this day, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/10/i-am-the-vine-ye-are-the-branches</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1976-general-conference/1976-10-1040-elder-dean-l-larsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="4019437" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 1976 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faith, Courage, and Making Choices</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I would like to speak to the young men of the Aaronic Priesthood about faith and courage and about making choices. I hope what I say will help you to face the special challenges you will be required to meet in your maturing years.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03102_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="APnF2w">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="XMdfa9dDbUCzNcP055gW8g" hash="h_WBZw">Faith, Courage, and Making Choices</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="dM-GC6ByGEOckJ2OgAD4Pw" hash="VXIyUA">Dean L. Larsen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-246c.jpg" alt="Elder Dean L. Larsen" pid="n2qqMwrgq0armOdcOBQCog" hash="TC6x9Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p1" pid="9XWVrbGtKEW8LQCVwgMoAA" hash="-2eZlQ">I would like to speak to the young men of the Aaronic Priesthood about faith and courage and about making choices. I hope what I say will help you to face the special challenges you will be required to meet in your maturing years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p2" pid="esKsdlR1IkqCg60EbVL9Lg" hash="-Kd9hQ">Recently I met a young man who was receiving the missionary discussions. He had read the Book of Mormon and felt he had received answers to his prayers. He was now faced with the decision of whether or not to be baptized.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p3" pid="vVIN90oOak-MOgheZPNbeQ" hash="MB2uwQ">This was a rather remarkable young man. He had experienced some severe tests in his life, and he had demonstrated great courage and resourcefulness. The prospect of becoming a member of the Church, however, gave him a different kind of challenge.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p4" pid="ff159O9Am0O7rWh1bIqUPw" hash="gfrClQ">As we talked about this newest and most important decision with which he was faced, he asked, “Why are so many people critical of Mormons?” He then described some of the things he had experienced at the hands of friends, family, and fellow employees for having associated with the missionaries. “I’m not sure I can live with that kind of feeling against me if I join the Church,” he said. “Why can’t I believe what your church teaches, but just go on being a good Christian without becoming a Mormon?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p5" pid="a1G1namDs0SyzLtMY6w41Q" hash="eO_nKg">It isn’t difficult for us to know what the consequences will be for this young man if he chooses not to be baptized because of the fear of incurring ill feelings from family and friends. He is, of course, perfectly free to make this choice, but he is <span class="emphasis">not</span> free to determine the consequences of that decision.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p6" pid="c5maeNPQqkG7aimbZKRajg" hash="E1mVOw">We may occasionally find ourselves in situations where we are tempted to set aside our identity as Latter-day Saints while we indulge in some thought or act that is unworthy of the trust the Lord has placed in us. We are regularly required to make choices on the basis of what we know to be right. We are free in most instances to make our own decisions, but we are never free to determine the final outcomes of our choices.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p7" pid="dRalVfaLEUGJaN7yjfyQpA" hash="AVZ6vA">It is not enough for us to know what is right and to believe it is good. We must be willing to stand up and be counted. We must be willing to act in accordance with what we believe under all circumstances. It is of little value for us to believe one way if we behave contrary to that belief in our private actions or in our public performance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p8" pid="GMHvPsDJf0OwRrcJpp9ejg" hash="0L664w">Today it requires great courage to be a loyal Latter-day Saint. For many it is not easy, and it will likely not become easier. The tests of our day are severe. This is particularly so for you young men of the Aaronic Priesthood. Being true to the way of life the Lord has given us does not always make us public heroes. Having the courage of our convictions has its own rewards, however. Armin Suckow, Jr., a thirteen-year-old boy from Germany discovered this. He tells of an interesting experience in a letter he wrote to the <span class="emphasis">New Era</span> magazine. Armin says, “We spoke one Christmastime with one of our school teachers about Jesus. He said that after Jesus died, he had gone from the earth and was now dead. As the teacher spoke, I thought about our church and knew that after three days Jesus was resurrected and was seen by many people. Later, then, he ascended into heaven. I had the feeling that I should tell the teacher and the students that the truth was entirely different from what the teacher had just said. The teacher didn’t want to hear my opinion at all, but in spite of that, I … told them that Jesus was resurrected. It didn’t please the teacher at all that I should correct him, but I continued. Then he said that this was simply a matter of opinion. I answered him that anyone can read of this event in the scriptures and that it is so clearly described there that no one can get a different opinion on the story than the one that I had given. After the class the teacher wanted to know to which church I belonged. I told him that I belonged to The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. On that day I had a real good feeling inside of me.” (“The Savior Lives!” <span class="emphasis">New Era,</span> Dec. 1977, p. 18.).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p9" pid="rUgK9_iDukaPSnLe7HkqFg" hash="6WoOzQ">We have to admire Armin’s decision to speak out on what he believed. It was not easy for him, but his action was consistent with what he knew to be right.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p10" pid="j8waePMrr0KquhWib7iKTQ" hash="gsYy_w">Sometimes the challenges we must face in this life are of a very personal nature. They can result from such things as physical handicaps or similar limitations. But even these give us an opportunity to make choices that bring satisfaction and fulfillment into our lives rather than discouragement and defeat. Some of you read in the May 1976 <span class="emphasis">New Era</span> about Stephen Farrance, who learned when he was four years old that he had a type of muscle disease that was incurable. His doctors said he would not live beyond his twelfth year. Instead of withdrawing from life and becoming a dejected invalid, Stephen pressed himself into every possible activity. His life was full of enthusiasm and optimism. He invented ways to compensate for his handicaps. He lived six years longer than his doctors had said he would; and though in his last years he had great difficulty in getting about without help, he never lost his enthusiasm, his creativity, or his sense of humor. He not only succeeded in making his own life happier and more productive, but he was also an inspiration and a positive influence to all who knew him. If you young men have not read about Stephen in the <span class="emphasis">New Era,</span> I recommend you do so. (See Pene Horton, “Stephen,” <span class="emphasis">New Era,</span> May 1976, p. 36).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p11" pid="DKxSiBOodE6bek2ycVESLg" hash="pyf7yA">Some years ago I coached a high school basketball team through a rather unusual season. The season began with a number of disappointing losses. Some of the fans and townspeople didn’t make a secret of their unhappiness over the team’s failures. There was considerable public comment, and it was a challenging time for members of the team. Several of them finally became discouraged and withdrew from the team. Those who remained didn’t lose faith in themselves or in their coach. The rough going seemed to be an incentive for them to try even harder.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p12" pid="lg-LOF17wUyMCurUER7Nnw" hash="hOwbnQ">At mid-season the team began to win their games. They qualified for the district tournament and surprised everyone there by winning a place in the state play-offs. To the amazement of everyone, they went on to win the state championship—the first ever to be won by that school!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p13" pid="mm4KPmYV_0qIfNQcZRIj9w" hash="wYagNg">Following the celebration and the awarding of trophies after the championship game, I drove several of the team members back to our city. There was silence during much of the ride as we each reflected on the incredible outcome of our season’s efforts. Finally, one of the young men spoke. (He had been honored for being one of the outstanding players in the tournament.) “Coach,” he said, “I think we were supposed to win tonight.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p14" pid="L3xigFp_p0u-z8vQAA0VOQ" hash="ciCR3w">I was curious to know what had prompted this conclusion. “Why do you think we were <span class="emphasis">supposed</span> to win?” I asked.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p15" pid="AgnatHv94ECubZwSfZin9Q" hash="YFIKvQ">His response was simple and direct—and I will never forget its impact. “Because we paid the price,” he said.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p16" pid="Wd3TQggDqEu_BuoEpVp02w" hash="KjIR9g">Indeed they had, and I am sure the lessons learned by those young men during that eventful year have been valuable to them throughout their lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p17" pid="DTBlAMnzTUm6i-xEfOoZiA" hash="Fvyfgg">The nature of the challenges we face in this life is not nearly so important as what we choose to do about them. When we have the courage and faith to live up to the best we know, we fulfill the purpose for which we came to this earth, and we provide an incentive for others to do the same.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p18" pid="ER9zZw2MdUexkONH0Qikuw" hash="fiDBEA">The young man to whom I referred in the beginning of my remarks has a very important decision to make. In the final analysis he cannot hedge on his decision. He must be willing to face the consequences of baptism and membership in the Church if he is ever to enjoy the blessings that Church membership can bring. He must be willing to pay the price. This will require much trust and faith on his part. It is so with each of us whenever we face challenging choices. You young men of the Aaronic Priesthood have a tremendous trust placed in you by the Lord, and he expects you to measure up—to stand up and be counted. All of you came here to be winners. The Lord’s work will prevail, and you will have much to do with the success of his kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices.p19" pid="yO0BuidmMUe6EduZOMCzAQ" hash="O12r-Q">May God help each of us to “pay the price” so that we may one day be qualified to return to him, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1978/10/faith-courage-and-making-choices</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1978-general-conference/1978-10-3020-elder-dean-l-larsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5101342" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1978 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Accountability and Human Progress</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My comments today will bear upon President Kimball’s challenge to us to rise above the plateaus we have been on. They will relate also to the added flexibility and freedom we are being encouraged to assume in the new pattern of Sunday worship and wee</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03122_000_033" doc-version="2" hash="ntPSRA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="cD3oBD6wIE6CyUINzR84XQ" hash="iRoweg">Self-Accountability and Human Progress</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Mdg-9bv_xkikaDMroO0aCg" hash="VXIyUA">Dean L. Larsen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-246c.jpg" alt="Elder Dean L. Larsen" pid="wjaT5YIfR0y7c9lJl8XwLw" hash="TC6x9Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p1" pid="LDroRM33AUCxnQ09KDpJaQ" hash="u8F6qw">My comments today will bear upon President Kimball’s challenge to us to rise above the plateaus we have been on. They will relate also to the added flexibility and freedom we are being encouraged to assume in the new pattern of Sunday worship and weekday activity. I’ll speak to the principle which undergirds these new developments. Latter-day Saints understand that mortal life was purposefully designed to place us in circumstances where we can be individually tested and where, by the exercise of the agency God has given us, we can determine what our future possibilities will be. The ancient prophet Lehi understood this when he said to his son Jacob, “Wherefore, men are free according to the flesh; and all things are given them which are expedient unto man. And they are free to choose liberty and eternal life, through the great Mediator of all men, or to choose captivity and death” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.27" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:27</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p2" pid="L6IJKiOi_0WFhDTDk2MLcQ" hash="nSw8qA">He further explained that men “have become free forever, knowing good from evil; to act for themselves and not to be acted upon, save it be by the punishment of the law … according to the commandments which God hath given” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.26" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:26</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p3" pid="X1TOSmUWJUKk4fp0ie-lAA" hash="saW_PQ">On one occasion the Lord explained that it was his desire that “every man may act in doctrine and principle pertaining to futurity, according to the moral agency … given unto him, that every man may be accountable” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/101.78" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 101:78</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p4" pid="GqIJxTCy5UqmN_5dPJjOPg" hash="rpNf5A">When we understand what is right and what is wrong, we are in a position to exercise our freedom in making choices. In so doing, we must stand accountable for our decisions, and we cannot escape the inevitable consequences of these choices. Such freedom to exercise moral agency is essential in an environment where people have the highest prospects for progress and development.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p5" pid="5dKO508FoEumUfvB_jvK4Q" hash="_50rHw">By our very endowment as children of an Eternal Father, we have had implanted within our souls the urgency to be free. It is natural for us to want to be accountable for our own fates, because there is a whispering within us confirming that this accountability is absolutely essential to the attainment of our eternal destiny.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p6" pid="zzosccGt602u0owR6gyH3w" hash="m-NrSg">The existence of laws, regulations, and procedures has never been sufficient to compel men to obedience. Productive obedience comes through the exercise of free will. Elder Albert E. Bowen of the Quorum of the Twelve once said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p7" pid="4BZoDxxv7029vnYzvmlR6g" hash="w11HoA">“It is a truism that no law is any better than the people who administer it. Howsoever well framed a law may be or however worthy its purpose, it can degenerate into utter futility unless wisely administered by those sympathetic with its purposes” (<span class="emphasis">The Church Welfare Plan,</span> Sunday School manual, 1946, p. 115).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p8" pid="ts4gkIzg3EedWQxHBBTgNg" hash="FvZnEA">We are told in the scriptures that prior to the creation of this earth, fully one-third of all the hosts who contemplated the challenges of mortal life allowed themselves to be deluded into thinking that there were acceptable alternatives to the essential risks that accompany the exercise of agency and free will (see <a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.27-28" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:27–28</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/rev/12.4" class="scriptureRef">Rev. 12:4</a>). The price they paid is beyond comprehension. Today we are being encouraged to accept greater responsibility for the allocation of our time, for our spiritual development through personal and family study of the gospel, and for giving loving Christian service. We must be willing to respond to this new challenge. Our willingness to accept this added accountability will exert an influence that will reach far beyond our Sunday worship service and religious life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p9" pid="dmjU0O5y_0KaQFhNUp11Hg" hash="-DFUMg">Unless we retain a vibrant desire to be free, and unless we understand and practice the principles that give life to essential freedoms, we have little reason to hope they will endure. If we allow ourselves to accept dependency and regulation and to cease valuing independence and self-accountability, then we are vulnerable to the forces that destroy freedom. If righteousness is judged primarily by the degree to which one responds to programmed activity, then a condition develops within which opportunities for progress decline. The resulting tragedy affects the mortal potential of man and has a profound effect on his eternal possibilities as well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p10" pid="X_tDv6-Czk2GVJt2zAzkPQ" hash="6-XtHQ">Programmed behavior cannot produce the level of spiritual development required to qualify one for eternal life. A necessary range of freedom and self-determination is essential to one’s spiritual development. With an understanding of correct principles and an intrinsic desire to apply them, one must be motivated within himself to do many good things of his own free will; for, as the revelation says, the power is in him wherein he is an agent unto himself (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.27-28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:27–28</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p11" pid="Tk7nnzxeD0CaBcN8Y8FuHg" hash="PyGJtw">In preserving our freedom for self-determination, we cannot ignore the need for carefully ordered structure and procedure within government or any other organization. A careful balance must be maintained between that which is ordered for the welfare of the group and that which is reserved for the conscience and the incentive of the individual.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p12" pid="0GCk_hTsBUeqap2xPGW5Iw" hash="ld2hhA">This necessary balance of freedom and restraint is essential to right relationships within families and communities, and it cannot be ignored in our assignments within the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p13" pid="MTPx-bXpjkmKIhtonzIDHw" hash="MiNbVQ">I have pondered the injunctions that have come to us in recent months from leaders of the Church to simplify and reduce the number of programmed activities prescribed for the members. There seems to be a sensitivity to the need for maintaining this essential balance. We have heard increased emphasis given to the need for individual initiative and accountability within families. In his concluding remarks at the April 1979 general conference, President Kimball said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p14" pid="q7pirDKgrke6BiuCMI-uLg" hash="xZobwg">“The basic decisions needed for us to move forward, as a people, must be made by the individual members of the Church. The major strides which must be made by the Church will follow upon the major strides to be made by us as individuals. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p15" pid="LzLMu13e3U28hQRo0eSmsQ" hash="2VVGAw">“… Our individual spiritual growth is the key to major numerical growth in the kingdom” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign, </span>May 1979, p. 82).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p16" pid="A15BWhYOO0-8Y_sB4SG83Q" hash="Wxn4OQ">I rejoice in the spirit and intent of this instruction from a living prophet. I see in it the purposeful effort to preserve our individual accountability in the context of our Church membership and religious life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p17" pid="iLs6iakLYkieiFZSWPRu_w" hash="V1DO-w">When members of the Church exercise self-determination in their application of gospel principles they need not relax in their compliance with these principles. In fact, optimum progress can only occur when conditions are ideal for it, and these conditions must include the necessary degree of freedom and self-accountability. Anything less will guarantee stunted spiritual growth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p18" pid="ZSjTFxv9A0-0QXH1JBIXgg" hash="Vb6dPw">We must understand that as freedom for unrestricted development is enhanced, the possibilities for failure are also increased. The risk factor is great. The ideal cannot be achieved otherwise. Celestial attainment can be reached in no other environment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p19" pid="mJXa_uaWIkW0NK0Pp7gdCw" hash="J7mfmg">We have inspired leaders today who are reconfirming the fact that there is no ultimate safety in programmed security where others assume accountability for our direction and performance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p20" pid="6Kx2JxcAZ06S4LunivU_Uw" hash="F4XCrg">Those who insist that a Church program exist for every contingency and need are as much in error as their counterparts who demand that government intervene in every aspect of our lives. In both instances the ideal balance is destroyed with a resultant detriment to human progress.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p21" pid="vBrFR9OL7kytmvEfIaIZ2g" hash="uaj9Lg">These are essential truths which our leaders are reinforcing for us today. These are challenging truths. They demand much of us. They press us to make our lives better by our own initiative and by our own efforts. They make no unconditional promises.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress.p22" pid="FVPAOv_tPEOjVYPKss0dWg" hash="7eBnLg">At the same time, our obedience to them preserves for us the elements of life which make individual progress possible. They make life purposeful and full of promise. They lead to eternal progress. Humanity cannot fulfill its destiny when these truths are disregarded and abused. I cherish them with all my soul and am unreservedly committed to their promulgation among all the peoples of the earth. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1980/04/self-accountability-and-human-progress</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1980-general-conference/1980-04-5040-elder-dean-l-larsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5073743" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 1980 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Strength of the Kingdom Is Within</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within?lang=eng</link>
      <description>On one occasion a group of Pharisees confronted the Savior and demanded to know when the kingdom of God would come upon the earth. (See .) Their tradition had taught them that God’s kingdom would be impressive in its demonstration of power and in its</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03141_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="C3xmWg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="dci50N1okUGLWpnrZUxbdA" hash="APCWIw">The Strength of the Kingdom Is Within</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ZSWaC840aU2eZOWOmiIzhA" hash="VXIyUA">Dean L. Larsen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-246c.jpg" alt="Elder Dean L. Larsen" pid="LsxYt5ruNkiriJFNrj-MrA" hash="TC6x9Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p1" pid="IXM6xRcrZE6xwO2kXG4SWA" hash="aK9ksw">On one occasion a group of Pharisees confronted the Savior and demanded to know when the kingdom of God would come upon the earth. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/17.20" class="scriptureRef">Luke 17:20</a>.) Their tradition had taught them that God’s kingdom would be impressive in its demonstration of power and in its earthly dominion. Their question, therefore, was a challenge to the Lord’s assertion that when the kingdom of God was established on the earth, it would not be as other earthly kingdoms. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/18.36" class="scriptureRef">John 18:36</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p2" pid="AIGEiJ6IW0Kubk-Fw3jV7Q" hash="G4qR-g">The Master’s response on this occasion teaches a significant lesson regarding the real source of power and influence within his kingdom. He answered, “The kingdom of God cometh not with observation:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p3" pid="ya2CHj90ckmYk5hQhJzGdg" hash="dz4ZCg">“Neither shall they say, Lo here! or, lo there! for, behold, the kingdom of God is within you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/17.20-21" class="scriptureRef">Luke 17:20–21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p4" pid="yuTR51YOOEuSZiGzvVH_bg" hash="O-KM2A">The Savior attempted to impress his questioners with the fact that the real power in the kingdom of God is not represented in outwardly observable things. Its strength is in the quality of the lives of its members. It is in the depth of their purity, their charity, their faith, their integrity, and their devotion to truth. This great lesson escaped the perception of the Pharisees. It has significance for us today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p5" pid="jelm7ytLZ0Cn9kH2NXS4Kg" hash="o_y1Sw">Today our chapels and congregations dot almost every land in the free world. Our temples will soon be within easy traveling distance of almost every member. The percentage of members who attend meetings and activities is at an all-time high. These are encouraging signs. We hope that they are indicators of inward strength. We rejoice in the growth that has marked the development of the Church in this century, and particularly in the last decade or two. We take encouragement from our missionary successes, as rightly we should, but in all of this outward manifestation of increasing strength, we cannot forget the Savior’s injunction to those who looked for the kingdom of God to manifest itself in ways that would be impressive by earthly standards. “Behold,” he said, “the kingdom of God is within you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p6" pid="7SxrboU6wkm47f1P3nOvHg" hash="F5CH7A">Several months ago I attended a conference in a stake that had compiled an impressive statistical record. By all observable standards, this was a stake composed of devoted, faithful Latter-day Saints. As I met with the stake president in our first interview, I was not surprised that he was anxious to review with me the excellent statistical record that his people were making. The reports had been arranged on his desk to facilitate this review. Before looking at them, I asked the president, “Tell me, how do you feel about your people? Generally speaking, in their spiritual qualities, are they standing on higher ground this year than they were a year ago?” I wanted to assess the president’s personal discernment regarding the spiritual strength of his members. He immediately seized this opportunity to direct my attention to the reports. Sensing that he had misunderstood the intent of my question, I explained, “I will be pleased to review the reports with you, but before we do, would you tell me how you <span class="emphasis">feel</span> about your people?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p7" pid="HQCMj9joeEmxPx7agaLnVg" hash="NFnt8w">My insistence on his making this kind of assessment apart from the information in the reports was both frustrating and perplexing to the president. I was sensitive to his frustration, and without further discussion we went through the statistical information. It indicated considerable progress in many areas that are amenable to a quantitative evaluation. I believe the reports were significant indicators of the spiritual quality of the people. However, I had failed to draw from the president the kind of discerning evaluation I had solicited. At the same time, I sensed that he was a little perplexed and somewhat pensive at the conclusion of our interview. His pensiveness continued throughout the meetings of the afternoon and evening and caused me some concern.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p8" pid="Qkrikax7PEKu1BJ-BH6ZUA" hash="nmrUUA">On the following day, as the president delivered his address in the general session of the conference, he surprised me by telling the members about his experience with me the previous day. He acknowledged his frustration over my apparent reluctance to go into an immediate review of his correlated reports, and this frustration had remained with him into the night. As he was pondering these things, there came into his mind an experience he had had during the week prior to the conference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p9" pid="WKaZhCFW30evKyuo5fh5Sw" hash="ukye0Q">He had visited a member of the stake who was in a hospital recuperating from surgery. During this visit a nurse had entered the room, making her regular calls on the patients. She had gone to some charts that were hanging at the foot of the patient’s bed, carefully perused the notations, and then added some of her own. She had then stepped to the side of the patient, felt her pulse, placed a hand on her forehead, asked some questions, and received some responses. The president said, “It occurred to me that the nurse was attempting to assess some of the patient’s vital signs—some that were not reflected in the notations on the charts.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p10" pid="Py6K6ILqwUGu4eouSqZLtA" hash="v7HCrw">The president said that it was then in his reflections that the purpose of my questioning the day before had registered with him. “I realized,” he said, “that Elder Larsen was asking me to assess your spiritual vital signs in ways that the reports may not have revealed.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p11" pid="QsX3eFrHT0GxUKurocGf-g" hash="gyBzew">He then continued, “Today I am going to talk with you about those spiritual vital signs—those that go beyond the information on the charts.” He proceeded to give one of the finest talks I have heard a stake president give. Interestingly, he made no reference in his remarks to the statistical reports.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p12" pid="P8FLAW61pUuqFLOU63ID0w" hash="4d-ibQ">We have good reason to feel encouraged and optimistic today as we observe the rapid growth of the Church throughout the world. We are pleased with the level of participation of the members, even though we acknowledge it can be improved. The willingness of the people to serve and to sacrifice for the sake of the Lord’s work is commendable.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p13" pid="Dvc4MkQ5lEKRq9wK9tWz1g" hash="Z2ORxw">But what of the kingdom that is within our own souls? There are evidences that we are not completely free from weaknesses within. Family problems multiply. Divorce becomes more common. Signs of preoccupation with worldly, material concerns are apparent on every side. Questionable compliance with principles of trust and integrity in business dealings is too frequent. Courtesy and kindness are too often replaced by abruptness and rudeness in human relations. Growing evidences of promiscuity and infidelity to marriage covenants beset us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p14" pid="QODOcD4n7EG3qX0pZ-LKyw" hash="x9gK5Q">While acknowledging that The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is “the only true and living church upon the face of the whole earth, … speaking unto the church collectively and not individually,” the Lord expressed a reservation about the individual members and explained, “For I the Lord cannot look upon sin with the least degree of allowance.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.30-31" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:30–31</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p15" pid="5Itc1qEiPUizk7ssOS0MJQ" hash="jwi2uA">At another time he warned those of his church:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p16" pid="IHZTryrpi0iARs8Jh1FPEw" hash="D5j5CQ">“Behold,” he said, “vengeance cometh speedily upon the inhabitants of the earth. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p17" pid="KmeqBbphoEKkfFWbQwIQ-Q" hash="G9o8ng">“And upon my house shall it begin, and from my house shall it go forth, saith the Lord;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p18" pid="zzPGW00jdE2ui0EuSJICKw" hash="4dutWw">“First among those among you, saith the Lord, who have professed to know my name and have not known me, and have blasphemed against me in the midst of my house, saith the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/112.24-26" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 112:24–26</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p19" pid="tGtPNxQ0GEKXhLWJ0MHu0g" hash="l_ruZg">In this time of impressive Church growth, it is well for us to look within our own souls to assess our individual spiritual vital signs. Too frequently Latter-day Saints of all ages yield to the temptation to explore and sample forbidden things of the world. Often this is not done with the intent to embrace these things permanently, but with the knowing decision to indulge in them momentarily, as though they hold a value of some kind too important or too exciting to pass by. While some recover from these excursions, an increasingly large number of tragedies occur that bring a blight and a despair into many lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p20" pid="5gBhJ4DwC06EPeEIAI2w8g" hash="lm7-Pg">The cumulative effect of this is devastating. The reverberations will affect the lives of those who indulge, as well as the lives of those who have loved and trusted them, in unfortunate and unforeseen ways for indefinite periods of time. As a consequence of these things, humanity slips inexorably to a lower level, the real power and influence in the Church and kingdom of God are diminished, and all mankind will inevitably feel the loss. Furthermore, as a collective church, we jeopardize our capacity to merit and claim the preserving and protecting blessings from the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p21" pid="T8s-yGFRfEOBhIQsxe0rag" hash="KLARkg">For those who keep the trust placed in them and who do not yield to the pattern of the times, and for those who have made or are making their way back from dark paths, I have the most profound admiration and gratitude. You are our shining hope. You are our real strength. You will make a significant difference in the final outcome of things. You are the last great counterforce against the evil that is engulfing the earth. God bless you for this!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p22" pid="caRQ_XMkLk-QHeljULxr8Q" hash="HZr_Ng">As I view the days that lie ahead, I am hopeful because of the Lord’s promise, and I know his kingdom will prevail, but I tremble as I read his declaration to us:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p23" pid="ShG2r54kdUmq2A_FS7H9OA" hash="1O2AyQ">“For this is a day of warning, and not a day of many words. For I, the Lord, am not to be mocked in the last days.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/63.58" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 63:58</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p24" pid="4PrUxSnasUaaqDu1DgF98Q" hash="CKp7Tg">The enduring strength of the kingdom is not to be found in the number of its members, the rate of its growth, or the beauty of its buildings. In God’s kingdom, power is not equated with body count nor with outward routine compliance with prescribed performances. It is found in those quiet uncharted acts of love, obedience, and Christian service which may never come to the attention of official leadership, but which emulate the ministry of the Lord himself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within.p25" pid="gktIArc9Kken2asdqPD5eQ" hash="l2-Bkg">It is a time for us to assess our own spiritual vital signs in those essential areas that take us beyond the information on the charts. “For, behold, the kingdom of God is within you.” In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1981/10/the-strength-of-the-kingdom-is-within</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1981-general-conference/1981-10-2050-elder-dean-l-larsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="6152467" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 1981 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Royal Generation</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Tonight in this meeting of the priesthood, we will be talking about the importance of families. Other matters of importance will also be discussed, but special attention will be given to families. The more we learn about the power of the influence ex</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03161_000_017" doc-version="2" hash="IHRz0A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="rFnC5tI-Bk6zM2KanaEpYA" hash="BJw0wA">A Royal Generation</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="FA8kc_0C9EeGflwiMzZVkQ" hash="VXIyUA">Dean L. Larsen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-246c.jpg" alt="Elder Dean L. Larsen" pid="WyxA3vyFikKKGxgir6mOxg" hash="TC6x9Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p1" pid="-nAr0MWqsUCs2lcT3r0RZg" hash="vJ75CA">Tonight in this meeting of the priesthood, we will be talking about the importance of families. Other matters of importance will also be discussed, but special attention will be given to families. The more we learn about the power of the influence exerted in families, the more we can appreciate the counsel given to us by our leaders from the earliest days of the Church to make certain that the circumstances in our homes are what they should be. We have said much over the years about the responsibility of parents to provide a wholesome home life for their children. We will receive additional encouragement of that kind tonight. It is vital that we do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p2" pid="qmh8toYtUEm9_CNXgzalaw" hash="InR-kg">We have recently completed some very comprehensive studies that confirm the power of the influence that we work upon one another in our families and in our homes. The influence of the family has a greater effect upon what we think, how we feel, and what we do about our lives than all of the other sources of influence combined. The patterns we set in our homes and the values we develop there, whether they be good or bad, almost cannot be overcome.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p3" pid="_hhQvcsrnkKZO7Owy69jow" hash="8meLwg">All of us have a responsibility to contribute to the quality of our home life. Parents make a great contribution, but so do the children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p4" pid="uw3Ps49X90WK7TaXip7tCg" hash="xBqTbQ">Tonight I would like to talk principally to the young men of the Aaronic Priesthood about the responsibility you have to live in such a way that you can be a good influence in your homes, whatever the conditions there may be, and so that you can qualify to do all that the Lord expects of you during your lifetime.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p5" pid="yvaFyN_67UW1yukJ-_NZ-w" hash="GW4ySg">Young men, I do not believe that you are here upon the earth at this time by accident. I believe you qualified in the premortal life to come into mortality at a time when great things would be required of you. I believe you demonstrated before you came here that you were capable of being trusted under unusually difficult circumstances—that you could measure up to the most difficult challenges. Don’t misunderstand me. I don’t suggest that you are inherently better than or superior to any of the other generations that have come to the earth. You do not automatically qualify for any more blessings or advantages than anyone else who has lived since the earth was created. You can go astray, become involved in transgression, and incur the judgments of God as readily as any who have preceded you here. In fact, you live in an environment in which it is probably as easy to disqualify yourselves in this way as any generation has ever experienced. But God trusts that you will not. He relies upon you to keep yourselves eligible to accomplish the monumental tasks that he expects you to achieve.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p6" pid="MOVRuZsfY0i-O7U_AVQP2g" hash="RVREfQ">You are growing to maturity in a period of the earth’s history that all of the great prophets of all the ages have looked forward to with anticipation. It is a time of final preparation before the earth and its inhabitants undergo a remarkable transformation. It is properly referred to as the “fulness of times.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/112.30" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 112:30</a>.) It is the period during which the Lord and his servants will make the final great effort to take the message of truth to all the peoples of the earth and to reclaim the descendants of ancient Israel who have lost their true identity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p7" pid="m9O_zeRtLkKXpXYEmYg0xA" hash="w0cOqA">The prophet Zenos, whom Jacob quotes in the Book of Mormon, compares this effort to the work of the laborers who prune and nurture a vineyard and gather its fruit for the last time. Zenos likens the Savior to the master of the vineyard, who says to those who are his helpers, “Wherefore, let us go to and labor with our might this last time, for behold the end draweth nigh, and this is the last time that I shall prune my vineyard.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/5.62" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 5:62</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p8" pid="EbUoT74mPkCo6APc3zjJVw" hash="FZm9vQ">You have come to the earth when the foundation has been laid for this great work. The gospel has been restored for the last time. The Church has been established in almost every part of the world. The stage is set for the final dramatic scenes to be enacted. You will be the principal players. You are among the last laborers in the vineyard. This is the yoke that is set upon your necks. This is the service for which you are chosen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p9" pid="15vjoMHS2U6NJqafJLE1lg" hash="W-Z4gw">Let me now describe the setting within which you will perform your labors. The Savior himself said that conditions toward the end of this dispensation would very much resemble those that existed just before the Flood. “As the days of Noe were,” he said, “so shall also the coming of the Son of man be.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/24.37" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 24:37</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p10" pid="nC-vDPjFC0yd4CZhjtSzmQ" hash="t79WQQ">Joel saw the period of time in which we live as a great battleground for the souls of men, “Proclaim ye this among the Gentiles [he said]; Prepare War, wake up the mighty men, let all the men of war draw near; let them come up:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p11" pid="U3Bkg0LZw06pUoxF4qomNg" hash="GjygKg">“Beat your plowshares into swords, and your pruninghooks into spears: let the weak say, I am strong.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/joel/3.9-10" class="scriptureRef">Joel 3:9–10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p12" pid="FhNHVkKi_kqZZdWvORqo6w" hash="r_2pAw">Joel saw that this great battle would not be regarded in a casual way. It would be no time for weakness nor weaklings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p13" pid="GsmTJkbVd0mM3e9V2-gZAw" hash="UZbojA">The Apostle Paul wrote to his young missionary companion, Timothy, “This know also, that in the last days perilous times shall come.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/3.1" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 3:1</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p14" pid="lQ2j3_jXlEiyM1cX5irh9A" hash="tbGFXg">The challenging conditions we find in the world today should be no surprise to us. As we approach the time of the Savior’s return, wickedness will increase. There will be more temptations in our daily lives, and they will become more intense. It will become more acceptable in the world to break the laws of God or to disregard them altogether. The stigma attached to immoral, dishonest behavior will disappear.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p15" pid="Amp6jW3LmUaSCiNwl6w9uQ" hash="Urb67A">In this difficult environment we will be expected to steer our own course in an upward direction. As President Kimball has warned us, it will neither be acceptable nor safe to remain on the plateaus where our present conduct has kept us. Abrupt downward forces, represented by increasing wickedness in the world, can only be offset by forces that move correspondingly upward. Our lives must be better than they have ever been before. This simply means that we will become increasingly different from those around us whose lives follow the world’s way. It is not easy to be different. There are intense pressures that work against us. But we must clearly understand that it is not safe to move in the same direction the world is moving, even though we remain slightly behind the pace they set. Such a course will eventually lead us to the same problems and heartaches. It will not permit us to perform the work the Lord has chosen us to do. It would disqualify us from his blessing and his protecting care.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p16" pid="k_2vcKwbtEidoIroUgzdvA" hash="xFJYzw">The Lord has said that the time will come when there will be “an entire separation of the righteous and the wicked.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/63.54" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 63:54</a>.) Nephi, in the Book of Mormon, said, “For the time speedily cometh that the Lord God shall cause a great division among the people, and the wicked will he destroy.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/30.10" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 30:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p17" pid="S1d-YUjRBEaB1gKdH0adVQ" hash="K8JfQg">As we consider these promises, we should not forget the warning given by the Lord to the Latter-day Saints. “Nevertheless, Zion shall escape if she observe to do all things whatsoever I have commanded her.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p18" pid="rUAnqnPyrUWz33WqMosYQA" hash="GFa7QA">“But if she observe not to do whatsoever I have commanded her, I will visit her according to all her works, with sore affliction, with pestilence, with plague, with sword, with vengeance, with devouring fire.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/97.25-26" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 97:25–26</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p19" pid="SESeGEf9_kaIhw9j6_fwrw" hash="Fd-GHg">We must recognize from this warning that it is not enough to be a Latter-day Saint in name only. It is not enough to simply declare that we are a chosen people of the Lord. We must keep the trust he has given us. We must qualify for his blessing by the way we remain different from the world in our obedience to his laws. Otherwise, we have no promise, and our fate will be the fate of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p20" pid="7Xgff7PcLEKKPruz6zCfng" hash="CfomJg">One of the reasons I feel such a deep concern for you young men is that we see some evidences today of an inclination among our young people to follow the trends of the world. We do not always keep up with the pacesetters, but in some ways we follow not too far behind them. I know there are many who are exceptions to this pattern and who faithfully keep the commandments of God and whose lives remain pure and unspotted from the things of the world, even in the face of great temptation and challenge. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:9</a>.) You who are faithful in this way have our profound respect and our great confidence. You are living up to the trust the Lord has placed with you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p21" pid="q4H51rVKoEKnq-ugntSWDA" hash="sQYuig">But there are too many whose lives are being contaminated by the worldly trends. This is not a light matter. The judgments of God will not be withheld from those who willfully, knowing who they are and what is expected of them, allow themselves to be drawn along the precarious paths of worldly conduct. To such as there are who are within the sound of my voice tonight, I say: Take the upward path. “Be not deceived; God is not mocked: for whatsoever a man soweth, that shall he also reap.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/gal/6.7" class="scriptureRef">Gal. 6:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p22" pid="29KFsm35QkOSq5UBpanetg" hash="X2COBw">Several years ago I expressed the following thoughts in an article that was printed in an issue of the <span class="emphasis">New Era</span> magazine. They are appropriate to my subject tonight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p23" pid="hIWqBDWwHEOgCLHyqT8msQ" hash="Ckj25A">“Not long ago I interviewed a young man who desired to fill a mission, but he had been guilty of some very serious transgressions during his teen years. He was a member of an active Latter-day Saint family, and he himself had been an actively participating member of the Church, even during the time of his transgressions. Ultimately he had gone to his bishop and confessed his wrongdoings. Now, for more than a year, his life had been free of the earlier difficulties, and he was anxious to serve a mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p24" pid="rK2VPBllCU6wGonhyivByg" hash="X_by7Q">“As we talked about his situation and the decisions he had made earlier in his life that led to his questionable standing in the Church, he said, ‘Oh, I knew that what I was doing was wrong, and I was sure that one day I would put things back in order and go on a mission.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p25" pid="OM6n0PvoO0exWvU5Wn7BUw" hash="xAN7sQ">“While I was pleased with this young man’s desire to reorder his life and serve the Lord as a missionary, I was troubled by the apparent premeditated, calculated way in which he had allowed himself to move off the proper course to engage in some destructive, immoral behavior, and then, almost as if he were following a timetable set by himself, he had begun to reconstruct his resolve to be obedient.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p26" pid="K7Px4c7hnEWeptrZ9zTaYw" hash="S4Egeg">“If my experience with this young man had been an isolated one, it would not be worthy of note here; unfortunately, however, it is not unique. There appears to be an increasing tendency and temptation for young people to sample the forbidden things of the world, not with the intent to embrace them permanently, but with the knowing decision to indulge in them momentarily as though they held a value of some kind too important or exciting to pass by. It is one of the great tests of our time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p27" pid="U5WewafQ-kSfMbGES7aJ_A" hash="csWApA">“While many recover from these excursions into forbidden territory, an increasing number of tragedies are occurring that reach out to bring a blight and a despair to many lives and that have long-lasting consequences. There is no such thing as private sin. Although its commission can be calculated … , its effects cannot be regulated by the person guilty of the misbehavior. To believe otherwise is to become gullible to one of the most insidious lies ever perpetrated by the father of lies.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p28" pid="dO9CTM1DlU6XRKK0O8VrBw" hash="5K0WkA">“[Not long ago] I attended a graduation ceremony at a local high school. The students who had been invited to speak for their classmates expressed themselves in terms of the grand and noble challenges that lay before them as they stepped across the threshold into adult life. The adult speakers extolled the virtues and potential of today’s youth and spoke of the horizons to be conquered in future years, the new scientific frontiers to be opened by members of the graduating class, the dread diseases for which cures would be found, and the breakthroughs in diplomacy and human relations that would bring lasting peace to the earth. It was a stimulating, inspiring service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p29" pid="zVITtto1L0KpGPRqkcqh6g" hash="p7xb5w">“As I listened to the impressive addresses on this occasion, I found myself framing in my own mind the things I would have liked to say to this group of young people. I knew that most of them were Latter-day Saints. I knew they came from families where high expectations were held for them, where there was a shared pride in their accomplishments. I also knew about the experiences some of these young people had planned for themselves in the hours and days immediately following the graduation service. I found myself wanting to plead with this graduating class, not about the glorious, obscure years of the dim future when they would hopefully accomplish so much for mankind, but about the here and now. I wanted to say to them, ‘I am not so much concerned about what you do next year or in the next generation; I am worried about what you are going to do tonight and tomorrow when you have handed in your cap and gown. What have you planned? Where will you go? What will you do tonight?’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p30" pid="nIaUS0EUTUu7JcoD3ixJ7A" hash="tD0uQQ">“I know now, as I record these thoughts, that there were those in that graduating class, as well as some others in similar groups, who willfully, with calculated premeditation, placed themselves in circumstances following their graduation services where they dishonored themselves, their families, their Church, and their Heavenly Father. Their behavior was not intended to become a permanent fixture in their lives. It was done as a lark, a momentary thrill, a dare. But its cumulative effect is devastating. The reverberations will [affect] their lives, and the lives of those who loved and trusted them, in unfortunate and unforeseen ways for indefinite periods of time. Humanity will have slipped inexorably to a lower level. Some will never completely recover, and all mankind will inevitably feel the loss.” (<span class="emphasis">New Era,</span> June 1980, pp. 4–5.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p31" pid="Txwe1pq2sU-NUV9dfEHV_A" hash="GQ3FUg">Young men, remember who you are. Remember the purpose for which you have come to the earth—the service you have been chosen to give. Stay true to the divine trust that our Heavenly Father and his Son, Jesus Christ, have placed upon you. You can contribute as much to the spiritual environment of your homes as any member of your family, and you have an obligation to do so. Study the scriptures and encourage the other members of your family to do so. Say your prayers and do all you can to influence other members of your family to pray. Pay your tithes. Obey the Word of Wisdom. Be chaste. You may have a greater influence than you have thought possible, if you will do your own part.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p32" pid="byof0q4cxEuoVXAMuDwxVA" hash="GIiYmw">Remember these words of Edward W. Bok: “Once we are convinced … that we are put here for a purpose: that the seed of divine energy has been given us and that it is for us to cultivate it to its fullest bloom, the way will be shown us. It is our part to make the effort and to put the fullest force and integrity into that effort. It is the young man of little faith who says, ‘I am nothing.’ It is the young man of true conception who says, ‘I am everything,’ and then goes out to prove it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation.p33" pid="JD8MzjavFkSjqnsTWrd57g" hash="jbrTZA">Young men, let us prove by the way we live and serve that we are everything the Lord expects us to be, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1983/04/a-royal-generation</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1983-general-conference/1983-04-3010-elder-dean-l-larsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="8447780" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 1983 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordination and Cooperation</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1984/10/coordination-and-cooperation?lang=eng</link>
      <description>It’s a marvelous thing to see this tabernacle filled with sisters and then to realize that tens of thousands of others are met in centers throughout the country to participate in this most notable meeting. We realize also that through the recordings </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/coordination-and-cooperation" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03180_000_036" doc-version="2" hash="Zjbguw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/coordination-and-cooperation.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="efci5TNB3EKJptgwrcjo9A" hash="_G68iw">Coordination and Cooperation</h1><p class="authorName" guid="4662327c-8fc3-4358-a90b-fbd39cb56f6d" pid="vcQHtkD2S0-GolblTgmfsQ" hash="VXIyUA">Dean L. Larsen</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="bda5a980-5c7e-49ac-aa33-d2c3ceb1ac81">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/coordination-and-cooperation.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-246c.jpg" alt="Elder Dean L. Larsen" guid="3b46eb05-b4f0-42ad-8a02-689c7844bd7e" pid="BGjRXeiqxEmjuY5g9Bkayg" hash="TC6x9Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/coordination-and-cooperation.p" pid="aunv6_t31kS_1YXKlpA9Nw" hash="DPjf1A">It’s a marvelous thing to see this tabernacle filled with sisters and then to realize that tens of thousands of others are met in centers throughout the country to participate in this most notable meeting. We realize also that through the recordings of this meeting, eventually most of the sisters throughout the world will have an opportunity to share in the proceedings of this special conference for the sisters of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/coordination-and-cooperation.p" pid="8TwhHO5wFUitlL_Bdz4TsQ" hash="bBU3sQ">We greet you, we commend you for your attendance, and we honor you for being what you are.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/coordination-and-cooperation.p" pid="Ainc1aFhWE6ssH3wohQmtQ" hash="uOXJmQ">This evening I would like to comment briefly on two matters that relate closely to the theme of this meeting, and to the fact that you are here tonight, not as members of Primary and Young Women and Relief Society, but as members of a great sisterhood who have many interests, needs, and traits in common.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/coordination-and-cooperation.p" pid="U4CjetliHEuvk2b6XBvW6A" hash="c1Mjtg">I think it may be well for you to know that in the last months and weeks, the general presidencies and boards of Relief Society and Young Women and Primary have taken some historic steps to draw closer together. They have determined that they will coordinate and cooperate more closely than ever before in planning activities and in preparing programs and materials that will bless your lives. In a very short time, these three presidencies will have their offices located in the same building here in Salt Lake City. This will make it easier for them to communicate with one another and to share many of their resources. They will also be able to represent more effectively than ever before the interests of the sisters of the Church and coordinate their organizational concerns, which of course all of them have.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/coordination-and-cooperation.p" pid="1xNdSYY4o0iUMUWZTWyXeQ" hash="-3s6ig">Now, these developments do not imply in any way that there has been a consolidation or an amalgamation of these three organizations. That is not the case. And there will be no differences in the operation of these organizations in the field. But obviously it is the wish of these general officers that the closeness, harmony, and unity which are manifest in the efforts they are making here at Church headquarters will reflect to those of you who serve and work together on the ward and stake levels.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/coordination-and-cooperation.p" pid="bFvIyQW9ZUColXwD5-A-MQ" hash="xrrAAg">One other matter closely related to the first has to do with the fact that at the present time, under the consolidated meeting schedule, the Sunday classwork of Relief Society and Primary and Young Women occur at the same time. This requires that many of the adult sisters who serve in callings in Primary and Young Women are not able to participate regularly in the Sunday class meetings of Relief Society. We hope that those of you sisters who are called to serve for a time in the Primary and Young Women will continue to feel a sense of the sisterhood that I hope you feel in this meeting tonight. I hope you will recognize that in giving service in those organizations, you are having not only great opportunities to bless and enrich the lives of others, but also unique opportunities to develop and grow yourselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/coordination-and-cooperation.p" pid="-Ze7rioUTUqH1zDjAyeSRw" hash="L1z01Q">I know the parallel is not a perfect one, but perhaps it would be appropriate to acknowledge that for most of my adult life I have had assignments in the wards and stakes where I have lived that have precluded my meeting with my priesthood quorums on a regular basis on Sundays. However, I have never felt that this service, which kept me away from those meetings, separated me from the fellowship of my quorums. In every way that was possible I have continued to participate in the service projects, the social activities, and the home teaching assignments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/coordination-and-cooperation.p" pid="-8k-xdO8CkO-pJ6QioPc5A" hash="z-kTug">I hope you sisters who are called to serve temporarily outside of Relief Society will recognize that you have great opportunities during this time. I have never felt that my service outside my quorum has diminished in any way my opportunity for spiritual growth or for opportunities to serve and hopefully that service has provided some blessings and help for others. So we ask you to cooperate and work closely together, in the wards and stakes, in a spirit of common sisterhood, with an eye single to the glory of God and to the development of the talents and abilities that all of you have and that qualify you for ultimate service in the kingdom of God in the eternities to come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/coordination-and-cooperation.p" pid="7YvYq0X5PkGYrmSVIixDFQ" hash="LnCCpA">Now, finally, I’d like to pay a special tribute to all of you sisters for being who you are, in recognition of the unique contributions that you bring to the quality of life that we all enjoy and to which we aspire. The longer I live and the more I observe, the more convinced I become that there are some basic differences in the very natures of men and women. I’m convinced that you carry with you, by virtue of these unique differences, some qualities and some traits that allow you to make contributions that are uniquely your own. I don’t know of a better way to illustrate this than to share with you quickly a recent experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/coordination-and-cooperation.p" pid="jrfwq7aoDEKmdogNBUnvqw" hash="AlirKw">Sister Larsen and I were assigned earlier this year to visit two stakes in Europe. The conferences were on successive weekends. Midweek one of our daughters and her husband, who were in Europe on business of their own at that time, arranged their schedules so that they could join us for a day in one of the beautiful cities of Europe. During the course of the day, we visited a lovely shopping center that featured the beautiful porcelain ware for which that city is well known. The work is exquisitely beautiful and very expensive.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/coordination-and-cooperation.p" pid="ILrIYI7iTkuF8jviRBmVeQ" hash="BYOrSg">As my daughter and I were standing side by side admiring some of the porcelain figurines that were placed on the shelves of this store, and older lady stepped up to our side, apparently attracted by one of the beautiful figurines on a shelf above us. Wanting to inspect it more closely, she reached up and took it in her hands to bring it down closer to her. It slipped from her fingers to the marble floor and broke into many pieces.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/coordination-and-cooperation.p" pid="TufHF3BSAka-zNZJhbfy5w" hash="4BBGbA">The sound of breaking attracted the attention of everyone in the shop. Instinctively, I stepped away. Just as instinctively, my daughter did the opposite thing. She quickly stepped to the side of this elderly lady, put her arm around her, whispered some consoling words in her ear, and then stooped to begin to pick up the pieces of the porcelain object. I felt a little chagrined for myself, but a deep sense of pride and love for my daughter. In my mind and by commitment, I knew what I should have done, but instinctively, I did not. By instinct, she did what the Savior would have done.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/coordination-and-cooperation.p" pid="6ywYvN7qNk-SG_5-sgd9FQ" hash="1g0yCw">I can think of no better illustration to reflect the marvelous qualities that you as sisters, as daughters of God, bring to bear, not only in making our own lives better, but in contributing, in a most essential way, to the successful operation of the plan of life and salvation that God has provided for all of his children. I honor you and express my deep love and appreciation to all of you for these wonderful gifts you have. May you be blessed to enlarge them, to expand them, and to use them, striving together in effective ways to bless all of God’s children and to assist in the great onward movement of his work in this vital time in which we all live, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-246c.jpg" alt="Elder Dean L. Larsen" guid="3b46eb05-b4f0-42ad-8a02-689c7844bd7e" pid="cxGJlLyliUKNbkmDsR19ww" hash="TC6x9Q1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="3b46eb05-b4f0-42ad-8a02-689c7844bd7e"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1984/10/coordination-and-cooperation</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1984-general-womens-meeting/1984-09-0010-elder-dean-l-larsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="6312330" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 1984 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“By Their Fruits Ye Shall Know Them”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In recent months, several items of historical interest have surfaced in one way or another, stirring a renewed interest in the life of Joseph Smith and the means through which he established the Church. A wide range of opinions has been expressed reg</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03193_000_024" doc-version="2" hash="gtlw1A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="TSUPexK26ked3bMBe06B_A" hash="hKmG7g">“By Their Fruits Ye Shall Know Them”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="rkQUvNmPiEq4OvrxfdPSZg" hash="VXIyUA">Dean L. Larsen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-246c.jpg" alt="Elder Dean L. Larsen" pid="EgUERqv1UEqRoLMjs_v3vg" hash="TC6x9Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p1" pid="anK7hPGNdky3fMWaVjnQ6g" hash="-67jwQ">In recent months, several items of historical interest have surfaced in one way or another, stirring a renewed interest in the life of Joseph Smith and the means through which he established the Church. A wide range of opinions has been expressed regarding the extent to which these new disclosures should affect our perceptions of the traditional and scriptural accounts of Joseph’s divine calling and his part in bringing about the restoration of the gospel and the church of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p2" pid="dFpweHEl-kCC8gVQW45FLA" hash="TnpF1Q">In my remarks today I do not wish to make any assessment of the validity of the newly discovered documents nor the extent to which they might, in the eyes of some, affect the reconstruction of Church history. I would like, instead, to point to some ultimate tests that can be applied to determine the divine nature of any religious work. These are tests which the Lord himself prescribed. They overreach the tentative significance of any historical document that may survive the passage of time, whether it relates to specific events or to the people who participated in the events. The Lord’s work is known by its fruits. Often, documents of historical interest reflect, at best, the way one individual recalls or perceives events or the actions and motives of those who participated in them. Such reflections may be interesting, but they may not always be accurate. They may even tell more about the one doing the reflecting than the one being reflected upon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p3" pid="3VPRABhF2UGvbr0iMtMsPA" hash="HK6gsQ">In any case, the Lord’s test is the only one that will stand with the passage of time and reveal the truth about those who claim to do his work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p4" pid="iNY6ar92AUWH82GUXpE_Kw" hash="J8383w">The Savior acknowledged that there would be imposters who would attempt to pass themselves off as his authorized representatives. He warned of false prophets who would come in sheep’s clothing but who would have their own selfish motives to fulfill. “Ye shall know them by their fruits,” he said.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p5" pid="Atzf_xpQ5USj-_XWMUZ4DQ" hash="yqGWqg">“Do men gather grapes of thorns, or figs of thistles?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p6" pid="icdjQqTj50yAAqmLX3guGQ" hash="fOUh-A">“Even so every good tree bringeth forth good fruits; but a corrupt tree bringeth forth evil fruit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p7" pid="SBRVHJ0i5kCL_eq9I-cHYw" hash="dUIqKg">“A good tree cannot bring forth evil fruit; neither can a corrupt tree bring forth good fruit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p8" pid="M_BW6-DSj0aP17nN423JOg" hash="_xdn_g">“Wherefore by their fruits ye shall know them.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.15-20" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 7:15–20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p9" pid="N_yaRsuYtEahtNc2JFTxmA" hash="AHI9bQ">It is interesting that this declaration by the Savior was made in response to accusations from the scribes and the Pharisees that he was performing his miracles and healings by the power of the devil. “This fellow doth not cast out devils, but by Beelzebub, the prince of the devils,” they protested. (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/12.24" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 12:24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p10" pid="AlFzmfalrkm-Tf-CqnxP3g" hash="wPT0KQ">The attempts by the Savior’s enemies to destroy his work by discrediting him were futile. All he said and did has stood the test of time and has borne good fruit in the lives of millions of people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p11" pid="aPujdRtu6Ei9ITIiq9fjTA" hash="QVz-pQ">In addition to the record of the good works performed by the Savior, we are given the personal affirmation and testimony of the Eternal Father regarding Jesus’ divine nature and calling. Those who were present at the baptism of the Master heard the Father’s voice declare from the heavens, “This is my beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/3.17" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 3:17</a>.) Again, on the Mount of Transfiguration, the chosen Apostles of the Lord heard the repeated affirmation: “This is my beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased; hear ye him.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/17.5" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 17:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p12" pid="WKpDywK3zUa6tQpqWEeC3Q" hash="n8VgFw">In a similar fashion we have the Lord’s own testimony as to the divine calling of Joseph Smith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p13" pid="Ib9fGp4PH02mz87Gm_Pm0Q" hash="TIqx8g">“Wherefore, I the Lord, knowing the calamity which should come upon the inhabitants of the earth, called upon my servant Joseph Smith, Jun., and spake unto him from heaven, and gave him commandments.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.17" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p14" pid="GOa7IXAm6UqJPWRjGLnygg" hash="cS06Fg">Also: “I, the Lord, am God, and have given these things unto you, my servant Joseph Smith, Jun., and have commanded you that you should stand as a witness of these things; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p15" pid="DTETxbdn_UaWWWSN89n8Yw" hash="F9Qhaw">“For hereafter you shall be ordained and go forth and deliver my words unto the children of men. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p16" pid="lc2jbBgrXEGKq1fHxsALQQ" hash="WYA54Q">“But this generation shall have my word through you.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/5.2,6,10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 5:2, 6, 10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p17" pid="zFBk9tZuJE-mKCQ4ZiEFHQ" hash="X3B7tQ">And: “The ends of the earth shall inquire after thy name, and fools shall have thee in derision, and hell shall rage against thee;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p18" pid="dmeorYBQ7EywplTcKNobcg" hash="DeLJcQ">“While the pure in heart, and the wise, and the noble, and the virtuous, shall seek counsel, and authority, and blessings constantly from under thy hand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p19" pid="ThHCvfZtQEOPrpBosMvfJQ" hash="P6kLyQ">“And thy people shall never be turned against thee by the testimony of traitors.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/122.1-3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 122:1–3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p20" pid="tpOauTuiQ0Gs6MALlbJhhQ" hash="hLWtKA">Joseph Smith declared that his work was the Lord’s work. His credentials as a prophet of God are not adequately tested by historical relics.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p21" pid="M9uqvOZNlUK1NcUXtRYl8A" hash="l8zG0A">The fruits of the restored gospel of Jesus Christ are the real test of Joseph and his work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p22" pid="pPLh7iHOY06hP8Q4cyk92A" hash="eFs_XQ">Among these fruits which are easily available for assessment today are the scriptures that came from his efforts. These, of course, include the Book of Mormon, the Doctrine and Covenants, and the Pearl of Great Price. They are tangible fruits that cannot be displaced by all of the commentary of those who have an interest in reconstructing history. They contain the revelations of God. The value of the eternal principles which they propound can be tested by daily application.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p23" pid="fuL6CpbxzE61eFCPSbQsTw" hash="hHhM3w">In fact, this is the only true test. Alma, in his segment of the Book of Mormon record, issues a challenge for such a test. “Behold,” he says, “if ye will awake and arouse your faculties, even to an experiment upon my words, and exercise a particle of faith, yea, even if ye can no more than desire to believe, let this desire work in you, even until ye believe in a manner that ye can give place for a portion of my words.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.27" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p24" pid="COBWnNAIGUSNNgSaVGJVrg" hash="Ak5eig">Comparing this experiment to the planting of a seed, Alma continued: “Now, if ye give place, that a seed may be planted in your heart, behold, if it be a true seed, or a good seed, if ye do not cast it out by your unbelief, that ye will resist the Spirit of the Lord, behold, it will begin to swell within your breasts; and when you feel these swelling motions, ye will begin to say within yourselves—It must needs be that this is a good seed, or that the word is good, for it beginneth to enlarge my soul; yea, it beginneth to enlighten my understanding, yea, it beginneth to be delicious to me.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.28" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p25" pid="Hp_Qljhf30qG1bUje3mTQA" hash="5wnHrA">For more than 150 years, since the founding of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, millions of people have tried the experiment proposed by Alma as it pertains to the gospel that Joseph Smith restored. They and others in increasing numbers throughout the world today bear testimony to the good fruit that the experiment has borne. They have applied the Savior’s sure test.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p26" pid="_1cIlS4BwUuN_pp2r9Jt9A" hash="QVb2GQ">Within the context of the Savior’s prescribed testing of the fruit lies an implied challenge and warning for all who receive the restored gospel of Christ, who accept Joseph Smith as a prophet of God, and who claim membership in The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. The challenge is given by the Savior in the Sermon on the Mount;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p27" pid="ih9lJ_Qd8EmrSCq11isLPQ" hash="jOneKw">“Ye are the salt of the earth: …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p28" pid="UJ7flt2-CU2hFYB9oDeD_Q" hash="2ySmew">“Ye are the light of the world. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p29" pid="ufowgWdw_Ue8yyJTy4cYOg" hash="rXUv1Q">“Let your light so shine before men, that they may see your good works, and glorify your Father which is in heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.13-16" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:13–16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p30" pid="YS2UCEwIsECtR1b9L2Ky1g" hash="FqBplA">Those who receive the gospel are expected to manifest its fruits in their lives, not only for their own benefit and blessing, but for the purpose of drawing others to the truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p31" pid="aSlKAItSAUKJ79AwKrh93g" hash="kcVQ1g">This does not suggest that all who are obedient to the principles of truth will be free of all earthly cares and concerns, for all are tested. But those who are compliant with the Lord’s plan of life will be able to meet the tests and not be overcome. They will endure. In significant ways their lives will manifest the fruits of the gospel and set them apart as a beacon to all who are seeking for light and truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p32" pid="z2a-oDamq0KIrqiYorjhRg" hash="aYwEhg">When we fail to measure up to this trust, we betray the covenants we have made. Not only do we then fail to gain the full benefits of the gospel for ourselves, but we become a stumbling block for others. In such a case it is with us as it was with the disobedient missionary son of Alma, who fell to the temptations of the world, and of whom Alma mourned: “Behold, O my son, how great iniquity ye brought upon the Zoramites; for when they saw your conduct they would not believe in my words.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/39.11" class="scriptureRef">Alma 39:11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p33" pid="UdKRG5AgF0OhMlqgEQarug" hash="EwA9MQ">The Savior warned those who, knowing the truth, pursue another course: “But if the salt shall have lost his savour, … it is henceforth good for nothing, but to be cast out, and to be trodden under the foot of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.13" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p34" pid="ho1mY4_tNk-Bio_KPfjUVA" hash="myR7Wg">Enjoying the fruits of the gospel should not make us arrogant and aloof, but it should set us apart from the world in much of our conduct.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p35" pid="tpByA9lljEWtrH8E789dxg" hash="bach5Q">It is, perhaps, well in these times, when so many of the fundamental truths of the Restoration and the validity of the Lord’s work are being challenged, that we ask ourselves to what degree our conduct sets us apart and manifests the fruits of the gospel. In our homes and in our families, are we enjoying and qualifying for the love and support of family members? In our business dealings, are we fair and honest and prompt in meeting our obligations; is our word as good as our bond? Are our private and innermost thoughts free from the contaminations of the world? Do they reflect our absolute loyalty and fidelity to those with whom we have made eternal vows? Are we nourishing through prayer and a regular study of the Lord’s revealed truths the spiritual and moral strength which is required in today’s environment? In the entertainment and recreation we seek, are we keeping ourselves unspotted from the world and in harmony with the Lord’s holy Sabbath? Are we generous with our means and inclined to be serviceable to others? Do we acknowledge our faults and shortcomings and seek forgiveness from those whom we have wronged or offended?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p36" pid="Q_1hcO8knEyQxHf2V_kyig" hash="7vebnw">Let me repeat again that those who do the Lord’s work demonstrate it by the fruits of their labors. Analyzing and criticizing others, either from a historical perspective or from what we may view of a contemporary life, will be of little consequence unless it balances with the Lord’s assessment. The Apostle Paul said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p37" pid="nw01h9SB-EKMBLAmWivEhA" hash="qxOnqw">“But why dost thou judge thy brother? or why dost thou set at nought thy brother? for we shall all stand before the judgment seat of Christ. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p38" pid="zGL3PUJRY0yACZoexd3kFg" hash="0VYsTQ">“So then every one of us shall give account of himself to God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p39" pid="ui4_KLFE90OLBSOkR93Ccg" hash="AG9eWw">“Let us not therefore judge one another any more: but judge this rather, that no man put a stumblingblock or an occasion to fall in his brother’s way.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/14.10,12-13" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 14:10, 12–13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p40" pid="nXzi-7N0vU6rmAcfT3gDsg" hash="nn1XTA">I bear testimony that Joseph Smith was a prophet of God through whose instrumentality the Lord has reestablished his true church and the only plan of life that can bring eternal happiness and exaltation. I further testify that those who have succeeded him in his prophetic role down to the present day have been men who are chosen and endowed with power and authority to accomplish the Lord’s work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p41" pid="6hpSg7RrqUyO0UGhBOCeFA" hash="wGQDIA">I humbly acknowledge the responsibility I share with you to make manifest in my life the fruits of the gospel of Jesus Christ. And to those who may question the validity of this work, I leave the Savior’s challenge: “Either make the tree good, and his fruit good; or else make the tree corrupt, and his fruit corrupt: for the tree is known by his fruit.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/12.33" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 12:33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p42" pid="mV8zhLSrJkCClqGRJiyfHA" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1985/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1985-general-conference/1985-10-4040-elder-dean-l-larsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="6958852" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 1985 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking beyond the Mark</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark?lang=eng</link>
      <description>When I was a young man, I enjoyed participating in athletic activities of various kinds. I was never very expert in these things, but this did not diminish my interest nor the satisfaction that came from my participation. I was particularly intereste</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03219_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="NYQ7Lw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Flq4YzaKd0aBs5jvG_CCCQ" hash="BYfBAw">Looking beyond the Mark</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="kpSrbLJOIE6vVDZBQuMooA" hash="VXIyUA">Dean L. Larsen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-246c.jpg" alt="Elder Dean L. Larsen" pid="n91x_kgpjEm-Sy1-TRHPEg" hash="TC6x9Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p1" pid="0VWf6XDmAU2kwweHhqLIGQ" hash="JRNYLQ">When I was a young man, I enjoyed participating in athletic activities of various kinds. I was never very expert in these things, but this did not diminish my interest nor the satisfaction that came from my participation. I was particularly interested in track and field events. In my school years I competed in the hurdle races as well as in the shot put and the discus throw. These last two events required that the participant launch his effort from within a ring that was marked out on the playing field. So long as the competitor remained within the ring while making his throw of the discus or the put of the shot, his effort was qualified to be measured in the competition. If he stepped outside the circle, his effort was disqualified as a foul. Generally, three preliminary attempts were permitted in each of these events, and then three more for those whose tosses were long enough to qualify them for the finals. If a competitor fouled in each of his attempts, he was out of the competition.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p2" pid="9GWe-oSbM0-D-3mzoaqT8A" hash="30Aqzg">Those of us who participated in these sports learned the importance of staying within the mark.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p3" pid="rivQuKLBF0eqoHjeW1vkig" hash="nauviA">I found myself reflecting on these early experiences recently as I read from the fourth chapter of Jacob in the Book of Mormon. In this part of his record, Jacob reminds us of the Israelites in ancient times who got themselves into great difficulty: “They despised the words of plainness, and killed the prophets, and sought for things that they could not understand. Wherefore, because of their blindness, which blindness came by <span class="emphasis">looking beyond the mark,</span> they must needs fall” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.14" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:14</a>; italics added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p4" pid="5qLknbYj80mjAC5_RmhNVA" hash="X3EIYw">Generally, a figurative expression such as the one Jacob uses in this text—“looking beyond the mark”—comes from something that is common and familiar to the experience of those with whom it is used. Each language and each culture has similar idiomatic expressions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p5" pid="iAFlQ_0gIEaPPvNp5tP_Cg" hash="5mAA_w">I have wondered what was actually in Jacob’s mind as he wrote of “looking beyond the mark” in describing a failing that was common to ancient Israel. As I have already indicated, Jacob’s idiom brings to my mind the experiences of my early activities in certain sports events when it was so important to stay within the mark. All of the strength and skill and effort a competitor could muster in the field events I have just described were of little value if he did not stay within the circle.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p6" pid="rDcLw-v7q02lTpvTqNeoYw" hash="YcQFXw">Jacob speaks of people who placed themselves in serious jeopardy in spiritual things because they were unwilling to accept simple, basic principles of truth. They entertained and intrigued themselves with “things that they could not understand” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.14" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:14</a>). They were apparently afflicted with a pseudosophistication and a snobbishness that gave them a false sense of superiority over those who came among them with the Lord’s words of plainness. They went beyond the mark of wisdom and prudence, and obviously failed to stay within the circle of fundamental gospel truths, which provide a basis for faith. They must have reveled in speculative and theoretical matters that obscured for them the fundamental spiritual truths. As they became infatuated by these “things that they could not understand,” their comprehension of and faith in the redeeming role of a true Messiah was lost, and the purpose of life became confused. A study of Israel’s history will confirm Jacob’s allegations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p7" pid="bFvCsTgut0SODXiVKaQBhw" hash="csD8Ag">It seems to me that every generation faces its challenges with “looking beyond the mark.” The Apostle Paul worried about those whom he had helped to develop a testimony of Jesus Christ. Paul advised Titus to “avoid foolish questions … and contentions, and strivings about the law; for they are unprofitable and vain” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/titus/3.9" class="scriptureRef">Titus 3:9</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p8" pid="crlShMMSFUi6Bri-pk5t4g" hash="Z2aYfQ">To Timothy, Paul wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p9" pid="jH1X7r5fi0WDNX4fwyHkXQ" hash="J--qgg">“Preach the word; be instant in season, out of season; reprove, rebuke, exhort with all longsuffering and doctrine.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p10" pid="yJSa7CemwEuAJV7795J_5A" hash="mhtz6g">“For the time will come when they will not endure sound doctrine; but after their own lusts shall they heap to themselves teachers, having itching ears;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p11" pid="9A3ZqSfOfE6FdWAi3YyBbQ" hash="k76C7Q">“And they shall turn away their ears from the truth, and shall be turned unto fables” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/4.2-4" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 4:2–4</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p12" pid="ghsxCfUJFEy4NQIhra070g" hash="ngK6nA">Earlier, Paul had counseled Timothy not to “give heed to fables and endless genealogies, which minister questions, rather than godly edifying which is in faith” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-tim/1.4" class="scriptureRef">1 Tim. 1:4</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p13" pid="-J5dFuuLB0u-J6eQZXvo2Q" hash="eEpUvA">As I have wondered how we might protect ourselves in the present day from “going beyond the mark,” I have resolved to do several things which I share with you for whatever application you may wish to make in your own lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p14" pid="djeMOtbF6kecbFlBaPylTw" hash="Rvfa5g">I am going to give more time and attention to the study and pondering of the scriptures themselves, rather than to the commentaries and criticisms that others have written about them. In doing this, I am going to be as open as I can be to the Spirit of the Lord so that I can understand these things for myself. Jacob said: “For the Spirit speaketh the truth and lieth not. Wherefore, it speaketh of things as they really are, and of things as they really will be; wherefore, these things are manifested unto us plainly, for the salvation of our souls” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.13" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p15" pid="IlOPRRCkKEm0687RdPuUnA" hash="A52l2w">I am much more concerned about understanding the admonitions of Samuel the Lamanite as he stood on the walls of the city of Zarahemla and called the rebellious Nephites to repentance than I am about identifying the location of that city in today’s geography.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p16" pid="31sRKymYgkWTO-CTsudoJw" hash="Rl9hRg">I am more vitally interested in what the Father and the Son commissioned Joseph Smith to do, and the fruits of his prophetic labors, than I am in whether he made mention of one divine personage or two in his initial recounting of the First Vision.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p17" pid="NBAxhylGgk-x1uucsnyC1Q" hash="tGBLEA">I am going to make a greater effort to be worthy of holding an ordained office in the priesthood of God, and be less concerned about confirming the exact date and place of the appearance of Peter, James, and John to restore this divine authority and power.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p18" pid="GY4JGvcK5EGKMSP4eO6ruQ" hash="evl5FA">I think I am going to try to keep in my mind more consistently the perfect pattern for human relationships that the Savior demonstrated in his own life and try with greater effort to emulate that pattern of caring, love, and sacrifice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p19" pid="uvvStXO6xU-2p1EiuntZYg" hash="Um2Rdw">I am going to try to be more earnest in teaching what the Savior would have me teach and be less concerned about having my own biases aired. If I am going to influence others, I want to influence them toward the things that promote faith rather than to unsettle them with speculation and questions that cannot be resolved.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p20" pid="pNunslCVVkW0JKgq5wen9g" hash="od57Ag">I think I will not want to stifle a wholesome appetite for learning, for reaching out to new levels of understanding. But as I push toward these new horizons, I will want to come back always to the circle of my established faith, and I will continually nourish that faith with a prayerful study of God’s revealed truths.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p21" pid="FX4PAWxY2Uil_gec-amCeA" hash="G-Cl2Q">In the many hours I spent as a young man practicing to perfect my skills at putting the shot to greater distances, I sometimes moved outside the ring to work on a particular technique or detail. I learned, however, that unless the new device would allow me to remain safely within the mark when the competition was on, it was of little value to me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p22" pid="wSkv7yTZmk2TopqutBs9kg" hash="USn7Gg">Analogies are seldom perfect, and the one I have used in these remarks is probably less so than most; but sometimes it is useful to analyze our situation against the background of such a simple comparison.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p23" pid="m5W8mEdInEKStP57j7Ewxw" hash="vCyTGQ">There are other ways in which many of us often look beyond the mark. Sometimes we focus too much of our attention and energy upon our temporal wants, not only to entertain ourselves and gratify our physical appetites, but also to gain recognition, position, and power. We can become so consumed by the pursuit of these things that we sacrifice the sweetness and enduring peace of mind that are found in spiritual well-being, in well-nurtured family relationships, and in the love and respect of friends and associates.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p24" pid="mMh0SPrNd0627ForGekBGg" hash="Qh3t4w">Too often we permit the narrow demands of our daily routine to dull our appreciation of the beauty of God’s creations and the refining influences that are all about us. We fail to experience the fulfillment that comes from developing the gifts and talents with which we have been endowed. We do not draw close enough to the Lord to know him and feel of his redeeming love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p25" pid="Ro6z5TjpFEO1P4t-KYrVaw" hash="MR6FFA">In today’s complicated world with its diversity of demands and sometimes distracting voices, it is so important for us to keep our eyes upon the basic things that matter most and that will have the greatest eternal consequence for us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark.p26" pid="cEKKlMstlUWnmVkG0Z0e5Q" hash="_QLRKA">May God help us to do so and to keep from looking beyond that mark, I pray earnestly in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1987/10/looking-beyond-the-mark</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1987-general-conference/1987-10-1030-elder-dean-l-larsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5506469" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 1987 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winding Up Our Spiritual Clocks</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Since the announcement yesterday of the change of status of some of the members of the Seventies quorums, I have been trying to think of words that might appropriately pay tribute to these good men. I’ve concluded that words are inadequate and that i</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03245_000_024" doc-version="2" hash="w_9ACw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="_WG45axic0qYjfQhyDlZHQ" hash="_oG-vw">Winding Up Our Spiritual Clocks</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="zgtoHW-x7kOieKTn7qDjUA" hash="VXIyUA">Dean L. Larsen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-246c.jpg" alt="Elder Dean L. Larsen" pid="yKP-TD8nakCJODG5Uzztrw" hash="TC6x9Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p1" pid="85DyfjfWc0iikzai1n8cig" hash="o8GxKQ">Since the announcement yesterday of the change of status of some of the members of the Seventies quorums, I have been trying to think of words that might appropriately pay tribute to these good men. I’ve concluded that words are inadequate and that in reality their real tribute will be found in the lives of people throughout the earth who have been touched by their influence, which influence will continue for generations to come. We love these men with a love that will not be diminished, even though our contact with some of them will not be as frequent as in the past. We acknowledge that they have pioneered many of the aspects of the Church in many parts of the world. And now they are pioneering a new course that some of the rest of us will soon follow. They go with our love, our prayers, our deep respect and admiration, and our eternal gratitude.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p2" pid="XeRyPsbj_0KzsRTlZ3iveA" hash="yQI53g">On the wall of the kitchen in our home hangs a clock. It’s a windup clock. That is, it is necessary every seven or eight days to wind up the mechanism with a key. If this is not done at regular intervals, the clock eventually begins to lose time; its chimes become sluggish and off-tone. Finally it stops until it is rewound again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p3" pid="SCp7b6YFQEuQ8tLRzeYvMQ" hash="N2okig">Sometimes when I am rewinding this clock, I think how good it would be if I could restore my physical powers to their youthful vigor in a manner as simple as this. I suppose increasing age sometimes brings these thoughts to all who move into the later years of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p4" pid="txANVm8ZM0-f1DEWdB5jYQ" hash="K9J39g">In some ways, and to some degree, I can effect a partial rejuvenation through exercise, rest, and proper nourishment. I realize, however, that my physical clock is gradually winding down. The mechanism becomes increasingly sluggish. The chimes are less vibrant and sometimes a little out-of-pitch. One day the clock will stop altogether, in spite of all my desire and effort to keep it going.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p5" pid="VLJt6mkXjE27QM_PumIN6A" hash="rKBoUg">So it is with the physical clock in each one of us. It is part of the Lord’s plan. Our time here is but one phase of an eternal existence. As our physical clock winds down, we have the assurance of new beginnings and even greater possibilities as other phases open to us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p6" pid="VfV-oZ2PyE-Palf0f8Wraw" hash="tkwxCw">As I think of these sobering realities, there comes to mind another figurative clock that operates within me. It is my spiritual clock. It has some similarities to the physical one. It, too, needs regular winding to stay in time and keep its true tone. Unlike the physical clock, however, the spiritual one is not necessarily destined for dissolution. In fact, with proper attention and regular care it grows more vigorous—more perfect in its operation, more clear and resonant in its tones. But this is not an automatic process. Just as with the clock that hangs on our kitchen wall, unless there is a regular winding up of the mechanism, a spiritual sluggishness develops, the spiritual tone becomes off-key, and, unless something is done to correct the winding-down process, the clock can stop.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p7" pid="68b0WjBOxUqMZrLpgpXxmw" hash="YDubmg">In the world’s environment today, spiritual clocks that do not receive regular attention can wind down very quickly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p8" pid="SQdxw7nsmUODxrIWP2STOA" hash="_jFhQQ">Just forty years ago, in the October conference of 1949, Elder Albert E. Bowen, a member of the Council of the Twelve, spoke these words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p9" pid="rlU2plDVjUuvyvf-uXvfQw" hash="cvUgfw">“Men are mortal and beset by human frailties. They are enticed by the pressures of immediate … desire to depart from the high standards of the perfect law. When they are under the influence of an exalted occasion, they make high resolves. They firmly determine to avoid past mistakes and to do better. But gone out from under the spell of that influence and absorbed in the complicated pursuits of life, they find difficulty in holding fast to their noble purposes. … So it is essential that they come again, and frequently, under the influence which kindles anew the warmth of spirit in which good resolutions are begotten, that they may go out fortified to withstand the pressures of temptation which lure them into false ways. Happily, if they refresh themselves frequently enough under ennobling influences, the spirit of repentance will be at work with them, and they will make conquest of some temptations—rise above them—and advance thus far toward their final goal.” (In Conference Report, Oct. 1949, p. 139.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p10" pid="wJoEA6M3ME2k1Q9Uj8Ghkw" hash="EX_2Cg">All of us require the “ennobling influences” about which Elder Bowen spoke to “wind up” our spiritual clocks. Just as exercise, proper nourishment, and rest are essential to our physical well-being, so are such things as regular prayer, scripture study, Sabbath worship, partaking of the sacrament, and service to others necessary for our spiritual vigor. Without these continuing influences in our lives, our spiritual clocks wind down.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="tNKRlf8QQUicgh-Xzr9XUg" hash="7ButCA">Prayer</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p11" pid="2gdW0-98zUaskEzNj3B1Cw" hash="aDr8RQ">Nephi said, “If ye would hearken unto the Spirit which teacheth a man to pray ye would know that ye must pray; for the evil spirit teacheth not a man to pray, but teacheth him that he must not pray.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p12" pid="n81zpaJFq0OmE3QdMtwgMw" hash="QGw2fA">“But behold, I say unto you that ye must pray always, and not faint.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/32.8-9" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 32:8–9</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p13" pid="XixPmt4op0aiWhPzrZ5UVw" hash="NUlF-Q">Amulek understood the importance of prayer as a spiritually rejuvenating influence. “Humble yourselves,” he said to the Zoramites, “and continue in prayer. …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p14" pid="J5M01YJIZkmV_rNaXKmP4A" hash="uA2zeQ">Ye must pour out your souls in your closets, and your secret places, and in your wilderness.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/34.19,26" class="scriptureRef">Alma 34:19, 26</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p15" pid="7rPmgneoxkmHLRGpx0BgSw" hash="r4v5EA">Amulek counseled the people to pray over their flocks, their households, and their fields. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/34.20-21" class="scriptureRef">Alma 34:20–21</a>.) “Yea,” he said, “and when you do not cry unto the Lord, let your hearts be full, drawn out in prayer unto him continually for your welfare, and also for the welfare of those who are around you.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/34.27" class="scriptureRef">Alma 34:27</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p16" pid="nJO7bDcttkiBSKJDtv8exw" hash="TEu6NQ">Earnest, sincere prayer is an essential ingredient in maintaining spiritual tone.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="og-acPXDeUSr6iVCzg7gDQ" hash="OOoI2g">Scripture Study</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p17" pid="AxK7D-YKa0-9b0VdSIg44w" hash="KlDy4g">No leader of the Church in this dispensation has given greater emphasis to the study of the scriptures than has President Ezra Taft Benson. His inspired counsel to the members of the Church, and to all people, has led many to draw close to the scriptures, particularly the Book of Mormon. The testimonies that can be borne to the value of scripture study are numerous. There is a special power in the scriptures. Scripture study, combined with daily, purposeful prayer, can provide much of the resolution that is necessary today to offset the influences so prevalent in the world that lead us into forbidden ways.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p18" pid="e1RjHMv0u0OqeRmQ33yskA" hash="b2IMCQ">Alma likened the word of God to a seed. “We will compare the word unto a seed,” he said. “Now, if ye give place, that a seed may be planted in your heart, behold, if it be a true seed, or a good seed, if ye do not cast it out by your unbelief, that ye will resist the Spirit of the Lord, behold, it will begin to swell within your breasts; and when you feel these swelling motions, ye will begin to say within yourselves—It must needs be that this is a good seed, or that the word is good, for it beginneth to enlarge my soul; yea, it beginneth to enlighten my understanding, yea, it beginneth to be delicious to me.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.28" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:28</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p19" pid="nTVpo8OvcUG6cWIOlwr5QA" hash="RUYDkA">I can testify that Alma’s analogy is a valid one. One who regularly turns to the word of God for spiritual strength and enlightenment will find it good—delicious to the spiritual taste.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p20" pid="7EpYO_ZxsEyXk888MSbB7g" hash="sDKiCw">Alma promises that the seed that is planted by studying and applying the word of God will grow to the stature of a tree. But he warns those that begin to slacken in this effort:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p21" pid="J6ms4nRUI0Swya-8qG12gA" hash="SatNNw">“If ye neglect the tree, and take no thought for its nourishment, behold it will not get any root. …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p22" pid="UrWx4PRPT0qR43nYElJqSA" hash="cG9H2Q">“Now, this is not because the seed was not good, neither is it because the fruit thereof would not be desirable; but it is because your ground is barren, and ye will not nourish the tree. …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p23" pid="cy9JaLRus0W0ktqEIp_xTQ" hash="wCTZTA">“But if ye will nourish the word, yea, nourish the tree as it beginneth to grow, … it shall take root; and behold it shall be a tree springing up unto everlasting life.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.38-39,41" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:38–39, 41</a>.)</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="5DwfLv0Gb0elQOq3iif90Q" hash="CjbeYA">Sabbath Worship and Partaking of the Sacrament</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p24" pid="Weo5CZTEIU-STiLp-OhJvw" hash="ef-gSw">One of the most effective ways to wind up our spiritual clocks is to worship on the Sabbath day and partake of the sacrament.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p25" pid="e7guKjHAaUmPIuh3ztQMoA" hash="PtbNeg">“That thou mayest more fully keep thyself unspotted from the world, thou shalt go to the house of prayer and offer up thy sacraments upon my holy day.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:9</a>.) These are the Lord’s instructions to us. He knows that our spiritual clocks wind down quickly without this regular experience.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p26" pid="KCPdGQZTi0exE2kpC7r2IA" hash="ZWHCyA">There is something essential about joining together with other believers to worship, to sing, to pray, to learn of God’s will for us, and to acknowledge his goodness to us. He has commanded that this should be so.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p27" pid="I7Yi7eiUo0Ob56F7Y8O3Qw" hash="vGWvJw">It may be well to emphasize also that our church buildings are not the only places where we can worship. Our homes should also be places of devotion. It would be well if each day we could “go home to church.” There should be no other place where the Spirit of the Lord is more welcome and more easily accessible than in our own homes.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="kVHaNskcJ0ac1YEfAyplMQ" hash="s6TuxQ">Service</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p28" pid="KWEEf_eoYk-3JKZqcFE-Mg" hash="E-kuNQ">A final comment about service to others and its influence in winding up our spiritual clocks: Anyone who has unselfishly given of himself in service to another can testify of the lift that comes to the giver. We need this reinforcement to our spiritual well-being. When we cast our bread upon the water in this sense, it inevitably comes back to us in even greater abundance.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p29" pid="jzbC6trJ9kOx856qgXwAfA" hash="5yiSrw">President Spencer W. Kimball once said, “I have learned that it is by serving that we learn how to serve. When we are engaged in the service of our fellowmen, not only do our deeds assist them, but we put our own problems in a fresher perspective. When we concern ourselves more with others, there is less time to be concerned with ourselves. In the midst of the miracle of serving, there is the promise of Jesus, that by losing ourselves, we find ourselves.” President Kimball added, “There is great security in spirituality, and we cannot have spirituality without service!” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Dec. 1974, pp. 2, 5.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p30" pid="vKK5awtyeUiGfFGBnqzxgA" hash="v4SRHQ">In this, as is true with all of the other virtues, the Master is the perfect example. He is our Lord, our Savior, and our Redeemer and the perfect example in all things.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks.p31" pid="4H7HjPuFREqbHA3a9bL4Cw" hash="9Uq9NA">I testify to you that these things are true. May those “ennobling influences” about which Elder Bowen spoke come regularly enough into our own lives that our spiritual clocks will continue to run strong and true is my earnest prayer. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1989/10/winding-up-our-spiritual-clocks</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1989-general-conference/1989-10-4030-elder-dean-l-larsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="6660729" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 1989 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Beware Lest Thou Forget the Lord”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We welcome the Brethren whom you have sustained this morning as new members of the Seventies Quorums. They are men of faith and devotion with a broad background of experience in Church leadership. Their call is a reflection of the continuing growth o</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_91905_000_007" doc-version="2" hash="AanEcQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="NOlRhPEAnkuP8NkPsF7KzA" hash="3MdK5Q">“Beware Lest Thou Forget the Lord”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="y18-HlLOYE-HsbL23wL7Jw" hash="VXIyUA">Dean L. Larsen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-246c.jpg" alt="Elder Dean L. Larsen" pid="1YZZX98cXEGmliZU9vCmhA" hash="TC6x9Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p1" pid="C_Pjp7bmVUunO9tsjrdJqA" hash="Wyvx0g">We welcome the Brethren whom you have sustained this morning as new members of the Seventies Quorums. They are men of faith and devotion with a broad background of experience in Church leadership. Their call is a reflection of the continuing growth of the Church worldwide.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p2" pid="VS3VcKVcV024mlcuz5KfVg" hash="tdOeyA">As the tribes of ancient Israel prepared to cross over Jordan to enter the land of Canaan, Moses gave them his final counsel and instructions. They were about to enter a land that Joshua and Caleb had described as “a land which floweth with milk and honey.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/num/14.8" class="scriptureRef">Num. 14:8</a>.) It would be a dramatic change in the circumstances of Israel. For a full generation they had known only the desolation of the desert places, depending upon the Lord for their daily subsistence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p3" pid="vlP3D5mFwU6Qac_1lJMlig" hash="ujAXDQ">Moses felt some concern for the capacity of his people to cope with the abrupt transition they were about to experience. “Hear, O Israel,” he said. “Thou art to pass over Jordan this day, to go in to possess nations greater and mightier than thyself, cities great and fenced up to heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/deut/9.1" class="scriptureRef">Deut. 9:1</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p4" pid="EUTPBYHO1E-e9SOl4eUI9A" hash="rxckbg">“And it shall be, when the Lord thy God shall have brought thee into the land which he sware unto thy fathers, to Abraham, to Isaac, and to Jacob, to give thee great and goodly cities, which thou buildedst not,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p5" pid="oYEpG_lNKUC59Vcrny-NEw" hash="TscvIQ">“And houses full of all good things, which thou filledst not, and wells digged, which thou diggedst not, vineyards and olive trees, which thou plantedst not; when thou shalt have eaten and be full;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p6" pid="1XNm_xaom0On-IJEn7VblQ" hash="5XU4HA">“Then beware lest thou forget the Lord, which brought thee forth out of the land of Egypt, from the house of bondage.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/deut/6.10-12" class="scriptureRef">Deut. 6:10–12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p7" pid="6iz3S-sJFkOCA6UP5RtqBA" hash="1bX96w">The concerns expressed by Moses for his people have been repeated by other prophet leaders through all of the gospel dispensations. It has seemed that one of the inevitable side effects that occurs as people apply gospel principles in their lives is that their material circumstances also improve. This does not suggest that it should be the right nor the expectation of all who accept the gospel of Jesus Christ to become wealthy in the possession of the world’s goods. The Lord has made it clear, however, that when his people are obedient, he desires to bless them with the necessities and the comforts of life so that none should live in want.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p8" pid="omQ8XsLDBkG6hvOhyRcogQ" hash="iAeD8A">To the Prophet Joseph Smith the Lord said: “I have made the earth rich, and behold it is my footstool, wherefore, again I will stand upon it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p9" pid="9RHihb8TjUK10YxE0WLGVQ" hash="zRF6ug">“And I hold forth and deign to give unto you greater riches, even a land of promise, a land flowing with milk and honey, upon which there shall be no curse when the Lord cometh.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.17-18" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:17–18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p10" pid="IjVENk8L_kWQ8FEvu2EGiw" hash="hRe4Aw">Historically, the abundance with which the Lord has blessed his people has proved to be one of their greatest tests. The cycles of their acquiring worldly wealth and their subsequent spiritual decline are well documented in scriptural and historical records.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p11" pid="hsMS3cboe0KTVFX7hrylfQ" hash="0GbYdw">Moses’ concern for his people proved to be justified in the years following their entry into the land of Canaan. It was when they became settled in this goodly land that they began to take their abundance for granted and to forget the real source of these blessings. Moses had counseled them: “For the Lord thy God bringeth thee into a good land, a land of brooks of water, of fountains and depths that spring out of valleys and hills;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p12" pid="5NBsMJX4-0ehcqPMGl6gXQ" hash="EnRmBg">“A land of wheat, and barley, and vines, and fig trees, and pomegranates; a land of oil olive, and honey;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p13" pid="rqOHqw3H9UyUAyaiSGSOrg" hash="oDxJcQ">“A land wherein thou shalt eat bread without scarceness, thou shalt not lack any thing in it; a land whose stones are iron, and out of whose hills thou mayest dig brass.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p14" pid="0OLZy_0w1US7RiMwtwmkXg" hash="m4ynvQ">“When thou hast eaten and art full, then thou shalt bless the Lord thy God for the good land which he hath given thee.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p15" pid="NlDeJjZrS0eR39FPPrS8MQ" hash="lOSFeQ">“Beware that thou forget not the Lord thy God, in not keeping his commandments, and his judgments, and his statutes, which I command thee this day:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p16" pid="NX_2nPeFKU28oWH3AaYbSw" hash="InxKLQ">“Lest when thou hast eaten and art full, and hast built goodly houses, and dwelt therein;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p17" pid="HbG7_WLu6kywQSkb4Idzww" hash="RZPOiw">“And when thy herds and thy flocks multiply, and thy silver and thy gold is multiplied, and all that thou hast is multiplied;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p18" pid="CWrE4mtqFEGCM3dMxZtLRw" hash="TFXMbA">“Then thine heart be lifted up, and thou forget the Lord thy God, which brought thee forth out of the land of Egypt, from the house of bondage. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p19" pid="c8xv3zeYMkyLTju76t3Agw" hash="eO-z8Q">“And thou say in thine heart, My power and the might of mine hand hath gotten me this wealth.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/deut/8.7-14,17" class="scriptureRef">Deut. 8:7–14, 17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p20" pid="BkGWKqcJH02lVqxo5e8JrA" hash="KeugkA">Not long after the early Latter-day Saints had entered the Salt Lake Valley, and as they struggled in their poverty to establish homes and to survive in a land that had been a wilderness, reports came of the discovery of gold in northern California. The news spread to all parts of the country, and fortune hunters passing through the Salt Lake area en route to the gold fields spoke of their hopes for striking it rich in the newly discovered bonanza. It was a great temptation to some of the Saints who were so destitute in their own circumstances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p21" pid="q_g6VEJXFkeTeP4jP60owg" hash="jRuavQ">Brigham Young, sensing feelings that circulated among some of the people, said, “I hope that the gold mines will be no nearer than 800 miles. … Prosperity and riches blunt the feelings of man.” (Journal History of the Church, 8 July 1849.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p22" pid="WF_ZVXwIl0SFU0ymjz1aQw" hash="cHpQqw">And then, in his customary candor, he added at a later time: “The worst fear I have about this people is that they will get rich in this country, forget God and His people, wax fat, and kick themselves out of the Church and go to hell. This people will stand mobbing, robbing, poverty, and all manner of persecution, and be true. But my greater fear … is that they cannot stand wealth.” (James S. Brown, <span class="emphasis">Life of a Pioneer,</span> Salt Lake City: Geo. Q. Cannon and Sons Co., 1900, pp. 122–23.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p23" pid="RuWukIQMtE-6gtC5gUlAvw" hash="txFjHg">In his inspired wisdom, President Young felt some of the same apprehensions for his people that Moses had felt for the tribes of Israel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p24" pid="XRqe4FWS5ki2TQTGeZqp-w" hash="qa-2Jg">His counsel to the early Saints reflects the sentiments expressed by Jacob in the Book of Mormon. These men felt there was nothing inherently wrong in acquiring wealth. The danger lay in its obscuring the need for acknowledging the Lord’s hand in these blessings, and in failing to use the abundance to bless others and to accomplish the Lord’s purposes. Jacob said, “Think of your brethren like unto yourselves, and be familiar with all and free with your substance, that they may be rich like unto you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p25" pid="BCoLDFTO7UmUsw9VVw8acw" hash="lmOLVQ">“But before ye seek for riches, seek ye for the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p26" pid="OOPkVXRJK0OYlSGrK-B2NA" hash="2sVO1g">“And after ye have obtained a hope in Christ ye shall obtain riches, if ye seek them; and ye will seek them for the intent to do good—to clothe the naked, and to feed the hungry, and to liberate the captive, and administer relief to the sick and the afflicted.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/2.17-19" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 2:17–19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p27" pid="yssFLuKvjEmv34mJcY__hQ" hash="jnC8nw">The coveting of wealth so often has resulted in avarice, dishonesty, and greed. The acquisition of wealth has frequently produced pride, self-satisfaction, and arrogance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p28" pid="7UNQ5HeXdEq7VhMnMu37KQ" hash="j8YWTQ">An episode during the time of Alma in the Book of Mormon illustrates the cycle that has so often occurred when people are blessed materially by the Lord and then turn away from him. In the instance referred to, the Nephite people were struggling to overcome the effects of a devastating civil strife and a Lamanite invasion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p29" pid="hcmEDikhSEaysL5VP2KeZQ" hash="A1patg">Not only had there been great loss of life; the destruction to lands and to property had been sufficient to seriously jeopardize the prospects of recovery. Alma describes conditions in these words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p30" pid="uecVr5jhr0yv7R_8FqaPWQ" hash="pYqyFg">“But the people were afflicted, yea, greatly afflicted for the loss of their brethren, and also for the loss of their flocks and herds, and also for the loss of their fields of grain, which were trodden under foot and destroyed. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p31" pid="5dgoZcsmXkGk6t7srQ1Mng" hash="w82ovw">“And so great were their afflictions that every soul had cause to mourn; and they believed that it was the judgments of God sent upon them because of their wickedness and their abominations; therefore they were awakened to a remembrance of their duty.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p32" pid="Uuy-_Lv820CCoT_Maf8d9w" hash="NvISqw">“And they began to establish the church more fully; yea, and many were baptized in the waters of Sidon and were joined to the church of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/4.2-4" class="scriptureRef">Alma 4:2–4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p33" pid="k5L4eYYHREuNA2redONRCA" hash="ObRmJw">This spiritual reawakening among the people had a dramatic effect. Peace returned to the land. The Church prospered in its rapid growth. Not surprisingly, the people soon began again to enjoy an abundant life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p34" pid="bogK0v-3xk2VIJ3G2LY24w" hash="4QPbpg">The spiritual blessings granted by the Lord were accompanied by the acquisition of material wealth. Unfortunately the Nephites failed to meet this test. Within three years from the time of their earlier tragedy, Alma describes his people in this way: “The people of the church began to wax proud, because of their exceeding riches, and their fine silks, and their fine-twined linen, and because of their many flocks and herds, and their gold and their silver, and all manner of precious things, which they had obtained by their industry; and in all these things were they lifted up in the pride of their eyes.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/4.6" class="scriptureRef">Alma 4:6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p35" pid="o8ov5rUk-Ee2Cte0NSQLKw" hash="w1a4Vg">History repeatedly confirms that the abundance of earthly possessions can be both a blessing and a curse, depending upon the way these things are viewed and used. When we consume them on our own lust, we invoke tragedy.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.f2">
	<p pid="cECaJWZW8kuY_71BkFMEmg" hash="m2nHbQ">Wealth is a relative thing. Conditions vary dramatically from place to place in the world today. That which some consider to be the necessities of life, to others would be abundance, and even extravagance. In any set of circumstances, the challenges related to an improvement in material prosperity remain the same. The message that echoes to us from the pages of history and from the counsels of the Lord and his prophets is clear:</p>
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="2iLUQ6RGzEGH_MC1pBGPlA" hash="cUY5Sw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="GSt2cDhvbUWMGV5v6jlIrg" hash="U_kyxA">Seek ye first the kingdom of heaven.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="4eENsfCAMkijvkzfPhk-SQ" hash="FxFZ0w">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="23RullaTt0-5LiNtsudoOg" hash="A_xQBw">Seek not for riches to consume them on your own lusts.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="vwSUn3mCH0SUU6UWaVh0Sg" hash="4s8xQw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="I8H-EihxB02ysa7aOILofQ" hash="4mX8Dw">Thou shalt not covet.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="ITtjQPd17EuYlaQbEVWZVw" hash="ZZKX4w">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="32BvX25bGkS_u50G57fwEg" hash="mMVDnQ">Clothe the naked.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="hMreo4uH10G2KTFRRkfTKg" hash="6k1JJQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="cjaWMc6-ZUeduyLlFyM8RQ" hash="hdMogw">Feed the hungry.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="AlaqYEcql0uEfe0DDo2KKA" hash="-HOPaw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="oNm1T4DZF0m2Oz8gsGuTZw" hash="iekqUA">Relieve the sick and the afflicted.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Mu0ZyolvV0yG7SPyNn4R0A" hash="05bARw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="UT-pVu3yQ0CwdxfgQtiV4A" hash="wBscBw">Pay tithes and offerings.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="_LvTce04JE-4iSEgenPgTw" hash="61KgKA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="xfRWgj3Bp0-OPvAsO7I0mg" hash="Vg00vg">In all things acknowledge the Lord.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="7Bo30MDVAkGbNSHRRRkUXg" hash="SVRWMg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="cV8TShS1iE-qt1DbqLwn6A" hash="13QYQQ">Be grateful.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="wSTyhooK-U2-0u21hs1ZwQ" hash="SQ1qUA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="OEUTQGL6i0yHZamJKl_p6A" hash="lawycg">Be humble.</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p36" pid="K08aq_LhuUa21Dlv2QYEYw" hash="NcjoLA">The words of Moses to the tribes of Israel have appropriate application for us:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p37" pid="nuRE9o3gz0mTasTfYQNvPg" hash="9j5CFw">“Fear the Lord thy God, to keep all his statutes and his commandments, … thou, and thy son, and thy son’s son, all the days of thy life; and that thy days may be prolonged.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p38" pid="kFAR1diCWUu5P8Ye-1GSUg" hash="DIoKoA">“Hear therefore, O Israel, and observe to do it; that it may be well with thee, and that ye may increase mightily, as the Lord God of thy fathers hath promised thee, in the land that floweth with milk and honey.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/deut/6.2-3" class="scriptureRef">Deut. 6:2–3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord.p39" pid="Y2EGLPh1h0ijxdUqid8snQ" hash="qV6lWw">And “when thou hast eaten and art full, then thou shalt bless the Lord thy God for the good … which he hath given thee.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/deut/8.10" class="scriptureRef">Deut. 8:10</a>.) In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1991/04/beware-lest-thou-forget-the-lord</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1991-general-conference/1991-04-1050-elder-dean-l-larsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="6555726" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 1991 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lord Will Prosper the Righteous</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In behalf of the Presidency of the Seventy and the Quorum members, I would like to express a very warm welcome to Elders Eyring and Pace as they take their place now among the ranks of the Seventy. We also acknowledge the addition to the Seventies Qu</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_92911_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="Yb9dOg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ckYj_5cTQ0ixy7Zyr8Ay_A" hash="f-ziOg">The Lord Will Prosper the Righteous</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="b-4fRSvAx0uJmCbAEBOIlA" hash="VXIyUA">Dean L. Larsen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-246c.jpg" alt="Elder Dean L. Larsen" pid="TgMotp2WyUuUQnJPs8ylDQ" hash="TC6x9Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p1" pid="jIZn9H2GTkSTF_N1VM7eZA" hash="tc5sVw">In behalf of the Presidency of the Seventy and the Quorum members, I would like to express a very warm welcome to Elders Eyring and Pace as they take their place now among the ranks of the Seventy. We also acknowledge the addition to the Seventies Quorums of the fifteen men whose names President Hinckley read to you earlier and who have been serving since mid-August. Our best wishes also to Bishop Edgley and Bishop Burton, who now take their places beside Bishop Hales in the Presiding Bishopric of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p2" pid="oIGYkoWXvUa1uEIKgCDKig" hash="zZT-Yg">And we acknowledge our love and continuing deep respect and admiration for those men whose tenure as Seventies has concluded officially at this general conference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p3" pid="LSI_9UhewUedTC4AhvbJkA" hash="Dr--vg">During the conference of the Church in Fayette, New York, in 1831 the Lord gave a revelation through Joseph Smith that contains a remarkable promise. “I have made the earth rich,” the Lord declared, “and behold it is my footstool, wherefore, again I will stand upon it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p4" pid="lRD3zE_PXUCotrt9SSGK2w" hash="4klYBQ">“And I hold forth and deign to give unto you greater riches, even a land of promise, a land flowing with milk and honey, upon which there shall be no curse when the Lord cometh;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p5" pid="k7_wmx6cBE-Rmd9dWV4dEQ" hash="K1cMnw">“And I will give it unto you for the land of your inheritance, if you seek it with all your hearts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p6" pid="fSiSWMDfs02WruPu4WAVWQ" hash="oGwiLA">“And this shall be my covenant with you, ye shall have it for the land of your inheritance, and for the inheritance of your children forever, while the earth shall stand, and ye shall possess it again in eternity, no more to pass away.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.17-20" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:17–20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p7" pid="RJ7j2N-LR0ShsYCmh_H6aw" hash="Q_knhg">The Lord has demonstrated throughout the generations that when the inhabitants of the earth remember him and are obedient to his direction, he will bless them not only with spiritual blessings, but with material abundance as well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p8" pid="oTUlW3bG_kKhm5MGOIElag" hash="lF1bIA">The scriptures contain many evidences of the Lord’s willingness to prosper his people with the riches of the earth when they demonstrate that they will use this abundance prudently, with humility and charity, always acknowledging the source of their blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p9" pid="jkCuyrqQ6EGMO7naqVnCOQ" hash="VtUBRA">When the people of Lehi arrived in the Americas from the old world, they felt a great dependence upon the Lord as they established their homes and worked to provide for themselves. Nephi makes this entry in his record:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p10" pid="LHx-VNsJHUKWvlkNtMGilg" hash="tPpgWA">“And we did observe to keep the judgments, and the statutes, and the commandments of the Lord in all things. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p11" pid="xZYgIPGux0aS_N7OcbbDJw" hash="EeJa0w">“And the Lord was with us; and we did prosper exceedingly; for we did sow seed, and we did reap again in abundance. And we began to raise flocks, and herds, and animals of every kind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p12" pid="D9NjsTVBeEebi2JmiAZDVw" hash="kfNlmQ">“And it came to pass that we began to prosper exceedingly, and to multiply in the land.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/5.10-11,13" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 5:10–11, 13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p13" pid="UAjVD-gSzkW_TYHROLLUEg" hash="LUYngg">This kind of material prosperity has always been a fragile thing. It has proved to be one of the greatest tests with which a people can be confronted. The essential human qualities and other factors that generate abundance have always been difficult to sustain. We see this reflected in an episode that is described in the first chapter of Alma in the Book of Mormon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p14" pid="om7JrloQ00mqk8w_8lYhgw" hash="JQjyaA">As I read several of the verses from this account, make particular note of the elements that contribute to the material successes of the people and then the factors that lead to their subsequent misfortunes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p15" pid="vpl55ZeZ60qfPDFYACGUHw" hash="dj-jPw">“And when the priests left their labor to impart the word of God unto the people, the people also left their labors to hear the word of God. And when the priest had imparted unto them the word of God they all returned again diligently unto their labors; and the priest, not esteeming himself above his hearers, for the preacher was no better than the hearer, neither was the teacher any better than the learner; and thus they were all equal, and they did all labor, every man according to his strength.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p16" pid="e-EdRPCZgkCcA6g-78K-yA" hash="91akQQ">“And they did impart of their substance, every man according to that which he had, to the poor, and the needy, and the sick, and the afflicted; and they did not wear costly apparel, yet they were neat and comely.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p17" pid="e2dHExXkaUWhKwuyVBd7GA" hash="xE16Aw">“And thus they did establish the affairs of the church; and thus they began to have continual peace. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p18" pid="M931Ju44vkmDXk2_IVZDZw" hash="G7Yt5w">“And now, because of the steadiness of the church they began to be exceedingly rich, having abundance of all things whatsoever they stood in need—an abundance of flocks and herds, and fatlings of every kind, and also abundance of grain, and of gold, and of silver, and of precious things, and abundance of silk and fine-twined linen, and all manner of good homely cloth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p19" pid="xa-Pzq4-ekaKSbkUYhtzJw" hash="Yn2uHQ">“And thus, in their prosperous circumstances, they did not send away any who were naked, or that were hungry, or that were athirst, or that were sick, or that had not been nourished; and they did not set their hearts upon riches; therefore they were liberal to all, both old and young, both bond and free, both male and female, whether out of the church or in the church, having no respect to persons as to those who stood in need.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p20" pid="4NzUA_l7z0KXMwdtDwNUtQ" hash="3LX-ig">“And thus they did prosper.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/1.26-31" class="scriptureRef">Alma 1:26–31</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p21" pid="k_5ca1tBvkyrwYLCIrWCQA" hash="-nZQ1Q">It has always been so. When the lives of the people are in harmony with the Lord’s will, all of the essential factors that produce the blessings God deigns to give to his children seem to come into line. Love and harmony prevail. Even the weather, the climate, and the elements seem to respond. Peace and tranquillity endure. Industry and progress mark the lives of the people. It is as the Lord has promised: “If ye walk in my statutes, and keep my commandments, and do them;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p22" pid="hpg0LsT7L0q6-8l8-DEG4A" hash="zs0Axw">“Then I will give you rain in due season, and the land shall yield her increase, and the trees of the field shall yield their fruit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p23" pid="3yAPr14tfE2HT4BMHDBO6g" hash="XXh8Dg">“And your threshing shall reach unto the vintage, and the vintage shall reach unto the sowing time: and ye shall eat your bread to the full, and dwell in your land safely.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p24" pid="EYpPUo-r8kSz5mRzgVIz7w" hash="4KdNbw">“And I will give peace in the land, and ye shall lie down, and none shall make you afraid.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/lev/26.3-6" class="scriptureRef">Lev. 26:3–6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p25" pid="1XPjiZZzC0Sk_GJkbbaKvQ" hash="SNSScQ">Perhaps the greatest tragedies of all time have occurred when people have received the promised blessings of the Lord and then have forgotten the source of their good life. Moses cautioned the people of Israel against this natural inclination when he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p26" pid="zRUqiUgGjk-MTtR-FtsPTQ" hash="Tdljuw">“Beware that thou forget not the Lord thy God, in not keeping his commandments, and his judgments, and his statutes. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p27" pid="wYmVQ9Ng_EuiqWLzsRxPig" hash="InxKLQ">“Lest when thou hast eaten and art full, and hast built goodly houses, and dwelt therein;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p28" pid="YCAeaDy0zUWbYRBuOy5Pow" hash="RZPOiw">“And when thy herds and thy flocks multiply, and thy silver and thy gold is multiplied, and all that thou hast is multiplied;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p29" pid="Qu3JDCRm0k6LP7aRbSfZbg" hash="_x8Pfw">“Then thine heart be lifted up, and thou forget the Lord thy God. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p30" pid="Xjs6kq77c0CgXEJ8Imm2qg" hash="89Ec-g">“And thou say in thine heart, My power and the might of <span class="emphasis">mine</span> hand hath gotten me this wealth.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/deut/8.11-14,17" class="scriptureRef">Deut. 8:11–14, 17</a>; emphasis added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p31" pid="s2kQcnJoTEC-Xw5cZr9RbQ" hash="03tobA">Returning to the account in Alma to which I made earlier reference, not many years passed away from the time of prosperity described in such glowing terms until the people began to take all of the credit for the good times unto themselves. We find this sad entry in Alma’s record:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p32" pid="e-MQ6tGALEeFwB7MWupsBg" hash="j8w0Fg">“And it came to pass in the eighth year of the reign of the judges, that the people of the church began to wax proud, because of their exceeding riches, and their fine silks, and their fine-twined linen, and because of their many flocks and herds, and their gold and their silver, and all manner of precious things, which they had obtained by their industry; and in all these things were they lifted up in the pride of their eyes. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p33" pid="-2LSH9SOqke1A2T0EuvBlw" hash="2ZEPrg">“The people of the church began … to set their hearts upon riches and upon the vain things of the world, that they began to be scornful, one towards another.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/4.6,8" class="scriptureRef">Alma 4:6, 8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p34" pid="AGAD-ZtY3k6WJi4johc5Cg" hash="qYqGRQ">The same cycle occurred in the days of Helaman. At one point Helaman describes his people in this way:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p35" pid="k7AvAtnaP0KaTIEo5mLYXg" hash="80egdQ">“And it came to pass that in this same year there was exceedingly great prosperity in the church, insomuch that there were thousands who did join themselves unto the church and were baptized unto repentance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p36" pid="Yr1OIUjmdkCZQl4L6byNUw" hash="BoL3EQ">“And so great was the prosperity of the church, and so many the blessings which were poured out upon the people, that even the high priests and the teachers were themselves astonished beyond measure.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/3.24-25" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 3:24–25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p37" pid="wTRRNymJw0eis4o4XGY9wQ" hash="et3POA">It was not long until the full cycle was completed, however. Within five years from the period just cited, Helaman makes this report regarding members of the Church: “And in the fifty and first year of the reign of the judges there was peace also, save it were the pride which began to enter into the church—not into the church of God, but into the hearts of the people who professed to belong to the church of God—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p38" pid="UTDf2m8RKkWOlcV20I0tZg" hash="dkjRCQ">“And they were lifted up in pride, even to the persecution of many of their brethren” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/3.33-34" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 3:33–34</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p39" pid="bCQTIDxnnkybflPYAJOruQ" hash="8XdS4g">These abrupt changes in the condition of the people led Helaman to lament:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p40" pid="JP-DZydlS0CJW8aCNRcvQg" hash="M0lnEQ">“And thus we can behold how false, and also the unsteadiness of the hearts of the children of men; yea, we can see that the Lord in his great infinite goodness doth bless and prosper those who put their trust in him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p41" pid="HH-bBEy4T0SlUKwhFS7Edw" hash="VO43Rg">“Yea, and we may see at the very time when he doth prosper his people, yea, in the increase of their fields, their flocks and their herds, and in gold, and in silver, and in all manner of precious things of every kind and art; sparing their lives, and delivering them out of the hands of their enemies; … and in fine, doing all things for the welfare and happiness of his people; yea, then is the time that they do harden their hearts, and do forget the Lord their God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/12.1-2" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 12:1–2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p42" pid="hbLGKUNbN0GNNPHnMd-e-A" hash="cF2nNQ">It is one thing to look back upon the events of history. It is another to regard our own time. We have the Lord’s assurance that he will bless and prosper his people if they will keep his commandments and remember to look to him as the source of their blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p43" pid="BeUbiKvPAEihUn7eicYVPg" hash="HTTgDA">On the other hand, we must not forget that these blessings are conditional. As King Limhi warned his people, “For behold, the Lord hath said: I will not succor my people in the day of their transgression; but I will hedge up their ways that they prosper not; and their doings shall be as a stumbling block before them” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/7.29" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 7:29</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p44" pid="pQIsLtV1oE6Whl_GrkDI9g" hash="vqNMtw">As bearers of the priesthood to whom the Lord has entrusted the leadership for his work, we must look carefully at our own lives. And we must assess honestly the level of faith and obedience of our people. Too many of the indicators are not encouraging. Only a small percentage of the Church members worldwide are tithe payers today. For many who live in conditions of material poverty, there may be no other way to escape their impoverishment than to give obedience to this law. As I visit among the stakes of the Church, I find it is not uncommon to discover that fewer than 50 percent of the households are contributing to the fast offerings of the Church, and the trends are not improving.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p45" pid="EEZMmo59yEe9d75Z2lydKA" hash="f_Npmw">We have reached a point where more of our adult men are becoming prospective elders than are receiving the Melchizedek Priesthood. About half of the endowed members of the Church hold current temple recommends. Reports of other violations of the Lord’s law are a source of concern.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p46" pid="r9nN5dDc20qD0MU0l3S7mw" hash="48CqEw">These indicators may seem to carry a direful tone, but as Enos declared in the Book of Mormon, sometimes it is necessary to resort to “exceedingly great plainness of speech” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/enos/1.23" class="scriptureRef">Enos 1:23</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous.p47" pid="I032pL4WSE2ovAq2_meupg" hash="o41pWg">As the world continues to ripen in iniquity, our lives of necessity must become increasingly different from the world and its standard. It will be a great challenge for us. We must be better than we have ever been before. As we succeed, we have the sure promise of the Lord that he will prosper us in every way necessary for our well-being. That is my faith and my testimony. But it is a conditional promise. May we qualify for its fulfillment in our lives and in our time is my earnest prayer in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1992/10/the-lord-will-prosper-the-righteous</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1992-general-conference/1992-10-3020-elder-dean-l-larsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="7133990" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 1992 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
