<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Dean M. Davies</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Dean M. Davies.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Dean%20M.%20Davies.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Dean M. Davies.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>A Sure Foundation</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Let us accept the Savior’s invitation to come unto Him. Let us build our lives upon a safe and a sure foundation.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10785_000_13davies" doc-version="2" hash="3FogWA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="ZZ5UIRoogEWY8dXNRdFsXQ" hash="2IXASQ">A Sure Foundation</h1><p class="authorName" pid="KrLktgVE8EyZSKxM4syaDg" hash="cBJoTw">By Bishop Dean M. Davies</p><p class="kicker" pid="ZCF0w-g-60WOCCzKNvQZhA" hash="5bhWXA">Let us accept the Savior’s invitation to come unto Him. Let us build our lives upon a safe and a sure foundation.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" pid="3fCs26UXtEC4MiGKB7luTA" hash="QS3EUA">
				<span class="story">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p5" pid="yGOm9_w2FEmZUKxJqReNlQ" hash="Nlz35Q"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="9"></span>On October 17, 1989, while driving home after work, I was approaching a stoplight at the intersection of Market and Beale Streets in San Francisco, California. At that moment I felt the car shake and thought, “I must have a flat tire.” As the car continued to shake, I noticed a bus quite close to me and thought, “That bus just hit me!” Then the car shook more and more, and I thought, “I must have four flat tires!” But it wasn’t flat tires or the bus—it was a powerful earthquake! As I stopped at the red light, there were ripples in the pavement like waves of the sea rolling down Market Street. In front of me a tall office building was swaying from side to side, and bricks began falling from an older building to my left as the earth continued to shake.</p>
				</span>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p6" pid="uoTb5F6lXU-xJjQCKUoSSQ" hash="x8isiw">The Loma Prieta earthquake struck the San Francisco Bay Area at 5:04 p.m. that day and left as many as 12,000 people homeless.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p7" pid="xb2BXhBB20uJpI33HZ3BFw" hash="Sdi67Q">The earthquake caused severe damage in the San Francisco Bay Area, most notably on unstable soil in San Francisco and Oakland. In San Francisco, the Marina District had been “built on a landfill made of a mixture of sand, dirt, rubble, … and other materials containing a high percentage of groundwater. Some of the fill was rubble dumped into San Francisco Bay after the 1906 San Francisco earthquake.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p8" pid="_4xqLMjdzEapQ90zJ4WUhA" hash="kULWrg">In about 1915, apartment buildings were erected on the landfill. In the 1989 earthquake, the water-saturated unconsolidated mud, sand, and rubble converted to a liquid-like mass, causing the buildings to collapse. The buildings were not built on a sure foundation.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p9" pid="VAUxbEb2WEyGC0iED9WByg" hash="S40WEQ">The Loma Prieta earthquake impacted many lives, including my own. Pondering the events of that day reaffirms in my mind and heart that in order to successfully withstand the tempests, earthquakes, and calamities of life, we must build upon a sure foundation.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p10" pid="OLcpVNNTW0qg5SEgxshA3w" hash="840oCQ">The Nephite prophet Helaman gave unmistakable clarity to the importance of building our lives on a sure foundation, even the foundation of Jesus Christ: “And now, my sons, remember, remember that it is upon the rock of our Redeemer, who is Christ, the Son of God, that ye must build your foundation; that when the devil shall send forth his mighty winds, yea, his shafts in the whirlwind, yea, when all his hail and his mighty storm shall beat upon you, it shall have no power over you to drag you down to the gulf of misery and endless wo, because of the rock upon which ye are built, which is a sure foundation, a foundation whereon if men build they cannot fall” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/5.12" class="scriptureRef">Helaman 5:12</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p11" pid="4jzqNx66O0u-wLRhCF3WFg" hash="7OFQ_Q">In the development of modern-day temples, careful attention is given to the design, engineering, and use of building materials. Thorough testing of the soils and geology takes place on the site where a temple will be built. Studies of wind, rain, and changes in the weather for the area are considered so that the completed temple can withstand not only storms and climate common to an area, but the temple is designed and positioned to withstand the unexpected earthquakes, typhoons, floods, and other natural calamities that may occur. In many temples, concrete or steel piles are driven deep into the earth to anchor the temple foundation.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p12" pid="3kMGFRwSu02LCcVfSSgHiw" hash="9fGSag">Like the designers and builders of our time, our loving and kind Father in Heaven and His Son have prepared plans, tools, and other resources for our use so that we can build and frame our lives to be sure and unshaken. The plan is the plan of <span class="pageBreak" page-number="10"></span>salvation, the great plan of happiness. The plan lays out for us a clear picture and understanding of the beginning and the end and the essential steps, including ordinances, which are necessary for each of Father’s children to be able to return to His presence and dwell with Him forever.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p13" pid="CwMwfbEXMU2WsC3NMweOrQ" hash="faDF7Q">Faith, repentance, baptism, the gift of the Holy Ghost, and enduring to the end are part of the “blueprints” of life. They help to form the appropriate building blocks that will anchor our lives to the Atonement of Christ. These shape and frame the supporting structure of a person’s life. Then, just as temple plans have specifications that give detailed instructions about how to form and integrate essential components, praying, reading the scriptures, partaking of the sacrament, and receiving essential priesthood ordinances become the “specifications” that help integrate and bind together the structure of life.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p14" pid="00Zz_qj9xUinTjNdQaya8g" hash="8gEtCA">Balance in the application of these specifications is vital. For example, in the process of making concrete, precise amounts of sand, gravel, cement, and water are used in order to achieve maximum strength. An incorrect amount or exclusion of any portion of these elements would make the concrete weak and not able to perform its important function.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p15" pid="KejN5c1-FUS8PbiHALcX0g" hash="NJkUqg">In like manner, if we do not provide for an appropriate balance in our lives of daily personal prayer and feasting from the scriptures, weekly strengthening from partaking of the sacrament, and frequent participation in priesthood ordinances such as temple ordinances, we too are at risk of being weakened in our spiritual structural strength.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p16" pid="BXCvEXRnyE2MlNWPjPX23g" hash="TwQNmg">Paul, in a letter to the Ephesians, said it this way, which we can apply to the need for a balanced and integrated development of our character and soul: “In whom all the building fitly framed together groweth unto an holy temple in the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/2.21" class="scriptureRef">Ephesians 2:21</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p17" pid="JOTdPX4zlkiq8dXJRo3VRw" hash="04T-aA">Prayer is one of the most basic and important foundational building blocks of our faith and character. Through prayer we are able to express our gratitude, love, and devotion to God. Through prayer we can submit our will to His and in return receive the strength to conform our lives to His teachings. Prayer is the avenue we can follow to seek His influence in our lives, even revelation.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p18" pid="N3CmWDDxnU6p4inMzn2Wvw" hash="nNtyJQ">Alma taught, “Counsel with the Lord in all thy doings, and he will direct thee for good; yea, when thou liest down at night lie down unto the Lord, that he may watch over you in your sleep; and when thou risest in the morning let thy heart be full of thanks unto God; and if ye do these things, ye shall be lifted up at the last day” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.37" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:37</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p19" pid="ZWEsL8CLfkObAz4KHNDEZQ" hash="ls4K6w">Sharing our thoughts, feelings, and desires with God through sincere and heartfelt prayer should become to each of us as important and natural as breathing and eating.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p20" pid="UTG_r-CMoEit0uulBCZ9PQ" hash="uC5oyw">Searching the scriptures on a daily basis will also fortify our faith and character. Just as we need food to nourish our physical bodies, our spirits and souls will be replenished and strengthened by feasting upon the words of Christ as contained in the writings of the prophets. Nephi taught, “Feast upon the words of Christ; for behold, the words of Christ will tell you all things what ye should do” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/32.3" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 32:3</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p21" pid="A3KZWiEWNE6kWVM1c8oAAA" hash="KUicjg">While reading the scriptures is good, reading by itself is insufficient to capture the full breadth and depth of the Savior’s teachings. Searching, pondering, and applying the words of Christ as taught in the scriptures will bring wisdom and knowledge beyond our mortal understanding. This will strengthen our commitment and provide the spiritual reserves to do our best in all situations.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p22" pid="0Zd-LWIhukGJaiISzeQc2Q" hash="6UfpDQ">One of the most important steps we can take to strengthen our lives and remain firmly attached to the foundation of the Savior is to worthily partake of the sacrament each week. The sacrament ordinance affords every Church member the opportunity to ponder his or her life in advance, to consider the actions or nonactions that may need to be repented of, and <span class="pageBreak" page-number="11"></span>then to partake of the bread and water as sacred emblems in remembrance of the body and blood of Jesus Christ, a witness of His Atonement. If we partake with sincerity and in humility, we renew eternal covenants, are cleansed and sanctified, and receive the promise that we will have His Spirit to be with us always. The Spirit acts as a type of mortar, a welding link that not only sanctifies but also brings all things to our remembrance and testifies again and again of Jesus Christ. Worthily partaking of the sacrament strengthens our personal connection to the foundation rock, even to Jesus Christ.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p23" pid="dIzE0PpjokOD9xCzcaA8eA" hash="gJvAMQ">During His ministry the Savior taught with love and clarity the doctrines, principles, and necessary actions that would preserve our lives and strengthen our character. At the end of the Sermon on the Mount, He stated:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p24" pid="ORCiRaHXR0qHRMs7138Z7Q" hash="yxIyng">“Therefore, whoso heareth these sayings of mine and doeth them, I will liken him unto a wise man, [which] built his house upon a rock—</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p25" pid="-TiQUHgMSUWhsCeDnptKVg" hash="boT1ww">“And the rain descended, and the floods came, and the winds blew, and beat upon that house; and it fell not, for it was founded upon a rock.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p26" pid="ynTV92LsJU2oKf8LpKrHVw" hash="LNi1dg">“And every one that heareth these sayings of mine and doeth them not shall be likened unto a foolish man, [which] built his house upon the sand—</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p27" pid="UOvW4lTWHUq-mXwRSHeIPA" hash="YaLNgQ">“And the rain descended, and the floods came, and the winds blew, and beat upon that house; and it fell, and great was the fall of it” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/14.24-27" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 14:24–27</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.24-27" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 7:24–27</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p28" pid="VDRlaB1LBkqHtfO56Hqhxg" hash="T6BUxg">Brothers and sisters, none of us would knowingly construct our homes, places of work, or sacred houses of worship on sand or rubble or without appropriate plans and materials. Let us accept the Savior’s invitation to come unto Him. Let us build our lives upon a safe and a sure foundation.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation.p29" pid="fogVAwbZnUCAZiwhAOWLJA" hash="E9-rEQ">I humbly testify that by anchoring our lives to Jesus Christ and to His Atonement and by carefully following His plans for our happiness, including daily prayer, daily scripture study, and weekly partaking of the sacrament, we will be strengthened, we will experience real personal growth and a lasting conversion, we will be better prepared to successfully withstand the storms and calamities of life, we will experience the joy and happiness promised, and we will have the confidence that our lives have been built upon a sure foundation—a foundation that will never fall. In the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2013/04/a-sure-foundation</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2013-general-conference/2013-04-1030-bishop-dean-m-davies-64k-eng.mp3" length="5183291" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Law of the Fast: A Personal Responsibility to Care for the Poor and Needy</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Bishop Dean M. Davies counsels all members to follow the Savior by caring for the poor and needy through the law of the fast.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10991_000_33davies" doc-version="5" hash="Pl9IQw">
			
			<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.head1">
				<h1 class="title" pid="pS3afAISMUywphnIaE3cmA" hash="qvsVNA">The Law of the Fast: A Personal Responsibility to Care for the Poor and Needy</h1>
				<div class="byline">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p2" pid="CCfyrmHgVkCPs6HvMep3mw" hash="cBJoTw">By Bishop Dean M. Davies</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p3" pid="vMpgksWVP0WF4i0Lc3XcfA" hash="9-VD6g">Second Counselor in the Presiding Bishopric</p>
					<a href="gl://image/?pid=A91HSZ_830mgZJKBNAy-AQ"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255515/5915e33a5356403f9575a0cc18714e05/100x137.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x68="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255515/5915e33a5356403f9575a0cc18714e05/50x68.jpg" data-src-100x137="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255515/5915e33a5356403f9575a0cc18714e05/100x137.jpg" data-src-200x275="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255515/5915e33a5356403f9575a0cc18714e05/200x275.jpg" data-src-320x441="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255515/5915e33a5356403f9575a0cc18714e05/320x441.jpg" data-src-460x634="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255515/5915e33a5356403f9575a0cc18714e05/460x634.jpg" data-src-640x882="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255515/5915e33a5356403f9575a0cc18714e05/640x882.jpg" data-src-1024x1412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255515/5915e33a5356403f9575a0cc18714e05/1024x1412.jpg" data-src-2048x2825="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255515/5915e33a5356403f9575a0cc18714e05/2048x2825.jpg" data-src-3874x5344="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255515/5915e33a5356403f9575a0cc18714e05/3874x5344.jpg" altText="Bishop Dean M. Davies" pid="A91HSZ_830mgZJKBNAy-AQ" hash="fK6QAQ"></img></a>
				</div>
				<p class="kicker" pid="bMJLahnio0y0oS4gUJa6gA" hash="JAs_LA">As followers of the Savior, we have a personal responsibility to care for the poor and needy.</p>
			<p class="authorName" pid="bGcYFiNkRUudRE69-BeF5Q" hash="cBJoTw1">By Bishop Dean M. Davies</p></div>
			<div class="bodyBlock">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p5" pid="_gnOFSpCeEOFYLFMlA9Oow" hash="EXZsPQ">My dear brethren, I love the priesthood, and I love being with you. I am so deeply grateful that we can serve together in this great cause.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p6" pid="bQl8rAQKykGssWKmtdIXeA" hash="gWGyQA">We live in remarkable times. Miraculous advances in medicine, science, and technology have improved the quality of life for many. Yet there is also evidence of great human suffering and distress. In addition to wars and rumors of wars, an increase in natural disasters—including floods, fires, earthquakes, and disease—is impacting the lives of millions worldwide.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p7" pid="CLj3Pl6TiEiaL2OKpEAL7w" hash="daHhcA">Church leadership is aware of and vigilant regarding the well-being of God’s children everywhere. When and where possible, Church emergency resources are provided to respond to those in need. For example, last November, Typhoon Haiyan hit the island nation of the Philippines.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p8" pid="pLjYi697ZkqExmlkik6brw" hash="A1lR8Q">A Category 5 super typhoon, Haiyan left in its wake extensive destruction and suffering. Complete cities were destroyed; many lives were lost; millions of homes were severely damaged or destroyed; and basic services such as water, sewer, and electricity ceased functioning.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p9" pid="XCuT_801rUOqxpAXnx5E0g" hash="P7wvHA">Church resources were made available in the very early hours following this disaster. Church members living in the Philippines rallied to the rescue of their brothers and sisters by providing food, water, clothing, and hygiene kits to members and nonmembers alike.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p10" pid="kxXD9F9YgUqxaqs43tX9Ug" hash="V_AELw">Church meetinghouses became places of refuge to thousands of the homeless. Under the leadership of the Area Presidency and local priesthood leaders, many of whom had lost everything they had, assessments were made as to the condition and safety of all members. Inspired plans began to take shape to help restore members to acceptable living conditions and self-reliance.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p11" pid="_YDBZecX7UCqRMYtf0yg3g" hash="KeotJg">Modest resources were provided to help Church members rebuild their wood-frame shelters and homes. This was not just a free handout. Members received training and performed the needed labor for themselves and then for others.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p12" pid="N4H1azTAXEe5JoqeFSN3iQ" hash="ImJ_Jg">One resulting blessing was that as members developed carpentry, plumbing, and other construction skills, they were able to secure meaningful work opportunities as nearby cities and communities began rebuilding.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p13" pid="2rmozGYUfEyghdBgGIuzGw" hash="S63HDg"><span class="emphasis">Caring for the poor and needy is a fundamental gospel doctrine and an essential element in the eternal plan of salvation.</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p14" pid="NVBzfeyrC0SmqwawZO9ORg" hash="Qt_a2Q">Prior to His mortal ministry, Jehovah declared through His prophet: “For the poor shall never cease out of the land: therefore I command thee, saying, Thou shalt open thine hand wide unto thy brother, to thy poor, and to thy needy, in thy land.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p15" pid="O0_DrD9PUUGPHxZB0kPi8Q" hash="vMNDkQ">In our day, caring for the poor and needy is one of four divinely appointed Church responsibilities that help individuals and families qualify for exaltation.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p16" pid="9O6R5AycIkuXRz5bZfc6aw" hash="0Qy_Zg">Caring for the poor and needy contemplates both temporal and spiritual salvation. It includes the service of individual Church members as they personally care for the poor and needy, as well as formal Church welfare, which is administered through priesthood authority.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p17" pid="bs8-uhPgOU2Fyhrj38ecmA" hash="4o8kSw">Central to the Lord’s plan for caring for the poor and needy is the <span class="emphasis">law of the fast.</span> “The Lord has established the law of the fast and fast offerings to bless His people and to provide a way for them to serve those in need.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p18" pid="cjJ52eu9tUWvWwF4MfSNMA" hash="4t3YAA">As followers of the Savior, we have a personal responsibility to care for the poor and needy. Faithful Church members everywhere assist by fasting each month—abstaining from food and water for 24 hours—and then giving to the Church a financial fast offering equal to at least the value of the food they would have eaten.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p19" pid="hTWnn1T1PkuT1RDGuaBTPA" hash="zReEBw">Isaiah’s words should be prayerfully considered and taught in every home:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p20" pid="RA-kz0GR5EOoX3YiuN8cOQ" hash="O0FXCQ">“Is not this the fast that I have chosen? to loose the bands of wickedness, to undo the heavy burdens, and to let the oppressed go free, and that ye break every yoke?</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p21" pid="1NBqN27ux0qrv55CaoPdCw" hash="n0d69w">“Is it not to deal thy bread to the hungry, and that thou bring the poor that are cast out to thy house? when thou seest the naked, that thou cover him; and that thou hide not thyself from thine own flesh?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p22" pid="0vSu5qLZt0erVFdg5QOO9Q" hash="KLCbUg">Isaiah then went on to list the wonderful blessings promised by the Lord to those who obey the law of the fast. He says:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p23" pid="Hjm1IkGiZ0CCBStV4dXBqw" hash="-r9VGw">“Then shall thy light break forth as the morning, and thine health shall spring forth speedily: and thy righteousness shall go before thee; the glory of the Lord shall be thy rearward.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p24" pid="Ww0o6NW17UOQLWplKv61kQ" hash="V8g9uQ">“Then shalt thou call, and the Lord shall answer; thou shalt cry, and he shall say, Here I am. …</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p25" pid="kcX3dJrRjUKdB4FR8boOcw" hash="OOgyqg">“And if thou draw out thy soul to the hungry, and satisfy the afflicted soul; then shall thy light rise in obscurity, and thy darkness be as the noonday:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p26" pid="QaFf3WPSo0KQ7OVV39O_hw" hash="vefLjA">“And the Lord shall guide thee continually, and satisfy thy soul in drought.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p27" pid="7QuDrF9bD0e-TtNlOFS2Vw" hash="nXbnSA">Regarding this scripture, President Harold B. Lee had this to say: “The tremendous blessings that come [from fasting] have been spelled out in every dispensation, and here the Lord is telling us through this great prophet why there is fasting, and the blessings that come from fasting. … If you analyze … the 58th chapter of the book of Isaiah you will find unraveled why the Lord wants us to pay fast offerings, why he wants us to fast. It’s because by qualifying thus we can call and the Lord can answer. We can cry and the Lord will say, ‘Here I am.’”</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p28" pid="ri8GgczEpEa0NPcugIKqcQ" hash="PniQZw">President Lee adds: “Do we ever want to be in a condition where we can call and he won’t answer? We will cry in our distress and he won’t be with us? I think it is time we are thinking about these fundamentals because these are the days that lie ahead, when we are going to need more and more the blessings of the Lord, when the judgments are poured out without mixture upon the whole earth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p29" pid="ZPoULq1SSky-nwevkxqJDg" hash="nWlcSA">Our beloved prophet, President Thomas S. Monson, has shared his testimony of these principles—a testimony borne of personal experience. He said: “No member of the Church who has helped provide for those in need ever forgets or regrets the experience. Industry, thrift, self-reliance, and sharing with others are not new to us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p30" pid="_JRAMhmOSUismNNSVIOMXQ" hash="45-qCA">Brethren, members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints are a covenant-making, commandment-keeping people. I cannot think of any law, any commandment, which, if kept faithfully, is easier to keep and which provides greater blessings than the law of the fast. When we fast and give an honest fast offering, we contribute to the Lord’s storehouse what would have been expended on the cost of the meals. It does not require monetary sacrifice in excess of what would be expended normally. At the same time, we are promised the extraordinary blessings, as previously noted.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p31" pid="WzbGL9G1tkqRy3UfPe-IQg" hash="62OnpA">The law of the fast applies to all Church members. Even young children can be taught to fast, beginning with one meal and then two, as they are able to understand and physically keep the law of the fast. Husbands and wives, single members, youth, and children should begin the fast with prayer, giving gratitude for blessings in their lives while seeking the Lord’s blessings and strength through the fast period. Complete fulfillment of the law of the fast occurs when the fast offering is made to the Lord’s agent, the bishop.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p32" pid="tEd8WEH-OkiFToBBLb7o9Q" hash="Ycq0aw">Bishops, you direct welfare in the ward. You have a divine mandate to seek out and care for the poor. With the support of the Relief Society president and Melchizedek Priesthood quorum leaders, your goal is to help members help themselves and become self-reliant. You minister to the temporal and spiritual needs of members by carefully using fast offerings as a temporary support and as a supplement to extended family and community resources. As you prayerfully exercise priesthood keys and discernment in helping the poor and needy, you will come to know that the correct use of fast offerings is intended to support life, not lifestyle.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p33" pid="v2mfx8SavkyYzIwZ808LDw" hash="bnIvEg">Aaronic Priesthood quorum presidents, you hold keys and have the power to administer in outward ordinances. You work with the bishop and instruct quorum members regarding their duties in the priesthood and in seeking out Church members to give them the opportunity to contribute to the fast. As you Aaronic Priesthood holders magnify your priesthood responsibilities and extend this opportunity to all Church members, you frequently facilitate the promised blessings of the fast to those who may need them the most. You will witness that the spirit of caring for the poor and needy has the power to soften otherwise hardened hearts and blesses the lives of those who may infrequently attend Church.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p34" pid="rQOMNLKJ306C5vKcxIjhrg" hash="AEnQ3g">President Monson has said, “Those bishops who organize their Aaronic Priesthood quorums to participate in the collection of fast offerings will find increased success in this sacred responsibility.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p35" pid="Yr80JQcBoka1XGfb0rlXDw" hash="R_9ugQ">Bishops, remember that circumstances vary widely from one area to another and from country to country. Door-to-door contacting by Aaronic Priesthood quorum members may not be practical in the region where you live. However, we invite you to prayerfully consider the prophet’s counsel and seek inspiration on appropriate ways in which the Aaronic Priesthood holders in your wards can magnify their priesthood by participating in the collection of fast offerings.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy.p36" pid="uIqoL4aFSkaYzqCyhB98UA" hash="qpEGDw">In <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.27" class="scriptureRef">chapter 27 of 3 Nephi</a>, the risen Lord asked, “What manner of men ought ye to be?” He responded, “Even as I am.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> As we take upon ourselves the name of Christ and strive to follow Him, we will receive His image in our countenance and become more like Him. Caring for the poor and needy is inherent in the ministry of the Savior. It is in everything He does. He reaches out to all and lifts us. His yoke is easy, and His burden is light. I invite each of us to become more like the Savior by caring for the poor and needy, by faithfully keeping the law of the fast, and by contributing a generous fast offering. I humbly testify that faithfully caring for the poor and needy is a reflection of spiritual maturity and will bless both the giver and the receiver. In the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div>
			
		</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/10/the-law-of-the-fast-a-personal-responsibility-to-care-for-the-poor-and-needy</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2014-general-conference/2014-10-3030-bishop-dean-m-davies-64k-eng.mp3" length="5559714" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Blessings of Worship</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Bishop Davies teaches us what true worship of Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ is and how we can have the blessings that accompany it.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60001311_000_56davies" doc-version="1" hash="YP5h9Q">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="NWpUM17-FE2yZtXf3ZDvPQ" hash="0zRwVQ">The Blessings of Worship</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p2" pid="swabuahoK0ampGqtdOp0lQ" hash="cBJoTw1">By Bishop Dean M. Davies</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p3" pid="c2FoDvtt6ka7o9-3wyWLHA" hash="BSOiaA">First Counselor in the Presiding Bishopric</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="4fo_MEXQuUqxmK4bWth2XA" hash="MS0KZA">Worship is essential and central to our spiritual life. It is something we should yearn for, seek out, and strive to experience.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="XjEAaUGaUUGyjw6AkutguQ" hash="cBJoTw">By Bishop Dean M. Davies</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.t1">
				<h2 pid="d5awCzZ9dUyia24drKrIJg" hash="R-4f0A">His Visit</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p6" pid="rRyVKA9JTka9oCFEE5MYew" hash="VD_bCg">One of the most remarkable and tender experiences recorded in holy scripture is the account of the visit of the Savior to people in the Americas following His death and Resurrection. The people had suffered a destruction so great that it caused “the whole earth [to become] deformed.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> The record of those events relates that following the catastrophe, all the people wept continually,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> and in the midst of their deep grief, they hungered for healing, peace, and deliverance.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p7" pid="8oclmpFVskegxBJKKT_hKg" hash="m8ZL5g">When the Savior descended from heaven, the people twice fell at His feet. The first time occurred after He pronounced, with divine authority:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p8" pid="PI8iYiYKKEuNWyt5BCPiXg" hash="20pE4g">“Behold, I am Jesus Christ, whom the prophets testified shall come into the world.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p9" pid="fZFSAOSMdkOW4kmCLnqfPQ" hash="AXB2nw">“And behold, I am the light and the life of the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p10" pid="MQFoJEC8KUySYFD2ShB7-w" hash="kYx_jQ">He then invited those present to “arise and come forth unto me, that ye may thrust your hands into my side, and also that ye may feel the prints of the nails in my hands and in my feet, that ye may know that I am the God of Israel, and the God of the whole earth, and have been slain for the sins of the world. …</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p11" pid="we3bYX7VIUaJpxl6AVC3wA" hash="einIIQ">“And when they had all gone forth and had witnessed for themselves, they did cry out with one accord, saying:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p12" pid="hbomexrQKECtrYiSYckPXA" hash="SMYxow">“Hosanna! Blessed be the name of the Most High God!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p13" pid="HEfxgbdjKEOIt7XRjP43wQ" hash="OrGS6w">And then, for a second time, “they did fall down at the feet of Jesus.” But this time with purpose, for we learn that they “did worship him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.t2">
				<h2 pid="aOwbFNOIU0eO1oMQ2cfO4Q" hash="4PK-4g">Present Day</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p15" pid="nQQ5AOOxUkWQrTI9EhVbjg" hash="tTJvEw">Earlier this year I was on assignment visiting a stake in the western United States. It was a normal Sunday, a normal meeting, with normal members of the Church. I watched as people entered the chapel and reverently moved to available seats. Last-second, whispered conversations echoed throughout the hall. Mothers and fathers tried—sometimes in vain—to quiet energetic children. Normal.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p16" pid="Vadd2bXLDkSeM7ozuqWikw" hash="BgZ-lQ">But then, before the meeting began, words inspired of the Spirit came into my mind.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p17" pid="EWxj7mqmB0miqG81_4IJbQ" hash="FiXCXw">These members had not come just to fulfill a duty or listen to speakers.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p18" pid="YiKFNczhGEKN2MVGPvwGUA" hash="5fy4Bg">They had come for a deeper and far more significant reason.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p19" pid="fQDSR8EIekyrFIDBwb2qgw" hash="BVM_bQ">They had come to worship.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p20" pid="kqMdQIhLXU2QYgPc4-X7jw" hash="RgK-Kg">As the meeting progressed, I observed various members in the congregation. They had an almost heavenly expression, an attitude of reverence and peace. Something about them warmed my heart. The experience they were having that Sunday was something quite extraordinary.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p21" pid="Q8vmBCsOJ02T4ptLa5vPag" hash="BGWHoA">They were worshipping.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p22" pid="ZCq-DobfK0uXEFq7Cdh3Cg" hash="DBaAOw">They were experiencing heaven.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p23" pid="pQtbXBMmB0KVh0GMV7UPbg" hash="RUfvYw">I could see it in their countenances.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p24" pid="ddqbR3ZSMU67w_OFVrF_fg" hash="2mAFgA">And I rejoiced and worshipped with them. And as I did so, the Spirit spoke to my heart. And on that day, I learned something about myself, about God, and about the role of true worship in our lives.</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.t3">
				<h2 pid="3dFEp49Z3U6emXwE3xyRlA" hash="w9Hlbw">Worship in Our Everyday Lives</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p26" pid="3Duxx03Z2UCcPcsuPQzwSw" hash="NROpqQ">Latter-day Saints are exceptional when it comes to serving in Church callings. But sometimes we may go about our work routinely, as though we are merely performing a job. Sometimes our attendance at meetings and our service in the kingdom may lack the holy element of worship. And without that, we are missing an incomparable spiritual encounter with the infinite—one we are entitled to as children of a loving Heavenly Father.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p27" pid="6pDMNhuQRkuMe1Kax5Z_GQ" hash="pXjl4g">Far from being an accidental, happy occurrence, worship is essential and central to our spiritual life. It is something we should yearn for, seek out, and strive to experience.</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.t4">
				<h2 pid="vgKiZ1mjtUaJWBe6na2AXA" hash="EC-Ubw">What Is Worship?</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p29" pid="Qrrj3uEIlEq1oQ5Mf9pGIA" hash="N9rObg">When we worship God, we approach Him with reverent love, humility, and adoration. We acknowledge and accept Him as our sovereign King, the Creator of the universe, our beloved and infinitely loving Father.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p30" pid="epe2rxe3sE-lrD_ZzMtbMQ" hash="ZMbrJA">We respect and revere Him.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p31" pid="JrVixR0uGkqPRJW2PMvNpA" hash="AVvn6A">We submit ourselves to Him.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p32" pid="34hHX9-NJkK_OfWZ_4EhfQ" hash="SdAAqg">We lift our hearts in mighty prayer, cherish His word, rejoice in His grace, and commit to follow Him with dedicated loyalty.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p33" pid="_QoXqQUm8UKmk5Hvtz9UTA" hash="eocsTA">Worshipping God is such an essential element in the life of a disciple of Jesus Christ that if we fail to receive Him in our hearts, we will seek for Him in vain in our councils, churches, and temples.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p34" pid="5OZ_9qWfgkSx1iOKgNx8Zw" hash="qJpU1A">True disciples are drawn to “worship him that made heaven, and earth, and the sea, and the fountains of waters—calling upon the name of the Lord day and night.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p35" pid="Vb-f-iBWcUuZHHLaOTAddQ" hash="06IzUA">We can learn much about true worship by examining how others—people who perhaps were not so different from ourselves—encountered, behaved, and worshipped in the presence of the divine.</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.t5">
				<h2 pid="J1u4y4Y4BkKvldHnIOMtPw" hash="7xDbJg">Wonder, Gratitude, and Hope</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p37" pid="w2kfruG_q0aI2ayxLKbNPg" hash="28Qolg">In the first part of the 19th century, the Christian world had all but abandoned the idea that God still spoke to man. But in the spring of 1820, that changed forever when a humble farm boy entered a grove of trees and knelt to pray. From that day on, a stream of remarkable visions, revelations, and heavenly appearances have bathed the earth, endowing its inhabitants with precious knowledge regarding the nature and purpose of God and His relationship with man.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p38" pid="wBeRuoaIhEa5vCMoFDc7bQ" hash="Y2nDiQ">Oliver Cowdery described those days as “never to be forgotten. … What joy! what wonder! what amazement!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p39" pid="Av3_KV43fkG342KpxrPc_w" hash="Fi5u_g">Oliver’s words convey the first elements that accompany true worship of the divine—a sense of majestic awe and profound thanksgiving.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p40" pid="CfXvzv6nVEaGTJkTQfBtwg" hash="oudang">Every day, but especially on the Sabbath day, we have the extraordinary opportunity to experience the wonder and awe of heaven and offer our praises to God for His blessed goodness and overwhelming mercy.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p41" pid="6m1BFfbn40CkD-pOqG51KA" hash="h8tB1g">This will lead us to hope. These are the first elements of worship.</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.t6">
				<h2 pid="zTwZkpcM1ki8gwHIhj_-Zg" hash="lezNdQ">Light, Knowledge, and Faith</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p43" pid="jFJ8l87NK0GFoXPT2p9kyg" hash="fT7NSA">On the blessed day of Pentecost, the Holy Spirit entered into the hearts and minds of the disciples of Christ, filling them with light and knowledge.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p44" pid="hWg11ZuWqUO0ytUuXAKduQ" hash="86k4Og">Until that day they were at times unsure of what they should do. Jerusalem had become a dangerous place for a follower of the Savior, and they must have wondered what would become of them.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p45" pid="HjG-50wL5kOCr39-gs94sw" hash="tm2u9Q">But when the Holy Spirit filled their hearts, doubt and reluctance vanished. Through the transcendent experience of true worship, the Saints of God received heavenly light, knowledge, and a strengthened testimony. And that led to faith.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p46" pid="_IVljahqj0GvXWMZsDOz-g" hash="vVch2A">From that moment on, the Apostles and Saints acted with determined direction. With boldness they preached Christ Jesus to all the world.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p47" pid="MAR62y2v3E2SkeQLcgq-Lg" hash="8_R_qg">When we worship in spirit, we invite light and truth into our souls, which strengthens our faith. These too are necessary elements of true worship.</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.t7">
				<h2 pid="B4Qrq9Yf80OiVjZflUQsFw" hash="LuZT9A">Discipleship and Charity</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p49" pid="1EygTtr2sUulNANSdfWqQQ" hash="LUcSkQ">In the Book of Mormon we learn that from the moment Alma the Younger was delivered from suffering the consequences of his own rebelliousness, he was never the same. He boldly “traveled throughout all the land … and among all the people … , zealously striving to repair all the injuries which [he] had done to the church.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p50" pid="brYUpta38UWculWwSTBAng" hash="e9nLqg">His constant worship of the Almighty God took the form of energetic discipleship.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p51" pid="E5ncXlxy60ah2nNNQG4k8A" hash="3NJ0qA">True worship transforms us into sincere and earnest disciples of our beloved Master and Savior, Jesus Christ. We change and become more like Him.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p52" pid="UgkKF2RYCUysMk6ufze5Ig" hash="Ni6gFg">We become more understanding and caring. More forgiving. More loving.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p53" pid="1DBf4fz850ye5uBB8rD55w" hash="wNHztA">We understand that it is impossible to say that we love God while at the same time hating, dismissing, or disregarding others around us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p54" pid="Wz_cJ8wGHESuBJERzfm1UA" hash="oRSKZQ">True worship leads to an unwavering determination to walk the path of discipleship. And that leads inevitably to charity. These too are necessary elements of worship.</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.t8">
				<h2 pid="egLQ4IzEsECfxuVqqPmbFA" hash="pPl7dg">Enter into His Gates with Thanksgiving</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p56" pid="Q2y7DtKYLEiHL2lUiivUZw" hash="9QjlSQ">When I reflect back on what began as a normal Sunday morning, in that normal meetinghouse, in that normal stake, even today I am moved by that extraordinary spiritual experience that will forever bless my life.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p57" pid="NKFk1D4600i4cjHiKkWo6w" hash="MrxaDw">I learned that even if we are exceptional managers of our time, callings, and assignments—even if we check all the boxes on our list of the “perfect” individual, family, or leader—if we fail to worship our merciful Deliverer, heavenly King, and glorious God, we are missing much of the joy and peace of the gospel.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p58" pid="JLAYr3luFEKcW_lYP_AI8A" hash="LzBS7Q">When we worship God, we acknowledge and receive Him with the same reverence as those ancient people of the Americas. We approach Him with incomprehensible feelings of wonder and awe. We marvel in gratitude at the goodness of God. And thus, we acquire hope.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p59" pid="UmYTzY7Or061hCvtN2ghpg" hash="BU4jrA">We ponder God’s word, and that fills our souls with light and truth. We comprehend spiritual vistas that can be seen only through the light of the Holy Ghost.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> And thus, we acquire faith.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p60" pid="qF46E0Jk3EaS8CKDGXQGuA" hash="MDxHEQ">As we worship, our souls are refined and we commit to walk in the footsteps of our beloved Savior, Jesus Christ. And from this resolve, we acquire charity.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p61" pid="ixgjA-HiJ0eOWYJQOgNeXg" hash="fX9d9w">When we worship, our hearts are drawn out in praise to our blessed God morning, noon, and night.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p62" pid="Cxq_iziSr0eSr7evKc7Svw" hash="Y0MACg">We hallow and honor Him continually—in our meetinghouses, homes, temples, and all our labors.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p63" pid="4SLLeNWpeEuBtJqQSmrr7w" hash="8YXYMw">When we worship, we open our hearts to the healing power of the Atonement of Jesus Christ.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p64" pid="B7fQiuWv-UaDPZmreptlTg" hash="W3h6pA">Our lives become the token and expression of our worship.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p65" pid="y6tgVzcc_k6ewxaLZXDMZw" hash="dDHosQ">My brothers and sisters, spiritual experiences have less to do with what is happening around us and everything to do with what is happening within our hearts. It is my witness that true worship will transform ordinary Church meetings into extraordinary spiritual feasts. It will enrich our lives, broaden our understanding, and strengthen our testimonies. For as we incline our hearts to God, like the ancient Psalmist, we “enter into his gates with thanksgiving, and into his courts with praise: [we are] thankful unto him, and bless his name.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p66" pid="ujlv8jrPHEWPJF_-gT8GIw" hash="ZDXxHA">“For the Lord is good; his mercy is everlasting; and his truth endureth to all generations.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p67" pid="M2t-sd88bEmXXZy-503Mbg" hash="P0825g">Through sincere and heartfelt worship, we blossom and mature in hope, faith, and charity. And through that process, we gather heavenly light into our souls that infuses our lives with divine meaning, abiding peace, and everlasting joy.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship.p68" pid="y3qW2SQd3UqHdJbv9c4q3g" hash="CaXtjQ">That is the blessing of worship in our lives. Of this I humbly testify in the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/10/the-blessings-of-worship</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2016-general-conference/2016-10-4060-dean-m-davies-64k-eng.mp3" length="5553844" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
