<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Don R. Clarke</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Don R. Clarke.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Don%20R.%20Clarke.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Don R. Clarke.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming Instruments in the Hands of God</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god?lang=eng</link>
      <description>A person does not need to have a Church calling, an invitation to help someone, or even good health to become an instrument in God’s hands.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006562_000_037" doc-version="2" hash="mbuRjA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="NIhtcBtTSky8vFtDJAnCxQ" hash="Fll-xA">Becoming Instruments in the Hands of God</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="arD73g9X70WUjMt6paSMZA" hash="yJHuSg">Don R. Clarke</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="YnC0fQLY4U-aYlBdSYtYsg" hash="q1tiYg">A person does not need to have a Church calling, an invitation to help someone, or even good health to become an instrument in God’s hands.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/ClarkeDR_06.jpg" alt="Elder Don R. Clarke" pid="dDTMVRfi-U2TK-KEY5bCwg" hash="E7rDEg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.p1" pid="tBnqbT1ZYkOZ3IpZ0Dxh-Q" hash="j7U-JA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="97"></span>My maternal grandfather, Alma Benjamin Larsen, was only 34 years old when he woke up one morning and noticed that he had problems seeing. Shortly thereafter, he lost his sight entirely. Grandfather had served a mission and been a faithful member of the Church. He was a farmer with a wife and three children, and he could not imagine life without sight. Grandfather’s wife and small children now had to bear the extra burdens of helping on the farm, and money became tight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.p2" pid="Ucxb702L6E6JdVqwQZDnjQ" hash="aOoZMQ">During this time of physical darkness, many people became instruments in God’s hands to help my blind grandfather. One experience that had a powerful impact on his family happened in 1919. It was a year of great financial difficulty for all the people in Grandfather’s town. Farms were being foreclosed, and businesses were going broke. There was a sizable mortgage on his farm, and Grandfather received a statement saying he would have to pay $195 in order to carry the mortgage over for another year. For him, paying this bill was like demanding a pound of flesh. Nearly everyone was in the same condition, and it seemed impossible to obtain that much money. If he had gathered everything that the farm produced—the horses, cows, and machinery—he could not have sold them for $195. Grandfather asked a neighbor to butcher two or three of his cows, and he sold them and some other products. He had extended credit to his neighbors with the understanding that they would pay at the end of the year, but none of his debtors was able to pay him. The economic situation for his family was bleak.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.p3" pid="lCdO-FbuP0-rTK9CQBUvIQ" hash="4zxXGg">In his journal, Grandfather recounts: “I shall never forget that cold evening, just before Christmas of 1919. It looked as though we would lose the farm. My daughter, Gladys, laid a slip of paper in my hand and said, ‘This came in the mail today.’ I took it to her mother and asked her what it was. This is what my wife read to me, ‘Dear Brother Larsen, I’ve had you on my mind all day today. I am wondering if you are in financial trouble. If you are, I have $200 you may have.’ The letter was signed ‘Jim Drinkwater.’ Jim was a small, crippled man, and he would have been the last man on earth that anyone would have thought had that much money on hand. I went to his house that night and he said, ‘Brother Larsen, I received a wireless message from heaven this morning, and I could not get you off my mind all day. I was sure you were in financial trouble.’ Brother Drinkwater gave me $200 and we sent the $195 to the mortgage company, and with the extra $5 we bought boots and clothes for the children. Santa Claus did come that year.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.p4" pid="gIscr3jQeE6OV4tSMjGlDw" hash="ND7KZQ">My grandfather then goes on to bear his testimony: “The Lord has never let me down. He has touched the hearts of others as He touched the heart of Brother Drinkwater. I bear witness that the only safety and security that I have ever found has come through trying to keep the commandments of the Lord and upholding and sustaining the authorities of this Church.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.p5" pid="i5LADMQUyECirKtIo6rUyw" hash="eiEdtg">I have thought about Jim Drinkwater many times and wondered how he came to be one that the Lord could trust. Jim was a little, crippled man that God trusted to help a blind farmer with a heavy mortgage and three children. I have learned a great deal from my grandfather’s experience with Jim Drinkwater. I have learned that a person does not need to have a Church calling, an invitation to help <span class="pageBreak" page-number="98"></span>someone, or even good health to become an instrument in God’s hands. How then do you and I become instruments in God’s hands? The prophets and the scriptures teach us how.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.p6" pid="HiR2c7-KSEWhN6AFvYsG3Q" hash="tKi78w">First of all, we must have love for God’s children. When the lawyer asked the Savior, “Master, which is the great commandment?” the Savior replied:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.p7" pid="GfLMbPj6WkCGlaWBEHD32A" hash="aZeI9w">“Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.p8" pid="A8_y6x_4nUGtaoV6tyCMgA" hash="pLnaTg">“This is the first and great commandment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.p9" pid="4OINy1JBvUiYKwwGZhmQHw" hash="lhrsxg">“And the second is like unto it, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.36-39" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 22:36–39</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.p10" pid="VO_qRy27_0KyNcSBdnC9Dg" hash="7Ch8gQ">Joseph F. Smith said: “Charity, or love, is the greatest principle in existence. If we can lend a helping hand to the oppressed, if we can aid those who are despondent and in sorrow, if we can uplift and ameliorate the condition of mankind, it is our mission to do it, it is an essential part of our religion to do it” (in Conference Report, Apr. 1917, 4). When we feel love for God’s children, we are given opportunities to help them in their journey back to His presence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.p11" pid="_IgsdnW43ESOjmcGhSshag" hash="d6MVTA">The missionary experiences of the sons of Mosiah also help us understand how to become instruments in God’s hands. “And it came to pass that they journeyed many days in the wilderness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/17.9" class="scriptureRef">Alma 17:9</a>). We must be willing to journey. The sons of Mosiah were willing to step outside their surroundings and do that which was uncomfortable. Had Ammon not been willing to journey into a foreign land, inhabited by a wild and a hardened and a ferocious people, he never would have found and helped Lamoni and his father, and many Lamanites may have never learned about Jesus Christ. God has asked us to journey, go on missions, accept callings, invite someone to church, or help someone in need.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.p12" pid="NPfrdLppAkuomAXhy0VKVg" hash="be9vgw">In their pursuit to help their Lamanite brothers, the sons of Mosiah also learned the importance of fasting and prayer: “They fasted much and prayed much that the Lord would grant unto them a portion of his Spirit to go with them, and abide with them, that they might be an instrument in the hands of God to bring, if it were possible, their brethren, the Lamanites, to the knowledge of the truth” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/17.9" class="scriptureRef">Alma 17:9</a>). Do we really want to be instruments in God’s hands? If so, our desire will permeate our prayers and be the focus of our fasts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.p13" pid="OOm2voCNn0OGLwh8rO9g_g" hash="Gh6dUQ">After losing his eyesight, my grandfather fasted and prayed that if he was to remain in darkness, the Lord would give him peace. He states that almost within the hour “my mind was enlightened and the cloud of darkness had lifted from me.” He could see again, not with physical eyes, but spiritual eyes. Later, Alma Benjamin Larsen was called to be a patriarch, where he served for 32 years. Like the sons of Mosiah, my grandfather fasted and prayed, and as a result, he was given the opportunity to bless thousands of God’s children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.p14" pid="piVwnI6MME-OVmggUEZ6lA" hash="2tpI9Q">We, like Jim Drinkwater and my grandfather, also need to be receptive <span class="pageBreak" page-number="99"></span>to the promptings of the Holy Ghost, for when we desire to be an instrument in the hands of God, we can receive revelation. The prophet Alma the Younger tells us of revelations that he received: “I know that which the Lord hath commanded me, and I glory in it … yea, and this is my glory, that perhaps I may be an instrument in the hands of God to bring some soul to repentance; and this is my joy” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/29.9" class="scriptureRef">Alma 29:9</a>). Alma had received revelation of what to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.p15" pid="Qejzmvd_wUaithCer18ddw" hash="hqVwDw">I have a little book that I carry with me, where I record the inspiration and thoughts that I receive from the Spirit. It does not look like much, and it becomes worn out and needs to be replaced from time to time. As thoughts come to my mind, I write them down and then I try to do them. I have found that many times, as I have done something on my list, my action was the answer to someone’s prayer. There have also been those times that I didn’t do something on my list, and I have found out later that there was someone I could have helped, but I didn’t. When we receive promptings regarding God’s children, if we write down the thoughts and inspiration we receive and then obey it, God’s confidence in us increases and we are given more opportunities to be instruments in His hands.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.p16" pid="8bXmlQN0cUyntRJ2xmgEvQ" hash="vAreyw">In the words of President Faust: “You can be powerful instruments in the hands of God to help bring about this great work. … You can do something for another person that no one else ever born can do” (“Instruments in the Hands of God,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 2005, 115). God treasures those who help His children. I invite all of us to follow the counsel of the prophets and become instruments in the hands of God and be among His treasures because we have helped His children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god.p17" pid="6TzRivlwQEKsLaqJOx-XyQ" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/10/becoming-instruments-in-the-hands-of-god</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2006-general-conference/2006-10-5050-elder-don-r-clarke-64k-eng.mp3" length="4682745" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blessings of the Sacrament</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We will be blessed as we feel gratitude for the Atonement of Jesus Christ, renew our baptismal covenants, feel forgiveness, and receive inspiration from the Holy Ghost.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10491_000_56clarke" doc-version="2" hash="p7tKyA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="DB5BEAeQr0G4JrTsq52jMA" hash="6-Mq5Q">Blessings of the Sacrament</h1><p class="authorName" pid="nXPANItayk6hcOTVU2z-4A" hash="qEYxjw">By Elder Don R. Clarke</p><p class="kicker" pid="huFMccKwTUSmr7uu8d8XIQ" hash="xgLV1g">We will be blessed as we feel gratitude for the Atonement of Jesus Christ, renew our baptismal covenants, feel forgiveness, and receive inspiration from the Holy Ghost.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" pid="sOqZK12iwUmdESFLQWcb9g" hash="JAF8oQ">
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p5" pid="VNgh0slLiU6GGOmuu00MDw" hash="TwjG-Q">
      <span class="pageBreak" page-number="104"></span>I grew up in Rexburg, Idaho, where I was influenced and taught by a wonderful family, friends, teachers, and leaders. There are special experiences in the lives of all of us that touch our souls and make things different forever. One such experience happened in my youth. This experience transformed my life.</p>
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p6" pid="GIAAdA1MckeWaciwU0MSXA" hash="Y4BL9Q">I was always active in the Church and progressed through the Aaronic Priesthood. When I was a teenager, Brother Jacob, my teacher, asked that I write down on a card what I had thought about during the sacrament. I took my card and began to write. First on the list was a basketball game we had won the night before. And then came a date after the game, and so went the list. Far removed and certainly not in bold letters was the name of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p7" pid="Npw6RgxqVEmLHXzsjf1b6w" hash="Hb8UjA">Each Sunday the card was filled out. For a young Aaronic Priesthood holder, the sacrament and sacrament meeting took on a new, expanded, and spiritual meaning. I anxiously looked forward to Sundays and to the opportunity to partake of the sacrament, as understanding the Savior’s Atonement was changing me. Every Sunday to this day, as I partake of the sacrament, I can see my card and review my list. Always on my list now, first of all, is the Savior of mankind.</p>
    </span>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p8" pid="rGPqY499x0Gu1MIShBHD6Q" hash="j-qROw">In the New Testament we read of the time that the Savior and His Apostles met in an upper room for the Feast of the Passover.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p9" pid="1ZEF9ZlEkU63dEZQ_v_xxA" hash="WtQVFA">“And he took bread, and gave thanks, and brake it, and gave unto them, saying, This is my body which is given for you: <span class="emphasis">this do in remembrance of me.</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p10" pid="F6xtIOl2RkWMwMHkPlEY7Q" hash="GZ9iYQ">“Likewise also the cup after supper, saying, This cup is the new testament in my blood, <span class="emphasis">which is shed for you.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p11" pid="Dt4eOuGTfk2VSKKtkmxb4A" hash="M7tzXQ">Jesus also instituted the ordinance of the sacrament during His visit to the Nephites.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> I have come to know the importance of these two events.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p12" pid="xtha5I8s5kufB_3GnaLTrA" hash="bDoc-g">President David O. McKay said, “I feel impressed to emphasize what the Lord has designated as the most important meeting in the Church, and that is the sacrament meeting.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> If we properly prepare for the sacrament, we can transform our lives. I would like to suggest five principles that can bless our lives as we partake of the sacrament worthily.</p>
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.t1" pid="UuepE8uJqEmGsnvMQAOjnw" hash="lOCg_A">
      <h2 class="title" pid="4tvWfS47w0ik2AG-mPqWgw" hash="7qhgZA">I. Have a Feeling of Gratitude for the Atonement of Jesus Christ</h2>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p14" pid="N-miORmI_UOQdqJa59Ehog" hash="QEQoVA">The first principle is to have a feeling of gratitude to Heavenly Father during the sacrament for the Atonement of His Son. The following story is told about passing the sacrament:</p>
      <span class="story">
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p15" pid="SmbyrJRBjkONN1PMhxa_7A" hash="xT3Auw">“The sacrament never really meant much to me until the Sunday I was ordained a deacon. That afternoon I passed the sacrament for the first time. Prior to the meeting, one of the deacons warned me, ‘Look out for Brother Schmidt. You may have to wake him up!’ Finally the time came for me to participate in the passing of the sacrament. I handled the first six rows quite well. Children and adults partook of the bread with no noticeable thought or problem. Then I got to row seven, the row where Brother Schmidt always sat. But I was surprised. Instead of being asleep he was wide awake. Unlike many of the others I had served, he took the bread with what seemed to be great thought and reverence.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p16" pid="P-Rx-3_sEkqoeAKHcYishg" hash="grUifw">“A few minutes later I found myself again approaching row seven with the water. This time my friend was right. Brother Schmidt sat with his head bowed and his big German eyes shut. He was evidently sound asleep. What could I do or say? I looked for a moment at his brow, wrinkled and worn from years of toil and hardship. He had joined the Church as a teenager and had experienced much persecution in his small German town. I had heard the story many times in testimony meeting. I decided finally to gently nudge his shoulder in hopes of waking him. As I reached to do so, his head slowly lifted. There were tears streaming down his cheeks and as I looked into his eyes I saw love and joy. He quietly reached up and took the water. Even though I was only twelve then, I can still remember vividly the <span class="pageBreak" page-number="105"></span>feeling I had as I watched this rugged old man partake of the sacrament. I knew without a doubt that he was feeling something about the sacrament that I had never felt. I determined then that I wanted to feel those same feelings.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      </span>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p17" pid="h8GwALtJVUyDHr9pcthaNA" hash="Y-aHdQ">Brother Schmidt had communicated with heaven, and heaven had communicated with him.</p>
    </div>
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.t2">
      <h2 class="title" pid="Zei-t1A1AkaHQ1touSb2SA" hash="gspuIA">II. Remember That We Are Renewing Baptismal Covenants</h2>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p19" pid="SuRUfyStyUSQJXVfrAG1IQ" hash="bYUlEA">The second principle is to remember that we are renewing our baptismal covenants as we partake of the sacrament. Some of the promises that we make, as recorded in the scriptures, include:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p20" pid="f1wImZihCk2F9OFdxM-XTA" hash="IgBmvg">“Come into the fold of God, and to be called his people, … to bear one another’s burdens, … to mourn with those that mourn … , and to stand as witnesses of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p21" pid="O6xZrWecY0qidbLHkBJ0RA" hash="4nnmGA">“Come forth with broken hearts and contrite spirits, … willing to take upon them the name of Jesus Christ, having a determination to serve him to the end,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> and to keep His commandments and always remember Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p22" pid="cSBJE3PX8EGCblHsBdnJxg" hash="FhC9TQ">The sacramental prayers are a reminder of these covenants. When we partake of the sacrament, we renew our commitment to live up to these covenants. I believe it would be appropriate to memorize the sacramental prayers in our minds and in our hearts. This will help us focus on renewing our baptismal covenants. Whether we were 8 or 80 years old when we were baptized, I hope we will never forget that day and the covenants we made.</p>
    </div>
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.t3">
      <h2 class="title" pid="wKR8li6PYUecIA5B2-HBDw" hash="PwBbyw">III. During the Sacrament We Can Feel Forgiven of Our Sins</h2>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p24" pid="ODFimbOcWkaBmiGN8MYOag" hash="HR_Xdg">Thirdly, during the sacrament we can feel forgiven of our sins. If we have spent time before sacrament meeting repenting of our sins, we can leave sacrament meeting feeling clean and pure. President Boyd K. Packer said: “The sacrament renews the process of forgiveness. Every Sunday when the sacrament is served, that is a ceremony to renew the process of forgiveness. … Every Sunday you cleanse yourself so that, in due time, when you die your spirit will be clean.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Partaking of the sacrament worthily can help us feel like the people of King Benjamin, who “were <span class="emphasis">filled with joy,</span> having received a <span class="emphasis">remission of their sins, and having peace of conscience.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
    </div>
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.t4">
      <h2 class="title" pid="KQCWQaErmE2dQEvxSRaMKA" hash="zp8-RA">IV. We Can Receive Inspiration for Solutions to Our Problems</h2>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p26" pid="4HKlypOTqUmdXIYv36y66g" hash="TUQjZw">The fourth principle is that we can receive inspiration for solutions to our problems during sacrament meeting. When I was a mission president in Bolivia, my wife, Mary Anne, and I had the blessing of attending a mission presidents’ seminar with President Henry B. Eyring. In that meeting he taught that there are three important ways to prepare to benefit from a meeting. We should come with our problems, humble as children ready to learn, and with the desire to help God’s children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p27" pid="Fsjjr0Fu8kuFdGU8_Ronww" hash="N_fkgg">As we humbly come to sacrament meeting, we can be blessed to feel impressions for solutions to our daily problems. We must come prepared, be willing to listen, and not be distracted. In the scriptures we read, “But, behold, I say unto you, that you must <span class="emphasis">study it out</span> in your mind; then you must <span class="emphasis">ask me if it be right,</span> and if it is right I will cause that your <span class="emphasis">bosom shall burn</span> within you; therefore, <span class="emphasis">you shall feel that it is right.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> We can know what we should do to solve our problems.</p>
    </div>
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.t5">
      <h2 class="title" pid="saVbW7SvUkGbfzRbSSyLTw" hash="CIXKzQ">V. Partaking of the Sacrament Worthily Will Help Us Be Filled with the Holy Ghost</h2>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p29" pid="sIW0KzIKn0aMiS6bzdPhNQ" hash="DY1sRA">The fifth principle, partaking of the sacrament worthily, will help us be filled with the Holy Ghost. Upon instituting the sacrament during His visit to the Nephites, Jesus stated, “He that <span class="pageBreak" page-number="106"></span>eateth this bread eateth of my body to his soul; and he that drinketh of this wine drinketh of my blood to his soul; and his soul shall never hunger nor thirst, but shall be filled.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> They had been promised that if they hungered and thirsted after righteousness, they would be filled with the Holy Ghost. The sacramental prayer also promises that if we live up to our covenants, we will always have His Spirit to be with us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p30" pid="QAcpK23XS0ml_yrYiwlZZA" hash="egTVZw">Elder Melvin J. Ballard said: “I am a witness that there is a spirit attending the administration of the sacrament that warms the soul from head to foot; you feel the wounds of the spirit being healed, and the load being lifted. Comfort and happiness come to the soul that is worthy and truly desirous of partaking of this spiritual food.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
    </div>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament.p31" pid="LvnGbMGnbU60Roa15IlBwg" hash="8uEQAQ">We will be blessed as we feel gratitude for the Atonement of Jesus Christ, renew our baptismal covenants, feel forgiveness, and receive inspiration from the Holy Ghost as we partake of the sacrament each week. It will always be a great sacrament meeting if the sacrament is the center of our worship. I express my gratitude for the Atonement of Jesus Christ. I know He lives. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2012/10/blessings-of-the-sacrament</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2012-general-conference/2012-10-5060-elder-don-r-clarke-64k-eng.mp3" length="4720962" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
