<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Donald L. Staheli</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Donald L. Staheli.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Donald%20L.%20Staheli.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Donald L. Staheli.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Apr 1998 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 1998 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Obedience—Life’s Great Challenge</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Lord recognizes that many of us tend to stray from His counsel when all is going well with us, yet when trouble comes we seek after Him and His blessings.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_98905_000_034" doc-version="2" hash="0JIrWg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="SlkmfFhtM06_o5U6_t5VnQ" hash="plF6YA">Obedience—</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="gqhqz3OdQU6MGqQycFj-Bg" hash="ymsqTA">Life’s Great Challenge</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ynlj9U4fLEqJQ7jAksv6zA" hash="jaqdiA">Donald L. Staheli</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="W1wwv5AGk0mR0sb7jQqbgQ" hash="MhZtBQ">The Lord recognizes that many of us tend to stray from His counsel when all is going well with us, yet when trouble comes we seek after Him and His blessings.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1d62.jpg" alt="Elder Donald L. Staheli" pid="2MGzl1X_MUyUWmRQezJ-Gw" hash="0CnQXw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge.p1" pid="E2rdyaJvM0i5BlOPF6W-ZA" hash="cxMlOw">My brothers and sisters, I am humbled and grateful for the calling which brings me before you today. I am blessed with a wonderful wife and family. I am buoyed up by the strength of the Brethren with whom it is now my blessing to serve. But most importantly, I cherish my testimony and my relationship with my Savior. I bear personal witness that He lives and He leads His Church through our beloved prophet and president, Gordon B. Hinckley.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge.p2" pid="5qGf78bYIEyXSueQjRnfEA" hash="5yFpTA">As I have made my transition this past year from the corporate world of business to that of trying to be a faithful full-time servant of our Father in Heaven and an especial witness of Jesus Christ, it has been a very tender experience for me. It has made me more sensitive to the responsibility, the blessings, and the opportunities that the gospel affords each of us if we will be obedient to its principles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge.p3" pid="Lhnqb-NInU-9NzTs47mQ9Q" hash="J1kRYw">President Boyd K. Packer has stated on a number of occasions that “we all have the right to inspiration and direction by the Spirit of the Holy Ghost.” And then he adds, “We all live far below our privileges.” As I have pondered the implications of his statement, it becomes clear that many of us are missing some spiritual opportunities and blessings by letting “the things that should matter most in life be at the mercy of the things that matter least.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge.p4" pid="ByoVE-I06kSRdqZYjKUW0w" hash="CAC7Pg">If any one of us were asked what is most important in life, most of us would quickly respond, “Our families and the opportunities the gospel affords us to be celestial families—together forever.” Yet the pressures of everyday living frequently and subtly move us away from that pursuit which we so proudly proclaim. And in the process the priorities that should really matter most to us become captive to those things that, while seemingly important at the moment, have little or no relevance to our long-term goal. And in many cases, the temptations and pressures to pursue the less-important matters lead us down the wrong paths of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge.p5" pid="9q0aOszalk2m-HWuMlFTTg" hash="UUrn6g">President Spencer W. Kimball warned us, “The cares of the world are so many and so entangling, even very good people are diverted from following the truth because they care too much for the things of the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge.p6" pid="wgTrkIeK1UCB9DZa7i2xkA" hash="SQ2Urw">While I have had my share of lessons on obedience during my life, one of the most memorable was taught to me as a young boy by my dog and my mother. When I was about eight years of age, my father brought home a puppy which I promptly named Spot. We became the greatest of pals as I tried to teach him a few tricks and obedience to my commands. He learned well, except he could not conquer an overwhelming desire to chase and bark at cars as they came down the dusty street by our home in our small southern Utah town. As hard as I tried, I could not break Spot of his bad habit. One day a neighbor came speeding by in his large truck. He knew Spot and he knew Spot’s bad habit. This time, just as Spot approached the truck in his usual aggressive manner, this man swerved toward Spot, running over him with the rear wheel of his truck.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge.p7" pid="dkNdZ_gbi0-V_EUWRvUQoA" hash="qy_dQg">With tears streaming down my face, I cradled Spot in my arms and ran to the house, calling to my mother and brother for help. As we washed the blood from his head, it soon became apparent that Spot’s disobedient act had dealt him a fatal blow. As the burial of Spot was completed and the tears dried, my mother then taught me one of the great lessons of life as she explained the principle of obedience and its application in my life. She made clear that seemingly small acts of disobedience can result in longer-term consequences of unhappiness, regrets, and even fatal results.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge.p8" pid="ikywuRxKs060uM3jy6koSg" hash="ofHXiw">As we grow in the gospel, we learn the value of obedience to principles which will consistently align us with the teachings of our Savior and prophets. As we are obedient to their teachings, we then begin to understand what the Savior meant when He said, “For whosoever will save his life shall lose it: and whosoever will lose his life for my sake shall find it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge.p9" pid="8-EIbgicMUerGiFjU_q72w" hash="OvCAAQ">Since we each have periodic challenges of obedience, we can take heart in President Hinckley’s encouragement “that the Lord will not give us commandments beyond our power to observe. He will not ask us to do things for which we lack … capacity.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge.p10" pid="4jNB0TG4_02lx3CVHNv6Jg" hash="cfk0eQ">All of us, but especially you young people, would do well to remember the prophet’s counsel as you are tempted by the peer pressures of your everyday world. As we mature into young adults and beyond, setting priorities and managing pressures between work, Church, and family is a balancing act that requires continual reevaluation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge.p11" pid="9ekMMgZ7YkK4CwEUWFX0pA" hash="xz5sdQ">Periodically one might well ask, “If I continue to travel the road I am currently following, where will it lead me and what will happen to my family?” Are we establishing the foundation for an eternal family, or are we focusing more on the pride of personal accomplishments and a collection of temporal trophies that are taking precedence over the things that should really matter most?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge.p12" pid="qJ62IHXTZkyAO5ys2dUOVQ" hash="9Lc8KQ">Regardless of our age and stage in life, daily obedience to gospel principles is the only sure way to eternal happiness. President Ezra Taft Benson put it most poignantly when he said, “When obedience ceases to be an irritant and becomes our quest, in that moment God will endow us with power.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge.p13" pid="e7FLkqFErEm86inFZEZBkQ" hash="brvTvw">The Book of Mormon is a continual saga of the various people whose obedience ebbed and flowed with the times. The result of their disobedience is clear. The wake-up calls they received are just as applicable to each of us today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge.p14" pid="v8h9bAtTqECzr9m3-PhNiQ" hash="m6IaEg">The scriptures make it clear the Lord recognizes that many of us tend to stray from His counsel when all is going well with us, yet when trouble comes we seek after Him and His blessings. He has also warned us about the consequences of our straying: “And my people must needs be chastened until they learn obedience, if it must needs be, by the things which they suffer.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge.p15" pid="uFDxN1InR0mxgrpwNIzdaA" hash="FxBqXg">Whether we are being chastened or challenged as we are being tossed to and fro on the seas of life, obedience to the teachings of our Savior and prophets will qualify us for King Benjamin’s great promise to those that keep God’s commandments: “For behold, they are blessed in all things, both temporal and spiritual; and if they hold out faithful to the end they are received into heaven, that thereby they may dwell with God in a state of never-ending happiness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge.p16" pid="L2ryDzavBEG-SzkHS7InjA" hash="xdpSeQ">To the Savior’s call “Come, follow me”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> or to His admonition “If ye love me, keep my commandments,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> our response should be clear and unequivocal. As we are obedient to His call, it is my testimony that we will enjoy His love and His peace in our lives. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1998/04/obedience-lifes-great-challenge</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1998-general-conference/1998-04-5050-elder-donald-l-staheli-64k-eng.mp3" length="3880159" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 1998 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing Our Testimonies</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Frequently reading, pondering, and applying the lessons of the scriptures, combined with prayer, become an irreplaceable part of gaining and sustaining a strong, vibrant testimony.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030208_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="xWPZpw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="erxDGJwiDkeaP0b62jnakw" hash="-cehdQ">Securing Our Testimonies</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="eOKE6xAM40OVJXUxgsdSUg" hash="jaqdiA">Donald L. Staheli</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="55dnxnxPJ0eINjZfp1ZjHQ" hash="jofHwQ">Frequently reading, pondering, and applying the lessons of the scriptures, combined with prayer, become an irreplaceable part of gaining and sustaining a strong, vibrant testimony.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-643.jpg" alt="Elder Donald L. Staheli" pid="zEaZASlBjESl-1nntKgGtQ" hash="P0tqlw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p1" pid="DG8uXw8QH0WJ1qjzpTJ18w" hash="JIm3QQ">Recently I had an engaging conversation with a young man who was contemplating a mission. As we talked, it became apparent that he was struggling with his decision, because he was questioning the strength of his testimony of the gospel of Jesus Christ. He wanted to know why he had not received more clear answers to his prayers and study of the scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p2" pid="LvyDH_tI6k-1RdYkcm0edQ" hash="w7uxag">This young man, whom I will call Jim, was raised in the mission field in a home with loving parents who were doing their best to teach gospel principles to their children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p3" pid="gcdY5FnzUEWfIueEGaoT5g" hash="blIOGw">He is an outstanding athlete and popular among his friends at school. However, he is only one of a very few LDS students in a large high school.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p4" pid="GAdoT35fWESRsxHi3OrZNw" hash="vmrwAA">Having raised my family in the mission field, I quickly related to Jim’s challenges of wanting to stay true to gospel principles while being accepted by good friends, yet friends whose values and beliefs generally differed from his.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p5" pid="-TGU5dPlT0-cf7kplDKNAw" hash="2haISQ">He was looking for further confirmation of his testimony of Jesus Christ and the Restoration of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p6" pid="hn6XBipX8EqauIH23s_kGA" hash="yoxbYQ">Today I speak to Jim and many others like him—young men and young women across the world who are unsure about their testimonies but very much want to develop strong, vibrant testimonies that will guide them through the shoals of life that lie ahead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p7" pid="Pdubt6pG8UyajsbitHnRdg" hash="iDjfhw">I also speak to those adults who have not yet felt deeply the spirit of the gospel in their lives. In the absence of a compelling testimony, some have let their daily thoughts and actions become so focused on the things of the world that they have minimized the influence of the light of the gospel in their everyday lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p8" pid="cMfGpsrmSUif4xmsiP8TDA" hash="h5Q_QA">And then as Elder Neal A. Maxwell has so eloquently described, also included are those “‘honorable’ members who are skimming over the surface instead of deepening their discipleship and who are casually engaged rather than ‘anxiously engaged’ (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.75" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:75</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.27" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:27</a>)” (in Conference Report, Oct. 1992, 89; or <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1992, 65).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p9" pid="enbUf2kPyEWIv4XVZr9-Ag" hash="9dQuLw">As I attended the funeral services of Elder Neal A. Maxwell and Elder David B. Haight and listened to their well-deserved tributes, I more fully internalized the extraordinary examples of testimony and discipleship that the lives of these two great brethren demonstrated. I kept pondering how their examples could help strengthen our testimonies and deepen our resolve to come closer to Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p10" pid="S0wd5xN_dk2bBb8KK6kKNA" hash="HsNZNg">These two great disciples of Christ exemplify President Gordon B. Hinckley’s admonition to all of us when he said: “I have been quoted as saying, ‘Do the best you can.’ But I want to emphasize that it be the very best. We are too prone to be satisfied with mediocre performance. We are capable of doing so much better” (“Standing Strong and Immovable,” <span class="emphasis">Worldwide Leadership Training Meeting,</span> 10 Jan. 2004, 21).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p11" pid="HiW4HNm7VUOHTNB5xeh6-A" hash="vDD2Yg">Surely President Hinckley’s counsel and encouragement applies as much to the development and strengthening of our testimonies of Jesus Christ as to anything else.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p12" pid="7cOGJSGpAkCN-iwmVH2OOw" hash="S2w_4g">True testimonies bring the light of the restored gospel of Jesus Christ into our lives and focus all of us toward the same goal of returning to our Father in Heaven—yet our individual testimonies come through varied experiences and at different stages in our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p13" pid="3bhyRTFbl0uaVk8tHnxyhw" hash="ORff6w">Like Jim, as a young man I was privileged to have “goodly parents” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/1.1" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 1:1</a>). They taught gospel principles and values to our family by precept and example. As a young boy I thought I had a testimony. I believed! Then came some personal spiritual experiences through faith, prayer, scripture study, and especially father’s blessings in our home that caused me to think more seriously about the principles I had been taught and believed—but even more deeply about what I was beginning to feel. I will be forever grateful to parents who helped coach me through those precious spiritual experiences. They have had a lasting impact on me and on the strength of my testimony.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p14" pid="kAxyd-5Tkki-Vmoiqj6dTQ" hash="sv6Smg">I think Alma must have had us in mind as he was teaching the Zoramites how to gain testimonies of the truth:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p15" pid="cD4v5qFMVUmzvXOneE4LZA" hash="fTNAWQ">“But behold, if ye will awake and arouse your faculties, even to an experiment upon my words, and exercise a particle of faith, yea, even if ye can no more than desire to believe, let this desire work in you, even until ye believe in a manner that ye can give place for a portion of my words” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.27" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:27</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p16" pid="80Ii-jCzAEuGNgPJlBgJpw" hash="0hkb8w">Alma then went on to “compare the word unto a seed.” He explained that as hearts are opened, “it will begin to swell within your breasts” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.28" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:28</a>). Alma then gave us the key to developing a successful testimony:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p17" pid="P56znN4LJ0CYk5xy-sgUaQ" hash="XRRKwA">“But if ye will nourish the word, yea, nourish the tree as it beginneth to grow, by your faith with great diligence, and with patience, looking forward to the fruit thereof, it shall take root; and behold it shall be a tree springing up unto everlasting life” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.41" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:41</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p18" pid="J0Tv1nUqakewtRr29DwREw" hash="sZ1-vA">And then the promise!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p19" pid="H54-5ZJ7T0GBvZyINH0aLQ" hash="eclqaA">“Then, my brethren, ye shall reap the rewards of your faith, and your diligence, and patience, and long-suffering, waiting for the tree to bring forth fruit unto you” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.43" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:43</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p20" pid="iJJIz4b1-EiAlFnmD8gjHw" hash="lqSb0A">Think with me for a moment, brothers and sisters, about what Alma is teaching us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p21" pid="XVfN_goxIk2lwdRiL46nrQ" hash="syFArQ">First, we must have a sincere <span class="emphasis">desire</span> to believe. Phrases such <span class="emphasis">as “awake,” “arouse your faculties,” “experiment,”</span> and <span class="emphasis">“exercise a particle of faith”</span> are action words that suggest sustained effort on our part.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p22" pid="xaaD0wm3PEqD_FfQP_RKGA" hash="K-KfPA">His description of the swelling in our breast describes the feeling of the Holy Spirit. And as Moroni promises, “By the power of the Holy Ghost ye may know the truth of all things” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.5" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p23" pid="AJfF_Jobwkyq4WV5QpGEcw" hash="vWGNgw">To keep that Spirit growing, Alma says we must nourish it by “faith with great diligence, and with patience.” He then promises that the rewards of faith, diligence, patience, and long-suffering will bring forth everlasting life (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.41" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:41</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.43" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:43</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p24" pid="8xl7-XYJfk2nQVXTPAeHAQ" hash="V2q2Pw">Like Alma, latter-day prophets have been clear in their teachings of the things we need to do to develop and strengthen our testimonies.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p25" pid="5e_qH9_ZR0u-5BHuypS2Eg" hash="_zhqIA">We have been sent here to work out our individual salvation through the tests and challenges of daily life. We cannot do that by relying heavily upon the borrowed light of someone else’s testimony. As we receive inspiration when we hear prophets, leaders, and peers bear their testimonies, those spiritual feelings should further enhance our desire to strengthen our own convictions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p26" pid="p6pOgYs75ECcXwGmUlmUwg" hash="WrNjiQ">To my young friend, and to all wherever you may be, never give up on the Lord. The answer to your prayers may not be as clear or as timely as you would like, but keep praying. The Lord is listening! As you pray, ask for help in understanding the promptings of the Holy Spirit. And then do your very best to be worthy to receive those promptings. As you recognize or feel the impressions and whisperings of the Spirit, then act upon them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p27" pid="kQW52cMYZEm-uzv_jT2eAA" hash="EeEoNw">Daily fervent prayers seeking forgiveness and special help and direction are essential to our lives and the nourishment of our testimonies. When we become hurried, repetitive, casual, or forgetful in our prayers, we tend to lose the closeness of the Spirit, which is so essential in the continual direction we need to successfully manage the challenges of our everyday lives. Family prayer every morning and night adds additional blessings and power to our individual prayers and to our testimonies.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p28" pid="SdhJpUnOZUqYBbwRYOgQjA" hash="fRtEzA">Personal, sincere involvement in the scriptures produces faith, hope, and solutions to our daily challenges. Frequently reading, pondering, and applying the lessons of the scriptures, combined with prayer, become an irreplaceable part of gaining and sustaining a strong, vibrant testimony.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p29" pid="ts3d6kLThEWXgvQd2XT_5A" hash="Ocqheg">President Spencer W. Kimball reminded us of the importance of consistent scripture reading when he said, “I find that when I get casual in my relationships with divinity and when it seems … no divine voice is speaking, … if I immerse myself in the scriptures the distance narrows and the spirituality returns” (<span class="emphasis">The Teachings of Spencer W. Kimball,</span> ed. Edward L. Kimball [1982], 135).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p30" pid="pNo3OJUHfEm_T4SU3jHmAA" hash="jKJ9Og">The Savior taught, “Search the scriptures; for in them ye think ye have eternal life: and they are they which testify of me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.39" class="scriptureRef">John 5:39</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p31" pid="8Psvh7e91UWtln4sT8TaXw" hash="OFmsFA">The strong, unwavering testimonies that so many of you wonderful, faithful members of the Church embrace have come from prayerfully following counsel from our prophets and the scriptures. That same priceless blessing is available to each of us who earnestly seek it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p32" pid="2Zm-lvSZnkuYrGWbx6I-hg" hash="MAwrIw">To my young friend Jim, and all others who may have periodic concerns about the strength of their testimonies, know that you are loved and watched over daily by your Father in Heaven. He will respond as you strive to keep His commandments and reach out for His loving hand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p33" pid="o24oTJLM4kCTXvIblTbbEA" hash="MjHJAg">We all share the same promise that the Lord gave to the Prophet Joseph Smith: “Draw near unto me and I will draw near unto you; seek me diligently and ye shall find me; ask, and ye shall receive; knock, and it shall be opened unto you” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.63" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:63</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p34" pid="J2W15AZfGEGYp7kdd6DQQw" hash="To3HxQ">Our prophet’s call to do our “very best” challenges each of us, individually and within our families, to carefully examine our personal lives and then commit to change those things which will more fully assure our testimonies are strong and secure.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p35" pid="mz6CNipMYEKLmlJCo8srOg" hash="kOC7xw">Strong testimonies become the driving force for each of us to do “much better.” They become the impenetrable bulwark of armor that protects us from the unrelenting things of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p36" pid="pPrMM9o4GEOFBFeXlPbK0w" hash="CK3UjA">I bear my witness that we have a loving, caring Father in Heaven and that He and His Beloved Son, Jesus Christ, appeared to the boy Joseph to usher in the Restoration of the gospel in this last dispensation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p37" pid="iOsF9-9DJku7w-fRTB_jKQ" hash="qJ-gTw">Jesus Christ heads this Church. President Gordon B. Hinckley is His chosen prophet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies.p38" pid="LffDAUR7oEGCjxy-ZaJPIg" hash="Qq5mhg">May we have the courage and the conviction to follow the prophet’s counsel. As we do so, our personal testimonies will be secure. That this may be so I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2004/10/securing-our-testimonies</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2004-general-conference/2004-10-2070-elder-donald-l-staheli-64k-eng.mp3" length="5087399" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2004 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
