<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Donald L. Hallstrom</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Donald L. Hallstrom.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Donald%20L.%20Hallstrom.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Donald L. Hallstrom.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2000 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Cultivate Righteous Traditions</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Uplifting traditions … that promote love for Deity and unity in families and among people are especially important.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10028166_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="imeOBg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="hUCkNgU250GwRXlxplWmow" hash="X22RJg">Cultivate Righteous Traditions</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="xQDvtMfOtUyJm_zO4rnNmg" hash="G9S_AQ">Donald L. Hallstrom</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="sYcrsZ74hU--GakYQ7F8WQ" hash="H65IRw">Uplifting traditions … that promote love for Deity and unity in families and among people are especially important.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-acb.jpg" alt="Elder Donald L. Hallstrom" pid="i56HBUs4AUug27WRUamUDQ" hash="FdOfsg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions.p1" pid="qRJ0FmT2e0Kb1kf_o7pwmQ" hash="pAWp5A">I will ever be grateful for having been born and nurtured in Hawaii, part of what the scriptures often refer to as “the isles of the sea.” Called a melting pot, because of its multiethnic composition, others have more accurately referred to the islands as a “delicious stew,” with each culture maintaining an identity, but blending together in a harmonious societal broth which can be savored by all. Having additionally served a mission in England, spending significant time on the United States mainland, and now living and serving in Asia, I have long been interested in culture and tradition and their influence on how we look, think, and act. Culture is defined as “the customary beliefs, social forms, and … traits of a … group” (<span class="emphasis">Merriam-Webster’s Collegiate Dictionary,</span> 10th ed.). Traditions, established patterns of behavior transmitted from generation to generation, are an inherent part of culture. Our culture and its related traditions help establish our sense of identity and fill the vital human need to belong.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions.p2" pid="ywH9YYAI8kqWAPcQjl-ejg" hash="0SX8vA">Of traditions which are complementary to the gospel of Jesus Christ, Paul admonished the Thessalonians, “Therefore, … stand fast, and hold the traditions which ye have been taught” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-thes/2.15" class="scriptureRef">2 Thes. 2:15</a>). In the Church, powerful traditions remind us of the strength and sacrifice of our ancestors and inspire our efforts. Among them are industry, frugality, and complete devotion to a righteous cause. Others are based on doctrine and standards which may seem peculiar to the world but are consistent with God’s pattern. These include chaste behavior, modesty of dress, unpolluted language, Sabbath observance, adherence to the Word of Wisdom, and the payment of tithes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions.p3" pid="s-RH6vQk00-xDOJNeC8MoQ" hash="ZBH6IA">Even in ethnic culture, many traditions can reinforce gospel standards and principles. For example, anciently, Hawaiians had a practice, the spirit of which is still exhibited today by many in the islands. When greeting another person, one would come face-to-face and offer an expression of “ha,” even expelling their breath for another to feel. The literal translation of <span class="emphasis">ha</span> is “the breath of life.” It was a way to give of oneself and show another a deep sense of brotherly love and caring. When foreigners first came to Hawaii, they did not exhibit this same respect for others. They were called <span class="emphasis">haole, ha-ole, </span>meaning “without ha.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions.p4" pid="_joAGIVvEEWJmXxmPFnwFA" hash="WRTPew">If there is a people who should have “ha,” an intense feeling of charity and compassion toward others, it is members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. A true Latter-day Saint possesses a love for others that is consistent with a belief that everyone is a brother or a sister.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions.p5" pid="KFwvB00lqUqU2jQepAnsZw" hash="Yyt4HA">Uplifting traditions play a significant role in leading us toward the things of the Spirit. Those that promote love for Deity and unity in families and among people are especially important.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions.p6" pid="xuUbUT9NDUSGzLM-nwvIzQ" hash="3po3Yg">The power of tradition, however, poses a significant danger. It can cause us to forget our heavenly heritage. To achieve eternal goals, we must reconcile our earthly culture with the doctrine of the everlasting gospel. This process involves embracing all that is spiritually elevating in our family and societal traditions and discarding that which is a barrier to our eternal view and achievement. We must transform ourselves from being “natural” men and women as defined by King Benjamin, and “becometh a saint” by yielding “to the enticings of the Holy Spirit” (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/3.19" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 3:19</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions.p7" pid="05ZKGEpFJ0eQLSaHu_wbSA" hash="lxE9Vw">Also warning of this peril and its gravity, the Prophet Joseph Smith was inspired to clarify one of Paul’s epistles to the people of Corinth by stating, “And it came to pass that the children, being brought up in subjection to the law of Moses, gave heed to the traditions of their fathers and believed not the gospel of Christ, wherein they became unholy” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/74.4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 74:4</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions.p8" pid="Clmuh1ks102BrnB_1w0nsg" hash="m3_sfw">Please be not dismissive and think this principle applies only to others and their culture; know that it is valid for you and for me, wherever on earth we may live or whatever our family circumstances may be.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions.p9" pid="v4ZSY3AUaUKyPHOXv6FK9A" hash="IFLD1w">Unwanted traditions are those which lead us away from performing holy ordinances and keeping sacred covenants. Our guide should be the doctrine taught by the scriptures and the prophets. Traditions which devalue marriage and family, abase women or do not recognize the majesty of their God-given roles, honor temporal success more than spiritual, or teach that reliance upon God is a weakness of character, all lead us away from eternal truths.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions.p10" pid="qTOD9NN3dUqDtZ-h32UiDg" hash="corYjg">Of all the traditions we should cultivate within ourselves and our families, a “tradition of righteousness” should be preeminent. Hallmarks of this tradition are an unwavering love for God and His Only Begotten Son, respect for prophets and priesthood power, a constant seeking of the Holy Spirit, and the discipline of discipleship which transforms believing into doing. A tradition of righteousness sets a pattern for living which draws children closer to parents, and both closer to God, and elevates obedience from a burden to a blessing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions.p11" pid="raCrJJznqEmMHsrXQ5Sp9w" hash="zAaV9w">In a world where traditions often confuse right and wrong:</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions.f2">
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="zt4L3UPqs0mQzKp3aLCX4Q" hash="pHKcdg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="x5AnxtG3rEao71Uz66bR0w" hash="Ju9fKA">We are inspired by the courage of each young person who has honored the Sabbath day, kept the Word of Wisdom, and remained chaste when popular culture has established the opposite as not only acceptable but expected.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="y8QvDH4YFEONG7OPNrzGlg" hash="wHXyog">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="qzi1D-CVwE-xSwZevMg-yQ" hash="j9dDEA">We are inspired by the wisdom of each man who has molded a career which properly supports his premier responsibility to spiritually lead his family when wealth and power are more highly valued by the world.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="DTP0rHxNMk2s2ehnQQyF3A" hash="eMnmsA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="Mzi5-UN-hkiHc-dkaIOc_Q" hash="1TusJg">We are inspired by the nobility of each husband and wife who have established a relationship of equality and kindness when one of selfishness and indifference is so common.</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions.p12" pid="aYbfJ5MqEkydkTYvsVWi4Q" hash="cEYIIw">As the supernal nature of our life begins to be understood and experienced, we desire nothing temporal to impede our celestial journey.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions.p13" pid="pb-EYSWj8kKq6u7ZTHJK7Q" hash="Dk9VJw">Humbled by the responsibility but joyous in the opportunity to preach the gospel and bear witness in all the world, I affirm my knowledge of eternal truths and everlasting culture. I testify of 15 men with prophetic calling and apostolic authority and one among them, even President Gordon B. Hinckley, who presides with dignity, vision, and a clear sense of righteous tradition. Of most significance, I testify of the Savior and Redeemer of mankind, of His Church, and of His atoning love, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2000/10/cultivate-righteous-traditions</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2000-general-conference/2000-10-2040-elder-donald-l-hallstrom-64k-eng.mp3" length="3767844" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2000 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do It Now</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Now is the time to reconcile with God through the merciful process of change afforded us by the Redeemer.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008332_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="LDmcJw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="MfSe1t39sEqW6EZFF2AmsA" hash="UR28cg">Do It Now</h1><p class="authorName" guid="9a0afdf3-bbfe-4929-89cd-ab1437566237" pid="ZL4nauybUkWVpOFHR9ZMCQ" hash="G9S_AQ">Donald L. Hallstrom</p><p class="kicker" pid="m0n3SGgV_km8rFpPQ7cyMg" hash="t2GASQ">Now is the time to reconcile with God through the merciful process of change afforded us by the Redeemer.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="f6327979-9530-48de-b08d-57b91dc6cc86">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/HallstromDL_all.ob.jpg" alt="Elder Donald L. Hallstrom" guid="b8f6bc9f-1344-470a-8906-b436d2334235" pid="GtyLacWCkEOf1ONWw1SKFg" hash="3bfqCA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.p" pid="M2UkMk17g0OMm8qm1R3Bxg" hash="2XDE5w">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="49"></span>When our oldest child (who is now a father of three and sits in this priesthood congregation this evening) was 11 years of age, he was given an assignment, along with the other sixth graders of his school, to submit his favorite family recipe. As its contribution to a large spring fair, the sixth grade was producing a cookbook that would be distributed throughout the community. When the teacher announced the project and a deadline of a week from Friday, our son Brett immediately concluded there was plenty of time later to get the job done and dismissed it from his mind. Early the next week, when the teacher reminded the students of the Friday deadline, Brett decided he could easily complete the required task on Thursday night and until then he could occupy himself with other more enjoyable matters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.p" pid="SPJGWFFTj0KY7aVoDj6E4Q" hash="8jn5UQ">On the appointed Friday morning, the teacher directed the students to pass their recipes to the front of the class. Brett’s procrastination had caused him to forget the assignment and be completely unprepared. Flustered, he turned to a fellow student seated nearby and confessed his problem. Trying to be helpful, the classmate said, “I brought an extra recipe. If you want, use one of mine.” Brett quickly grabbed the recipe, wrote his name on it, and turned it in, feeling he had escaped any consequences related to his lack of preparation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.p" pid="gQB9rplkk0WPB3B9_xCIyA" hash="_H6Q8g">One evening several weeks later, I arrived home from work to freshen up before going to my evening Church meetings. A few days prior, I had been called as a stake president after serving several years as a bishop. We were somewhat known in our community as members of the Church who tried to live the tenets of our religion. “There’s something you need to see,” my wife, Diane, said as I walked through the door. She handed me a bound book with a page marked. Glancing at the cover, titled <span class="emphasis">Noelani School’s Favorites—1985,</span> I turned to the identified page and read, “Hallstrom Family, Favorite Recipe—Bacardi Rum Cake.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.p" pid="ZPMe0T92QUWv7-dlOo6bEQ" hash="_WHODQ">Many of us place ourselves in circumstances far more consequential than embarrassment because of our procrastination to become fully converted to the gospel of Jesus Christ. <span class="pageBreak" page-number="50"></span>We know what is right, but we delay full spiritual involvement because of laziness, fear, rationalization, or lack of faith. We convince ourselves that “someday I’m going to do it.” However, for many “someday” never comes, and even for others who eventually do make a change, there is an irretrievable loss of progress and surely regression.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.p" pid="kIl4UO7sVk6eT0DkvoGOnw" hash="MY3O7w">As a partial self-appraisal of our spiritual-procrastination standing, what is our attitude when we attend the meetings of the Church? Is it to learn “by study and also by faith” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.118" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:118</a>), which seamlessly translates what we learn into what we do? Or do we have an “I’ve heard it all before” mentality that immediately blocks the Spirit’s access to our minds and our hearts and enables procrastination to become a major part of our character?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.p" pid="FkGRlp4lNECmR_PH9XAcZQ" hash="k-UxHQ">Of a prominent early investigator of the restored Church, who covenanted that he would obey any command that the Lord would give him, it was said, “And he received the word with gladness, but straightway Satan tempted him; … and the cares of the world caused him to reject the word” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/40.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 40:2</a>). Contrast that with the Lord’s clear statement: “He that receiveth my law and doeth it, the same is my disciple” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/41.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 41:5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.p" pid="njvRg9jqP0m6k75tsfKWYg" hash="_xyvUg">Alma, with deep emotion, declared, “And now, my brethren, I wish from the inmost part of my heart, yea, with great anxiety even unto pain, that ye would hearken unto my words, and cast off your sins, and not procrastinate the day of your repentance” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/13.27" class="scriptureRef">Alma 13:27</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.p" pid="JdQjb5WOOk2FFzNXnTvfag" hash="0lu3XQ">Amulek, Alma’s friend and teaching companion, amplified the message by proclaiming:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.p" pid="bkhhB98oT0SMgzlNL0mryA" hash="wa9P0g">“For behold, this life is the time for men to prepare to meet God; yea, behold the day of this life is the day for men to perform their labors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.p" pid="XtbtGaZK50a3btsQ4aj69g" hash="L4mHPw">“And now, … as ye have had so many witnesses, therefore, I beseech of you that ye do not procrastinate the day of your repentance until the end” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/34.32-33" class="scriptureRef">Alma 34:32–33</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.p" pid="c-e4E3lWz0OeJFOZVmmX5w" hash="ZNEoPw">When I was the age of a teacher in the Aaronic Priesthood, it seemed every Saturday morning for months I was awakened to the sound of my father doing yard work outside my bedroom window. (It took me a long time to figure out why he always started his work under my window.) After a period of trying to ignore the noise, I would get up and join my father in my weekly responsibility to help him maintain the yard surrounding our home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.p" pid="FdllTFsR70eLnbiuDwK6lg" hash="GykUeA">Perhaps after a few mornings of my not arising very quickly or due to other similar events when his repeated encouragement was needed before I acted, one day my father sat with me and showed me a large photograph of a sloth, an animal known for its laziness. Then he opened the Doctrine and Covenants and had me read, “For behold, it is not meet that I should command in all things; for he that is compelled in all things, the same is a <span class="emphasis">slothful</span> and not a wise servant; wherefore he receiveth no reward” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.26" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:26</a>; emphasis added). Since that day, that image and its lesson have been valuable assets in my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.p" pid="VbCD1_POeUGcc2_eFBlvwQ" hash="7z-nAA">One of President Spencer W. Kimball’s effective encouragements was the succinct “Do It.” He later expanded this to “Do It Now” to pointedly teach the need for timeliness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.p" pid="fF6ETPutOkCGuQP2u_xlgg" hash="Mwz21g">President Kimball also taught the profound principle that procrastination leads to the loss of exaltation. He said: “One of the most serious human defects in all ages is procrastination, an unwillingness to accept personal responsibilities <span class="emphasis">now.</span> … Many have allowed themselves to be diverted and have become … addicts to mental and spiritual indolence and to the pursuit of worldly pleasure” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of Presidents of the Church: Spencer W. Kimball</span> [2006], 4–5).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.p" pid="O4BGowN_v0GxtqnVzk9FMA" hash="VKsk9g">Many of us want the simple way—the process that will not require serious work and sacrifice. Well, I once thought I found it. Driving in the back of a verdant valley above the city of Honolulu, I looked up, and there it was—<span class="emphasis">Easy Street!</span> As I was dreaming of the life-changing benefits of my discovery, I took out my camera to record the blissful moment. As I looked through the viewfinder, however, my focus literally and figuratively <span class="pageBreak" page-number="51"></span>became clear. A large yellow sign returned me to reality—Easy Street was a dead end!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.p" pid="H4VjwWD9jUuYgXzXpqRrLA" hash="UHhs0A">Procrastination may seem the easy way, as it momentarily removes the effort required to accomplish something of value. Ironically, in time, procrastination produces a heavy burden laced with guilt and a hollow lack of satisfaction. Temporal and, even more importantly, spiritual goals will not be achieved by procrastination.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.p" pid="IdcZv0jNt06wxPbPKczZ_w" hash="dAuW8A">
        <span class="emphasis">Now is the time</span> to exercise our faith. <span class="emphasis">Now is the time</span> to commit to righteousness. <span class="emphasis">Now is the time</span> to do whatever is required to resolve our undesired circumstances. <span class="emphasis">Now is the time</span> to reconcile with God through the merciful process of change afforded us by the Redeemer of mankind.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.f1"><p pid="RGsf-zPQmEiOWUN9QtsAbQ" hash="pzFJRQ">We appeal:</p><ul class="bullet" guid="eb24488b-ef8d-43b8-96df-d5934de8ac42"><li guid="0ab58bb4-a19e-414f-ab0a-b96b7e275926" pid="TTexJp0AW0Co4XIObopJNQ" hash="FkapFQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p guid="25e02038-da79-42ad-925b-522212648845" pid="ojYED4qeLkC8u37zYe8XXg" hash="iwXwGQ">To anyone who has received a witness of the truthfulness of the gospel and The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and has not been baptized and confirmed.</p>
        </li><li guid="78898daa-5873-4527-beb7-4d61bfa72a74" pid="gVkLJD4Y10WaML5N2iZiew" hash="wrrYow">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p guid="f0617121-c0bc-438d-b953-9e1b2572e6f8" pid="3VR9nJBwNEqrOWC8VOcTqA" hash="uuWkgA">To any holder of the Aaronic or Melchizedek Priesthood who, either by transgression or just doing nothing, is living in opposition to a sacred oath and covenant (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.33-39" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:33–39</a>).</p>
        </li><li guid="45581fbe-1548-40b5-8011-771dd2abea91" pid="i31MSWX85UGkAJyiTF7_1Q" hash="HIN85g">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p guid="ea212d52-f72b-4df6-b0a8-958e5863dd57" pid="uqSwCZQkwk6rr6Zc3dYXFA" hash="mk6sXQ">To any endowed member of the Church who does not currently qualify for a temple recommend.</p>
        </li><li guid="28965261-4a5a-46ea-9dbf-11ffcb370b5d" pid="vd3kvEmEjkan2RP4Fm54nw" hash="XXyNlQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p guid="9cb1bdf7-8973-4448-97e8-3c53c9a75ba8" pid="0OHfvRO3_UGX4SdkGr8ACw" hash="bTQLuA">To any member who has been offended by the actions of another and has in any manner disassociated him or herself from the Church.</p>
        </li><li guid="3a22ed9a-d611-415d-b072-28195fe6f2f4" pid="3YspKsmrgEuMvhejsTfqew" hash="sp5MTw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p guid="94a402c6-a02d-4f89-98a4-2cdead050887" pid="w6841MSEiEGlYhMif4f-aA" hash="ND6pog">To anyone who is living a duplicitous life and is burdened by unresolved sin.</p>
        </li></ul></div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now.p" pid="qw0rgEwcG0O4keZCO6lKuA" hash="NfEh4g">It is my witness that you and all of us can change, and it can be now. It may not be easy, but our afflictions can be “swallowed up in the joy of Christ” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/31.38" class="scriptureRef">Alma 31:38</a>). I so testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/HallstromDL_all.ob.jpg" alt="Elder Donald L. Hallstrom" guid="b8f6bc9f-1344-470a-8906-b436d2334235" pid="nUUIJzGcFEakk4gP0n_fNw" hash="3bfqCA1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="b8f6bc9f-1344-470a-8906-b436d2334235"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/10/do-it-now</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2007-general-conference/2007-10-3020-elder-donald-l-hallstrom-64k-eng.mp3" length="4494249" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turn to the Lord</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/04/turn-to-the-lord?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Never let an earthly circumstance disable you spiritually.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/turn-to-the-lord" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021388_000_031" doc-version="2" hash="tEY8rQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/turn-to-the-lord.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="EJlPcLeHGUi3O52JS39G-Q" hash="3BJYgQ">Turn to the Lord</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="KhBnG4A2DkKub8EADKXrjA" hash="G9S_AQ">Donald L. Hallstrom</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="2s8_FmBvtEGwiNLz1I9cLg" hash="Vcl6Xg">Never let an earthly circumstance disable you spiritually.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/turn-to-the-lord.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/turn-to-the-lord.p1" pid="3LTh--tgWkazOtS_CFQIsQ" hash="i-VdBg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="78"></span>Many years ago, I observed a heartbreak—which became a tragedy. A young couple was nearing the delivery of their first child. Their lives were filled with the anticipation and excitement of this monumental experience. During the delivery, complications arose and the baby died. Heartbreak turned to grief, grief turned to anger, anger turned to blame, and blame turned to revenge toward the doctor, whom they held fully responsible. Parents and other family members became heavily involved, together seeking to ruin the reputation and the career of the physician. As weeks and then months of acrimony consumed the family, their bitterness was extended to the Lord. “How could He allow this horrible thing to occur?” They rejected the repeated efforts of Church leaders and members to spiritually and emotionally comfort them and, in time, disassociated themselves from the Church. Four generations of the family have now been affected. Where once there were faith and devotion to the Lord and His Church, there has been no spiritual activity by any family member for decades.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/turn-to-the-lord.p2" pid="piLwuIhLrU6KX0KTHo-eFA" hash="ixCWJg">In the most difficult circumstances of life, there is often only one source of peace. The Prince of Peace, Jesus Christ, extends His grace with the invitation “Come unto me, all ye that labour and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/11.28" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 11:28</a>). He further promises, “My peace I give unto you: not as the world giveth, give I unto you” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.27" class="scriptureRef">John 14:27</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/turn-to-the-lord.p3" pid="XK-OuDU2x0KGzuEVSuVnNA" hash="WbPLFA">My paternal grandparents had two children, a son (my father) and a daughter. After serving a mission and military service in Hawaii, my father returned to the islands in 1946 to establish himself professionally and raise his family. His parents lived in Salt Lake City, as did his sister. She married in 1946 and four years later was expecting a child. There is something very special for parents to anticipate a daughter (in this instance an only daughter) giving birth for the first time. No one knew that she was carrying twins. Sadly, she and the twins all died during childbirth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/turn-to-the-lord.p4" pid="AdhZYrfYgkGSS3wsGh4Q0g" hash="jhwjrA">My grandparents were heartbroken. Their grief, however, immediately turned them to the Lord and His Atonement. Without dwelling on why this could happen and who might be to blame, they focused on living a righteous life. My grandparents never had wealth; they were never among the socially elite; they never held high position in the Church—they were simply devoted Latter-day Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/turn-to-the-lord.p5" pid="RtljngKFOE6iyI9bdytuRw" hash="EiCPLg">After retiring professionally in 1956, they moved to Hawaii to be with their only posterity. The ensuing decades found them loving their family, serving <span class="pageBreak" page-number="79"></span>in the Church, and mostly, they just enjoyed being together. They never liked being apart and even spoke of whoever died first finding a way to help them reunite soon. Nearing their 90th birthdays and after 65 years of marriage, they passed away within hours of each other by natural causes. As their bishop, I conducted their double funeral.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/turn-to-the-lord.p6" pid="GbTIQBFBT0Cd2C7du2ANsA" hash="CKfpPQ">The faithfulness of Grandpa Art and Grandma Lou, especially when faced with difficulty, has now influenced four generations that have followed. Directly and profoundly, it affected their son (my father) and my mother when my parents’ own daughter, their youngest child, died due to complications caused by giving birth. At 34 years of age, she passed away 10 days after childbirth, leaving 4 children, 10 days to 8 years old. With the example that they had seen in the previous generation, my parents—without hesitation—turned to the Lord for solace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/turn-to-the-lord.p7" pid="a56bzTPGfEGAYICZEROJWg" hash="mq7lQw">Throughout the world and among the membership of the Church, there is great joy and great pain. Both are part of the plan. Without one, we cannot know the other. “Men are, that they might have joy” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.25" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 2:25</a>) and “for it must needs be, that there is an opposition in all things” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.11" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 2:11</a>) are not contradictory; they are complementary. In describing how he felt when he turned to the Lord, Alma the Younger said, “My soul was filled with joy as exceeding as was my pain” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/36.20" class="scriptureRef">Alma 36:20</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/turn-to-the-lord.p8" pid="3ujzBCif602NOAG9yfVbDg" hash="cqgVgg">Some are overcome by major problems; others let small matters become big. Symonds Ryder was a Campbellite leader who heard about the Church and had a meeting with Joseph Smith. Moved by this experience, he joined the Church in June 1831. Immediately thereafter, he was ordained an elder and called to serve a mission. However, in his call letter from the First Presidency and on his official commission to preach, his name was misspelled—by one letter. His last name showed as R-i-d-e-r, not the correct R-y-d-e-r. This caused him to question his call and those from whom it came. He chose not to go on the mission and fell away, which soon led to hatred and intense opposition toward Joseph and the Church. In March 1832, when Joseph Smith and Sidney Rigdon were ripped from home during the night by an angry mob and tarred and feathered, a voice was heard to shout, “Simonds, Simonds <span class="emphasis">[sic], where’s the tar bucket?</span>” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 1:262–63). In less than 10 months, Symonds Ryder went from an eager convert to a mob leader, his spiritual decline starting with <span class="pageBreak" page-number="80"></span>the offense taken over the misspelling of his name—by one letter. No matter the size of the issue, how we respond can reset the course of our life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/turn-to-the-lord.p9" pid="LqIHah8TikSPra4ItxPv2A" hash="izabUg">The Prophet Joseph Smith provided a model in handling personal tragedy and opposition. Revealed to him while in the inhumane surroundings of the Liberty Jail was this divine direction (which, in part, was a description of Joseph’s life to that point and also a forewarning): If “fools shall have thee in derision, … if thou art called to pass through tribulation; … if thine enemies fall upon thee; … if thou shouldst be cast into the pit, or into the hands of murderers, … and all the elements combine to hedge up the way; and above all, if the very jaws of hell shall gape open the mouth wide after thee, know thou, my son, that all these things shall give thee experience, and shall be for thy good” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/122.1,5-7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 122:1, 5–7</a>). Then the profound statement: “The Son of Man hath descended below them all. Art thou greater than he?” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/122.8" class="scriptureRef">verse 8</a>). This is followed by clear direction and great promises. “Therefore, hold on thy way, and … fear not what man can do, for God shall be with you forever and ever” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/122.9" class="scriptureRef">verse 9</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/turn-to-the-lord.p10" pid="Nyc-jjQtn0qcXdmwjmvCEg" hash="cKYKeQ">Over the ensuing years, Joseph Smith continued to righteously endure a life full of adversity. He offered this faith-filled perspective: “And as for the perils which I am called to pass through, they seem but a small thing to me. … Deep water is what I am wont to swim in. … I … glory in tribulation; for … God … [has] delivered me out of them all, and will deliver me from henceforth” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/127.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 127:2</a>). Joseph’s confidence in overcoming constant opposition was based on his ability to continually turn to the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/turn-to-the-lord.p11" pid="vyA7MAPV50isGSkpMDtcCQ" hash="Eo7wUA">If you feel you have been wronged—by anyone (a family member, a friend, another member of the Church, a Church leader, a business associate) or by anything (the death of a loved one, health problems, a financial reversal, abuse, addictions)—deal with the matter directly and with all the strength you have. “Hold on thy way” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/122.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 122:9</a>); giving up is not an option. And, without delay, turn to the Lord. Exercise all of the faith you have in Him. Let Him share your burden. Allow His grace to lighten your load. We are promised that we will “suffer no manner of afflictions, save it were swallowed up in the joy of Christ” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/31.38" class="scriptureRef">Alma 31:38</a>). Never let an earthly circumstance disable you spiritually.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/turn-to-the-lord.p12" pid="M1rru3_Hy0-Olhaexi6DYA" hash="GSppLw">His most exemplary act, the Atonement, required Jesus to descend “below all things” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:6</a>) and suffer “the pains of all men” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/9.21" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 9:21</a>). Thus we understand the Atonement has broader purpose than providing a means to overcome sin. This greatest of all earthly accomplishments gives the Savior the power to fulfill this promise: “If ye will turn to the Lord with full purpose of heart, and put your trust in him, and serve him with all diligence … , if ye do this, he will … deliver you out of bondage” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/7.33" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 7:33</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/turn-to-the-lord.p13" pid="i5SjCk4670uwZiJNR8rj8Q" hash="li2ynQ">As we commemorate this Easter morning, let us turn to the Lord, our “bright and morning star” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rev/22.16" class="scriptureRef">Revelation 22:16</a>). I testify He will forever light our way, our truth, and our life (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.6" class="scriptureRef">John 14:6</a>), in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/04/turn-to-the-lord</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2010-general-conference/2010-04-4030-elder-donald-l-hallstrom-64k-eng.mp3" length="5214417" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Converted to His Gospel through His Church</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The purpose of the Church is to help us live the gospel.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10485_000_14halls" doc-version="2" hash="I-64QQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="-pULg7lhSUmhG_lDn5EmYw" hash="roCxEg">Converted to His Gospel through His Church</h1><p class="authorName" pid="hJ2_uw331UKljbcD1LOvsA" hash="PVwkhA">By Elder Donald L. Hallstrom</p><p class="kicker" pid="xxW7brUGT06NDjuoRZwSYg" hash="06FBMA">The purpose of the Church is to help us live the gospel.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" pid="RU_nRTFym0GDykenaTFrVg" hash="BK1y9A">
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church.p5" pid="B76iq9P7M0u2BDwymZ5V0g" hash="LCIxFw">
      <span class="pageBreak" page-number="13"></span>I love the gospel of Jesus Christ <span class="emphasis">and</span> The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. Sometimes we use the terms <span class="emphasis">gospel</span> and <span class="emphasis">Church</span> interchangeably, but they are not the same. They are, however, exquisitely interconnected, and we need both.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church.p6" pid="5pP-UgCZokWXr_Qbi8rvkQ" hash="jvepRg">The gospel is the glorious plan of God in which we, as His children, are given the opportunity to receive all that the Father has (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:38</a>). This is called eternal life and is described as “the greatest of all the gifts of God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/14.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 14:7</a>). A vital part of the plan is our earthly experience—a time to develop faith (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.26" class="scriptureRef">Moroni 7:26</a>), to repent (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/3.12" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 3:12</a>), and to reconcile ourselves with God (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.11" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:11</a>).</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church.p7" pid="xtqWgVlHMEq3CCJEzK2G5g" hash="kYE1wg">Because our mortal frailties and “opposition in all things” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.11" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 2:11</a>) would make this life profoundly difficult and because we could not cleanse our own sins, a Savior was needed. When Elohim, the Eternal God and Father of all our spirits, presented His plan of salvation, there was one among us who said, “Here am I, send me” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.27" class="scriptureRef">Abraham 3:27</a>). His name was Jehovah.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church.p8" pid="77yzBnw8FEu0VGW4YPNw9A" hash="cjBj4Q">Born of a Heavenly Father, both spiritually and physically, He possessed the omnipotence to overcome the world. Born of an earthly mother, He was subject to the pain and suffering of mortality. The great Jehovah was also named Jesus and additionally was given the title of Christ, meaning the Messiah or Anointed One. His crowning achievement was the Atonement, wherein Jesus the Christ “descended below all things” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:6</a>), making it possible for Him to pay a redeeming ransom for each of us.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church.p9" pid="_nTttUf0DEaStSeHyleBaw" hash="2JOKwg">The Church was established by Jesus Christ during His earthly ministry, “built upon the foundation of the apostles and prophets” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/2.20" class="scriptureRef">Ephesians 2:20</a>). In this, “the dispensation of the fulness of times” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/128.18" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 128:18</a>), the Lord restored what once was, specifically telling the Prophet Joseph Smith, “I will establish a church by your hand” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/31.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 31:7</a>). Jesus Christ was and is the head of His Church, represented on earth by prophets holding apostolic authority.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church.p10" pid="-Xgih8RubkeZwDtQRwtXyA" hash="C0U9EQ">This is a magnificent Church. Its organization, effectiveness, and sheer goodness are respected by all who sincerely seek to understand it. The Church has programs for children, youth, men, and women. It has beautiful meetinghouses that number more than 18,000. Majestic temples—now totaling 136—dot the earth, with another 30 under construction or announced. A full-time missionary force of over 56,000, comprised of the young and less so, are serving in 150 countries. The Church’s worldwide humanitarian work is a marvelous display of the generosity of our members. Our welfare system cares for our members and promotes self-reliance in a manner unduplicated anywhere. In this Church we have selfless lay leaders and a community of Saints who are willing to serve one another in a remarkable way. There is nothing like this Church in all the world.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church.p11" pid="JdWH_fHb7UabWNcQCrDjbQ" hash="9b1uWg">When I was born, our family lived in a tiny cottage on the grounds of one of the great and historic meetinghouses of the Church, the Honolulu Tabernacle. I now apologize to my dear friends in the Presiding Bishopric, who oversee the facilities of the Church, but as a boy I climbed over and under and through every inch of that property, from the bottom of the water-filled reflecting pool to the top of the inside of the imposing lighted steeple. We even swung (Tarzan-like) on the long hanging vines of the huge banyan trees that are on the site.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church.p12" pid="3iJ5nujB4UWfPB7A6x-Lgw" hash="mTssIA">The Church was everything to us. We went to lots of meetings, even more than we have today. We attended Primary on Thursday afternoons. Relief Society meetings were on Tuesday mornings. Mutual for the youth was Wednesday night. Saturday was for ward activities. On Sunday, men and young men would go to <span class="pageBreak" page-number="14"></span>priesthood meeting in the morning. Midday we would attend Sunday School. Then in the evening we returned for sacrament meeting. With comings and goings and meetings, it seemed our time was consumed with Church activities all day Sunday and most other days of the week.</p>
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church.p13" pid="UQwTMMzQm0qAoFJTpKR5ig" hash="IgsgUw">As much as I loved the Church, it was during those boyhood days that, for the first time, I had a sense there was something even more. When I was five years old, a major conference was held at the tabernacle. We walked down the lane on which we lived and over a small bridge leading to the stately meetinghouse and sat on about the 10th row in the large chapel. Presiding and speaking at the meeting was David O. McKay, the President of the Church. I do not recall anything he said, but I vividly remember what I saw and what I felt. President McKay was dressed in a cream-colored suit and, with his wavy white hair, looked very regal. In the tradition of the islands, he wore a triple-thick red carnation lei. As he spoke, I felt something quite intense and very personal. I later understood that I was feeling the influence of the Holy Spirit. We sang the closing hymn.</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church.f1">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="ixO_zsK6SUSDurDWb6Nx-g" hash="ONbe3A">Who’s on the Lord’s side? Who?</p>
          <p class="line" pid="aF1h1vWeNkGBMSgIodWhQA" hash="PucKKg">Now is the time to show.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="3e_ytZunbUW-cyT6efUmMw" hash="wjp6Aw">We ask it fearlessly:</p>
          <p class="line" pid="KWUei2xwlEOSjMmpOBM4nA" hash="ONbe3A1">Who’s on the Lord’s side? Who?</p>
        </div>
        <p class="citationInfo" pid="vdDr1StZWUesP5jJU0cZfQ" hash="m9fsDA">(“Who’s on the Lord’s Side?” <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 260)</p>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church.p19" pid="zjiXnZomSk6smZw6SMulJQ" hash="mGX23g">With those words being sung by nearly 2,000 people but seeming to be a question posed just to me, I wanted to stand and say, “I am!”</p>
    </span>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church.p20" pid="7BV7wDdDUUSXY0ZR1-xQiw" hash="zRhdtg">Some have come to think of activity in the Church as the ultimate goal. Therein lies a danger. It is possible to be active in the Church and less active in the gospel. Let me stress: activity in the Church is a highly desirable goal; however, it is insufficient. Activity in the Church is an outward indication of our spiritual desire. If we attend our meetings, hold and fulfill Church responsibilities, and serve others, it is publicly observed.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church.p21" pid="OHjION5Z3Ee3kfW7TABbbw" hash="DnggAw">By contrast, the things of the gospel are usually less visible and more difficult to measure, but they are of greater eternal importance. For example, how much faith do we really have? How repentant are we? How meaningful are the ordinances in our lives? How focused are we on our covenants?</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church.p22" pid="tc4RhTjYoUipWPFttsC8_A" hash="-s4IGA">I repeat: we need the gospel <span class="emphasis">and</span> the Church. In fact, the purpose of the Church is to help us live the gospel. We often wonder: How can someone be fully active in the Church as a youth and then not be when they are older? How can an adult who has regularly attended and served stop coming? How can a person who was disappointed by a leader or another member allow that to end their Church participation? Perhaps the reason is they were not sufficiently converted to the gospel—the things of eternity.</p>
    <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church.f2"><p pid="gKgQBU7ekkSLdGLhbuariA" hash="LLVGdg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="15"></span>I suggest three fundamental ways to have the gospel be our foundation:</p><ol class="number" guid=""><li pid="9n8QV8EJ3keEHoSiRX1KCA" hash="x3WXew">
        <span class="label">1.</span>
        <p pid="_-vvUKnLJ0KpXcxL4hhIuA" hash="rIE7Rw">
          <span class="emphasis">Deepen our understanding of Deity.</span> A sustained knowledge of and love for the three members of the Godhead are indispensable. Mindfully pray to the Father, in the name of the Son, and seek direction from the Holy Ghost. Couple prayer with constant study and humble pondering to continually build unshakable faith in Jesus Christ. “For how knoweth a man the master … who is a stranger unto him, and is far from the thoughts and intents of his heart?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/5.13" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 5:13</a>).</p>
      </li><li pid="CNIy7x40FEGnBE4XJUnVKg" hash="iBRFfA">
        <span class="label">2.</span>
        <p pid="ZqbGDgkUDkSN3zmZ3hb9Rw" hash="VkGPnQ">
          <span class="emphasis">Focus on the ordinances and covenants.</span> If there are any of the essential ordinances yet to be performed in your life, intently prepare to receive each of them. Then we need to establish the discipline to live faithful to our covenants, fully using the weekly gift of the sacrament. Many of us are not being regularly changed by its cleansing power because of our lack of reverence for this holy ordinance.</p>
      </li><li pid="N-GGFvjIdEmLkM_N9WMFVw" hash="0sqnUA">
        <span class="label">3.</span>
        <p pid="wlKP30GQbE6GLCDJBKj5NQ" hash="e0lyOA">
          <span class="emphasis">Unite the gospel with the Church.</span> As we concentrate on the gospel, the Church will become more, not less, of a blessing in our lives. As we come to each meeting prepared to “seek learning, even by study and also by faith” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.118" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:118</a>), the Holy Spirit will be our teacher. If we come to be entertained, we often will be disappointed. President Spencer W. Kimball was once asked, “What do you do when you find yourself in a boring sacrament meeting?” His response: “I don’t know. I’ve never been in one” (quoted by Gene R. Cook, in Gerry Avant, “Learning Gospel Is Lifetime Pursuit,” <span class="emphasis">Church News,</span> Mar. 24, 1990, 10).</p>
      </li></ol></div>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church.p27" pid="jkwpxetIXkWPziryQi1SKw" hash="p5wIsA">In our lives we should desire what occurred after the Lord came to the people of the New World and established His Church. The scriptures read, “And it came to pass that thus they [meaning His disciples] did go forth among all the people of Nephi, and did preach the gospel of Christ unto all people upon the face of the land; and they were converted unto the Lord, and were united unto the church of Christ, and thus the people of that generation were blessed” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/28.23" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 28:23</a>).</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church.p28" pid="LKzMXZsj40Kydyrv67_1Tw" hash="Ebe7hg">The Lord wants the members of His Church to be fully converted to His gospel. This is the only sure way to have spiritual safety now and happiness forever. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2012/04/converted-to-his-gospel-through-his-church</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2012-general-conference/2012-04-1040-elder-donald-l-hallstrom-64k-eng.mp3" length="5532736" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Manner of Men?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Donald L. Hallstrom urges priesthood holders to be willing to change in order to become more like the Savior Jesus Christ.
		</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10985_000_32hallstrom" doc-version="3" hash="RNIbXA">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="5RA8KKjY4UqI3wxqcMASnw" hash="joV0Wg">What Manner of Men?</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men.p" pid="K7h7-LOrmE6QS4A8YmBIpQ" hash="PVwkhA">By Elder Donald L. Hallstrom</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men.p" pid="xUOmp5OLTkqj4tNzvzCn0w" hash="hptprg">Of the Presidency of the Seventy</p>
		</div>
		<img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/leaders/donald-l-hallstrom.jpg" altText="Elder Donald L. Hallstrom" pid="CEXt67UrAki9guCARCciMA" hash="P8sx4g" />
		<p class="kicker" pid="4ly54JiTkUC5yb0KgDYd-w" hash="v-Hn4Q">What changes are required of us to become the manner of men we ought to be?</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="PzOyZQCYikSi-GR6HzvR8A" hash="PVwkhA1">By Elder Donald L. Hallstrom</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="qH2amUSzCEK8XoPvDZCn7w" hash="PgbQDw">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men.p5" pid="5nbmbEGrdkeUYaQayDd4AQ" hash="Zm6ygw">
			<span class="pageBreak" page-number="53"></span>As we visualize this worldwide meeting, we are reminded that there is nothing comparable to this gathering—anywhere. The purpose of the priesthood session of general conference is to teach priesthood holders what manner of men we ought to be (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.27" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 27:27</a>) and to inspire us to reach that ideal.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men.p6" pid="ET4ABZYcVkmnYeunCegj3A" hash="oAffqQ">In my Aaronic Priesthood years in Hawaii half a century ago and as a missionary in England, we would gather in meetinghouses and (with intense effort) listen to the priesthood session using a telephone connection. In later years satellites allowed broadcasts to selected Church locations with those enormous dish receivers so we could both hear and view the proceedings. We were in awe of that technology! Few could have imagined today’s world, where anyone who has access to the Internet with a smartphone, tablet, or computer can receive the messages of this meeting.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men.p7" pid="LmN30NdYm0qhqTpMJQsXLg" hash="rhbHgQ">However, this vastly increased accessibility to the voices of the Lord’s servants, which are the same as the Lord’s own voice (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:38</a>), has little value unless we are willing to receive the word (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/11.21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 11:21</a>) and then follow it. Simply stated, the purpose of general conference and of this priesthood session is fulfilled only if we are willing to act—if we are willing to change.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men.p8" pid="yQMPToknNUe7GWeuIgkzXA" hash="Jtk-mw">Several decades ago I was serving as a bishop. Over an extended period I met with a man in our ward who was many years my senior. This brother had a troubled relationship with his wife and was estranged from their children. He struggled to keep employment, had no close friends, and found interaction with ward members so difficult he finally was unwilling to serve in the Church. During one intense discussion about the challenges in his life, he leaned toward me—as his conclusion to our numerous talks—and said, “Bishop, I have a bad temper, and that’s just the way I am!”</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men.p9" pid="mjhCLZyxh0CjmdqrRA86WQ" hash="R3HY7A">That statement stunned me that night and has haunted me ever since. Once this man decided—once any of us conclude—“That’s just the way I am,” we give up our ability to change. We might as well raise the white flag, put down our weapons, concede the battle, and just surrender—any prospect of winning is lost. While some of us may think that does not describe us, perhaps every one of us demonstrates by at least one or two bad habits, “That’s just the way I am.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men.p10" pid="8nU5vpuy_UW6Uqqtis0ZIg" hash="INeM1g">Well, we meet in this priesthood meeting because who we are is not who we can become. We meet here tonight in the name of Jesus Christ. We meet with the confidence that His Atonement gives every one of us—no matter our weaknesses, our frailties, our addictions—the ability to change. We meet with the hope that <span class="pageBreak" page-number="54"></span>our future, no matter our history, can be better.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men.p11" pid="7dqV_MoYjkuuyszqLEPIMA" hash="ol6Ikg">When we participate in this meeting with the “real intent” to change (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.4" class="scriptureRef">Moroni 10:4</a>), the Spirit has full access to our hearts and minds. As the Lord revealed to the Prophet Joseph Smith, “And it shall come to pass, that inasmuch as they … exercise faith in me”—remember, faith is a principle of power and of action—“I will pour out my Spirit upon them in the day that they assemble themselves together” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/44.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 44:2</a>). That means tonight!</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men.p12" pid="NcGeVhe0KEqCk9r3fTgcyA" hash="s0QLbA">If you think your challenges are insurmountable, let me tell you of a man we met in a small village outside of Hyderabad, India, in 2006. This man exemplified a willingness to change. Appa Rao Nulu was born in rural India. When he was three years old, he contracted polio and was left physically disabled. His society taught him that his potential was severely limited. However, as a young adult he met our missionaries. They taught him of a greater potential, both in this life and in the eternity to come. He was baptized and confirmed a member of the Church. With a significantly raised vision, he set a goal to receive the Melchizedek Priesthood and to serve a full-time mission. In 1986 he was ordained an elder and called to serve in India. Walking was not easy—he did his best, using a cane in each hand, and he fell often—but quitting was never an option. He made a commitment to honorably and devotedly serve a mission, and he did.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men.p13" pid="NjCLyRi0vkqkC4yYH-VmQQ" hash="bY1SLA">When we met Brother Nulu, nearly 20 years after his mission, he cheerfully greeted us where the road ended and led us down an uneven dirt path to the two-room home he shared with his wife and three children. It was an extremely hot and uncomfortable day. He still walked with great difficulty, but there was no self-pity. Through personal diligence, he has become a teacher, providing schooling for the village children. When we entered his modest house, he immediately took me to a corner and pulled out a box that contained his most important possessions. He wanted me to see a piece of paper. It read, “With good wishes and blessings to Elder Nulu, a courageous and happy missionary; [dated] June 25, 1987; [signed] Boyd K. Packer.” On that occasion, when then-Elder Packer visited India and spoke to a group of missionaries, he affirmed to Elder Nulu his potential. In essence, what Brother Nulu was telling me that day in 2006 was that the gospel had changed him—permanently!</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men.p14" pid="KiluDBoIlUq9XZ1fspqYjQ" hash="bzlfYA">On this visit to the Nulu home, we were accompanied by the mission president. He was there to interview Brother Nulu, his wife, and his children—for the parents to receive their endowments and be sealed and for the children to be sealed to their parents. We also presented the family with arrangements for them to travel to the Hong Kong China Temple for these ordinances. They wept with joy as their long-awaited dream was to be realized.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men.p15" pid="fkj0VKKlnkmHWnQWb6sBlA" hash="7KeZPw">
			<span class="pageBreak" page-number="55"></span>What is expected of a holder of the priesthood of God? What changes are required of us to become the manner of men we ought to be? I make three suggestions:</p>
		<div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men.f1">
			<ol class="number" guid="">
				<li pid="OaZZqGNCgEWXYkFadwTrAQ" hash="Iq9Bog">
					<span class="label">1. </span>
					<p pid="r2oLDFlKh0GRWxQHSeVTWw" hash="FxCaeg">We need to be priesthood men! Whether we are young men holding the Aaronic Priesthood or men bearing the Melchizedek Priesthood, we need to be priesthood men, showing spiritual maturity because we have made covenants. As Paul said, “When I was a child, I spake as a child, I understood as a child, I thought as a child: but when I became a man, I put away childish things” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/13.11" class="scriptureRef">1 Corinthians 13:11</a>). We should be different because we hold the priesthood—not arrogant or prideful or patronizing but humble and teachable and meek. Receiving the priesthood and its various offices should mean something to us. It should not be a perfunctory “rite of passage” that automatically happens at certain ages but a sacred act of covenant thoughtfully made. We should feel so privileged and so grateful that our every action shows it. If we seldom even think about the priesthood, we need to change.</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="PQIljCpo2kS0YCfoySrC-w" hash="3dWQaQ">
					<span class="label">2. </span>
					<p pid="OMKrKVHt_0CNSIN72ZH-Uw" hash="hlQy1Q">We need to serve! The essence of holding the priesthood is to magnify our calling (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.33" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:33</a>) by serving others. Avoiding our most important duty to serve our wives and children, not accepting or passively fulfilling callings in the Church, or not caring about others unless it is convenient is not who we should be. The Savior declared, “Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.37" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 22:37</a>) and later added, “If thou lovest me thou shalt serve me” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.29" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:29</a>). Selfishness is the antithesis of priesthood responsibility, and if it is a trait of our character, we need to change.</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="eJnXN7tLQECoifGRTYC9qg" hash="wpGJPQ">
					<span class="label">3. </span>
					<p pid="LSQN4PmOCkGj3IN4w29Ddg" hash="X92b0w">We need to be worthy! I may not have the ability of Elder Jeffrey R. Holland when he spoke in a priesthood session a few years ago to “get in your face … , nose to nose, with just enough fire … to singe your eyebrows” (“We Are All Enlisted,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign</span> or <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> Nov. 2011, 45); but, dear brethren, we need to wake up to how commonly accepted practices in the world choke our power in the priesthood. If we think we can even flirt with pornography or violations of chastity or dishonesty in any form and not have it negatively affect us and our families, we are deceived. Moroni stated, “See that ye do all things in worthiness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/morm/9.29" class="scriptureRef">Mormon 9:29</a>). The Lord powerfully directed, “And I now give unto you a commandment to beware concerning yourselves, to give diligent heed to the words of eternal life” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.43" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:43</a>). If there are any unresolved sins preventing our worthiness, we need to change.</p>
				</li>
			</ol>
		</div>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men.p19" pid="9FEhQ07eiUGcSD06baEdaA" hash="cWBzXg">The only complete response to the question posed by Jesus Christ “What manner of men ought ye to be?” is the one He succinctly and profoundly gave: “Even as I am” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.27" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 27:27</a>). The invitation to “come unto Christ, and be perfected in him” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.32" class="scriptureRef">Moroni 10:32</a>) both requires and expects change. Mercifully, He has not left us alone. “And if men come unto me I will show unto them their weakness. … Then will I make weak things become strong” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.27" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:27</a>). Relying upon the Savior’s Atonement, we can change. Of this I am certain. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/04/what-manner-of-men</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2014-general-conference/2014-04-3020-elder-donald-l-hallstrom-64k-eng.mp3" length="5760472" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2014 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Am a Child of God</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13285_000_23hallstrom" doc-version="2" hash="WZOorA"&gt;
	
	&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.head1"&gt;
		&lt;h1 class="title" pid="_cjrVmMdQ0-dJcSoLwKS5Q" hash="Sxrctg"&gt;I &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;Am&lt;/span&gt; a Child of God&lt;/h1&gt;
		&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p2" pid="T9VVmQ3E00iiueXkL3Ad1g" hash="PVwkhA1"&gt;By Elder Donald L. Hallstrom&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p3" pid="_nyz55bbgE-_StjXR6JTZg" hash="hptprg"&gt;Of the Presidency of the Seventy&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=cwx5a3tKbUWpe9MAey0LEQ"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" altText="Elder Donald L. Hallstrom" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255743/5060933cb79b4d8b8d0afdf5e8033b1f/103x130.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x63="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255743/5060933cb79b4d8b8d0afdf5e8033b1f/50x63.jpg" data-src-103x130="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255743/5060933cb79b4d8b8d0afdf5e8033b1f/103x130.jpg" webURL="elder-donald-l-hallstrom-lds_1255743.jpg" pid="cwx5a3tKbUWpe9MAey0LEQ" hash="AAAAAA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="kicker" pid="OmIc5ptcAUmiy8EYGEeJew" hash="fskdNA"&gt;A correct understanding of our heavenly heritage is essential to exaltation.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="authorName" pid="J6VWa74SQ0yEWaffejX4Nw" hash="PVwkhA"&gt;By Elder Donald L. Hallstrom&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class="bodyBlock"&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p5" pid="moN0fKDU2kGx6XOnmmjoBw" hash="OMRLmA"&gt;Our most fundamental doctrine includes the knowledge that we are children of a living God. That is why one of His most sacred names is Father—Heavenly Father. This doctrine has been clearly taught by prophets through the ages:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;ol class="number"&gt;
			&lt;li pid="WIUM9DicSU6V4xeC7sVL_A" hash="YTnVaA"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p6" pid="HmOXEJJkzEaCSZiOYsSftA" hash="zEby4g"&gt;When tempted by Satan, Moses rebuffed him, saying: “Who art thou? For behold, I am a &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;son of God.&lt;/span&gt;”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="-byDYEPsAUelKtqJKwwJWQ" hash="B4mUzA"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p7" pid="Thznzd0ZV0e827yzNMqgRw" hash="zWBBog"&gt;Addressing Israel, the Psalmist proclaimed, “All of you are &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;children of the most High.&lt;/span&gt;”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="a-598C6wXEycWujjrAFm-w" hash="blzUwg"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;3.&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p8" pid="LaWu1Kf-JEiL6qQXf2CODA" hash="TDXwFw"&gt;Paul taught the Athenians on Mars Hill that they were &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;“offspring of God.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="0Pwh_-UyRk-oLYsYFErXpA" hash="t0BOlw"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;4.&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p9" pid="uTZhIcHCdkmLe8nvQ9-bSw" hash="TfFeNQ"&gt;Joseph Smith and Sidney Rigdon received a vision in which they saw the Father and the Son, and a heavenly voice declared that the inhabitants of the worlds “are &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;begotten sons and daughters unto God.&lt;/span&gt;”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="SAPUb2XXokm-C5AYzv9uhQ" hash="61Fu_A"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;5.&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p10" pid="hyl3x9VW6UekTTkGdsLWcg" hash="BT_BCQ"&gt;In 1995, the 15 living apostles and prophets affirmed: “All human beings … are created in the image of God. Each is a &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;beloved spirit son or daughter of heavenly parents.&lt;/span&gt;”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="J_xS0J-vfkuJlQ7V3X7_9w" hash="lW4VRg"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;6.&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p11" pid="xnRqKjVLkkylfHYnqsjklQ" hash="INDgiA"&gt;President Thomas S. Monson testified: “We are &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;sons and daughters of a living God. …&lt;/span&gt; We cannot sincerely hold this conviction without experiencing a profound new sense of strength and power.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p12" pid="wCJDgcI3RkCowauvvmyfmA" hash="L_XZaw"&gt;This doctrine is so basic, so oft stated, and so instinctively simple that it can seem to be ordinary, when in reality it is among the most extraordinary knowledge we can obtain. A correct understanding of our heavenly heritage is essential to exaltation. It is foundational to comprehending the glorious plan of salvation and to nurturing faith in the Firstborn of the Father, Jesus the Christ, and in His merciful Atonement.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt; Further, it provides continual motivation for us to make and keep our indispensable eternal covenants.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p13" pid="eTvk_81-sUyk-ASMRODL2Q" hash="_hjUSQ"&gt;With few exceptions, everyone participating in this meeting could right now, without written lyrics or music, sing “I Am a Child of God.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8"&gt;8&lt;/span&gt; This beloved hymn is one of the most often sung in this Church. But the critical question is, do we &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;really&lt;/span&gt; know it? Do we know it in our mind and in our heart and in our soul? Is our heavenly parentage our first and most profound identity?&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p14" pid="6N8CuRpPp0CRafuvvKmNuw" hash="ycDbMw"&gt;Here on earth, we identify ourselves in many different ways, including our place of birth, our nationality, and our language. Some even identify themselves by their occupation or their hobby. These earthly identities are not wrong &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;unless&lt;/span&gt; they supersede or interfere with our eternal identity—that of being a son or a daughter of God.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p15" pid="4mLVf5B3Ik-By6WPN5Bs9Q" hash="b1EwKw"&gt;When our youngest child was six years old and in the first grade at school, her teacher gave the children an in-class writing assignment. It was October, the month of Halloween, a holiday observed in some parts of the world. While it is not my favorite holiday, I suppose there may be some innocent and redeeming aspects of Halloween.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p16" pid="t1dWY5uow0SO8GUvj-gnTQ" hash="YvzEkg"&gt;The teacher passed out a piece of paper to the young students. At the top was a roughly drawn picture of a mythical witch (I told you this was not my favorite holiday) standing over a boiling cauldron. The question posed on the page, to encourage the imaginations of the children and to test their rudimentary writing skills, was “You have just drunk a cup of the witch’s brew. What happened to you?” Please know that this story is not being shared as a recommendation to teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p17" pid="Z7F-g-k_pUebSCdWhkKhBw" hash="XbWDjQ"&gt;“You have just drunk a cup of the witch’s brew. What happened to you?” With her best beginner’s writing, our little one wrote, “I will die and I will be in heaven. I will like it there. I would love it because it is the best place to be because you are with your Heavenly Father.” This answer likely surprised her teacher; however, when our daughter brought the completed assignment home, we noted that she was given a star, the highest grade.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p18" pid="k8N2wAcEXU-ZYxoqTOYoRw" hash="EEdZwg"&gt;In real life, we face actual, not imagined, hardships. There is pain—physical, emotional, and spiritual. There are heartbreaks when circumstances are very different from what we had anticipated. There is injustice when we do not seem to deserve our situation. There are disappointments when someone we trusted failed us. There are health and financial setbacks that can be disorienting. There may be times of question when a matter of doctrine or history is beyond our current understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p19" pid="hfbhnwfFZEu06C1bGU1ynA" hash="MmOkKA"&gt;When difficult things occur in our lives, what is our immediate response? Is it confusion or doubt or spiritual withdrawal? Is it a blow to our faith? Do we blame God or others for our circumstances? Or is our first response to remember who we are—that we are children of a loving God? Is that coupled with an absolute trust that He allows some earthly suffering &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;because&lt;/span&gt; He knows it will bless us, like a refiner’s fire, to become like Him and to gain our eternal inheritance?&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9"&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p20" pid="kN8UEc1iPkKXGdE6oRjqjQ" hash="nsnEjA"&gt;Recently, I was in a meeting with Elder Jeffrey R. Holland. In teaching the principle that mortal life can be agonizing but our hardships have eternal purpose—even if we do not understand it at the time—Elder Holland said, “You can have what you want, or you can have something better.”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p21" pid="kQoGpkTwN02Vx5uAG1F3Ag" hash="MMMEPw"&gt;Five months ago, my wife, Diane, and I went to Africa with Elder and Sister David A. Bednar. The sixth and last country we visited was Liberia. Liberia is a great country with a noble people and a rich history, but things have not been easy there. Decades of political instability and civil wars have worsened the plague of poverty. On top of that, the dreaded Ebola disease killed nearly 5,000 people there during the latest outbreak. We were the first group of Church leaders from outside the area to visit Monrovia, the capital city, since the World Health Organization declared it safe to do so after the Ebola crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p22" pid="Yxv3aErGb0KnSyceD9SBxg" hash="fSabIA"&gt;On a very hot and humid Sunday morning, we traveled to a rented meeting facility in the center of the city. Every available chair was set up, totaling 3,500 seats. The final count of attendees was 4,100. Almost all who came had to travel by foot or some form of inconvenient public transportation; it was not easy for the Saints to gather. But they came. Most arrived several hours before the appointed meeting time. As we entered the hall, the spiritual atmosphere was electric! The Saints were prepared to be taught.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p23" pid="DC7aG8bAbU6P8VumfvNlVg" hash="twJHVw"&gt;When a speaker quoted a scripture, the members would say the verse aloud. It did not matter—short scripture or long; the entire congregation responded in unison. Now, we do not necessarily recommend this, but it was certainly impressive that they could do it. And the choir—they were powerful. With an enthusiastic choir director and a 14-year-old young man at the keyboard, the members sang with vigor and strength.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p24" pid="vGwBjaKBAUeDOtL_3cm7Xw" hash="IKH9BQ"&gt;Then Elder Bednar spoke. This, of course, was the anticipated highlight of the gathering—to hear an Apostle teach and testify. Clearly with spiritual direction, partway through his remarks, Elder Bednar stopped and said, “Do you know ‘How Firm a Foundation’?”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p25" pid="ryfzr-mgzUOwPJxOTbPkOA" hash="GY5jtw"&gt;It seemed that 4,100 voices roared in response, “YES!”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p26" pid="vHoV4AeCxUOFKct4yP3SEw" hash="f3Jweg"&gt;He then asked, “Do you know verse 7?”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p27" pid="ey0kmuZhpUaGK6uZIeA4aA" hash="envMtg"&gt;Again the entire group answered, “YES!”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p28" pid="NmwG2U37RUOM0nvW9B_Xcw" hash="CiUzHQ"&gt;The arrangement of the mighty hymn “How Firm a Foundation” sung by the Mormon Tabernacle Choir for the last 10 years has included verse 7, which was not sung much previously. Elder Bednar instructed, “Let’s sing verses 1, 2, 3, and 7.”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p29" pid="JgvbQU99w0yssJ4nn-kd5g" hash="qpEvgA"&gt;Without hesitation, the choir director jumped up and the Aaronic Priesthood–bearing accompanist immediately began to energetically play the introductory chords. With a level of conviction I have never felt before in a congregational hymn, we sang verses 1, 2, and 3. Then the volume and spiritual power was elevated when 4,100 voices sang the seventh verse and declared:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;div class="poetry"&gt;
			&lt;div class="stanza"&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p30" pid="Mfnl4MthvU-QFcl8EZawxw" hash="GXMgtQ"&gt;The soul that on Jesus hath leaned for repose&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p31" pid="QhDTFRF9CU6a8Jowid6VaQ" hash="S-taFQ"&gt;I will not, I cannot, desert to his foes;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p32" pid="SYYCx0dx_Eya0PyNIk5DUg" hash="BiVvuQ"&gt;That soul, though all hell should endeavor to shake,&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p33" pid="ZIXGm95jAkKS8KSfjR59qg" hash="y152Ug"&gt;I’ll never, no never, I’ll never, no never,&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p34" pid="Ii0zBCOHm0uoe5lyKrxJUg" hash="YJEd7g"&gt;I’ll never, no never, no never forsake!&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p35" pid="qIIZVgx6a06T4mn9gZeD_Q" hash="Raa__Q"&gt;In one of the most remarkable spiritual events of my life, I was taught a profound lesson that day. We live in a world that can cause us to forget who we really are. The more distractions that surround us, the easier it is to treat casually, then ignore, and then forget our connection with God. The Saints in Liberia have little materially, and yet they seem to have everything spiritually. What we witnessed that day in Monrovia was a group of sons and daughters of God who knew it!&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god.p36" pid="4lgIlvWLtUyzoIzEI7-V2w" hash="5KzsLw"&gt;In today’s world, no matter where we live and no matter what our circumstances are, it is essential that our preeminent identity is as a child of God. &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;Knowing&lt;/span&gt; that will allow our faith to flourish, will motivate our continual repentance, and will provide the strength to “be steadfast and immovable” throughout our mortal journey.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11"&gt;11&lt;/span&gt; In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/04/i-am-a-child-of-god</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2016-general-conference/2016-04-1030-donald-l-hallstrom-64k-eng.mp3" length="5572243" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
