<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Dwan J. Young</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Dwan J. Young.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Dwan%20J.%20Young.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Dwan J. Young.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 1982 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>An Invitation to Grow</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The following addresses were delivered at the General Women’s Meeting held Saturday evening, March 27, in the Tabernacle, Salt Lake City. Latter-day Saint women twelve and older gathered to view the locally televised broadcast; the program was also v</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03148_000_041" doc-version="2" hash="5mbWPA">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="1bO1G7EIzkKtUoYURopfRA" hash="jmF4IA">An Invitation to Grow</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="BIw-MjQrAEKHXJP45z6IrA" hash="3inxug">Dwan J. Young</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.t1">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p1" pid="XofRzZ5PaEC1I1FqL27nFg" hash="DdpE5w">The following addresses were delivered at the General Women’s Meeting held Saturday evening, March 27, in the Tabernacle, Salt Lake City. Latter-day Saint women twelve and older gathered to view the locally televised broadcast; the program was also viewed live in areas where satellite dishes were in operation. Videotapes of the program have been supplied to each region of the Church worldwide.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p2" pid="tzVQMLui5k-yR3r4uO4Pkw" hash="ABR4rQ">In addition to prerecorded taped segments, speakers at the meeting were, in the following order: Sister Dwan J. Young, general president of the Primary; Sister Elaine A. Cannon, general president of the Young Women; Sister Barbara Smith, general president of the Relief Society; and Elder Mark E. Petersen of the Quorum of the Twelve.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p3" pid="GWaLUmkmo0yBg7GTNiFpVg" hash="OpNHVw">Theme for the meeting was “The Legacy—Remembered and Renewed.”</p>
			<img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/ensignlp.nfo-o-274e.jpg" alt="Dwan J. Young" pid="P4dumJwYs02yTcQY4zDkmg" hash="SMgpXg" />
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p4" pid="K481X2Q3-EeFWnxuk2E6uA" hash="DzkAvw">Annette, your voice has filled this hall with beautiful music as you pled, “Teach me, teach me.” In many parts of the world, I have looked at other children one by one who were singing this same song. (See “Teach Me to Walk in the Light,” <span class="emphasis">Sing with Me,</span> p. B-45.) I prayed then, as I pray now, that there is someone close-by who is teaching you to walk in the light.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p5" pid="4VZuiSP930Kz4I_vkA6lvg" hash="JCikZA">Each of us comes into this world separately, one by one. This is not an accident. I think it’s the Lord’s way of reminding us of the infinite worth of each soul.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p6" pid="sG-IbHEUv0uFSJhsIMzhBg" hash="hTsJRw">There is something very sacred about the time of birth. I remember so clearly the coming forth of each of my own children. My firstborn came after three years of desperate waiting. He was very small, only five pounds. I felt so responsible. It seemed like such a miracle and there was a great surge of gratitude. Now I had a baby of my very own. With each child came a sharper realization of life’s challenges and possibilities. Rocking my babies to sleep, I sang them the lullabies which came to my lips—soft, private words, carrying my dreams for their future. I have marveled at this miracle of potential that we cradle in our arms: the ultimate of creation, a human child.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p7" pid="GqlCqlw2RkuY3l3BmS2evw" hash="zpVuyw">Growth is inevitable. This is the natural phenomenon of life itself. It quickly becomes apparent that the child is engaged in some dynamic process of physical growth over which one has very little control. Shortly the birth weight is doubled. Turn around, as the song says, and they’re three. Turn around, and they’re four. Turn around, and they’re a young man or woman going out of the door.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p8" pid="RFl_2i2y9EqpgSTzaNiQDw" hash="UL3w3A">As young children start to learn, it’s like opening a floodgate. There’s no stopping, no end to their capacity to grow and to learn. First they imitate, and then they move out on their own. I was always astonished when it seemed like we had to show our children only once some new skill, some new task, and then they were swept away on their own, pursuing their own star.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p9" pid="0jPtY-3hz0KY45YdglWh0g" hash="lsGpVg">As we observe the process of natural growth, we become acutely aware of certain eternal principles upon which all growth is predicated. First, growth is the expected norm. It’s the divine challenge given to each soul as it enters mortality. Our Heavenly Father expects us to use the great gift of life to enjoy and to celebrate this central truth. Because we have life, we can grow and develop and do some things on earth we cannot do anywhere else.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p10" pid="9FwACzo-W0ynlpjnMuRuZw" hash="whKfhQ">Very soon we become aware of another great truth. Only God’s children have the capacity to direct their own growth. This means that we can use this time on earth to bring optimum growth and development because we have the power to make choices. It’s not enough just to grow. Even the weeds and the biblical tares can do that. It is expected of us that we will shape our growth so that we will not be like Topsy (in <span class="emphasis">Uncle Tom’s Cabin</span>) who “just growed,” but rather we will successfully negotiate the bumps and curves by enlarging upon our talents, by disciplining ourselves, so that our mortal experience brings us toward greater and greater mastery of those characteristics which make us worthy of association with the Divine.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p11" pid="OQMnZRifxECXvuFRfw0eGQ" hash="QJoDYA">Intelligent observation tells us that growth comes one step at a time. The scriptures say precept upon precept, line upon line. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/98.12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 98:12</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p12" pid="J9G9VhPsYE6JQliHw2usDA" hash="IcdB4Q">Just as the baby learns to walk one faltering step at a time and learns to speak one word at a time, we learn to care, to serve, and to love one step at a time. We learn to master everything one concept at a time.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p13" pid="gHOGMALF4U2ynj_B0LzYYA" hash="QM99Cw">The Lord has carefully explained this great truth to us in 2 Nephi 28:30:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p14" pid="vLnk3G1IVkSa_xk0L9OIxw" hash="bp1Vyg">“I will give unto the children of men line upon line, precept upon precept, … and blessed are those who hearken unto my precepts, and lend an ear unto my counsel, for they shall learn wisdom; for unto him that receiveth I will give more; and from them that shall say, We have enough, from them shall be taken away even that which they have.” [<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/28.30" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 28:30</a>]</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p15" pid="CbOvN6ELQUutsFOWCSAesg" hash="RiQZXQ">There’s a kind of wonder and awe that comes to us as we observe the natural phenomenon of physical growth. You remember the song that says, “I don’t remember growing older,” or “When did he grow to be so tall?” (“Sunrise, Sunset,” <span class="emphasis">Fiddler on the Roof</span>.) We have a special place in our home where the children record their height on the wall. With the help of a book placed on top of their head, they can tell if they’ve grown since the last mark was made. Cheers are heard if they’ve made progress. That is natural growth. But what greater joy and satisfaction comes when the change that is wrought has come about by constant personal choice and effort!</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p16" pid="ng_D7sh3W0CQEyF_DMI6Bw" hash="0cgEIg">I’m reminded of the little child who came to her daddy and said, “Give me something <span class="emphasis">hard</span> to do.” So he thought of things she could do, but she would say, “No, daddy, that isn’t hard enough. I want something hard to do.” He was carrying his briefcase into the house, and he said, “Well, carry this; this will be very hard to carry.” She grabbed hold. Oh, boy, it was heavy! She said, “I think I can.” She struggled and staggered until she finally got it to the house. We all like to feel that we have met the challenge of something hard to do.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p17" pid="sDyOFm_c_k2eN_Drg9IJcg" hash="ItcKyg">Be aware that growth is a process. It is never fully and finally achieved; it’s just a steady picking our way upward along the mountain path. Ultimately the process requires hope and faith. We have potential for development much like the seed Alma so eloquently described which, when tended and nurtured, will burst into full flower. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.28-43" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:28–43</a>.) Once the preparation is completed, full growth is realized only when we have the faith to venture forth.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p18" pid="KJAwA7qLu0-zdkigL1w6Rw" hash="Ud1kHQ">Remember the words of Victor Hugo:</p>
			<div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.f2">
				<div class="stanza">
					<p class="line" pid="_4FIOxrdgEymrAHO3gCsgQ" hash="ZKvQ3A">
						<span class="emphasis">Be like the bird, who</span>
					</p>
					<p class="line" pid="3C6RX0L6P0Wxd9M6gpM6Hg" hash="WQgllQ">
						<span class="emphasis">Halting in his flight</span>
					</p>
					<p class="line" pid="fMD8Z57FEUqIyZGCitpUmw" hash="N0ihSg">
						<span class="emphasis">On limb to slight</span>
					</p>
					<p class="line" pid="MBllo2vaYUCqMUb7WWrQ-g" hash="sn7eww">
						<span class="emphasis">Feels it give way beneath him,</span>
					</p>
					<p class="line" pid="LekMrqsHkUiq_0Vk6gtP8Q" hash="FAzIdQ">
						<span class="emphasis">Yet sings</span>
					</p>
					<p class="line" pid="aXsb_-tqq0q_3qoc1y4dtg" hash="slkdPw">
						<span class="emphasis">Knowing he hath wings.</span>
					</p>
				</div>
			</div>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p19" pid="vPelaObSt0u1Jul-vsiDRQ" hash="2ba-Tw">Each new truth becomes ours only as we, like the bird, realize that we’re not afraid to venture forth and live by truth, knowing that we too have the capacity to fly.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p20" pid="n5KWGU-950Gh76lUdJ8jZw" hash="q66y-Q">When a baby is very small, parents often make the choices which direct its path. But slowly, surely, as the body and spirit mature, the matter of choice becomes personal and individual. Someone has observed: “You yourself must set flame to the torches which you have brought.” (<span class="emphasis">Words of Life,</span> ed. Charles L. Wallis, New York: Harper &amp; Row, 1966, p. 91.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p21" pid="1LJXKwoop0ivwu6ag6nCiw" hash="8F0iig">As we struggle forward each day intent upon accepting the Lord’s invitation to have life and have it more abundantly (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/10.10" class="scriptureRef">John 10:10</a>), let us remember the great truth that we, as God’s children, have the capacity to direct our own growth.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow.p22" pid="JGcZvBSVDESReGT3kJmo_g" hash="e_xUXA">May our Heavenly Father strengthen and guide us as we accept his invitation to grow. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1982/04/an-invitation-to-grow</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1982-general-womens-meeting/1982-03-7010-dwan-j-young-64k-eng.mp3" length="8579220" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 1982 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prepare to Teach His Children</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Tonight I want to tell you about a girl who was a pianist of some promise. When she was quite small, her mother sat with her on the piano bench each day, taught her the notes, and encouraged her to practice while she learned those first pieces.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03167_000_037" doc-version="2" hash="0wR9YQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="6gGcks7E6Eaa0o23QqVYhw" hash="8Bk0gw">Prepare to Teach His Children</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="4QgipySM_Uq75gmGHyOYxQ" hash="3inxug">Dwan J. Young</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/ensignlp.nfo-o-274e.jpg" alt="Dwan J. Young" pid="pjUMAE-l-k-otWeemA9ciA" hash="SMgpXg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p1" pid="IOmvTm2C0kCXHR7SdG6PtA" hash="Ax1RQQ">Tonight I want to tell you about a girl who was a pianist of some promise. When she was quite small, her mother sat with her on the piano bench each day, taught her the notes, and encouraged her to practice while she learned those first pieces.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p2" pid="0oAfMvK5AUWb4VRDdiob9A" hash="6a8jIQ">Soon this wise mother decided she had taught her as much as she knew and that her daughter should begin taking lessons from a professional teacher. The young woman was encouraged constantly, and while in high school she had the opportunity to play part of a piano concerto with a symphony orchestra.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p3" pid="4InXTs5XLEqTG40NOZhh9Q" hash="47RK8Q">As she entered the hall the night of the concert, there was excitement in her heart. She felt confident and ready because her preparation had been thorough. She took her place at the piano bench. The conductor lifted his baton, and she raised her eyes to watch for his signal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p4" pid="AO-sV7FchkmBcQh3k4bwvQ" hash="byWThg">Suddenly her eye caught the face of someone she knew. It shifted her attention so that, when the conductor gave the cue, she could not respond. Her mind went blank; her memory failed; her fingers froze; she could not think of the beginning notes. The conductor cued her once more; still no response. Finally, after an agonizing pause, someone passed her the music so she could begin.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p5" pid="FhBWC5TUVUyzEgILhy-ZVw" hash="89qWnw">When the number was over, she rushed from the stage, thoroughly devastated by what had happened. She wanted the earth to open up and swallow her. Anything would do, so long as she didn’t have to face her parents, her friends, the orchestra members, or any of the audience. Suddenly, in one brief moment, her whole life stopped, so she thought. But of course it didn’t. She had to stand up and walk out of that concert hall.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p6" pid="_31ofY4x6ke_8Cbl7TICCA" hash="h3RF2Q">She didn’t die; the world didn’t stop. In fact, there is no record that it even skipped a beat on that momentous day. I know because I was there—I was that girl. I lived to play other pieces and to perform before other audiences because my teacher said I could. And my parents reminded me that I must go on. The humiliation still races through me when I think about it. But I have come to realize that my life did not end that night because, though I had been preparing for a piano performance, I had also been preparing in other ways. Perhaps more significantly, others had been teaching me and preparing me to pick myself up and try again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p7" pid="qtdExNa2GUOwF8irAt3v0w" hash="rauEZA">My time of preparation had been carefully guided by people who loved me to include experiences with gospel principles. Those teachings were well cultivated inside me so that, when the time of hurt and embarrassment came, I knew I was not alone. I knew there was more to the valued experience of life than playing the piano.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p8" pid="ee8RKNqBHE-seb8ANX8zJA" hash="sF63gQ">The scriptures tell us to “train up a child in the way he should go, and … he will not depart from it.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/22.6" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 22:6</a>.) One of the major assignments given to parents is to teach their children the gospel. This provides what others have called a “value system.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p9" pid="XGjiUMl9P0eRUfbsV4zFlQ" hash="QlHpTw">This plan outlined by the Lord is designed to impress us with the worth of human life and the profound importance of the individual. He has revealed that there is purpose in living. That purpose is for each of us to learn those Christlike attributes which will make us worthy of eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p10" pid="7G60uTWQm0Wv_Qg0Vo0K-w" hash="H1g80g">Mortality is the time to learn to walk by faith. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/2-cor/5.7" class="scriptureRef">2 Cor. 5:7</a>.) It is the time to learn to be doers of the word, not hearers only. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.22" class="scriptureRef">James 1:22</a>.) It is the time to gain knowledge and master some wisdom. It is the time to realize that it is not enough to know; we must also act on knowledge with wisdom. And finally, by the Lord’s definition, it is the time to learn how to love one another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p11" pid="wbCCA1OHEkCQpgC_I6YTeA" hash="34PjKQ">President Kimball says the Lord sends us on his errands (see <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1981, p. 78), for it is the best way we learn about charity—that perfect love of Christ—the love which nurtures and renews. Charity is the power which changes human life. It is the power which soothes the aching heart and restores the soul. Charity comes to us from the Lord and from those who see our needs. It comes into our lives when we give loving service to someone else in need.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p12" pid="QDl3a2dItUmyGqutkRf5rQ" hash="fMmOcA">To have faith and understand that each of us is truly a child of God gives assurance to our sense of worth. These are the important things which he has asked us to teach our children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p13" pid="8NAToZCNxkqceD7cPpeLaw" hash="QS5Ong">But before we can teach our children, we must understand and live the principles ourselves. It is vital that the child learn from our example that what we say and what we live are the same.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p14" pid="jWIOV34jykSx2VZdfJ1BUw" hash="4dJpVg">Mothers and fathers need to read the words of the Lord with their children and discuss the scriptures constantly. It is only through hearing the word and watching it manifest itself in our lives that children come to be familiar with the voice of the Good Shepherd. As we cuddle those infant children, we sing lullabies and talk of important things. In the soft and gentle arms of a mother’s love, children can come to know the voice of the Lord. Then, in later years, when the stress of living comes, the soul has at its command the teachings and the tools by which to overcome.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p15" pid="RJ_cTE3aAEqGI1N9uUZwWg" hash="zLYGtw">We learn and grow ourselves; we teach and prepare our children; but an additional responsibility given to all of us is that of feeding the sheep. You will remember when Peter appealed to the Lord with his declarations of faith and loyalty, Jesus turned to him and said, “Feed my lambs.” “Feed my sheep.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/21.15-16" class="scriptureRef">John 21:15–16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p16" pid="ZMEBotMo3UeajioCWZdS8A" hash="GoKpxw">Beyond ourselves, beyond our family circles, we have responsibility. We must reach out to give others that same testimony which we have cultivated in our own souls and extended to our children. Wherever we are called to serve, we must remember the responsibility to feed his lambs and give them an understanding of their real worth and eternal potential.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p17" pid="KUIDLeQiokGU8GkQbuzKIg" hash="NLdcsQ">In our day-to-day living we will associate with neighbors, shopkeepers, plumbers, and builders. The lineup of people with whom our lives cross is almost endless. How will our behavior affect them in their search for meaning and faith? I expect our example is part of the feeding his sheep that the Lord called to our attention.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p18" pid="4JjvV9XYRE2XpSeahDn3RQ" hash="Vnxrgw">The time to prepare is now. In the parable of the wise and foolish virgins, the Lord reminds us that we need to be prepared when the Bridegroom cometh. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.1-13" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:1–13</a>.) We need to recommit ourselves to the daily tasks of living the gospel. We need to learn to pray by praying every day. We need to learn to hear the word of the Lord by studying the scriptures every day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p19" pid="c2_mpr4KUkqrwKoQ2RqEtQ" hash="wyOvOQ">Preparing for gospel living really is very much like learning the piano after all. We cannot learn the notes from afar. Our fingers have to touch the keys time after time after time. Our teachers have to direct our learning experience. We have to give children opportunities to make decisions, to give love and service until they know how to do it on their own. We have to show them how to seek the Lord’s help in bearing grief and pain and seek his direction and his sustaining power.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children.p20" pid="JFL6L4XxAUmzReGDGUvl2Q" hash="_Y9NXw">Now is the time for each of us to prepare—to gain the strength necessary to meet our individual challenges. I know the Lord is anxious to respond to us if we will only turn to him. I pray that we will all have the faith necessary to be receptive to his promptings, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1983/10/prepare-to-teach-his-children</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1983-general-womens-meeting/1983-09-0020-dwan-j-young-64k-eng.mp3" length="4574329" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 1983 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping the Covenants We Make at Baptism</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In July my husband and I went to Philmont, the Scout training center in New Mexico. Gathered there were 150 priesthood leaders and their families in that beautiful camp where the plain meets the soaring, pine-covered mountains.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03180_000_037" doc-version="2" hash="LGegzw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="QdyGOLkmG02ODgdBFKtX4w" hash="nbBW-A">Keeping the Covenants We Make at Baptism</h1><p class="authorName" guid="64d47568-da38-4104-8e3b-f259589c2a88" pid="JtSG1SD3Fk6MVKoUUZyNFA" hash="3inxug">Dwan J. Young</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="92b90700-f28f-4cb4-bf3e-094092ed2c19">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/ensignlp.nfo-o-274e.jpg" alt="Dwan J. Young" guid="976c2918-2792-4379-9360-9f25b3fe6f35" pid="ayGFglzMX0uEYhRmJB_ulg" hash="SMgpXg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="gCT60j0CtkOfnIjamwJYew" hash="I_Q8ng">In July my husband and I went to Philmont, the Scout training center in New Mexico. Gathered there were 150 priesthood leaders and their families in that beautiful camp where the plain meets the soaring, pine-covered mountains.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="MLmXLmo-rk6Tl2UEHob1NA" hash="vK0veQ">Jeremy Judd was there with his family, and he celebrated his eighth birthday during that week. Because Jeremy wanted to be baptized on his eighth birthday, his father, Alma, made the arrangements. That Saturday afternoon I participated in one of the most spiritual baptismal experiences of my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="tYPD4FXkJEyaZ3dnWZ8WTA" hash="2tYnOQ">Baptismal clothes were borrowed from a nearby ward. We drove to a stream located about fifteen minutes from camp where the water was deep enough to perform the ordinance. It was a secluded spot in the wilderness. A bank overlooked the stream as it flowed through a clearing of stately cottonwoods. We stood in the high grass and listened carefully as first the mother and then the father spoke to their son about the ordinance that was about to be performed. They reminded Jeremy of the importance of the covenant he was about to make. They indicated that the covenant he was making was a promise, or an agreement, to obey all the laws of the gospel. They told him he should consider baptism as the entrance into a new life—with the Savior as his example.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="Wb5S4x3qA0ukjW76Inc8mg" hash="t4fhbw">Then the father took his son by the hand and walked down the bank, over the pebbles, and into the water. There he immersed his young son in the water of the clear-flowing stream after the pattern given by the Lord. The boy’s sixteen-year-old sister stood by my side, and tears streamed down her cheeks as she whispered, “I am so happy for Jeremy.” I too was happy for Jeremy, and at that moment I remembered the joy I felt at my own baptism.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="UF3aSAzBh0WAaXidSMX2-g" hash="jGM3xw">After Jeremy had changed his clothes, he stood in the clearing while his father and the other brethren laid their hands upon his head and confirmed him a member of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="fFMq1cxDsEyO0cCNQnRH1w" hash="ePo9YQ">With the sunlight on his wet hair and a radiance on his face, Jeremy felt a reverent calm, and he confided in me with wonder and excitement, “I was baptized in a river just like Jesus!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="mEmqu6E1nUe5WAGaBb1jnQ" hash="Yujq2g">The spot in the River Jordan where Jesus was baptized by John the Baptist must have looked something like this beautiful place where we stood. I could almost hear John protesting, “I have need to be baptized of thee, and comest thou to me?” Then the quiet, calm reply of the Savior, “Suffer it to be so now: for thus it becometh us to fulfil all righteousness.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/3.14-15" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 3:14–15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="vw3l07haQ0iifz07qrzGuw" hash="ucLJ3w">And Jesus was baptized to fulfill the law and to give us the pattern to follow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="bmGyPOjH5ECOq6-Qz_lmbQ" hash="WtqhqQ">When Jeremy’s father said amen to the words of his son’s confirmation prayer, I looked at that young boy and wondered if he was ready for the responsibility of the covenant he had just made. Would he follow the teachings of Jesus by living a new and renewed life? Did he understand his commitment to bear witness to the world of Jesus Christ?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="ZFqQ7ac0-0CwVMcxRQqGrw" hash="xBGxWg">I think a great deal about these things because children are my special concern. I tell you that they <span class="emphasis">can</span> and <span class="emphasis">do</span> honor their commitments made in the waters of baptism.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="mSbStz2bnkyr7cs7EHg1hA" hash="sRLezg">You will find examples of them around the world—like Lisa. Lisa, age eleven, lives in England. She came home from school one day feeling very excited. She had been asked to read a part in the school devotional assembly the following morning. She said to her mother, “But some of the words are wrong.” Her mother discovered that one paragraph referred to God and the Holy Ghost as being one and the same person. Lisa and her mother decided to write a letter to Lisa’s teacher explaining that this paragraph was contrary to Lisa’s belief, and that she would feel much happier leaving it out.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="DJkJyVeoqkC27AVnR6ShBA" hash="B-ybeA">The next afternoon her mother waited anxiously for Lisa to return home from school. She came home with a big, bright smile on her face. Not only had the teacher let her leave the paragraph out, but she had asked for more information about the Church. In addition, the teacher asked Lisa to present an assembly about the Church. All this came about because Lisa lived up to the covenant she had made and was willing to witness to the world her own beliefs.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="DzpmOFgNuE2ADjV8NmFlVw" hash="wfNV_w">Thinking about Alma Judd and his son Jeremy reminds me of another Alma who stepped into a fountain of pure water in the land of Mormon to perform the ordinance of baptism for other believers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="p1J9dbkL5Ee_jaFcud3V5g" hash="99vAKg">The Book of Mormon records that Alma was one who heard the teachings of Abinadi and believed. He urged King Noah not to put Abinadi to death, and this made the wicked king angry. Alma was driven out of the city and hid in a thicket by a spring of pure water.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="Po3yC8mLQkOCdEBMr5G_dw" hash="MYRFAA">From this place of refuge in the wilderness, Alma began to teach the words of Abinadi. Those who believed came out of the city to the pure waters of Mormon, and there Alma preached unto them repentance, redemption, and faith on the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="1G2TaThqM0eAsR_87p6l0g" hash="WMKOUA">Then Alma said to them: “As ye are desirous to come into the fold of God, and to be called his people, … what have you against being baptized in the name of the Lord, as a witness before him that ye have entered into a covenant with him, That ye will serve him and keep his commandments, that he may pour out his Spirit more abundantly upon you?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.8-10" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:8–10</a>.) Then one by one Alma took them into the waters and baptized them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="urzNVRuoFkuJhIkHpedogg" hash="YHFANw">Baptism is the beginning of a new life for each one of us, a life of purpose. The Lord is very clear as to what it means to keep his commandments, come into his fold, and be called his people. His people are “willing to bear one another’s burdens, that they may be light;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="94Zk9Ye6u0KwDLvIlmdgsA" hash="5yYlWg">“Yea, and are willing to mourn with those that mourn; yea, and comfort those that stand in need of comfort.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.8-9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:8–9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="9GuljQfQg0GYJR-pMPXdmQ" hash="pWQdgQ">And, like Lisa, the eleven-year-old girl from England, his people are willing “to stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things, and in all places.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:9</a>.) It is the Lord’s will that children at the age of eight <span class="emphasis">begin</span> to be responsible for the kind of lives they lead. You girls who are ten and eleven, and all of us, must assume this same responsibility. In so doing we are becoming a Zion people, which the Doctrine and Covenants says are people who are “pure in heart.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/97.21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 97:21</a>.) After baptism we can live a new, more thoughtful life as described by the Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="0nUMHem2uk6xh7dg7-unHA" hash="ShEcaQ">Into our office come countless stories of the faithfulness of children who are keeping the promises they have made at baptism.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="uWuM9XO_WU2xKP7jAmIkdQ" hash="DBCU2g">Christina was such a girl. When her Primary teacher’s husband died, Christina showed great concern. As soon as she heard the sad news, she went to her teacher and told her not to worry, that she would check in on her every day to make sure that she was all right. And she did. She would often take fresh vegetables from the garden to cheer her up. She wanted her teacher to know she cared. Christina truly comforted one who needed comfort.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="YzAyzepqwUyWHm3pxSriYg" hash="2up2bw">From Idaho comes a story of Jonathan, who went to school in the cold weather wearing his warm hat. When he got to school, he noticed another boy’s ears were frostbitten because he had had to wait so long in the cold for the school bus to pick him up. On his own, Jonathan went to the telephone, called his mother, and asked if it would be all right to give the younger boy his hat because he needed it more. As we bear on another’s burdens, as Jonathan did, we are fulfilling the covenant we made at baptism.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="efqGAmZwu0uNFhyk6muuvw" hash="VyTx4A">Ellen was a young girl who really gained an understanding of repentance. While at the store, she took an item without paying for it. But when she got home, she felt miserable. She confided in her mother: “I’m so sorry I took it; will you take it back for me?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="B9kIwQsilU6u8qHr-qQrTQ" hash="oTN98w">Her mother said, “I can’t repent for you, Ellen. You must repent yourself. <span class="emphasis">You</span> will have to take it back and say you are sorry.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="VXjeu8_7Bke2KmydRd_1YA" hash="UAHo8Q">It was hard, but she did it. “This is my first repentance,” Ellen said. “I’m glad I know how to make things right.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="Xlcpw7922kiRyyjOhQdGoA" hash="X3AbCw">Repentance makes it possible to return to the straight and narrow path and become as pure as we were at baptism.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="71OuzWXzmE6ImuvW3IjluA" hash="ApUwNw">We can all do what Christ asks us to do. He has a plan that will bring us happiness. As he whispers through the Spirit, he tells us how to follow his plan.</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.f1" guid="2c388f4d-4559-4238-9a84-d6328e073973">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="KccNgK-CCEekXlYzMsXptA" hash="HLryJA">
            <span class="emphasis">I Can Follow God’s Plan for Me</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="wOUno2NNC0SSRQILvye1FA" hash="G75Fcg">My life is a gift; my life has a plan.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="OlPsZqtbH0idy4vxJfrLZA" hash="jTqvuw">My life has a purpose; in heav’n it began.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="q2-FveTPUE-1fQK7QYoYRQ" hash="SLqYCg">My choice was to come to this lovely home on earth,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="lKVj7V6xPkqiobsyFwIprg" hash="JJjiMQ">And seek for God’s light to direct me from birth.</p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="2Jcp6y2kN0WZtLRbZxlgvw" hash="HLryJA1">
            <span class="emphasis">I can follow God’s plan for me,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="q_-C6Bp62E6-JYPX-wg8LA" hash="1NAcUg">
            <span class="emphasis">Holding fast to his word and his love.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="YKvtjlxSzkqxRM9Fx_p2SQ" hash="hfUMUQ">
            <span class="emphasis">I will work and I will pray;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="26unMAZSYk2faoUz9cphOw" hash="dXQ-DQ">
            <span class="emphasis">I will always walk in his way.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="x97yoGb7AUyorsA0nrWP2g" hash="6iOeLQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Then I will be happy on earth,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="f4bmzSjV50OGyCpt5IGb2w" hash="g_zL-A">
            <span class="emphasis">And in my home above.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="PJJxJhAn-UaYUxUYsysKTg" hash="JKYM2g">In this song the ten- and eleven-year-old girls have told us we can be happy now and forever if we follow God’s plan, which begins with baptism. It is the gate to the celestial kingdom. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.18" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="kZhRm2I0VUu62I0-ocYYmg" hash="IWuHTw">As followers of Christ, we should “look forward with one eye, having one faith and one baptism, having … hearts knit together in unity and in love one towards another.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.21" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="DzbmI7KfXkykd9XezC5AoQ" hash="Kk-mzA">Each of us who has been baptized has covenanted with the Lord to serve him and keep his commandments. Like Lisa, we must stand as a witness of God. Like Christina, we must comfort those in need. Like Jonathan, we must bear one another’s burdens. Like Ellen, we must repent.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism.p" pid="WuR-t1FTL0KrqM8E_J4Muw" hash="JOedrw">I pray that we will have unity and love as we strive together to keep the covenant we have made at baptism, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/ensignlp.nfo-o-274e.jpg" alt="Dwan J. Young" guid="976c2918-2792-4379-9360-9f25b3fe6f35" pid="cwVrjhx8306KpqUPfwScaA" hash="SMgpXg1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="976c2918-2792-4379-9360-9f25b3fe6f35"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1984/10/keeping-the-covenants-we-make-at-baptism</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1984-general-womens-meeting/1984-09-0020-dwan-j-young-64k-eng.mp3" length="6610733" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 1984 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Draw Near to Him in Prayer</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Thank you, girls, for that beautiful song. The words you have just sung remind me of a prayer—and singing hymns is one way for us to pray, one way for us to draw near to our Heavenly Father.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03193_000_035" doc-version="2" hash="_XzJhg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="SlbOe-87wE6Gt1E5LLp4OA" hash="sMOKZw">Draw Near to Him in Prayer</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="777zJ38fdEekWDwOAcW5bg" hash="3inxug">Dwan J. Young</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/ensignlp.nfo-o-274e.jpg" alt="Dwan J. Young" pid="AXBoh5T6XUqb7sfR6ITENQ" hash="SMgpXg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p1" pid="U-LfmXBoE0KFrKNlnM1Q6Q" hash="o9pSKA">Thank you, girls, for that beautiful song. The words you have just sung remind me of a prayer—and singing hymns is one way for us to pray, one way for us to draw near to our Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p2" pid="vdDyuOe_VUGDeiZJWb0Pzw" hash="zIKCQw">Prayer is what I want to talk to you about tonight. Our Heavenly Father has said, “Draw near unto me and I will draw near unto you.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.63" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:63</a>.) The way to draw near to our Father in Heaven is to speak with him, and this is what we call prayer. We speak with our Father in Heaven in much the way we would speak with our earthly parent, whom we love and honor.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p3" pid="IMvSczFV20urMEA3KRJU4Q" hash="RGCpkw">Does it frighten you to speak with your Heavenly Father? It shouldn’t. It’s true that he is powerful, more than any of us can even understand. But he also loves us—much more than we can ever know. He knows all about you, knows all of your secrets, all the things you are afraid of, and even more—he knows what you are capable of doing. He knows you even better than you know yourself. He wants what is best for you, and he wants you to be successful and happy in your life. In order for him to help you, he wants you to talk with him often in reverent, humble prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p4" pid="JFnvdJ2Ouk-eEp9Iv9u4Hg" hash="EokYow">Some people say they don’t know how to pray, but there are just four steps to take when you want to talk with your Father in Heaven:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p5" pid="k_0xiZjmS02VTCJZ6yyqyA" hash="PSZh0Q">The first one is to <span class="emphasis">prepare.</span> Remember who it is with whom you are speaking. We are to come to our Father with humility and meekness, ready to listen as well as to talk. We should always remember that this is our Eternal Father we are speaking with, and so, whenever possible, we kneel. We fold our arms and bow our heads to show him that we have reverence for him. Sometimes it isn’t possible to do these things—not even possible to close our eyes for a moment while we pray. But even in these unusual situations, we can still begin with reverence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p6" pid="cb3eJmtq1kqXzWckVN6U-w" hash="DZqNng">I’ll give you some examples. I have prayed silently for help while driving my car—when it would be dangerous to fold my arms, and certainly to close my eyes even for a moment. I sometimes bow my head briefly while I’m at a stop sign. Some people pray while they are walking in the woods or in some other peaceful place. Others pray while they ride in elevators, or on buses, or in school just before a test. The need for prayer can come at any time; when it does, just remember to be reverent—kneel, bow your head, close your eyes whenever you can. Then begin by calling on your Father in Heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p7" pid="M1j5jRyyW0mEDa-xNoFzuw" hash="q5v_Ww">The second step is to <span class="emphasis">be grateful.</span> Remember to thank your Heavenly Father for his blessings. This is a very important step, not just because Heavenly father wants us to be grateful, but because it does so much for us. Most of the time we think of prayer only when we want something; but when we start by expressing gratitude for the things we already have, we begin to see our lives in a new way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p8" pid="jLzp7dfVnkecPXuh6rUldg" hash="WIBG_w">I experience this as the Primary general president. My calling is to care not only for the children in our church, but for the children in all of the world. This is a tremendous responsibility, and at first I could feel only the burden of it. But I seek for the Lord’s help constantly. I pray for enough strength and insight to do the work I have been called to do, and for the leaders around the world, that they might have the Spirit of the Lord to help them love and understand the children for whom they are responsible. I plead with Heavenly Father to give each teacher a sense of deep responsibility, so that they might help the children to know the gospel of love. I pray for parents to love and teach their children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p9" pid="1SGHAKcjyECjplXYteLBqQ" hash="-Nq49g">Then, just the other morning, I thought, “I have been asking for so much. This morning I am not going to ask for one thing. I’m just going to be grateful.” I knelt and thanked the Lord for my good health, for my understanding husband, for our children, for our missionary son, for the privilege of serving, for the board members and staff who assist me, for stake and ward members throughout the world who are serving, and especially for the teachers who give and care so much. I thanked him for the children everywhere. I thanked him for the prophet. And the list went on. My spirit soared. What an astounding experience to know that I have so much! It takes a grateful heart to experience that soaring, that realization of how much Heavenly Father loves you, how much he does for you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p10" pid="NYDx4L8d0Uqcj4VGLjxxrA" hash="eyjpzQ">Sometimes being grateful doesn’t come easily. Sometimes when we come to our Heavenly Father we are in such despair that it is hard to think of anything to be grateful for. These are times when prayer is especially important, times when drawing near unto him is essential because we so desperately need him to draw near unto us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p11" pid="BAJpp9Hr40KkRUzUpzGLYQ" hash="ItkeAg">My young friends, I want you to know that there is nothing so terrible in your life that you cannot take it to the Lord. Maybe you feel lonely. Perhaps you think there is not one person in the whole world who cares about you, but I promise, Someone does. No matter what, you have a Father who cares, who knows your heart, who is ready to listen anytime. Draw near unto him in prayer; allow him to draw near unto you. Go to him, acknowledge him as your Eternal Father, and be grateful—for life, and for the opportunity to grow, if for nothing else. And then you will be ready for the third step in prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p12" pid="LtlyKv5qykG5nZucRedSzQ" hash="eePSOw">The third step is to <span class="emphasis">seek.</span> Ask for his help, but ask with an open, searching spirit. Plead for guidance to meet the challenges you have been given. Ask, knowing as Nephi did, that “the Lord giveth no commandments unto the children of men, save he shall prepare a way for them that they may accomplish the thing which he commandeth them.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 3:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p13" pid="Vedt7qYMhE2iFHv3kxWsIA" hash="fR9f_Q">Part of seeking is to give space for an answer. After you have asked for help, pause and listen. Many times the Lord answers our prayers in a still, small voice. It may be an answer you don’t want to hear. Or you may not recognize what happens to you as an answer to your prayers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p14" pid="mEpdUIlG10WzPgn6dhGAQg" hash="dvD7_Q">I’ll give you an example. Three little boys were flying a kite in a field away from their homes. It began to rain, and they wanted to save their kite. As they hastily pulled it from the sky, it caught on a tree limb high over their heads.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p15" pid="oSOo-VT630mMsYCqheo6ag" hash="zs1-zw">They found a long stick and tried to pull it down, but they couldn’t reach it. They tried everything they could think of to get it down, but the kite just turned and twisted in the storm. One of the boys finally said to the others, “I think we should pray.” The other two looked at him, then followed his lead, bowing their heads while he said the words. As they opened their eyes, they saw a car coming toward them down the road that let to the field. As it neared, the boys stood motionless and almost breathless, staring at the lady driving the car.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p16" pid="A4KN_JLjNkCa2OmmpCDmAA" hash="ShcYLg">Their stares fascinated the lady, so she stopped and called to them, “Are you having trouble?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p17" pid="MVgjKmF9a06G0wlT1IX9AQ" hash="7dyAew">“Yes,” they said. “Our kite is caught on the tree. Will you help us get it down?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p18" pid="f9L5_EJDvE6jWaCnfKvC6g" hash="7lD4fg">“I’ll try,” she said. “Stand away while I back up.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p19" pid="2d70qQHE2ECJPX4bvM3C7A" hash="zxuqjw">She backed her car to position it under the kite, then she got out, climbed on top of the car, and, with the long stick retrieved the kite.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p20" pid="zCGx6eVDSUaGJDI6YcdYFw" hash="XFbFOA">When the boy who had offered the prayer carried his kite into the kitchen, he told his mother about the kite’s getting caught in the tree. She asked, “Who helped you get your kite down?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p21" pid="7TcH_fJMika5Xnk_iTs3Vw" hash="tvDhuA">“Heavenly Father,” he replied. The boy, who had prayed with perfect trust, knew the answer to a prayer when he saw it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p22" pid="hRFAWQqgmE-rqd0ynOuyCQ" hash="A7DPVQ">The fourth and last step to prayer is to close. Remember to offer your prayer in the name of Jesus Christ. He is our emissary, our representative, to the Father. That is why we offer our prayers in his name. It is our acknowledgement of him as our Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p23" pid="XP07j4HegkeudnsEMmZqYQ" hash="409c-Q">So these are the four steps of prayer: First, <span class="emphasis">prepare;</span> second, <span class="emphasis">be grateful;</span> third, <span class="emphasis">seek;</span> and fourth, <span class="emphasis">close</span> in the name of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p24" pid="UkOPHIVQnkmiIAvDDEuS9Q" hash="cA1A8g">Your prayer can take many forms. It can be sung in a hymn, or whispered, or even thought. It can be as short as one word—“help!”—or it could be as long as Enos’s prayer that lasted all night and all day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer.p25" pid="fqIFGpLlAk2x5ZgrisSHUQ" hash="oRi3tQ">The important thing to remember is to pray often, talk to Heavenly Father, seek his counsel so that he can guide you. When you draw near to Heavenly Father in prayer, he will draw near to you. You need never feel alone again. I testify to this in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1985/10/draw-near-to-him-in-prayer</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/1985-general-womens-meeting/1985-09-0020-dwan-j-young-64k-eng.mp3" length="10109997" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 1985 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Light of Hope</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The scriptures tell us to abound in hope. Like an early morning sunrise or a happy child’s face, we all want our lives to be touched with light—because darkness has no power against the light.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03206_000_033" doc-version="2" hash="ZM_sJw">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="YVfsQovqW0eHXPOxK_UmBA" hash="xLZvww">The Light of Hope</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="q3_u3qgBPUKmZqJtDKhTqA" hash="3inxug">Dwan J. Young</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.t1">
			<img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/ensignlp.nfo-o-274e.jpg" alt="Dwan J. Young" pid="RjpI2POt-k6XVO79J8N06Q" hash="SMgpXg" />
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p1" pid="ZLMfWmYbVEq5u0F2qLln8w" hash="mZhD0g">The scriptures tell us to abound in hope. Like an early morning sunrise or a happy child’s face, we all want our lives to be touched with light—because darkness has no power against the light.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p2" pid="uyNS2rrIRkixDEUDnCjKtg" hash="yWIquA">Let me tell you about a time when our family needed the Lord to stretch forth his hand, dispel the darkness, and touch our lives with light.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p3" pid="eEEbcjeTCECHR5JJDpyeIA" hash="xjcrIQ">Late one February afternoon in New Zealand, just as I was going into a Primary conference, my husband and I received a phone call from our son Paul in Arizona. He told us of the birth of their third child, Amy, but he said that she had some serious problems. Her lungs were very congested, and when the doctor inserted a tube into her throat, he discovered there was not a passageway from her mouth to her stomach. The baby would be flown by helicopter to a newborn intensive care unit in another city.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p4" pid="fBfobFM640C1AB12HPfE6g" hash="sAbbzQ">When Amy was just one day old, surgery was necessary. This little family was in a stressful situation. Our daughter-in-law, Kathryn, was still recuperating in the hospital in Mesa; the new baby was at another hospital. The two other children, ages two and three and a half, needed constant care. Kathryn’s parents were serving as missionaries in the Bahamas. We were on the other side of the world.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p5" pid="E0-H4vFgY0aaRxcib7joIw" hash="5w7YSQ">The first surgery was to repair the esophagus (the tube which extends from the mouth to the stomach). But even after that operation, Amy developed pneumonia. After weeks of intensive care, the doctors determined that another surgery was critical for Amy’s survival. A test showed that when Amy slept, she stopped breathing.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p6" pid="wRw2jrEX2UWw6YJm_iaW8A" hash="mx-3kA">These were difficult weeks for Paul and Kathryn. Kathryn’s days at the hospital were full of discouragement and loneliness as she watched the little infant struggle for life and wondered if this were the last time she would hold Amy’s small hand. Each day she and Paul would meet briefly at the hospital as he came from work to spend the night with Amy and she went home to care for the other two children.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p7" pid="FQkmLbNJJUKbd5E9soaw4g" hash="It_vvA">We had many prayers and special fasts. The family was sustained by loving, compassionate ward members who cared for the two children for more than three months. At regular intervals, the young women in the ward cleaned their home. The visiting teachers made arrangements for meals to be brought in every day. They also did the washing and the ironing.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p8" pid="gKcGnapK2kCLM9BBprxDiQ" hash="D98ssw">Interestingly enough, one visiting teacher told Kathryn that it was the happiest time in her life because she had had an opportunity to serve.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p9" pid="fAhiehN2PEGxhN6wISelfg" hash="uufi1g">What carried the family through this anguish? We never lost hope. Paul had given Amy a blessing as soon as she was born. He felt that all would not be well immediately and that they would have to put their trust in the Lord. We all knew that if we did all we could, we would have the courage to face whatever would come.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p10" pid="_mwUV0YT4EinNVAm3rm0Ng" hash="D58rhQ">That is the nature of hope. We do all we can, and then the Lord stretches forth his hand and touches our lives with light and courage and, most of all, hope.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p11" pid="3LRVpLO3yU2wqPokeE7JRw" hash="WWjpFg">What happened to Amy? Well, after more than three months of hospital rooms, intensive care, respirators, and close calls, the doctors announced that they must take her off the respirator. They had little hope that she would breathe on her own.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p12" pid="b2vyxSNZl061RlG33JjmFQ" hash="TLalMg">All of the family members had a special fast. The morning the respirator was removed, the doctor stood by, ready to perform yet another surgery. But because of the faith, hope, and prayers in her behalf, Amy began to breathe. Almost immediately her color returned. She was on the road to recovery.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p13" pid="qW9iuDODPE-2aEiRIGZ5Zg" hash="vyFPuw">Amy is now three years old—normal and happy. And what if there hadn’t been such a blessed outcome? Could we still go on with hope? Yes, because hope is knowing that whatever comes, the Lord can whisper peace. Our hope in Christ gives us an unchanging reason to rejoice.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p14" pid="Rw_IE-RtAEOmNVOGeL9XIA" hash="3EBZIA">As Paul said to the Romans: “Now the God of hope fill you with all joy and peace in believing, that ye may abound in hope” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/15.13" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 15:13</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p15" pid="95QYsg68JUaGKmkbn_WlqQ" hash="g6wQ8Q">The Lord wants us to be filled with hope—not just because it points us to a brighter tomorrow, but because it changes the quality of our lives today. <span class="emphasis">Hopeless</span> may be the saddest word in our language. Despair is the enemy of our souls. It can paralyze us, halt our progress, and cause us to lose our way. But hope awakens us like a light shining in the darkness.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p16" pid="eg4sZD3zL0GV27ZeULBc4Q" hash="hiB3Qw">You remember that the thirteenth article of faith states: “We believe all things, we <span class="emphasis">hope</span> all things, we have endured many things, and <span class="emphasis">hope</span> to be able to endure all things” [<a href="/scriptures/pgp/a-of-f/1.13" class="scriptureRef">A of F 1:13</a>] (italics added).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p17" pid="IHL4PjrCsE6bLnjvOXvGNg" hash="bRJuMw">We can endure all things when our hope is centered in one who will never fail us—our Savior, Jesus Christ, who is the light of the world.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p18" pid="TyxVotPh1EeHRA7i2-H1MQ" hash="-9XytA">How do we develop that hope—that hope that lights our way across life’s stormy seas? There are times, as there were for our family, when darkness surrounds us and threatens to engulf us altogether. At such times we can take a lesson from the brother of Jared. You remember the Lord instructed the brother of Jared to make barges so his people could travel safely to the promised land. But because these boats were dark and without air, the brother of Jared took his concerns to the Lord in words that any of us might use to describe our own troubled times: “There is no light. … we cannot breathe” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/2.19" class="scriptureRef">Ether 2:19</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p19" pid="FrWfuB5tJku8ggLMl8UIwg" hash="S26H-A">How does a person venture out into the darkness without fear? How do any of us venture out day after day into a world where there are no guarantees of safety? The Lord gave a profound answer that again applies not just to the dark sea the brother of Jared faced, but to our own dark seas as well: “Ye cannot cross this great deep save I prepare you against the waves of the sea” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/2.25" class="scriptureRef">Ether 2:25</a>). “I will bring you up again out of the depths of the sea” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/2.24" class="scriptureRef">Ether 2:24</a>). The Lord was not going to spare the Jaredites from the experience, but he prepared them for it and gave them the sweet promise of bringing them up again out of the depths of the sea.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p20" pid="0zQ443OlmkWSfO2MlljILw" hash="CTQrkw">Then the brother of Jared asked the Lord, How are we to get light in vessels without windows? And the Lord said: “What will ye that I should do that ye may have light in your vessels?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/2.23" class="scriptureRef">Ether 2:23</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p21" pid="YQ--3fEYFESAZ3BFM1oe1g" hash="XRDfug">The Lord wanted the brother of Jared to suggest a solution, and he did well. He went to the mountain and refined out of a rock sixteen stones clear as transparent glass. I cannot imagine that this was an easy task; it took time and faith. When he finished, he took these stones to the Lord, asking the Lord to stretch forth His finger and make them shine so that his people might not travel in the terrifying darkness. And the Lord did touch the stones with light.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p22" pid="PzMPkBGKwUGe7lufClh0Ng" hash="7Zm3rw">Like the Jaredites, we’re afraid of traveling in the darkness, and we need light, which is hope. Sometimes, in the midst of our problems, we lose the vision of why we’re here or where we’re going. We wonder if we’re equal to the tasks that are given us. It is then that we can ask the Lord to touch the unlighted stones of our lives with light. He can deliver peace and hope when all around us speak against it.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p23" pid="0GjnLdgX8kqaerQc5mwAHw" hash="MRWZZQ">“Touch my life with light,” we can ask the Lord. “Fill my heart with hope.” The Lord will do this if we ask in faith and continue to live his commandments. Like the brother of Jared, it is only with the Lord’s light that we can see all things clearly.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p24" pid="y-JOoUcP9UmgWEi5hgwSdw" hash="TnDfww">Why do we need to have hope?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p25" pid="nFKYcf7QJE-hEvocvfRS2Q" hash="4LAoKg">
				<span class="emphasis">Hope casts out fear.</span> This is a world where our safety is never assured. One eleven-year-old girl I talked to hopes she will have a friend this year at school. Facing a new school year alone is frightening. But the Lord understands her concern and can fill her with hope. Not only will he help her, he will help us through our trials; he will consecrate them to our good. Our seeming misfortunes can often become blessings.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p26" pid="uJ2q-orqYkqQPI2cbMJktA" hash="lQQzUg">
				<span class="emphasis">Hope means we really trust the Lord</span>.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p27" pid="gu_vV8cb-0upOe5CpaboEQ" hash="5pGi_w">
				<span class="emphasis">Hope gives us perspective.</span> Because we know we are living not just for this life, but for another, eternal one as well, we look at life’s events differently. As you review the last year or the last ten years, what is the best day you remember? A person without hope centered in Christ may choose a day that was simply fun or easy. But the best day may really have been the one when life’s events forced you to your knees to communicate with your Father with new intent; it may have been a day that wasn’t convenient or even happy, but you became a bigger and better person when you faced a problem with courage.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p28" pid="OcO_nUcomkW6yQHP1yGoBw" hash="NyHUlw">
				<span class="emphasis">Hope moves us to action.</span> A ten-year-old girl said, “I hope I can grow up to be a good person and always obey the commandments.” With determination, she is starting today to reach her lifetime goals. When we have no hope for tomorrow, we do not move as effectively today. It is hope combined with faith that motivates us to plant the seed, that moves us when we’re too weary, that causes us to take the first step and then another.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p29" pid="3CyfPV6Ik0GGsJM1CVkfhg" hash="CmupFA">Young girls, you will have many challenges in your lives, but if you will always center your life in Jesus Christ and never lose hope, you will have peace. Remember that darkness has no power against the light.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p30" pid="-N7j-T5dCkGQ0yLP7m_ytA" hash="9Ts26g">Like the brother of Jared, like our family with Amy, it is only with the Lord’s light that we can see all things clearly.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope.p31" pid="AK28-AuZZUWTLzc4wdNSiw" hash="YXnv0w">I pray that each of us will seek this gift of hope so that we will be filled with joy and with peace, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1986/10/the-light-of-hope</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1986-general-womens-meeting/1986-09-0010-dwan-j-young-64k-eng.mp3" length="5645974" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 1986 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teach Children the Gospel</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Holly loved the towering pine tree in front of her home. Its branches shaded her favorite place to play.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03226_000_031" doc-version="2" hash="ogJDUw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="5X_p4vJ7Z0qMX4j4MafRhg" hash="gSXpqA">Teach Children the Gospel</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="p8wMgIN9rkayYXmOtrbErg" hash="3inxug">Dwan J. Young</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/ensignlp.nfo-o-274e.jpg" alt="Dwan J. Young" pid="XKcQeHxoe0mKY3PrC1O8qQ" hash="SMgpXg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p1" pid="V674mSBp20OZhYdQGyOJZA" hash="PsO8OA">Holly loved the towering pine tree in front of her home. Its branches shaded her favorite place to play.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p2" pid="erOrbszY6Em_K37RowD5og" hash="Gjv_PA">The day of the accident, there were three younger children listening to Holly read under the tree. Suddenly, in her mind, something whispered to her. Holly’s heart started to thump as the command echoed in her head, “Move!” She responded at once. Scrambling to her feet, she shouted to the children to run. She grabbed the smallest one, and the rest followed. The children thought it was a game until they heard a terrible crash.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p3" pid="4pTUTvSf7ESXNXKFSAcl_w" hash="ys54Vw">A driver had lost control of his car and hit the big pine tree where the children had been reading only minutes before. They would have been badly hurt if they hadn’t moved. Some of the children were so frightened that they started to cry. But not Holly. She was thinking about the small voice she had heard in her mind and heart that told her to move. She knew that the warning had come to her from the Holy Ghost. The gift that she had received from Heavenly Father after she had been baptized and confirmed had helped her, just as she had been promised (see Elaine Cannon, <span class="emphasis">Baptized and Confirmed: Your Lifeline to Heaven,</span> Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1986, pp. 36–37).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p4" pid="XdAYZsUCHUSqIodmHHXqCw" hash="Fr1B0w">Now, there are many Hollys among us—children who have been taught to be sensitive to the Spirit. Who are these children? Our beloved President Benson told us not long ago, “God has saved for the final inning some of His stronger and most valiant children, who will help bear off the kingdom triumphantly” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> April 1987, p. 73). They are all sons and daughters of God, each with a special mission to perform. Their self-esteem grows as they learn who they truly are.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p5" pid="oYicU4ayT0OaOuZRkle5ow" hash="2M6Nzg">But many of our children today are learning under less than ideal circumstances. Even in elementary schools, some of the children are confronted with drugs, alcohol, profane language, and even immorality among their classmates. In many cases, family members are involved in so many activities away from home that there is no time for parents and children to develop meaningful relationships with one another. Fewer families are praying together and eating their meals together. Fewer fathers are spending time with their children, and more mothers are too tired at the end of the day to share an hour of reading or visiting with their children. Time that could be spent with family members is often spent watching television. By the age of eighteen, a child has typically spent more time in front of the television set than in school.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p6" pid="xADdv-FxQkWLo9_JPagMDg" hash="NkXeiw">In this kind of an environment, we <span class="emphasis">must</span> take time to teach the children about the important things of life—about Heavenly Father, the Savior, and the Holy Ghost. We must teach them about repentance, baptism, honesty, and doing good to others. Now, you might say, “I’m not a parent; I don’t teach children.” Actually, we are all teachers of children—parents, aunts, uncles, grandparents, priesthood leaders, ward members, neighbors. Children are always watching and learning. We teach them through our behavior as well as by what we say. They watch how we treat each other. They listen to the voices of their parents and to the voices at church. Unfortunately, they also listen to voices on television and elsewhere which sometimes teach values contrary to gospel principles. We must teach them at an early age to listen to the right voices, as Holly did.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p7" pid="J0TpGP9bbkavOf78yfdQxQ" hash="TlUNmg">Over the years, I’ve learned certain truths about children I’d like to share with you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p8" pid="tcYceniq7kKjdwWIrF99Ug" hash="ld6JDQ">
        <span class="emphasis">First,</span> children <span class="emphasis">want</span> to be taught. This was brought home to me when I was visiting a Primary in Bolivia. I planned to visit an older class when three little girls tugged at my sleeve. They had been to their classroom, but they came back because there was no teacher. “Please, will you teach us?” they asked. “We need a teacher.” This was one of the sweetest teaching experiences I have ever had because those children were thirsty for gospel truths.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p9" pid="ObevslFeTUu_yyvRFC8bWQ" hash="cyITnA">
        <span class="emphasis">Second,</span> children understand quiet whisperings of the Spirit, as Holly understood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p10" pid="QU3uo38Gtk2VLvRKy-19rg" hash="Dz1IpQ">
        <span class="emphasis">Third,</span> as children learn, they can have a great influence for good. One young girl was taught a lesson about temples and eternal families. She went home and asked her father what would happen to her, because her family wasn’t sealed. Would she be given to another family? The faith of this tender soul touched her father and moved him to action. Within a year their family was sealed in the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p11" pid="eG5hI2qioUW9IpNlYXNuwA" hash="bPwvfA">
        <span class="emphasis">Fourth,</span> parents are commanded to teach their children gospel principles. In Doctrine and Covenants 68:25 [<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.25" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:25</a>], the Lord instructs parents to teach their children “the doctrine of repentance, faith in Christ the Son of the living God, and of baptism and the gift of the Holy Ghost by the laying on of the hands.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p12" pid="Y55iDxHgHku1rZme14oahA" hash="OCYziw">The Savior also teaches parents something more—that they should be as teachable as their children. He said, “Teach parents that they must repent and be baptized, and humble themselves as their little children, and they shall all be saved with their little children” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/8.10" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 8:10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p13" pid="7q1ZqL7_tUW0sdJv5LTH7g" hash="m4uNfg">
        <span class="emphasis">Fifth,</span> gospel truths make a difference in the lives of children. Over the past few years, I’ve seen countless examples of children who have been taught gospel principles. When they learn these truths, they build a reservoir of strength to draw from throughout their lives. Let me share two examples with you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p14" pid="WDVLdG4-S0CCoUsWKdy1Sw" hash="Jc-M9g">Eight-year-old Annie spent a night at her friend’s house. When they finally settled down, their conversation turned to serious things. Were the scriptures true? They each asked Heavenly Father in their prayers and felt a strong witness from the Spirit that, yes, the scriptures are true. The next day Annie told her mother about that witness of the Spirit and made a commitment to start regular scripture study.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p15" pid="0r0dJE8LtketB_XTNMsIXg" hash="6zjtuw">Now, like most eleven-year-old boys, Steven loved basketball. One afternoon he went with his friends to watch a game on television. Thirty minutes later, he returned home. His mother was surprised because she knew the game wasn’t over. When she questioned Steven, he said the boys had decided to watch a different program, but the program made him feel dark inside. That feeling had helped Steven recognize he was in a setting where the Spirit could not be present, and he was too uncomfortable to stay.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p16" pid="ntUwQ6PSFU6VFAFIgVAQUg" hash="9E3WFA">Although it is our responsibility to teach the children, they often teach us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p17" pid="XFurjd8ar0G-qWuOCtORbg" hash="GWxdtw">I shall be eternally grateful for my Primary experience and for all that the children have taught me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p18" pid="PHiI4DoHW0mgKwz4bs_fEg" hash="MoMsyQ">I am also grateful for loving parents and dedicated Primary leaders, including those who have served by my side, who faithfully teach eternal principles of the gospel of Jesus Christ to our children. May each of us recognize the importance of teaching children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel.p19" pid="lvi2RSWyCk6nhcGDUCdmDQ" hash="KeV2bQ">On this beautiful Easter Sunday I bear witness that Jesus Christ lived and died for us, and that he lives again. He is my Savior, my example, my friend, and I love him. I pledge my continued devotion and service to him, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1988/04/teach-children-the-gospel</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1988-general-conference/1988-04-5050-dwan-j-young-64k-eng.mp3" length="4204632" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 1988 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
