<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Earl C. Tingey</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Earl C. Tingey.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Earl%20C.%20Tingey.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Earl C. Tingey.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 1991 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Redemption of the Dead</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My beloved brothers and sisters, I am thankful for the opportunity to express my love and appreciation to the Lord for the call that came to me last December. I accept the call. I am grateful for the opportunity to bear testimony of Jesus Christ. I w</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_91905_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="G4ZADw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="DjmC4aiPtkORdov1LY6qYg" hash="mx8wAg">Redemption of the Dead</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="c8EsEQgUtU2581yuvC9WRQ" hash="CBgxUg">Earl C. Tingey</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1d4e.jpg" alt="Elder Earl C. Tingey" pid="qNGuNB0TjUme1RbNsJqDmg" hash="1kETHg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p1" pid="K1g1ZEXrZUCKILxRkNtV1Q" hash="V49L_Q">My beloved brothers and sisters, I am thankful for the opportunity to express my love and appreciation to the Lord for the call that came to me last December. I accept the call. I am grateful for the opportunity to bear testimony of Jesus Christ. I will consecrate all of my time, energy, and talent to magnify this calling. I express appreciation to the Brethren; my wife, Joanne; our children; grandchildren; our parents and extended family; and to all of our friends and neighbors who have voiced confidence in my ability to do this work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p2" pid="3Y08ymW2h0yG9ZPip2wT1w" hash="5YBjhQ">I have been called to serve in the Family History Department of the Church, and I would like to speak of that today. Here we see the great work of the redemption roll forth in its decreed course.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p3" pid="2Of8iZl8UkuP--pnrIBguA" hash="KCWHpQ">I salute the thousands of workers, volunteers, and service missionaries who, as the scriptures say, “wear out [their] lives” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/123.13" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 123:13</a>) to redeem those who are living beyond the veil. Their complete and unselfish service is a true demonstration of the love we should have for the Savior and our fellowmen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p4" pid="GAqeg-dNbkmXD5ajQWZZeA" hash="0UNrCQ">Much has been accomplished over the years. Faithful Saints in years past and today have identified many millions of their ancestors. The Church has assisted by gathering information on nearly two billion individuals who have at one time lived on this earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p5" pid="VQ5RWQqS3UKVobx945F1vg" hash="sk0aKg">The Church has further provided beautiful temples where the Saints may enter and have sacred ordinances performed on behalf of their kindred dead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p6" pid="IORo_nYxOkGMW-iMaWFeQQ" hash="MYh5tQ">My brothers and sisters, many things are occurring today to help us accelerate this work. I am impressed that the Lord will help us when we make an effort to do what He has asked of us as counseled by our prophet and other Church leaders.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p7" pid="SrQY6K3R5EyGBJ6kg4al2A" hash="iMg-aA">In 1977, major emphasis was given to the redemption of the dead. Speaking to a meeting of Regional Representatives, Elder Boyd K. Packer spoke of the marvelous capacity of the computer and of how this new technology would hasten the work. He further assured us that the Lord would continue to assist the Church along the way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p8" pid="jMzTjjCqqEGXzDZybWO_jA" hash="nndIAA">“When the servants of the Lord determine to do as He commands, we move ahead. As we proceed, we are joined at the crossroads by those who have been prepared to help us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p9" pid="1UWssBKzq06v-B040Svr0Q" hash="YQFJeg">“They come with skills and abilities precisely suited to our needs. And, we find provisions; information, inventions, help of various kinds, set along the way waiting for us to take them up.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p10" pid="5hXMac8Em0OJF7EOOD9n9w" hash="sxXXgg">“It is as though someone knew we would be traveling that way. We see the invisible hand of the Almighty providing for us.” (Address delivered at regional representatives’ seminar, 1 Apr. 1977.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p11" pid="DsEXG-hCLEOpCeOVNEGQKw" hash="EAXDbg">Brothers and sisters, the Lord has met His servants at the crossroads. Many of these tools and skills are now in our hands. Our failure to now do this work cannot be lightly passed over.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p12" pid="pdk9fkTyEEK1g_MoG8vRjg" hash="QNxUOg">The most prominent of the new tools which we now have in many of our fifteen hundred family history centers is the computer-aided resource entitled FamilySearch™, which has the following features.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p13" pid="YGbZp5o2JUihRLxLmJPvYQ" hash="uOr9VQ">First, the Ancestral File™ provides over seven million names linked into family relationships. The identity of the submitting party is also provided, thus facilitating cooperative research.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p14" pid="OVfOYrcW_kSuwmBCnlTMdQ" hash="MUHkfQ">Second, the Family History Library Catalog™ provides easy access to the Church’s Family History Library and its resources.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p15" pid="O_9ew7ghfkyKp3dObR2uLw" hash="xklG9Q">Third, the International Genealogical Index™ provides data on over 147 million deceased individuals. Many millions of additional names are being added to this index.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p16" pid="H6umLs2UskC51u7Hr46KcQ" hash="NlEchA">And fourth, a new Personal Ancestral File™ computer program will permit members, in their homes, to easily organize their family history records.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p17" pid="0khl4Q0DU0KECYpVo2JsPg" hash="9ns12Q">In addition, over eight hundred stakes are now participating in the new Family Records Extraction Program.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p18" pid="36sexLs2lkON8tEuiFDCmQ" hash="j8CH7Q">This vital effort, involving over seventy-five thousand volunteers who serve primarily in their homes, will soon allow members to clear names for temple work, in their own meetinghouses, rather than waiting for headquarters approval.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p19" pid="bv_ni0Vfb0mwXNH9XOF7Hg" hash="TDwsxQ">Yes, the invisible hand of the Almighty is providing for us, and we should live and act to merit a continuation of His help and blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p20" pid="zMgaPMm7NEiYPmZJVWO2NQ" hash="wzPO_A">The Almighty, through the appearance of the angel Moroni to Joseph Smith in 1823, introduced the doctrine and work of the redemption of the dead. Moroni told Joseph that the Old Testament prophet Elijah would return before the second coming of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p21" pid="037JFYPQv0Cn3XO5jDnVkg" hash="RtZORA">Slightly modifying the Malachi reference to Elijah, Moroni said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p22" pid="5jOjzNHKgUyw-MiXHV-WWg" hash="qnO1Mg">
        <span class="emphasis">“He [Elijah] shall plant in the hearts of the children the promises made to the fathers, and the hearts of the children shall turn to their fathers.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.39" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:39</a>.)</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p23" pid="DDqBGPIP8Eik_elArD1RXQ" hash="kZIwTg">The word <span class="emphasis">plant</span> was introduced by the angel Moroni. What does it mean to plant in the hearts of the children the promises made to the fathers? What were the promises made to the fathers?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p24" pid="cudqqLppjEqz5zd261t-Kg" hash="ncFyDQ">The promises relate to the covenant of the Lord that He is no respecter of persons and that He has a plan whereby all of His children may have opportunity to return to His presence by being obedient to the laws, principles, and ordinances of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p25" pid="7wXCSgg5R0iSD0TiyVK8Yg" hash="gQ6H4w">To plant these promises in the hearts of the children, and to turn the hearts of the children to their fathers, was defined by Elder Mark E. Petersen in the October 1971 general conference, as follows:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p26" pid="ncUZGR26BEujnOGf9t0VnA" hash="xxNfMQ">“Malachi plainly outlined the mission of Elijah—to establish a bond of interest between present and past generations … to create in the hearts of living men and women an interest in their ancestors.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Jan. 1972, p. 49.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p27" pid="9jtwtyG07kmlQ4-5hV6hxw" hash="diwRKw">The seed planted by the Lord, through Elijah’s appearance to Joseph Smith in 1836, was not a full-grown tree, but only a seed. At that time there were no genealogical societies in existence. History confirms that family research in America generally commenced with the forming of the New England Historical Genealogical Society in Boston in 1844.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p28" pid="ZCwuAiL0XkOoJLwknrp-7g" hash="pfZtlQ">Thus, just eight years after that small seed of genealogical interest in our ancestors was planted by Elijah, it began to grow until now, as a result of skills, tools, and computer technology, which have been provided by the Lord, the lowly seed has become a beautiful, fruit-bearing tree.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p29" pid="ka_wVY2zCk690E6Mnzd3FA" hash="xbyOVQ">Brothers and sisters, in conclusion, many years ago humble listeners asked Peter, “Men and brethren, what shall we do?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/2.37" class="scriptureRef">Acts 2:37</a>.) Peter replied, “Repent, and be baptized every one of you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/2.38" class="scriptureRef">Acts 2:38</a>.) To your silent questions, Where should I begin? What should I do? we say, Seek out those who are called to direct this work in your ward or branch. Go to your family history center and the temple. Identify those of your ancestors whose identity may be lost to human memory. Get started now, and the Lord will help you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead.p30" pid="0iPtRVUsukiLPaZwoSqlIw" hash="An1Cqw">I bear humble testimony that this work of the redemption is true. Jesus Christ presides over and directs this work by revealing His will to President Ezra Taft Benson, our living prophet. I pray that we will do this work. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1991/04/redemption-of-the-dead</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1991-general-conference/1991-04-2030-elder-earl-c-tingey-64k-eng.mp3" length="4410701" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 1991 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sabbath Day and Sunday Shopping</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Good morning, brothers and sisters. My subject is the Sabbath day, specifically as it relates to shopping on Sunday.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_96905_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="icxNYw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="4ibVNghNwES2_iYkkPzAWQ" hash="VXRokQ">The Sabbath Day and Sunday Shopping</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="epxJ8g-x9E-vp-CTNz0GoA" hash="CBgxUg">Earl C. Tingey</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1d4e.jpg" alt="Elder Earl C. Tingey" pid="PJTBcoJv3EGsZCGfTXgAmA" hash="1kETHg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p1" pid="csuQXa_cFUuZzRgjGS-7AA" hash="6DsN6g">Good morning, brothers and sisters. My subject is the Sabbath day, specifically as it relates to shopping on Sunday.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p2" pid="Ex_VGQZxNUOTD3tvq8xaQg" hash="oPkCnw">From the beginning, God has instructed prophets to teach the covenant people to honor the Sabbath day. God rested from His creative labors on the seventh day.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> This day was blessed and sanctified as a holy day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p3" pid="hK3YMduDFkKzh_8gocBw0A" hash="KPvnJw">The fourth commandment to Moses was to “remember the sabbath day, to keep it holy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p4" pid="SG52HwB5x0asT5MoaI2kGg" hash="riVp9g">Elder Bruce R. McConkie taught that “Sabbath observance was a sign between ancient Israel and their God whereby the chosen people might be known.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p5" pid="gRqVzHUYR0WLQuKykfVJnQ" hash="chBEBw">Members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints recognize Sunday as the Sabbath in commemoration of the fact that Christ came forth from the grave on Sunday, and the Apostles commenced meeting thereafter on the first day of the week.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p6" pid="H9WqCIPLpkClLh69TJjm1w" hash="0YVtHg">On Sunday, 7 August 1831, the Lord revealed the following to the Prophet Joseph Smith:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p7" pid="Yen2NSx8ikeB7Cl07zAwtQ" hash="Q3O1ag">“And that thou mayest more fully keep thyself unspotted from the world, thou shalt go to the house of prayer and offer up thy sacraments upon my holy day;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p8" pid="ckNi_4gj1E2DflvaTk8VnA" hash="l40wEg">“For verily this is a day appointed unto you to rest from your labors, and to pay thy devotions unto the Most High;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p9" pid="4os7zvy9_UCVBjQLYv4h5g" hash="hOn1QA">“Nevertheless thy vows shall be offered up in righteousness on all days and at all times;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p10" pid="YFPREXYmJ0a6KxRYgRDJRQ" hash="uV9KJA">“But remember that on this, the Lord’s day, thou shalt offer thine oblations and thy sacraments unto the Most High, confessing thy sins unto thy brethren, and before the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p11" pid="rsmw8_gGwUauWPHzsXW-kw" hash="_3Td9A">“And on this day thou shalt do none other thing, only let thy food be prepared with singleness of heart that thy fasting may be perfect, or, in other words, that thy joy may be full.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p12" pid="GGQuI5Lu2km9PV1Na-LvYQ" hash="hEZrtA">In a recent regional training meeting for priesthood leaders, President Gordon B. Hinckley expressed concern that members of the Church may have a tendency to take on the ways of the world. He said: “We don’t adopt them immediately, but we slowly take them on, unfortunately. I wish I had the power to convert this whole Church to the observance of the Sabbath. I know our people would be more richly blessed of the Lord if they would walk in faithfulness in the observance of the Sabbath.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p13" pid="_3Hwjs7Qg0y8x7cifkBjMA" hash="dDsOdg">A very important aspect of properly observing the Sabbath concerns shopping on Sunday. Unfortunately, many commercial businesses and establishments are open on Sunday. The world sees no conflict in Sunday shopping. But we of the Church have been counseled and taught by prophets to keep ourselves “unspotted from the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> We should not shop on Sunday.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p14" pid="YlMb2pisy0yav30lUUtB_A" hash="rCND9w">President Hinckley continued with the following instruction to priesthood leaders: “There isn’t anybody in this Church who has to buy furniture on Sunday. There really isn’t. There isn’t anybody in this Church who has to buy a new automobile on Sunday, is there? No. There isn’t anybody in this Church who, with a little care and planning, has to buy groceries on Sunday. No. … You don’t need ice cream to be bought on Sunday. … You don’t need to make Sunday a day of merchandising. … I don’t think we need to patronize the ordinary business merchants on the Sabbath day. Why do they stay open? To get customers. Who are those customers? Well, they are not all nonmembers of this Church. You know that and I know that.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p15" pid="VISaD6g6GUyFzEc7QUnYcA" hash="RZsuOA">In the book of Nehemiah, in the Old Testament, the people were taught to observe the Sabbath with the following instruction: “And if the people of the land bring ware or any victuals on the sabbath day to sell, that we would not buy it of them on the sabbath, or on the holy day.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p16" pid="iNEsffq06EWfc0shz3HpsQ" hash="z74u_A">Elder Dallin H. Oaks, of the Quorum of the Twelve, has taught: “Modern-day prophets have encouraged us not to shop on Sunday. … Those of us who shop on the Sabbath cannot escape responsibility for encouraging businesses to remain open on that day. Essential services must be provided, but most Sabbath transactions could be avoided if merchants and customers were determined to avoid doing business on the Lord’s day.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p17" pid="NcAPGGikJk-tKP7laWJiNA" hash="Was6xw">Brothers and Sisters, let’s not shop on Sunday. One way we avoid this is by planning ahead. Fill up the gas tank on Saturday. Acquire the needed groceries for the weekend on Saturday. Don’t you be the means of causing someone to work on Sunday because you patronize their establishment. Of course, we know that there are essential businesses that must be open on Sunday. These are emergency, medical, transportation, and some forms of protective services, such as police and fire. We are grateful for those persons who staff these essential public establishments and afford us protection and comfort.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p18" pid="s8t-2Jc820Sh0KXDUU289A" hash="C0_V6w">In many countries of the world, and in many states of the Union, shopping on Sunday is not done or is prohibited by law. We as a community of Saints should use our influence, in a positive way, to encourage other citizens to not shop on Sunday. We should start with ourselves. If we will not shop on Sunday, businesses which open on Sunday will have no financial reason to remain open on Sunday. It’s really that simple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p19" pid="G__3NiULeE2-a8w0jcPZvQ" hash="aHWVzA">I often drive through small rural communities of Utah on a Sunday afternoon as I return home from stake conference assignments. I observe that almost always the tractors are idle and the fields are empty. I thank God for the faith of the humble farmers. When I enter the cities, I see the parking lots of many stores filled with cars on a Sunday, and I am saddened that the Lord’s law is being broken. The justification for and reason often cited by the owners and operators of such businesses is to be competitive, to conform to corporate policy, and so on.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p20" pid="PobywTsEMUi1SD6gLwz38A" hash="4GqFpw">I well remember an interview President Spencer W. Kimball once had with a faithful Church member. It went like this: “‘What is your occupation?’ And [the man] said, ‘I operate a service station.’ And I asked, ‘Do you operate on the Sabbath?’ His answer was, ‘No, I do not.’ ‘Well, how can you get along? Most service station operators seem to think they must open on the Sabbath.’ ‘I get along well,’ he said. ‘The Lord is good to me.’ ‘Do you not have stiff competition?’ I asked. ‘Yes, indeed,’ he replied. ‘Across the street is a man who keeps open all day Sunday.’ ‘And you never open?’ I asked. ‘No, sir,’ he said, ‘and I am grateful, and the Lord is kind, and I have sufficient for my needs.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p21" pid="NbVqTpsw1UuqIsWpDSm86A" hash="ANtppg">Members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints are a covenant people. We know we live in the world, but we are taught to not be of the world. Like ancient Israel, who also was a covenant people, we should encourage the proper observance of the Sabbath day by not shopping on Sunday. Let this become a sign with our God by which we shall be known.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p22" pid="0r2XlGW-d0uaSszgEqB0Fw" hash="D0esPQ">This is our heritage. In this dispensation, from the days of our pioneer forefathers, we have been so taught. I recall a talk given by President Hinckley several years ago wherein he said: “May I take you back 142 years when there was, of course, no tabernacle here, nor temple, nor Temple Square. On July 24, 1847, the pioneer company of our people came into this valley. An advance group had arrived a day or two earlier. Brigham Young arrived on Saturday. The next day, Sabbath services were held both in the morning and in the afternoon. There was no hall of any kind in which to meet. I suppose that in the blistering heat of that July Sunday they sat on the tongues of their wagons and leaned against the wheels while the Brethren spoke. The season was late, and they were faced with a gargantuan and immediate task if they were to grow seed for the next season. But President Young pleaded with them not to violate the Sabbath then or in the future.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p23" pid="BTpwho7IeUe9DvyGz4GkZA" hash="jTZmtg">Can we possibly imagine how tempting it must have been for our pioneer forefathers to break the Sabbath day? Their survival depended upon the food they could grow and harvest. Yet their leaders counseled them to exercise faith in the promises of the Lord and to respect the Sabbath day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p24" pid="I2UrgOXgnUe7F1LzG9qyfg" hash="Kn6FEA">What are the promises and blessings of the Lord to those who honor the Sabbath day by not shopping on Sunday? The 59th section of the Doctrine and Covenants and the 26th chapter of Leviticus, in the Old Testament, give similar promises: The fulness of the earth is yours, the land will be blessed with rain and will yield its increase; there will be peace in the land, and God will magnify His faithful people, have respect for them, and establish His covenant with them.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p25" pid="ryFOU5bdlkyAbvYNMkm3Kg" hash="67fIPg">As another blessing, and a warning, I think of the counsel of President George Albert Smith, when he said, “Much of the sorrow and distress that is afflicting … mankind is traceable to the fact that they have ignored his[God’s] admonition to keep the Sabbath day holy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p26" pid="f4JZVmQXE0GHaJfv4Ew7jQ" hash="Nin7EA">In conclusion, and appropriate to this beautiful Easter season, our observance of the Sabbath is an indication of the depth of our conversion and our willingness to keep sacred covenants. Elder Mark E. Petersen has said: “Our observance or nonobservance of the Sabbath is an unerring measure of our attitude toward the Lord personally and toward his suffering in Gethsemane, his death on the cross, and his resurrection from the dead. It is a sign of whether we are Christians in very deed, or whether our conversion is so shallow that commemoration of his atoning sacrifice means little or nothing to us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping.p27" pid="RvDhTOtlM0OMbJ_jZHM-Eg" hash="45gjRA">I bear humble witness of the sanctity of the Sabbath day and of our need to resolve not to shop on Sunday. It is an element of our faith and obedience to eternal principles. It is a sign between our God and His chosen people. It is a true law and commandment of God. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1996/04/the-sabbath-day-and-sunday-shopping</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1996-general-conference/1996-04-1030-elder-earl-c-tingey-64k-eng.mp3" length="5837503" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 1996 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Missionary Service</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The excitement and thrill of being a full-time missionary is one of the greatest blessings a young man of the Aaronic Priesthood can aspire to.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_98905_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="pdt5mA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="2YXJJM7Ky0Ojwe1QxvvlFg" hash="OZzOVg">Missionary Service</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ju3FVJd2-k6vgMdXpfdJGQ" hash="CBgxUg">Earl C. Tingey</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="ZYcFnGStxEKGGb_IJx5lIw" hash="Kx3T1g">The excitement and thrill of being a full-time missionary is one of the greatest blessings a young man of the Aaronic Priesthood can aspire to.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1d4e.jpg" alt="Elder Earl C. Tingey" pid="OHBGqDwUpEOlXVRTGiT7Iw" hash="1kETHg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p1" pid="pfNhxpvdz0a3Od3ek1q_1g" hash="7nt86A">Tonight I speak to all young men of the Aaronic Priesthood preparing to serve missions, all full-time missionaries, and all fathers and grandfathers who motivate and prepare young men to serve.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p2" pid="6WZ6zEtu6ke7qqvDr1BDaQ" hash="TQvnVw">Several months ago I visited Far West, Missouri. At one time it was the home and place of refuge for three to four thousand members of the Church. Today the homes are gone and only fields of grass remain. In July 1838 the Prophet Joseph Smith received a revelation that the Twelve were to depart Far West on April 26, 1839, to commence missionary work in Great Britain.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p3" pid="Z5ijRyNtxECVd3_9uNXKXA" hash="ybWXfA">In the <span class="emphasis">Discourses of Wilford Woodruff,</span> we read: “When that revelation was given, all was peace and quietude, comparatively, in that land. But when the time came for the twelve apostles to fulfil that revelation, the Saints had all been driven out. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p4" pid="qu_MchXa0EiFhZxDozffXw" hash="Ik88kQ">“President Young asked the twelve who were with him—’What shall we do with regard to the fulfilment of this revelation?’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Some of the Brethren said that the Lord would accept the intent of the Twelve and that the Lord would not require their lives to fulfill the revelation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p5" pid="49vRyM4cjkyWIkKeUMTV5g" hash="8SaQ6g">Wilford Woodruff continues: “The Spirit of the Lord rested upon the twelve, and they said—’The Lord God has spoken, and we will fulfil that revelation and commandment’; and that was the feeling of President Young and of those who were with him.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p6" pid="Ml4VUj-ln0a7hGhGA9T2tw" hash="-Wj_xQ">The Twelve, in obedience to the revelation, departed for their missions. Wilford Woodruff was so sick he could hardly stand on his feet. Heber C. Kimball wrote that Brigham Young was so sick that he was unable to walk a distance of 30 rods without assistance. He left his wife and children lying sick in bed. When he left home, Brigham Young was wearing a long quilt over his shoulders because he had no coat.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p7" pid="O7gQZpw5Ok6QKmIaFmjPeg" hash="EXDAig">On August 28, 1852, five years after the Saints arrived in the Salt Lake Valley, Brigham Young convened a special conference where approximately 100 men were called to serve missions to the far corners of the earth. The charge given the missionaries by George A. Smith of the Twelve was as follows: “The missions we will call for during this conference, are generally, not to be very long ones; probably from 3 to 7 years will be as long as any man will be absent from his family.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p8" pid="Gbq-20gvuk2gekPyBOA-AQ" hash="0U4qVQ">Today, our missionaries do not serve or depart for their missions under such extreme circumstances. They go with relative comfort and ease, appropriately dressed, adequately fed, and travel by jet airplane.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p9" pid="r-Ya1hsV7USxcd57LJ2wFA" hash="3N0FMQ">Currently over 58,000 full-time missionaries serve in 136 nations and territories. By July there will be 331 missions. The excitement and thrill of being a full-time missionary is one of the greatest blessings a young man of the Aaronic Priesthood can aspire to.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p10" pid="cfRsiXr6R0yxz9BcjLxf6w" hash="kt59FA">Most missionaries receive special training in one of the 15 missionary training centers throughout the world. The largest, in Provo, currently has approximately 3,000 missionaries in residence. I thought you might be interested in several statistics shared with me during a recent visit to the MTC. In one month the missionaries consume over 5,000 pounds of dry cereal. That is over 2 1/2 tons. Of that amount, 2,200 pounds is Lucky Charms. Lucky Charms is a popular breakfast dry cereal. Maybe one of the best preparations for being a missionary is to eat Lucky Charms. For you parents who try to focus your young men’s eating habits on what you may consider is more nutritious food, you might be aware that in one month missionaries consumed only 16 pounds of All Bran.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p11" pid="agq29qiNpEa1R5SMtQ9CIw" hash="_RP_ig">Young men of the Aaronic Priesthood, may I suggest six ways you can prepare for your mission:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p12" pid="bKDQbzkU8U-yX7o55RcLdg" hash="irHOFQ">First, secure your individual testimony of the truth of the gospel of Jesus Christ. Know for yourself that you hold the priesthood and that Jesus Christ is your Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p13" pid="P00ZEkr7S0u6SNjz0GHjRA" hash="3HhR2Q">Second, study and ponder the Book of Mormon to the point where you can declare that it was received by Joseph Smith from the angel Moroni and that the Prophet Joseph translated the book from the golden plates.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p14" pid="toDJCvs8vU6ryU8OMZGKZA" hash="oep-Mw">Third, be clean and pure. To those who have slipped, repentance is available if you will approach your bishop and seek his help and counsel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p15" pid="FfIAVoYAXkmTNgaBiImzYA" hash="1T8z0A">Fourth, pay your tithes and offerings so that you can bear witness of this great principle of the gospel. Save money so that you can serve a mission. A mission is not free, and each missionary should expect to financially contribute towards the cost of his mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p16" pid="bIjHhP0QNkmda-rDO2yY3g" hash="_YuFHg">Fifth, learn how to work. Be willing to get up early in the morning, work hard all day, and retire on time. As you prepare for your mission, learn how to work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p17" pid="UtYiZI8o-kClZmRIyW8CnQ" hash="W5DGyQ">And sixth, serve as a home teacher in your ward to know the joy of service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p18" pid="z92zMoSDMEuifIyJYxP5xw" hash="tDpz_A">For all full-time missionaries, I have several suggestions:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p19" pid="ERcwEJ4X70abMHNbRv1bIg" hash="h8I5mQ">First, open your mouth. The Lord tells us, “And thou must open thy mouth at all times, declaring my gospel with the sound of rejoicing.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p20" pid="7sKAq5ujGU-7Xdm_yYSMjg" hash="8qWp9A">Speak to everyone: shopkeepers, passengers riding buses, people on streets, and everyone you meet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p21" pid="Vh0hXoSWm02HLu4LEuNsgg" hash="Jxq-MA">Second, work hard. Missionary work results in many rejections. It is easy to be discouraged. “And ye are called to bring to pass the gathering of mine elect; for mine elect hear my voice and harden not their hearts.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p22" pid="gYVAgaw0YEWj-NRKnjzHBA" hash="gGdP5Q">Third, be obedient, faithful, and true. Missionaries serve in companionships for protection. A missionary best protects his companion when he is loyal to the Lord and helps his companion. By keeping the missionary rules, you gain the freedom of having the Spirit assist you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p23" pid="bJtaeSlg9kuMry69lgSX-g" hash="yJUeoA">Fourth, teach and testify. “And ye shall go forth in the power of my Spirit, preaching my gospel, two by two, in my name, lifting up your voices as with the sound of a trump, declaring my word like unto angels of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p24" pid="gygmxRU0t0OkAspDMAX3Dw" hash="GN64Uw">And fifth, when you complete your mission, maintain the spirit, appearance, and trust of a missionary. Brigham Young once said to the returned missionary: “Come home with your heads up. Keep yourselves clean, from the crowns of your heads to the soles of your feet; be pure in heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p25" pid="dO4pScTu3k6TakqNAwK-pw" hash="LDFAbA">To the fathers and grandfathers of Aaronic Priesthood young men:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p26" pid="XmzXjeZZBUyKElrzWS0RrQ" hash="pokrdw">Motivate and encourage your sons and grandsons to serve missions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p27" pid="oOpZTKIGbkSbwX0XR3I-jw" hash="pF995w">Provide a righteous home and an atmosphere of peace and stability where young men can be reared and prepared to serve.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p28" pid="eSVrT6K1uE2fuqNncmRjmw" hash="_5AdVA">Set a personal example by keeping the commandments. Pay tithes and offerings, attend sacrament meetings, read the scriptures, and have family home evenings so that your sons will be prepared for their missions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p29" pid="VATJVsAVfkioUDEFI5JnWA" hash="4a8I-Q">As couple missionaries, you and your wife should prepare to serve when that time comes. We need many, many more couple missionaries.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p30" pid="VcYbfYsSlkCu3DuUcl119Q" hash="gnuGhw">The joys and blessings of serving a full-time mission are so personally sacred, they are hard to express adequately. Thirty-five years after I served my first mission, I received a letter from a family whom I had taught but did not baptize. The letter shared that their family of four little children whom I once knew now consisted of four temple marriages, three full-time missionaries, three bishops, a Relief Society president, and a dozen grandchildren maturing and developing in the gospel. You can well imagine the thrill and joy I received knowing that I had helped to find them and to teach them the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p31" pid="xJLBkgHHG0GqGQNQktutew" hash="HpGQOA">In conclusion, may I testify of the blessings of missionary service. Last year, my father passed away at age 88. As a young man, he was called on a mission during the Depression, when few were able to serve. It was hard and difficult. He always said that his decision to serve a mission was the best decision he ever made. When he died, he left 10 children, 9 living; 56 grandchildren; and 116 great-grandchildren. Of his posterity, 32 served full-time missions and 15 spouses who married into the family had served missions, resulting in 47 full-time missionaries or almost 100 years of full-time missionary work. All of this resulted, in part, because one man served a mission. I shall be forever grateful that my father served a mission and that I was motivated and taught to follow his example.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service.p32" pid="O5M8s3Uhfk2y_k3UdmzVQA" hash="RsEujw">I bear witness of this great privilege we all have in the Church—to be missionaries. Inherent in our responsibility of holding the priesthood is to be a missionary. I pray that we will all fulfill that obligation we have to the Lord. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1998/04/missionary-service</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1998-general-conference/1998-04-3020-elder-earl-c-tingey-64k-eng.mp3" length="5099846" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 1998 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Widows of Zion</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Lord loves widows. … [We] should care for and assist the widows within our family, home, ward, and neighborhood.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10033256_000_026" doc-version="2" hash="8Jvmcw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="a2nfD9zmS0aU77a0R7OIvQ" hash="3wtkBg">The Widows of Zion</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="cY97NI-ilkK4J1_lQ7LX-w" hash="CBgxUg">Earl C. Tingey</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="f0Q6M1_0xEGMscPJrCXs6Q" hash="V_CGjw">The Lord loves widows. … [We] should care for and assist the widows within our family, home, ward, and neighborhood.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-ecd.jpg" alt="Elder Earl C. Tingey" pid="dog7mcwwt0uG-4KLW5f9Yw" hash="IgrXRQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p1" pid="cU6ojs8K50aCkGmKCD1zQQ" hash="qKKa0Q">I have entitled my talk “The Widows of Zion.” The dictionary defines a widow as “a woman who has lost her husband by death and … has not remarried.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p2" pid="N3YjQBHX2U6qTcxP1BL-VA" hash="UY8Nzg">Some widows are young. Their husbands often have met an untimely death. If young children adorn their home, the young widow bears the sole responsibility for rearing them. She has an unanswered question, “Why has this happened to me?” Extreme loneliness is not unusual.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p3" pid="aVt9SSML2EGpOu3YMwmzpg" hash="n-UXfg">Other widows are older. Their husbands, following a lifetime of cherished companionship, have died of old age or ill health. Decades of loving memories, shared joy in rearing a noble family, and mutual service to Church and community are replaced by loneliness and feelings of being unneeded or unwanted. The question “How long must I wait before I can join my eternal companion?” remains unanswered. Their temple work may increase. Life often becomes more difficult. Living with family or in assisted-care facilities may replace a family home filled with a lifetime of memories.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p4" pid="Tohjb1-pPUC5urkCZO-vTQ" hash="dRe6Qg">Being alone is foreign to our sisters when they become widows. They want to be helpful and to contribute to the well-being of others. Many have limitations because of poor health. They want to remain faithful so they may one day join their eternal companions. They can teach us much about faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p5" pid="YYzswggNFUCIS6bpCoaGJw" hash="X70Afw">The doctrine of the Church is very clear regarding widows.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p6" pid="maeVdSI-2EWZJYXiopwu_A" hash="_vTAMA">In the early Church, the leaders were chastised for neglecting their widows. “Seven men of honest report” were called to assist.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p7" pid="vRvI-OS9_EOCA9p8qO7qfg" hash="UQvvmA">Paul instructed the Saints to honor widows.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> He taught that anyone who provided “not for his own, and specially for those of his own house, … hath denied the faith, and is worse than an infidel.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p8" pid="DgGSW38EgUSRKaM2RahoOg" hash="kBh7Fg">As Brigham Young organized the first pioneer trek to the valley of the Great Salt Lake in 1847, he counseled the Saints as follows:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p9" pid="wPPXdQ9ghUa4cnVFfoMP_Q" hash="9srFpQ">“Let each company bear an equal proportion, according to the dividend of their property, in taking the poor, the widows, the fatherless, and the families of those who have gone into the army, that the cries of the widow and the fatherless come not up into the ears of the Lord against this people.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p10" pid="vxiz5TtoWUi2J2ubzP22QA" hash="lUPqjQ">I believe this effort of helping the widows cross the plains is one of the greatest modern examples of how we should care for widows.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p11" pid="_1IHTFXSrEeW0S-DSwBBbw" hash="gfFrMw">Modern revelation reveals the order of the Church: “Women have claim on their husbands for their maintenance, until their husbands are taken. … Children have claim upon their parents for their maintenance. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p12" pid="_8LHWvkgvEyQ9zSZCtRjeA" hash="1hSu5g">“And after that, they have claim upon the church.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p13" pid="pn9g1HXeeEK5b5ufzq7Yww" hash="FxsBFg">The Doctrine and Covenants states further, “And the storehouse shall be kept by the consecrations of the church; and widows and orphans shall be provided for, as also the poor.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p14" pid="6g66g1rRa06CoJezufd7vA" hash="QK4MoQ">The book of James contains one of the most beautiful descriptions of the doctrine of the Church regarding our responsibility as family and friends of widows: “Pure religion and undefiled before God and the Father is this, To visit the fatherless and widows in their affliction, and to keep himself unspotted from the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p15" pid="OJdrW641-kOtiSn38F0-Bg" hash="HSgh3g">The term <span class="emphasis">widows</span> is used 34 times in the scriptures. In 23 of these passages, the term refers to widows and the fatherless. I believe the Lord has a tender feeling toward widows and the fatherless, or orphans. He knows that they may have to rely more completely on Him than on others. Their prayers will be more personal and lasting, service to fellowmen more genuine, and faith greater.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p16" pid="nNO5lxHCTE-zgyhsYyHXEA" hash="x7nfRA">The faith of widows is legendary in scripture.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p17" pid="KbFU-efojEmfdL-V22smYQ" hash="citf3w">The widow of Zarephath showed her faith when she provided the prophet Elijah with a morsel of bread rather than using the last of her meal and oil to feed her son and herself and then die. The scriptures record: “And she went and did according to the saying of Elijah: and she, and he, and her house, did eat many days.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p18" pid="je-vwW7j0UWNSct2aZDtKA" hash="6Mfv4A">“And the barrel of meal wasted not, neither did the cruse of oil fail, according to the word of the Lord, which he spake by Elijah.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p19" pid="XF2rz10X90m9RMBfW0W4Nw" hash="xrQsMg">Perhaps symbolic of the trust widows have in the Lord is the phrase “and she went and did according to the saying of Elijah.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p20" pid="qZiL1s4dlEKgmdBcSqvy4g" hash="WErT_Q">Anna, a widow of 84 years who served continually in the temple, recognized the infant Jesus at His presentation in the temple.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p21" pid="v2VgkmZCwUKIBFGFfonGRg" hash="0PGPhA">Perceiving the great faith of the widow of Nain, Jesus Christ raised her dead son, her only son, as he was being taken outside the gate of the city to be buried.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p22" pid="N_wGyoc0G0CUGR9lb9twEg" hash="SLRJ9Q">As an example of the true spirit of giving, the story of the widow’s mite is forever immortalized as among the greatest of all the Savior’s teachings:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p23" pid="NSxnwEDXsUSqw3UAB9RGMQ" hash="gJVYpA">“The people cast money into the treasury: and many that were rich cast in much.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p24" pid="5HonufOSGEGrvL96jeUWrQ" hash="kTPWnA">“And there came a certain poor widow, and she threw in two mites. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p25" pid="7LliVNGz9UGM24g6ZQZ_FQ" hash="4lFl4Q">“And he called unto him his disciples, and saith unto them, Verily I say unto you, That this poor widow hath cast more in, than all they which have cast into the treasury:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p26" pid="Tp8NrVGLFkCIOEt2mE3lPQ" hash="pnF57g">“For all they did cast in of their abundance; but she of her want did cast in all that she had, even all her living.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p27" pid="l0g0g9TcikmY_YxGNmNpPA" hash="LeEckw">To you wonderful sisters who find yourselves as widows, please know that God loves you. You are the choice among the choice. I know whereof I speak. My own mother has been a widow for almost three years. She presides as a noble matriarch over an extended family of 247. My wife’s mother, who is 97, remains faithful and continues to endure to the end, despite failing health. Dear sisters, your very lives, as an example of righteous living, continue to inspire younger family members to do better. You continue as teachers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p28" pid="YhNAIzbsMEKVJXOf21PnMQ" hash="eXlMAg">At some period in God’s timetable, you will join your eternal companion and serve together, forever, in the great work in the spirit world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p29" pid="BIDWWNxkI0Sv3VMgxiXL1Q" hash="fevhag">For you young widows with ever-increasing family responsibilities, know that God is aware of your needs and that He will provide. Continue to exercise faith and good works. Faithful family and Church members will assist. Be willing to receive assistance from others as necessary. Your children will know that you provide them with a double measure of love. It is my testimony that our Heavenly Father will abundantly compensate your family with eternal blessings because of the goodness of your hearts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p30" pid="g6T4jySxcUS34JDo9Gw05w" hash="6kOnCQ">To the family and friends of widows, God knows of your service and He may judge your works by how well you assist the widow. President James E. Faust once shared with the General Authorities a wonderful story about how neighbors and friends in a small farming community in central Utah treated the widows. They each had so many hours or minutes to take water turns to irrigate their home gardens. They agreed that they could each take a little less water so that the widows of the neighborhood could have more water for their gardens.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p31" pid="OpRmtvN3s0KHq_kopWcFBA" hash="z5WWBQ">I recently observed five elderly widows drive together to a Church meeting in a modest car. They entered the meeting together and sat down beside each other. They seemed to draw strength and protection from one another. I felt the goodness of their noble lives as I watched their tender association with one another in the twilight of their lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p32" pid="WhvkvfVmkkalutGSnZKdCw" hash="4Dg-4g">Brothers and sisters, the Lord loves widows. I know that the leaders of the Church are concerned about the welfare of widows. We members should care for and assist the widows within our family, home, ward, and neighborhood. I urge you young people—members of the Primary, youth, and young adults—to take the opportunity to assist and draw strength from the widows in your community.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion.p33" pid="NaB1fEfcmkqczd9Wq63Q9g" hash="zCsq5Q">May we be more caring and considerate to the widows of Zion is my humble prayer. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2000/04/the-widows-of-zion</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2000-general-conference/2000-04-4030-elder-earl-c-tingey-64k-eng.mp3" length="4408028" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2000 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Law of Tithing</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Lord has established the law of tithing as the law of revenue of His Church. … It is also a law by which we show our loyalty to the Lord.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029598_000_004" doc-version="2" hash="3aFjPg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Wi7mn9eCzUeHUgOs6g-BVw" hash="r8UIog">The Law of Tithing</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="PRfRYwIBG0uLJD3sD9CReg" hash="CBgxUg">Earl C. Tingey</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="e_IeyGF5OkSGFYOQjCrRLQ" hash="Q95ONA">The Lord has established the law of tithing as the law of revenue of His Church. … It is also a law by which we show our loyalty to the Lord.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-ecd.jpg" alt="Elder Earl C. Tingey" pid="ZMgWa_rqGkCZ7ly7-9xqbQ" hash="IgrXRQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p1" pid="Dm5uKP0IHE61TvDMBVLtmA" hash="pRezfQ">Last Christmas I received a special gift from my mother. She had carefully kept in her possession over these many years a little book I first received from my parents in 1944, when I was 10 years of age.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p2" pid="RkOAmG2vJ0-yDjvjkbJ5Dw" hash="lIcOPg">This is the book. It is a journal in which I was taught to record on a weekly basis my income and expenses.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p3" pid="BtVnfToyrUyKhD27Wc9NEw" hash="ptk1Cw">As an example, my entry for the week of 29 July 1944 records that I started the week with $24.05 on hand and earned $7.00 working on our family farm. For expenses, I spent 5 cents for candy, $3.45 for a purchase, 20 cents for a movie, and $2.37 for personal clothing. I also invested $20.00 in a war savings bond and paid 70 cents tithing. I ended the week with $4.28 on hand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p4" pid="h5Jtg1lRlkekGB3amAwRYw" hash="U92tcQ">I remember questioning my father whether my wage of 25 cents an hour might be increased. But remembering that a movie was 20 cents and candy cost only 5 cents, I now realize I was probably overpaid.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p5" pid="uARQ_zUvvkK_-mEyGZ-INg" hash="UjKHDA">As I looked through this journal of more than 50 years ago, I noted that every week during the years 1944 and 1945, I paid tithing of 10 percent of my income for that week. In December 1944 I recorded that I had paid $12.35 in tithing that year—a full tithing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p6" pid="TpEqcJ0MZEy5r0XS-QRqyg" hash="GpV8Jw">This is where and how I learned to pay tithing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p7" pid="IXAtmqKUD0WALRMujncTrA" hash="8ypV2w">My wife and I taught our children the importance of setting aside tithing each week as they received an allowance or earned money babysitting or doing special jobs. They put the tithing in a little box. On fast Sunday they gave the tithing to the bishop. They also learned the value of money by saving a goodly portion of the balance of their income for a future mission and education.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p8" pid="ZwOj8nAfkUuFOSk-3QoNEw" hash="RrbSng">Our grandchildren are now following a similar pattern.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p9" pid="8OOd3Mut50uxfbmbwoD6Xg" hash="MStCYg">Let us teach this principle to our children and be sure they see us paying tithing. President Joseph F. Smith said, “Our children, as soon as they become old enough to earn means, should be taught to pay their tithing, that their names may be written in the book of the law of the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p10" pid="1GElDMhoVUKfTNtaLiyWwg" hash="cQf5ag">In my day, in Primary, we learned this little poem:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="T4WSBbhzgUmRz0wLqZWcCg" hash="JtQxIw">
            <span class="emphasis">What is tithing?</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="3gvt2J-3g0mgB3MSMmWPcg" hash="WS_Jmw">
            <span class="emphasis">I will tell you every time.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="AGDDzdk8pku9EzXFGs812A" hash="BXmgTg">
            <span class="emphasis">Ten cents from a dollar</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="pMvVosI_xUOJGS8ksS-Nzw" hash="5kzaoA">
            <span class="emphasis">And a penny from a dime.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p11" pid="fCZgthjyNEC1sVesLfpLrg" hash="98Uo5w">The doctrine of paying tithing is woven like a tapestry throughout the scriptures. Abraham paid tithing to Melchizedek.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> The children of Israel were taught to bring their tithes to the Lord.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Probably the most quoted scripture on the subject of tithing in the Old Testament is found in Malachi:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p12" pid="04LKkJslDE6PGzoppxj6uA" hash="ckhwjg">“Will a man rob God? Yet ye have robbed me. But ye say, Wherein have we robbed thee? In tithes and offerings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p13" pid="GrsGhCazLEykpb3C64jQPw" hash="IR5YPg">“Bring ye all the tithes into the storehouse, that there may be meat in mine house, and prove me now herewith, saith the Lord of hosts, if I will not open you the windows of heaven, and pour you out a blessing, that there shall not be room enough to receive it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p14" pid="EF95fDiQgUuu4quq-PP8Qw" hash="fr-KhQ">The amount of tithing we pay is the most perfect and equitable arrangement of which I know. It is one-tenth of our increase. All, from the poorest to the richest, pay the same percentage. Christ taught that principle in the story of the widow’s mite:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p15" pid="s_DAXIJlC0e23hjS2o9Jtw" hash="aMXuSQ">“And Jesus sat over against the treasury, and beheld how the people cast money into the treasury: and many that were rich cast in much.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p16" pid="-XYxPy2AmUi2E_dF6u34mw" hash="wx_stA">“And there came a certain poor widow, and she threw in two mites, which make a farthing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p17" pid="1BgMGzw1j0CnVxwxzo220Q" hash="4lFl4Q">“And he called unto him his disciples, and saith unto them, Verily I say unto you, That this poor widow hath cast more in, than all they which have cast into the treasury:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p18" pid="qPt9b8kRLkiRlGx68lPX1A" hash="Z9yHTg">“For all they did cast in of their abundance; but she of her want did cast in all that she had, even all her living.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p19" pid="0-ySFBluz0C3ybEQnbrR0w" hash="-cHkUQ">A mite is a very small coin. It was the smallest bronze coin used by the Jews. It was one-sixty-fourth of a Roman silver penny.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p20" pid="gYNVdPWQLEmaWClMFLYwnA" hash="ddTv2A">In this dispensation, the Lord has established the law of tithing as the law of revenue of His Church. Without it, we could not carry out the eternal purposes of the Lord. It is also a law by which we show our loyalty to the Lord and prove ourselves worthy for privileges, ordinances, and blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p21" pid="xv7I7B5qzE-Chwi_QTAMYg" hash="ME3dHw">I was recently in Independence, Missouri, and felt a need to drive an hour north to Far West. The Latter-day Saints settled Far West in 1836 as a place of refuge from persecution. Far West became the county seat, with an estimated 3,000 to 5,000 inhabitants. It was the headquarters of the Church for a season. My own ancestors lived there.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p22" pid="vL5F8-cR3ECvMugNCUNnqg" hash="iQSSQg">As I arrived at Far West and looked about, all I could see was rolling farmlands. There was no city, no roads or buildings. There was only a peaceful, grassy temple site containing four cornerstones, surrounded by a modest fence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p23" pid="NHcFrvVQ-kW7OvDK9qeTfw" hash="3SgqYA">In 1838 the Saints were driven from Far West. Joseph Smith and others were arrested and taken to the nearby Liberty Jail. There they languished under the most horrible conditions imaginable for six months. My own ancestors suffered terribly in Far West and almost lost their lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p24" pid="DCCz6ugIkkCXQrzKSzku0w" hash="bQrOdA">As I stood in Far West and visualized what it once was, I opened my scriptures and read section 119 of the Doctrine and Covenants. This revelation was given through the Prophet Joseph Smith at Far West on 8 July 1838, in the midst of these persecutions:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p25" pid="ipLgfJwCI0aQu0f1FVu--g" hash="swkhuA">“And this shall be the beginning of the tithing of my people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p26" pid="UfB6oHUNKEy8JhA9yI8UGQ" hash="cQ1_wg">“And after that, those who have thus been tithed shall pay one-tenth of all their interest annually; and this shall be a standing law unto them forever, for my holy priesthood, saith the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p27" pid="SYCso8hBY0SLBxobgMX0sw" hash="ek4Bvw">I thought to myself that the law of tithing could not have been received by the members of the Church at a less opportune time than then. But they received it, and the members commenced living this new law at a time when they were losing their possessions and, in some cases, their lives. As I visited Far West, I gained a spiritual testimony of the law of tithing that was stronger and deeper than I had ever before felt.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p28" pid="voc6m7hlD0ekz9cUtVmQTQ" hash="aV_UrA">I would like to offer a word of counsel to the many thousands of members joining the Church today as a result of the diligent efforts of our missionaries. Exercise your faith. Pay your tithing. This law may be different from that to which you were accustomed prior to your baptism. But nothing you do as a new convert will more completely prepare you to enjoy the wonderful blessings that await you—even temple blessings—than paying your tithing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p29" pid="_uUSKh5VG0GB7XVXjaVcuQ" hash="Tx69eQ">Now, a brief word of counsel to missionaries. Teach tithing to your investigators in such a way that they will gain a testimony of this wonderful principle of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p30" pid="X6esxBvUA0KngKZR-Isktw" hash="ku8E5w">Joseph F. Smith’s mother was known as “Widow Smith.” She was the widow of Hyrum Smith, who was martyred with the Prophet Joseph. She once rebuked the tithing clerk who stated that because of her poverty, she should not have to pay her tithing. She said: “‘Would you deny me a blessing? If I did not pay my tithing, I should expect the Lord to withhold his blessings from me. I pay my tithing, not only because it is a law of God, but because I expect a blessing by doing it. By keeping this and other laws, I expect to prosper, and to be able to provide for my family.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p31" pid="tvTHyg-ZG0KAOODa0lp3HA" hash="-QYdkQ">Did she prosper? Her son and grandson became presidents of the Church, and her descendants today include a member of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles and many notable Church leaders.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p32" pid="1uB4nPaWjkq_Zbdm66fCGA" hash="C0R01Q">Speaking of his mother, Joseph F. Smith once said she paid “tithes of her sheep and cattle, the tenth pound of her butter, her tenth chicken, the tenth of her eggs, the tenth pig, the tenth calf, the tenth colt—a tenth of everything she raised.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p33" pid="5OCpcZoTkUK8PBAU47i5qw" hash="Unp-xw">I was once teaching the law of tithing to a group of Church leaders in Africa. One brother said, “Elder Tingey, how can I pay tithing when I have no income?” I inquired and determined that he had a large family of seven or eight children and was unemployed. I asked how he fed his family. He said he had a small garden and raised geese. I asked, “What do the geese do?” He replied, “They lay eggs.” I responded, “What if one morning you discovered 10 geese eggs in the nests of your geese?” A light flickered on in his soul. “I could take one egg and give it to my branch president,” he answered. He understood, and he could become a full-tithe payer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p34" pid="cITp6tphLUu21O1qHvq3Gw" hash="pmpkKA">As we pay and teach our children to pay tithing, we develop a family that is deeply rooted in making and keeping temple covenants. The most glorious of all blessings we receive in this life and in the eternities are blessings that come from knowing that our families are sealed together for all eternity. Today some may find that they are denying themselves these privileges by their failure to pay tithing. To those who find themselves in this situation, my counsel is to exercise your faith, prove the Lord herewith, and pay your tithing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p35" pid="v797jeYQ5EeYooE6cnR79A" hash="4qdBDw">A special peace that will surpass all understanding will come to you and your family as you pay a full tithing. You will find that all fears concerning finances and care of family will diminish. You will come to know that your Heavenly Father loves you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing.p36" pid="TjNTt6SFlUi1DV2n3keAxA" hash="MZDR3w">I am grateful that my parents taught me to pay tithing. I bear my humble testimony that paying tithing is a true principle of the gospel of Jesus Christ. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2002/04/the-law-of-tithing</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2002-general-conference/2002-04-1030-elder-earl-c-tingey-64k-eng.mp3" length="5477414" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2002 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For the Strength of Youth</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The standards of the Church are firm and true. They are for your safety and eternal security.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10031248_000_021" doc-version="2" hash="O-yMgA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="0gU4Ouh87Uadwwz1etEA5A" hash="ex-ezQ">For the Strength of Youth</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="H1Z5EaDPxkedlvnxthggpA" hash="CBgxUg">Earl C. Tingey</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="7cesISQj1EWPFfGTiR4zdQ" hash="0VUHPg">The standards of the Church are firm and true. They are for your safety and eternal security.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-153.jpg" alt="Elder Earl C. Tingey" pid="D5PheIMJ9ECpVphpFzf80w" hash="-0EviQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p1" pid="EBdl7jVkkkKCgdDD9HEW8w" hash="CLv9oA">My dear brethren of the priesthood, how honored I am to be with you this evening. Four of my grandsons are in the Conference Center tonight—Craig, Brent, Kendall, and Michael. I would like to speak to them and all Aaronic Priesthood bearers and invite others to listen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p2" pid="ewTp-kYTbEKHMWKeSDNTzQ" hash="Qlgj_A">In a message from the First Presidency, included in the <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth</span> booklet, we read:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p3" pid="M9s99QyaEkacweC8gVqzdA" hash="VpAUFA">“Our beloved young men … , we have great confidence in you. You are choice spirits who have come forth in this day when the responsibilities and opportunities, as well as the temptations, are the greatest. You are at the beginning of your journey through this mortal life. Your Heavenly Father wants your life to be joyful and to lead you back into His presence. The decisions you make now will determine much of what will follow during your life and throughout eternity.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p4" pid="mQxshhCsHE2i6sb24M-uEQ" hash="igDBNg">You live in a world of great uncertainty. There are many voices. There are many paths. Not all lead to our Heavenly Father. How will you know to whom to listen or where to go?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p5" pid="wrZA2WUUREG19uB109S3CQ" hash="Yp9g0Q">The prophet Jacob answered these questions in the following scripture: “The Spirit speaketh the truth and lieth not. Wherefore, it speaketh of things as they really are, and of things as they really will be.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p6" pid="vIfJDdcwZ0uV73_gk6oMrw" hash="TBN9hA">But what are “things as they really are” as referred to by Jacob? Elder Neal A. Maxwell, addressing this subject, has said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p7" pid="GHdhkNFY_0yC7qlwmDe27Q" hash="BDko-w">“Without the obedient response to ‘things as they really are,’ there are the endless detours and the empty searches for another course of life. … A course of life that is wrong now cannot and will not be proven right later on. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p8" pid="7jqvCSDPJUy_7bNy6nc-aA" hash="Kz1PIA">“The gospel of the Lord Jesus Christ gives us many truths … —that there really is the living God; there really is the living Church; there really are living prophets; there really are living scriptures; and there really will be a resurrection with a judgment.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p9" pid="ukFE1uG54keEev-bgS6bMg" hash="Nr1RkA">There are certain truths, certain “things as they really are,” that are enforced by standards—many of which can be measured. Let’s look at several examples in athletics.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p10" pid="D3mA0t_ZK02dq8FZAYMYZA" hash="uUfCNg">The cover of the March 2004 <span class="emphasis">New Era</span> shows a picture of Moroni Rubio of Mexico. Two years ago, at age 16, he took first place at the Central American Junior Championships in the 100-meter sprint. His current best time is 10.46 seconds.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> He would be timed by a stopwatch, which measures performance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p11" pid="XnVvOmM230mhwDB9osML6w" hash="iGjLQw">The men’s world record for high jump is held by a Cuban athlete who jumped approximately 8 feet (2.4 m). Can you imagine jumping that high? High jumpers leap over a horizontal bar resting on two vertical poles. This bar represents a standard, a measure to meet or exceed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p12" pid="LoQEDc9ZLkmQGcnKSG6pHg" hash="bT9Xkg">Imagine holding a track meet where the runners are not measured by a stopwatch or where the high jumpers do not have a horizontal bar to measure their jumps.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p13" pid="4Y_pFW_qLEuRhGSS3BumZw" hash="zQJtqA">In life, as in athletics, there are standards, or measured behavior. There are rights and wrongs. As priesthood holders, we do not high jump without a horizontal bar.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p14" pid="LPJH7Bujvk29lMI1Aumm2w" hash="nQVHvg">Unfortunately, we are seeing the removal of traditional standards of morality and behavior in today’s world. The vernacular of today is “anything goes.” The world views time-honored standards as old-fashioned or out-of-date.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p15" pid="cXGI-u3yz0a-UFKDo9AjZw" hash="BfS1lw">We belong to a church where adhering to standards is expected. Things that have always been wrong in the past are still wrong today. The Church does not modify standards of morality by adapting to changing customs or to the mores of the societies in which we live.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p16" pid="cZiIWaKhLkuUZyP_RU4Iqw" hash="oZgm6A">President Gordon B. Hinckley tells of an experience he had as a boy lying in the bed of an old farm wagon at night with his brother Sherman. They “looked at the myriads of stars in the heavens, and took turns picking out familiar stars and tracing the Big Dipper, the handle and the cup, to find the North Star.” President Hinckley said he was fascinated by the North Star. Regardless of the earth’s rotation, the North Star maintained its position in the heavens and never moved. He said: “I recognized it as a constant in the midst of change. It was something that could always be counted on, something that was dependable, an anchor in what otherwise appeared to be a moving and unstable firmament.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p17" pid="lhttFF3-PkmnO2pG3aGQhw" hash="fdDNhg">Noting the unwavering, absolute position of the North Star, one writer told the contrasting story of a young boy who became lost on a camping trip. When his father finally found him, his father asked if he had remembered to pick out something in the landscape that he could always see. This, his father said, would have helped him to fix a steady position. The boy said, “I did.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p18" pid="Euq5EeY5wUeAwzg_SPnGwA" hash="MaI_Yw">“What was it?” the father asked.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p19" pid="_azqJW2zik-PlGI4uXiyaQ" hash="hc8Kdw">“That rabbit over there,” the boy said.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p20" pid="kzEpnhlg_UCb7hVGdgGGjQ" hash="Y4Xs8g">Young men of the Aaronic Priesthood, fix your gaze on the unchanging standards of the gospel and not on the moving rabbit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p21" pid="L09Klldiu0SHCw-FcMrR_Q" hash="GdSXwA">In the <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth</span> booklet, the following standards, among others, are like a North Star to you: choose friends with high standards, do not disfigure your body with tattoos or body piercings, avoid pornography, do not listen to music that contains offensive language, do not use profanity, date only those who have high standards, remain sexually pure, repent as necessary, be honest, keep the Sabbath day holy, pay tithing, keep the Word of Wisdom.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p22" pid="wxMIU1mfVkWnDFDgFfqVsQ" hash="wYaSDw">A dozen years ago, in one of the countries of Africa, we had faithful members of the Church who had been meeting in their homes for several years. I went to that country to see if we could receive permission from the government to bring in missionaries and establish the Church. I met with a high-ranking government minister. He gave me 20 minutes to explain our position.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p23" pid="MKZhiKret0qkpYumF9QX9w" hash="Ww2ugw">When I finished he said, “I do not see where anything you have told me is any different from what is currently available in our country. I see no reason to approve your request to bring missionaries into our country.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p24" pid="9-iayE3nkkmGSe0ucCi_0g" hash="WFKLpw">He stood up to usher me out of his office. I was panic-stricken. I had failed. In a moment our meeting would be over. What could I do? I offered a silent prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p25" pid="nK14n1YF-0uZGoqz-e7qlQ" hash="8axQXw">Then I had an inspired thought. I said to the minister, “Sir, if you will give me five more minutes, I would like to share one other thought with you. Then I will leave.” He kindly consented.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p26" pid="Ld1R0IIg70ae5kQAJFaf0g" hash="W10psg">I reached for my wallet and removed this small <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth</span> booklet, which I have always carried.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p27" pid="rD_7RA24r0qhbJpFlKVISQ" hash="8DtWtg">I said, “This is a little booklet of standards we give all of the youth in our Church.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p28" pid="NkqZPE_XZkyJt7gIIKJmHw" hash="NoQEww">I then read some of the standards I have mentioned tonight. When I finished he said, “You mean to tell me you expect the youth of your church to live these standards?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p29" pid="BzL71eden0irs8Tnsb0LsQ" hash="ER4TGg">“Yes,” I replied, “and they do.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p30" pid="9Ov4ng73mkeJq6yYEB_shw" hash="8S4Ayw">“That is amazing,” he said. “Could you send me some of these booklets so that I could distribute them to the youth of my church?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p31" pid="P_Z6uoMxI0yiQitYX8cXQw" hash="SxEKsQ">I replied, “Yes,” and I did.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p32" pid="KFbyCekQgkCl-8x6pHqSBg" hash="FviXEQ">Several months later we received official approval from the government of that country to come and establish the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p33" pid="bh2MKTCqp0acQ5CR0GCnoA" hash="ZLDDdA">Young men, these standards you are privileged to keep are truly a pearl of great price. The world does not understand them. Many good people seek them. You have them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p34" pid="RLkR9ase-kCjdyJAd3Lhkg" hash="xt4RHg">The Prophet Joseph Smith received a revelation that establishes how we may know today which voices to listen to—what standards to follow. In this revelation, our time, or generation, was referred to as a time when men would “see an overflowing scourge” and “a desolating sickness [would] cover the land.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p35" pid="7HUcRWT8EkeUd3-IPNOXCg" hash="DFs4_A">The Lord then gave the standard of safety that will protect faithful followers. He said, “But my disciples shall stand in holy places, and shall not be moved.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p36" pid="NoIzdKh3SUWYh11VtsZcGg" hash="SulSpg">The Brethren of the First Presidency and the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles are disciples who stand in holy places. They are not moved or swayed by changing times from what has been established as true in all prior generations. The standards of the Church are firm and true. They are for your safety and eternal security. When you commit to live them, you are measured against time-proven standards that are approved by God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p37" pid="KXmTJrGXNU-jIFxdriSH5Q" hash="PSeCpg">Now, my grandsons and dear brethren of the Aaronic Priesthood, you are in a race for life. It is not a brief sprint. It is more like a marathon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p38" pid="WHTCbJa8d0q21A-oYn92MQ" hash="BFUnRw">You will be tested and proven against God’s established standards. You will be guided by the Spirit to help you know what to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p39" pid="bz858g3dR0ik3WQs14ejlA" hash="FMpJhA">We are almost the only organization left that has established, time-honored standards. Most others have succumbed to the culture of our world. How blessed we are to have living prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth.p40" pid="kLunye55Jka36q0MG4vEaA" hash="gZTxYQ">May you be blessed as you keep the standards of the Church. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2004/04/for-the-strength-of-youth</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2004-general-conference/2004-04-3030-elder-earl-c-tingey-64k-eng.mp3" length="5411859" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2004 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Great Plan of Happiness</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Through the infinite Atonement, God has provided a means whereby we can both overcome our sins and become completely clean again.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006561_000_025" doc-version="3" hash="oNZT6w"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="Z3tu5IGF7EKAosqRFRAgIg" hash="LkdWvQ">The Great Plan of Happiness</h1><p class="authorName" uuid="c5c167ab-7f9e-4b99-9e0a-103cbbc9f335" pid="TJtkG_NFS0S_M4zhsD92Mw" hash="CBgxUg">Earl C. Tingey</p><p class="kicker" pid="X9AfOrseF0WBAQShVkLbnA" hash="Ykia5w">Through the infinite Atonement, God has provided a means whereby we can both overcome our sins and become completely clean again.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" uuid="3612e2c8-6161-4309-911a-966832933c16">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.t1" uuid="">
      <img src="en2006lp.nfo-o-dd.jpg" alt="Elder Earl C. Tingey" uuid="5f08b1fe-02d5-4c99-ae2b-408980e4bd17" pid="hwM5ClbfGEGca2CPKf2d1A" hash="eUJ7uw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p1" uuid="9b3394ff-62cd-4510-aec1-403b0213dfed" pid="Pns4v0o0ckW80e_ffflGdg" hash="IBqsjg">The prophet Jacob asked, “Why not speak of the atonement of Christ, and attain to a perfect knowledge of him?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p2" uuid="4d678268-756d-42cf-b5c2-d7c543f9205c" pid="X44heoRMA0eylJfeLZpwvw" hash="0iufCg">I take that question as the subject of my talk—why not speak of the Atonement of Jesus Christ?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p3" uuid="c8ae7d23-4196-441b-bf60-f3633d72d4c8" pid="xJdIJojr2UuCo1uapj4AkA" hash="tE_78g">Alma refers to the Atonement as “the great plan of happiness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> I shall use that phrase to describe the beautiful doctrine we know as the Atonement of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p4" uuid="ec71ef04-1ab3-44a6-a26c-f5696baf104b" pid="GjeX4CKoZk-9CQ-VopH6oQ" hash="OecqFA">President Hugh B. Brown once declared: “Sooner or later life’s vicissitudes bring each of us to grips with this important subject … of the immortality of the soul, and man’s relationship to Deity. … Each of us, regardless of color, creed, or nationality, has a rendezvous with the experience that we call death.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p5" uuid="649c1521-3200-4941-8dd4-a2018d898c24" pid="p2424m1CBUSIl7GRHp0lmw" hash="kpOFSA">Most of us, in sorrow and loss, have reverently stood at the grave of a loved one and asked the question, “Is there any happiness in death?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p6" uuid="e8a807e3-7faa-49be-970a-4e6128d34381" pid="QIOXYgGcTUG3toumeGqjqQ" hash="R1EqQA">A Book of Mormon prophet answers this question for us with joyful expressions of thanksgiving for the Atonement of Jesus Christ, which ransoms us from death: “O the wisdom of God, his mercy and grace! … O the greatness and the justice of our God!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p7" uuid="f54daf60-8a2e-4001-b998-ae7b52f63f51" pid="bccJi4fh8EWTzvvNfRp_9A" hash="IHz0Qw">Let me share five truths of the great plan of happiness that have brought this kind of joy to me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p8" uuid="a78e2f9f-4a6d-4ae4-a681-9242802b1974" pid="qbuGpI8PhEywkC5t7kd_Ow" hash="Kx0NvA">
        <span class="strong">First:</span> A knowledge of the plan confirms that there is a God and He has a Son, Jesus Christ. The Father and the Son are perfect. They live in heaven, and They possess glorified bodies of spirit, flesh, and bones.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p9" uuid="e2a89371-a9e0-4889-af2b-a93281ff2c12" pid="TD1dMuHQxkaHHGwJizfpLg" hash="iWKmaA">These truths were revealed to us in this dispensation when the boy Joseph Smith knelt in humble prayer and later declared: “I saw two Personages, whose brightness and glory defy all description, standing above me in the air. One of them spake unto me, calling me by name and said, pointing to the other—<span class="emphasis">This is My Beloved Son. Hear Him!</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p10" uuid="5327c095-860c-428c-b4d3-2da89ade6ac1" pid="FI_lo0axnkCI7TnxLj2grg" hash="rTTdZg">
        <span class="strong">Second:</span> Knowing the identity of the Father and the Son helps us know that all of us are placed on earth to acquire a physical body, gain experience, and prove ourselves worthy to return to our Heavenly Father. Laws govern our mortal life on earth. When we transgress the law, we sin. When we sin, we break eternal laws; the law of justice requires a penalty or a punishment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p11" uuid="ddd5c3c5-013b-46de-a347-fcc330322d76" pid="W3Lqw4rKqkeAmw5PdM-dTQ" hash="BI_AYA">Sin and the need to repent might be represented by a man who takes a journey. On his back is a large empty bag. From time to time, he picks up a rock, representing the transgression of a law. He places the rock in the bag on his back. Over time, the bag becomes full. It is heavy. The man cannot continue on his journey. He must have a way to empty the bag and remove the rocks. This can be done only by the Savior through the Atonement.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p12" uuid="a804df3d-c34c-45d5-9b95-6482c0c7d992" pid="cY-SjdxMCE6O0bWcxWE4Yg" hash="f_hoLw">This is possible when we exercise faith in Jesus Christ, forsake sin, and make covenants through the ordinances of the gospel. As we faithfully endure to the end, we can then return to live with our Heavenly Father and His Son, Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p13" uuid="544f834f-4070-4ee6-83b4-6306b0d281fc" pid="Y-3KLWpztUSajVKvrgUZGw" hash="SeChfw">
        <span class="strong">Third:</span> Through the infinite Atonement, God has provided a means whereby we can both overcome our sins and become completely clean again. This is made possible by the eternal law of mercy. Mercy satisfies the claims of justice through our repentance and the power of the Atonement. Without the power of the Atonement and our complete repentance, we are subject to the law of justice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p14" uuid="c0a6e3a6-e1fd-4f59-9b32-a7de9692482b" pid="8Vawf297ykSiJWneRZASyA" hash="nns-PA">Alma taught that “mercy claimeth the penitent”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> and that “the plan of redemption could not be brought about, only on conditions of repentance.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p15" uuid="2988a3bd-e3ca-4644-9618-d8e3f7542ad2" pid="0RFoBJnqREKuvh4mz8kLOA" hash="ycMuSQ">The great prophet Amulek taught, “And thus mercy can satisfy the demands of justice, and encircles them in the arms of safety, while he that exercises no faith unto repentance is exposed to the whole law of the demands of justice; therefore only unto him that has faith unto repentance is brought about the great and eternal plan of redemption.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p16" uuid="8db0d51d-b12a-4faa-9a3c-700b8e07f2a5" pid="9XgwReIlyEuIgEhhTGWHAQ" hash="5AnoZQ">Adam and Eve, our first parents, transgressed law and were cast out of the beautiful Garden of Eden. Adam and Eve were taught the great plan of salvation that they might find happiness in this life.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p17" uuid="48db5ea1-2135-4411-92dd-b61865a856f9" pid="9ETdr9BWG0Cg6gJiEtLzpw" hash="Ok31OQ">Adam said, “For because of my transgression my eyes are opened, and in this life I shall have joy, and again in the flesh I shall see God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p18" uuid="fcd48988-8ae3-457d-bf10-e8b514a34730" pid="Y4E4fk987Eu3529SOVtbqg" hash="EHnW4Q">Eve uttered a similar acclamation of happiness: “Were it not for our transgression we never should have had seed, and never should have known good and evil, and the joy of our redemption.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p19" uuid="3915bf8a-3e8c-4254-8075-02bf6cbc91e3" pid="pNOWtlqczkyUv2flBdrlZA" hash="nZkJEA">
        <span class="strong">Fourth:</span> The Fall of Adam and Eve brought about two deaths. We are subject to those deaths.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p20" uuid="35a4a9b8-3e38-4fa9-ac3e-cf852a65366e" pid="bWpOuK8ZokiUu_zRUU6lqg" hash="m5uX-Q">Physical death is the separation of the spirit from the physical body. Because of the Fall of Adam, all mankind will suffer physical death.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p21" uuid="6b76a1c8-afda-4a14-9baf-5580a9b314a1" pid="aQpEUGVCr0Kcq9YdJKqoHA" hash="k55K9A">The second death is spiritual. It is separation from God’s presence. Adam and Eve freely conversed with God in the Garden of Eden. After their transgression, they lost that privilege. Thereafter, communication from God came only through faith and sacrifice, combined with heartfelt petitioning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p22" uuid="81c306a1-e287-452a-a9b5-285053252653" pid="z1e1LWDUr0aITcg42-dvjQ" hash="EXkkRw">Currently, we are all in the state of spiritual death. We are separated from God. He dwells in heaven; we live on earth. We would like to return to Him. He is clean and perfect. We are unclean and imperfect.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p23" uuid="cc28c365-c9cf-4437-b406-e40164ca9668" pid="O3eI_Av6HEmlBQ22rPl08g" hash="6BbKBQ">The power of Christ’s Atonement overcame both deaths.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p24" uuid="98a55f4f-c7bb-4941-9c74-59ef8b1f9488" pid="uETXvq4uckCrvEa57KzVbg" hash="oYN_qQ">Following His Crucifixion and burial in a borrowed tomb, Christ was resurrected on the third day. This Resurrection reunited Christ’s physical body with His spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p25" uuid="c86eac78-cb72-4c34-b5e7-87ce6b281d07" pid="KlzjL60CbkWZ9wBmqz1dIw" hash="Av7oqQ">The Resurrection from the dead is a most beautiful aspect of the Atonement and truly a part of the plan of happiness; the Resurrection is universal and applies to the entire human family. We will all be resurrected. I bear testimony of that fact and truth. This is an unconditional gift from God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p26" uuid="49a4b3e9-8581-4509-b6ce-bd76c550a057" pid="RF6iD6mgykyW3HVrqu3vUQ" hash="PjFWXw">But to be resurrected does not overcome the second death. To gain eternal life and live in the presence of the Father and the Son, we must repent and become eligible for mercy, which will satisfy justice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p27" uuid="6bd361b0-048c-41b6-a633-6e874a3de44d" pid="GLNT5HjEBU2FjhsXi1Efig" hash="tLYHJA">The revelations teach:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p28" uuid="d7fec699-d4d3-4725-a0de-b25ce04a90f5" pid="vTFdnz2AgkyF6GzoNCETzA" hash="PxIU-g">“This life is the time for men to prepare to meet God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p29" uuid="4d644e53-8aa4-4719-88a6-ceca94bcd3ca" pid="OTo_vi0KIUSZcTJd3FtYJw" hash="TQtw_A">“Do not procrastinate the day of your repentance.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p30" uuid="d194b56e-a0a0-4643-b961-1054b8e0bd80" pid="IroKRtkPtUa0AtDD5L6yBA" hash="qOE7Rg">“That same spirit which doth possess your bodies at the time that ye go out of this life, that same spirit will have power to possess your body in that eternal world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p31" uuid="8b92187a-9a62-4156-85d2-b304b35355c8" pid="9ez2sqwSKkGpsxII8dOvkA" hash="2ogGGg">
        <span class="strong">Fifth:</span> Jesus Christ was born of an earthly mother, Mary. From her, He inherited mortality and became subject to death.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p32" uuid="55f000d5-cbf6-4f63-90aa-d0574497fbe1" pid="s1LxuXNwI0ySb6DN-aUipw" hash="jJRL-Q">Joseph was His earthly mentor. God in heaven was His Father. From Him, He inherited immortality, the power to overcome physical death.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p33" uuid="241d0d08-c1e9-4027-babc-4b1af491cae2" pid="vIavf57mjEClqOh_dzcYtQ" hash="eySM3w">As the one who was chosen to fulfill the requirements of the Atonement, Jesus Christ condescended to come to earth and be born as a helpless babe to Mary. He condescended to be tempted, tried, mocked, judged, and crucified, even though He had power and authority to prevent such actions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p34" uuid="ebbc9926-8d83-4395-8594-a7f7f4246d05" pid="y1P5nGri60eoSqcH6DLAXw" hash="FYzXsQ">President John Taylor described the condescension of Christ in these beautiful words: “It was further necessary that He should descend below all things, in order that He might raise others above all things; for if He could not raise Himself and be exalted through those principles brought about by the atonement, He could not raise others; He could not do for others what He could not do for Himself.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p35" uuid="ccf09de1-3059-476f-b4c1-9b44296115e9" pid="_QwnIPdcf0er44JjAjopBQ" hash="dDwWfw">Christ’s suffering in the Garden of Gethsemane epitomizes the most magnificent of all the attributes of Christ, His perfect love. Here we see that He truly loved all of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p36" uuid="5b4a6720-332d-4d58-ac88-39ed7ee01783" pid="KtjtUct-x06Wa1f1n-RGIg" hash="69lfpQ">An English theologian, writing in the nineteenth century, said of this event: “All that the human frame can tolerate of suffering was to be heaped upon His shrinking body. … Pain in its acutest sting, shame in its most overwhelming brutality, all the burden of … sin … —this was what He must now face.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p37" uuid="3571220d-6fda-45ca-b0fd-9a505f0224b3" pid="paQ-17JVuEO0xLb_5IwVgg" hash="tQnDsQ">Describing His suffering, the Lord said in modern revelation: “Which suffering caused myself, even God, the greatest of all, to tremble because of pain, and to bleed at every pore, and to suffer both body and spirit.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p38" uuid="f9a52594-a1c4-416e-aa9c-386b9df0ac27" pid="CVC7HPD1nE-383LwXSRP5g" hash="VpbqHw">The Atonement is an event that enables us to be reconciled to God. The word <span class="emphasis">atonement,</span> or “at-one-ment,” means to restore or to come back. In terms of family, it means to be reunited with one another and with God and His Son, Jesus Christ. It means sadness through separation will become happiness through reuniting.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p39" uuid="1f8abd17-bfcd-42df-af81-27c4630db92e" pid="N8u7UI_-jUakxXImSZtSPA" hash="nbJ2bA">In conclusion, I share the words of President Boyd K. Packer:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p40" uuid="0f0da17d-feb4-40d4-9d76-d7b700a9d95c" pid="OwJOXb3GmU-E879TFvfuPQ" hash="DMP5CQ">“If you understand the great plan of happiness and follow it, what goes on in the world will not determine your happiness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p41" uuid="19e95d98-a7e2-4338-82b9-c5b47451b630" pid="s1e_tV01Hket84JsRKMv1Q" hash="JJNM3A">I bear testimony of that truth and of the love that our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ has shown for us by providing the Atonement, the great plan of happiness, for all of us. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/04/the-great-plan-of-happiness</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2006-general-conference/2006-04-4030-elder-earl-c-tingey-64k-eng.mp3" length="5625135" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2006 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prophets—Pioneer and Modern Day</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Both President Brigham Young and President Gordon B. Hinckley are prophets who have led the Church by inspiration and revelation.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008333_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="eql8PA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="HTMN7wlMP0WNWQH54SyyTA" hash="A7-WEg">Prophets—</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="Tq9IGZm5SEuSMNVlgowPLg" hash="T47z5A">Pioneer and Modern Day</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="jxRZ1NJzJUuYrduWwA5Hhw" hash="CBgxUg">Earl C. Tingey</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="4atlyigdPUy1YHnCE9vHaw" hash="rNWpDg">Both President Brigham Young and President Gordon B. Hinckley are prophets who have led the Church by inspiration and revelation.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/TingeyEC_00.jpg" alt="Elder Earl C. Tingey" pid="K60aSPnFGU-yj2fDHw-Qag" hash="_cxxmg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p1" pid="1pF5wr4pjk-UrFvPaR_0qQ" hash="7jkqzQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="29"></span>My brothers and sisters, as I stand at the pulpit of this old but new Tabernacle, I am overwhelmed with the sense of history I feel at this moment. As one foot is planted in the past and the other in the future, I give thanks for pioneer and modern-day prophets and apostles who have had and still have the vision to construct and extend into the future this remarkable building.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p2" pid="-anglAmOnkG4oWM_iaEbNA" hash="NVgg9g">I wish to speak of two such men of vision: Brigham Young and his successor today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p3" pid="ZP13219tXUyt47Vm0xR07Q" hash="i3PhOw">Brigham Young was the second prophet of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. He led the Church for 33 years. He built this Tabernacle and presided at its dedication during the October general conference in 1875, more than 131 years ago.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p4" pid="-hfzPGFc8UCQtGfC3A6e5w" hash="5_Odpg">His other accomplishments were many, and I can refer to only a few.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p5" pid="naf3FZ0EXEe_lnsroYVSgw" hash="j8Rhgg">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">He was a pioneer, </span>
</span>meaning someone who opens or prepares the way for others to follow. One writer said of Brigham Young: “He led a ragged and impoverished band, stripped of virtually all their earthly goods, into an unknown territory. His critics and biographers note that the man was unique among the leaders of modern history, for he alone, without any political and financial backing, established from scratch in the desert an ordered and industrious society, having no other authority than the priesthood and the spiritual strength with which he delivered his teachings. By constant exhortations and instructions, he drew his people together and inspired them in carrying out the divine mandate to build up the kingdom of God on earth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p6" pid="IHaS113ObkeV_x8GzFQwyA" hash="0_wcHQ">When Brigham Young first entered the valley of the Great Salt Lake, he declared, “This is the right place.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> He later said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p7" pid="LZqU_NlmyESPYakrOg_UAA" hash="uttWmw">“God has shown me, that this is the spot to locate his people, and here is where they will prosper; he <span class="pageBreak" page-number="30"></span>will temper the elements to the good of the Saints; he will rebuke the frost and the sterility of the soil, and the land shall become fruitful, … and we shall build a city and a temple to the most high God in this place.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p8" pid="0jvAmdvseESNknC9Vub0ag" hash="mFxmlA">Today, we can all attest to the truth of this prophecy. Truly, the desert land and the valleys of the Rocky Mountains are a fruitful and a productive land of promise and prophecy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p9" pid="3exEa_kS30-s_layoiuTgA" hash="ahFSpA">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">He built temples. </span>
</span>He started the Salt Lake Temple, which took 40 years to complete. He also started the Manti and the Logan Temples. He dedicated the St. George Temple 4 1/2 months before he died.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p10" pid="DBSqxSJETEegT3OFLzFBKQ" hash="8cO8Gw">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">He was one of America’s greatest colonizers. </span>
</span>By the time of his death, nearly 400 colonies had been established.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p11" pid="trAFHYd000C9S2S7vs2l8w" hash="btu_fA">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">He organized the Perpetual Emigrating Fund </span>
</span>to reach out to those in need, assisting those of limited means in emigrating from countries in Europe.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p12" pid="KmGSJGtPFk6AcG7tc3aUCQ" hash="p_0QIw">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">He established universities. </span>
</span>The University of Deseret is now known as the University of Utah. Latter-day Saints’ College is now known as LDS Business College. And, of course, he also established Brigham Young University.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p13" pid="nbt9Ewiqu0iWqubobDKPVw" hash="AFUH6g">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">He loved the Church and its members. </span>
</span>Brigham Young had a unique way in which he referred to the Church:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p14" pid="aEtQvegnykWC-sp7Y3lkLg" hash="_KnWOQ">“God is at the helm. This is the mighty ship Zion. You stick to the ship and honor it, and see that you are in favor with the ship Zion and you need not worry about anything else. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p15" pid="80B7unZ-C0qGy2Ev4lRQ7g" hash="uZDGFw">“… He guides the ship, and will bring us safely into port. All we have to care about is to take care of ourselves and see that we do right. Let us man the ship manfully, everyone standing faithfully and firmly to his post, and she will outride every storm and safely bear us to the harbor of celestial bliss.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p16" pid="gSttjRpbYEiV5gm0s7Zysg" hash="Drh5gg">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">He loved the youth of the Church, </span>
</span>as is evidenced by the experience of Heber J. Grant. Nine days after Heber’s birth, his father, Jedediah M. Grant, who was Second Counselor to President Brigham Young, died. For the next 21 years, Brigham Young took special interest in the boy Heber J. Grant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p17" pid="Xzpa52cBl0Ww3KZAIJNpDg" hash="zSVWvw">Heber J. Grant wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p18" pid="ZRkei6LtFUenvKCiZI5VRA" hash="JfPUag">“I was almost as familiar in the homes of President Brigham Young as I was in the home of my own mother. In one home … if I was hungry I felt as free to go in and ask for something to eat there as in my own home. … I knelt down time and time again in his home in the Lion House at family prayers, as a child and as a young man.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p19" pid="o1IGjBlIQU-B526-0t4Kdw" hash="u1LP_A">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">He loved the Prophet Joseph Smith. </span>
</span>Of this, he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p20" pid="cdet2iFdIk64-QC3IttCBQ" hash="xGfTSQ">“What I have received from the Lord, I have received by Joseph Smith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p21" pid="I5JekioMmkm8xFlV8iFHQw" hash="OS5D4g">“I love his doctrine. … I feel like shouting Hallelujah, all the time, when I think that I ever knew Joseph Smith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p22" pid="lM62gGUp9ECqvVNAvoy7DA" hash="_oddJQ">How I love Brigham Young. His modern-day successor is President Gordon B. Hinckley, also a beloved and revered prophet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p23" pid="gHNm1dAdc0yEONRlX3WZvQ" hash="xZ74Cw">A beautiful painting shows President Hinckley looking forward to <span class="pageBreak" page-number="31"></span>the future, a set of architectural drawings before him. In the background is a portrait of Brigham Young, making it appear that President Young looks over President Hinckley’s shoulder.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p24" pid="87JsYXEDhka7w2AO890t4Q" hash="3LBNug">The portrait of Brigham Young shown in this painting actually hangs in President Hinckley’s office, and he has often spoken of it. In a recent general conference, he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p25" pid="xkyR9wx1HUKHteS3ZYDoNg" hash="8rzvtA">“At the close of one particularly difficult day, I looked up at a portrait of Brigham Young that hangs on my wall. I asked, ‘Brother Brigham, what should we do?’ I thought I saw him smile a little, and then he seemed to say: ‘In my day, I had problems enough of my own. Don’t ask me what to do. This is your watch. Ask the Lord, whose work this really is.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p26" pid="sQLALgcHYUuOpWJsAYES9Q" hash="BoFUSA">These two great prophets, President Brigham Young and President Gordon B. Hinckley, are linked together in their shared prophetic vision that comes from seeing the future and having the faith to bring that vision into present reality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p27" pid="72ur5j9ArEWZ1wLroFw1KQ" hash="W3uc-A">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">President Hinckley, like Brigham Young, is a pioneer and a builder. </span>
</span>He has traveled the world, meeting kings, queens, and presidents. He has been interviewed by the world’s media. He continues to bring the Church “out of obscurity.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> More than 75 temples have been built in the last 12 years. And he had the inspiration to build the majestic Conference Center.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p28" pid="utO2ho91b0ekpVNNT8avOQ" hash="lo676g">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">President Hinckley, like Brigham Young, spreads the gospel and values education. </span>
</span>Church membership now approaches 13 million in 176 nations, territories, and countries. More than 53,000 missionaries circle the globe. This conference is being translated into 90 languages. He continues to support Church universities and Church education. More than 26,000 members now enjoy the benefits of the Perpetual Education Fund.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p29" pid="rBOqnxC9l0G3NkTqewqfpA" hash="6hdiIQ">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">President Hinckley, like Brigham Young, loves the youth and all members of the Church. </span>
</span>The youth of the Church especially reach out to President Hinckley for prophetic counsel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p30" pid="k6DwleTUbkujWuR1M0i18g" hash="ynsD6A">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">President Hinckley loves the Prophet Joseph Smith. </span>
</span>Several years ago, he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p31" pid="gA_ckq1JpkaT_6UsUYGdzw" hash="-FVyjw">“I worship the God of heaven who is my Eternal Father. I worship the Lord Jesus Christ who is my Savior and my Redeemer. I do not worship the Prophet Joseph Smith, but I reverence and love this great seer through whom the miracle of this gospel has been restored. I am now growing old, and I know that in the natural course of events before many years, I will step across the threshold to stand before my Maker and my Lord and give an accounting of my life. And I hope that I shall have the opportunity of embracing the Prophet Joseph Smith and of thanking him and of speaking of my love for him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day.p32" pid="ZH3JDjanYEmeIMC7P-gbfw" hash="pc-1Qw">I bear my humble witness that both President Brigham Young and President Gordon B. Hinckley are prophets who have led the Church by inspiration and revelation. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/04/prophets-pioneer-and-modern-day</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2007-general-conference/2007-04-2020-elder-earl-c-tingey-64k-eng.mp3" length="4548999" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2007 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
