<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Eduardo Ayala</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Eduardo Ayala.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Eduardo%20Ayala.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Eduardo Ayala.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1990 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Word of Wisdom</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Dear brothers and sisters, throughout my life I have known men and women who keep the commandments of the Lord with diligence and joy and who have, through their examples, edified and blessed the lives of those around them. Some of them now occupy pr</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_90911_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="XtIQMw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Xj12pmuoNU2q8s8MYPQdgA" hash="ecGhOw">The Word of Wisdom</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="e61H3-dbyUOGSOzdLraBrA" hash="vTkNyg">Eduardo Ayala</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-20fc.jpg" alt="Elder Eduardo Ayala" pid="xofsHWbOEU2C8OM-yzBOUQ" hash="pj4ZhQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.p1" pid="71PMsNCRqkCHUrEA6F7wQA" hash="umiAvA">Dear brothers and sisters, throughout my life I have known men and women who keep the commandments of the Lord with diligence and joy and who have, through their examples, edified and blessed the lives of those around them. Some of them now occupy prominent, challenging positions in their personal and professional lives. In the midst of their success, they are not afraid of recognizing that they are where they are because of the blessings of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.p2" pid="MISoXgFev0WWizr6QV9tJg" hash="P7hz2w">Allow me to share the experience of a faithful member of the Church who occupies a prominent position among the world’s microneurosurgeons. This is a position he has obtained, according to his own testimony, with the help of the Lord and through obedience to the Word of Wisdom. He joined the Church at an early age and promised himself to faithfully live the commandments. As the years went by, he had the opportunity of fulfilling two of his great goals—the opportunity to pursue a university education and to marry the woman of his dreams.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.p3" pid="luj_cNgSjkauP6c8w70E2Q" hash="p23Bbw">During this period of time something happened that totally changed the course of his life. One of his daughters became seriously ill with a brain disease which ultimately took her life. None of the efforts made in her behalf were sufficient to save her. During this frustrating and painful experience, which happened while he was a medical student at the university, he set a new and challenging goal, that of becoming a neurosurgeon. The fact that his daughter had suffered and died through a brain disease awakened in him the desire to study microneurosurgery, schooling that would be long and difficult.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.p4" pid="9htlpulEwkW9hJ9CB50Szg" hash="g9O4Dw">Microneurosurgery requires, among other things, a great deal of physical discipline and dexterity. At this point in his life, while he was pursuing his studies, he discovered the blessings that come through obedience to the Word of Wisdom. He asked the Lord in humility and love that the promises contained in section 89 of the Doctrine and Covenants would be made manifest in him so he could bless the lives of those who would depend on his skill. [<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/89.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 89</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.p5" pid="PWdt2Baqk06B4-hUufMTMg" hash="HMxLDw">During those difficult learning years, he worked untiringly to become the best in his area of specialization. As the years went by, he gained great dexterity in his hands and mastered the art and the skill necessary to work on the human brain. As we can imagine, any physical slip or unsteadiness in his hands could cause damage to his patients, perhaps injuring them for life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.p6" pid="7KAN442q-0eXZCy3k9WOCw" hash="6PkUHA">As he studied section 89 of the Doctrine and Covenants, [<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/89.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 89</a>] he obtained a strong testimony that when we refrain from taking into our bodies substances that are harmful to it, we are blessed with intelligence and a healthy and strong body. As a doctor, he knew that these promises were there, within his reach, and he had earnestly sought them in his own behalf.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.p7" pid="WYkc_xPI7ka1sQhSi1HAcw" hash="CMyL4A">As the time arrived for his proficiency exam, the final exam in his chosen career, he prepared himself with great care in order to perform to his very best and to demonstrate to the examining doctors the skills he had acquired. The day prior to the examination, he noticed some heavy trembling in his normally skillful hands, and in humility he prayed to the Lord, asking Him to make his hands firm and sure as they had always been to this point. The following day, he discovered with great alarm that there were unsure movements in his hands. He went off to a solitary spot and, in deep meditation, he mentally searched for any sin he may have committed that would cause him to experience this problem. But in his search, he found nothing that might be contrary to the Word of Wisdom. Then he thought: “I need these promises to come to me now,” and he prayed to our Father in Heaven with all his heart that His guidance and protection would be with him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.p8" pid="5O_X2kgnPUO7DLPbz0essQ" hash="gopD-g">The time came to perform brain surgery on his patient, and when the doctor saw his hands through the microscope, he noted with great emotion that his prayer had been heard and that his hands were steadier than they had ever been.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.p9" pid="kMmsuAk9o0SZH6FMwtmURA" hash="3CbVFQ">He felt a great surge of gratitude, and his sure and skillful hands flew in their activity, healing the damaged brain of his patient. The blessings and the promises of the Word of Wisdom were with him, and he was able to carry out this difficult surgery in an hour less than the normal expectation. It was a complete success, and he humbly accepted congratulations from the examining physicians. With gratitude in his heart for the success he had achieved, he returned to his home, and there, with his family, he reviewed the promises of the Lord that “all saints who remember to keep and do these sayings, walking in obedience to the commandments, shall receive health in their navel and marrow to their bones;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.p10" pid="lfTjgZJuT0aICi2uqYnTFA" hash="lDGWKg">“And shall find wisdom and great treasures of knowledge, even hidden treasures;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.p11" pid="0M__um5JZkqDNARHi3rB6g" hash="xbSVrQ">“And shall run and not be weary, and shall walk and not faint.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/89.18-20" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 89:18–20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.p12" pid="a8KlK317tkWnqx71Cvixbw" hash="EXYcTg">Today as he visits some of the famous clinics and hospitals, and his colleagues have the opportunity of listening to him, he expresses to them and to members of the press: “First, I am a member of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, and then I am a microneurosurgeon.” Not all prominent men achieve the humility to be able to recognize the blessings of the Lord in their lives, which are the result of obedience to the commandments, as this good member of the Church has done.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.p13" pid="M2d_-G0XbEikxbVP8MpiKw" hash="bi57tg">Without question, the Word of Wisdom is one of the commandments which we most need to obey in these days, due to the great quantity of stimulants and drugs that have weakened the lives of those individuals who ignore the marvelous promises that the Lord has made to men if they will avoid using these harmful substances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.p14" pid="gsQDIJlWJEuTjwngTKwn2A" hash="a4xHcA">This commandment is very important today. As an example of the power of the Word of Wisdom, I quote another verse from section 89 of the Doctrine and Covenants. The Lord said, “And again, tobacco is not for the body, neither for the belly, and is not good for man.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/89.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 89:8</a>.) The Prophet Joseph Smith received this revelation in February of 1833, and it has been the cause of many controversies. Perhaps in that early period it was only significant to the faithful members of the Church, but now medical doctors have come to recognize that tobacco, in addition to being addictive, also kills those who use it. Used to any degree, tobacco has been the cause of so much damage among mankind that the need to carry out great campaigns against its use cannot be avoided.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.p15" pid="u5qwWFk7DkygAiy_BlXEDQ" hash="PVSpzA">How I wish that each of us could have a strong testimony of the Word of Wisdom and that we could share with others the results of its sacred promises so that our future generations can be healthy and intelligent, and so our families and nations can be strengthened. In this way, we can become worthy of the final promise of the Lord as contained in this section of the Doctrine and Covenants: “And I, the Lord, give unto them a promise, that the destroying angel shall pass by them, as the children of Israel, and not slay them.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/89.21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 89:21</a>.) When we humbly recognize and fully accept the counsel of the Lord, nothing will be able to hold back man’s intelligence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.p16" pid="Ppszz_NV102vWaQUfN7f9A" hash="1ugh5w">The living prophets constantly teach us about these sacred principles, but men seem to mock them, even as they are being undermined and destroyed by those harmful substances which not only destroy the body and the mind, but also the spirit. Our clinics and hospitals are full of these people, and yet men still resist the word of the Lord and refuse to recognize the wisdom that lies therein.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.p17" pid="PQ4QeWhzl0qC578T7RbMAw" hash="_gyr3g">I pray for those who can still be saved, and for those who have now accepted the counsels of the Lord and have separated themselves from those things that could cause their destruction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom.p18" pid="tP-_1_rG70WlQm1Xmr8H4w" hash="vllhJw">I earnestly desire that we will accept the wisdom of this word of warning, in the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1990/10/the-word-of-wisdom</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1990-general-conference/1990-10-1040-elder-eduardo-ayala-64k-eng.mp3" length="4209359" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1990 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Have Kept the Faith</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Due to the nature of our calling as General Authorities, we are assigned to visit various nations, places, or groups. In some of these, there are risks and dangers. The varying circumstances under which these areas function frequently prevent us from</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95905_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="bsdQnA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="JEZ7OGHa5EiMf5em5lGqRg" hash="c_4SMA">We Have Kept the Faith</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="uoy96BWDJ0a91J3WC_1Iig" hash="vTkNyg">Eduardo Ayala</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-20fc.jpg" alt="Elder Eduardo Ayala" pid="dzT0vvtO0UCpvz3nYhMH3g" hash="pj4ZhQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p1" pid="s6c2EmP7JkaqtThZsOCs4w" hash="m1H0AQ">Due to the nature of our calling as General Authorities, we are assigned to visit various nations, places, or groups. In some of these, there are risks and dangers. The varying circumstances under which these areas function frequently prevent us from reaching the places we have been assigned to visit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p2" pid="LmPx05f96UmRtisxHMm3Xw" hash="gwlCrw">On one occasion, I received the assignment to visit a stake located in the beautiful mountains of the Peruvian highlands. This unit of the Church had not been visited by a General Authority for more than two years because of the dangers involved in traveling there. After obtaining proper authorization, and with the help of the mission president, we commenced the five-hour trip that took us to the beautiful Mantaro River valley.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p3" pid="LzQAELm5hEuYb5GiSd0nZg" hash="hDbx0g">When we arrived at the stake center, the president and his counselors were waiting for us. Upon seeing us, their faces lit up with happiness and we joined in a strong, brotherly embrace. Some three years previously, two of our beloved missionaries had been killed in this city. After embracing the president close to my heart, trying to communicate to him all my love, I asked, “Have you suffered greatly during this time in which we haven’t been able to come?” He answered with his eyes filled with tears, “Yes, we have suffered greatly, but we have kept the faith.” This simple phrase touched our hearts, and we could feel that the hand of the Lord had been with them in the difficult circumstances they had experienced as a people and as members of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p4" pid="QxoU5c4lPUKlsUCThY1FKw" hash="GGkHlw">During our meeting with them, we learned many things, one of which was how to keep the faith in areas such as these, far from large cities and far from the headquarters of the Church. In the things that we learned, we were able to distinguish at least five principles which aided them to overcome their difficulties.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p5" pid="SRMf15SsbE6nU6Yg9WTDAA" hash="R3a2vg">
        <span class="strong">First: They never stopped trusting in the Lord, and they placed all of their faith in him.</span> This was the foundation for their assurance. They trusted in the fact that he would protect and guide them. The Lord has said, “If ye will have faith in me ye shall have power to do whatsoever thing is expedient in me” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.33" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:33</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p6" pid="NaGG1TkUrUOfPIHw3jCzbg" hash="dugf5A">Occasionally, in the midst of our desperation, we seek other ways, other guides. But those who counsel us are not always prepared to help, because they do not understand our spiritual needs. They are not prepared to give us the counsel and the revelation that we need in trying circumstances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p7" pid="qSa2QwERtkiABOmkEThm0Q" hash="T4Gyrw">We have the great example of the sons of Mosiah, who endured so much adversity and so many trials. Because of the trust they had in the Lord, “the Lord did visit them with his Spirit, and said unto them: Be comforted. And they were comforted. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p8" pid="HLRuyaO2e0OE4UKgNQjjHw" hash="XqEQDg">“Yet ye shall be patient in long-suffering and afflictions, that ye may show forth good examples unto them in me, and I will make an instrument of thee in my hands unto the salvation of many souls” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/17.10-11" class="scriptureRef">Alma 17:10–11</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p9" pid="PNLrq3PkgEuBhIYCaub4XQ" hash="ObChwQ">
        <span class="strong">Second: They remained faithful in prayer.</span> Each member, whether adult, child, or adolescent, faithfully followed this holy practice each day, praying individually and as families with all of their faith. As we know, prayer is the means by which we communicate with our Heavenly Father. He listens to us because we are his children and he loves us, and he is anxious to bless us when we keep the commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p10" pid="yG83mlehWUuqe46BqWnByA" hash="ziyx1w">As the Savior instructed the Nephites, he taught them: “Pray in your families unto the Father, always in my name, that your wives and your children may be blessed” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.21" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:21</a>). No one could have given them greater assurance that they would be heard by the Father than his own Son.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p11" pid="FV_3joiNOECbhCawPF1LBQ" hash="FDrIvA">
        <span class="strong">Third: They never stopped studying the scriptures.</span> In the scriptures they found faith to overcome fear, solutions to their problems, divine comfort from the Master, the loving counsel of the Father, and especially the assurance of being guided in righteousness towards eternal life. “Search the scriptures; for in them ye think ye have eternal life: and they are they which testify of me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.39" class="scriptureRef">John 5:39</a>). They lived this commandment even in the midst of all their difficulties. One of the Saints there said, “We have never been as close to the Lord as when we were reading the scriptures.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p12" pid="SxAYlT2vKESEjmbL8-OF6g" hash="VCDwpg">
        <span class="strong">Fourth: They implemented priesthood programs.</span> Due to the fatal incident that had taken place there, it was necessary to remove full-time missionaries. In order to make up for the help that was lost, it became necessary to organize the returned missionaries so that they could teach the gospel to those who wanted to hear it. References came in from member families. Home teaching increased. Nobody was overlooked. Just as they said, they had kept the faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p13" pid="FZLJYNPQUECnI8-kXhEnKw" hash="OBuw-w">
        <span class="strong">Fifth: They humbled themselves before the Lord.</span> They purified their lives, they repented, they tried to live together as Saints, sharing much of what they had, fasting when problems arose or when they were threatened.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p14" pid="Hz-4QSBAh0iLW3qRFNLbZA" hash="NCfw6A">These simple yet powerful principles enabled them to sustain themselves, to be preserved, to remain faithful and active as members of the Church in that area.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p15" pid="FZ274tNxD0WrDezKIb_bHA" hash="31k64A">What wonderful teachings we are able to find in these distant and isolated villages, where frequently it is difficult to sustain a religion or to live the principles of the gospel. We would imagine that it is also difficult to sustain life there and to keep the faith. Only their confidence in God and their faith in Jesus Christ sustain them, move them, and purify them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p16" pid="zlYfBg8pnE-9GKc38UbcwA" hash="P6teUQ">Keeping the faith must also be a challenge for those who are alone in the Church, for those whose families are not converted, for those who have lost a companion, a spouse, or a child. Great courage is needed in order to continue onward, but we always have comfort from on high.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p17" pid="7xMzA3_6YkGMFhYm2YaVUQ" hash="RAzF7w">Our pioneers did not complain; they did not deny the faith or turn back. It is difficult to conceive of the great loneliness of the people of the Church during those first years when they were a small group, the only Church members on all the face of the earth. They were persecuted, humiliated, rejected, and some were killed. The faith which they developed in the Lord, in the face of so much adversity, made them strong and humble at the same time. It must have been very difficult to keep the faith when there was so much opposition, so much loneliness, so much anguish. It was a glorious time, a time of martyrs, a time in which to lay the foundation of a courageous and inspiring religion such as ours.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p18" pid="9OtWQhudU0649BPBSIbDww" hash="GAc5iQ">President Kimball said regarding this theme, “Suffering can make Saints of people as they learn patience, long suffering, and self-mastery. The sufferings of our Savior were part of his education” (“Tragedy or Destiny,” <span class="emphasis">Brigham Young University Speeches of the Year,</span> Provo, Utah: BYU Extension Division, 1955, p. 5).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p19" pid="nZp90NXzPkeNd3tbWwyiiA" hash="3Zqjxw">How grateful we are for those who, with their simple example, allow us to follow without fainting, seeking to return to our Father. Perhaps isolation makes small and distant towns and villages stronger and more pure.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p20" pid="lXPiC1KQnUK2EU-VJypgPw" hash="1ij2Sg">At the close of the conference in that stake, I assured the members that God loved them, that the First Presidency and the Twelve Apostles were mindful of them, and that this was the reason we were there—to give them our testimony of the fact that they were part of the Church, that we had not forgotten them, and that we prayed for them. There was gratitude in their hearts, and again they smiled as humble members who had been comforted by the Spirit of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p21" pid="KeyUMz01uUCFiqCFpkSMkQ" hash="d_sErA">As he gave the closing prayer in one of the conference sessions, a worthy elderly man, nearly eighty years of age, expressed well the ways in which they remember the prophets. In his prayer he said, “Heavenly Father, we give thee thanks for having sent one of thy servants here to the Mantaro Valley, where thy beloved servant, President Kimball, knelt down and blessed this land that it would feed us and always provide us a livelihood.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p22" pid="IVZFoM5IzUywVg7zNbCR5g" hash="ltCN4w">How fortunate and privileged we are to be today in the presence of the prophets of God and to receive their loving influence. Due to the worldwide growth of the Church, a large number of our good members have never had the privilege to be near one of these wonderful leaders at any time during their lives. But I testify to you that they love the General Authorities, that they are following their teachings, and that they await humbly and patiently the day in which they can be at the feet of the prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p23" pid="HZyd_swqSka0HyET8uO_bA" hash="YMYyIQ">The conditions of peoples and of nations change due to progress in the world; nevertheless, in many such places, be it in the frosty mountain heights, in the warm valleys, at the rivers’ edges, or in the desert places, wherever members of our church are found, there will always be those who live these basic principles, and by so doing they bless the rest of the people. Let us face our earthly challenges courageously in spite of where we live, or whatever difficult circumstances we may be called to endure. Let us keep the faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p24" pid="cFqqIEmRAE6H6vmL1KxfkQ" hash="rxsN9Q">We are fortunate this day to be able to sustain a new prophet and his counselors, whom we love and support. In the coming days, in nearly all the nations of the earth, even in the most remote towns and villages, our members will also have the privilege of raising their hands joyfully to sustain them as we have done today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p25" pid="nM0E2i-BOEiegpFUsfLkuA" hash="8osNSg">Someday our journey here on the earth will end, and we will return to the presence of our Heavenly Father. I pray that on that day we may have the same courage and give the same testimony given by the Apostle Paul to Timothy: “I have fought a good fight, I have finished my course, I have kept the faith” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/4.7" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 4:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith.p26" pid="COLuyQyl5EC3m3VFhZ8v5A" hash="zReifw">May the Lord bless us to continue being valiant, humble, and faithful. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/04/we-have-kept-the-faith</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1995-general-conference/1995-04-2060-elder-eduardo-ayala-64k-eng.mp3" length="5560675" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 1995 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
