<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Eduardo Gavarret</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Eduardo Gavarret.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Eduardo%20Gavarret.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Eduardo Gavarret.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Returning Home</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home?lang=eng</link>
      <description>What a tremendous impact we can make in the lives of so many … when we accept the Savior’s invitation to feed His sheep.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00009501_000_032" doc-version="2" hash="e67MmQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="UVW-SlZ8okuWwKYreiIIfA" hash="GbqTRA">Returning Home</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="snNXzYJgm0yqJ2r8uO8Qmg" hash="W3x0Sg">Elder Eduardo Gavarret</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="8OcqKyj0xEyzHNCaCp_i5A" hash="lvYCxQ">What a tremendous impact we can make in the lives of so many … when we accept the Savior’s invitation to feed His sheep.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p1" pid="Owgr5G_YAUiHZeCF3QhGYg" hash="1OEn0w">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="98"></span>It gets very cold during the winter in my hometown of Minas, Uruguay. At sunset my mother used to place logs in the fireplace in order to keep our dining room warm, and one by one, my parents, sisters, and I would gather together, once our daily chores were done. That cozy room—created by the warmth of the fireplace, combined with the presence of each one of the members of the family—instilled feelings within me that I shall treasure forever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p2" pid="s0CqXS1wyU-7Ds7nmpmCfw" hash="wse8Fw">After my wife and I formed our own family, wherever we were living, we all also gathered often, whether around a fireplace or simply around the warmth we always feel whenever we are reunited with our children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p3" pid="08uZwb0S7UuvrrYnH2Wc5w" hash="7Evhuw">What a beautiful feeling! What a lovely place is our house, our home, our refuge.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p4" pid="LyeVixIZUkyxQc4_1xli6g" hash="8go5XQ">Through the years our family has lived in different countries, and in each one of them we were able to find within the Church the same feeling of warmth from members in every ward we attended.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p5" pid="AldAKmduGkOAZSMYEqicHQ" hash="TrLD1A">Each member of the Church should have the opportunity to experience such pleasant feelings, and they can experience these feelings through our efforts of reactivation and missionary work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p6" pid="nh4tJOfb60mj_uFfVeLXYg" hash="VX5ZMQ">Let me share with you something that has been happening in some stakes and districts in Peru, and in so doing, I will mention some family names: the Causo family, the Banda family, the Vargas family, and the list goes on. It includes over 1,700 names of members who have come home. They are members of different wards, branches, stakes, and districts from all over the country of Peru who were invited by stake presidents, bishops, and leaders of quorums and auxiliary organizations to return home. They accepted the invitation made by priesthood leaders, full-time missionaries, and others who took upon themselves the responsibility to help them return to Church and come unto Christ. To each one of them, we say, “Welcome. Welcome home!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p7" pid="R7e7EoLXVUypWEwJW2HFbw" hash="xSGX1w">What made it possible for these persons to return home? It was the combined effort of 14 stakes and <span class="pageBreak" page-number="99"></span>4 districts in a mission laboring for one year to bring about the return of all these persons through reactivation and the ordinances of baptism and confirmation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p8" pid="5NAkEuu8lEyiO6lNkqom-A" hash="YizJjw">This effort was inspired by the Savior’s words: “Lovest thou me? … Feed my sheep” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/21.16" class="scriptureRef">John 21:16</a>) and by the teaching of President Thomas S. Monson, who said: “Over the years we have issued appeals to the less active, the offended, the critical, the transgressor—to come back. ‘Come back and feast at the table of the Lord, and taste again the sweet and satisfying fruits of fellowship with the Saints’ ” (“Looking Back and Moving Forward,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 2008, 89).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p9" pid="aCMh8laHiE2TiFGOiFZwWA" hash="tYI05w">Alma, feeling great suffering for the souls of his brethren, prayed to the Lord, saying:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p10" pid="tgF80iqjKEyhEMeShCbiTQ" hash="-ySHTA">“O Lord, wilt thou grant unto us that we may have success in bringing them again unto thee in Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p11" pid="2Ao7UaTKmkyqfPsnIUndaQ" hash="AyN2Kg">“Behold, O Lord, their souls are precious, and many of them are our brethren; therefore, give unto us, O Lord, power and wisdom that we may bring these, our brethren, again unto thee” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/31.34-35" class="scriptureRef">Alma 31:34–35</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p12" pid="vypsxraB_0ODmO5tqh4X0w" hash="9o3qzA">President Angel Alarcón from the Puente Piedra stake in Lima, Peru, shared the following experience with me: “Each Saturday, the missionaries, the bishop, some leaders from auxiliary organizations, and I visit less-active members, nonmembers, and new converts from 8:30 a.m. till noon.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p13" pid="sxa0YcX5uk2IuFXX9CBcjQ" hash="crAUhQ">At this point of his story, the words of the hymn came to my mind:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="fA8dYfjSzkmohlgy7on_uw" hash="2eaXgw">
            <span class="emphasis">Dear to the heart of the Shepherd,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="nnW53vNl8EWuAaXFs5gTEQ" hash="_VzhSA">
            <span class="emphasis">Dear are the lambs of his fold;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="mX-Wdq7kOESduRQAwyqdog" hash="mlc1Zw">
            <span class="emphasis">Some from the pastures are straying,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="BVkOtGszs0m6X5UIe580oA" hash="0jLLDg">
            <span class="emphasis">Hungry and helpless and cold.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="rYOtpBXL0E6w5dCuXDjV4w" hash="3nHRDQ">
            <span class="emphasis">See, the Good Shepherd is seeking,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="gbFHoyCFEkGUrN_id9aVwA" hash="1lpDoA">
            <span class="emphasis">Seeking the lambs that are lost,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="XYesAqSSoEWbscQzz-Al6Q" hash="a1Hdhw">
            <span class="emphasis">Bringing them in with rejoicing,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Xx_es0vb-0S4x_aBKKLNeQ" hash="RkTMaQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Saved at such infinite cost.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p14" pid="SdXTcw9yK0qybTK7rAtVuA" hash="OpzQWQ">Brother Vargas, whose home was located in an area of limited access, received a call one Saturday morning. It was President Alarcón, calling from his mobile phone, announcing his arrival. Brother Vargas then said: “I am surprised; it is very hard to reach my house.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p15" pid="zNOiLBWcf0yla6X-wmU_4g" hash="QfWIDQ">To which came the reply: “Well, I am at your door right now, and I wish to speak to you. We need you, and we invite you to come to our Church meetings tomorrow.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p16" pid="8AUBbM0BkkSFmHyllqUXyg" hash="w0kTsQ">Then the man, who had stopped attending church for many years, replied, “I will be there.” Thus, he started his journey back home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p17" pid="5NRh_IuOXUaNoAdf6imKDQ" hash="ad-a6Q">“For I was an hungred, and ye gave me meat: I was thirsty, and ye gave me drink: I was a stranger, and ye took me in:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p18" pid="11vhsDQx6k-NhFdzdjp3mQ" hash="VTTALg">“Naked, and ye clothed me: I was sick, and ye visited me: I was in prison, and ye came unto me. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p19" pid="WawSja4wxkmG1j1hwcTuoA" hash="8L-tSQ">“… Inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.35-36,40" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 25:35–36, 40</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p20" pid="kD2GWZy-xk6StDhJ8RtyJA" hash="Qrdjvg">While taking part in Sunday meetings a couple of weeks ago, I had the chance to meet a brother who was attending for the first time after many years of being away. He was accompanied by his wife, who was not a member of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p21" pid="6im6W4G5Y0aNjtROj99lbg" hash="ASvPEw">When I asked him why he had decided to return, he replied, “My friend Fernando and this good bishop invited me to come, and I did. I found the Church many years ago, and I have a small flame still burning within my heart. It may not be strong, but it is there.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p22" pid="HyLB3mFiA06GTouldR5gXQ" hash="SOGWEQ">I concluded, “Well, as your brethren, we shall blow that flame together to keep it alive.” Then we gave each other a hug.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p23" pid="FzQB2XGo-k2mYluvdiY4YA" hash="VAsChA">The interest, attention, and care towards our brethren are profound manifestations of love for our Heavenly Father. In fact, we express our love for God when we serve and when this service is focused on our neighbor’s well-being.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p24" pid="eGVjHy83VEak4qqluEpu9Q" hash="0NqRlw">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="100"></span>King Benjamin taught about it: “And behold, I tell you these things that ye may learn wisdom; that ye may learn that when ye are in the service of your fellow beings ye are only in the service of your God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.17" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2:17</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p25" pid="89VV9YDww02UI7mCS1Ftog" hash="ofdvFQ">What a tremendous impact we can make in the lives of so many less-active families and of those who are not members of the Church when we accept the Savior’s invitation to feed His sheep and help everyone to come unto Christ!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p26" pid="hmRWpaXL40y3ZdAHVXqXpA" hash="qaPxOQ">These experiences are a few of what thousands of brethren are quietly doing: accepting the Lord’s invitation to feed His sheep. Let us remember that love and service are like twins who seek each other’s companionship.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p27" pid="OOzrou7X1kOz1n369B9BrQ" hash="1xL1gw">Oh, that each one of us would accept, as a beautiful demonstration of our love for our Heavenly Father, the responsibility we bear as members of this Church to seek after those who are not here with us! If through this loving service we should bring only one soul to the Church and if we would make it the object of our lives, how much rejoicing would we bring upon us and upon those whom we help return to Christ!</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.f3">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="tn0XH0XDsUaVO8fjkmsa5g" hash="RBsMGQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Hark! he is earnestly calling,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="yZ47wyrzDEuDQfGjOQWcdg" hash="IjhDbA">
            <span class="emphasis">Tenderly pleading today:</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="OWc9H4C08EWuAOoRsxHr3w" hash="g91BxA">
            <span class="emphasis">“Will you not seek for my lost ones,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="kWJECCUV2k-Uh6B8P0CaFw" hash="1eTlbg">
            <span class="emphasis">Off from my shelter astray?”</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p28" pid="Sn3CO5MK9Uq9nuQKN4qkOA" hash="dxD9dQ">I testify that we are sons and daughters of a Heavenly Father, who loves us and who knows each of us by our own name.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home.p29" pid="wZUT4xocRUC-42cF3aeRRQ" hash="-thVAw">I bear my testimony of the love of our Father and Savior. He loved us first and gave His Son so that, through Him, we could be able to come back home. I express my love for Him, my Savior, my Lord, my Master, and my Redeemer, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2008/10/returning-home</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2008-general-conference/2008-10-5040-elder-eduardo-gavarret-64k-eng.mp3" length="5569470" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yes, Lord, I Will Follow Thee</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10991_000_26gavarret" doc-version="8" hash="RA0nqw"&gt;
			
			&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.head1"&gt;
				&lt;h1 class="title" pid="C9exfSa_aUmYXqXt3meEtg" hash="8QDtvQ"&gt;Yes, Lord, I Will Follow Thee&lt;/h1&gt;
				&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p2" pid="HQ-ZK61PE0m7CGdGq3PChQ" hash="KxekSw"&gt;By Elder Eduardo Gavarret&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p3" pid="ryFViO8xCkKH3qF1oB2uXQ" hash="sSmk3g"&gt;Of the Seventy&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=-Lejhl1_q0adTIzUcf6sQw"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255529/587a0e491cb24947888fbcc601122ca5/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255529/587a0e491cb24947888fbcc601122ca5/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255529/587a0e491cb24947888fbcc601122ca5/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x278="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255529/587a0e491cb24947888fbcc601122ca5/200x278.jpg" data-src-320x446="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255529/587a0e491cb24947888fbcc601122ca5/320x446.jpg" data-src-460x641="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255529/587a0e491cb24947888fbcc601122ca5/460x641.jpg" data-src-640x892="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255529/587a0e491cb24947888fbcc601122ca5/640x892.jpg" data-src-1024x1427="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255529/587a0e491cb24947888fbcc601122ca5/1024x1427.jpg" data-src-2048x2855="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255529/587a0e491cb24947888fbcc601122ca5/2048x2855.jpg" data-src-3634x5067="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255529/587a0e491cb24947888fbcc601122ca5/3634x5067.jpg" altText="Elder Eduardo Gavarret" pid="-Lejhl1_q0adTIzUcf6sQw" hash="SCv8MQ"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;p class="kicker" pid="5OdmWOVJ8kGsXVCmrmyjVg" hash="-6qR0A"&gt;The Lord invites us using various verbs: “Come unto me,” “Follow me,” “Walk with me.” In each case it is an invitation to act.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="authorName" pid="zzP9OujfA0mAzi4Y2EFu2A" hash="KxekSw1"&gt;By Elder Eduardo Gavarret&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;div class="bodyBlock" pid="R8NFDjlqrEC49TCKlyu-vg" hash="Ay4hsA"&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p5" pid="IbWV64jCPEGDlrbxudj8eQ" hash="7FaD9w"&gt;“For behold, the Lord doth grant unto all nations, of their own nation and tongue, to teach his word.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; Today this scripture is fulfilled once more as I have been given the opportunity to express my feelings in my native tongue.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;span class="story"&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p6" pid="XJ5CjL-DLUu_RBPFp5PUYg" hash="oDwjMQ"&gt;It was the year 1975, and I was serving in the Uruguay-Paraguay Mission as a young missionary. During my first month in the mission, the zone leaders held an activity to demonstrate a gospel principle. Each missionary in the zone was blindfolded, and we were told that we were to follow a path leading to the cultural hall. We were to follow the voice of one particular leader, a voice we heard before starting to walk. However, we were warned that during the journey, we would hear several voices that would try to confuse us and get us to stray from the path.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p7" pid="YZKd56AcYkSHLHsVY2LqUg" hash="7PRN4g"&gt;After some minutes of hearing noises, talking, and—in the midst of it all—a voice that said, “Follow me,” I felt confident I was following the right voice. When we arrived at the cultural hall of the chapel, we were asked to take off our blindfolds. When I did so, I realized that there were two groups and that I was in the group that had followed the wrong voice. “It sounded so much like the right one,” I said to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p8" pid="QjwWF1Q0jUGDkEzjoijSRA" hash="9ynn9g"&gt;That experience of 39 years ago had a lasting effect on me. I told myself, “Never, ever again follow the wrong voice.” Then I told myself, “Yes, Lord, I will follow Thee.”&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p9" pid="NqA806PISkySTVjOjmUoTg" hash="THF8Fg"&gt;I want to relate this experience with the Savior’s tender invitation to us:&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p10" pid="zFzYgXZtXkWOuV0nFD24Zw" hash="vtrVAQ"&gt;“I am the good shepherd, and know my sheep. …&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p11" pid="hvTLHPA-ZkCE2lpdY7ZelA" hash="X07XaA"&gt;“My sheep hear my voice, and I know them, and they follow me.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p12" pid="yBfo_tvfpk2DT5EqYWgmgQ" hash="kxD_cg"&gt;The invitation to “follow Him” is the most simple, direct, and powerful invitation we can receive. It comes from a clear voice that cannot be confused.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p13" pid="dzInR6mJ3k61LC8ey9sRLw" hash="PlnUGQ"&gt;The Lord invites us using various verbs: “Come unto me,” “Follow me,” “Walk with me.” In each case it is not a passive invitation; it is an invitation to act. It is addressed to all mankind by the one who is the Prophet of prophets, the Teacher of teachers, the Son of God, the Messiah.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.t1" pid="bzCU_DcLnEe1Pqd0bogxKw" hash="wSw3gg"&gt;
					&lt;h2 pid="EgHtJBJaTU-ME6z2epnRQg" hash="XmEr0Q"&gt;The Invitation to “Come unto Me”&lt;/h2&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p15" pid="C2a6BUe4KEGG5shBj7vZZQ" hash="6QF9IA"&gt;“Come unto me, all ye that labour and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p16" pid="cmoh3BKTF0OHo2okgkcWGA" hash="4DtgoA"&gt;You who are not yet members of the Church will receive this invitation through the voice of the missionaries with the words, “Will you read the Book of Mormon? Will you pray? Will you attend church? Will you follow the example of Jesus Christ and be baptized by those who have authority?”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; How will you answer this invitation today?&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p17" pid="APrpWwDrnEyvftGX0FJV6Q" hash="FcCkrA"&gt;I invite you to listen to and accept the message by saying, “Yes, Lord, I will follow Thee!”&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;span class="story"&gt;
						&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p18" pid="SSjnUKDfLU2wYtlu7u66bg" hash="82yLcQ"&gt;Carlos Badiola and his family, of Minas, Uruguay, were meeting with the missionaries. Since the elders asked a lot of questions during the lessons, they decided to invite a nonmember neighbor—a beautiful 14-year-old girl named Norma—to help them answer. Norma was a dedicated high school student who was studying the Bible at school that year, so when the missionaries asked a question, Norma answered. She was a “golden investigator.” The lesson taught that day was about the Word of Wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p19" pid="zXF1DNcPTU62V3TxdshoWg" hash="w-5MNw"&gt;When she returned home after the lesson with the missionaries, Norma knew what she had to do. She said to her mother, “Mom, from now on, no more coffee with milk for me. Just milk.” That response was the visible manifestation of her desire to accept the invitation to follow Christ, as extended by the missionaries.&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p20" pid="u0USJvD7KkeZD2tyOP-ecg" hash="W1ppuQ"&gt;Both Carlos Badiola and Norma were baptized. Later on, following Norma’s example, her mother, father, and siblings were also baptized. Norma and I grew up together in that little but powerful branch. Later on, when I returned from serving a mission, we were married. I always knew that it would be easier to follow the Savior with her by my side.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;/span&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p21" pid="1go4HLIUOEiIFLWghOdHPg" hash="-5N2bA"&gt;One who is a member of the Church and has accepted this invitation renews the commitment each week by partaking of the sacrament.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; Part of that commitment includes keeping the commandments; by doing so you are saying, “Yes, Lord, I will follow Thee!”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.t2" pid="jSbb2RiRzUWhechweLK0xA" hash="i0d0KQ"&gt;
					&lt;h2 pid="awqnCtS860yKO9_JEklbHg" hash="aEkhow"&gt;The Invitation to “Follow Me”&lt;/h2&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p23" pid="M4TvJVPJfkWOofWi7vU12A" hash="G75Dig"&gt;“Follow me” was the Lord’s invitation to the rich young ruler. The rich man had kept the commandments throughout his life. When he asked what more he could do, he received an answer with a clear invitation: “Come, … follow me.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8"&gt;8&lt;/span&gt; However, even though the invitation was simple, it was not without sacrifice. It required effort—coupled with decision and action.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p24" pid="bfDlyaQnWkOLylbCrtdqYw" hash="Q5EHwQ"&gt;The prophet Nephi invited self-reflection when he questioned: “And [Jesus] said unto the children of men: Follow thou me. Wherefore, my beloved brethren, can we follow Jesus save we shall be willing to keep the commandments of the Father?”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9"&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p25" pid="WeIHZq-nXk-oh4l-vB_Xtw" hash="vOF8QA"&gt;The invitation to “come unto me,” to listen to His voice, and to follow it has been the message of missionaries from the beginning, helping many to change their lives for good.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;span class="story"&gt;
						&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p26" pid="kDoRZ-nIzUikdIwMk9eNrw" hash="4XmkGg"&gt;Fifty years ago the missionaries entered my father’s watchmaker shop to leave a watch to be repaired. As good missionaries do, they took advantage of the opportunity to speak with my father and mother about the gospel. My father accepted the missionaries, and my mother accepted the message and invitation to follow Christ. From that day to this, she has remained active in the Church. She said, “Yes, Lord, I will follow Thee!”&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;/span&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p27" pid="T_m7jmQtgkS4clry8gdtxg" hash="zqM09A"&gt;As you strive to come to Him, you will gain the power to relieve life’s burdens, whether physical or spiritual, &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;and experience a positive inner change that will help you be happier.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.t3"&gt;
					&lt;h2 pid="C4s6itWCik-O0Jw6Qqi3Zw" hash="Nt44Jw"&gt;The Invitation to “Walk with Me”&lt;/h2&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p29" pid="pEngmG3WqkW2ctg-chmF-g" hash="TqsJeg"&gt;Enoch was called to preach the gospel to a difficult, hard-hearted people. He did not feel qualified. He had doubts about whether he could do it. The Lord calmed his doubts and strengthened his faith through the invitation “Walk with me”—an invitation that, like a blind man’s cane or a friend’s arm, can guide the footsteps of one whose step is not sure. By taking the Savior’s arm and walking with Him, Enoch found that his step became firm and he became a great missionary and a prophet.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p30" pid="75kMxfqwY0qhEr-JvCq1vA" hash="cU3a8Q"&gt;The decision to “come unto me” and “follow me” is personal. When we accept this invitation, our level of commitment is raised, and it is then that we can “walk with Him.” This level establishes a closer relationship with the Savior—the fruit of our accepting the first invitation.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.t4"&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p31" pid="OU2Cnu5fskuxf0NphXYqNw" hash="_hTesg"&gt;Norma and I individually accepted the invitation to “come unto me” and to “follow me.” Then, together, supporting each other, we have learned to walk with Him.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p32" pid="qDWVwZq4B0icNukoYemSSw" hash="8udK9A"&gt;The effort and the determination to seek Him and to follow Him will be rewarded with the blessings we need.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p33" pid="RiRperned0G5CTwb9oNYLQ" hash="E-bqMw"&gt;Such was the case of the woman who, with great effort, managed to touch the Savior’s garment&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11"&gt;11&lt;/span&gt; or of Bartimaeus the blind man, whose determination was a key factor in the miracle that happened in his life.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12"&gt;12&lt;/span&gt; In both cases a healing of body and spirit was granted.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p34" pid="D0X3ybpBcke3Q85tWKhXnA" hash="n_JZag"&gt;Reach out your hand, touch His garment, accept His invitation, say, “Yes, Lord, I will follow Thee!”—and walk with Him.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p35" pid="V8T-DVrTD0G4c1q0ByVmWw" hash="cu0Asg"&gt;“Come unto me,” “Follow me,” and “Walk with me” are invitations containing inherent power—for those who accept them—to transform your life and generate a &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;change within you&lt;/span&gt; that will lead you to say, “[I] have no more disposition to do evil, but to do good continually.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p36" pid="jos_MCTSlE2ESUi2BnEJQA" hash="1ml2Lg"&gt;As an outward manifestation of that change, you will feel the strong desire to “succor the weak, lift up the hands which hang down, and strengthen the feeble knees.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14"&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p37" pid="xlZ5Z0Goqkm6uval3_zHTQ" hash="OOroIA"&gt;What steps can we take today to “walk with Him”?&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;ol class="number"&gt;
						&lt;li pid="aS3Ah6mIs0ChvCBlULHz3w" hash="FSJhnQ"&gt;
							&lt;span class="label"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt;
							&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p38" pid="SFWOQNqqTUmGOGEv2UMKEg" hash="YOZK5g"&gt;&lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;Feed the desire&lt;/span&gt; to be a better follower of Christ.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15"&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li pid="vZ577v5S7Eqkg7ol5Ifd9A" hash="t8lxCQ"&gt;
							&lt;span class="label"&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt;
							&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p39" pid="qQPocEe5UESbqB7bpfnH-w" hash="Jp3-tg"&gt;&lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;Pray&lt;/span&gt; for this desire that your faith in Him may grow.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16"&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li pid="tb6AbPs640q0PZYG1W2L2Q" hash="wZvr-w"&gt;
							&lt;span class="label"&gt;3.&lt;/span&gt;
							&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p40" pid="FpHXLBVgOEOZ0Tn5P8WgSQ" hash="0c2tqw"&gt;&lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;Obtain knowledge&lt;/span&gt; from the scriptures, lighting the way and strengthening your desire to change.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17"&gt;17&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li pid="0lfKsadNrkK4E8NNV3z6xg" hash="tLaZQQ"&gt;
							&lt;span class="label"&gt;4.&lt;/span&gt;
							&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p41" pid="1XkCLwv0jU6MbgA68cAfEQ" hash="vspFyA"&gt;&lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;Make the decision today&lt;/span&gt; to act and say, “Yes, Lord, I will follow Thee!” Simply knowing the truth will not change your world unless you turn knowledge into &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;action.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18"&gt;18&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li pid="B4NzB6-AbkufLzz2fOqvyA" hash="giETBA"&gt;
							&lt;span class="label"&gt;5.&lt;/span&gt;
							&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p42" pid="8CjZBVM8SEyyhDzMl9FLxQ" hash="OKhL9A"&gt;&lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;Persevere&lt;/span&gt; in the decision you have made by exercising these principles daily.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19"&gt;19&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ol&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p43" pid="ARhFlPz9AUq2DTz_4v7QVg" hash="2M4fWg"&gt;May the words of our beloved prophet, President Thomas S. Monson, motivate us to action in our desire to accept the Savior’s invitation. President Monson said: “Who is the King of glory, this Lord of hosts? He is our Master. He is our Savior. He is the Son of God. He is the Author of our Salvation. He beckons, ‘Follow me.’ He instructs, ‘Go, and do thou likewise.’ He pleads, ‘Keep my commandments.’”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20"&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p44" pid="xQCX8EB7DkGTOOJCeyuEFw" hash="uU8Uzw"&gt;May we make the decision today to increase our level of worship and commitment to God, and may our response to His invitation be heard loud and clear: “Yes, Lord, I will follow Thee!”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21"&gt;21&lt;/span&gt; In the sacred name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee.p45" pid="y9K9AnI-f0qyG1Nt4n1gEA" hash="_FIBnA"&gt;This address was delivered in Spanish.&lt;/p&gt;
				
			&lt;/div&gt;
			
		&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/10/yes-lord-i-will-follow-thee</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2014-general-conference/2014-10-2060-elder-eduardo-gavarret-64k-eng.mp3" length="5279383" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
