<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Elaine Cannon</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Elaine Cannon.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Elaine%20Cannon.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Elaine Cannon.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 1982 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Reach for Joy</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Part of our precious legacy—to be remembered and renewed—is that though deepening trials throng our way, we know that our afflictions can be consecrated to our good.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03148_000_042" doc-version="2" hash="U7_SdQ">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="fnkY-02EJ0-AEQzXDG-9Jw" hash="22itlA">Reach for Joy</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="B_x4Xaghf0Svjf3R6vgXtQ" hash="UkVHKQ">Elaine Cannon</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.t1">
			<img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a68.jpg" alt="Elaine Cannon" pid="9Moss6Qvf0eDLa2-ftJVcA" hash="nUb3pw" />
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p1" pid="-pk4MlfExkGis2XDIjii6A" hash="fPTa4w">Part of our precious legacy—to be remembered and renewed—is that though deepening trials throng our way, we know that our afflictions can be consecrated to our good.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p2" pid="q-rczpWg5UGbEizN7s7mUw" hash="qRaHVQ">Good can come from trouble. Trauma can enliven the heart and enrich the soul. Clouds do have silver linings, and the leaf will burst again on the dry branch. “Weeping may endure for [the] night,” sang the psalmist, “but joy cometh in the morning.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/30.5" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 30:5</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p3" pid="NaCymGnIrUaliUDhzLUQug" hash="JGi44g">My dear sisters, the daily work of the Lord involves changing hopeless to hopeful—for all of us. And it is for us to find at last that in the midst of winter we have within us an invincible summer. In a world filled with adversity we can reach for joy.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p4" pid="scC5d2g3uUOtxviSR54v3w" hash="R4aBAA">My heart responds to you—to you who are young women, so beautiful and so refreshing; to you wise and wonderful ones who have lived a little longer and suffered some; to you with many dreams and to you whose dreams have been dashed; and to some of you who have given way for a time to the temptings that are unleashed upon all of us in these latter days; and to you stricken ill; and to all whose faith has faltered and whose tears have washed the cheeks of your baby or dampened the pillow at night. To all of you, I express my love and my compassion, and I give you my blessed witness that our Heavenly Father and the Lord Jesus Christ live and sustain us and that the Comforter witnesses within us—even now—that our personal joy can be full.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p5" pid="PySvwvzZGUGPX4a5YE6CYg" hash="6261YQ">But first the testing—the bitter so that we can appreciate the sweet. First the trial—and then the witness of our faith. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.6" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:6</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p6" pid="UOYd4M8fSU2HDcF5jdCd7Q" hash="_r4IxA">It is our understanding that in the world before this one we all heard the plan of life presented by the gods. We had our agency—and each of us voted to come down to earth to be proven herewith. To me that means something like: “I will go down and I will take up my life no matter what comes. I will go down and suffer a learning disability or watch the man I love marry someone else; or I will endure a frustrating relationship; or I’ll take up my life as the only Latter-day Saint in my high school or the only Latter-day Saint in my family; or I’ll live my life working hard all my years without apparent success. But I will go down to earth to be proven and to learn.” (See <a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.25" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:25</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p7" pid="_P_UVx4-n0ixmvART87SiQ" hash="pa_qRQ">Trials come in different ways at different stages of life. You’ve no doubt heard about the young girl who complained to her teenage brother about the terrible blows that life had dealt her. And she said, “It just isn’t fair; you got the curly hair and the straight nose.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p8" pid="JuWyOseL50qDi7QmEafULQ" hash="RDNCqA">And he said, “Well, you got the curly nose and the straight hair!” Brothers are so wonderful.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p9" pid="G8GX40kulESsesfni79jQg" hash="P0zhTQ">But whatever life offers, it is to be lived, it is to be learned from. We need to get on with it—and reach for joy.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p10" pid="2ux-at7Q6kC2cxAG7JQNNw" hash="JKJ2Xw">One certainty of life is that each of us will meet some mighty test. This is part of the plan. Another thing that we can count on is that neither here nor hereafter are we suddenly going to emerge with qualities we haven’t developed or a pattern of living for which we have not prepared ourselves. Adversity is an important part of the preparation for at least three reasons. One, God knows whom he can trust and who, like Job, will stand firm and love him unconditionally. Second, adversity well handled can increase our understanding and compassion. And we will be more effective in helping others when we’ve had a few challenges of our own. We just may need to be an answer to somebody else’s prayer.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p11" pid="d7gdYTy3EEuOM1DMp5XqPw" hash="pbUznA">And third, we draw closer to our Heavenly Father when we are in deep need. Our prayers of thanksgiving and joy of course should be part, and are a part, of our worship, but I guess there isn’t anybody here who won’t admit that we pray more fervently when we’re under the press of problems. Attitude in adversity turns hopeless to hopeful.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p12" pid="o_X-xTeUD0iHCoLiZyp8MQ" hash="UPCWyQ">It is a matter of the lemon and the lemonade, after all. In adversity we can complain bitterly, “Why me? Why now?” and wallow in self-pity, thus denouncing God. Or we can find our way by asking that all-important question: “Which of my Heavenly Father’s principles will help me now?” And when we find that appropriate principle, the next step is to live that law, “irrevocably decreed” upon which the particular blessing that we need is predicated. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/130.21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 130:21</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p13" pid="KWV_vV3s4k-MUkrNAKIVwQ" hash="3O4vQw">God’s plan is a plan of ultimate joy for each of us. His principles suffice in any situation. But each one of us, young and old, must rise to her challenges in her own way. Each one of us must reach for her own joy.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p14" pid="gNwpDSWbhUOs6O1yp9x5JQ" hash="2wl_OQ">Let me tell you about some sisters.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p15" pid="hllUlku1vkqpmWklKp76pQ" hash="JoWZAQ">For thirty years and more, Sister Louise Lake, who has now passed away, lived alone trapped in a wheelchair. A parade of problems plagued her constantly. But she made it, beautifully prepared to meet our Heavenly Father. And this is how she did it. Each morning over the years she practiced an “exercise in joy”—a kind of fervent blessing-counting session upon awakening. Imagine! An exercise in joy under those circumstances. She didn’t curse God and die. (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/job/2.9" class="scriptureRef">Job 2:9</a>.) She gave thanks and lived—anyway—touching many of us in remarkable ways because of what she had learned about trouble.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p16" pid="iz2gxpWAH06niCNXFrvj7g" hash="qeTlCA">Sister LaRue Longden, a former counselor in the General Presidency of the Young Women, was a ward Young Women’s president at the time of the serious illness of her little daughter. She and Brother Longden were kneeling in fervent prayer by the side of their bed when word came that the little girl had passed away. They were heartbroken. But after the funeral all the leaders and the young women held flowers and formed an aisle while she, their president, had to walk past them. And during this time of intense emotion she suddenly realized that they were watching her. “I <span class="emphasis">had</span> to live what I’d been teaching,” Sister Longden said. “I <span class="emphasis">had</span> to be an example of what I really believed.” So she lifted her chin and smiled her famous smile upon them.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p17" pid="2t69UYijkEeWBvmXYnP1EQ" hash="YGOsWQ">A fourteen-year-old girl I know has survived a serious bout with cancer. She knows now that she’ll never be able to bear children. She told me that the theme for the Young Women, which is “The Lord is the strength of my life” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/27.1" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 27:1</a>), has helped her meet her test, and she is determined to become the very best teacher of children that Heavenly Father ever had. Find the principle, sisters. Live it! Reach for joy.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p18" pid="MynCpYLEEEGtcuiLb4l4Mw" hash="O5Wwcg">A special friend of mine was left with the burden of being a single parent, not by her choice. One day she was particularly desperate for help. She was very much in need of comfort and direction. And yet she felt so alone: her parents were away on a mission, the bishop was busy, her home teacher was out of town. And finally, tear weary, she turned to the scriptures and read the beloved words “Draw near unto me and I will draw near unto you.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.63" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:63</a>.) Here she found her answer. She prayed and she was helped. It was wonderful. It worked!</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p19" pid="t-abEdtxC0m84tPTTgHaTA" hash="wn4iTQ">Today we women of all ages can draw upon the powers of heaven. We can seek strength through the priesthood, find solace and direction in our patriarchal blessing, be guided by studying the scriptures.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p20" pid="pDYoOljJ4EmtSV8cidXTXg" hash="44jf2g">Life may not always be exactly what we had in mind, but we are not alone. This special promise is recorded in Mosiah: “Lift up your heads and be of good comfort. … And I will … ease the burdens … upon your shoulders, that even you cannot feel them upon your backs, even while you are in bondage; and this will I do that ye may stand as witnesses for me hereafter, and that ye may know of a surety that I, the Lord God, do visit my people in their afflictions.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/24.13,14" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 24:13, 14</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p21" pid="keG5jW7C406gq9r3__DmtQ" hash="kTl2Lg">Isn’t that beautiful?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p22" pid="muhS5U3r-EeVQU40SOPOoQ" hash="yVZFig">I know that our Heavenly Father keeps his promises. I, like you, have been sorely tried in a variety of ways. But this kind of seasoning teaches us that every burden on the back can become a gift in the hand.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p23" pid="hJEO4MuQ0U2v-zc_RZyPXg" hash="jLNdIg">This I firmly believe, and I earnestly pray that in time of trial we may stand firm, sisters, in The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, that we may stand as witnesses of Christ and of peace in the plan of life. And thus reach our joy.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy.p24" pid="YEe45Nkw5UqX63TW0gyEQg" hash="LwXngg">We love you. We pray for you. We find comfort in your example. And I pray this day that we may help each other make it through our times of trial—and while we reach for our joy—in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1982/04/reach-for-joy</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1982-general-womens-meeting/1982-03-7020-elaine-a-cannon-64k-eng.mp3" length="11557204" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 1982 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agency and Accountability</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability?lang=eng</link>
      <description>A good man had been given the assignment in his ward of arranging the Boy Scout banquet. He had worked hard, made his choices, and carried them through. The tables were set, the food was in the pot, and the hour was drawing nigh.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03167_000_038" doc-version="2" hash="qqSleg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="7oWNNwzNxECIU3DscOgSfg" hash="RSZesA">Agency and Accountability</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="nXePYgGzvke04wJAPQPogA" hash="UkVHKQ">Elaine Cannon</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a68.jpg" alt="Elaine Cannon" pid="B0jL_-Fsakq6m1yn7Qmhjg" hash="nUb3pw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p1" pid="kj1cranCl0OKMTpNq78T5g" hash="HERbRQ">A good man had been given the assignment in his ward of arranging the Boy Scout banquet. He had worked hard, made his choices, and carried them through. The tables were set, the food was in the pot, and the hour was drawing nigh.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p2" pid="kwwqMWjexkCOUoB1bD3Wtw" hash="9hGQJQ">His wife came over early to check things out. Everything seemed in order, but it looked mighty colorless to her trained eye. She turned to him and said, “Okay, Honey, but what are you going to use for the centerpieces?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p3" pid="JkyylGTxbEir1GYEIyXJDg" hash="UtbtFg">Surprised, he looked at the stark setting and considered the matter gravely for a moment. Then, in the full agency of his manhood, he replied, “Butter—squares of butter!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p4" pid="jCI5EJFEJUCM6R6W3cjxiw" hash="ZtED-g">Now that is what you might call freedom of choice—agency. And that’s what we’re going to talk about for a few minutes, agency and accountability. I must add that should we happen to choose butter for the centerpiece, we can’t expect compliments on the decor. We have our free agency, but we also have to accept the consequences of our choices. It isn’t so serious in centerpieces, but in matters of life, and of life after death, it is critical.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p5" pid="JMAilChI9U2JkIqsG44XYg" hash="XTItoA">Agency is an eternal principle and is implicit in the test of life. We must constantly choose between opposites: good and evil. Satan sought to destroy the free agency of man, and here on earth he’s still working to entangle man in sin. (See <a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/4.3-4" class="scriptureRef">Moses 4:3–4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p6" pid="vzaXFedLgUKtqSRPkgqOMg" hash="6NBzZw">To use our agency wisely we need information to act upon. We need a knowledge of the laws of life, with their accompanying blessings and protective punishments. When we know the gospel, the elements of the “thou shalts” and the “thou shalt nots,” we’ll make better choices.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p7" pid="f6XNMCvAmE-4jNxzi6A7qQ" hash="f4yU5g">The scriptures remind us, “And ye shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.32" class="scriptureRef">John 8:32</a>.) Our job is to search for the full truth and apply it in our lives. Though we are free to act, we are not free to decide what is right or wrong. That was determined eons ago. We can scoff at sacred things, rationalize our behavior, spout our own ideas, agree or disagree, but it doesn’t change anything. We cannot alter God’s laws, his truth. We can choose to use truth wisely and reach our goal, or we can refuse to learn truth, to live it, and then pay the inevitable penalty.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p8" pid="y1mRl-mqUESiP3yr_-2tLw" hash="JnrPyA">Accountability is the natural product of agency and is the basis of the plan of life. We are responsible for our own actions and accountable to God for what we choose to do with our lives. Life is God’s gift to us, and what we do with it is our gift to him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p9" pid="8_hJsSpImECpNmVsIyO-ow" hash="ybpqUQ">In Galatians we read, “Be not deceived; God is not mocked: for whatsoever a man soweth, that shall he also reap.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/gal/6.7" class="scriptureRef">Gal. 6:7</a>.) Sisters, translated into simple idiom that means that if you pick up one end of a stick, you pick up the other. When you pick a path, you choose the place it leads to.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p10" pid="kJ2G5768Sk2TIr8-A1buDA" hash="eui1lg">I well remember a striking scene that gave me a dramatic perspective of agency and accountability. I was in a village hotel in Taiwan, several floors up, looking out the window at great numbers of the beautiful children of Taiwan on their way to school. From my vantage point I could see the school some distance away. The children knew the school was there, though they couldn’t see it yet, and, of course, they were unaware of my presence. They were charming in the official school uniform—short navy skirt or pant; clean, white starched shirt; and, on this rainy day, a canary-yellow slicker. Now, some of the children carelessly dragged their slickers behind them; a few let them fly open; others wore them tightly buttoned, like the whole armor of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p11" pid="Xk_a4KB86EG4BWTTV--yBg" hash="ihyvlg">The path they were taking through the rice paddy was well trampled, but there were big mud puddles, exciting places to hide between tall rushes, temptations behind a small shop across the way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p12" pid="pi8JJVJctUC1hPSZGFiCSQ" hash="vAtVeQ">The children came around the corner of the hotel—wave after wave of these little people of Heavenly Father’s family—and according to their agency, they dawdled along, were detoured by the slightest distraction, or else pressed toward the mark—the school way up ahead. It was up to them now; parents weren’t around.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p13" pid="AmBtSq-Zl0C3Ham209UYMQ" hash="-MVPnQ">I was fascinated watching the children deal with their environment. Some deliberately plowed right through the deep mud puddles time and again and came forth filthy. Others automatically marched around the puddle, almost oblivious to it. Many absolutely couldn’t resist the temptation to gingerly touch a toe in the mire. One little girl, afterwards, stooped over and tried to wipe the mud from her shoe, then from her hand; then she brushed the spot on her clothes where she had wiped her hand. <span class="emphasis">Mud is tough to erase.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p14" pid="sB_rW-_QJkyNrdxFWrnxaQ" hash="aMYpQw">Interesting, isn’t it? Life from a window. Agency and accountability. They made their choices, and so do we.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p15" pid="X1OYN8l7uEGPwe0rTm6Jtg" hash="yRyoXg">We are like children walking a path in the rain. We can walk in or around the mud of life as we desire, but with our choices come the consequences. And we are rapidly becoming what we are choosing to be for all eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p16" pid="OYVJ-49Na0K7zX1dHvTMDg" hash="3d6swA">Spiritual maturity is understanding that we cannot blame anybody else for our actions. Some factors may make it harder for us to perform according to God’s plan for us, but being accountable for how we use our agency means being answerable for our own behavior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p17" pid="juvn7AKAGk2h9PhLDvUIyA" hash="HcfR7w">It is one of the things that I admire most about mother Eve—her absolute strength in personal accountability. When she was called on the proverbial carpet by God, she explained that Lucifer had tempted her with the fruit. But then she admitted, “And I did eat.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/4.19" class="scriptureRef">Moses 4:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p18" pid="cVFK8HMPgUe2sVkqQbnzbg" hash="Rt5KfQ">By strict obedience Jesus won. He did not succumb to Satan’s temptings. And if we do what the Lord says, we have no need to fear the consequences. “Thy will, not mine, O Lord” can be comforting in times of testing or decision. God loves us. He loves you! His will for you when obeyed means your ultimate joy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p19" pid="BYO0qegr40CWtzl5g5-zKQ" hash="2GiP0w">But I worry, Sisters. I sometimes wonder if we know God’s will for us, if we know what is hurtful or sinful and why, if we have the faintest notion, on the other hand, of the glories he has in store for our reward, here as well as hereafter, if we are obedient. I wonder if mothers have <span class="emphasis">really</span> taught daughters about truth, agency, and accountability. Are daughters sharing with mothers their own learnings? Individuals and families are strengthened as we help each other grow in the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p20" pid="arbUx1tVCkCLGOMr1VpIzQ" hash="PdgEeQ">The 1984 scriptural theme approved by the General Authorities for young women to recite in class each week is “I will go and do the things which the Lord hath commanded, for I know that the Lord giveth no commandments unto the children of men, <span class="emphasis">save he shall prepare a way</span> for them that they may accomplish the thing which he commandeth them.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 3:7</a>; italics added.) We <span class="emphasis">can</span> do what we’re supposed to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p21" pid="mm9rL55b5UOg6KC_sYT8Kg" hash="JC70rA">We are not alone. We can feel the sustaining power of the Savior. He will help us as we strive to make right choices all along the path.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p22" pid="3O2XeUF4k0SS7xfV4QFCpA" hash="rFE0xg">Now, Sisters, let’s love him enough to be obedient. This is the season for strength. This is a time for us to choose to stand as a people who have made covenants through baptism and in the temple to be valiant and to be lifters of those not as blessed as we are.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p23" pid="Y9nkrrQt6UOhr7-I11rc0Q" hash="8j926Q">Recently I was doing some prayerful thinking about this heavy responsibility I have right now—young women need so much guidance, protection, and love. On this occasion I felt inadequate, and as I measured my weaknesses, against all the wickedly clever ones in the world, I admit that I sagged for a time. But after praying earnestly, I looked deep inside to the core of me, where the Spirit can touch us, and I knew then that I wouldn’t give up. Whatever I am, whatever I need to overcome, I will be one upon whom the Lord can count. We can all use our agency this way—to be one upon whom the Lord can count.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability.p24" pid="tQBGr2UqQUO-liSCyNQsZw" hash="bEhRWQ">Let’s do it! In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1983/10/agency-and-accountability</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1983-general-womens-meeting/1983-09-0030-elaine-a-cannon-64k-eng.mp3" length="4775416" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 1983 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
