<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Elaine S. Dalton</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Elaine S. Dalton.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Elaine%20S.%20Dalton.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Elaine S. Dalton.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2003 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Press Forward and Be Steadfast</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast?lang=eng</link>
      <description>You can press forward with vision. The Holy Ghost will help you remain steadfast, and your testimony of the Savior will help you proceed with a perfect brightness of hope.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030371_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="IiSiDQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="_GWfide9uUOXKfQKp8MSwQ" hash="N5mmTg">Press Forward and Be Steadfast</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="yhjhpvcKi0W3k_4cf_U2WA" hash="0nm0pw">Elaine S. Dalton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="MAHwCVUaKUe1x2XmoI0l7A" hash="RY22Bw">You can press forward with vision. The Holy Ghost will help you remain steadfast, and your testimony of the Savior will help you proceed with a perfect brightness of hope.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-aa5.jpg" alt="Elaine S. Dalton" pid="tEQu9fnrmkO781zT8ddE3A" hash="bsxRdw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.p1" pid="mLEplCg1AUeKpr1kmhpd6Q" hash="-Rb3Ww">On a pier in Copenhagen, Denmark, is a bronze statue of a young woman named Kristina. Kristina stands looking out to sea toward her goal to join the Saints in Zion. The wind is blowing against her fiercely, but she does not look back. She is steadfast as she presses forward doing a very hard thing, but one she knows to be right. I love that statue, for to me Kristina represents my own Danish great-great-grandmother who chose to join the Church amid great resistance. I am grateful for her courage and testimony. On her choice that day rested not only my eternal destiny but also the destiny of generations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.p2" pid="r1JspRVYtEWt5hRaGbcOHg" hash="mtmfhw">In the Book of Mormon, Nephi tells us that we can “press forward” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.20" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:20</a>). He says we not only can but <span class="emphasis">must.</span> Perhaps Nephi, like Kristina, could see that the steadfast choices of one individual affect generations. When Nephi’s father sent him back to Jerusalem to obtain the plates of Laban, Nephi said, “Behold, it is wisdom in God that we should obtain these records, that we may preserve unto <span class="emphasis">our children</span> the language of our fathers” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.19" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 3:19</a>; emphasis added). Nephi was thinking of his future family, even though he had no prospect for marriage. Remember, his family was <span class="emphasis">alone</span> in the wilderness! Nephi not only had a vision of how to return to his heavenly home, but he also had a vision of what he wanted in his earthly home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.p3" pid="uO0NdNo02UWSNQbcojDjag" hash="ufcKyw">The Savior will help you see and understand the vision He has for you. You are His beloved daughters. He knows you personally and has a plan for your life. He has promised that as you live worthily, His Spirit will always be with you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.p4" pid="95Jcl2kEAEenFRExRJ7ajA" hash="nLYTiA">Just as the wind blew fiercely in the opposite direction Kristina faced on that pier in Denmark, each of you will experience resistance from worldly forces. “Pressing forward” implies resistance. The scripture doesn’t say walk forward, or move forward, or simply proceed forward. It says to <span class="emphasis">press</span> forward! In order to do this, you must have a vision of where you are going. The Holy Ghost will help you remain steadfast, and your testimony of the Savior will help you proceed with a perfect brightness of hope.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.p5" pid="Nv6J60WZ3EKb1QD-zh-OhA" hash="U1tNYg">Several years ago, my husband and I qualified to run the Boston Marathon. The night before the marathon, in an effort to visualize what it would be like to complete the race, we went to downtown Boston about a mile from the finish line. There in the quiet of the evening we laced up our running shoes and ran that last mile to the finish. As we crossed the line we held our hands victoriously high in the air and pretended that we had won the race! We imagined thousands of observers in the stands cheering for us. The next day we ran the race. Twenty-six point two miles (41.3 km) is a challenging distance. There are hills that are called “Heartbreak” for a very good reason. The entire time I was running those hills, I kept in mind that finish line and what it had felt like the night before to cross the line victorious. That vision of the finish line helped me to finish that marathon in a pelting, cold New England storm.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.p6" pid="-JH2Fva3bUSZwhImERlfag" hash="baaobQ">Your vision of your future will help you press forward. Take a few minutes to envision where you want to be in one year or two or five. Then take action to prepare yourselves. People don’t just run a marathon when they decide to do it. They must train daily, slowly building stamina and endurance to run the 26.2-mile distance. So it is with life. It is daily diligence with prayer and scripture study that will help you reach your goals. Your daily decisions will influence generations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.p7" pid="pjZhWCRDiUaNVC4AP4gzCQ" hash="ACWldQ">Seminary helped Melissa envision the kind of young woman she wanted to become. She was not a member of our Church, but she enrolled in seminary with her friends. When she turned 18, she was taught by the missionaries. She knew the things they taught her were true! The spirit was so sweet at her baptism. It felt as if not only all her friends and family were present but also her future family. The bishop remarked that he could almost hear her future family saying, “Thanks, Mom!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.p8" pid="v4L5pAXMMUSGu7crumkQnA" hash="IdwyUA">Like Melissa, you have made baptismal covenants. Keeping your covenants will enable you to be guided by the Holy Ghost. The Holy Ghost will protect and strengthen you and tell you “all things [that] you should do” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/32.5" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 32:5</a>). This gift sets you apart from the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.p9" pid="H7cECM1eCEyObr-zb3hJYw" hash="7r4eRQ">We know you receive a lot of resistance to your standards. Young women in Tennessee and Arkansas told me they face resistance at school because of their beliefs. The young women I met in Haiti also face daily pressure to participate in things that are not appropriate for a young woman of covenant. Yet their eyes shine brightly with the hope of the gospel. They remain steadfast because they listen to the “still small voice” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-kgs/19.12" class="scriptureRef">1 Kgs. 19:12</a>) of the Holy Ghost and obey its promptings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.p10" pid="LrozIoAdBkeax5I7A893lw" hash="LJZwpA">The Holy Ghost will also guide you as you make decisions regarding your future. Another young woman I know was dating a tall, handsome young man—the star of the school basketball team and senior class president. While discussing their future plans, she explained that she had made a decision a long time ago to marry a returned missionary in the temple. A mission was not part of his plans, and nothing more was said. The following Christmas, he gave her a small gift. As she opened it, she realized that it was a letter from a prophet of God calling her friend to serve a mission. Her righteous influence helped him make that important decision.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.p11" pid="8L5FM_Uy0Uicn26ymI9F0w" hash="NhFPlQ">You too can influence the young men with whom you associate to “rise a little higher [and] be a little better” (Gordon B. Hinckley, “The Quest for Excellence,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Sept. 1999, 5; <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> Sept. 1999, 8). You can help young men prepare for and serve honorable missions. You can help them remain morally clean so they can bear their priesthood with honor. Your righteous influence in the life of a young man can have an eternal effect in not only his life but the lives of generations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.p12" pid="hBTgzH_WzkudBYGCU4TWkw" hash="33o9Aw">When our daughter Emi was 15, she made a decision. One morning I noticed her Book of Mormon opened to Alma, chapter 48. She had marked the verses that describe Captain Moroni: “Moroni was a strong and a mighty man; he was a man of a perfect understanding. … Yea, and he was a man who was firm in the faith of Christ” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/48.11,13" class="scriptureRef">Alma 48:11, 13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.p13" pid="ws4wHSZdCkWSScE6THrnhg" hash="EznS9Q">In the margin she had written, “I want to marry a man like Moroni.” Seven years later, she did! Emi gained her vision for her future husband as she read the scriptures and listened to the promptings of the Holy Ghost. She also came to know and understand the Savior and His “great plan of happiness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/42.8" class="scriptureRef">Alma 42:8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.p14" pid="6qsrRRpZHk26yD1aOzMyKQ" hash="EsiEDw">As you read the scriptures, you will come to know that the Savior is not only the light and life of the world; He is our one bright hope. Through Him you can have the hope of returning to live with your Father in Heaven. Through Him you can repent and overcome the things that will keep you from being steadfast. Through Him you can find the strength and courage to press forward even when the winds of resistance blow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.p15" pid="32EGULj1_k-rE5owcLxFPA" hash="qe8j-A">Now you may not have to stand on a pier and make difficult choices like Kristina. And you may never find yourself pressing forward on the hills of a marathon. But you will find yourself faced with choices that will have eternal implications. You can press forward with vision. The Holy Ghost will help you remain steadfast, and your testimony of the Savior will help you proceed with a perfect brightness of hope.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.p16" pid="y59nnKAZ2EWgHbIgVtix7g" hash="b18r-Q">There may be some steep hills ahead, but our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ, has promised to climb with you every step of the way. There has never been a more important time to press forward and be steadfast.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast.p17" pid="nrZyMdoq6USiXTU9oQu70g" hash="Pre_Hg">And so I say with Nephi: “Wherefore, ye <span class="emphasis">must</span> press forward with a steadfastness in Christ, having a perfect brightness of hope. … Wherefore, if ye shall press forward, … and endure to the end, … thus saith the Father: Ye shall have eternal life” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.20" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:20</a>; emphasis added). In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2003/04/press-forward-and-be-steadfast</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2003-general-young-women-meeting/2003-03-0030-elaine-s-dalton-64k-eng.mp3" length="4891782" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2003 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Believe!</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2004/04/believe?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Believe in yourselves. Believe that you are never alone. Believe that you will always be guided.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10031248_000_040" doc-version="2" hash="XCDtCA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="OAY13kCF0kyWbyObxX5_6Q" hash="GNqN2A">Believe!</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="CC9Kw0AhUkK5GzyFSnTeSQ" hash="0nm0pw">Elaine S. Dalton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="6OOaliRikUmspHWjyiXBBA" hash="oZvUjw">Believe in yourselves. Believe that you are never alone. Believe that you will always be guided.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-f3.jpg" alt="Elaine S. Dalton" pid="hV53pmp71EOvlBI4J_Uo2g" hash="ua38KQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p1" pid="hHat-TQjy0a8jlu7WLS_Fg" hash="6bO0Hw">Several months ago, I was invited to speak to the young women in the stake in which I had grown up. I was excited and anxious for this opportunity. My mother went with me, and we arrived a little early. The meeting was held in the building where I had attended church until I went away to college. I had not been back for a long time, and I did not anticipate what would happen when I walked inside the front doors. A flood of memories came washing over me, and I began to cry. My mother looked at me and said, “Elaine, don’t start that now.” But the tears flowed as I viewed the office at the top of the beautiful marble stairs where my father had served as the bishop. As I reached the top of the stairs, the door to the bishop’s office was open. I went inside and saw that it had been converted to a small classroom, and again a flood of memories came washing over me. In my mind’s eye, I could see my father sitting behind the desk and myself as a little girl sitting on the chair in front of it paying tithing and as a young woman having interviews and receiving priesthood blessings. My love for that building was deeply tied to the spiritual experiences and feelings I had had there.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p2" pid="1QVKQJZPR0KAHZ8q6J74tA" hash="516RaQ">Often as a young girl I would accompany my bishop father to the church and wait until his meetings or interviews were over. I would busy myself by exploring. I knew every nook and cranny of that building. One of my favorite rooms was the tower room. It was a large room at the top of some steep steps. Inside there was a picture of the Savior, which hung over a large fireplace. I was always drawn to that room. I would ascend the steps and reverently go inside. I would sit on a chair and look at the picture of the Savior and pray to Heavenly Father. These were simple prayers. But always when I prayed, a very special feeling seemed to engulf me, and I knew that He heard my childlike prayers. This is where I began to believe.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p3" pid="-TeUZ22zYkK-7znAtDZjdA" hash="utDXMQ">The Lord has promised us that as we “search diligently, pray always, and <span class="emphasis">be believing,</span> … all things [will] work together for [our] good” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/90.24" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 90:24</a>; emphasis added). That doesn’t mean that everything will be perfect or that we will not have any trials, but it does mean that everything will be okay if we just “hang in there.” Ours is the opportunity to “be … an example of the believers” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-tim/4.12" class="scriptureRef">1 Tim. 4:12</a>), and the Savior has promised that “all things are possible to him that believeth” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/9.23" class="scriptureRef">Mark 9:23</a>). So believe in yourselves. Believe that you are never alone. Believe that you will always be guided.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="_KI1SjSKkEy4j6DAUUuX6g" hash="I95z-g">Believe in Yourselves</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p4" pid="VKXwV09uiESKS2MZCJrk6A" hash="lb2jUw">Elder David B. Haight of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles said of you: “We believe in you, your parents and brothers and sisters believe in you, and God expects the best from you. You must believe in yourself. Don’t give in when the going is rough, for you are laying the foundation of a great work, and that great work is your life” (“A Time for Preparation,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign, </span>Nov. 1991, 38).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p5" pid="Xpt4IzFANkO72DFN16cEMQ" hash="bZw9hA">President Gordon B. Hinckley has told us: “I believe in myself. I do not mean this in an egotistic way. But I believe in my capacity and in your capacity to do good, to make some contribution to the society of which we are a part, to grow and develop, and to do things that we may now think impossible. … I believe in the principle that I can make a difference in this world. It may be ever so small. But it will count for the greater good” (“I Believe,” <span class="emphasis">Tambuli,</span> Mar. 1993, 8; <span class="emphasis">New Era, </span>Sept. 1996, 8).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p6" pid="tBEakNBJqkiR7x8GAT52rA" hash="Wjhu5g">You are one of the greatest generations of young women ever to live on this earth. Before you came to this earth you were tutored at your Father’s knee. You have been reserved to come to the earth for a special purpose. There are things for each of you to do that no one else can do as well. You have a destiny to fulfill.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p7" pid="uTpmSwG6u0yG81hf5QevlQ" hash="9cbqvA">Your righteous example as one of the believers will make a difference in the world, so “be not weary in well-doing, for ye are laying the foundation of a great work” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.33" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:33</a>).</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="qHml56ZcWEOzIqOQlWBrPQ" hash="KD3oCA">Believe That You Are Never Alone</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p8" pid="FkrRGO48G0WQhwBQSZ0tCA" hash="7Kevuw">As you strive to be an example of the believers, you may feel that you are standing alone. You may feel that you are the only one who is trying so hard to be righteous and pure. You may feel you are the only one striving to be modest in your actions, speech, and appearance. <span class="emphasis">But you are not alone.</span> There are thousands of young women like you all over the world who are striving to be an example of the believers.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p9" pid="8ma0NAK7GUCu6xQ-Cw7Ibw" hash="u1qatQ">Carmelita and Rosario, two young women in Jalapa, Mexico, are among those believers. They are the only members of the Church in their family, and they are living alone. When I visited their small home, they said they knew Heavenly Father loved them very much because He sent the missionaries to teach them the gospel. Although things are hard, each day they rely on their Heavenly Father’s loving care and guidance.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p10" pid="s_p9-sTAkU-soehC4hRpDg" hash="Z3Rdew">To Carmelita and Rosario and to each of you, I testify that you are not alone. The Lord has promised: “I will go before your face. I will be on your right hand and on your left, and my Spirit shall be in your hearts, and mine angels round about you, to bear you up” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.88" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:88</a>).</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="ROmncrAaYE-pbYnjWBwKAw" hash="xisXxg">Believe That You Will Be Guided</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p11" pid="vUgG-aDcmUiYUFa4K8aByQ" hash="BMrgvg">As you search the scriptures diligently and pray always, you will be guided by the Lord. A young woman living in Mongolia listened to the words of the prophets as the missionaries read passages to her from the Book of Mormon. The Book of Mormon had not yet been translated into her language, but as the missionaries translated the words for her, she <span class="emphasis">believed </span>and was baptized. She became an example of the believers in Mongolia.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p12" pid="S5bd7roEIkm7RrsHWnD4_w" hash="rSpJ_A">Later she was called on a mission to Salt Lake City. What joy she felt! She learned English, and she purchased her very own scriptures. When she visited our home, she read reverently from her new scriptures. She loved them. I noticed that almost everything on every page was underlined in yellow. I said, “Sister Sarantsetseg, your scriptures look like the golden plates.” She replied, “I only underline the things I like.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p13" pid="UvfyAXipM0GjcL5Ad7tgLQ" hash="6CPOYg">Everything in the scriptures is applicable to our lives. The scriptures answer our questions, they provide role models and heroes, and they help us understand how to handle challenges and trials. Many times the scriptures you read will be the answer to your prayers.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p14" pid="H5xbfv8ggEaSEXhjrfc-AA" hash="kfuUxg">When I was about your age, my father became seriously ill. We thought it was just the flu, but as the days progressed, he became more and more ill. It was during that time that I really learned what it means to “pray always” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/32.9" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 32:9</a>). I had a constant prayer in my heart, and I would seek solitary places where I would pour out my soul in prayer to my Heavenly Father to heal my father. After a few weeks of illness, my father passed away. I was shocked and frightened. What would our family do without our father whom we loved so dearly? How could we go on? I felt that Heavenly Father had not heard nor answered my fervent prayers. My faith was challenged. I went to Heavenly Father and asked the question—“Heavenly Father, are you really there?”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p15" pid="aIamVVH1RUqV6sK7Sxnnhw" hash="s6z7oQ">Over a period of many months, I prayed for help and guidance. I prayed for my family, and I prayed to understand why my father had not been healed. For a time, it seemed to me that the heavens were silent, but as a family we continued to pray for comfort and guidance. I continued to pray also. Then one day, many months later, as I was sitting in a sacrament meeting, my answer came in the form of a scripture. The speaker said: “Trust in the Lord with all thine heart; and lean not unto thine own understanding. In all thy ways acknowledge him, and he shall direct thy paths” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/3.5-6" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 3:5–6</a>). A feeling came over me, and I felt I was the only person in the chapel. That was my answer. Heavenly Father had heard my prayers!</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p16" pid="aHOGgEhOmkyQBKsZ0islIw" hash="oYsN0A">That experience happened many years ago, but I still remember it vividly, and I testify that He has directed my paths. I know that when we believe and trust in Him, “all things [will] work together for [our] good.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p17" pid="NF_crK8dfkis6Rz0jPhg4w" hash="UZzHoA">Now the call to each of you is the same as the call the Apostle Paul made to his young friend Timothy: “Be thou an example of the believers” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-tim/4.12" class="scriptureRef">1 Tim. 4:12</a>). Will you do that? Will you show the world and the Lord that you believe by the way you dress, by the way you speak, by the way you respect your body, by the very purity of your lives? The world needs young women who are believers.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p18" pid="fQFTMJTdpkWpf8p4GPxJdg" hash="dP77Tw">Believe in the Savior. He loves you, and I testify that He will not leave you alone. He has promised:</p>
        <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.f2">
          <div class="stanza">
            <p class="line" pid="j0nVQym3REKC_a8kbqrlGw" hash="JiafUw">
              <span class="emphasis">Fear not, I am with thee; oh, be not dismayed,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="Gl9EArHXIESdOxGGXPZOpg" hash="Ba8YjA">
              <span class="emphasis">For I am thy God and will still give thee aid.</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="iCXUBMOW80SheqUVGII5kg" hash="XdA1Jw">
              <span class="emphasis">I’ll strengthen thee, help thee, and cause thee to stand, …</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="QiGnXLHoYk-NsDJ1ZFgexg" hash="bamq-A">
              <span class="emphasis">Upheld by my righteous, omnipotent hand.</span>
            </p>
          </div>
        </div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/believe.p19" pid="qxG7wYpMAEqZIVoxDFNpXg" hash="-jU6jg">I believe that each one of you has the power to change the world. Believe in yourselves. Believe that you are never alone. Believe that you will be guided. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2004/04/believe</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2004-general-young-women-meeting/2004-03-0030-elaine-s-dalton-64k-eng.mp3" length="10627583" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2004 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Did This for You</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Temple work is the work that we have been prepared to do. It is a work for every generation, including and especially the youth.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030208_000_030" doc-version="2" hash="oprHGw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="6Nk85JKsIUSzMayUR-zF7g" hash="a0N29A">We Did This for You</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="uGTDyDvP3UCqU5pNgiqXpw" hash="0nm0pw">Elaine S. Dalton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="uMMa8os9E0up-cByc94mWQ" hash="g7_d6Q">Temple work is the work that we have been prepared to do. It is a work for every generation, including and especially the youth.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-f3.jpg" alt="Elaine S. Dalton" pid="X5xJVZ1tFkmkJUUbQ1heeQ" hash="ua38KQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p1" pid="3SrFWt5iTkeyziAPHuMs8g" hash="zuc_BA">A little over a year ago, my husband and I visited Nauvoo. As we walked through the Old Pioneer Cemetery searching for the grave of an ancestor, Zina Baker Huntington, I was touched by the peaceful solitude and spirit I felt. I walked through the trees and read the names on the gravestones, many of them children and families. I wept as my heart was turned to our forefathers, many of whom had joined the Church and come to Nauvoo. In my mind I asked many questions: Why did they leave their comfortable homes and families? Why did they suffer persecution, sickness, even death? Why did they sacrifice all that they had to come to this place and build a temple? They hardly had shelter, and yet they were building a temple! Why did they do it? And when the temple was nearly completed, how could they leave it behind? As I sat silently contemplating this scene, the answer came forcefully yet softly to my mind and heart: “We did this for you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p2" pid="Va1oEqfwA0qN3i8xfjsdHA" hash="jZ0cew">Those words, “We did this for you,” reminded me that our ancestors, along with many other faithful Saints, sacrificed everything because of their testimonies and faith in Jesus Christ. They knew that the gospel had been restored to the earth once more and that they were led by a prophet of God. They knew that the Book of Mormon was true and understood its message and witness. They knew that through the restoration of priesthood keys, families could be sealed together for eternity through holy priesthood ordinances available only in a temple. They knew that temple work was the key to the salvation and exaltation of the human family. They knew the importance of this work, and they were willing to give all that they had in order to provide a house acceptable to the Lord wherein this holy work could be performed. They sacrificed everything so that past and future generations would have access to the eternal blessings of the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p3" pid="YImZcq1bi0WLQFfANJpyrg" hash="k9jVPA">Prior to coming to Nauvoo, the Saints sacrificed greatly to build the first temple of this dispensation in Kirtland, Ohio. It was there that the Lord Himself appeared to Joseph Smith and Oliver Cowdery. Three other heavenly messengers also appeared there. One of these was Elijah the prophet, who restored, through the Prophet Joseph Smith, keys pertaining to the restoration of the priesthood and the “great work to be done in the temples of the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> This happened in accordance with the promise that is recorded in the Doctrine and Covenants wherein the Lord said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p4" pid="fqNtFsa9e0yyLagybgvM_w" hash="cGnUyQ">“Behold, I will reveal unto you the Priesthood, by the hand of Elijah the prophet. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p5" pid="IWFbOIT_rEWLGQaDp3HAAA" hash="OUxrkQ">“And he shall plant in the hearts of the children the promises made to the fathers, and the hearts of the children shall turn to their fathers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p6" pid="urpkQBDjcEuvnPYGZpN8DQ" hash="KjEj9Q">“If it were not so, the whole earth would be utterly wasted at his coming.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p7" pid="k904n8h4RkKST1mHcnVq1w" hash="xUhXcw">The early Saints understood what this scripture meant, and on that beautiful morning in the old cemetery in Nauvoo, I understood also.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p8" pid="Q4Heo7ruhE2SWZIlWAjIcA" hash="KL0dqQ">How can the promises made to the fathers be planted in the hearts of the children? How can the hearts of the children be turned to their fathers? This can happen only when we understand our identity and roles in this work and remain worthy and prepared to enter the temple and act on behalf of those who have gone before.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p9" pid="-wrejRWoLkaJRvW17PSeDg" hash="WD2NCA">Brigham Young said: “We have a work to do just as important in its sphere as the Savior’s work was in its sphere. … We are now called upon to do ours; which is to be the greatest work man ever performed on the earth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p10" pid="MvYcqlpxj0K8q75eon0r1g" hash="ykfYNg">In the vision of the redemption of the dead given to President Joseph F. Smith, he saw many of the noble and great prophets who had been on the earth prior to the Savior’s coming. He also saw the Prophet Joseph Smith, Hyrum Smith, his father, and “<span class="emphasis">other choice spirits</span> who were reserved to come forth in the fulness of times to take part in laying the foundations of the great latter-day work.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Who were those other choice spirits? Our generation was somewhere there among those “noble and great” leaders, prepared in the world of spirits to be on the earth at this time! The scriptures tell us that “even before they were born, they, <span class="emphasis">with many others,</span> received their first lessons in the world of spirits and were prepared to come forth in the due time of the Lord to labor in his vineyard for the salvation of the souls of men.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> The labor we were prepared and reserved to perform includes “the building of the temples and the performance of ordinances therein for the redemption of the dead.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p11" pid="zZ_O574zRUqCDPKbq3MeRw" hash="ftHqdw">Brigham Young foresaw the time in which we are now living. He said, “To accomplish this work there will have to be not only one temple but thousands of them, and thousands and tens of thousands of men and women will go into those temples and officiate for people who have lived as far back as the Lord shall reveal.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p12" pid="jyCFGjpiyEKpZqUg9JxNSg" hash="D3LuZQ">When I was young, my grandfather Martin taught me that in the latter days, temples would literally dot the earth. At the time my grandfather expressed this thought to me, I could hardly imagine it. But I was raised with this knowledge and feeling in my heart. Recently I looked on the Church’s Web site under “temples,” and I could plainly see that the temples, designated by red dots, are starting to spread over much of the earth.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p13" pid="hBrKmQhX8E-6iJ6jh_bXjQ" hash="w5zRLQ">Our beloved prophet, President Gordon B. Hinckley, has said, “We are determined … to take the temples to the people and afford them every opportunity for the very precious blessings that come of temple worship.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Our prophet knows that it is difficult to do temple work if we are not near a temple. This is our day, and temple work is the work that we have been prepared to do. It is a work for every generation, including and especially the youth of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p14" pid="rjDCBgvpT0STbcMlsPduLQ" hash="lT6vpA">In order to perform this great work, we must be worthy. No wonder we are surrounded on every side with things designed to discourage, distract, or disqualify us. We must keep our focus, and we must remember that the temple is the reason for everything we do in the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p15" pid="F-oI4lghYUSDWXrW811UBQ" hash="1jStJQ">Youth programs such as Personal Progress and Duty to God encourage youth to be worthy to attend the temple. These programs are designed to help youth make and keep commitments, thus preparing them to make and keep covenants. They also encourage youth to participate in journal writing, family history, and performing baptisms for their ancestors. The <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth</span> pamphlet teaches doctrine and principles that, if understood and lived, will help youth be worthy to attend the temple. These programs are powerful tools to be used by youth, parents, and leaders. They help youth prepare to be worthy to attend the temple. And our youth do not have to wait until a mission or marriage to visit the temple. They can have temple experiences beginning at age 12 by doing baptisms and confirmations, and these can continue throughout their teen and adult years. Great blessings will literally “be poured out upon the heads” of those who are endowed in the temples, and a portion of these blessings will come to our youth as they live worthily to participate in the house of the Lord.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p16" pid="lNxD9rOALUinHzRc2eS10Q" hash="67W16w">The Salt Lake Temple baptistry is a thrilling place to be on Saturday mornings! I was there early one morning to be baptized for some of my ancestors. As I sat waiting on the bench in the baptismal area, I noticed that the young woman on my left was reading her patriarchal blessing. The girl on my right was reading her scriptures. I asked her if she had come here with a group. Her reply was: “No, I come with my friend every Saturday. It makes my whole week go better.” These young women, along with many other young men and women, know a grand secret—the temple blesses not only our families’ and ancestors’ lives, but also our own. We are promised that those who are endowed in the temple will go forth from that holy house “armed with thy power, and that thy name may be upon them, and thy glory be round about them, and thine angels have charge over them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> These are great blessings and promises. What youth does not desire to prepare to receive these blessings in order to navigate in today’s ever-darkening world?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p17" pid="nhfHl88PbEmgpChPDopNYQ" hash="hyxkNQ">When President Faust talked to the young men in the priesthood session last October, he called on them to lead out and become a part of temple and family history work. He said: “I encourage you … to begin to unlock the knowledge of who you really are by learning more about your forebears. … You can easily access a vast collection of family history records using the Internet on your home computer or at your nearest family history center. … Temple work is essential … because ‘we without them cannot be made perfect; neither can they without us be made perfect.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p18" pid="UUeAtdNS1kygooL1EmyyQA" hash="58G-AQ">The youth have been prepared “for such a time as this.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> They are intelligent and bright. They are proficient on computers and the Internet. They are a great untapped resource for good in the world! They have been reserved for these latter days, and they have a great work to do. And not only do they have a great work to do there, but the temple will also be a refuge for them that will protect them from worldly pressures and influences.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p19" pid="tJSnsxeFfkqQscry1sIviQ" hash="M2-myA">As I contemplate President Faust’s words, I can visualize an army of righteous youth prepared and worthy to attend the temple. I can see families sealed together for eternity. I can see youth who understand what it means to be “saviours … on mount Zion.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> I can see youth whose hearts are turned to their fathers.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> And I can envision youth growing up in such a way that they will come forth from the temples filled with strength to resist worldly pressures.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> I can see a generation of youth who will “stand … in holy places, and be not moved.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you.p20" pid="Xv62V-hU8EOjTA7rzqcqiw" hash="Bps6Kg">Zina Baker Huntington, along with so many other faithful Saints, sacrificed <span class="emphasis">everything</span> in order that we might have the blessings of the restored gospel. It is my prayer that we might understand our role in this great work and remain worthy to enter His holy temples. I know that if we will do this, the joyful day will come when we shall meet our ancestors once again and be able to say to them, “<span class="emphasis">We</span> did this for you.” In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2004/10/we-did-this-for-you</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2004-general-conference/2004-10-5020-elaine-s-dalton-64k-eng.mp3" length="6145752" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2004 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>He Knows You by Name</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name?lang=eng</link>
      <description>You may not have heard the Lord call you by name, but He knows each one of you and He knows your name.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10032029_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="G_Armw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="q6GaFtwsOUSY0ZpBnINetQ" hash="HO72Qg">He Knows You by Name</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="QiAPdkVj0E2GJ4HWgsd3Fg" hash="0nm0pw">Elaine S. Dalton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="P0oWmAr4G0OUy5X7ix3H9A" hash="yt05Mw">You may not have heard the Lord call you by name, but He knows each one of you and He knows your name.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-f3.jpg" alt="Elaine S. Dalton" pid="ai_9DcBHHEuf0UOng8fIiw" hash="ua38KQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name.p1" pid="4d6SrNdGNkK9t0v7zIZsKQ" hash="f5cSiA">It was on “the morning of a beautiful, clear day, early in the spring of eighteen hundred and twenty” when 14-year-old Joseph Smith went into the grove, knelt in prayer, and “saw two Personages, whose brightness and glory defy all description, standing above [him] in the air.” He said: “One of them spake unto me, <span class="emphasis">calling me by name</span> and said, pointing to the other—<span class="emphasis">This is My Beloved Son. Hear Him!</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Can you imagine how 14-year-old Joseph must have felt to see God the Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, and to hear Heavenly Father call him by his name?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name.p2" pid="rxbNbgnA2kSut5vbsSwlCQ" hash="0b0viw">When I visited the Sacred Grove, I tried to imagine what it must have been like to have been Joseph Smith. In those quiet moments, the Spirit whispered to my beating heart that I was standing on holy ground and that all that the Prophet Joseph Smith had said was true. Then came the powerful realization that we are all the beneficiaries of his faith, courage, and steadfast desire to obey God. He had received an answer to his humble prayer. He had seen the Father and His Beloved Son. There in the Sacred Grove, I knew that Heavenly Father not only knew Joseph Smith by name, but He also knows each of us by name. And just as Joseph Smith had an important part to play in this great and marvelous work, we too have an important part to play in these latter days.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name.p3" pid="d50hDD26dUm0p_TvXGHQ5A" hash="DRcXnw">Did you know that Heavenly Father knows you personally—by name? The scriptures teach us that this is true. When Enos went into the woods to pray, he recorded, “There came a voice unto me, saying: <span class="emphasis">Enos,</span> thy sins are forgiven thee, and thou shalt be blessed.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Moses not only prayed but also talked to God face-to-face, and God said to Moses, “I have a work for thee, <span class="emphasis">Moses,</span> my son.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> The Lord knew Jacob’s name and changed it to<span class="emphasis"> Israel</span> to more accurately reflect his mission on the earth.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Similarly, He changed the names of Paul and Abraham and Sarah. In Doctrine and Covenants, section 25, Emma Smith is given a blessing for her comfort and guidance in life. The Lord begins this blessing by saying, “Hearken unto the voice of the Lord your God, while I speak unto you, <span class="emphasis">Emma Smith,</span> my daughter.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name.p4" pid="rIKpoPLBPEG9WUgt5WtdNA" hash="QS8ooQ">You may not have heard the Lord call you by name, but He knows each one of you and He knows your name. Elder Neal A. Maxwell said: “I testify to you that God has known you individually … for a long, long time (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:23</a>). He has loved you for a long, long time. He not only knows the names of all the stars (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/147.4" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 147:4</a>; <a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/40.26" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 40:26</a>); He knows your names and all your heartaches and your joys!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name.p5" pid="QVGSN0wjb0elbJVhX8AIzg" hash="Deu0ew">How can you know that your name and needs are known by our Heavenly Father? Elder Robert D. Hales counseled: “Turn to the scriptures. Kneel in prayer. Ask in faith. Listen to the Holy Ghost. … Live the gospel with patience and persistence.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name.p6" pid="0KL7osQzlEC5nUMS-onQ2w" hash="hN990A">That’s what Joseph did. His testimony helps all of us know that we are known and loved by our Heavenly Father. We are truly daughters of a Heavenly Father who loves us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Elder Jeffrey R. Holland has told us: “No one of us is less treasured or cherished of God than another. … He loves each of us—insecurities, anxieties, self-image, and all. … He cheers on <span class="emphasis">every</span> runner, calling out that the race is against sin, <span class="emphasis">not</span> against each other.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name.p7" pid="4EUTXSL9IEqy93SxZPIOBg" hash="dKE9uA">Once Joseph Smith received this knowledge, his life didn’t get easier. In fact, he was faced with intense pressure from peers and adults. Joseph Smith’s history provides an important pattern for each of us. We can apply his teachings when we don’t know what to do, when we are faced with peer pressure, when we feel surrounded by temptation, or feel unworthy or alone. We can pray! We can call upon God in the name of His holy Son, Jesus Christ, and seek comfort, guidance, and direction. Have you ever had a problem and not known what to do? Joseph said: “My mind was called up to serious reflection and great uneasiness. … I often said to myself: What is to be done?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name.p8" pid="YVUGIrwQPkqkc25ojfwbZQ" hash="QGRWtw">How did he receive comfort and guidance? He studied the scriptures, pondered their promises, and then “came to the determination to ‘ask of God.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> The answer he received that beautiful spring day changed his life and direction. He <span class="emphasis">knew.</span> He gained a testimony of God and Jesus Christ, and his testimony enabled him to live the gospel with patience and persistence. He was undeterred by peer pressure and persecution, for in his words he said, “I had seen a vision; I knew it, and I knew that God knew it, and I could not deny it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> He could stand firm because of his testimony. And so can you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name.p9" pid="3GvhkgBdfk-GudimNBkjYA" hash="HZchJQ">If you have ever felt the tug of peer pressure, pray, ask in faith, and listen to the Holy Ghost. Then live the gospel. Joseph keenly realized his imperfections and weaknesses. Again—he prayed. In response to this prayer, he was visited by the angel Moroni. Joseph recounted: <span class="emphasis">“He called me by name”</span> and said “that God had a work for me to do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name.p10" pid="GuovZ5n92kmHHcmZjAMp4Q" hash="hjT5DA">As we pray, the Lord will guide and prepare us to do our part. One summer, while touring Europe with the BYU International Folk Dancers, I learned an important lesson. I was sick and I became discouraged. I wanted to quit and go home. We were in Scotland to perform our show for the members, investigators, and missionaries. We went to the mission home for a prayer. As I entered, I glanced at a stone in the front garden. Chiseled in the stone were the words “What-e’er thou art act well thy part.” That message went like electricity to my heart. I felt that that stone was speaking to me. It changed me. I knew at that instant that I had a part to play not only on that dancing tour but throughout my life and that it was very important to “act well” my part.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name.p11" pid="3Jl-2F0iDU-M8RB3JzX0gA" hash="Bdtz4g">What does the Lord expect us to do? He expects us to play our part in the final scenes prior to His coming. He expects us to prove ourselves worthy to return and live with Him. He expects us to become like Him. Follow Joseph’s pattern. I love the words in the hymn the choir just sang: “But undaunted, still he trusted / In his Heav’nly Father’s care.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> To be <span class="emphasis">undaunted</span> means unshaken in purpose, resolutely courageous. Joseph described himself as a “disturber” of the adversary’s kingdom. He said, “It seems as though the adversary was aware … that I was destined to prove a disturber and an annoyer of his kingdom.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> I have written in the margin of my scriptures, <span class="emphasis">“Be a disturber!”</span> Trust in your Heavenly Father’s care.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name.p12" pid="Ik2T_kmS-UivSkA2nJ-SLA" hash="COfZnw">Each of us will play an important part if we follow the pattern established by Joseph Smith. The Lord strengthened Joseph Smith for his divine mission. He will strengthen you for yours. He may even send His holy angels to tutor you. Now the challenge is this: Will you be in such a place that angels can enter? Will you be still enough to hear? Will you be undaunted and trust?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name.p13" pid="Vf3_HSwWaEmoUtDl9RrNXQ" hash="MNWV8Q">We are living at a time when the fulness of the gospel has been restored to the earth through the Lord’s prophet, Joseph Smith. We are living in a time when we have the Book of Mormon to guide us. We are living in a time when we have a living prophet, the priesthood power on the earth, and the sealing power to bind families together for eternity in holy temples. Truly these are days “never to be forgotten”!<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name.p14" pid="ieWap6YVJ0Sud4LvLuEyhQ" hash="JtDzKA">It is my prayer that each one of us might be firm in our faith, that we might follow the pattern Joseph Smith established for us to gain a testimony. I also pray that each of us will worthily represent the Savior as we take upon ourselves His name. He has promised: “As the new heavens and the new earth, which I will make, shall remain before me, … so shall your … name remain.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name.p15" pid="ZVoQGUuJAkqmnnTOZFJ3dQ" hash="qB1UQw">My testimony of the restored gospel of Jesus Christ has served as a guide and an anchor in my life. I am grateful to stand before you today and say with all the energy of my heart, “We thank thee, O God, for a prophet.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> I am so grateful for the integrity of a 14-year-old young man who prayed for an answer to his questions and then remained true to the knowledge he received.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name.p16" pid="SYWAcUUmJkizYzpvb9YLmg" hash="7bcuSg">Each of you has a part to play in this great and marvelous work. The Savior will help you. He will lead you by the hand.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> He knows you by name. I so testify, in the sacred <span class="emphasis">name</span> of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2005/04/he-knows-you-by-name</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2005-general-young-women-meeting/2005-03-0030-elaine-s-dalton-64k-eng.mp3" length="10187045" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2005 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It Shows in Your Face</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face?lang=eng</link>
      <description>You reflect His light. Your example will have a powerful effect for good on the earth.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006561_000_038" doc-version="3" hash="PUFdeg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="JuoXrbjTrki5aZbsekY2DQ" hash="2sY23g">It Shows in Your Face</h1><p class="authorName" uuid="96d469fa-ea3d-4b8b-ad3a-cd03b387ee06" pid="H1sJZUJ7rk2t7UVyFpdroA" hash="0nm0pw">Elaine S. Dalton</p><p class="kicker" pid="buh4ABGtTEqMrnu4o6BqgA" hash="GnOOEA">You reflect His light. Your example will have a powerful effect for good on the earth.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" uuid="cd88f8a9-8b50-44e9-997b-c8323e00b2d6">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face.t1" uuid="">
      <img src="en2006lp.nfo-o-b5.jpg" alt="Elaine S. Dalton" uuid="a8c3aa5f-5a90-4d85-8994-d1d85899e483" pid="pAlmrYJ3ukmeWrYXP_eEjA" hash="lKHcow" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face.p1" uuid="d31b50c3-f46b-48fd-ad02-411f36803195" pid="xBI15jMJnUySldjctG_qBg" hash="n-bRaw">There has never been a better time to live on the earth than this. These are “days never to be forgotten.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> These are your days, and they are amazing. You are amazing! As I look into your eyes and see your shining faces, I marvel that you can be so good, so strong, and so pure in a world that is so challenging. I am reminded of a poem my grandfather used to say to me when I was about your age. He said:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face.f1" uuid="261da56e-435a-4112-af76-beff9ba61886">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="1_0WvKfsR0m0cgQfWh66bg" hash="qa7jvQ">
            <span class="emphasis">You don’t have to tell how you live each day;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="hTvuFN4wyEyUCfqo2fhF0w" hash="HUzg1w">
            <span class="emphasis">You don’t have to tell if you work or play;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="06YtY1p0wEO5GIrEUK_Xfw" hash="IQgBww">
            <span class="emphasis">A tried and true barometer stands in its place—</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="iy8qhwPGN0iMDC9dVtWReA" hash="9peBeA">
            <span class="emphasis">You don’t have to tell, it will show in your face. … </span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="znOsm3jBj0CM7hwjUTN1xw" hash="pJDH0g">
            <span class="emphasis">If you live close to God and His infinite grace—</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="UzA_Y9ebDEKmNzxAN-a2Ng" hash="CStjsA">
            <span class="emphasis">You won’t have to tell, it will show in your face.</span>
            <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face.p2" uuid="876ce661-d1e5-41ea-a066-cae5d4cc3fd1" pid="fJ8JjjW6QEusc0TMs8cGDQ" hash="nKEiqA">I have never forgotten that simple poem, and I have always tried to live in such a way that it <span class="emphasis">would</span> show in my face. I can see that you are doing that also. The light in your countenance comes because you have made and kept covenants with our Heavenly Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, and you have made choices which qualify you to have the companionship of the Holy Ghost. I express my admiration for each one of you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face.p3" uuid="f7ea31b2-7fb2-4061-b42e-84aba0280419" pid="U4IS_QhR90-gPUsEugF_0A" hash="-IXF5Q">President Gordon B. Hinckley has said of you, “You are … the finest [and strongest] generation of young people ever in the history of this Church.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> I believe you have been prepared and reserved to be on the earth at this time when the challenges and opportunities are the greatest. I believe that the Lord is counting on you to be a leader for righteousness and to stand as a witness “at all times and in all things, and in all places.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Indeed, it can be said of you that you are the “bright shining hope” of the future.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face.p4" uuid="8c97da49-f2cf-4685-982a-4a65f5373d60" pid="1jXfmcU3cUa8GlgzN_tJ7w" hash="OFYAmA">I believe that you are included in those spoken of by the Apostle Peter when he said, “Ye are a chosen generation, a royal priesthood, an holy nation, a peculiar people; that ye should shew forth the praises of him who hath called you out of darkness into his marvellous light.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face.p5" uuid="2b86d01e-c97d-4d2b-acf7-dc753b806809" pid="vugByqzRbkSrusZeC6Y5Jg" hash="pBVnQA">That light is the Savior’s light. It is the light of the restored gospel of Jesus Christ. By the way you live the gospel, you reflect His light. Your example will have a powerful effect for good on the earth. “Arise and shine forth, that thy light may be a standard for the nations”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> is a call to each of you. It is a call to move to higher ground. It is a call to leadership—to lead out in decency, purity, modesty, and holiness. It is a call to share this light with others. It is time to “arise and shine forth.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face.p6" uuid="22aa1bd7-b454-4df3-97fb-a4c781a9d3f9" pid="WZrsC3CthEuEygEVOE_k1g" hash="x7rNWQ">Can one righteous young woman change the world? The answer is a resounding “yes!” You have the Holy Ghost as your guide, and He “will show … you all things … [you] should do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> It is the daily consistent things you do that will strengthen you to be a leader and an example—daily prayer, daily scripture study, daily obedience, daily service to others. As you do these things, you will grow closer to the Savior and become more and more like Him. Like Moses and Abinadi and other faithful leaders,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> your face will glow with the fire of your faith. “Have ye received his image in your countenances?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> “Arise and shine forth.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face.p7" uuid="fa28fd43-7b87-4803-b7a9-33e93a848367" pid="3NUYpHm_6UGQAzrZtYj_yw" hash="SAaDtQ">In 1856, at age 13, Mary joined the Church with her family in England, traveled to America, and joined the Martin handcart company. In her personal history she recounts the difficulty of the journey—the loss of her baby brother and older brother, the freezing of her own feet, and finally the death of an infant sister and her mother. When she arrived in the Salt Lake Valley, the doctor amputated her toes, but she was promised by the prophet, Brigham Young, that she would not have to have any more of her feet cut off. She recounts: “One day I sat … crying. My feet were hurting me so—when a little old woman knocked at the door. She said she had felt someone needed her there for a number of days. … I showed her my feet. … She said, ‘Yes, and with the help of the Lord we will save them yet.’ She made a poultice and put on my feet and every day after the doctor had gone she would come and change the poultice. At the end of three months my feet were well.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face.p8" uuid="6983e79c-195b-4318-8890-9d9128d0302e" pid="f6vpVfjpIUyEWg5kjhE1ZQ" hash="yTfQ0A">But Mary had sat in her chair so long that the cords of her legs had become stiff and she could not straighten them. When her father saw her condition, he cried. He rubbed her legs with oil and tried to straighten them, but it was of no use. One day he said, “Mary I have thought of a plan to help you. I will nail a shelf on the wall and while I am away to work you try to reach it.” She said that she tried all day for several days and at last she could reach the shelf. Then her father put the shelf a little higher. This went on for another three months, and through her daily diligence her legs were straightened and she learned to walk again.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face.p9" uuid="32b8724c-020c-46b7-891d-db5590fc77e6" pid="4DbbRFKOG0aQ0-LnXj7Yig" hash="_6gu_w">I believe that you are learning, like Mary Goble, to reach just a little higher to the shelf our leaders have raised for us, and that if you will reach higher as those ideals are raised, you will become able to walk into the future with confidence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face.p10" uuid="980992d4-78ec-4519-8057-46e4a8622bfb" pid="TNoxbe5XkEiC2j5IP-dCkQ" hash="18UsDA">The faces of the young women in West Africa shine with the radiant light of the Holy Ghost. They live the standards in the <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth</span> pamphlet, they are guided by the Spirit, and they are preparing to be leaders. They love the Lord and are grateful for His light in their lives. Some of these young women walked three hours to share their testimonies with me. Because of them, I will never be the same.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face.p11" uuid="69d92e2b-bf22-4e0e-b887-5879bbde3073" pid="2unZbMhHqU61d5uFt8sJFw" hash="poRy4g">When I was in South America, the young women and their leaders sang, “I’m Trying to Be like Jesus.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> They not only sang the words, but they meant it. In Asia and India, young women are examples of faith, modest dress, and purity. Their eyes shine and they are happy. The young women in England, Ireland, and Wales are standing for truth and righteousness in their schools. In an ever-darkening world, they are making a difference. Some of you are the only members in your family or your school. You are making a difference. You are leading in righteous ways.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face.p12" uuid="9c9ad367-39b3-41a0-a490-47ddc3bbb6e9" pid="erUsGy5AuE2EsQHQW0Tcjw" hash="aA7Ckg">Not so long ago, I hiked with a group of youth to the top of Ensign Peak. There we looked at the city of Salt Lake and the temple and talked of the sacrifice so many had made for the gospel. Then each of the youth unfurled a banner. On their banners they had drawn symbols of their message to the world—what they wanted to stand for in these latter days. It was thrilling to hear the commitment and testimony of each one. Then we sang “High on the Mountain Top”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> and the youth cheered together, “Hurrah for Israel!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> I echo those words today. Hurrah for you! I hope you will never hesitate to “let your light so shine … that [others will] see your good works, and glorify your Father which is in heaven.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> I hope you too will raise your banners high. I know that as you lead in righteousness, this scripture in Isaiah will be fulfilled: “For, behold, … the Lord shall arise upon thee, and his glory shall be seen upon thee.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> It will be discernable, and “the Gentiles shall come to thy light, and kings to the brightness of thy rising.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face.p13" uuid="30fec57b-f415-4790-a7e4-57df8df98e3c" pid="MQn0Q32X4ECtRB4ZeZkdbQ" hash="lK5YHw">I can see a day when the world will look to you and say: “Who are you? Who are these young women who radiate this light? Why are you so happy? Why do you know your direction in such a confusing world?” And you will arise and stand on your feet and say with conviction: “We are daughters of our Heavenly Father, who loves us, and we love Him. We will ‘stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things, and in all places.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face.p14" uuid="4c580625-6815-4a18-9fa4-196f3f637afb" pid="PEW4o_a8LUCZR0xE85FM7g" hash="JWjCwA">My call to you is the same as Moroni’s call: “Awake, and arise … , O daughter[s] of Zion.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> He saw you. He saw this day. These are your days! It is up to you to decide that you will “arise and shine forth.” I believe that as you awake and arise, your light will be a standard to the nations, but I also believe your standards will be a light to the nations. You are set apart. You distinguished yourselves in the premortal existence. Your lineage carries with it a covenant and promises. You have inherited the spiritual attributes of the faithful—even Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob. Your very nature reflects your divine heritage and destiny. The fact that you were born a girl is not by chance. Your divine characteristics will be magnified as you lead others and arise to your divine potential. Draw close to the Savior. He lives! He is the light, life, and hope of the world. He will lead you and give you courage to share your light. As my grandfather taught me, “When you live close to God and His infinite grace, you won’t have to tell, it will show in your face.” In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/04/it-shows-in-your-face</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2006-general-young-women-meeting/2006-03-0030-elaine-s-dalton-64k-eng.mp3" length="10545781" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2006 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Look toward Eternity!</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/10/look-toward-eternity?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Do you understand why it is so important to remain clean and pure?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/look-toward-eternity" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006562_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="rgIUtw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/look-toward-eternity.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="x5CYGbdiyEWFmOQVmOCBPw" hash="ie_OZw">Look toward Eternity!</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="GOXFJfPDRkCp9F-a-8PQvw" hash="0nm0pw">Elaine S. Dalton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="VawfxihGwU-59V9GydeQWg" hash="cAK5Hw">Do you understand why it is so important to remain clean and pure?</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/look-toward-eternity.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/DaltonES_03.jpg" alt="Elaine S. Dalton" pid="0j0tSB3UUEGh29unhPqW7A" hash="aB68iA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/look-toward-eternity.p1" pid="_9beY4fJq0upCJVZLhyB_g" hash="qYqElQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="31"></span>When our first grandson was born, the entire family rushed to the hospital. It was an amazing experience for me to see our oldest son, Matthew, holding this precious new baby boy. While standing at the nursery window with our youngest son, Chad, we gazed into the eyes of this new little spirit—so clean, so pure, so recently from heaven. It seemed that all time stood still, and for an instant, we could see the great eternal plan. The sacredness of life was crystal clear, and I whispered to Chad, “Do you understand why it is so important to remain clean and pure?” He responded reverently, “Oh yes, Mom, I get it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/look-toward-eternity.p2" pid="R35rgTv97kOfZpc94fP5Xg" hash="WxyfuQ">That moment was so powerful that I desire for every young man and woman, every young adult, and indeed each one of us to feel and know the importance of living a worthy and pure life. It is our personal worthiness that will qualify us to fulfill our individual earthly missions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/look-toward-eternity.p3" pid="xqdwOHNUEUiihD1QciWH-A" hash="D2abcw">Our personal mission began long before we arrived on the earth. In the premortal life, we were “called and prepared” to live on the earth at a time when temptations and challenges would be the greatest. This was “on account of [our] exceeding faith and good works” and because of our “having chosen good.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> We understood our Father’s plan and knew that it was good. We not only chose it, but we defended it. We knew that our earthly missions would be fraught with temptation, challenges, and hardship, but we also knew that we would be blessed by the fulness of the gospel, living prophets, and the guidance of the Holy Ghost. We knew and understood that our success on this earth would be determined by our worthiness and purity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/look-toward-eternity.p4" pid="xLuW0we8_UWkutM41rLlOQ" hash="4Bi0wg">What does it mean to be worthy? In the Book of Mormon, Lamoni’s father implored, “What shall I do that I may have this eternal life of which thou hast spoken?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Then the king made a commitment to the Lord by saying, “I will give away all my sins to know thee.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Once Lamoni’s father understood who he was and the great plan of which he was a part, worthiness became his heart’s desire.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/look-toward-eternity.p5" pid="1VRlgsPgK0WhMmls6zQVSg" hash="31iqqg">To become worthy, we make choices that will enable us to return to our Heavenly Father’s presence. We do those things which will qualify us to claim all the blessings that He has in store for us. This is the reason we are here on the earth—“to see if [we] will do all things whatsoever the Lord … shall command.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> It is through our faith in the Lord Jesus Christ that we can resist temptation.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Our faith will enable us to shun evil. It will be repulsive to us because “light cleaveth unto light” and “virtue loveth virtue.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/look-toward-eternity.p6" pid="FXaxURwBGU6Lw-m2_rSTMg" hash="OFJd1g">To become unspotted from the world requires not only faith but repentance and obedience. We must live the standards and do those things which will entitle us to the constant companionship and guidance of the Holy Ghost—for the Spirit cannot dwell in unholy temples.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/look-toward-eternity.p7" pid="kIcUiT-g9kC43G8mmBGd6w" hash="Hvivlw">One young man I know said: “It’s just too hard. Living the standards in my world is not realistic. It’s just too hard.” Yet knowing that we are sons and daughters of God, we must strive for worthiness. Another group of youth adopted the motto “I Can Do Hard Things.” They understand their identity, their mission, their source of guidance, and they receive strength through keeping their covenants. They also understand that when they make a mistake, they can change! Satan wants all of us to think that repentance is not possible. This is absolutely not true. The Savior has promised forgiveness.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Each week, worthily partaking of the sacrament makes it possible for each of us to become clean and pure as we covenant to “always remember [the Savior], and keep his commandments.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> The gospel of Jesus Christ is one of simplicity, and we are given the tools that make the pathway straight and narrow. The way is clear: “For my <span class="pageBreak" page-number="32"></span>yoke is easy, and my burden is light.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/look-toward-eternity.p8" pid="HTEmicBMt0S8Kue_K7a9hg" hash="EUpDsQ">Thirty-eight years ago my husband and I were married in the Salt Lake Temple by President Gordon B. Hinckley. The counsel and direction he gave us that day have become a beacon for our lives. When we left the temple as husband and wife, we went to a park near the temple grounds and recorded in a journal the words of wisdom we had received. He counseled us to always remember our prayers night and morning, to pray as a couple and as a family. He counseled us to always pay a full and honest tithing. He counseled us to read the scriptures daily and to apply the principles in our lives. And he counseled us to remain worthy. He said, “Always live in such a way that when you need the Lord’s blessings, you can call upon Him and receive them because you are worthy.” He said: “There will come times in your life when you will need immediate blessings. You will need to live in such a way that they will be granted—not out of mercy but because you are worthy.” I didn’t comprehend then what that meant, but in the 38 years that have followed, we have called upon our Father in Heaven for many “immediate blessings.” Daily, these holy habits and righteous routines have helped steady us on the path that leads back into our Father’s presence. And today I say, “We thank thee, O God, for a prophet to guide us in these latter days.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/look-toward-eternity.p9" pid="QiTkKszVmEin52G8QkTiag" hash="AGDhzA">Personal worthiness is essential to enter His holy temples and to ultimately become heirs to “all [the] Father hath.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> The Lord has said, “Let virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly; then shall thy confidence wax strong in the presence of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> When we do this, we can confidently enter the holy temples of God with a knowledge that we are worthy to go where the Lord Himself goes. When we are worthy, we can not only <span class="emphasis">enter</span> the temple, the temple can <span class="emphasis">enter</span> us. The Lord’s promises of salvation and happiness become <span class="emphasis">ours</span>—and our earthly mission becomes <span class="emphasis">His.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/look-toward-eternity.p10" pid="QLfrh_6FfE6ff-AVoBSoqw" hash="uz-UHQ">Just last month our youngest son, Chad, went to the temple with a beautiful, worthy young woman to be married for time and all eternity. As he took her hand and knelt at the altar, I looked into the mirrors on either side and again I wanted to whisper, “Do you understand why it is so important to be clean and pure?” But this time I didn’t have to remind him because the Spirit did the whispering.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/look-toward-eternity.p11" pid="dsMLsznaGkurfsj9ykughA" hash="ddVrjw">To the youth of the noble birthright, look into the windows of eternity! See yourselves in the Lord’s holy temples. See yourselves living worthy and pure lives. Generations are depending on you! I testify that worthiness is possible because of the redeeming and enabling power of the Atonement of Jesus Christ. I pray that it may be said of each one of us, “They shall walk with me in white: for they are worthy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/10/look-toward-eternity</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2006-general-conference/2006-10-2040-elaine-s-dalton-64k-eng.mp3" length="3859744" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2006 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stay on the Path</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sometimes we think we can live on the edge and still maintain our virtue. But that is a risky place to be.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008333_000_043" doc-version="2" hash="bOKqMw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="YEaGNRb2yEiI4-fvzbYHQw" hash="ang95w">Stay on the Path</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="XneCahYYRU-JPynAkwHysg" hash="0nm0pw">Elaine S. Dalton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="fgz_KdMVpUGzSgSJqOsb3Q" hash="O7TobA">Sometimes we think we can live on the edge and still maintain our virtue. But that is a risky place to be.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/DaltonES_07.jpg" alt="Elaine S. Dalton" pid="9pBWrJRA8UiOsKMu_w0F2g" hash="0xpFmg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path.p1" pid="BpEE77IZhkSgcxV_n3xc6Q" hash="XvvEtA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="112"></span>On one of the trails in a canyon near my home, there is a sign that says Stay on the Path. As one embarks on that trail, it soon becomes very clear that this is sound advice. There are hills and turns and steep drop-off areas. In some places the ground beyond the path is unstable, and during certain seasons of the year, an occasional rattlesnake appears. My message to each of you tonight is the same as the message on that sign—Stay on the Path.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path.p2" pid="VXUscXyW6Ua9v0R80hhOdA" hash="z5QkPw">Several years ago I went on a backpacking trip in the Teton Mountains of Wyoming with a group of young women. It was a difficult hike, and on the second day we arrived at the most dangerous part of the hike. We were going to hike along Hurricane Pass—aptly named because of the strong winds which almost always blow there. We were instructed by a ranger to stay in the center of the path, stay as low as possible on the exposed part of the trail, secure everything in our packs, and move quickly. This was no spot for photographs or for lingering. I was very relieved and happy when each one of the young women had navigated that spot successfully. And do you know—not one of them asked how close to the edge they could get!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path.p3" pid="xymK6tpKNUGUBGbF3XnUzA" hash="g84J3Q">Sometimes as we walk life’s paths, we want to loiter in dangerous places, thinking that it is fun and thrilling and that we are in control. Sometimes we think we can live on the edge and still maintain our virtue. But that is a risky place to be. As the Prophet Joseph Smith told us, “Happiness is the object and design of our existence; and will be the end thereof, if we pursue the path that leads to it; and this path is virtue” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 5:134–35).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path.p4" pid="tWmYV8c5m0iBbiukiVY28Q" hash="yUC10A">The Lord’s advice to Emma Smith in Doctrine and Covenants section 25 is His advice to <span class="emphasis">all</span> of His precious daughters. There we are given a code of conduct and counseled to “walk in the paths of virtue” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/25.2" class="scriptureRef">v. 2</a>). Virtue “is a pattern of thought [or] behavior based on high moral standards” (<span class="emphasis">Preach My Gospel</span> [2004], 118). So what are the high moral standards that help us to be virtuous?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path.p5" pid="0f72iI4y5keHIIQIPo7LkQ" hash="5-eU-w">Virtue encompasses modesty—in thought, language, dress, and demeanor. And modesty is the <span class="pageBreak" page-number="113"></span>foundation stone of chastity. Just as one does not hike trails inhabited by rattlesnakes barefoot, similarly in today’s world it is essential to our very safety to be modest. When we are modest, we show others that we understand our relationship with our Father in Heaven as His daughters. We demonstrate that we love Him and that we will stand as a witness of Him in all things. Being modest lets others know that we “cherish virtue” (“Dearest Children, God Is Near You,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns, </span>no. 96). Modesty is not a matter of being “hip.” It is a matter of the heart and being holy. It is not about being fashionable. It is about being faithful. It is not about being cool. It is about being chaste and keeping covenants. It is not about being popular, but about being pure. Modesty has everything to do with keeping our footing securely on the path of chastity and virtue. It is clear that virtue is a requirement for exaltation. Mormon helps us understand that both virtue and chastity are “most dear and precious above all things” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/9.9" class="scriptureRef">Moroni 9:9</a>). We simply cannot afford to be casual or get too close to the edge. That is dangerous ground for any daughter of God to walk.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path.p6" pid="sO6egyRVnUCyI9L1mKABlw" hash="z4BSeg">We are counseled in Doctrine and Covenants section 25 that we must <span class="emphasis">cleave</span> to our covenants (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/25.13" class="scriptureRef">v. 13</a>). <span class="emphasis">Cleaving, </span>to me, means to stick to, to adhere, and to really hold on tight to the promises we make with the Lord. Our covenants will strengthen us to resist temptation. Keeping our covenants will steady us on the path of virtue. As we keep the covenants we have made at baptism, we will remain in the center of the path. Elder Jeffrey R. Holland reminds us:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path.p7" pid="QfY_4DQEh0m2N6KMxPiolQ" hash="j0JZtg">“Beginning with our baptism, we make covenants as we follow this path to eternal life, and we stay on the path by keeping them. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path.p8" pid="O6fMOYEAGUCTm0uxJGDQVg" hash="0NMWGQ">“… The promptings of the Holy Ghost will always be sufficient for our needs if we keep to the covenant path. Our path is uphill most days, but the help we receive for the climb is literally divine. We have three members of the Godhead—the Father, the Son, and the Holy Ghost—helping us because of the covenants we have made.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path.p9" pid="KHfJwfLteUa_V43a0oUN2Q" hash="p__8QA">“To remind us of those covenants, we partake of the sacrament each week. In the prayer offered on the bread, we ‘witness unto thee, O God, the Eternal Father, that [we] are willing to take upon [us] the name of thy Son, and always remember him and keep his commandments which he has given [us]; that [we] may always have his Spirit to be with [us]’ [<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.77" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:77</a>]” (“What I Wish Every New Member Knew—and Every Longtime Member Remembered,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign, </span>Oct. 2006, 11–12).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path.p10" pid="CWU5BmdPfUuNdMyYBAgTjQ" hash="jM3t_g">Guided by His Spirit, you will be confident and happy, and virtue will garnish your thoughts unceasingly. The Book of Mormon describes what happened when a whole society kept their covenants and lived clean and virtuous lives: “And surely there could not be a happier people among all the people who had been created by the hand of God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/4-ne/1.16" class="scriptureRef">4 Nephi 1:16</a>). Guided <span class="pageBreak" page-number="114"></span>by the Holy Ghost, you will also be a righteous influence on others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path.p11" pid="PWvjBWQsXE-WCw7mTOicrQ" hash="rFe8HQ">I have in my office the pictures of the generations of women in my family—my great-grandmother, my grandmother, my mother, and my daughter, Emi. Their lives of commitment and faith in the plan have helped me climb higher and journey further. Looking at that picture now, I can see very clearly the importance of living a virtuous life. Today I not only have one daughter, but five daughters-in-law and five little granddaughters to add to that picture. I feel a deep sense of responsibility to live an exemplary life of virtue and holiness before them. Even if you are the first in the line of generations to come, you too have a responsibility to those that will follow you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path.p12" pid="jpOmPAkKFUSyeTZjRJjl1Q" hash="zWrT3w">Recently, I embarked on that same hike in the Tetons I spoke of earlier, only this time with my husband and a group of friends our same age. When we started, it was thrilling and easy, but before we arrived at our destination, we were exhausted and I knew I was in trouble. I was not as prepared for the hike physically as I had been when I hiked with the young women years before—and I had packed my equipment carelessly and taken too much. The weight of my pack began to make me weary and ready to give up. The others were also feeling the rigors of the altitude, the steep terrain, and heavy packs. My husband sensed this and hurried ahead. I felt abandoned. However, after about an hour I could see my husband descending the trail on the other side of the valley. He was running toward me. When he reached me, he took my pack, dried my tears, and led me to the destination—a crystal clear lake surrounded by lofty pine trees. Then he turned around, went back down the trail, and did the same thing four more times for the other hikers. As I watched him, I was sorry I was so unprepared and even more sorry that I had so many extra things in my pack that had added to the weight he had to carry for me. But I was so grateful for his strength, for his unselfishness, for his preparation, and for his love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path.p13" pid="tWIEjEj7YUayUtJVA9QhOw" hash="3o12wQ">As you climb the mountains of life, stay on the path of virtue. There will be others to help you—your parents, family members, bishops, advisers, and righteous friends of all ages. And if you are weary or take a wrong turn, change your direction and get back on the path of virtue. Always remember that the Savior is there for you. He will enable you to repent, strengthen you, lighten your burdens, dry your tears, comfort you, and continue to help you stay on the path.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path.p14" pid="DO5CPTLeXUKLYTdgnCdifA" hash="YhW6tA">The Savior is the perfect example of virtue. When Jesus walked the roads of the Holy Land, He “went about doing good” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/10.38" class="scriptureRef">Acts 10:38</a>). He healed the sick and caused the blind to see and raised the dead. “He taught the truths of eternity, the reality of our premortal existence, the purpose of our life on earth, and [our] potential [as] … daughters of God in the life to come” (see “The Living Christ: The Testimony of the Apostles,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Apr. 2000, 2–3). One of my favorite scriptures says: “Trust in the Lord with all thine heart; and lean not unto thine own understanding. In all thy ways acknowledge him, and he shall direct thy paths” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/3.5-6" class="scriptureRef">Proverbs 3:5–6</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path.p15" pid="94q20UVQoUeUaoBtUTx6Rg" hash="NFySJg">I testify that this is true. He has not only marked the way, but He has even led me by the hand at times. “His way is the path that leads to happiness in this life and eternal life in the world to come” (“The Living Christ,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Apr. 2000, 3). I bear you my testimony that He lives! He will hear your prayers and guide your steps. Jesus Christ is our Exemplar and our Guide. Stay on the path! Be modest. Cleave to your covenants, and be worthy of the companionship of the Holy Ghost. The Lord promises: “Be of good cheer, for I will lead you along. The kingdom is yours and the blessings thereof are yours, and the riches of eternity are yours” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/78.18" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 78:18</a>). Truly, I stand all amazed at “His matchless life and the <span class="emphasis">infinite virtue</span> of His great atoning sacrifice” (“The Living Christ,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign, </span>Apr. 2000, 2; emphasis added). In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/04/stay-on-the-path</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2007-general-young-women-meeting/2007-03-0030-elaine-s-dalton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5548261" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2007 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At All Times, in All Things, and in All Places</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As you stand as a witness, obey the commandments, and press forward with “a steadfastness in Christ,” you will never be alone.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00009475_000_042" doc-version="2" hash="GPSpIg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="4sqyDA4eqUyRyreAYeX8ZQ" hash="lw9cHQ">At All Times, in All Things, and in All Places</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="yB9Y9nNAgUCWxiZ0ID9Mhg" hash="0nm0pw">Elaine S. Dalton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="BnZAByACNEC-JJ43vaAh2w" hash="-ZNhcQ">As you stand as a witness, obey the commandments, and press forward with “a steadfastness in Christ,” you will never be alone.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places.p1" pid="cvX_NaTGrkOK6sJ60VVOng" hash="y4mOuQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="116"></span>It is a privilege to stand before you and bear testimony of the Savior and His matchless life. He came to the earth to show us how to live the plan that was authored in heaven—a plan that, if lived, will make us happy. His example showed us the way to return home to our Heavenly Father. No other who has ever lived has been so “steadfast and immovable” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/5.15" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 5:15</a>). He was never distracted. He was focused on carrying out the will of the Father, and He remained true to His divine mission. Indeed it can be said of Him that He was true at all times, in all things, and in all places (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:9</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places.p2" pid="tgvFGpUk10W22Konkrsalg" hash="1zwq3Q">You are a part of that wondrous plan that was presented in the premortal realms. Your coming to the earth now has been anticipated since the plan was accepted. Your position in time and place is no accident. Your “exceeding faith and good works” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/13.3" class="scriptureRef">Alma 13:3</a>) then has laid the foundation for what you may accomplish now if you are faithful and obedient. You are God’s precious daughters, and you have a great work to do. In order to accomplish your divine mission and live the plan of happiness, you too must be steadfast and immovable “at all times and in all things, and in all places” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:9</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places.p3" pid="XbK4lv5j6kaJSN0pKGGwDQ" hash="18CJdw">Several years ago I was given a photograph of three sheds, two of which were leaning on the third and smallest shed. The accompanying caption read: “You need to be strong when you are the last one to take a stand.” You too need to be strong. As you are faithful and righteous, others will look to you for support and strength.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places.p4" pid="K84I3iaRKUe4kfgHM1DMrw" hash="7ckMrw">Helaman describes how this is possible: “And now, … remember, remember that it is upon the rock of our Redeemer, who is Christ, the Son of God, that ye must build your foundation; … which is a sure foundation, a foundation whereon if men build they cannot fall” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/5.12" class="scriptureRef">Helaman 5:12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places.p5" pid="NwuRc71zZ0uytUldFQvfdw" hash="cazYhg">Your foundation of faith must be firmly centered on Jesus Christ. Having that kind of faith means you rely on Him, you trust in Him, and even though you do not understand all things, you know that He does. You also know that you are a daughter of God, that He knows you by name, that He hears your prayers, and that He will help you accomplish your earthly mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places.p6" pid="R3mS_6h9MU65l_tkD7YK5A" hash="II2EEA">A young man I know well was elected to be the student body president at a large university. The university sent him to a leadership seminar where student leaders from across the United States gathered in Chicago, Illinois, to be trained and educated. They participated in an initial game outdoors on the college campus so that they could become acquainted with each other. The students were presented with current issues facing today’s youth and were asked to take a position. In response to the issue presented, they were directed to run to several trees in the grassy area marked “strongly agree,” “partially agree,” “strongly disagree,” or “mildly disagree.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places.p7" pid="hzlcbP7gwUeO18G3Z1H6vQ" hash="nQdrVg">Toward the end of this exercise, the leader asked, “Do you believe in premarital sex?” Without hesitation, this young man ran to the tree marked “strongly disagree.” To his amazement, he was the only one there! All the other student leaders were laughing and pointing at him and saying, “Oh, Jess, you are so funny. We all know you’re not really serious.” At that moment Jess said he knew exactly what he must do and so he loudly declared, “I’m not funny. I’m serious!” There was a stunned silence, and then <span class="pageBreak" page-number="117"></span>the group dispersed, leaving Jess standing alone by the tree. He felt out of place and, yes, weird. But he wasn’t weird. He was right. And he was not alone. During the week, many of the student leaders came to him privately and said that they wished they had known years earlier what he knew. Jess later said, “It was easy because I knew that I represented not only the university but my family, the Church, and the Savior.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places.p8" pid="jtULAeUxokqEhWO0PJs5rA" hash="a_LK2Q">A testimony that Jesus Christ is the Savior and Redeemer made Jess firm and quick to respond. You can gain that same confidence as you pray daily, search for answers in your scriptures, and obey the commandments. As you sincerely seek to gain a testimony, the knowledge that will come through the Holy Ghost will assist you with your challenges, with questions, and with living the standards. And it will be easy for you also to commit to be steadfast and immovable at all times and in all things and in all places.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places.p9" pid="nZhFWEjcG0GFSLRSD0pv_Q" hash="wT-pyA">Being steadfast and immovable means being obedient. One of the reasons you are here on the earth is to see if you will exercise your agency and “do all things whatsoever the Lord … shall command” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.25" class="scriptureRef">Abraham 3:25</a>). When you renew your covenants each week by partaking of the sacrament, you covenant that you will always remember the Savior and keep His commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places.p10" pid="tndsDm8OWEimHg_8ynF4uw" hash="SC49WQ">The precious gift of your body enables you to exercise your agency and put your faith and obedience into action. Have you ever noticed that nearly all of Satan’s attacks are directed at your body? Pornography, immodesty, tattoos, immorality, drug abuse, and addictions are all efforts to take possession of this precious gift. This was a gift that was denied Satan. Obedience to the commandments and standards enables each of you to be steadfast and immovable in protecting the precious gifts of your agency and your body.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places.p11" pid="01uDtkJw-kO61pUiUsoNeQ" hash="deJaag">Being steadfast and immovable also means that you keep moving forward with “a steadfastness in Christ” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.20" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 31:20</a>). Several years ago, I had the opportunity to run the Boston Marathon. I had trained hard and felt I was prepared, but at mile 20 there are hills. The locals call the steepest and longest hill Heartbreak Hill. When I reached that point, I was physically spent. The hill was long, and because I was a novice, I allowed myself to do something no seasoned runner ever does—I started to think negatively. This slowed my pace, so I tried to think positively and visualize the finish line. But as I did this, I suddenly realized that I was in a big city, there were thousands of people lining the route, and I had not made any arrangements to locate my husband at the end of the marathon. I felt lost and alone, and I started to cry. I was wearing a big red T-shirt with the word <span class="emphasis">Utah</span> printed on the front in big block letters. As the spectators saw that I was crying, they would yell, “Keep going, Utah.” “Don’t cry, Utah.” “You’re almost finished, Utah.” But I knew I wasn’t, and I was lost. I also knew that even if I stopped running and dropped out of the race, I would still be lost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places.p12" pid="52Y9g0A_40GzdMW-C1UiRQ" hash="vFzO0Q">Do any of you ever feel like you’re running up Heartbreak Hill and that even though there are people lining <span class="pageBreak" page-number="118"></span>the route, you are alone? That’s how I felt. So I did what every one of you would do—I began to pray right there on that marathon route. I told Heavenly Father that I was alone and that I was on a hill. I told Him that I was discouraged and afraid and that I felt lost. I asked for help and strength to be steadfast and to finish the race. As I continued to run, these words came into my mind:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="JmNNuFgvk0SlZVW9a7wAIw" hash="JiafUw">
            <span class="emphasis">Fear not, I am with thee; oh, be not dismayed,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="2FFNgB9SLkGU2n4c1SuBwg" hash="Ba8YjA">
            <span class="emphasis">For I am thy God and will still give thee aid.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="B0AzfbXGZ0Wg8DfYZiCMxg" hash="xaF1rA">
            <span class="emphasis">I’ll strengthen thee, help thee, and cause thee to stand,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="_7E-zL3-a0WoaEQLvttAnA" hash="bamq-A">
            <span class="emphasis">Upheld by my righteous, omnipotent hand.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places.p13" pid="NAXshvFtJE-AClNzhbrx_g" hash="lOCcFA">That sweet answer to my prayer gave me the strength to continue on until I crossed the finish line. And despite my fears, my husband was right there and all was well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places.p14" pid="jTmxlx-L_Ea4b-uED6N8HQ" hash="uw0NsQ">That day I experienced more than a marathon. I learned some important lessons. First of all, never wear a big red shirt with the word <span class="emphasis">Utah</span> printed on it. Second, I learned that no matter how well prepared you think you are, there are hills on the course. I learned that people cheering for you along the way are absolutely essential. I learned again that day that we are never alone. Our Heavenly Father is only a prayer away, and the Holy Ghost is within whispering distance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places.p15" pid="F3fQaAJY8EGEdFoe-KpcNA" hash="-AJqTg">I testify that as you stand as a witness, obey the commandments, and press forward with “a steadfastness in Christ,” you will never be alone. You can rely on the enabling power of the Savior’s Atonement. And I testify that building on this firm foundation will help you to become like Him—steadfast and immovable at all times, in all things, and in all places. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2008/04/at-all-times-in-all-things-and-in-all-places</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2008-general-young-women-meeting/2008-03-0020-elaine-s-dalton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5063651" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2008 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Return to Virtue</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2008/10/a-return-to-virtue?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Now is the time for each of us to arise and unfurl a banner to the world calling for a return to virtue.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/a-return-to-virtue" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00009501_000_026" doc-version="2" hash="aAvPgQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/a-return-to-virtue.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="fYYf6ehtvkSie2W86V2gKw" hash="Rtk8xw">A Return to Virtue</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Kq8N6T2_JEK6kZAShiGujQ" hash="0nm0pw">Elaine S. Dalton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="iMWowFR-n0qVm-HVFVv-0A" hash="_n2Zmg">Now is the time for each of us to arise and unfurl a banner to the world calling for a return to virtue.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/a-return-to-virtue.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/a-return-to-virtue.p1" pid="Y1QgpKOJ90aSyTR7i1i7MA" hash="lwkYng">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="78"></span>Last general conference, I was called by President Monson to be the new Young Women general president. As I stood in the presence of a prophet of God and was given this sacred trust, I pledged that I would serve with all my heart, might, mind, and strength. Prior to this calling, I had a small plate inscribed with a motto that read, “I can do hard things.” That little plate bearing that simple motto gave me courage. But now if I could change that motto, it would read: “In the strength of the Lord, I can do <span class="emphasis">all</span> things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> It is on that strength that I rely today as I stand at this sacred pulpit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/a-return-to-virtue.p2" pid="FsSAHR12SEiKfir-Ko5QMA" hash="fpxv3Q">Last April, two days after general conference, we held our first meeting as a newly sustained presidency. We hiked to the top of Ensign Peak, and as we looked on the valley below, we saw the temple with the angel Moroni shining in the sun. For each of us, it was clear. The vision for our presidency was the temple. And our responsibility was also clear. We must “help prepare each young woman to be worthy to make and keep sacred covenants and receive the ordinances of the temple.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/a-return-to-virtue.p3" pid="MPm8WC0kOkC8CNGIxFscoQ" hash="6zB4tg">The temple is the reason for everything we do in the Church.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> The temple was the reason our pioneer ancestors left their established homes and came west. It was the reason they suffered privation and even death. Temple covenants were the reason that, although babies were buried along the way, those pioneers could sing:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/a-return-to-virtue.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="MvqzHoinwUK-9h_H2N7V9Q" hash="vaQXUw">
            <span class="emphasis">Come, come, ye Saints,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="CnlJsm7CVEqxUWgiq5J2eg" hash="M-IoiQ">
            <span class="emphasis">No toil nor labor fear;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="PC0lQvxM80uVYe8h_6ZGEw" hash="bE50mQ">
            <span class="emphasis">But with joy wend your way.</span>
            <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/a-return-to-virtue.p4" pid="7Z_vT7ra706KqERUd1T4nQ" hash="qnooqA">Some lost everything but came into the valley with <span class="emphasis">everything,</span> really—temple ordinances, sacred covenants, and the promise of eternal life together as families.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/a-return-to-virtue.p5" pid="KE3T6BO7_UO_FQf1B_je5Q" hash="KAK-Zg">Just two days after the Saints arrived in the Salt Lake Valley, Brigham Young and his associates hiked Ensign Peak. Atop that peak they unfurled a banner—a yellow bandana tied to a walking stick, which symbolized an ensign or standard to the nations.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> The Saints were to be the light, the standard. Last April, atop Ensign Peak, we three women also <span class="pageBreak" page-number="79"></span>unfurled a banner which we made from a walking stick and a gold Peruvian shawl. It was <span class="emphasis">our</span> ensign, <span class="emphasis">our</span> standard to the nations—<span class="emphasis">our</span> banner calling for a return to virtue.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/a-return-to-virtue.p6" pid="V46Q28VZhEisHoTsOFJ0JA" hash="uJ0lDQ">Virtue is a prerequisite to entering the Lord’s holy temples and to receiving the Spirit’s guidance. Virtue “is a pattern of thought and behavior based on high moral standards.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> It encompasses chastity and moral purity. Virtue begins in the heart and in the mind. It is nurtured in the home. It is the accumulation of thousands of small decisions and actions. <span class="emphasis">Virtue</span> is a word we don’t hear often in today’s society, but the Latin root word <span class="emphasis">virtus </span>means strength. Virtuous women and men possess a quiet dignity and inner strength. They are confident because they are worthy to receive and be guided by the Holy Ghost. President Monson has counseled: “<span class="emphasis">You</span> be the one to make a stand for right, even if you stand alone. Have the moral courage to be a light for others to follow. There is no friendship more valuable than your own clear conscience, your own moral cleanliness—and what a glorious feeling it is to know that you stand in your appointed place clean and with the confidence that you are worthy to do so.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/a-return-to-virtue.p7" pid="4ehA9TX4P0W3iAp3EEtQVQ" hash="ZjyI4A">Could it be that we have been slowly desensitized into thinking that high moral standards are old-fashioned and not relevant or important in today’s society? As Elder Hales has just reminded us, Lehonti in the Book of Mormon was well positioned on the top of a mountain. He and those he led were “fixed in their minds with a determined resolution” that they would not come down from the mount. It only took the deceitful Amalickiah four tries, each one more bold than the previous, to get Lehonti to “come down off from the mount.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> And then having embraced Amalickiah’s false promises, Lehonti was “poison[ed] by degrees”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> until he died. Not just poisoned, but “by degrees.” Could it be that this may be happening today? Could it be that first we tolerate, then accept, and eventually embrace the vice that surrounds us?<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Could it be that we have been deceived by false role models and persuasive media messages that cause us to forget our divine identity? Are we too being poisoned by degrees? What could be more deceptive than to entice the youth of this noble generation to do nothing or to be busy ever-texting but never coming to a knowledge of the truths contained in a book that was written for you and your day by prophets of God—the Book of Mormon? What could be more deceptive than to entice women, young and old, you and me, to be so involved in ourselves, our looks, our clothes, our body shape and size that we lose sight of our divine identity and our ability to change the world through our virtuous influence? What could be more deceptive than to entice men—young and old, holding the holy priesthood of God—to view seductive pornography and thus focus on flesh instead of faith, to be consumers of vice rather than guardians of virtue? The Book of Mormon relates the story of 2,000 young heroes whose virtue and purity gave them the strength to defend their parents’ covenants and their family’s faith. Their virtue and commitment to be “true at all times” changed the world!<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/a-return-to-virtue.p8" pid="5rDzCIjkBESv5d9aA-VSOg" hash="zsnuiA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="80"></span>I truly believe that one virtuous young woman or young man, led by the Spirit, can change the world, but in order to do so, we must return to virtue. We must engage in strict training. As the marathon runner Juma Ikangaa said after winning the New York Marathon, “The will to win is nothing without the will to prepare.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Now is the time to prepare by exercising more self-discipline. Now is the time to become “more fit for the kingdom.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> Now is the time to set our course and focus on the finish. A return to virtue must begin individually in our hearts and in our homes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/a-return-to-virtue.p9" pid="xx9YO65QCU-6IIUEx4536w" hash="kUUPxA">What can each of us do to begin our return to virtue? The course and the training program will be unique to each of us. I have derived my personal training program from instructions found in the scriptures: “Let virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> “Cleave unto [your] covenants.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> “Stand … in holy places.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> “Lay aside the things of [the] world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> “Believe that ye must repent.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> “Always remember him and keep his commandments.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> And “if there is anything virtuous, lovely, or of good report or praiseworthy, … seek after these things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> Now more than ever before, it is time to respond to Moroni’s call to “awake, and arise” and to “lay hold upon every good gift, and touch not the evil gift, nor the unclean thing.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/a-return-to-virtue.p10" pid="VRCO3RdZ1k6PIPdCyaLr4A" hash="_XyYlA">Recently I attended the blessing of our newest granddaughter. It was a holy sight to me as my husband and our sons, along with many other loved ones, encircled this little infant. She was so elegant all dressed in white—and it didn’t hurt a bit that she was named after her two grandmothers! But the thing that touched me most was the blessing given by her father, our son Zach. He blessed little Annabel Elaine that she would understand her identity as a daughter of God, that she would follow the examples of her mother, grandmothers, and sister, and that she would find great joy as she lived a virtuous life and prepared to make and keep sacred temple covenants. In that sacred moment, I prayed that <span class="emphasis">every</span> young woman might be encircled, strengthened, and protected by righteous priesthood power, not only at the time of birth and blessing but throughout life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/a-return-to-virtue.p11" pid="QEsez0fylku6NzUzTNdm2Q" hash="-BGV3A">During the solemn assembly last conference when President Uchtdorf called for the sustaining of our new prophet and First Presidency, I watched the entire congregation of priesthood brethren arise and stand. I felt your strength and your priesthood power. You are the guardians of virtue. Then I was overcome with emotion when he said, “Will the young women please arise?” From my seat, I saw all of you arise and stand together. Today there could be no more powerful force for virtue in the world. You must never underestimate the power of your righteous influence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/a-return-to-virtue.p12" pid="QPKh9TGlUEGhI3fpPCFOhQ" hash="-VtMQQ">I testify that a return to virtue is possible because of the Savior’s example and the “infinite virtue of His great atoning sacrifice.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> I testify that we will be enabled and strengthened not only to do hard things but to do <span class="emphasis">all </span>things. Now is the time for each of us to arise and unfurl a banner to the world calling for a return to virtue. May we so live that we can be instruments in preparing the earth for His Second Coming, “that when he shall appear we shall be like him, … <span class="emphasis">purified</span> even as he is pure.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2008/10/a-return-to-virtue</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2008-general-conference/2008-10-4040-elaine-s-dalton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5395055" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remember Who You Are!</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are?lang=eng</link>
      <description>There is no more beautiful sight than a young woman who glows with the light of the Spirit, who is confident and courageous because she is virtuous.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021388_000_047" doc-version="1" hash="7Xsf4w">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="MJdf36iha0aa4EhPRhQ00g" hash="V0XPrA">Remember Who You Are!</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="VGUPBVWa7UCeEPPv-GhR6g" hash="0nm0pw">Elaine S. Dalton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="tskOwlAn2kKEhvKZU1vCmg" hash="3bJqzg">There is no more beautiful sight than a young woman who glows with the light of the Spirit, who is confident and courageous because she is virtuous.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p1" pid="YTj40QuIlEqt7KG_R-8hcw" hash="-zlJ3A">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="120"></span>We <span class="emphasis">are</span> daughters of our Heavenly Father. He loves us, and we love Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> I am humbled and grateful to be in your presence. The Lord has blessed me with a very clear understanding of who you are and why you are here on the earth at this time. The Lord loves you, and I know you love Him. It shows in your countenance, in your modesty, in your desire to choose the right, and in your commitment to remain virtuous and pure.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p2" pid="cF58SO_wv0Ghc-TV2yeoNQ" hash="fdHWjg">Together we have shared many choice spiritual moments. We have borne testimony in camps around campfires, in chapels, and in firesides. We have been warmed by the fire of our faith. We have climbed mountains and unfurled golden banners—from Brazil to Bountiful—signifying the commitment deep within our hearts to remain virtuous and to always be worthy to enter the temple. We have prayed, read the Book of Mormon, and smiled every day, and together with our mothers, grandmothers, and leaders, we are working on our Personal Progress. And we have only just begun!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p3" pid="5sMI5QVzrkixZIsqBjn_BQ" hash="5x6bCg">This is a magnificent time to be on the earth and to be a young woman. Our vision remains the same. It is to be worthy to make and keep sacred covenants and receive the ordinances of the temple. This is our superlative goal! And so we will continue to lead the world in a return to virtue—a return to chastity and moral purity. We will continue to do all we can to help each other “stand … in holy places”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> and receive, recognize, and rely on the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p4" pid="HitINm0kUkCkZMDdezKrvg" hash="59x2zg">We will continue to talk of Christ, to rejoice in Christ, that each of us will know to what source we may look for a remission of our sins.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> And yes, we will continue to stand firm no matter what storms may rage around us because we know and testify that “it is upon the rock of our Redeemer, who is Christ, the Son of God, that [we] must build [our] foundation … , a foundation whereon if [we] build [we] cannot fall.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p5" pid="n3FoS5-cMUyOZ6gtr3F7mw" hash="5GCcyw">The Lord’s counsel to Joshua is His counsel to you today, the “youth of the noble birthright.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> “Be strong and of a good courage; be not afraid, neither be thou dismayed: for the Lord thy God is with thee whithersoever thou goest.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> You are not alone! Though you may be the only Latter-day Saint in your school or your group of friends or even your family, you are not alone. You can rely on the strength of the Lord. As Joshua said to the Israelites, “Sanctify yourselves: for to morrow the Lord will do wonders among you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> This was Joshua’s call for a return to virtue, and it is the same call to us today. We simply cannot do the work we have been reserved and prepared to do unless we can access the strength and confidence that comes by living a virtuous life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p6" pid="YjCm0biUwkS6gEWXMJeg0Q" hash="MueqXA">You are young women of great faith. You brought your faith with you when you came to the earth. Alma teaches us that in the premortal realms you exhibited “exceeding faith and good works.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> You fought with your faith and testimony to defend the plan that was presented by God. You knew the plan was good, and you knew that the Savior would do what He said He would do—because you knew Him! You stood with Him, and you were eager for your opportunity to come to earth. You knew what was going to be required of you. You knew it would be difficult, and yet you were confident not only that you could accomplish your divine mission but that you could make a difference. You <span class="pageBreak" page-number="121"></span>are “choice spirits who were reserved to come forth in the fulness of times to take part in laying the foundations of the great latter-day work, including the building of the temples and the performance of ordinances therein.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p7" pid="kTclWS9aC0Oe6z4xRQ0q5w" hash="uOFm7Q">And now you are here to do what you have been reserved and prepared to do. As I look out at you tonight, I wonder if this is what Helaman’s stripling warriors’ girlfriends must have looked like! No wonder Satan has increased the intensity of his attacks on your identity and virtue. If you can be dismayed, discouraged, distracted, delayed, or disqualified from being worthy to receive the guidance of the Holy Ghost or to enter the Lord’s holy temple, he wins.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p8" pid="V1VnJrcTyUWM7WhntwweEw" hash="kTJlyg">Young women of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, remember who you are! You are elect. You are daughters of God. You cannot be a generation of young women who are content to fit in. You must have the courage to stand out, to “arise and shine forth, that thy light may be a standard for the nations.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> The world would have you believe that you are not significant—that you are out of fashion and out of touch. The world calls to you with unrelenting, noisy voices to “live it up,” “try everything,” “experiment and be happy.” Conversely, the Holy Ghost whispers and the Lord invites you to “walk in the paths of virtue,” “lay aside the things of this world,” “and cleave unto [your] covenants.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p9" pid="AfdkGeDig0ORfLSFywmdbA" hash="KgjlKw">I have always loved the story of the son of King Louis XVI of France because he had an unshakable knowledge of his identity. As a young man, he was kidnapped by evil men who had dethroned his father, the king. These men knew that if they could destroy him morally, he would not be heir to the throne. For six months they subjected him to every vile thing life had to offer, and yet he never yielded under pressure. This puzzled his captors, and after doing everything they could think of, they asked him why he had such great moral strength. His reply was simple. He said, “I cannot do what you ask, for I was born to be a king.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p10" pid="TWep4mjNLk23lHVHaiyG6A" hash="L1W53g">Like the king’s son, each of you has inherited a royal birthright. Each of you has a divine heritage. “You are literally the royal daughters of our Father in Heaven.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> Each of you was born to be a queen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p11" pid="yPWemQdNykaxQAytfd0WZg" hash="mwUckg">When I was attending Brigham Young University, I learned what it truly means to be a queen. I was given a unique opportunity, along with a small group of other students, to meet the prophet, President David O. McKay. I was told to wear my best dress and to be ready to travel early the next morning to Huntsville, Utah, to the home of the prophet. I will never forget the experience I had. As soon as we entered the home, I felt the spirit which filled that home. We were seated in the prophet’s living room, surrounding him. President McKay had on a white suit, and seated next to him was his wife. He asked for each of us to come forward and tell him about ourselves. As I went forward, he held out his hand and held mine, and as I told him about my life and my family, he looked deeply into my eyes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p12" pid="nFUoZ29Z6k2gxbUGM56_bw" hash="WK-g3Q">After we had finished, he leaned <span class="pageBreak" page-number="122"></span>back in his chair and reached for his wife’s hand and said, “Now, young women, I would like you to meet <span class="emphasis">my queen.</span>” There seated next to him was his wife, Emma Ray McKay. Although she did not wear a crown of sparkling diamonds, nor was she seated on a throne, I <span class="emphasis">knew</span> she was a true queen. Her white hair was her crown, and her pure eyes sparkled like jewels. As President and Sister McKay spoke of their family and their life together, their intertwined hands spoke volumes about their love. Joy radiated from their faces. Hers was a beauty that cannot be purchased. It came from years of seeking the best gifts, becoming well educated, seeking knowledge by study and also by faith. It came from years of hard work, of faithfully enduring trials with optimism, trust, strength, and courage. It came from her unwavering devotion and fidelity to her husband, her family, and the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p13" pid="IVYit5pQfEmwrgDAsrmVZg" hash="94-95w">On that fall day in Huntsville, Utah, I was reminded of my divine identity, and I learned about what I now call “deep beauty”—the kind of beauty that shines from the <span class="emphasis">inside</span> out. It is the kind of beauty that cannot be painted on, surgically created, or purchased. It is the kind of beauty that doesn’t wash off. It is <span class="emphasis">spiritual</span> attractiveness. Deep beauty springs from virtue. It is the beauty of being chaste and morally clean. It is the kind of beauty that you see in the eyes of virtuous women like your mother and grandmother. It is a beauty that is earned through faith, repentance, and honoring covenants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p14" pid="b672dPuHD0m7mt4j7_aPTg" hash="KULCNQ">The world places so much emphasis on physical attractiveness and would have you believe that you are to look like the elusive model on the cover of a magazine. The Lord would tell you that you are each uniquely beautiful. When you are virtuous, chaste, and morally clean, your inner beauty glows in your eyes and in your face. My grandfather used to say, “If you live close to God and His infinite grace—you won’t have to tell, it will show in your face.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> When you are worthy of the companionship of the Holy Ghost, you are confident and your inner beauty shines brightly. And so “let virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly; then shall thy confidence wax strong in the presence of God; and … the Holy Ghost shall be thy constant companion.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p15" pid="m96In7mSxUm4oUuTphk7-Q" hash="H3T6yw">We have been taught that “the gift of the Holy Ghost … quickens all the intellectual faculties, increases, enlarges, expands and purifies all the natural passions and affections. … It inspires virtue, kindness, goodness, tenderness, gentleness and charity. <span class="emphasis">It develops beauty of person, form and features.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> Now, that is a great beauty secret! That is the beauty I observed in the home of a prophet. That day I learned that the beauty I saw in Sister McKay was the only beauty that really matters and the only kind of beauty that lasts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p16" pid="_9_draqWFkuJTygLEctVSQ" hash="mUdzVw">Alma asks a penetrating question for each of us to consider: “Have [you] received his image in your countenances?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p17" pid="9y4lpSssdEyngtR1gzlyOQ" hash="3eUiJA">Recently, a group of young women visited my office. At the end of the visit, one young woman confided with tears in her eyes, “I have never thought of myself as beautiful. I have always felt very ordinary. But today, as I walked past the mirror in your office and glanced into it, I was beautiful!” She <span class="emphasis">was</span> beautiful because her face shone with the Spirit. She saw herself as our Heavenly Father sees her. She had received His image in her countenance. That is deep beauty.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p18" pid="4Ht7QyEt60enIoaa7BB-tw" hash="kf3sQQ">Young women, look into the mirror of eternity. Remember who you are! See yourself as our Heavenly Father sees you. You are elect. You are of noble birth. Don’t compromise your divine inheritance. You were born to be a queen. Live so you are worthy to enter the temple and there receive “all that [the] Father hath.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> Develop deep beauty. There is no more beautiful sight than a young woman who glows with the light of the Spirit, who is confident and courageous because she is virtuous.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p19" pid="RzVn8wMBMkec4ZfOEgzo5w" hash="XZHT5g">Remember, you are daughters of our Heavenly Father. He loves you so <span class="pageBreak" page-number="123"></span>much that He sent His Son to show you the way to live, so that you could return to Him someday. I testify that as you draw close to the Savior, His infinite Atonement makes it possible for you to repent, to change, to be pure, and to receive His image in your countenance. His Atonement will enable you to be strong and courageous as you continue to raise your banner for virtue. You are golden. You <span class="emphasis">are</span> the banner!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are.p20" pid="tw6kbfz57USRpOUg3E80cQ" hash="jSqYgg">And so I conclude with the Lord’s words to each of us, His precious daughters: “Behold, … thou art an elect lady, whom I have called.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> “Walk in the paths of virtue. … Lay aside the things of [the] world. … Cleave unto the covenants which thou hast made. … Keep my commandments continually, and a crown of righteousness thou shalt receive.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> Of this I bear my witness in the holy name of our Savior, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/04/remember-who-you-are</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2010-general-young-women-meeting/2010-03-0040-elaine-s-dalton-64k-eng.mp3" length="6903702" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2010 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guardians of Virtue</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Prepare now so that you may qualify to receive all the blessings that await you in the Lord’s holy temples.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50028768_000_0040" doc-version="1" hash="XwgJVw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.head1">
    <h1 class="title" pid="zoyMycCbvkCIrPEZuspqUw" hash="ErSCOQ">Guardians of Virtue</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="TxBJ_lLs8Emakq8Y9RRDhA" hash="0nm0pw">Elaine S. Dalton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="dE-M4uOw9kOInuLWOwyUXg" hash="qgmYAA">Prepare now so that you may qualify to receive all the blessings that await you in the Lord’s holy temples.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p1" pid="qJf8ndrpsEOB7eMIaHs5iQ" hash="K8lQvA">There are times when words cannot express what we feel. I pray that the Spirit will witness to your hearts your divine identity and your eternal responsibility. You are the hope of Israel. You are elect and royal daughters of our loving Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p2" pid="KEmMICbIL02d1oMqi_jlDg" hash="7cF3Gg">Last month I had the opportunity to attend the temple wedding of a young woman I have known since she was born. As I sat in the sealing room, looking at the beautiful chandelier sparkling in the light of the temple, I remembered that day when I first held her. Her mother had her dressed in a little white dress, and I thought she was one of the most beautiful babies I had ever seen. Then this young woman walked through the door, once again dressed in white. She was radiant and happy. As she entered the room, I wished with all my heart that every young woman could envision that moment and strive to always be worthy to make and keep sacred covenants and receive the ordinances of the temple in preparation to enjoy the blessings of exaltation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p3" pid="s7l38z4c8E6Y1FXQSJ0O5w" hash="TW7mLg">As this couple knelt at the sacred altar, they received promises beyond mortal comprehension that will bless, strengthen, and assist them on their mortal journey. It was one of those moments when the world stood still and all of heaven rejoiced. As the newly married couple looked into the large mirrors in the room, the groom was asked what he saw. He said, “All those who have gone before me.” Then the couple looked into the large mirror on the opposite wall, and the bride said with tears in her eyes, “I see all those who will follow after us.” She saw her future family—her posterity. I know that she understood again in that moment how important it is to believe in being chaste and virtuous. There is no more beautiful sight than a couple, properly prepared, kneeling together at the altar of the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p4" pid="RY1cCmkDW0Gazuum9C1dhw" hash="wz_LEw">Your years in Young Women will prepare you for the temple. There you will receive the blessings to which you are entitled as a precious daughter of God. Your Heavenly Father loves you and wants you to be happy. The way to do this is to “walk in the paths of virtue”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> and “cleave unto [your] covenants.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p5" pid="_wolR9D9e0mRvAW8q3YjTQ" hash="2YdAAQ">Young women, in a world ever growing in moral pollution, tolerance of evil, exploitation of women, and distortion of roles, you must stand guard of yourself, your family, and all those with whom you associate. You must be guardians of virtue.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p6" pid="CKlLlxNOlkGd06j9woacpQ" hash="-OAWLA">What is virtue and what is a guardian? “Virtue is a pattern of thought and behavior based on high moral standards. It includes chastity and [moral] purity.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> And what is a guardian? A guardian is someone who protects, shields, and defends.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Thus, as a guardian of virtue, you will protect, shield, and defend moral purity because the power to create mortal life is a sacred and exalted power and must be safeguarded until you are married. Virtue is a requirement to have the companionship and guidance of the Holy Ghost. You will need that guidance in order to successfully navigate the world in which you live. Being virtuous is a requirement to enter the temple. And it is a requirement to be worthy to stand in the Savior’s presence. You are preparing now for that time. Personal Progress and the standards found in <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth</span> are important. Living the principles found in each booklet will strengthen and help you become “more fit for the kingdom.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p7" pid="I22wygrb_UCQ2h9IUU5nsg" hash="8KnA5A">Last summer a group of young women from Alpine, Utah, decided that they would become “more fit for the kingdom.” They determined to focus on the temple by walking from the Draper Utah Temple to the Salt Lake Temple, a total distance of 22 miles (35 km), just as one of the pioneers, John Rowe Moyle, had done. Brother Moyle was a stonemason who was called by the prophet, Brigham Young, to work on the Salt Lake Temple. Each week he walked the distance of 22 miles from his home to the temple. One of his jobs was to carve the words “Holiness to the Lord” on the east side of the Salt Lake Temple. It was not easy and he had many obstacles to overcome. At one point, he was kicked in the leg by one of his cows. Because it would not heal, he had to have this leg amputated. But that did not stop him from his commitment to the prophet and to work on the temple. He carved a wooden leg, and after many weeks he again walked the 22-mile distance to the temple to do the work he had committed to do.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p8" pid="FsggKb54VEq_KLbaIqS6rw" hash="XWSlzg">The young women in the Cedar Hills Sixth Ward decided to walk that same distance for an ancestor and also for someone who was their inspiration to remain worthy to enter the temple. They trained each week at Mutual, and as they walked, they shared what they were learning and feeling about temples.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p9" pid="hsFjlOrdokKRr9cBw3OH2g" hash="U75_ew">They began their walk to the temple early in the morning with a prayer. As they started out, I was impressed with their confidence. They had prepared well, and they knew they were prepared. Their eyes were set on their goal. Each step they took was symbolic of each of you as you too are preparing now to enter the temple. Your personal training has begun with your daily personal prayers, your daily reading of the Book of Mormon, and your working on Personal Progress.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p10" pid="cvcguXg8REaNrvaMnoXuSg" hash="M1ArJQ">As these young women continued to walk, there were distractions along the course, but they stayed focused on their goal. Some began to feel blisters forming, and others felt knees starting to protest, but they kept going. For each of you, there are many distractions, hurts, and obstacles along your path to the temple, but you too are determined and keep going. The route these young women took was mapped out by their leaders, who had walked and driven the course and determined the safest and most direct way to go. Again, your course is marked, and you can be assured that the Savior has not only walked the course but will again walk it with you—every step of the way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p11" pid="fWJfeA2j9kys_sjuM6PFJg" hash="j5pz1Q">Along this journey to the temple there were fathers, mothers, family members, and priesthood leaders acting as guardians. Their job was to ensure that everyone was safe and protected from danger. They made sure each young woman stayed well hydrated and had enough nourishment to maintain her stamina. There were aid stations provided by their priesthood leaders, with places to rest and to drink water. Young women, your fathers, your mothers, your bishops, and so many others will be your guardians as you walk your path to the temple. They will call out cautions and direct your course, and should you become injured or hurt or get off course, they will help you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p12" pid="cMkgm2L_8kmTSJEQIgZuQg" hash="uRJH6A">I was impressed that in the final miles of their walk, brothers, other young men, and friends came to support these determined young women and to cheer them on. One brother lifted his sister, who had large blisters on her feet, and carried her on his back the final distance to the temple. As these incredible young women reached their goal, tears were shed as they touched the temple and made a silent commitment to always be worthy to enter there.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p13" pid="GwMzMeq2w0WRBKUDjszNow" hash="t4QP6A">The temple walk is a metaphor for your life. Parents and priesthood leaders stood guard along the route. They provided support and aid. Young women guarded and encouraged each other. Young men admired the strength, commitment, and stamina of the young women. Brothers carried sisters who had been injured. Families rejoiced with their daughters as they ended their walk at the temple and took them safely home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p14" pid="nMoodzP5_USoijdm922afQ" hash="y83_tg">In order to stay on the path to the temple, you must guard your personal virtue and the virtue of others with whom you associate. Why? Mormon taught in the Book of Mormon that virtue and chastity are “most dear and precious above all things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p15" pid="Y3Grds8h2kOXyVR0auYUDA" hash="fz5YVg">What can each of you do to be a guardian of virtue? It starts with believing you can make a difference. It starts with making a commitment. When I was a young woman, I learned that some decisions need to be made only once. I wrote my list of things I would <span class="emphasis">always </span>do and things I would <span class="emphasis">never </span>do in a small tablet. It included things like obeying the Word of Wisdom, praying daily, paying my tithing, and committing to never miss church. I made those decisions once, and then in the moment of decision, I knew exactly what to do because I had decided beforehand. When my high school friends said, “Just one drink won’t hurt,” I laughed and said, “I decided when I was 12 not to do that.” Making decisions in advance will help you be guardians of virtue. I hope each of you will write a list of things you will <span class="emphasis">always </span>do and things you will <span class="emphasis">never </span>do. Then live your list.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p16" pid="6Os2LZYBA0WxpI1OvGUj7Q" hash="LNNiAw">Being a guardian of virtue means you will always be modest not only in your dress but also in your speech, your actions, and your use of social media. Being a guardian of virtue means you will never text words or images to young men that may cause them to lose the Spirit, lose their priesthood power, or lose their virtue. It means that you understand the importance of chastity because you also understand that your body is a temple and that the sacred powers of procreation are not to be tampered with before marriage. You understand that you possess a sacred power that involves the holy responsibility of bringing other spirits to earth to receive a body in which to house their eternal spirit. This power involves another sacred soul. You are a guardian of something “more precious than rubies.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Be faithful. Be obedient. Prepare now so that you may qualify to receive all the blessings that await you in the Lord’s holy temples.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p17" pid="tObsfwKi-UWfJi3y_UVzeQ" hash="JBm6iw">For the mothers listening tonight, you are your daughters’ most important example of modesty and virtue—thank you. Never hesitate to teach them that they are royal daughters of God and that their value is not based on their sensual appeal. And let them see your belief modeled correctly and consistently in your own personal attitude and appearance.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> You are also guardians of virtue.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p18" pid="u7d23sRpUEC7E728TFqrxA" hash="xQix3Q">This week I again climbed Ensign Peak. It was early in the morning, and as I looked down from that mount at the mountain of the Lord’s house—the Salt Lake Temple—it was again crystal clear. The pioneers gave everything they had to come to the tops of the mountains so that you and I could have the blessings of the temple and be sealed eternally as families. Forty years of sacrifice, painstaking work, and even walking from Alpine to the temple—why? Because, like you, they believed! They believed in a prophet. They believed he had seen and talked with God and His Beloved Son. They believed in the Savior. They believed in the Book of Mormon. That’s why they could say, “We believe all things, we hope all things, we have endured many things, and hope to be able to endure all things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> They endured many things and so can we. The thirteenth article of faith is what we believe because those are the very things that qualify us to be worthy to enter the temple and to one day stand in our Heavenly Father’s presence—proven, pure, and sealed. This will require that you be “more fit for the kingdom” and that you prepare now and gain the confidence that you can do hard things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p19" pid="FIO0wMvAv0ONHfeo7OSbEA" hash="wlu5jw">Young women, you are engaged in a great work! And you are not alone! As you guard your virtue and purity, you will be given strength. As you keep the covenants you have made, the Holy Ghost will guide and guard you. You will be surrounded by heavenly hosts of angels. President Thomas S. Monson reminds us, “Remember that we do not run alone in this great race of life; we are entitled to the help of the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> Prepare for that day when you will come to the Lord’s temple worthy and prepared to make sacred covenants. As guardians of virtue, you will want to <span class="emphasis">seek </span>the Savior in His holy house.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue.p20" pid="F9Wf9isZKk6t5runUzW4nA" hash="-qb3oQ">I testify that God lives and that His Beloved Son, our Redeemer, Jesus Christ, lives and because of the redeeming and enabling power of His infinite Atonement, each of you will be guided and guarded on your path to the temple and back into Their presence. I pray that each of you will be strengthened for that work which will be your finest hour. Live for that beautiful day spoken of in the book of Revelation when you will “walk … in white: [because you] are worthy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/04/guardians-of-virtue</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2011-general-young-women-meeting/2011-03-0040-elaine-s-dalton-64k-eng.mp3" length="7226426" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Love Her Mother</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother?lang=eng</link>
      <description>How can a father raise a happy, well-adjusted daughter in today’s increasingly toxic world? The answer has been taught by the Lord’s prophets.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50029123_000_4040" doc-version="2" hash="tjHwRg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="7iXwEHtDNUO04M4f8ILwEQ" hash="UFLV7g">Love Her Mother</h1><p class="authorName" guid="96d469fa-ea3d-4b8b-ad3a-cd03b387ee06" pid="3e9S_heagkGFiQRcEWJJiA" hash="0nm0pw">Elaine S. Dalton</p><p class="kicker" pid="iuCt-HJw5kmSVYq8QZY1JQ" hash="rQeUVg">How can a father raise a happy, well-adjusted daughter in today’s increasingly toxic world? The answer has been taught by the Lord’s prophets.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="5b85d615-8ac7-46b7-b36d-d8045156b99e">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.p1" guid="800f8cd6-3576-4e37-920e-0225dff550d7" pid="KJ7y4ekqykSGXB3emKIOCg" hash="F_tjbA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="77"></span>No words describe the sacred occasion when a new father holds a baby daughter in his arms for the first time. This year three of our sons have become new fathers of baby girls. As I watched our rugged, strong, rugby-playing son, Jon, hold his first baby daughter in his arms, he looked at her with a reverent tenderness, and then he looked at me with an expression that seemed to say, “How do I raise a girl?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.p2" guid="77f6d563-77e4-4a70-9b66-21a6b4d1fae5" pid="eDUi-VhOfkSyhldteAPO_w" hash="s7YDqQ">This morning I would like to speak to our sons and to all fathers. How can a father raise a happy, well-adjusted daughter in today’s increasingly toxic world? The answer has been taught by the Lord’s prophets. It is a simple answer, and it is true—“The most important thing a father can do for his [daughter] is to love [her] mother.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> By the way you love her mother, you will teach your daughter about tenderness, loyalty, respect, compassion, and devotion. She will learn from your example what to expect from young men and what qualities to seek in a future spouse. You can show your daughter by the way you love and honor your wife that she should never settle for less. Your example will teach your daughter to value womanhood. You are showing her that she is a daughter of our Heavenly Father, who loves her.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.p3" guid="340f3415-1d09-4254-a3cb-436c799f96df" pid="2RXmT3B5LECqlmZnJDhWBA" hash="Ie8CcQ">Love her mother so much that your marriage is celestial. A temple marriage for time and all eternity is worthy of your greatest efforts and highest priority. It was only after Nephi had completed the temple in the wilderness that he stated, “And … we lived after the manner of happiness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> The “manner of happiness” is found in the temple. It is covenant keeping. Don’t let any influence come into your life or your home that would cause you to compromise your covenants or your commitment to your wife and family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.p4" guid="645158df-e695-4569-af7e-934b9b67a999" pid="Z7dkIg8vuEmUnuEw-oWGDA" hash="fCu4aA">In Young Women we are helping your daughter understand her identity as a daughter of God and the importance of remaining virtuous and worthy to receive the blessings of the temple and of a temple marriage. We are teaching your daughter the importance of making and keeping sacred covenants. We are teaching her to commit now to live so that she can always be worthy to enter the temple and not to allow anything to delay, distract, or disqualify her from that goal. Your example, as her father, speaks louder than our important words. Young women worry about their fathers. Many express that their greatest desire is to be united eternally as a family. They want you to be there when they go to the temple or get married in the temple. Stay close to your daughter and help her prepare and remain worthy for the temple. When she turns 12, take her with you to the temple often to perform baptisms for your ancestors and others. She will cherish these memories forever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.p5" guid="0f9e73e3-b857-4481-be7a-12cae4778f7e" pid="Tf9MmRj030C-VXWiuUBYJw" hash="SG6XNw">Today’s popular culture tries to erode and demean your eternal role as a patriarch and father and minimize your most important responsibilities. These have been given to you “by divine design,” and as fathers you “are to preside over [your] families in love and righteousness and are responsible to provide the necessities of life and protection for [your] families.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.p6" guid="4f67fa60-2ecb-4ed2-a61d-31e246a60c2e" pid="sIENOKuxuUaq-VQ-ASf1Hg" hash="DKSsZQ">Fathers, you are the guardians of your homes, your wives, and your children. Today “it is not an easy thing to protect one’s family against intrusions of evil into [their] minds and spirits. … These influences can and do flow freely into the home. Satan [is very clever]. He need not break down the door.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.p7" guid="fc5cf6e8-b5ca-4bb1-ad6d-eb7802e74425" pid="8MiNYOLr5Eu87YwPGOsp8Q" hash="Mqml4Q">You must be the guardians of virtue. “A priesthood holder is <span class="emphasis">virtuous.</span> Virtuous behavior implies that [you have] pure thoughts and clean actions. … Virtue is … an attribute of <span class="pageBreak" page-number="78"></span>godliness.” It “is akin to holiness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> The Young Women values are Christlike attributes which include the value of virtue. We now call upon you to join with us in leading the world in a return to virtue. In order to do so, you “must practise virtue and holiness”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> by eliminating from your life anything that is evil and inconsistent with one who holds the holy priesthood of God. “Let virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly; then shall thy confidence wax strong in the presence of God; and … the Holy Ghost shall be thy constant companion.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> So be cautious about what you view in entertainment media or print. Your personal virtue will model for your daughters, and also your sons, what true strength and moral courage are. By being a guardian of virtue in your own life, in your home, and in the lives of your children, you are showing your wife and daughters what true love really is. Your personal purity will give you power.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.p8" guid="2049712f-a4db-40ca-9b7a-0dc1e448a2e1" pid="NhLXZWYfUkaXwH125gxH2g" hash="lZmATg">You are your daughter’s guardian in more than the legal sense. Be present in your daughter’s life. Let her know your standards, your expectations, your hopes and dreams for her success and happiness. Interview her, get to know her friends and, when the time comes, her boyfriends. Help her understand the importance of education. Help her understand that the principle of modesty is a protection. Help her choose music and media that invite the Spirit and are consistent with her divine identity. Be an active part of her life. And if in her teenage years she should not come home from a date on time, go get her. She will resist and tell you that you have ruined her social life, but she will inwardly know that you love her and that you care enough to be her guardian.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.p9" guid="5e73af94-2efa-47c6-ab5d-cf59f558427f" pid="wjtBA5m5t0mlKf2VBlJWaw" hash="xOmIaA">You are not ordinary men. Because of your valiance in the premortal realms, you qualified to be leaders and to possess priesthood power. There you exhibited “exceeding faith and good works,” and you are here now to do the same.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Your priesthood sets you apart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.p10" guid="a4910d70-cb90-4956-9288-09721dda34c9" pid="uApqxiIVskemZ_TSIlIUCQ" hash="pnr_nA">Within a few weeks our three sons will have given their baby daughters a name and a blessing. I hope this will be the first of many priesthood blessings they receive from their fathers, because in the world in which they will grow up, they will need those blessings. Your daughter will cherish the priesthood and determine in her heart that this is what she wants in her future home and family. Always remember “that the rights of the priesthood are inseparably connected with the powers of heaven” and can “be controlled … only upon the principles of righteousness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.p11" guid="0a8be3d5-0340-411f-9077-88677013873c" pid="cyaPpkEtFU6zlMbGw-_-iA" hash="ZoGpVQ">Fathers, you are your daughter’s hero. My father was my hero. I used to wait on the steps of our home for him to arrive each night. He would pick me up and twirl me around and let me put my feet on top of his big shoes, and then he would dance me into the house. I loved the challenge of trying to follow his every footstep. I still do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.p12" guid="83ad5ce1-64fd-4973-8fb6-4bf6d691b26f" pid="2f1KYfzJjE27ik8EI10HjA" hash="-A5zwQ">Did you know that your testimony has a powerful influence on your daughters? I knew my father had a testimony. I knew he loved the Lord. And because my father loved the Lord, I did too. I knew he cared about the widows because he took his vacation to paint the home of the widow who lived next door. I thought that was the greatest vacation our family ever had because he taught me how to paint! You will bless the life of your daughter for years to come if you will look for ways to spend time with her and to share your testimony with her.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.p13" guid="76626d68-96ef-4fd3-a349-64bc7375ebb3" pid="4-_lZc7UHEqDIarOPISWIg" hash="TGG8qw">In the Book of Mormon, Abish was converted by her father’s sharing with her his remarkable vision. For many years thereafter, she kept her testimony in her heart and lived righteously in a very wicked society. Then the time came when she could no longer be still, and she ran from house to house to share her testimony and the miracles she had witnessed in the king’s court. The power of Abish’s conversion and testimony was instrumental in changing an entire society. The people who heard her testify became a people who “were converted unto the Lord, [and] never did fall away,” and their sons became the stripling warriors!<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.p14" guid="5ca20415-63a4-42af-8f97-6c097d780cf2" pid="AYWxv46_40OCkw_SqgOW3w" hash="GYs0DA">As the hymn says, “Rise up, O men <span class="pageBreak" page-number="79"></span>of God!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> This is a call to you, the men who bear the holy priesthood of God. May it be said of you as was said of Captain Moroni:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.p15" guid="7b4c5851-9891-493b-98db-bc6a0a45414b" pid="SQ_Rrc6vOUSkbCqjwGUVbA" hash="AFUFXQ">“[He] was a strong and a mighty man; … a man of a perfect understanding; … a man who was firm in the faith of Christ. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.p16" guid="3ad7fb48-bee6-42cf-a595-3200b523fe17" pid="bna_ec3fK0iBqOUj2xALbA" hash="5q0ncw">“… If all men had been, and were, and ever would be, like unto Moroni, behold, the very powers of hell would have been shaken forever; … the devil would never have power over the hearts of the children of men.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.p17" guid="98ca0437-1a40-4e4a-ac78-086c3388fa90" pid="-hagHn5hIk-_3L3xomHRsw" hash="fQL4OQ">Brethren, fathers, young men, “Be loyal to the royal within you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother.p18" guid="ff1c37ef-41b1-4f36-bb0f-7770fd3094f6" pid="eGhaoiLQ30icZVCARUJIoA" hash="2SL9DQ">So how do you raise a girl? Love her mother. Lead your family to the temple, be guardians of virtue, and magnify your priesthood. Fathers, you have been entrusted with our Heavenly Father’s royal daughters. They are virtuous and elect. It is my prayer that you will watch over them, strengthen them, model virtuous behavior, and teach them to follow in the Savior’s every footstep—for He lives! In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/10/love-her-mother</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2011-general-conference/2011-10-4040-elaine-s-dalton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5196420" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2011 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Now Is the Time to Arise and Shine!</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As daughters of God, you were born to lead.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10485_000_63dalto" doc-version="1" hash="pj9i9Q"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="DEx6bMk3KEy0kPz4TTZwcQ" hash="cvn8Ag">Now Is the Time to Arise and Shine!</h1><p class="authorName" pid="iM6g2A_CR0u6Hv0ng5uo_Q" hash="vnCMbQ">By Elaine S. Dalton</p><p class="kicker" pid="_BN4zDrikkuFhqH7EW4jag" hash="WcHesw">As daughters of God, you were born to lead.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" pid="YBMYZWKP5Eqc-LxTpNdWIQ" hash="DLqiZA">
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine.p5" pid="t3-7_KY2zUCnNLeZPgRVXA" hash="x98ZdQ">
      <span class="pageBreak" page-number="123"></span>From my window in the Young Women office, I have a spectacular view of the Salt Lake Temple. Every day I see the angel Moroni standing atop the temple as a shining symbol of not only his faith but ours. I love Moroni because, in a very degenerate society, he remained pure and true. He is my hero. He stood alone. I feel somehow he stands atop the temple today, beckoning us to have courage, to remember who we are, and to be worthy to enter the holy temple—to “arise and shine forth,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> to stand above the worldly clamor, and to, as Isaiah prophesied, “Come … to the mountain of the Lord”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span>—the holy temple.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine.p6" pid="1mHoxtd9IU-Jbfuluf9wlQ" hash="-i_7Yw">Gathered here today are the Lord’s elect daughters. There is no more influential group standing for truth and righteousness in all the world than the young women and the women of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. I see your nobility and know of your divine identity and destiny. You distinguished yourselves in the premortal existence. Your lineage carries with it covenants and promises. You have inherited the spiritual attributes of the faithful patriarchs Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob. A prophet of God once referred to each of you assembled here tonight as “the one bright shining hope”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> of the future. And I agree! In a very challenging world, your light shines brightly. Indeed, these are “days never to be forgotten.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> These are <span class="emphasis">your</span> days, and <span class="emphasis">now</span> is the time for young women everywhere to “arise and shine forth, that thy light may be a standard for the nations.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine.p7" pid="8LCmqXe2qE-3FCZOz0VxPg" hash="_ycgJA">“A standard is a rule of measure by which one determines exactness or perfection.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> We are to be a standard of holiness for all the world to see! The new revised <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth</span> booklet contains not only standards to live with exactness but promised blessings if you do so. The words contained in this important booklet are standards for the world, and living these standards will enable you to know what to do to become more like the Savior and to be happy in an ever-darkening world. Living the standards in this booklet will help you qualify for the constant companionship of the Holy Ghost. And in the world in which you are living, you will need that companionship to make critical decisions that will determine much of your future success and happiness. Living these standards will help each of you qualify to enter the Lord’s holy temples and there receive the blessings and power that await you as you make and keep sacred covenants.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine.p8" pid="Plpjo0RQPEiTMRtp1KxLfg" hash="8LgZYA">When our daughter, Emi, was a little girl, she liked to watch my every move as I got ready for church. After observing my routine, she would comb her hair and put on her dress, and then she would always ask me to put on some “shiney.” The “shiney” she referred to was thick, gooey cream that I used to prevent wrinkles. As requested, I would put it on Emi’s cheeks and lips, and she would then smile and say, “Now we are ready to go!” What Emi didn’t realize is that she already had her “shiney” on. Her face glowed because she was so pure and innocent and good. She had the Spirit with her, and it showed.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine.p9" pid="iGLrZlLDQkyZ3tGa6ZoyMA" hash="bJTS5g">I wish every young woman assembled here tonight would know and understand that your beauty—your “shine”—does not lie in makeup, gooey cream, or the latest clothing or hairstyles. It lies in your personal purity. When you live the standards and qualify for the constant companionship of the Holy Ghost, you can have a powerful impact in the world. Your example, even the light in your eyes, will influence others who see your “shine,” and they will want to be like you. Where do you get this light? The Lord is the light, “and the Spirit enlighteneth every man through the world, that hearkeneth to the voice of the Spirit.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> A divine light comes into your eyes and countenances when you draw close to your Heavenly Father and His Son, Jesus Christ. That’s how we get the “shiney”! And besides, as all of you can see, the “shiney cream” didn’t really work on my wrinkles anyway!</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine.p10" pid="pd10dc-gXU2BBebgsaqcRQ" hash="N33SpA">The call to “arise and shine forth” <span class="pageBreak" page-number="124"></span>is a call to each of you to lead the world in a mighty cause—to raise the standard—and lead this generation in virtue, purity, and temple worthiness. If you desire to make a difference in the world, <span class="emphasis">you must be different from the world.</span> I echo the words of President Joseph F. Smith, who said to the women of his day: “It is not for you to be led by the [young] women of the world; it is for you to lead … the [young] women of the world, in everything that is … purifying to the children of men.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> These words ring true today. As daughters of God, you were born to lead.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine.p11" pid="tH162oPpMk2X_y_41mCpnw" hash="cpt-Nw">In the world in which we live, your ability to lead will require the guidance and constant companionship of the Holy Ghost, who will tell you “all things what ye should do”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> as you recognize and rely on His guidance and promptings. And since the Holy Ghost does not dwell in unclean temples, each of us will need to take inventory of our habits and our hearts. All of us will need to change something—to repent. As King Lamoni’s father stated in the Book of Mormon, “I will give away <span class="emphasis">all</span> my sins to know thee.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> Are we, you and I, willing to do the same?</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine.p12" pid="wo_Ag2zGE0Gr6b9mvGg_mg" hash="aY0fBA">A group of youth in Queen Creek, Arizona, determined to “arise and shine forth” and to lead the youth in their community in living the standards in <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth.</span> They each wrote something that they felt was holding them back or something they wanted to change in their lives in their journals, and then they literally dug a hole. They came together, tore out the journal page, and threw it into the hole in the earth, just like the people of Ammon did in the Book of Mormon with their weapons of war.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Then they buried those pages, and that day they each made a commitment to change. They repented. They determined to arise!</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine.p13" pid="aOJ4BIdFFUa3IFYeMJW4dw" hash="DfvXnA">Do you have something in your life that you need to change? You can do this. You can repent because of the Savior’s infinite atoning sacrifice. He made it possible for you and me to change, to become pure and clean again, and to become like Him. And He has promised that when we do, He will remember our sins and mistakes no more.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine.p14" pid="pWUsckiONEiNlB-h7N1tOw" hash="jmcqCA">Sometimes it may seem almost impossible to keep shining. You encounter so many challenges which may obscure the source of all light, which is the Savior. Sometimes the way is difficult, and it may even seem at times that a thick fog obscures the light. Such was the case with a young woman named Florence Chadwick. From the age of 10, Florence discovered that she was a talented swimmer. She swam the English Channel in record time of 13 hours and 20 minutes. Florence loved a challenge, and she later attempted to swim between the coastline of California and Catalina Island—some 21 miles (34 km). On this swim she grew weary after swimming 15 hours. A thick fog set in that obscured the view of the coastline. Her mother was riding alongside her in a boat, and Florence told her mother that she didn’t think she could finish. Her mother and her trainer encouraged her to continue, but all she could see was the fog. She abandoned her swim, but once inside the boat, she discovered she had quit within one mile (1.6 km) of the coastline. Later, when she was interviewed and asked why she had abandoned her swim, she confessed that it wasn’t the cold water and it wasn’t the distance. She said, “I was licked by the fog.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine.p15" pid="VUJwa14aukWmpLIypOjxkg" hash="MuIQPg">Later she attempted the swim again, and once more, a thick fog set in. But this time, she kept going until she successfully reached the coastline. This time when she was asked what made the difference, she said that she kept a mental image of the coastline in her mind through the thick fog and throughout the duration of her swim.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine.p16" pid="zjPkHjiwKEKTwMofnIkZWQ" hash="0jVofw">For Florence Chadwick, the <span class="pageBreak" page-number="125"></span>coastline was her goal. For each of us, the temple is our goal. Young women, stay focused. Don’t lose sight of your goals. Don’t let the thick fog of moral pollution and the detracting voices of the world keep you from reaching your goals, living the standards, enjoying the companionship of the Holy Ghost, and being worthy to enter holy temples. Retain the vision of the temple—the Savior’s holy house—ever in your hearts and minds.</p>
    </span>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine.p17" pid="xYwZ5iCSgkmh83MwyCGi3A" hash="_jq6DQ">Several weeks ago I stood in the celestial room of the Reno Nevada Temple. The light streaming into that room was brilliant and was made even more so by the crystal chandelier, which reflected the light on its many carved facets into rainbows of illumination everywhere. It took my breath away as I realized that the Savior is “the light and the life of the world,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> that it is <span class="emphasis">His</span> light we must hold up and reflect. <span class="emphasis">We</span> are the tiny crystals that reflect His light, and in order to do that, we must be clean and free from the dust of the world. As I stood in the temple that day, I heard again in my mind Moroni’s call to us—the daughters of Zion: “Awake, and arise from the dust.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> “And touch not the evil gift, nor the unclean thing.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> “Awake, and arise … , and put on thy beautiful garments, O daughter of Zion … , that the covenants of the Eternal Father which he hath made unto thee, O house of Israel, may be fulfilled.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine.p18" pid="CyxFn-qCG0eCbOLGNIDpFg" hash="bpL7Rg">The promised blessings of the temple extend not only to you but to all generations. As you make the temple your goal, your influence for good will transcend time and place, and the work you perform for those who have gone before will be the fulfillment of prophecy!</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine.p19" pid="jljm-e4rukKGEu8Kf5OX2g" hash="xQK7YA">Last general conference I thrilled as I listened to Elder David A. Bednar invite each of you to become anxiously engaged in doing your own family history and temple work for those who have passed on without the blessings of the restored gospel of Jesus Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> As he issued this invitation to you, my heart leapt inside. In the Doctrine and Covenants we read of “other choice spirits who were reserved to come forth in the fulness of times to take part in laying the foundations of the great latter-day work, including the building of … temples and the performance of ordinances therein for the redemption of the dead.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> This is your day, and your work has begun! Now is the time to be worthy of and obtain a temple recommend. As you do this work, you will become saviors on Mount Zion.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine.p20" pid="uuYEUU003UGCBJ6AXWS2DQ" hash="sX6xzA">Elder Russell M. Nelson said of you, “The influence of [the] young women of the Church, like a sleeping giant, will awaken, arise, and inspire the inhabitants of the earth as a mighty force for righteousness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> Young women, arise and take your place in the glorious events that will shape your future and the future of the world. Now is the time!</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine.p21" pid="UgPJ7YZi1kqJyCKJLKDSWw" hash="k4qdFQ">“High on the mountain top a banner is unfurled. Ye nations, now look up; it waves to all the world”!<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> Young women, you are the banner! Be virtuous and pure, seek the companionship of the Holy Ghost, bury your sins and transgressions, maintain your <span class="pageBreak" page-number="126"></span>focus, and don’t let the fog of moral pollution obscure your goals. Be worthy to enter the temple now. Put on your “shiney”! I testify with all my heart that God lives and that He will enlighten our lives as we draw close to His Beloved Son—our Savior, Jesus Christ. And I pray that, like Moroni, we will “arise and shine forth, that [our] light may be a standard for the nations”!<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span> In the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2012/04/now-is-the-time-to-arise-and-shine</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2012-general-young-women-meeting/2012-03-0040-elaine-s-dalton-64k-eng.mp3" length="6773845" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Not Moved!</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Stand firm. Be steadfast. “Stand for truth and righteousness.” Stand as a witness. Be a standard to the world. Stand in holy places.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10785_000_63dalton" doc-version="1" hash="2ApM1g">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="etDvRfJApU2P2WQ9achoFg" hash="OmdJkQ">Be Not Moved!</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="Fm0Zylp49kCXL1PDdErNag" hash="vnCMbQ">By Elaine S. Dalton</p>
		<p class="kicker" pid="6p_NRjYUuEiq9iPpH5LD8w" hash="VI7zww">Stand firm. Be steadfast. “Stand for truth and righteousness.” Stand as a witness. Be a standard to the world. Stand in holy places.</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="6xce4X4cPkqNPpLbLU5FgQ" hash="NAo-zw">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p5" pid="0I0ehQCxPkOCCdgcFplH9Q" hash="IuGe3A"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="121"></span>Tonight I stand in a holy place at this pulpit, in the presence of prophets, seers, and revelators and royal daughters of God. This is a magnificent time to be on the earth and to be a young woman. You are the elect daughters of our Father in Heaven. I hope you sense your identity and how beloved you are of our Father in Heaven. He loves each of you, and I do too.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p6" pid="baQemtB9EEeVcBscOkdGtw" hash="eeCmJQ">On the desk in my office, I have a bronze replica of a sculpture of a young woman whose name is Kristina. The original life-sized sculpture of Kristina stands on a pier in Copenhagen, Denmark, positioned so that she is looking out over the sea toward Zion. Her decision to join the Church and leave her home was not an easy one, and you can see that the opposing winds are blowing fiercely against her. She is standing firm, doing a very hard thing but one she knows to be right. Her descendants placed this sculpture there on that pier as a tribute to Kristina, for her decision that day had eternal significance for generations.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p7" pid="n-qhU3l_x0aktrNZwSBi6g" hash="kemzSg">For me this sculpture of Kristina represents each one of you. Like Kristina, you are standing on the edge of many important decisions and making choices daily, some of them difficult, that will shape not only your future but also the destiny of generations. You too are facing gale-force winds of opposition, adversity, peer pressure, and moral pollution. And yet you are standing immovable and living the gospel in the face of these raging storms in our society. Like Kristina, you are led by the Holy Ghost. You are making correct decisions. You are loyal, and you are royal.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p8" pid="aoKcEkwXL0C166wZzA_U6g" hash="CfrY6Q">I can think of no more important counsel from a loving Heavenly Father than His admonition for each of you to “stand … in holy places, and be not moved.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> He is saying: Stand firm. <span class="pageBreak" page-number="122"></span>Be steadfast.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> “Stand for truth and righteousness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Stand as a witness.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Be a standard to the world. Stand in holy places. And so my message to each of you is a simple one: Be not moved.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p9" pid="4qwPD1Jq3E6mzGF6vypCwA" hash="CHtyig"><span class="emphasis">First, be not moved in choosing right.</span> In these latter days, there are no small decisions. The choices you are making right now are of critical importance. Agency, or the ability to choose, is one of God’s greatest gifts to His children. It is part of the plan of happiness you and I chose and defended in our premortal existence. Live your lives in such a way that you can listen to and hear the Holy Ghost, and He will help you make correct decisions. In fact, He will tell you “all things what ye should do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p10" pid="7iuZAymSjEeRburLmSbYyQ" hash="N5codA">Several weeks ago I returned to my old high school for the first time in years. I was visiting a stake conference that was being held in the school’s auditorium. As I walked down the halls, a flood of memories began to pour into my mind. I remembered exactly how I felt when I attended high school as a young woman—insecure, unsure of myself, self-conscious, and so, so desirous to fit in. I went into the auditorium. Again a flood of memories came to mind. I was familiar with every detail of that auditorium. Only one thing had changed—me.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p11" pid="j6H7YnNIbUCSAr43AE5k8w" hash="--gbtQ">That day I had the opportunity to stand on the stage as I had done in high school many times as a student officer. I even saw some of my former classmates in the audience—some I had dated! But this time, instead of conducting an assembly, I had the privilege—there in my high school auditorium—to “stand as a witness”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> and bear my testimony of our Savior, Jesus Christ.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p12" pid="bAGcYuWNhE6572dyCoVqjw" hash="_0sszA">Young women, make sure your relationships with others are such that 40 years from now, you will not be embarrassed. No amount of peer pressure, no acceptance, no popularity is worth a compromise. Your influence on the young men will help them remain worthy of their priesthood power, of temple covenants, and of serving a mission. And who knows? Forty years from now, you may even have one of them walk up to you, there in your high school auditorium, and thank you for helping him remain worthy to fulfill his priesthood duty to serve an honorable mission. And who knows? You may even receive a letter from one of those young men’s wives, thanking <span class="emphasis">you</span> for the influence you had on her husband and their future family clear back in your high school days. Your choices matter. Your choices now not only affect you, but they also affect others. They are of eternal significance. Be not moved!</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p13" pid="T-hepPOJyUaS1GCOlLhAVg" hash="ES03Xw"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="123"></span><span class="emphasis">Second, be not moved in your desire and commitment to remain virtuous and sexually pure.</span> Cherish virtue. Your personal purity is one of your greatest sources of power. When you came to the earth, you were given the precious gift of a body. Your body is the instrument of your mind and a divine gift with which you exercise your agency. This is a gift that Satan was denied, and thus he directs nearly all of his attacks on your body. He wants you to disdain, misuse, and abuse your body. Immodesty, pornography, immorality, tattoos and piercings, drug abuse, and addictions of all kinds are all efforts to take possession of this precious gift—your body—and to make it difficult for you to exercise your agency. Paul asks, “Know ye not that ye are the temple of God, and that the Spirit of God dwelleth in you?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p14" pid="2Atj38O19Umh0kSoEZOHPg" hash="K7Cu9g">Your body is a temple. Why? Because it has the capacity to house not only your eternal spirit but also the eternal spirits of others who will come to the earth as part of your eternal family. Elder Dallin H. Oaks taught, “The power to create mortal life is [an] exalted power.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Your role is an exalted role. God has given you a sacred trust! You are preparing to be future mothers of generations to come. Keep yourselves pure and worthy, and guard that which is “most dear and precious above all”—your virtue and chastity.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Heavenly Father’s wise counsel to you personally, His elect daughters, is to “walk … the paths of virtue.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p15" pid="2D4Ty2zPgkeKXn_2jx7n8g" hash="mYTS0Q">Virtue is the golden key to the temple. <span class="emphasis">So, third, be not moved in being worthy to make and keep sacred covenants.</span> The covenant you make at baptism will tether you to the path of virtue and happiness as you renew that covenant each week by partaking of the sacrament. As you keep your baptismal covenant, you will look different, dress different, and act different from the world. Keeping this covenant will enable you to be guided by the Holy Ghost. Stand in holy places, and do not even go near those environments or music, media, or associations that might cause you to lose the companionship of the Holy Ghost.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> And as you keep your covenants, you will remain worthy and prepared to enter the Lord’s holy temples.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p16" pid="uE7yaA_0IEOWNLwPiCb8XQ" hash="thqUvA"><span class="emphasis">Last, be not moved in your acceptance of the Savior’s Atonement.</span> The Atonement is for you and for me. It is an enabling and a redeeming power. If you are not feeling worthy to stand in holy places, do not carry this burden one day longer. In mortality, we will all make mistakes. Be assured that the Savior loves you so much that He made it possible for you to change and to repent if you make a mistake. Satan does not want you to think you can change.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> He will try to convince you that all is lost. That is a lie. You can return. You can repent. You can be pure and holy because of the Savior’s infinite Atonement.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p17" pid="4frGKqRosUCW3EFH7AClaQ" hash="JQww8w">Now let me close with one of the greatest love stories ever told. You might ask, “What does a love story have to do with standing in holy places?” It has everything to do with standing in holy places. This is the story of a young woman named Rebekah.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p18" pid="eL4k87jeGUCkF0iRrJDvLQ" hash="VQV6JA">As this story unfolds, Abraham charges his servant with finding a worthy young woman to be his son Isaac’s wife. She must be one who qualifies for a covenant marriage—virtuous and pure and worthy. And so he sends his servant on a long and dangerous journey to a place called Haran. The reason he must go there is clear—holy men need holy women to stand by their sides. As the servant approached the city of Nahor, he stopped at a well <span class="pageBreak" page-number="124"></span>to water his camels and he prayed that he would be led to the right young woman and that he would recognize her by her offer to get water for him and his 10 camels. Now, I have ridden a camel, and this much I know—camels drink a <span class="emphasis">lot</span> of water!</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p19" pid="fRr63QDOcUaFrFjxuyHbkA" hash="iucayg">In Genesis we read that Rebekah not only went down to the well and got water, but she “hasted,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> or hurried, to accomplish this task. The servant then placed bracelets and jewelry on Rebekah and asked if there was room in her father’s home for him to stay. I am sure the jewelry helped! The scripture reads, “And the damsel ran, and told them of her mother’s house these things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> Rebekah must have been a runner!</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p20" pid="V1oJdB-mi0OUSGsmqC3vPA" hash="Y-crpA">The servant told Rebekah’s family the purpose of his long journey, and Rebekah agreed to become Isaac’s wife. The servant desired to leave the very next day with Rebekah, but her family entreated her to stay with them at least 10 more days. Then they asked Rebekah what she wanted to do, and her response was simply “I will go.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> Does that response sound familiar to the response of thousands who resolutely responded, “I will go; I will do”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> when our prophet, President Thomas S. Monson, announced the opportunity for young men and young women to serve missions at a younger age?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p21" pid="5REVNT0xn0-VsDu1UeKzvw" hash="zOcp5Q">Now the moral and ending of this love story: Rebekah was prepared and worthy to make and keep sacred covenants and to become a covenant wife of Isaac. She did not have to wait and prepare herself. Prior to her departure from her family, she was given a blessing, and the words are stirring to me, for she was promised that she would become “the mother of thousands of millions.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> But the best part of this love story is when Rebekah first saw Isaac and he first saw her. It doesn’t say this in the Bible, but I think it was love at first sight! For “virtue loveth virtue; [and] light cleaveth unto light.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> When Isaac went out to meet the caravan, Rebekah “lighted off [her] camel.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> And then it says, “And he loved her.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> This is where I sigh!</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p22" pid="jEIEz7CmrkWytEiote2nNQ" hash="oCLj8Q">For both Rebekah and Kristina, standing in holy places was not easy. Being not moved was not easy. The winds blew fiercely, the water from the well was heavy, and departing from their familiar homes and former lives certainly was not easy. But they made correct choices. They were guided by the Holy Ghost. They were virtuous, and they prepared themselves to make and keep sacred covenants. The Savior descended through Rebekah’s lineage. Did she know then that this would happen? No! Do your choices now matter? Yes!</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p23" pid="zCXXrCUpx0KvwA6GCijixg" hash="gAZRAA">Young women, generations are depending on the choices you make, your purity, and your worthy lives. Be not moved. You have a great destiny before you. This is your moment! I truly believe that one virtuous young woman, led by the Spirit, can change the world!</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved.p24" pid="ncayd8kbPEK9QcSH2Lji5Q" hash="dfvW9Q">I testify that the Savior lives! He will be with you. He will enable you. And in difficult moments, His “angels [will be] round about you, to bear you up.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2013/04/be-not-moved</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2013-general-young-women-meeting/2013-03-0040-elaine-s-dalton-64k-eng.mp3" length="14187759" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Are Daughters of Our Heavenly Father</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As daughters of God we are each unique and different in our circumstances and experiences. And yet our part matters—because we matter.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10785_000_14dalton" doc-version="2" hash="C5i2OQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="TziOqJnNkEGa4-0Amerclw" hash="XywwiA">We Are Daughters of Our Heavenly Father</h1><p class="authorName" pid="VFtV68TDc0CBSR02PLQxDA" hash="vnCMbQ">By Elaine S. Dalton</p><p class="kicker" pid="YdFmLxVuKEqaP07IEhXCDg" hash="SM59wQ">As daughters of God we are each unique and different in our circumstances and experiences. And yet our part matters—because we matter.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" pid="A-dy4bXsvkKhlpcrCG-wYA" hash="6eBq9Q">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p5" pid="b0rB7hX1hkOfgS6pp6oY_Q" hash="kCx7UQ"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="12"></span>Every week young women all over the world repeat the Young Women theme. No matter the language, each time I hear these words, “We are daughters of our Heavenly Father, who loves us, and we love Him,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> the Spirit affirms to my soul that they are true. It is not only an affirmation of our identity—who we are—but also an acknowledgment of whose we are. We are daughters of an exalted being!</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p6" pid="rub7PDZi9U-RQIyax57X5w" hash="pP4pdw">In every country and on every continent, I have met confident, articulate young women, filled with light, refined by hard work and trial, possessing pure and simple faith. They are virtuous. They are covenant keepers who “stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things, and in all places.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> They know who they are and that they have a significant role to play in building the kingdom of God.</p>
				<span class="story">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p7" pid="LUr2b0L470mGFi3-Qu_IKA" hash="BlfhjQ">When I was in college, I was a member of the BYU International Folk Dancers. One summer our group had the unique privilege to tour the missions in Europe. It was a difficult summer for me because a few months earlier my father had unexpectedly passed away. While we were in Scotland, I felt especially alone and became discouraged. We danced at a chapel that night, and then after our performance we went next door to the mission home. As I proceeded up the walk, I saw a stone placed in a well-kept garden by the gate. On it I read the words, “What-e’er thou art, act well thy part.” At that moment those words went deeply into my heart, and I felt the powers of heaven reach out and give me a message. I knew I was known by a loving Heavenly Father. I felt I was not alone. I stood in that garden with tears in my eyes. “What-e’er thou art, act well thy part.” That simple statement renewed my vision that Heavenly Father knew me and had a plan for my life, and the spirit I felt helped me understand that my part mattered.</p>
				</span>
				<span class="story">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p8" pid="cFd59jRPmkKd-xKWbRaTCQ" hash="g9U9AA">Later I learned that this saying had once motivated the prophet David O. McKay while he was serving as a young missionary in Scotland. He had seen it on a stone on a building at a discouraging time in his life and on his mission, and the words lifted him. Years later as the building was being torn down, he made arrangements to obtain the stone and had it placed in the garden at the mission home.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
				</span>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p9" pid="v7Mg8DUhvUSYCpAONvy5wA" hash="S5K6tw">As daughters of God we are each unique and different in our circumstances and experiences. And yet our part matters—because <span class="emphasis">we</span> matter. Our daily contributions of nurturing, <span class="pageBreak" page-number="13"></span>teaching, and caring for others may seem mundane, diminished, difficult, and demeaning at times, and yet as we remember that first line in the Young Women theme—“We are daughters of our Heavenly Father, who loves us”—it will make all the difference in our relationships and our responses.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p10" pid="766s9CuL_UmG1SS-LNYmSg" hash="plTmDA">Recently my magnificent 92-year-old mother passed away. She left this mortal existence as she had lived—quietly. Her life was not what she had planned. Her husband, my father, passed away when he was 45, leaving her with three children—me and my two brothers. She lived 47 years as a widow. She supported our family by teaching school during the day and teaching piano lessons at night. She cared for her aging father, my grandfather, who lived next door. She made sure that each of us received a college education. In fact, she insisted on it so that we could be “contributors.” And she never complained. She kept her covenants, and because she did, she called down the powers of heaven to bless our home and to send miracles. She relied on the power of prayer, priesthood, and covenant promises. She was faithful in her service to the Lord. Her steadfast devotion steadied us, her children. She often repeated the scripture: “I, the Lord, am bound when ye do what I say; but when ye do not what I say, ye have no promise.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> That was her motto, and she knew it was true. She understood what it meant to be a covenant keeper. She was never recognized by the world. She didn’t want that. She understood who she was and whose she was—a daughter of God. Indeed, it can be said of our mother that she acted well her part.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p11" pid="N6SyCT0AHkCxp2HlkZWlFg" hash="u7RZuw">Of women and mothers, President Gordon B. Hinckley once said:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p12" pid="uMTaoRyFMkW8cn6_IA6vzg" hash="I9HKuA">“We must never lose sight of the strength of the women. … It is mothers who most directly affect the lives of their children. … It is mothers who nurture them and bring them up in the ways of the Lord. Their influence is paramount. …</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p13" pid="vCguCw5S1UmPnjdbLOXwkw" hash="ONdDZg">“… They are the creators of life. They are the nurturers of children. They are the teachers of young women. They are our indispensable companions. They are our co-workers in building the kingdom of God. How great is their role, how marvelous their contribution.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p14" pid="1-8F9YrTmkWc2xRiZtVncg" hash="kYtA3g">So how do a mother and a father instill in their daughter the ennobling and eternal truth that she is a daughter of God? How do we help her step out of the world and step into the kingdom of God?</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p15" pid="hbqdwMffSES2tAubwbF1xQ" hash="w7k27Q">In a morally desensitizing world, young women need women and men to “stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things, and in all places.” Never before has this been more important than now. Young women need mothers and mentors who exemplify virtuous womanhood. Mothers, your relationship with your daughter is of paramount importance, and so is your example. How you love and honor her father, his priesthood, and his divine role will be reflected and perhaps amplified in your daughter’s attitudes and behavior.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p16" pid="7xjuNo47w0yb_HsB-sEu5Q" hash="wXQxhQ">What is that part we must all “act well”? The family proclamation is clear:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p17" pid="GA_viEekHEemgCVaXex4jw" hash="4nVmbg">“By divine design, fathers are to preside over their families in love and righteousness and are responsible to provide the necessities of life and protection for their families. Mothers are primarily responsible for the nurture of their children. In these sacred responsibilities, fathers and mothers are obligated to help one another as equal partners. …</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p18" pid="v2nPR902SUiI26INMZasfw" hash="6ZMQ5Q">“We warn that individuals who violate covenants of chastity, who abuse spouse or offspring, or who fail <span class="pageBreak" page-number="14"></span>to fulfill family responsibilities will one day stand accountable before God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p19" pid="82O36uDaTEq1wR9T-mkWlw" hash="Jt0_OQ">In the decadent society of Mormon’s time, he lamented that the women were robbed of that which was most dear and precious above all—their virtue and chastity.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p20" pid="YdDrZndR-UeEG7PHPKe4zw" hash="nSpW9Q">Again I renew the call for a return to virtue. Virtue is the strength and power of daughters of God. What would the world be like if virtue—a pattern of thought and behavior based on high moral standards, including chastity<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span>—were reinstated in our society as a most highly prized value? If immorality, pornography, and abuse decreased, would there be fewer broken marriages, broken lives, and broken hearts? Would media ennoble and enable rather than objectify and degrade God’s precious daughters? If all humanity really understood the importance of the statement “We are daughters of our Heavenly Father,” how would women be regarded and treated?</p>
				<span class="story">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p21" pid="kAWH0JMP10qqACs-xPKx4g" hash="Bqfj8g">Several years ago, as this Conference Center was being built and nearing completion, I entered this sacred building on the balcony level in a hard hat and safety glasses, ready to vacuum the carpet that my husband was helping to install. Where the rostrum now stands was a front-end loader moving dirt, and the dust in this building was thick. When it settled, it did so on the new carpet. My part was to vacuum. And so I vacuumed and vacuumed and vacuumed. After three days my little vacuum burned up!</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p22" pid="kDawqbu9E0mgVumQi104tA" hash="ru5K3Q">The afternoon before the first general conference in this beautiful building, my husband called me. He was about to install the last piece of carpet—under this historic pulpit.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p23" pid="HcxmCA_N1kKHbdmn1uXHOQ" hash="lvT6Kw">He asked, “What scripture should I write on the back of this carpet?”</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p24" pid="uaox8SLjxUKp4aySWedvMA" hash="oh8h8A">And I said, “<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:9</a>: ‘Stand as [a witness] of God at all times and in all things, and in all places.’”</p>
				</span>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p25" pid="-Ktqi00-DU-nCPv5rNXEPA" hash="X63txg">In an extremely challenging world, that is what I see young women and women of this Church doing. They are an influence for good. They are virtuous and exemplary, intelligent and industrious. They are making a difference because they <span class="emphasis">are</span> different. They are acting well their part.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p26" pid="_OwRNNqRTUyi1yBWC1JfeQ" hash="YSkcog">Years ago when I was vacuuming this carpet—trying to act well my small part—I didn’t realize that I would one day stand with my feet on the carpet under this pulpit.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father.p27" pid="AefDwkW950K5Tpjj_H5Yxw" hash="tNM-lw">Today as a daughter of God, I stand as a witness that He lives. Jesus is the Christ. He is our Redeemer. It is through His infinite atoning sacrifice that I will one day return to live with Him—proven, pure, and sealed in an eternal family. I shall ever praise Him for the privilege of being a woman, a wife, and a mother. I testify that we are led by a prophet of God, President Thomas S. Monson, and I am grateful for righteous men, whose priesthood power blesses my life. And I shall ever be grateful for the strength I receive through the enabling power of the Savior’s infinite Atonement as I continue to strive to “act well [my] part.” In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2013/04/we-are-daughters-of-our-heavenly-father</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2013-general-conference/2013-04-1040-elaine-s-dalton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5519559" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
