<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Elaine L. Jack</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Elaine L. Jack.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Elaine%20L.%20Jack.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Elaine L. Jack.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 1989 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Identity of a Young Woman</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The favorite part of my calling as a counselor in the Young Women General Presidency is getting acquainted with you young women when I visit your activities, your camps and conferences, and you tell me what’s important to you—about your goals, your p</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03245_000_035" doc-version="2" hash="FlJNcA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="AT-oPpXRokGzKE8WJTrwGQ" hash="JWyDnA">Identity of a Young Woman</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="jt2bzJGJxE-PfiFbtRYsGQ" hash="9JKBXA">Elaine L. Jack</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26e4.jpg" alt="Elaine L. Jack" pid="eZkRus4WCkO6BfUON7j2Wg" hash="QiNrvQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p1" pid="zbg9c_R2hE6eHByjFvUQCA" hash="MkrEXQ">The favorite part of my calling as a counselor in the Young Women General Presidency is getting acquainted with you young women when I visit your activities, your camps and conferences, and you tell me what’s important to you—about your goals, your projects, your friends, what’s hard for you. I love to listen to you sing “I Walk by Faith.” I get choked up when I hear that. I see you as good, and I see your great potential.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p2" pid="5gFfdEUhgkud8sZaxyus6A" hash="1SG_vQ">Tonight I am going to talk about having faith in your Heavenly Father, about the divine qualities you have inherited, and of your infinite worth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p3" pid="6z1PRhLOl0msiBd0pSoKJw" hash="9Og5NQ">Although I have faith in you, I know some of you who are feeling insecure, unhappy, lonely, who don’t think you’re as good as your friends, or not as pretty or as important. I want to say, “You are wonderful! You must not know how good you are. Can’t you see what you have going for you?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p4" pid="1RLer1faF0aKBKGPVfQ7gQ" hash="BaJc-g">I remember when I was fourteen and had many of those same feelings of doubt and insecurity, and I was wondering what I was to do with my life. My mother would say to me: “You can be anything in life you want to be, Elaine, if you work for it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p5" pid="rDeHNT5aYU6IH6xqcJ6xVQ" hash="Yw9Pww">I’m a long way from fourteen, but I’ve learned that she was right. Your life at fourteen or sixteen is much different than mine was. You are living in a computer and space age. I still use a pencil and marvel at a satellite launch. The world is so different, but the principles taught to me by my mother are the same.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p6" pid="D4AZX7XjMEaI_OEJZ1RyZA" hash="_W2o_A">Every Sunday throughout the world young women stand together and repeat the Young Women Theme. You say, “We are daughters of our Heavenly Father who loves us.” That theme has become part of the creed of my life. I personalize it and say, “I, Elaine Jack; am a daughter of my Heavenly Father who loves me, and I love him.” When I listen to you say it, I recall my feelings at your age. Sometimes I still feel that way. Even though I’m a grandmother, I need assurance that I am somebody. We all need to be reminded that we are daughters of a Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p7" pid="7b3oykvcvkuN34_Dqe836g" hash="Cc3ujg">That eternal truth is so important.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p8" pid="5pBff-tAVkCoJ2xM9pnvtw" hash="9XlZ0Q">In Romans 8:16, the Apostle Paul talked about it when he wrote that the Spirit of our Heavenly Father will teach us that we truly are daughters of God. Paul says it this way:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p9" pid="5YOefnCAJUat0c2FrDnoKg" hash="Q6UpZQ">“The Spirit itself beareth witness with our spirit, that we are the children of God.” [<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/8.16" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 8:16</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p10" pid="T1cgO3Vti0OoFOgEIQWLVw" hash="v7KMug">A Mia Maid in the Philippines expressed the same thought like this:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p11" pid="zxuNd33k4k2MUsge25xEhA" hash="E73dOA">“I used to ask myself, ‘Am I one of the chosen daughters of our Heavenly Father?’ and ‘Did God create all people?’ These questions prompted me to read the scriptures with the hope of receiving immediate answers. But the answers took long in coming. I became involved in the Young Women organization, and through the promptings of the Holy Ghost, I developed a strong faith that I am indeed a daughter of God, who created all of us.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p12" pid="5BlF0LqQx02QCG2IekgqYA" hash="B5e3aA">I’ve heard some of you say, “I don’t know if I have a testimony or not. I’ve never felt the Spirit.” You may not have recognized it, but you probably have. Maybe you’re feeling it right now. Very often it’s the influence of the Spirit that gives you a warm feeling about an experience; it makes a message sound right and true, and sometimes it makes you feel as if you want to cry. Always it brings peace. Listen to a letter from a young woman that a friend shared with me:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p13" pid="XpXDbUpZXUeW3KWuXSRIcg" hash="WJ0UWw">“For the past couple of months I felt like my testimony was starting to slip and that I wasn’t as close to my Heavenly Father as I should be. Then you came and spoke to us. You told us how you prayed every night that you’d have the blessing of the Spirit striving with you, so I decided, ‘What the heck? It sure couldn’t hurt, right?’ Well, for that first week, every day I felt that Spirit. It really made me feel at peace.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p14" pid="lCylYJLqbU6B2sd3YujdTA" hash="QVFI7g">I, too, have experienced what Paul taught when he said, “The Spirit beareth witness that we are children of God.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p15" pid="Zl0r1StU0kS8Lz0C4s19tA" hash="Ywbt0g">When you have that witness, then you know that you are part of God’s family, that Jesus Christ is your elder brother, and that you’ve inherited the characteristics of love, forgiveness, patience, service, tolerance, obedience. Christ is our example. If you wonder about other traits you have inherited, your patriarchal blessing will help you discover individual qualities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p16" pid="om2dM7laO0WK3hb-35PmAg" hash="l07-zw">Our prophet, President Ezra Taft Benson, has counseled:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p17" pid="EvvFxei5D0qWVcDHZrMEqQ" hash="KbOHBA">“I would encourage you young sisters, as you approach your teenage years, to receive a patriarchal blessing. Study it carefully and regard it as personal scripture to you—for that indeed is what it is.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1986, p. 82.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p18" pid="8YRD6p9jOUu-g3Esz4YdTQ" hash="9rQlLw">Have you had a patriarchal blessing? Are you preparing to get one soon? Think of this—what does a patriarchal blessing say? Have you ever heard of one which says, “I am sorry—you’re a loser. Do the best you can on earth, and we’ll see you in about seventy years. “Of course not! And you never will, because of the divine qualities each of God’s children has inherited. A patriarchal blessing is like a road map, a guide, directing you in your walk through life. It identifies your talents and the good things that can be yours.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p19" pid="A-ZXOsTo-k6RkexR6tsdkw" hash="yX611Q">In my blessing I’m promised that I can enjoy the gift of foresight, to be able to discern the thoughts of the heart and to detect the powers of evil. Then my responsibility is outlined: “These gifts you must cultivate, that you may not be deceived.” I received this blessing when I was very young. The circumstances were unusual, but I’m sure that the gifts and blessings that were promised would have been the same if I had been sixteen or thirty-six.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p20" pid="Im20n1x5cEu7vWDsWBZTjw" hash="qlVZwQ">Have you ever been told you are just like your mother, or you have your father’s smile, or all of your family have the same color of eyes? The physical characteristics that we inherit from our parents are obvious. The spiritual characteristics we inherit from our heavenly parents have to be developed. You have been born with all the godlike gifts that Christ has. They are within you, but you have to choose to cultivate and develop them. Spiritual growth doesn’t just happen without our best efforts. I know you understand this. A young woman writes:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p21" pid="Ven29LxNWUuNtl475ESr5g" hash="4Bhzhw">“A girl at school, not as popular, needs help in science. My friends in the higher group tell me to leave her alone or it would ruin my reputation. And then I remembered when I needed a friend and help in math. I put myself in her place. Not only did I help her out, I made a new friend.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p22" pid="gCfI5jzCHEqq1zmgZcbcrg" hash="-3cWGQ">Another young woman in England is developing her gift for being a peacemaker. She says:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p23" pid="kuyf1T6UoEm7gLpDwmnT1w" hash="Fx47gQ">“I love making and listening to music, and it is one of the best ways I know to calm down. If I am in a rotten mood, I quite often go to the piano and take out my anger on it. This isn’t very good for the piano, but soon I feel fine again, and usually I will end up playing a hymn. This puts me in a better humour, and everyone else responds to the music as well, so we get harmony in the home for a while at least.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p24" pid="bTZUdu9FSkaCaFriyzKXiA" hash="bmcM3Q">And a Laurel says:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p25" pid="Y0DBu_h5N0O2mKwXu9Ux1A" hash="cuq8-w">“I remember how I used to look up to the Laurels and try to emulate them. I fluttered when they spoke to me. When I got older, I realized that younger girls were looking up to me. One of the Beehives was asked to write a paper for school on ‘The Person I Most Admire.’ She wrote about me! I realized the importance of my influence and my obligation to be a good example.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p26" pid="OdxCprlVXESyVf7wVriTtw" hash="o7H50A">What you become might be different from anyone else, but you have a distinct responsibility to grow spiritually and to reach out to others. We are important to Heavenly Father as his children. God will never stop being our Father, but sometimes we turn away from being his children by not obeying his commandments or by showing disrespect for him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p27" pid="ZMRXH2tJ80qxV-gkFpaF5Q" hash="x7vKew">Do you know what <span class="emphasis">infinite</span> means? <span class="emphasis">Infinite</span> means having no boundaries or limits. “I am of infinite worth with my own divine mission which I will strive to fulfill.” Do you believe that? This young woman does. She says:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p28" pid="iTljQb26N02cjhc62yDf8Q" hash="BdJvcw">“I know I was sent down here at this time [being the most evil time] because I am strong and can resist temptation.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p29" pid="JY-c2zluOkyRnhZtiqDEZw" hash="gfr0Eg">And another relates:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p30" pid="YNnkZ18xgk67j1AV1GxnYg" hash="Nrv-PQ">“I know I occupy a bright spot in the Lord’s plan. As a young woman, I am blessed with the opportunity to become a mother someday.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p31" pid="lLgg7XWBYEKbP7keqzZQBg" hash="kmv-dw">Unfortunately, Satan will try to convince you otherwise. He would have you believe, “You’re no good; why try?” If you have those thoughts, don’t believe them. According to Elder Neal A. Maxwell, “Satan delights to have us put ourselves down. Self-contempt is of Satan. There is no such thing in Heaven.” The scriptures tell us that Satan would have you “be miserable like unto himself” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.27" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:27</a>) and that he “desireth to have you” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.18" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:18</a>). He would also try to convince you that there is no repentance, no way back, and that no one cares.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p32" pid="2M9QlgwCVEOxiO3RhwWVDQ" hash="TGlx-g">One young person who had left the activities of the Church and came back was asked, “What really made the difference in coming back?” She replied, “I had a friend, and I knew she really cared. I wanted help. I needed help. I knew I could get help from Heavenly Father.” In this life, we do make mistakes, but through the process of repentance and the blessings of the Atonement, they can be resolved.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p33" pid="01kEqh4bzU2nrjGZKUWe-A" hash="ZxTcDA">Repentance means turning the heart and the will to God. It denotes a change of mind, a fresh view about God, about oneself, and about the world. (See LDS edition of the King James Bible, Bible Dictionary, p. 760.) It is a cleansing process. It <span class="emphasis">is</span> the way back. There is someone who does care and will help. You can choose to wallow in despair or to make the changes that will bring lasting happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p34" pid="-Ep-iPFii02H2XigOVWuXQ" hash="yjiwAw">Your confidence becomes stronger as you practice making right choices. When you are with your friends, share your thoughts and feelings with them about doing good and being good.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p35" pid="uRFSUkYhW02xS0yVvzJI7w" hash="1sjBCA">Michelle discovered that she was of infinite worth to another person. As a popular high-school student, she received a letter from a former neighbor, a girl she termed “unfortunate.” The girl asked for some tips on how to make boys like her. Part of Michelle’s reply was, “Just be yourself, and people—not just boys—will like you for what you are.” Later Michelle received a letter from “her new friend.” (Isn’t that interesting? When she helped this girl, Michelle found a new friend—not an unfortunate neighbor.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p36" pid="OK-DCUF1bUG68bSGS5wiVQ" hash="1G1gVg">Michelle said: “In her writing and words I could feel the excitement. From a few kind words, I seemed to change another person’s life. I guess I know I can do anything I put my mind to.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p37" pid="1zp6kZ1NaEmpkCQ98pEB0A" hash="VoxWlw">The world would have you believe that you are of worth only if you have money, a certain physical appearance, stylish clothes, or social position. The gospel assures you that your value is not dependent on your looks or material possessions. What matters are the beliefs you have in your heart. What my mother taught me was true. When I have worked tirelessly, without giving up at small setbacks, I have progressed toward becoming what I want to be. Part of what it means to be a Latter-day Saint is to know within your soul your eternal worth, who you really are, and why you are here on earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p38" pid="Y4l6q5l7DkKrTd1p0dtyMA" hash="phgT_Q">Next time you are questioning your identity, remember the divine potential you have been given and the promises you can realize. Remember that we believe in you. Say with me: “I am a daughter of my Heavenly Father who loves me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman.p39" pid="kF_-Qk1eLEWE9-0hSC-Pnw" hash="QfngoQ">This I believe, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1989/10/identity-of-a-young-woman</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1989-general-womens-meeting/1989-09-0010-elaine-l-jack-64k-eng.mp3" length="6464159" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 1989 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“I Will Go and Do”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1990/04/i-will-go-and-do?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, first let me affirm my belief in the words of Nephi: “I will go and do the things which the Lord hath commanded, for I know that the Lord giveth no commandments unto the children of men, save he shall prepare a way … tha</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/i-will-go-and-do" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_90905_000_034" doc-version="2" hash="7tTo_A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/i-will-go-and-do.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="iHNFHpa2JU-58c7dMskLDg" hash="EByJkw">“I Will Go and Do”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="U_6kQv8vPEWinWj4nVmAEw" hash="9JKBXA">Elaine L. Jack</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/i-will-go-and-do.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e50.jpg" alt="President Elaine L. Jack" pid="O-UrdagclEqtQXMV5KndUQ" hash="Ra9gOA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/i-will-go-and-do.p1" pid="1JUeSNkfAkGDsWE4epqeoA" hash="uW5m4Q">My dear brothers and sisters, first let me affirm my belief in the words of Nephi: “I will go and do the things which the Lord hath commanded, for I know that the Lord giveth no commandments unto the children of men, save he shall prepare a way … that they may accomplish the thing which he commandeth them.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 3:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/i-will-go-and-do.p2" pid="Y2ViWjLmWEGEHyFEenodag" hash="yLKhkw">Without this belief there would be no way to accept the awesome responsibility to serve as Relief Society general president.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/i-will-go-and-do.p3" pid="5UCvhF5KuU2sDym2mepVvg" hash="T7tGoQ">I acknowledge with deep gratitude the magnificent women who have preceded me in this call—women like Sister Barbara Winder. I am grateful for her influence in my life. In my prayers each day I give thanks for the influence of many good people around me—for friends, for caring neighbors, for the Young Women office staff, and for Sister Jayne Malan and the board members with whom I have a close and cherished relationship.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/i-will-go-and-do.p4" pid="mhfmzQWexkCuwP4G1JYxdQ" hash="G92w1w">I feel the love and the great strength that come from my four sons and their families. I appreciate their candor and good humor. In fact, I can hear them now, on both coasts, watching this broadcast and saying, “My mother? Oh, sure!” Yesterday, I was telling our oldest son that President Monson had said that I might be called on for a few remarks today. President Monson had said, “We don’t want you to preach a sermon.” Dave replied, “Mom, that’s what we’ve been telling you for years!” I am grateful that they have the desire to do what’s right.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/i-will-go-and-do.p5" pid="pStFVgWIcUmbpHuUKBbL4Q" hash="L5m1Yw">I give thanks for my sister, who is my friend. Blessed is she who has one like her and thrice blessed if more than one. Sister Ardeth Kapp is like a sister to me. I pay tribute to her as a great woman of vision, called by the Lord to lead the Young Women around the world at a most critical time. She has tutored me, encouraged me, and allowed me to grow. I have served happily as a counselor in the Young Women organization.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/i-will-go-and-do.p6" pid="UXFKMEuv7U6xQS5JzFoeaA" hash="r0o6iQ">I love you young women. I know that you are understanding the importance of the Young Women Values—those gospel principles which help prepare you to make and keep sacred covenants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/i-will-go-and-do.p7" pid="X-KuCRRoqE6VAxK153ff2A" hash="773jgQ">No one who is as committed to home and family and personal growth as I could serve in this calling without the love and support of a husband who is devoted to the gospel. Joe is devoted, and he brings great strength and stability into my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/i-will-go-and-do.p8" pid="hp43yobf0UKecB2wp3AqqQ" hash="mvDCBQ">I know that Ezra Taft Benson is a prophet of God. I will follow his counsel, and the counsel of those Brethren who have been called to serve with him. I know that Jesus is the Christ, and that he will direct my path if I make myself worthy of his guidance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/i-will-go-and-do.p9" pid="uTD68_-xoUuSHwyUAF8-Jg" hash="VF1Dxw">I believe that the women of the Church have a unique contribution to make. In the words of a modern-day prophet: “Much of the major growth that is coming to the Church in the last days … will happen to the degree that the women of the Church reflect righteousness and articulateness in their lives and to the degree that [they] are seen as distinct and different—in happy ways—from the women of the world.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1979, pp. 103–4.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/i-will-go-and-do.p10" pid="RFpVo0nd40iR7WRnZagvBQ" hash="_0aeJA">This is a joyous gospel!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/i-will-go-and-do.p11" pid="yEJHLdoehE6AHeaIfUjQLg" hash="nT8XcA">My counselors and I look forward eagerly to serving. And we want to serve in a way that will help women everywhere contribute to the great forward movement of the Church. I know that in the strength of the Lord we can do all things required of us. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1990/04/i-will-go-and-do</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1990-general-conference/1990-04-5040-elaine-l-jack-64k-eng.mp3" length="3603335" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 1990 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“These Things Are Manifested unto Us Plainly”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear sisters, it’s been heartwarming for me to receive so many good wishes from you during the past six months and to feel your acceptance. Many of you have told me that you’re praying for our presidency. We feel that spiritual strength and gratef</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_90911_000_037" doc-version="2" hash="gul6kQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="NZcuVINhyk2ZSgYZkbH_FQ" hash="b8gnxw">“These Things Are Manifested unto Us Plainly”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ieRWbxhJOkuxUO4pV4Hpng" hash="9JKBXA">Elaine L. Jack</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e50.jpg" alt="President Elaine L. Jack" pid="Ft8J00u1o06-kFFlfLYH2w" hash="Ra9gOA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p1" pid="K7-s8AVd-0uyr7yJSnw0Xg" hash="J5g2cQ">My dear sisters, it’s been heartwarming for me to receive so many good wishes from you during the past six months and to feel your acceptance. Many of you have told me that you’re praying for our presidency. We feel that spiritual strength and gratefully acknowledge it—both to you and to our Father in Heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p2" pid="JcwXRl_bpU-V-26jDqoBhA" hash="VGg5kA">I’ve looked forward to this opportunity to speak to you as your Relief Society president and share the thoughts that many of you have shared with me, both in person and in letter. Those thoughts echo a common theme: sisters compare themselves to others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p3" pid="-malFdpgK0mCucUqiOxoJA" hash="sfkbwg">For thirty years I have wanted to meet the woman against whom more Latter-day Saint women have compared themselves than any other woman in the Church. She’s often thought of as “Superwoman.” Some call her the typical Relief Society sister, the woman who makes fabulous bread, plays the organ like a professional, and dresses her impeccably groomed children in the clothes she’s made.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p4" pid="GygBZ10_mki-p1BdR_0DaQ" hash="uE8gnQ">Where is she? Who is she? What does she do that makes her seem beyond the reach of any woman? I’ve made a careful study, and I’ve found this woman. Tonight I’ll introduce you to our sister so we can see her as she is.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p5" pid="GROKKgOf_0WDxu7beurVQg" hash="fCmu3g">The prophet Jacob taught, “The Spirit speaketh the truth and lieth not. Wherefore, it speaketh of things as they really are, and of things as they really will be; wherefore, these things are manifested unto us plainly, for the salvation of our souls.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.13" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p6" pid="_FmgjrsmGEG2A7cbGuUBcQ" hash="bGSLEw">Dear sisters, I wish to speak of “things as they really are, and of things as they really will be.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.13" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:13</a>.) For many of us, comparing ourselves to a practically perfect Latter-day Saint woman is part of how things are. While some of us are motivated and encouraged by such imagined or real-life models, others of us are disheartened and discouraged by this same ideal woman—whether she is a composite of many women, or someone of whom we have read, or even someone we know.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p7" pid="yxvtYRJiSkuqp0SIwXY_cQ" hash="6cYHXw">As women make these comparisons, I hear such comments as: “When they talk about being a good mother in Relief Society, I always feel so guilty because sometimes I shout at my children.” “I’m not comfortable in church because my husband isn’t active.” “I wish I didn’t have to work, but I need a paycheck to sustain my family.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p8" pid="D2Vj0qVR2Emm7Dh9kgaJTQ" hash="3VCMjw">I’ve heard: “I’m not a mother. I’m not married, and I’m most painfully aware of this in Relief Society and sacrament meeting. I often go home feeling that they don’t know what to do with me in the Church.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p9" pid="67RmohIy3EGGjVaQN-9OHw" hash="FOmdZA">These statements and others like them come, I believe, from unrealistic comparisons we make against some ideal. Because I know many of you, I know of your goodness and your individual gifts from the Lord. I can see that these comparisons may keep you from achieving your potential and basking in associations that will enrich your lives and the lives of others. Sometimes the basis for these incorrect comparisons comes from other Relief Society sisters, the Relief Society organization, or expectations about roles in life. Whatever the origin, the point of comparison is wrong unless it accounts for things as they really are—now and forever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p10" pid="3xNnSCjv40OuIx57uuW70w" hash="pYlSdQ">The prophet Jacob said things as they “really are” and “really will be” are “manifested unto us plainly, for the salvation of our souls.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.13" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p11" pid="zLswU41e8UKHk-M1xZubrA" hash="u1o93A">Sisters, how are these things manifest unto us? Plainly, through the fulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ, through the example of our Savior’s life. Only by living His gospel can we find what is real. We can never accurately take the measure of our lives based on social, economic, ethnic, age, marital, or physical conditions. Ask yourself, are the comparisons you may make of yourself and others based on the model of the Savior’s life, or do they come from trying to fit your life into the pattern of others’ lives?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p12" pid="DKA99f4L9kuVYzeyQGZxnQ" hash="uSboyg">Sometimes comparisons creep up on us. We sit in Relief Society surrounded by our neighbors and friends, all of whom seem to raise the best children, to teach the most profound lessons, and to possess the greatest spirituality. It can feel so discouraging.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p13" pid="tHx1OOwpwk27rO8QeHv1wQ" hash="M29RXw">Some of you may say, “I’m just average. There’s nothing special about me or my life.” And yet what is manifested plainly to me is that you are extraordinary, you whose average day is lived in accordance with our Heavenly Father’s laws.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p14" pid="f3K_pzQsgEWRNSBZuZOtNA" hash="alsm3A">No greater heroine lives in today’s world than the woman who is quietly doing her part. Generally unsung, you live everywhere—you live in Nebraska or Puerto Rico or Ghana or Canada or Czechoslovakia. You show your love for the Lord daily as you support husbands, nurture children, care for parents, benefit neighbors, serve in your schools, sit on community councils, and do much of the work of this world in and out of the home. No one is more impressive than you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p15" pid="rLcGmk3hqE-qv8f6mTYclA" hash="pJuNSA">I promised to introduce you to the typical Relief Society sister.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p16" pid="UaBU1bpUxkGPmxTxUiwabw" hash="FNM_5Q">The good news is that she actually does exist.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p17" pid="NPZZDTRLV0SN4IpbNZtVBw" hash="4bPyVA">The better news is that she is wonderful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p18" pid="4Ux2nONIKEa-hkV5faTL4A" hash="Yun0nQ">The best news is that she’s <span class="emphasis">you! </span>And this is who you really are!</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.f2">
	<ol class="symbol">
	  <li>
	    <p pid="TGFIdlixgUyVJvq0QVFyyA" hash="I2lXlg">—</p>
	    <p pid="vVEZx2-dBUmYvJ8KQYdYBQ" hash="XZclFA">2.78 million of you live in 128 countries and territories across the globe from Invercargill to Edmonton, from Chicago to Singapore.</p>
	  </li>
	  <li>
	    <p pid="uMqlxsbAbUWcOU1rK-vVXQ" hash="I2lXlg1">—</p>
	    <p pid="7DON4tTa9E-4nwfkfDxWTg" hash="X42laA">8,000 of you are single, full-time missionaries; 1,700 are serving your mission as part of a couple.</p>
	  </li>
	  <li>
	    <p pid="2eg2aHpJP0CKNi1xbdydLg" hash="I2lXlg2">—</p>
	    <p pid="9rUzr2xMF0GbPPKZXv86CA" hash="KqY2gQ">You are raising 1.2 million children, and a half million young women and one-half million young men who are teenagers.</p>
	  </li>
	  <li>
	    <p pid="1OlP2ui1TUKiJUxXMav5SA" hash="I2lXlg3">—</p>
	    <p pid="0WTNM5gUmEiXVXe9_bOb6Q" hash="YTRwYQ">You made approximately one million visits to each other doing visiting teaching in just the first five months of 1990.</p>
	  </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p19" pid="1EIYYWMyIUqmTVc3VDbODA" hash="0GUdVw">If I could have the desire of my heart for you, it would be that you feel valued for your own goodness. The starting point is knowing that you are a daughter of God. The Young Women say together each week, “We are daughters of our Heavenly Father who loves us, and we love him. We will stand as witnesses of God at all times, and in all things and in all places.” (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p20" pid="a2VSSZcMzEyUz7GWpfaPxw" hash="dYD7Hw">The Primary children sing, “I belong to The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. I know who I am. I know God’s plan. I’ll follow him in faith.” When my grandchildren and their parents sing this song together with great enthusiasm, it brings tears of joy. I know who <span class="emphasis">I</span> am, I know God’s plan, and this knowledge makes all the difference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p21" pid="1PW67TAgGkCZx5yAjBH91A" hash="OIiamg">We Relief Society sisters follow our motto, Charity Never Faileth. This motto is very personal to me. It means that we love our Heavenly Father, and we best express that love through all that we do for others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p22" pid="kEaiQp8IxEmUyFv_n6iI5Q" hash="NSuiOQ">To rejoice in being a daughter of God, to know God’s plan, and to follow the Savior’s example of service—these things are real.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p23" pid="fxw2xaRPvECX6Mpl9QIJzg" hash="vtEKBg">The Savior taught the Samaritan woman at Jacob’s well:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p24" pid="p98p8oieLk6dBfzWcfkFIw" hash="1LOBdA">“Whosoever drinketh of the water that I shall give him shall never thirst; but the water that I shall give him shall be in him a well of water springing up into everlasting life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p25" pid="ntct9kdLXkGwEOQVTe6O9w" hash="w9NXrA">“The woman saith unto him, Sir, give me this water, that I thirst not.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/4.14-15" class="scriptureRef">John 4:14–15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p26" pid="QF072yqRYk2NQV4yW4sZmg" hash="hgjewA">A Relief Society sister in Ghana visits a woman who thirsts for truth but cannot read. To give her sister the opportunity to drink deeply of gospel truths, the visiting teacher tries to be with her as often as possible. She reads the scriptures to her sister and explains their meaning, in her native tongue.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p27" pid="04FdPXV3FkuDtf59ZJ9afQ" hash="sOk56Q">We’ve learned of a remarkable, peppy, saintly, 60-year-old woman. She lives in Czechoslovakia. She is one of the handful of Saints who has remained active during the forty-year slumber when that country was denied full religious opportunity. The sister shares the gospel’s living water as she takes an 83-year-old branch president for a walk each day and does his shopping for him. He requires two canes for walking, and shopping in Czechoslovakia is no small task.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p28" pid="vHr-THhg8Euxmb0WnpRC1w" hash="0Ibwuw">Through their daily acts of service, these women partake of and pass on to others the water springing up into eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p29" pid="S906NeQBVEidTYBUUkZggA" hash="q31zAg">Another of you wrote, “I love being a mother. I love teaching my children the gospel. I substituted in Relief Society one week and got to give the lesson on family scripture study. This is something close to my heart, something I can’t imagine family life without. After the lesson, a sister came up to me and said, ‘I can’t believe all you do. I don’t have the patience.’ But she sings and takes music lessons. At times I’ve envied people who could sing well or play an instrument, because I love music.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p30" pid="mnfpATWBoEa78CUcqRdxSA" hash="R4DwkA">“After my conversation with her I felt that although I had not been blessed with great musical ability, Heavenly Father had blessed me with a love of motherhood and that this indeed was a gift and a talent for which I am grateful.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p31" pid="ylaZx3ZDbkWYRwL59haqIw" hash="e99KoQ">Isn’t the point of these three examples that each of these sisters serves as she is able, according to the needs around her? Isn’t that the point of your life?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p32" pid="NRYB2JVWFk2fqiRsv1Ue3A" hash="S2rgDw">Look at all you do. You make quilts for orphans and visit women in prison. You change countless diapers and kiss away endless tears. You collect clothing for earthquake victims. You tutor underachieving children. In the Church you preside, teach, counsel, visit teach, and render countless other acts of service. You may serve as Relief Society president, or librarian, or Star A teacher, or Gospel Doctrine teacher. All you do blesses children, youth, women, and men in every unit of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p33" pid="6ZVvPUKL6kehA3gSR6v2xw" hash="lpGPsw">Our focus in Relief Society for this new decade reflects our quest for things that are real and for the salvation of our souls. Our focus reflects our love and admiration for you, our sisters. We want you to live lives of spiritual maturity and fulfillment, free of unrealistic comparisons. In Relief Society we focus on these five points:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p34" pid="AC0-GyTKdUyBUIo69d6INw" hash="xoW4ow">First: Build personal testimony. This means leading lives of faith and hope, and becoming thoughtful, prayerful disciples of our Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p35" pid="y6TeFY8CaEmvDpjmWBy4AA" hash="BC7TnA">Second: Bless the individual woman. I believe in you. I delight in our diversity as Relief Society women and the joy we find in righteous living. The prophet Nephi tells us: “Behold, the Lord esteemeth all flesh in one; he that is righteous is favored of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.35" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:35</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p36" pid="C74d9YiPKEG_U1aA4PhsQA" hash="H1_DZQ">Third: Develop and exercise charity. Our Relief Society motto, Charity Never Faileth, is worth living by. The challenge ahead is to become more active in meeting the real needs of the world around us—loneliness, neglect, illiteracy, homelessness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p37" pid="Pt8lwjx290e_YoH5_n_zqA" hash="Npn4og">Fourth: Strengthen families. In the many types of family units, we love and nourish each other as we unite our efforts to become better disciples of our Savior. And then:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p38" pid="-ualiXq7kEqk0e6mV8MsGw" hash="ZSEf8Q">Fifth: Enjoy a unified sisterhood as we share our faith, our experiences, and our ideas in loving friendship.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p39" pid="QMNfDHvwfkKJOYI1NXrYiQ" hash="YSra8A">
        <span class="emphasis">Build, bless, develop and exercise, strengthen,</span> and <span class="emphasis">enjoy</span>—these are propelling, motivating action words that invite our personal best.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p40" pid="2l4yE1Tdv0O5m8vvomyXOg" hash="yk4pIA">Our goal is that each of you enjoys the process of life. Build your own personal testimony and rejoice with me in being a typical Relief Society woman.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p41" pid="MSMcz1X8l0ihzXPnFkKGeA" hash="hjSDBA">These things are real—testimony, individuality, charity, families, sisterhood. These are real. And so are you. You are everywhere. I pay tribute to you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly.p42" pid="mJcdaZ2_dk2zb-B96ubWLA" hash="46gY8A">I pray for the blessings of our Father in Heaven, who loves us, to continue to be with you, in every part of the world, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1990/10/these-things-are-manifested-unto-us-plainly</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1990-general-womens-meeting/1990-09-0010-elaine-l-jack-64k-eng.mp3" length="6215742" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 1990 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Charity Never Faileth”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Part of this address was filmed in Nauvoo, Illinois, and presented as part of the Relief Society Sesquicentennial Satellite Broadcast.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_92905_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="EsdQDw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="s6lsLAIOREeSsv_SslyEqQ" hash="HUZg1w">“Charity Never Faileth”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Z1okCuHXC0-u2gs7oiTQXg" hash="9JKBXA">Elaine L. Jack</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="qPyhxyf3nEiwMrPf88zrOw" hash="iBhu7g">Part of this address was filmed in Nauvoo, Illinois, and presented as part of the Relief Society Sesquicentennial Satellite Broadcast.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e50.jpg" alt="President Elaine L. Jack" pid="Zm0k0GcIUEe1gWF3SPt6CQ" hash="Ra9gOA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p1" pid="jp7oh52G4USzVqhB9LSB9g" hash="DfvZLw">This is truly a remarkable gathering of sisters. Never before have so many women in the world sat down together to pray, sing, and speak to each other the feelings of our hearts—to share in the ways the Lord has blessed us as women and as members of His Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p2" pid="9ePJrte6CUaotJpOvl77Og" hash="oWntiQ">“Lift up your hearts and rejoice” (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/25.13" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 25:13</a>), the Lord tells us, and we do rejoice. Relief Society is 150 years old. But today, we feel new and vibrant. We are full of expectations for our sisters everywhere, from the Philippines to Japan, England to New Zealand, and Paris to St. Petersburg. Our individual lives, our circumstances, and our challenges are as diverse as the countries and cultures we come from. Yet our commitment is the same. Today, we can all rejoice in being women in The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. We are united in devotion to our Father in Heaven and in our desire to touch the lives of others. We serve as partners with our brethren in building the kingdom of God. We are women who have become a mighty force for good in a world that needs our understanding and our spirituality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p3" pid="ewqW-UopokycKodT4W129w" hash="t2oiQg">One hundred and fifty years ago, sisters in Nauvoo, Illinois, the city called Beautiful, felt a need to be organized. They desired, as we do now, to be a force for good. For them, it was to help build the Nauvoo Temple and to extend a hand filled with help—needles to make shirts, spoons to stir food, pens to write poetry, cloths to soothe a feverish child. Our roots are in that small community that thrives even today as a historic restoration. And there is much we share with our sisters of early Nauvoo.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p4" pid="dDSvhXM4iEqwvuJQq56flg" hash="xnAtzQ">On the banks of the Mississippi River was a place where the Saints drained the swamp land, built a substantial city, and wanted to stay. Here, amid well-tended homes and fertile acres, was a pattern for Zion, a place where the people could be of one heart. Like the Nephite people so many years earlier, they wanted to “come into the fold of God, and to be called his people, … willing to bear one another’s burdens, that they may be light.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.8" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p5" pid="ubBpMrt8gkewVWk0rdm5Lw" hash="_SWx-Q">It was in this spirit that Relief Society was born when a handful of women gathered in Joseph Smith’s red brick store to unite their strength. First president, Emma Smith, told the women, “We are going to do something <span class="emphasis">extraordinary</span>—when a boat is struck on the rapids, with a multitude … on board, we shall consider <span class="emphasis">that</span> a loud call for <span class="emphasis">relief</span>—we expect extraordinary occasions and pressing calls.” (Minutes of the Female Relief Society of Nauvoo, 17 Mar. 1842; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p6" pid="mz19dvzU3kWqFKgfu6oALg" hash="GHWF1Q">They got them—involving themselves in everything from delivering breech babies to helping the destitute converts who steamed into Nauvoo. They were resolute, often sharing their hearts and hands in lonely moments when nothing else would lift the pain. They gathered goods and funds and distributed to those in need. Many worked in the fields and built their own homes. They cared for the sick, prayed for divine inspiration, and received and exercised power from on high.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p7" pid="-f2-wrFx4ke1DtjVdl9kZQ" hash="9YooxQ">Those Saints responded to the needs of their day. I am certain that their strength came from their ability to step forward with a resounding “Here am I, send me.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.27" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:27</a>.) Then they were off on the Lord’s errand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p8" pid="rxbRC4oF2kin11dFonD39A" hash="I4Z5JA">One of the youngest women in attendance at the first meeting of sisters was Bathsheba Smith, who served many years later as the fourth general president of the Relief Society. She had been well trained in those Nauvoo years and was known later for concluding her home visits—both social and compassionate—with the words, “Peace be unto thee, peace to this house.” (<span class="emphasis">Woman’s Exponent,</span> Sept. 1910, p. 18.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p9" pid="lEcmbTuYkkWI1UUro47ZDA" hash="B_Jitw">There are many Bathsheba Smiths in this world, many pioneering women who speak peace and give life to the Relief Society motto, “Charity Never Faileth.” In times past, more than one generation gleaned wheat in aprons and stored it in their own granaries, putting it to good use when the need came.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p10" pid="3afpeltqRU-FTtIZwD1pMw" hash="Tnpoag">And it did. Other sisters promoted health and nursing, establishing a hospital. Today, old and new blend as dedicated women bring sisterly support and love, keeping their appointed visits on horseback and on foot, by bus and by automobile. Over the decades and across continents, women have learned to value their faith and religion above comfort and personal priorities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p11" pid="a5nYPVIX1EeD-ZvABjpVCA" hash="kXvxHw">Our sisters are steadfast, always abounding in good works. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/15.58" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 15:58</a>.) They understand that the commandment is to develop an attitude as well as to undertake an action. “Be steadfast” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/31.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 31:9</a>)—immovable in righteousness, humble, caring, clever, kind, generous, thoughtful, dignified, gentle, diligent, direct. Women have such depth and such ability!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p12" pid="5K0BRyuIs0aMT4dNPF4IzQ" hash="r2eSpw">And such faith. Despite trials, worldly confusion, and caustic voices, we can trust in the Lord and go forward with happy hearts, knowing that with every challenge or problem, there’s the strength to go on. Why? Because we know His promises are real, that He does know us by name and has a plan for each of us. He will help us learn what it is and give us joy in doing it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p13" pid="EN_ubuUOfkGfzukVssFM1w" hash="bzYrgw">The experiences of women in Nauvoo and in every Relief Society throughout the Church prove that women individually can be a great force. Alma described the value of our contribution, stating, “By small and simple things are great things brought to pass.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.6" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:6</a>.) Women’s lives are full of small and simple things—discussions about how the day was, visits to schools, laughter at a homemade joke, work in its many forms, playing with children, trips to the doctor, tending the garden, cooking meals, teaching a lesson in church, helping a neighbor, serving a community group, sharing a lesson learned with a sister. Small and simple things that define relationships and build testimonies. Small and simple things that grow strong men and women.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p14" pid="_Vx7SQrtp0a0B9O97veGJQ" hash="rxvwpg">When we first organized as a sisterhood in Nauvoo, the Prophet Joseph Smith declared, “This is the beginning of better days.” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 6:607.) There has been an abundance of better days because of the contributions of women just like you. In homes large and small, rural and urban, Latter-day Saint women make a difference. In every type of family, women comfort hearts and renew dedication. We share wisdom and knowledge. We encourage and teach our family members.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p15" pid="eu34slzaZE-3mcOLsx3_nQ" hash="9hquTg">As sisters in Zion, we have added to the strength of each other. We see our sisterhood expressed in Sunday meetings and in homemaking meetings. Which of us has not felt a hand reach across to take ours just at the right moment? A sister has written a note or called to check on us just when our world was falling apart. As sisters we know, we understand, we feel for each other.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p16" pid="EUJW_UmEVEKMz-1W3p248w" hash="kqXXEw">Lucy Mack Smith, mother of the Prophet Joseph Smith, told the sisters of Relief Society in 1842, “We must cherish one another, watch over one another, comfort one another and gain instruction, that we may all sit down in heaven together.” (Minutes of the Female Relief Society of Nauvoo, 24 Mar. 1842.) Notice she talks of each of us eventually uniting in our Father’s house. But for now, we are here and we have work to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p17" pid="oAHjUDlS40SZ-Rix8KuP9g" hash="DJmpAQ">A year ago, in preparation for this great event, we asked members all around the world to send us pictures of women living the gospel in their daily lives. The response was dramatic! Folders came from all over the world. Some pictures were individually wrapped in tissues; some were priceless historical photographs; some sisters sent whole pages of scrapbooks. Some photographs were professionally done and some taken just with the family camera. Many included notes written in the native languages. No matter the country, the responses were similar to this message from Japan: “Thank you for the opportunity to be a part of this whole sisterhood. We love all of you.” Or this note from Africa: “You have lit a candle of joy in our minds.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p18" pid="oNKJMdyjMUO4le12qGmw_Q" hash="9pqZTw">We are part of a grand whole. We need each other to make our sisterhood complete. When we reach out to clasp the hands of our sisters, we reach to every continent, for we are of every nation. We are bonded as we try to understand what the Lord has to say to us, what He will make of us. We speak in different tongues, yet we are a family who can still be of one heart. We work, play, give birth, nurture, dream dreams; we cry, pray, laugh, sometimes clap for joy, and find that mortality teaches us our need for our Savior, Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p19" pid="1WU5tlultkOzGuXzA6kvKQ" hash="O59-ow">The Lord has told us, “Be glad, for I am in your midst.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/29.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 29:5</a>.) He is with all of us, and His spirit draws us closer as we link arms together in our gospel sisterhood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p20" pid="tBKq6wnZF0Kn9j0f7lSijA" hash="bmfxqw">As sisters in Zion, we still have pressing calls. We have calls to teach the gospel, to lift our families, to bless our neighbors, to aid our friends, to live by example, to share our understanding with others, and to bring souls unto Christ by the way we live and the way we love one another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth.p21" pid="lC9ttaA6gk-kfw5XCr6zSQ" hash="sj7aPg">Yes, as sisters in Zion, we are going to do something extraordinary.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1992/04/charity-never-faileth</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/relief-society-sesquicentennial-satellite-broadcast/1992-03-0010-elaine-l-jack-64k-eng.mp3" length="10291319" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 1992 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Look Up and Press On</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on?lang=eng</link>
      <description>When my four sons were all at home, my husband, Joe, and I spent many summer days hiking with them. Our favorite places to hike were in the high mountains. We all loved the challenge of a tough climb up and then that exhilarating moment of standing a</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_92905_000_049" doc-version="2" hash="EAdedQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="jc1I5Hi7x0y3tvZRxST8Rw" hash="MW5tOw">Look Up and Press On</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Hw50WTd1dk2Z2vY3ZXKH2Q" hash="9JKBXA">Elaine L. Jack</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e50.jpg" alt="President Elaine L. Jack" pid="oCj0IAvKOk2T8ePQNpFYQQ" hash="Ra9gOA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p1" pid="578Q8QGTBE-RrvNQVWtSqA" hash="1XRc5Q">When my four sons were all at home, my husband, Joe, and I spent many summer days hiking with them. Our favorite places to hike were in the high mountains. We all loved the challenge of a tough climb up and then that exhilarating moment of standing at what seemed to be the top of the world. We would carefully scan the horizon, relishing the sight of other peaks and valleys.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p2" pid="EC-viSGVmUqL9fcx0dBBYg" hash="ni7MEw">One of the best adventures of my life was the day we climbed three adjacent mountain passes. Beginning early in the morning, we began our ascent, moving ever higher. The hike proved long and demanding, yet each view held its own majesty and perspective. My satisfaction at what I saw far exceeded any weariness I felt. I have never forgotten the awe and accomplishment I experienced when I stood at the top of a mountain and looked out on this wide and wonderful world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p3" pid="dVxFONOevkSjccbktS3WAQ" hash="8Atd-A">Today, my beloved Relief Society sisters, we join hands around the world while we stand on another type of peak. From this pinnacle of 150 years of Relief Society, we survey the rich fruits of charity sown from seeds of faith in 135 countries and territories. How satisfying it is to see testimonies built, individuals blessed, charity developed and exercised, families strengthened, and sisterhood enjoyed by over three million Relief Society members.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p4" pid="aAyzDVfmWUquyGNOJdzP4A" hash="xYc6vw">Your vantage point may actually be a mountaintop. It may be the knoll of a grassy plain or a mound of sand in the desert. It could be a favorite stretch of beach or the icy crest of a snow-packed hill. It may be the top step of your own front porch. Whatever your perspective, today I ask you to stand arm in arm with me and look up! Let us climb together to new spiritual heights. We will echo Isaiah’s words, “Let us go up to the mountain of the Lord, to the house of the God of Jacob; and he will teach us of his ways, and we will walk in his paths.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/2.3" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 2:3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p5" pid="j3s9FwMMnkqa2gKFeVF6sQ" hash="0JSH2g">Today I ask you to undertake with me a spiritual journey worthy of our best efforts. I ask you to press forward with me in the quest for unparalleled levels of personal spirituality. Let us seek keener vision and stronger hearts. Let us make “Charity Never Faileth” a motto of such personal significance that the whole world will be blessed by us, the daughters of God who are the sisters of Relief Society.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p6" pid="Ym5peYKXmE6uFmSQ4NnXEA" hash="_e-c9A">With this broadcast, we join as we never have before. Never in the history of the Church have the women of Zion been linked so closely together. This is symbolic, reminding us that we come together in the greatest of all causes, the gospel of Jesus Christ. As a young girl growing up in the foothills of the Canadian Rockies, I often imagined climbing the distant peaks I could see. Today as we are literally linked together across the continents of the world, we ascend mountains far greater than those I saw.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p7" pid="9uPBFdFK2UGFjCyA2kS80g" hash="vwCE1g">Sisters, we are the covenant people, blessed to live on the earth when we can prepare in earnest for the second coming of our Savior. I pray that we will daily rejoice in being alive now when we can covenant through baptism and in the house of the Lord. I feel as Nephi expressed, “My soul delighteth in the covenants of the Lord … ; yea, my soul delighteth in his grace, and in his justice, and power, and mercy in the great and eternal plan of deliverance from death.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/11.5" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 11:5</a>.) To be a woman of covenant is a sacred and holy calling. Our covenants should ennoble us, serving as inspiration and incentive. A deepened understanding of our covenants lifts our vision to the loftier vistas awaiting us. As we are “true followers of … Jesus Christ,” we can become the daughters of God, “that when he shall appear we shall be like him, for we shall see him as he is.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.48" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:48</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p8" pid="x4UMTAUWCUiPcVP2zdZnlQ" hash="fSXb6A">In this quest for the best in us, we are like Sariah, who, with Lehi and their family, left Jerusalem at the Lord’s command. We stand with our “family, and provisions” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/2.4" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 2:4</a>), and we travel through the wilderness. We give “thanks unto the Lord our God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/2.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 2:7</a>.) Sometimes we grieve because of the hardened hearts of those we love. Some moments we are “filled with joy, and … exceedingly glad.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/5.1" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 5:1</a>.) At other times we “exhort … with all the feeling of a tender parent” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/8.37" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 8:37</a>), whether we are physical mothers or not. We toil. We encounter conflicts. We strive for faith. We “[suffer] all things.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.20" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:20</a>.) Yet, like Sariah, we keep moving towards exaltation, the ultimate promised land.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p9" pid="Ae-uHr78h02lHXBU8IGC8A" hash="5zSftQ">You recall that during the journey of Lehi and Sariah’s family, Nephi broke his bow. He was directed to “go forth up into the top of the mountain” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/16.30" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 16:30</a>) to obtain food for his family. I wonder when he reached the top if he paused, as I often have at such a height, to look around and see how far he and his family had come and the direction in which they still needed to go.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p10" pid="HPmbTz84CUKEAbSSX0zqzA" hash="9blYnQ">Beloved sisters, from my vantage point I see your goodness and potential. I know your lives have their difficulties. I also see how far you’ve climbed already and what dazzling heights you’ve attained. I feel the love of the Savior for you and your love for Him. Our Lord Himself promised, “I will go before your face. I will be on your right hand and on your left, and my Spirit shall be in your hearts, and mine angels round about you, to bear you up.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.88" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:88</a>.) With such a promise, we can keep going. With this assurance, we will rise to spiritual heights previously unimagined.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p11" pid="IirK9QicK0mlf9VILN22_w" hash="k9ZMYw">A ward Relief Society president recently shared with me the reaction of a community worker to her request to inform the sisters of local service needs. The president calmly explained that each Relief Society unit around the Church would be undertaking a project. The worker said, “You mean 18,000 groups of Relief Society women are going to do something in their local communities? Then you’ll change the world.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p12" pid="mdRhHklGQEeKpkKWtbt48g" hash="YuoA8g">We will change the world. For the better. For this journey to great heights is not any ordinary journey, any more than was Sariah’s. Ours is a quest to change ourselves, to become even truer disciples of our Lord and Savior. We will lift our eyes to the mountains and move ceaselessly towards exaltation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p13" pid="GB7_2shtEUmIL2-RPGuqsw" hash="sB_2_A">And how shall we scale this mountain? One faithful step at a time. I have a good friend with whom I have often counseled over the years about some of my gravest concerns. Particularly when I begin a new task and feel unsure, she invariably says enthusiastically, “How exciting! Elaine, you can do this.” I have been grateful for her confidence. Sisters, I say today, we can do this. We will build the kingdom of God—one person and one home at a time. Married, single, older, younger, mothering, or childless, we are going to prove that Eliza R. Snow, an early and inspired Relief Society leader, was right: “There is no sister so isolated, and her sphere so narrow but what she can do a great deal towards establishing the Kingdom of God upon the earth.” (<span class="emphasis">Woman’s Exponent,</span> 15 Sept. 1873, p. 62.) We will build the kingdom of God by lighting our homes with faith, whether we live alone or with a house full of family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p14" pid="U39TmoT33kOX96Fq9XXteQ" hash="K5nL2g">For many of us, the most rugged mountains we tackle are within the walls of our homes. Since we strive to become eternal family units, we should prize our families. Dear sisters, stay close to your husband, your children, your parents, your brothers and sisters, and those who feel like family because your lives have joined. Consider them your fellow voyagers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p15" pid="-9BENY2dp0Cxtxolr4id6Q" hash="K3uOqQ">A woman of mighty faith joined the Church and, because of pressing economic circumstances, left her family and homeland. Her journey took her far, but her faith took her farther. When she was well into her retirement years, she was called to be the ward Relief Society president. That calling brought forth a lifetime of knowledge and skill. She was a woman of such loving faith that the sisters of her Relief Society were drawn together as she put her arms around them physically and spiritually. A young mother asked her how she developed such radiant faith. This sister replied, “Turn your back on the problems and look for the light.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p16" pid="P-UnSTOAo0enUz_4yNZUrg" hash="I2htog">Sisters, as we climb the mountains, especially those in our own backyards, let us look to the Lord, who is the light. Show that light to your family and those who feel like family, for the brush at our feet will snag us, and obstacles will surely bruise us. But warm and steady, the light beckons us on. Follow it, knowing the challenges are real, but so is the Lord. Light a torch of faith at home and keep it burning brilliantly, even when the night is long and the journey difficult.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p17" pid="zgjQfmypHkaXe8coPT_7dA" hash="kp2H3A">We shall scale our spiritual peaks with courage. Courage is a powerful tool. With it we can dig into the bedrock and stand steady, even when the footing is treacherous. I see so much of courage in you. You walk miles to church. You rebuild a home ruined by floods. You go to school, sometimes with your desk on your head. You stretch limited money so you can feed your family. You face death, survive drought, and forgive after a divorce. You repent when that’s what is needed. You let go of old habits and espouse the gospel instead. You pay tithing when your children need shoes. You live through winter without warm clothes. You raise children alone. You accept a Church calling when you have no idea how to do it. You work to feel good about yourself, even as you feel so imperfect. You reach out to someone who may not extend a hand to you. You patch up a long-standing family argument. You put your family first, even when other options entice you. Cultivate courage, for it will help you live confidently and well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p18" pid="HjyC-CDkNUWbp0DOFAR_FA" hash="dY0Vxw">The prophet Moses told the children of Israel, who were ready to enter a new territory of many unknowns, “Be strong and of a good courage, fear not, nor be afraid … : for the Lord thy God, he it is that doth go with thee; he will not fail thee, nor forsake thee.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/deut/31.6" class="scriptureRef">Deut. 31:6</a>.) Sisters, the Lord will not fail or forsake us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p19" pid="bZUkc0PVe0mqZuS-lRJU_A" hash="aCs5jQ">We will climb our spiritual mountains rejoicing. Our hearts will resonate to Isaiah’s words, “For ye shall go out with joy, and be led forth with peace: the mountains and the hills shall break forth before you into singing, and all the trees of the field shall clap their hands.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/55.12" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 55:12</a>.) Each insight, each spiritual view should fill us with a spirit of thanksgiving that spills over into the lives of those around us. We sisters in Zion have the best reasons to thank the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p20" pid="KCYbqK89EUqN60myj9VO5Q" hash="atGPHw">Thank the Lord for your testimony. Thank Him for being alive now. When your challenges come, thank the Lord for your knowledge that He lives, and feel peace knowing He loves you. As you work hard, say, “The Lord doth give me exceedingly great joy in the fruit of my labors.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/36.25" class="scriptureRef">Alma 36:25</a>.) When you struggle, say, “I can do all things through Christ which strengtheneth me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/philip/4.13" class="scriptureRef">Philip. 4:13</a>.) With each new lesson learned and each answer to personal prayer, say, “I rejoice exceedingly that [my] Lord Jesus Christ hath been mindful of [me].” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/8.2" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 8:2</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p21" pid="golAd36ou0K9gDsqdyfcxQ" hash="bQWrOw">Today, arm in arm and hand in hand, we stand together on sand or rock or the steps of home. We look together in the direction of our heavenly home. May you, a member of Relief Society—and my sister—seek and find the loftiest, personal spiritual heights. May the peaks of spiritual awareness fill your soul with joy and inspire you to look up and to press on. And may this ascent we share witness in every home and in every nation “That he lives!” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:22</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on.p22" pid="sk7d1JkYJESLORXWWpHhWg" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1992/04/look-up-and-press-on</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/relief-society-sesquicentennial-satellite-broadcast/1992-03-0040-elaine-l-jack-64k-eng.mp3" length="12155254" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 1992 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Ponder the Path of Thy Feet”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear sisters, I want to share with you my feelings for the gospel and my love for my Father in Heaven. What a blessing to be together, to speak of the things that really matter, to know that we are united in this great work.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_93911_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="JSRCiQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="7S2VaQSrukO0pzOBiLJmwA" hash="wHFqwQ">“Ponder the Path of Thy Feet”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="fPNP_VlrAkK74ikLSkjpZQ" hash="9JKBXA">Elaine L. Jack</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p1" pid="LNJbsg6-pEeVol9VdRnKjg" hash="JNkTzA">My dear sisters, I want to share with you my feelings for the gospel and my love for my Father in Heaven. What a blessing to be together, to speak of the things that really matter, to know that we are united in this great work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p2" pid="ophhhqMdtUawZV2rb3oaxA" hash="DYcJlQ">We are here today not because of what we do but because of who we are—daughters of our Father in Heaven. We value such definition for we are women of covenant. Our covenants hold great significance because we have made them with the Lord. They act as a fortification against the powers of opposition, a reinforcement and reminder of why we are here. Women and men in this church bear testimony to the world that this life is the time to prepare to meet God. Even though we live in very difficult and challenging times, we are on the path to eternal life, and we cannot afford to be delayed or deterred.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p3" pid="WIA-cyFW-Eq869kh1Den3A" hash="ygjDmQ">In Proverbs we read the admonition, “Ponder the path of thy feet” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/4.26" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 4:26</a>). We have busy feet in this church. We do much. We have all heard the counsel to “be anxiously engaged” and then the qualifier “in a good cause” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.27" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:27</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p4" pid="EDrbYX_biEGMRVMfvkIZ7Q" hash="1nFavQ">It is that “good cause” I address tonight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p5" pid="ORgVRYARTUSMNVwHty9Bhw" hash="CVW6VQ">To be a woman of covenant is a sacred and holy responsibility. It is uniquely ours. It is not by chance that we are on the Lord’s errand at this time. It is by choice that we came to this earth to follow the path of the Savior. At baptism, we covenanted, as did the Nephites at the waters of Mormon, to be called his people, to serve him, to keep his commandments, to stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things and in all places (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.8-10" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:8–10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p6" pid="FlnyL_icWkWByFJwxGwYZQ" hash="9aoktw">Our covenant to follow Christ is in sharp contrast to many whose voices fill the newspapers, whose new morality blankets the screens, and whose values, while being updated, have become uprooted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p7" pid="KTaIICO7BUGLMWnvOG2a9A" hash="oMTs5Q">As women of covenant we seek exaltation and the peace that attends eternal life in the kingdom of heaven. With that resolve comes the quiet reassurance that speaks softly to our souls and reaffirms to us that peace and love, hope and gentility, reverence, joy, and obedience bring about change and good works. Indeed we stand before the world today to rejoice—not in the power of men and women—but in the goodness of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p8" pid="1d3871sGR0yV-SJO9Bve1g" hash="k8oqOw">Sisters, the time is past when we can merely believe. We must be passionate in our beliefs. Women hunger for things of the Spirit. One of the primary reasons women attend Relief Society is to be spiritually nourished, to learn more of God’s teachings. Our personal testimonies, growing as all of them are, champion our cause to “Come unto Christ.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p9" pid="pEumxcXhaUCye1yJwTJqcA" hash="wa3wug">Today we see all around us the adversary at work—and he is succeeding. He has twisted truths to his purposes, and throngs have followed. Either we are holding fast to the iron rod or, perhaps, unconsciously, we are letting go by just a few fingers and are slowly slipping away. “Not me,” you might say, but none of us is exempt. Nor are we immune to sidesteps in a frantic rush to do it all, the desire to have it all, and the justification to need it all—now. Satan is ruthless, and his efforts are never ending.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p10" pid="OWy59mGUpUmZ-DQUG3n7GQ" hash="AdLMYA">Eliza R. Snow said: “We stand in a different position … ; we have made covenant with God, we understand his order” (<span class="emphasis">Millennial Star,</span> Sept. 1871, p. 578). These covenants include the counsel to Emma Smith recorded in the Doctrine and Covenants to “lay aside the things of this world, and seek for the things of a better” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/25.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 25:10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p11" pid="w6vOrUIsukqAS6-WV2yBOg" hash="Rn5Xeg">I am dedicated to that charge.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p12" pid="18b4hVSNwEm3jPfihsa35w" hash="cuurAw">The path, straight and narrow, was marked by Jesus Christ. Isaiah called it the “highway … of holiness” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/35.8" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 35:8</a>). I testify to you today that the Lord has trusted the women of this church with most-sacred works on the path to perfection.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p13" pid="ETSTH1FKvUusjXcKh5VALA" hash="5QoMrQ">I heard from a mother of five small children in South Carolina. She had injured her back and was totally bedfast. She wrote to me of the “little mercy squads” in her ward who had cared for her night and day: “They fed me, conquered my mending pile, cleared the tears from my eyes, and administered therapy in the night. All the time they assured me it was no bother; they just wanted to learn more charity and just needed someone to practice on.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p14" pid="fO8SUngK0kSeQdVspxUFhA" hash="EE7oJA">There are times when we do have helping hands and times when there are no hands except the Lord’s hands.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p15" pid="qL22ehE2G0KSoGD9119WdQ" hash="urQC0A">A 93-year-old sister in Idaho describes her path with, “I have had happiness and much trouble, much sorrow.” Our experiences help us understand where she’s been. Though our Lord Jesus Christ could have called down the powers of heaven, his paths were often solitary and his agony—in the end—borne by him alone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p16" pid="KgVCGsqFVEa52DUzk49Xzw" hash="6Nonvg">Christ’s cause was singular and focused, for he proclaimed, “I came into the world to do the will of my Father” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.13" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 27:13</a>). And so must we. Our willingness to take seriously our covenants brings comfort amid sorrows, joy amid pain, blessings amid suffering.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p17" pid="FkFMYJapwUKL9wVjBX_wSQ" hash="Tayjsw">All around the Church are wonderful women who exert great influence. Sisters, we have much to share: our spiritual strength, our sense of purpose, our commitment to the gospel, our blessings as a result of the holy priesthood. Look closely with me at these four areas where we make such a difference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p18" pid="RT3DMdM8m0KbEtYF9cA8Rw" hash="i8782Q">
        <span class="emphasis">We are women with spiritual strength!</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p19" pid="pJocExznvEOR8uFgt8zV9w" hash="7iVTiw">We have within us the Spirit of the Lord to guide us on the path of righteousness. Daily, we choose between temptation and sanctification. We seek spiritual moments as we read the scriptures. We pray and carry that prayer in our hearts. We know the peace that comes from hearing not applause or an answering machine but that still small voice that whispers ever so softly. We listen less to the world and more to the promptings from on high.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p20" pid="nm6KWbS1dkONrynqIsdIUw" hash="XNLBOg">Remember that the spirit is not the same as self. The spirit is not enhanced by selfishness, self-pity, self-pride, and self-deception. “To be spiritually-minded is life eternal” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/9.39" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 9:39</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p21" pid="22e5w7NsUUOa09oYD202ow" hash="QUDoFw">Our spirituality is also recharged by each other. Show charity for each other. Show understanding, not judgment; kindness, not blame; joy, not envy. Love as the Lord loves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p22" pid="1NvYO9aV-0enK6i89WR6sA" hash="9Tx1mQ">I think of the small group of sisters in Bangalore, India, who meet together only once a month as Relief Society. The other weeks they meet individually in small groups in homes. I visited with them last year and quickly recognized how the Spirit of the Lord embraced that little band of women. When their thirty-year-old president, a convert of two years, introduced me and bore testimony of the blessings of the sisterhood of Relief Society, I was touched by the love felt for one another. They are women of God. I could feel his Spirit then just as I feel it with us tonight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p23" pid="ofOLAKv7VUCCRNI4JN_kSQ" hash="xizrNg">
        <span class="emphasis">We are women with a sense of purpose!</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p24" pid="Te7Kn4bFtkOl4bvhKJgKzQ" hash="CK9MIg">The Old Testament prophet Micah said, “For all people will walk every one in the name of his god, … we will walk in the name of the Lord our God for ever and ever” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/micah/4.5" class="scriptureRef">Micah 4:5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p25" pid="ZHuOmZFzIkS64SImcvXcDg" hash="prE0wg">How, in this complex world, do we walk in the name of the Lord, our God, when questions of home, family, marriage, work, children, age, and death play so much a part of our day-to-day experiences? How do we think like the Lord when we are low, wisely when we are weary, feel patient when we are pressured and respected when we are rejected?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p26" pid="pdasvtj3MEuatGLtp8eGbQ" hash="_vNB-g">Sisters, turn to the Lord. He cares so deeply for our happiness and our well-being. Talk with him earnestly and often, and your answers will come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p27" pid="4tQtFBLPqUGUg42ZmFPuyg" hash="5WKpSw">Next, look at your priorities. As women of covenant we must hold close to our hearts the things that really matter. Homes, families, and people matter. For those who have young and growing children, they are our first priority. I am not speaking of maintenance, not the wash, not the windows. I am speaking of loving our children and teaching them righteous principles. I am speaking of a willing heart that puts the eternal needs of children in our charge ahead of our own personal style. I’m talking about the pain when a child has strayed from the path and we lead that child back one step at a time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p28" pid="D9fKDYmg10C0BZB_vWHxFw" hash="w02B0A">As a young mother I remember saying to my youngest son, Gordon, when he fell from his bike and faced not only skinned knees but the loss of confidence as well, “I’m right here.” I would say as I put my arms around him to comfort him, “I’m right here.” Doesn’t that remind us of the Lord, who is with us always? (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/28.20" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 28:20</a>). He’s not just at church, in the temple, or when we kneel at our bed. He’s “right here” when we live by his teachings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p29" pid="jsNcbwmXhEKiNuafXLbp0Q" hash="f8YnBA">
        <span class="emphasis">We are women of commitment!</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p30" pid="oi4BWbb8bkmYfr2IeaLR7g" hash="QFAJAw">I witnessed commitment when I visited with a sister in her home in the Philippines. She had nothing by the standards of the world. Her family of eight children lived clustered in a two-room nipa hut that stood on stilts. After climbing the ladder to the door, I was taken immediately to a corner where on a small table sat a portable sewing machine. This was not a new model with 320 stitches, bells, whistles, and a serger. It was a machine older than my mother’s! But she was not showing off a possession; she was sharing her commitment. For two years, she had sewn for others on that simple machine to earn the money to take her family to the temple so that they would be sealed together. The last child, she said with a smile, was born under the covenant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p31" pid="IntTQjhd20OpfbTYWIP3Cw" hash="6yJQ1Q">She was committed to her covenants, and she valued the blessings of the priesthood that came into her life because of her faithfulness. She did not stop at baptism, for she understood, where “much is given much is required” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/82.3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 82:3</a>). By her efforts, her family was sealed—forever. Imagine their joy!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p32" pid="soh5fXV-PUa_cDKxIi-A6w" hash="-scnvQ">
        <span class="emphasis">We are women who know the blessings of the priesthood.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p33" pid="lx6Fzlw95EqcB2AGrmrwqw" hash="KOlmnw">We have the blessings of the priesthood in these latter days to help us see clearly and act accordingly. As disciples of Christ we are blessed with more than common sense, good ideas, and righteous inclinations. We must always remember that “Jesus Christ is the great High Priest of God; Christ is therefore the source of all true priesthood authority and power on this earth” (<span class="emphasis">Encyclopedia of Mormonism,</span> New York: Macmillan, 1992, p. 1133).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p34" pid="mock3aQTh0-Hb3B4nCPSfA" hash="jaajBg">We know what it is to place our faith, our prayers, our confidence, and our esteem in those whom God has appointed to lead. The Lord has told us that “whether by mine own voice or by the voice of my servants, it is the same” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:38</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p35" pid="eW649-nsAEysIoSeHn_HPw" hash="r0anlg">I want you to know that I, as the general president of the Relief Society, embrace the blessings that come from serving under the direction of leaders who hold the priesthood. We must stand united as a people for the Lord to call us one. Elder John A. Widtsoe spoke of men and women yoked together in their joint devotion to righteous principles when he said: “In the ordinances of the Priesthood man and woman share alike. … In the Church of Christ, woman is not an adjunct to, but an equal partner with man” (<span class="emphasis">Relief Society Magazine,</span> June-July 1943, p. 373).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p36" pid="Lh_HzLcYe0yI9Ja-coyLIw" hash="SBOBqA">Women and men have available every priesthood blessing essential for salvation—the blessings of being baptized, receiving the Holy Ghost, renewing our covenants through taking the sacrament, and making and keeping temple covenants. As women of covenant, we know and understand the guidance in the Doctrine and Covenants, which is counsel for women as well as for men: “Their hearts are set so much upon the things of this world, and aspire to the honors of men, that they do not learn this one lesson—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p37" pid="vKK9l-YezUGTeH7zmON1kQ" hash="QXXanQ">“… the powers of heaven cannot be controlled nor handled only upon the principles of righteousness” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.35-36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:35–36</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p38" pid="cq4r0GpJfUWuGaDGY-3RiA" hash="SFVI8g">Now, once again, may I say, “Ponder the path of thy feet.” Look to the Lord for direction and guidance as my choice counselors and this faithful sister have testified here tonight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p39" pid="OJL3dCLbdEuqBfVvfH9brg" hash="MT0j-g">Ponder the direct message from an Apostle of Jesus Christ. Elder M. Russell Ballard has counseled us not to judge others. We were reminded that each of us has the privilege to carefully and prayerfully seek the Lord’s will, just for us, regarding life’s challenges. Further, he reminded us that this is God’s plan and it is not our prerogative to alter or tamper with it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet.p40" pid="0D60iUlNpUC0Cd8Gt3WO8w" hash="brwgWA">I ask that each of you take to heart these messages and know that they come from the Lord through his servants. To their testimonies I add my own. I know that we, daughters of the Most High God, are here to do the Lord’s will in an era most difficult, yet at a time that the angels of God rejoice in our efforts. I know that the Lord reigns supreme and that he has prepared a place for us in his kingdom on high. I know that as women of covenant we will choose that path to life eternal. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1993/10/ponder-the-path-of-thy-feet</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/1993-general-relief-society-meeting/1993-09-0050-elaine-l-jack-64k-eng.mp3" length="7016455" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 1993 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Walk with Me”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I stand before you today grateful for our Redeemer, Jesus Christ, grateful for this gospel, grateful for the priesthood that blesses our lives, and for the goodness of all of you. This gathering of Saints at general conference reminds me of Isaiah’s </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_94905_000_007" doc-version="2" hash="4riSgA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="urDifSeiZE2mzEcUloBmtw" hash="jkvi-Q">“Walk with Me”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="6VK8j6MCFUe96GRQpKC0_g" hash="9JKBXA">Elaine L. Jack</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/ensignlp.nfo-o-1e50.jpg" alt="Elaine L. Jack" pid="Udu9zJMH3EeyJpyLnAvVgA" hash="Ra9gOA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p1" pid="3T6RoxXQb0ONccEcckB9vQ" hash="Sl9pKQ">I stand before you today grateful for our Redeemer, Jesus Christ, grateful for this gospel, grateful for the priesthood that blesses our lives, and for the goodness of all of you. This gathering of Saints at general conference reminds me of Isaiah’s joyous proclamation, “Holy, holy, holy, is the Lord of hosts: the whole earth is full of his glory” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/6.3" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 6:3</a>). Righteous Saints are the glory of God, and there are mighty legions gathered here and in many lands.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p2" pid="1T2x55ZQ0k-sspPBxDgd0A" hash="GWh7jA">Before we came to this earth, we shouted for joy at the opportunity to take this leap of faith in our eternal progression. When we were baptized, we stepped firmly onto the path to eternal life. The prophet Nephi said, “After ye have gotten into this strait and narrow path, I would ask if all is done? … Nay; for ye have not come thus far save it were by the word of Christ with unshaken faith in him. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p3" pid="frhHixfNCUiFYsGMDhndKg" hash="q6_y3w">“Wherefore, ye must press forward with a steadfastness in Christ. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p4" pid="SeuNflTQPE-VnSiPBLvJYw" hash="C6qGwA">“Behold, … this is the way” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.19-21" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:19–21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p5" pid="IeveXmf2BkyYGyz6ZYVHuQ" hash="jXMxkA">How do we press forward on the straight and narrow way? How do we focus on our eternal progression when we live in a world that demands such attention to daily tasks? How do we remain steadfast when so much around us is laden with sin? The people in Enoch’s day faced these same challenges. Enoch began his ministry preaching to an unrighteous audience, but the people softened their hearts and heeded the words of the Lord to “walk with me” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/6.34" class="scriptureRef">Moses 6:34</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p6" pid="sJQalwa2f0Wi0jw1iWMhOA" hash="ZjWbOA">So can we.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p7" pid="06D0pCxQmkyESS6py16Gfg" hash="NkCtww">Our eternal progression on that straight and narrow path in the company of the Lord Jesus Christ is the focus of my message today. This is a journey made up of many steps. Our progress on this journey is determined by recognizing the straight and narrow path, having an eternal perspective, and acting accordingly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p8" pid="KOX4ogNvm0GcrQTX8ypulQ" hash="FdZ-Hw">Remember, our eternal progression is the very essence of our earthly existence. It is the Lord’s plan to get us all the way home to our Father in Heaven. This I know: Each of us can get there from here.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p9" pid="IVj3GUJ02EK6sluSalpvOw" hash="kOqIbg">President Spencer W. Kimball promised, “It may seem a little difficult at first, but when a person begins to catch a vision of the true work, when he begins to see something of eternity in its true perspective, the blessings begin to far outweigh the cost of leaving ‘the world’ behind” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> June 1976, p. 6).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p10" pid="iVnyIzui0kOwkdXpm3UEBg" hash="zZjzvQ">Some of our steps come in learning that the path is indeed straight and narrow. The concept of a straight path intrigues me. So often we go around in a circle, spinning our spiritual wheels while only our temporal treads hit the road. That seems out of step and out of balance with the way the Lord intended. We have knowledge and spiritual power; such momentum far exceeds anything the world has to offer. Putting off to tomorrow is to fall behind, step backward, and open the door to the subtle influences of Satan. “There is no such thing as standing still in the eternal work of our God” (George Q. Cannon, <span class="emphasis">Millennial Star,</span> 23 Feb. 1899, p. 117).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p11" pid="d-ZgSk8LiEmM_bU3vb6yFA" hash="SLxfmQ">Elder Neal A. Maxwell has said, “There are no separate paths back to that heavenly home. Just one straight and narrow way, at the end of which, though we arrive trailing tears, we shall at once be ‘drenched in joy’” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1978, p. 11).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p12" pid="a7XF0ounT0abpsvjQasWhQ" hash="Lgnr8A">Indeed, the path is not soft, green grass; it is not without hardship and heartache. It is often an uphill climb strewn with rocks, many of them in the shape of mighty boulders. We can’t predict what our challenges will be because our lives are all different. Though the path is narrow, our moves are not scripted. There are diversions which attempt to lure us from the straight and narrow. It is our covenants that are the road signs to eternal life. Just as it is more difficult to read the signs on the main road from a side street, so too it is more difficult to hear the still, small voice of warnings, rough road ahead, when we have distanced ourselves from our covenants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p13" pid="llGpj9THbkGE1Du5w4jT5w" hash="3k0kzA">When the Lord says “walk with me” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/6.34" class="scriptureRef">Moses 6:34</a>), He is asking us to become more spiritual by being obedient to His word. Developing spirituality is critical to our eternal progress.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p14" pid="VUF1VRDxPUiNwc1TOb6E1g" hash="cLWgog">Our prophet has spoken for the Lord in our day, and his messages have been explicit: rid your heart of pride; read the Book of Mormon every day. In following that counsel, I discover new insights suddenly appearing in my Book of Mormon which are so pertinent to my immediate needs.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p15" pid="b6gHtNjZkk26JDMHaQxz6g" hash="aIRarA">We’ve been given tools to develop that spirituality. We are told to attend Church meetings, work hard in callings, go to the temple, be generous in offerings to the Lord, hold family home evening, and visit one another. But simply being there does not sanctify us; statistics do not drive eternal progression. Still, we cannot ignore that being in the right place at the right time will put us in a frame of mind to learn, in an environment where the Lord’s influence is invited and strong.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p16" pid="u4scsikc5EaNqZSbdUYHBg" hash="gm0lNg">Alma described what happens when we are not only present but counted as Christ’s disciples when he said, “Have ye spiritually been born of God? Have ye received his image in your countenances? Have ye experienced this mighty change in your hearts?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.14" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:14</a>.) Have ye “felt to sing the song of redeeming love?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.26" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:26</a>.) Spirituality is all about feeling the Spirit of God, wanting it with us, sharing the Spirit with others, and heeding its prompting.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p17" pid="wjMcy9j0aUCCSYB-ag3ThA" hash="mku9tg">Finally, progressing along the straight and narrow is characterized by making the Lord’s work our work, serving as He would. Such work is grounded in charity, a principle Relief Society sisters have embraced for many years, for “charity never faileth” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/13.8" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 13:8</a>). Charity helps us maintain our footing when all around us are skidding about.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p18" pid="SeWcgFCfakyEiIcFkBhc3w" hash="6fnH8g">Priscilla Samson-Davis, a sister in Ghana, has known struggles. There have been many rocks on the path of her life. As a teacher she has watched families nurse children through dysentery and malaria, work hard, barter daily for sacks of rice, onions, tomatoes, any food to keep their loved ones alive. She serves as a visiting teacher, regularly traveling on the bus to see a sister on the other side of town. When asked if this task were a burden, given all she had to manage, she simply replied, “It’s not hard. The woman I visit can’t read. When I go, I read the scriptures to her.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p19" pid="BdOQcBK44kuGx2ICUSY80A" hash="OhKYhg">Her simple answer testified to the faith and assurance she had that she was on the proper path. Though her bus route was halting and likely wound up and down streets, in the Lord’s eyes it was truly straight and narrow, for she was going in the right direction. She was about her Father’s business. She exemplified the spirit described by President Ezra Taft Benson when he said, “The best measure of true greatness is how Christlike we are” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1986, p. 78).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p20" pid="fI104dZdK0CbSbDg6FRyFA" hash="R8PjFA">Without question, those progressing eternally are those on the straight and narrow; they are spiritual and charitable. A bishop in the Dominican Republic exemplifies such a life. After sacrament meeting in his ward, a new convert approached him and said, “Bishop, I notice that the members are always looking at books when they sing. I want to do that. They look at books in Sunday School class. I want to do that.” Quietly, the brother said, “Bishop, I want to be a good member. I want to do all the Lord’s work. But I can’t read. Is there someone who can teach me?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p21" pid="-yMorGABTkqGMDa4XfluTw" hash="Gz9ReQ">“Yes,” said the bishop. And then he tried to think of a likely tutor. He found himself saying, “I’ll teach you to read.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p22" pid="hMtC5O727UWAT4vRFPdRvg" hash="FRy4HA">For many months this new convert and his wife met weekly with the bishop. They learned to read using the scriptures. Now this was a busy bishop, like they all are. He could have delegated the responsibility, but the Spirit had prompted him to take the assignment. They became friends in the gospel as they studied together. After two years, the bishop was released and a new bishop called. Sustained to follow him as the leader of the ward was his student of the scriptures. This bishop set out to teach his friends how to read the gospel message; and in the process, he showed them how to live it. Could this bishop have seen the end when he began? How often do we follow the dictums of the Lord and in doing so influence eternity?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p23" pid="-0VeeipORUKLZJ0R789s7A" hash="KhpxDA">Focusing on our eternal purposes can ease our burdens and make our lives happy and more productive. Indeed, we often can do less and have it mean more. In Luke we read of Martha receiving Jesus into her home. Her sister Mary “sat at Jesus’ feet, and heard his word.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p24" pid="FMc2ARhUYUKqil6RKhcCgA" hash="D03ZEA">“But Martha was cumbered about much serving” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.39-40" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:39–40</a>), and she complained that Mary did not help her. Did Jesus urge Mary to rush back to the tasks of the day? No. “Jesus answered and said unto her, Martha, … thou art careful and troubled about many things:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p25" pid="NGdxa9sf80ynJ7HEj1YmGg" hash="O3q-xQ">“But one thing is needful: and Mary hath chosen that good part” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.41-42" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:41–42</a>). The message holds true today: Choose the Lord’s way for it is glory everlasting.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p26" pid="gI9JG3M3I0KBJK1yZZm3mA" hash="ZVSO1w">We know why we are here. When we are on the path, we can feel it. The fruits of eternal progress are manifest in joy, peace, love, hope, increased confidence in the Lord. Though the path is narrow, it is sure. It is on this path that we testify daily of our love for the Lord, His children, His church, His counsel, and the richness of His blessings. By our good works we magnify what is mighty in us all, one step at a time, one day at a time, all the time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me.p27" pid="Dj5LU9-qQ02-n-rvqsrIug" hash="Qg9K_w">We know the path; in fact, we know it well. The prophet Nephi promised, “If ye shall press forward, feasting upon the word of Christ, and endure to the end, behold, thus saith the Father: Ye shall have eternal life” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.20" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:20</a>). May it be so. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1994/04/walk-with-me</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1994-general-conference/1994-04-1050-elaine-l-jack-64k-eng.mp3" length="5319879" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 1994 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Seek, and Ye Shall Find”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear sisters, how I have looked forward to this time when I can speak with you and share what is in my heart. As sisters in Relief Society, we are bound together by our faith in Jesus Christ and in his gospel. We always draw strength from being to</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_94911_000_035" doc-version="2" hash="l01Ueg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="7ZW7l1apuUKCvvkx-gM60w" hash="ZOiQrQ">“Seek, and Ye Shall Find”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="JKN8RObqFkCZpIPNllxbNA" hash="9JKBXA">Elaine L. Jack</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e50.jpg" alt="President Elaine L. Jack" pid="YpKTRIdS90SJIQp7gJkbGg" hash="Ra9gOA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p1" pid="XoH253OZqECwXeDnx_hIqA" hash="p8gmeQ">My dear sisters, how I have looked forward to this time when I can speak with you and share what is in my heart. As sisters in Relief Society, we are bound together by our faith in Jesus Christ and in his gospel. We always draw strength from being together—wherever we are assembled.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p2" pid="XD20B36OZEuZPGWQzCifiw" hash="Cusezw">I have lived during the leadership of eight different Presidents of the Church, and I have a testimony of the divine calling of each of these prophets and their predecessors. I was born when President Heber J. Grant was leading this church. I raised my family drawing upon the wisdom of President David O. McKay. I have served as general president of the Relief Society these past four years under the direction of President Ezra Taft Benson. Today we have the blessing of having with us the prophet, Howard W. Hunter, the fourteenth President of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p3" pid="isVczBtwMUWTz_vishSIRw" hash="lt5Yew">President Hunter, we love you. We are inspired by your quiet, noble countenance, your kindness, your discernment, and your dedication. We are grateful for your compelling message to follow the example of Jesus Christ in a spirit of thoughtfulness, compassion, and humility. And we thank God for the keys of the holy priesthood which you exercise and thus bless us all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p4" pid="M-SN1eLimUG_2s3HaqGVQA" hash="Guedyg">Speaking for more than three and a half million sisters of Relief Society, I express our support for you as a prophet, seer, and revelator of this church. Though the opportunity officially to raise our hands to sustain you is reserved for general conference next week, today, on behalf of the women of this church, I say, “We thank … God, for a prophet to guide us in these latter days” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> 1985, no. 19). President Hunter, we also commit our sustaining support for your Counselors, the members of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles, the Quorums of the Seventy, and the Presiding Bishopric. We want you to know that the sisters of this church work gladly and harmoniously under the direction of our priesthood leaders at both the general and the local levels.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p5" pid="4xvOAqjtTEKR_IsihcJsgg" hash="qX7ifA">As we have witnessed the transition of leadership from President Benson to President Hunter, it is clear this is a church of order. Jesus Christ has established the order of things on this earth. We need not worry, for he has told us, “Let your hearts be comforted concerning Zion; for all flesh is in mine hands; be still and know that I am God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/101.16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 101:16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p6" pid="3TKpAxit20eNnrrKbivU-A" hash="bVHyKg">Relief Society is a part of that order, for it is the Lord’s organization for women. Our reach extends around the world, and our influence is vital for all women. Forty years ago, President Belle S. Spafford paid tribute to pioneer women leaders, describing them as those who “had been given by divine insight a knowledge of the destiny of Relief Society” (Jill Mulvay Derr, Janath Russell Cannon, and Maureen Ursenbach Beecher, <span class="emphasis">Women of Covenant: The Story of Relief Society,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1992, p. 337). Today Relief Society is continuing to become what they envisioned so many years ago. As Relief Society sisters, we exemplify brightness and hope, spirituality and compassion. We are women of many cultures, ages, and experiences, united together to build testimonies and exercise the charity for which we are known.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p7" pid="PLb2lq1WCk6N8rfu8gdq3A" hash="vpx-ig">Sisters, this is a complicated era in which we live. Technology has simplified some tasks and opened up ways to learn that our grandmothers never imagined. But with a computerized society have come increased pressures, causing us to weigh carefully how we use our time, to evaluate thoughtfully what we can do that will make the greatest difference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p8" pid="3cowrLcOKkaCK7EFmtEvYw" hash="IoYbVw">Our society of sisters brings an ability to work, to influence, teach, train, and uplift. We also bring a remarkable zest for life. Daily—even courageously—sisters of this church are living true to the covenants they have made.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p9" pid="Uky8NYVBcE6zWbN1djN6oQ" hash="4m4QSg">So many of you have written to me of your experiences, your trials, your triumphs, and your testimonies. I am grateful for your willingness to share what you have learned. What I have seen emerging is a profile of women who understand that “the Lord requireth the heart and a willing mind” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.34" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:34</a>). Let me share some of these experiences with you, for they teach powerful lessons.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p10" pid="vjwr0DT7GUKytsMWwxkPbQ" hash="1eN1sQ">A sister in New Mexico described trying to gain an understanding of a conference message: “I read and reread the talk, prayed often, and pondered upon its meaning. … The results were astonishing to me. I had always believed I was a child of God, but somewhere in this study process I gained a spiritual confirmation that this was true.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p11" pid="lJCiXE5BLUCnsAIv2emL9g" hash="6NfAnQ">In Argentina, Relief Society leaders are trying to teach the importance of food storage. They wrote: “Unfortunately, most of the sisters [here] cannot afford to buy an extra kilo of sugar, or flour, or an extra liter of oil. However, they have been encouraged to save, even just a spoonful at a time.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p12" pid="f0UvpewFbU-vg1egooyqqA" hash="A2jgtw">In Tonga, Relief Society sisters came together to clean the local school. “It was a wonderful sight watching the sisters as they worked with their hoes and bush knives, … [hearing] the sweet sound of coconut-frond brooms as they gathered debris. The joy of working together has bonded the … sisters in the spirit of compassionate service.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p13" pid="r-z9_MBhd0iWPNoHTSPmVQ" hash="lcgrmA">A sister in South Africa wrote: “Our stake is one of the farthest from the headquarters of the Church, but even though we are continents apart, our hearts beat as one; and as Relief Society sisters, we are striving to emulate the Savior who gave His life in service to others.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p14" pid="knD8BzI470GVhVOh9P_Dpw" hash="tIDmLQ">I received a similar letter from Broken Arrow, Oklahoma, from a woman who said: “At the age of 19, I sat next to a sweet grandmother in Relief Society and learned to knit. She also was learning to knit. Over the years, I learned of bread making, of strength and perseverance. I learned that my toddler was just being a normal two-year-old, and I learned of a Heavenly Father who loves me. I learned to teach, to hug, to lead, and to follow.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p15" pid="RyNIgZR6IEmqb0wkXWnUaA" hash="3HYIZw">A Relief Society leader in Georgia wrote of the magnanimous service given after a devastating flood in the region. She said: “The sisters here are living the teachings of the Savior. Please tell Sister Jack not to worry about us. The sisters here are a mobilized unit of charity. We won’t fail.” Thank you! I take heart in the conviction that “we won’t fail.” All around this church, women are doing their part.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p16" pid="91PC4vaUNUmPdlCVRyEBWg" hash="5S022Q">The Lord has counseled us directly in this dispensation to seek the Spirit—to learn much—that we might “lay aside the things of this world, and seek for the things of a better” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/25.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 25:10</a>). I feel strongly that this is a clarion call for the women of this church at this time. For us to stand firm and faithful, we must be clearly focused on seeking the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p17" pid="i5RcKU63ZEqH7tMQ3opw3Q" hash="S1NIdw">Seeking implies so much more than merely looking. <span class="emphasis">Seek</span> means energy, direction, passion, purpose. To seek requires all our “heart, might, mind and strength” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/4.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 4:2</a>). We sisters are good at using our hearts and our hands in the Lord’s work. But we must also use our minds. More than one hundred years ago, Relief Society President Emmeline B. Wells said, “I believe in women, especially thinking women” (“Why, Ah! Why” <span class="emphasis">Woman’s Exponent,</span> vol. 3, Oct. 1, 1874, p. 67). So do I.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p18" pid="9uQ-_EQmXUOTeqiSHPCfLQ" hash="iMJGXQ">How do we seek with our minds? With our intellect we can ponder, we can analyze our circumstances, we can sort and sift information, weigh our options; we can store ideas, we can draw conclusions from our experiences, find answers to our problems; we can treasure thoughts and receive revelation. Isn’t that what the Lord meant when he said, “You must study it out in your mind” and then ask me if these things are not true? (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/9.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 9:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p19" pid="nD_QCjsvSUGVgESDNfcDOw" hash="1kYzAQ">This statement of the Prophet Joseph Smith inspires me: “Thy mind … if thou wilt lead a soul unto salvation, must stretch as high as the utmost heavens” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 3:295). We must stretch our minds if we are to reach that lofty goal so familiar to us all: “The glory of God is intelligence, or, in other words, light and truth” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:36</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p20" pid="hUAJEeTe_0S-hBuKY_4AtQ" hash="_7LPmw">As we earnestly seek light and truth, we develop clarity in our lives that reflects spiritual understanding and commitment. This clarity results as we learn from our daily experiences, our thoughtful study, and as we receive personal inspiration from the Holy Spirit. We have been promised:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p21" pid="hdXe4U4P0UWUYqzwPepzrA" hash="qqAJ5w">“Whatever principle of intelligence we attain … in this life, it will rise with us in the resurrection.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p22" pid="WO9qA27ykU-XheCcCZh5ng" hash="RMyJ5g">“And if a person gains more knowledge … in this life through his diligence … , he will have so much the advantage in the world to come” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/130.18-19" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 130:18–19</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p23" pid="pe3tWBkqj0ibFR6IX7b8vQ" hash="Hd4jvA">Learning—converting light and truth to everyday action in living the laws of God—is what we seek.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p24" pid="VvJ8Pio6G0i-iBZckoaRmg" hash="4MM2Ng">Not long ago I was speaking to Relief Society women in North Dakota. After our Saturday morning meeting, we boarded a chartered bus with some of the sisters who had attended the leadership meeting to return for a women’s fireside in South Dakota. We expected the bus ride to take four hours. It took the rest of the day and part of the evening.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p25" pid="yRauZ2hZQUiITWWT11-DZg" hash="vDvTFg">The bus broke down three times.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p26" pid="usABmQcKqUWzUnZIfFy3Kw" hash="tTO-2g">We spent half the afternoon at a rest stop, but after a tedious wait, the bus driver finally got the motor going.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p27" pid="dsg7yKfYfUSaJ1BVTJQi2A" hash="9eLI6g">This could have been a miserable experience. There were families anticipating their mothers’ return; there were rides waiting to take some women on the bus another three hours to their homes. It was hot.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p28" pid="6uCsGhF0gkSyvwp-dSRcKw" hash="x_p2hA">But on that prairie ride I had both a learning and a spiritually fulfilling experience. Two hours from our destination, one of the sisters stood in the aisle at the front of the bus and bore her testimony. One after another, sisters spoke of the power of priesthood blessings in their homes, of direct answers to prayers during serious illness, of the influence of the Spirit in employment opportunities, of being guided in accepting the gospel. Through their testimonies, I saw how easily the light and truth of the gospel influenced their daily learning experiences.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p29" pid="o8x-jbJ1i0Gmz3czLlwxnw" hash="Y8rqxQ">The Lord has given us a lifetime to learn. This process is part of our eternal progression. President Brigham Young emphasized its importance when he said: “When shall we cease to learn? … Never, never” (in <span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses,</span> 3:203).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p30" pid="zBg9qC92UUeOpLUN16h4kA" hash="i_MwtA">Relief Society is a modern forum where sisters learn spiritual truths together. We can learn in an accepting atmosphere of trust and friendship. In Relief Society we stretch our minds and we fill up our reservoir of faith. A sister from Spain wrote of this process: “Since we have become members of this church, our vision has changed. Our minds have been awakened, and we want to learn. We have a great desire to cultivate our intellect as we are taught through the manuals of our beloved organization.” She then describes how some are going on to school, and one, the bishop’s wife, has attended the university. “We are all so very proud of her,” she said.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p31" pid="FiqOS30eP0Cj_5D0UL_pVw" hash="V_ZZHg">These Relief Society sisters are seeking learning, and they are supporting each other in the process. They are using their minds and their might.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p32" pid="p4SjFq1KG06hm_uLeoH-mA" hash="CBxkTA">In their focus on learning, these women are part of a burgeoning literacy effort in the Church. In announcing the focus on literacy to all the Church, President Gordon B. Hinckley said: “Now a great new project is to be undertaken. … Its consequences will go on and on and be felt in the lives of generations yet to come. It is a program … designed to bring light into the lives of those who can neither read nor write” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Mar. 1992, p. 6).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p33" pid="6q9saSINSE-scRlzxKV3hQ" hash="J2s0uA">Seeking to be literate is a compelling challenge. Being able to read enables us to seek further light and truth. Light is more than being able to see with eyes. It includes revelation of things as they are, as they were, and as they are to come. Light brings definition out of darkness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p34" pid="FoxYYwGjUU2S51YlGsQwiw" hash="2sLFuQ">Light and truth are not obscure terms. Truth is basic to the gospel. The more we seek to know, the better we are able to distinguish between a foolish notion and a wise idea. From such wisdom, we find truth. As we sang, “Truth, the sum of existence, will weather the worst, Eternal, unchanged, evermore” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> 1985, no. 272).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p35" pid="dSYHDaFqAEKiSFI48SEvag" hash="ipJeVw">Fervently, we seek truth. Of course there are, all around us, many who seek to do good deeds, for we in the Church do not have a corner on goodness. But we have the Spirit that allows us to recognize and discern the truth wherever we find it. This knowledge sets us apart and brings joy, as well as weighty responsibility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p36" pid="OgGb_Zv7uUe_pCMV9aDjjw" hash="TRaVag">We must seek to know Jesus Christ, for this is knowledge that is singular and everlasting. Jesus told us explicitly, “Draw near unto me and I will draw near unto you; seek me diligently” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.63" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:63</a>). Sisters, if I could offer but two words of counsel, they would be “Seek Jesus!” Moroni counseled, “Seek this Jesus of whom the prophets and apostles have written, that the grace of God the Father, and also the Lord Jesus Christ, and the Holy Ghost, which beareth record of them, may be and abide in you forever” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.41" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:41</a>). What a promise, and what a challenge!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p37" pid="IYn6VrV3X0yRLpvmL6jNpw" hash="EMmBMg">Seeking Jesus feeds our spiritual soul and at the same time prompts us to feed others. We do it in small ways, and these efforts make a big difference. Seeking Jesus helps us to prioritize, to find time to read the scriptures every day so we can feel the Spirit of the Lord all day long. Seeking Jesus is learning to balance what we feel in our hearts with what we know to be true in our minds, and show through our actions that we understand that balance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p38" pid="pniRqrmvqEueCIAyJX6_ng" hash="VmW1Og">We often hear the statement “Times have changed,” and in some ways they have. But they have also stayed the same. What is constant is the message testified to us by the Holy Spirit that we must seek Jesus and the truths of the everlasting gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find.p39" pid="v5uGIff-ak6Udp5f0rH2Yw" hash="t7yB9g">I bear testimony that these truths are given to us by a loving Heavenly Father. They will give us the knowledge and strength to live our lives with hope, courage, and faith. May the shared sisterhood of Relief Society, established by the Lord through a prophet, bless and sustain the women of this church, I pray, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1994/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/1994-general-relief-society-meeting/1994-09-0010-elaine-l-jack-64k-eng.mp3" length="7605068" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 1994 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relief Society: A Balm in Gilead</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My message tonight is simple. Please know how I love Relief Society. I know the love and peace and unity that it brings into the lives of women of this church. Relief Society has been a source of strength in my life, it has helped me raise my family,</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95911_000_037" doc-version="1" hash="NW-HMg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="-25t0k71qEme_V4wUHffxA" hash="HizwEg">Relief Society:</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="g5aA2JaxQECN1hlyALN7Kw" hash="gd95_A">A Balm in Gilead</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="DL8-kWF9TUqY91VoFc1WjQ" hash="9JKBXA">Elaine L. Jack</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p1" pid="2ppBja0gXEasrAJcSKO1GA" hash="iA5LTw">My message tonight is simple. Please know how I love Relief Society. I know the love and peace and unity that it brings into the lives of women of this church. Relief Society has been a source of strength in my life, it has helped me raise my family, it has been at the heart of my closest friendships, it has prompted me to learn and grow in the gospel. It has helped me keep my focus on Jesus Christ and what he would have me do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p2" pid="If5SzztmWEmiS_GRBuaftg" hash="a8EA0A">When I was called as general president of Relief Society, I was given counsel by President Thomas S. Monson. I want to share with you just a little of what he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p3" pid="_L6X-WNph0qMqHBaUvAX7Q" hash="lsDlCg">“This is a time of great change in the world and in the Church as we observe modifications in family style and family characteristics. We recognize that there are many single-parent families; there are other families where difficulties exist between husbands and wives, and furthermore, we find the encroachment of the drug culture and other challenges which cause stress in families. You at this hour of need have been called … to direct the organization which can provide that ameliorating influence, that balm of Gilead to unite all sisters in the Church.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p4" pid="a3b3Wp2QOEeCtTMXHPbuWA" hash="WTb1sA">Tonight I want to talk about President Monson’s counsel. I want to talk about our families, about Relief Society, and how this great organization can be a balm of Gilead to all of us, particularly in helping us at home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p5" pid="b8rfEc2NdkGvSN4TgtHTsA" hash="yZ52bA">I know of two visiting teachers who had barely begun talking to a sister in her home when her two teenage daughters bounced in, announcing they were going to Young Women. Her husband, who also was leaving for an evening of meetings, detained their three-year-old son, who was determined to accompany his older sisters. Two other girls were arguing in the next room over which video to watch. When all the doors closed, the mother started to cry. It had been, she explained, a long week.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p6" pid="tqBxJhdJl0G-whTaAwN0uA" hash="s_KvYA">The visiting teachers wisely gave this very busy wife and mother a chance to talk. She discussed her week and how much she was missing her recently deceased mother. The three talked and shared their understanding of the gospel and the difficulties of every day application. The visiting teachers—one is single and has no children and the other is a single parent—praised their sister for all she was doing to raise her family well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p7" pid="tRPftt3ULkCF2CzzV1nyGA" hash="ChqfVA">The mother felt better. The visiting teachers grew closer to each other and to this dear sister. They all felt better. In the true spirit of Relief Society, these visiting teachers strengthened this sister and her home. I feel better. Why? Because this story witnesses what I know—that Relief Society is indeed a balm that unites us, that helps us in our families. Sisters, I testify to you that one of our most important roles as Relief Society members is to strengthen each other, so all of us are better able to help our families. We come together. We learn from each other. We go home and strengthen our families. It’s that simple, yet how profound it is that we have this organization to be our balm of Gilead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p8" pid="4aunTrmXJkCJUlhtQ8OVRw" hash="d8Hnhw">President Boyd K. Packer, in a talk to the women of the Church, quoted the First Presidency:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p9" pid="yVOyVFwiIUq7mpR8K2ULSA" hash="JVjl4g">“We ask our Sisters of the Relief Society never to forget that they are a unique organization in the whole world, for they were organized under the inspiration of the Lord. … No other women’s organization in all the earth has had such a birth” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1980, p. 111).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p10" pid="sHDKfzgIfEuPWjhPBxg2rA" hash="4XXVZw">That divine direction continues today as priesthood leaders counsel with us, give us guidance, encouragement, and inspiration. I am grateful for our prophet, Gordon B. Hinckley, and for the General Authorities of this church who reverence the work of Relief Society.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p11" pid="zIf6hS2CWUm0rB37WdHtpg" hash="tNMPdg">We honor the trust we have been given to show charity, to build individual testimonies of the gospel of Jesus Christ, to strengthen the families of the Church and focus on living the gospel. We do it in our meetings, in our homes, in our associations. This spiritual perspective is the balm of Gilead, that ameliorating influence spoken of by President Monson that brings peace to the soul. We carry this balm with us all the time, and it makes the difference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p12" pid="jHLhAMDhuEqCExWUE_5A5g" hash="gmTjEA">Spiritual peace is in short supply these days. For many in the world this is a time of confusion, mixed signals, scrambled priorities. There will always be problems and pressing issues to draw our attention from the work of the Lord. Remember, Relief Society is the Lord’s organization for women. It is much more than a class we attend on Sunday. Service in Relief Society magnifies every sister. A sister from Virginia wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p13" pid="bn4GVBiQk06nWPTlitd_tg" hash="uphApg">“I have served in almost all of the callings [in Relief Society] and obtained a deep love for this auxiliary which has helped to educate me in several ways. I see those years as the most spiritual and enjoyable of my experience in the Church. Relief Society has taught me that I am a person of worth” (Loretta H. Ison, Big Stone Gap, Virginia).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p14" pid="UjxEZaa47UCEoE6UBUovLA" hash="zGB8SA">In Relief Society we hold constant the virtues relating to women, mothers, families, and righteous living. At peace with this God-defined direction, Relief Society sisters can bring this balm of Gilead to troubled times. We have the spiritual resources of faith, hope, and compassion to apply as the balm.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p15" pid="9kdDmQ-UAka_vhZzk64v1A" hash="xNTrKw">In ancient days the balm of Gilead was an aromatic spice used to heal and soothe. Made from a bush or a tree that grew plentifully around Gilead, it was a popularly traded commodity, always in high demand. The strength of the balm is familiar to us through the words of a hymn:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="cVp8IMzjQEyTINB_9NUcCw" hash="iqoNBA">
            <span class="emphasis">There is a Balm in Gilead,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="EtWxq84kuUOhfgKRWY18sQ" hash="7TMZZA">
            <span class="emphasis">To make the wounded whole,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="DjLwz4ujmEK3nTvA0wrZbA" hash="iqoNBA1">
            <span class="emphasis">There is a Balm in Gilead,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="xRc3u24Aj0mKm2zj9Lj8Xw" hash="IPZAAw">
            <span class="emphasis">To heal the sin sick soul.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p16" pid="GumpXdP2mkWz_w99wfHtUQ" hash="AKvEuQ">As a presidency we desire that every sister in the Church recognize the significance of her service and be magnified in her work in the kingdom of God on earth. Sisters, ours is a sacred calling. As we devote ourselves to the purposes of Relief Society, we will see many of the problems reversed that are plaguing our homes and our communities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p17" pid="8CLMEj9uJUuHbSzbMKbvDQ" hash="PJwY4g">The very name “Relief Society” describes our purpose: to provide relief. While we often have the desire and the natural tendency as women to fix what’s broken, we are not the “solution society.” We are the Relief Society. We understand the power and strength of the fruits of the Spirit described in Galatians: love, joy, <span class="emphasis">peace,</span> longsuffering, gentleness, goodness, faith (<a href="/scriptures/nt/gal/5.22" class="scriptureRef">Gal. 5:22</a>; emphasis added). We can soothe a suffering heart when we can’t eliminate the trouble. We can bring reassurance and support, kindness, and calm.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p18" pid="cQhz5NbsT0m1z8qjy84WtA" hash="58-vYg">When the Prophet Joseph Smith was suffering in Liberty Jail, he wrote of the balm he received from his friends. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p19" pid="XowvWbgZU0qgZbW6NQPUUg" hash="M5qd3w">“Those who have not been enclosed in the walls of prison without cause … can have but little idea how sweet the voice of a friend is; one token of friendship from any source whatever awakens and calls into action every sympathetic feeling; … then the voice of inspiration steals along and whispers, … ‘peace be unto thy soul’” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 3:293).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p20" pid="44W7f-rZ1Uq2QGJB5vOAgw" hash="4xjvlg">Joseph recognized the role each of us plays in lifting, helping, and soothing so that the calamities of life can be stilled and the Lord’s voice can be heard.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p21" pid="R5X_56bJ8EWG9qBrdsbfLg" hash="4ggJow">This is the balm applied by the women of Relief Society today. In our worldwide church there are countless numbers of sisters who put their families first: women who read and ponder the scriptures, who follow the counsel of the living prophets; women who are serving in demanding callings, from setting up wilderness camps for Laurels to teaching the Articles of Faith to Primary children to greeting at the door of Relief Society on Sunday morning; and the world is blessed by their influence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p22" pid="z-7Ys9t_zUmReDbb-Zc0ZQ" hash="6HwRaA">So much of our contribution is done in quiet ways, one sister at a time. It has always been so. I think of Mary who bathed Christ’s feet after his hot and dusty journey and then dried his feet with her hair before applying a healing ointment (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/12.3" class="scriptureRef">John 12:3</a>). I think of Dorcas, sometimes called the Relief Society sister of the New Testament because her life through her good deeds prompted the women to weep and wail at her passing. They pleaded with Peter to restore her to life (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/9.36-39" class="scriptureRef">Acts 9:36–39</a>). I think of Helen who works with me at the general Relief Society offices. Untiring, patient, accommodating of all, Helen is a source of peace. She gives me comfort because I know she is always there, even and fine.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p23" pid="NgdbzJKwxUaznb0OLIz_CA" hash="8LRnVg">I have been privileged to meet many of you. Thank you for the steadfast love you extend to one another, for your example, for your service. Thank you for putting your arms around each other and drawing each other into the circle of sisters that is the heart and soul of a branch, a ward, or a stake.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p24" pid="NzjkiMSD2EGqJbOrLf4A2w" hash="gaUKfw">The fifth general president of Relief Society, Emmeline B. Wells, described the influence of the sisters when she said, “The sun never sets on the Relief Society” (“R.S. Reports: Alpine Stake,” <span class="emphasis">Woman’s Exponent,</span> Aug. 1904, p. 21).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p25" pid="Nb5tQCY_lUWxQpyGH_hHEg" hash="i21njQ">I have been to Relief Society gatherings in many parts of the world, and I know that the Lord has no finer forces than the good women in these congregations. Our balm of Gilead takes many forms for we minister with both our hearts and our hands.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p26" pid="6xcmYY1sCkSLgKD7yJDLCw" hash="2hY-tQ">I remember receiving a report from a sister in Georgia assigned to survey the damage done to homes in her stake after severe flooding in their area. She went into the kitchen of one home sloshing through mud above her ankles, and opened a cupboard. Inside was coiled a water moccasin snake. She quickly shut the door and tried another cupboard where she was eye-to-eye with yet another snake. In consternation she ran up the stairs to the second floor where she met up with an alligator. I’d class that as heroic charity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p27" pid="jh64Xv934UaIQ8uxpaa_Vw" hash="Ewqm4Q">A mother in North Carolina who had been cared for by willing Relief Society sisters during an illness said, “The sisters have taught me a lesson about the worth of a soul and that even at the bottom, stripped of all roles, titles, and responsibilities, we are valuable to our Father in Heaven and to each other and that charity never faileth.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p28" pid="YMSPYo8Es0iOCVcacbuGEg" hash="NeYW5A">Wherever we are, we can carry with us a reserve of our balm of Gilead and we can spread it around. It can be as simple as finding a seat in the room by someone who needs you. It may be a thoughtful comment in a lesson that answers another one’s prayer. It may be catching someone’s eye, lifting a child for a drink from a fountain, sending a note in the mail, reading the scriptures with someone. Or it may be visiting someone you’ve missed at meetings, someone you hear mentioned in your heart by the still, small voice. These little actions inspire us; they take the edges off our problems. Indeed, “Out of small things proceedeth that which is great” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.33" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:33</a>). The giver and the receiver are both blessed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p29" pid="QvqIujhugE-747re6h-L9g" hash="Goki_g">Our strength as Relief Society sisters in the gospel is most visible and most critical at home. Women are the heart of the home. Whatever your circumstance, you are the heart of your home. I call on you to sanctify your home, to make strengthening and nurturing your family your first priority.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p30" pid="G5bS7p6FrkiWl5lXwkIkUA" hash="QHQnAg">My sister and I speak often about the family in which we grew up. We were born of goodly parents. My mother was a devoted member of the Relief Society in Cardston, Alberta, Canada. As I was growing up, I felt the influence of the Relief Society sisters in my ward. I realize now that they were one of the constants in my life. My dear father had an unwavering testimony, and at age eighty-eight he gave me his final priesthood blessing. Our grandparents lived just next door, something that doesn’t happen much anymore. My grandfather served as the stake patriarch, and I served as his transcriber. What a rich blessing that was in my life. My sister, Jean, and I have happy, peaceful memories of our years at home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p31" pid="FKE5aoXB6UmPxp1r5L1Q_A" hash="duMxwA">Homes can be sacred havens from the world. Homes offer not only physical shelter but a feeling of security, a sense of belonging, a closeness with other family members. Families live in homes. Families are made up of mothers, daughters, sisters, aunts, and grandmothers. They also have grandfathers, uncles, brothers, sons, and fathers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p32" pid="u05B0NMtfUaHQmjox9zzyw" hash="Z06Lgw">Families bring us our greatest joys and sometimes our most wrenching heartaches. Families provide a learning environment, a schoolroom from which we never graduate but can always learn. In our families we learn to appreciate the spiritual peace that comes from applying the principles of charity, of patience, sharing, integrity, kindness, generosity, self-control, and service. These are more than family values, sisters; these are the Lord’s way of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p33" pid="KuUiUdbA7Uis75wNBGlEjw" hash="t6LVKA">The purpose of the Relief Society organization of the Church, stated in our handbook, is to help women and their families come unto Christ. This means bringing the influence of Jesus Christ into our homes. It means we focus on his gospel and we find joy in living his commandments. It means we reexamine our time commitments, and give emphasis to becoming a family that is united and at peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p34" pid="2qqbiCW90kmQ1k97mBy7rQ" hash="d-ptnA">It’s no news to you that this is no easy job. All forms of the media comment on the fragmentation or even the demise of the family. Economic pressures force families to make difficult choices. We’re pulled in myriad directions, and yet we must hold gospel principles firmly in place. Our efforts may seem unnoticed and unappreciated, but sisters, they are worth it. Families are the framework of our lives here and in the eternities. That families are sealed together indicates their central purpose in the Lord’s plan. And women have a key role in the family. We set the tone in our homes; we set the pattern for daily living; we set the standards for how people are treated; we are teacher, counselor, confidante, advocate, supporter, and companion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p35" pid="dncAnuwAR0mOs0uQFMKGXA" hash="oEKjug">We have a long and significant track record in Relief Society for putting families first. The “Mother’s Class” was the first standardized lesson taught in Relief Society. Starting in 1901, these lessons were the original Mother Education course. The intent was to help sisters manage their homes, inspire their children, teach the gospel, and live exemplary lives. Just as we do now.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p36" pid="DH_Ha5HNyUSTKljT1f4hHw" hash="wlKQsw">In our Relief Society today, we study one lesson a month and focus it on the needs of homes and families. But it doesn’t stop there. Homes and families are a central frame of reference in all lessons.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p37" pid="muQVYcZcT0amTEFDGDOqZg" hash="Xper0w">Because families are close to our hearts, they make us hurt sometimes. Take Lehi and Sariah as an example. How did they feel about the constant bickering of Laman and Lemuel? When Joseph was sold into Egypt, what did he think of his brothers? Did Queen Esther really want to hear from her Uncle Mordecai, “Who knoweth whether thou art come … for such a time as this?” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/esth/4.14" class="scriptureRef">Esth. 4:14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p38" pid="QwI-MJBg4UyC1qxYOX4eVg" hash="DS5OFg">Families signify responsibility to and for each other. This spring my seven-year-old grandson, David, called to see if I could come to his class’s spring concert because, he said, “I have a solo part.” It was on a Tuesday, my busiest day, but I promised I would try. On the day of the program, I was there, straining with his parents to identify our little David amidst the sea of faces framed by Mickey Mouse ears. David did have a solo; every child in the class had a solo. But the reward came at the end of the program when he bounded down the aisle saying, “Grandma, I knew you’d come.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p39" pid="EPyUBpJWGkqiILm6FS2Sig" hash="QjhC0w">A friend spoke to me recently of her father, who had suffered a stroke. She faced a hard time of life as she tried to determine the best way to care for and support him and also consider her mother, who had good health and days still filled with promise and grandchildren. Then my friend spoke of the reverence she felt for this time. She said, “I am finding I enjoy learning from him, watching him deal with this difficult process of an aging body.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p40" pid="SeT8WjRsu0O9YOjuDWuO7g" hash="Xmcdow">At the most difficult times our families can hold us steady. We learn this well from one of the most wrenching experiences in the history of the world, the crucifixion of Jesus Christ, the Son of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p41" pid="dbrOPzLr_EqnqhFxnQf0xw" hash="T0IYpQ">We read in John, “There stood by the cross of Jesus his mother, and his mother’s sister” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/19.25" class="scriptureRef">John 19:25</a>). They were there as they had been throughout his life. My mind darts back to the early years as Mary and Joseph raised this most remarkable child. I can hear Mary comforting the baby Jesus with soothing words that come so naturally to us: “I’m right here.” And then at this most dramatic moment of all time, there was the mother, Mary. She couldn’t soothe his pain this time, but she could stand by his side. Jesus, in tribute, offered those grand words, “Woman, behold thy son! Then saith he to the disciple, Behold thy mother!” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/19.26-27" class="scriptureRef">John 19:26–27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p42" pid="2ysYpAP9XkCzseRfYktPUw" hash="T-TJkQ">My sisters of Relief Society, we are the bearers of the balm of Gilead. May your Relief Society sisterhood soothe and bless you. May you know how I support you in all you do for and with your families. May you feel the ameliorating influence, the balm of Relief Society.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead.p43" pid="0qXYkxkIhE292_CQUshSqw" hash="z2zuAw">I leave you with my testimony that God lives, that Jesus Christ is his Son, and that his gospel has been restored in these latter days. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/10/relief-society-a-balm-in-gilead</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/1995-general-relief-society-meeting/1995-09-0010-elaine-l-jack-64k-eng.mp3" length="9267147" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 1995 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strengthened in Charity</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I am so thankful today to be with you sisters, the great women of our Church. You represent many different parts of the world, many languages, customs, and cultures. And yet, your righteousness is constant and far-reaching. No matter when you joined </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_96911_000_035" doc-version="2" hash="cf1gZQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="oBKOBvoQ7E6Weu9nvPHB5Q" hash="pp5n1w">Strengthened in Charity</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="INEqxUWLL0G7Kk4gFq206A" hash="9JKBXA">Elaine L. Jack</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p1" pid="Hh7faRGiHkiOFzxEZstPiA" hash="j5FLsQ">I am so thankful today to be with you sisters, the great women of our Church. You represent many different parts of the world, many languages, customs, and cultures. And yet, your righteousness is constant and far-reaching. No matter when you joined this Church or where you attend your meetings, your righteousness is evident in your goodness. Your contributions and example reflect your love of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p2" pid="KXTHlrKKxU-3LJQlVOGXWw" hash="ren9DA">In a radio interview I was once asked, “If you could have any wish for women, what would it be?” I said, “I would want women to know how good they are. I would want them to feel valued for their own goodness.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p3" pid="HA1qMJLtG0WxPUlVr7B4Ag" hash="i-AKsw">As I speak to you I can’t help but think of my mother, who died 26 years ago. Like many of you, I learned so much from my mother. She taught me the importance of grammar, manners, cleanliness, and education. She was a gracious woman. She taught me the principles of the gospel and doctrines of the kingdom of God. She was an example of great faith, hope in abundance, and pure charity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p4" pid="wUg4I9qawkawM24njCnMuA" hash="Z13mPw">I doubt my mother would ever have imagined that someday her daughter from the little community of Cardston would be speaking by satellite broadcast to women around the world and that I would be sharing those things that I learned at home. So many years have passed since the two of us were together, but I often feel my mother is right with me. This prompts me to ask, sisters, how can we ever gauge the effects of our touch, our reach, or our influence?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p5" pid="SLAVD6KqcEG0RFvnLUUhlQ" hash="riRbXA">As I have served in this calling, I have prayed that the Lord would help me understand the hearts of women in His Church. The heart is the key to our influence, for it counts and measures each kindness, each effort, each time we lift, praise, teach, or cheer one another. I have come to know that the hearts of Relief Society women are full of love. I have seen examples in every branch, ward, and stake I have visited, and I have heard of the goodness of the women of this Church in letters that bear testimony that “Charity Never Faileth.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p6" pid="kfigCAJTCEeyLETdZ8gWDQ" hash="yru61w">Charity is work of the heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p7" pid="PMkL_wnS_keznFL9PIAJ1w" hash="rTShcg">The Savior said that “the great commandment in the law” is “Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.36-37" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:36–37</a>). When we love the Lord with all our mind, soul, and heart, we love others. And charity abounds.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p8" pid="wuxjcQaaG028KAxRwEGF5w" hash="C8Cwlg">This isn’t news to you, because you spend your days doing good for others—for your family, your neighbors, your sisters, even strangers. Your efforts to assist and help others have become so much a part of your personal style that, for the most part, they are spontaneous, instinctive, immediate.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p9" pid="VwgNhmT-cEehXsaANu_tGQ" hash="bueF0g">Most of you think I am describing someone else. You may be saying, “There’s nothing special about me. I’m just ordinary.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p10" pid="l6Dg5dzAj0-ulpUgheKhbA" hash="eri8tA">I’d say the same thing. “I’m just an ordinary woman with the same joys and frustrations of every other woman.” Sometimes the frustrations are great; and sometimes the joys simple, like having an even number of socks come out of the dryer. We all work at feeling joy and finding peace. One of our greatest tools in the process is charity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p11" pid="k0dEnFXSx0KDEUPCIz4WDg" hash="IQSh_A">In the scriptures, we find many examples of women whose daily efforts reflected charity. With their hearts filled with the pure love of Christ, they responded to needs quickly and effectively.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p12" pid="6ard0-k8AUimG-BZ9qjsfg" hash="i5k4aw">Rebekah, who eventually became the wife of Isaac and the mother of Jacob and Esau, was just such a woman. In the normal pattern of her daily tasks, she was kind to Abraham’s servant who was visiting her village on the dramatic mission to secure a wife for Isaac.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p13" pid="GbieNHRxrEiiEN6R8f_RGA" hash="1znitw">The Lord knew Rebekah’s heart; he knew how she would respond when she observed a need. He answered the servant’s prayer that the young woman who was to become Isaac’s wife would offer him water.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p14" pid="JqcwCAKKK0SAaMtelJncHg" hash="44wHrg">In Genesis we read, “Behold, Rebekah came out … with her pitcher upon her shoulder” and went down to the well (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/24.15" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 24:15</a>). You know that story. The servant asked for a drink. Whole family trees hung in the balance of her answer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p15" pid="pBFEn52HjUmEvMfoOJt0zA" hash="vrt7ZA">She said, “Drink, my lord,” and then added, “I will draw water for thy camels also, until they have done drinking.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p16" pid="j-M-pXplJkOOohqdF91wBQ" hash="2Gd4Bw">“And she hasted, and emptied her pitcher into the trough, and ran again unto the well to draw water, and drew for all his camels” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/24.18-20" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 24:18–20</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p17" pid="N87tlSDhsUK17xNAR0rNLQ" hash="mUAiWw">Her brother Laban invited him to lodge, and not until the servant was introduced did she discover he was the servant of her uncle. Her charitable response to this stranger was automatic. She did not stop to think, <span class="emphasis">I am giving service,</span> nor did she consider the station of the one in need. She hastened to serve water—to camels.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p18" pid="NQS2fXVHd0uA18fYsbKCAQ" hash="xdHjnw">Respectfully, she offered an act of service, a simple one, and from that act was born a family of great influence for whole dispensations. Rebekah loved with worthiness and willingness as a daughter of God. Remember the question, Who can gauge the reach of our goodness?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p19" pid="qM_2FX6si06NqenvkK90GQ" hash="-UHF_w">From her we learn that charity, though often quantified as the action, is actually the state of the heart that prompts us to love one another. She offered water. It was in the offering that charity was manifest.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p20" pid="0sOrQFAluE-FY0PYDZAUTw" hash="CWSKGw">I recently received a letter from a sister serving a mission in Siberia that showed how a small group of Russian sisters was engaged in this active kind of love. Sister Okelberry said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p21" pid="jTLMum-twUWAJPu1j92BMg" hash="GKfF-Q">“I am proud to report that the women of Siberia have caught the vision of the Relief Society. Sister Kappenkova, a six-month Church member, has risen to the mighty challenge of Relief Society president of this northernmost group in Russia. She, along with her counselors, understands the importance of visiting teaching and is helping these sisters serve each other and build each other—saving them from the dangers of inactivity. They are teaching each other precious gospel principles and valuable skills in leadership as mothers, wives, and women in the Church. Conditions are not easy for them. Yet they understand and have already embraced those immortal words ‘Charity Never Faileth.’ It has been an honor to watch this develop right before my eyes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p22" pid="9GmDIQPt7k-JghG6wenLYA" hash="k_9AoQ">“With only one short and very precious week left of my missionary time, I know that my sisters will be left in good hands—they are all taking care of each other” (letter from Michelle Okelberry, 31 Jan. 1996).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p23" pid="RDM2dReJSk-uq4d4ziMSDw" hash="YjBnvA">Alma emphasized the importance of “having the love of God always in your hearts” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/13.29" class="scriptureRef">Alma 13:29</a>). Charity is that love. Charity is a gift of the Spirit, for “all things which are good cometh of God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.12" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:12</a>). And this gift is multiplied as it is used.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p24" pid="uWy2aQC4RUK_UQGP9bG10A" hash="69sIeQ">Both the giver and the receiver are blessed. For charity purifies and sanctifies all it touches, and “whoso is found possessed of it at the last day, it shall be well with him” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.47" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:47</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p25" pid="Kp3q3IlXS0-ULyM4OSBO0A" hash="oaxR3g">The greatest acts of charity come from giving of yourself and receiving expressions of charity with humility as well. President Spencer W. Kimball illustrated this truth in an inspiring example. He said: “[The Savior’s] gifts were rare ones: eyes to the blind, ears to the deaf, and legs to the lame; cleanliness to the unclean, wholeness to the infirm, and breath to the lifeless. His gifts were … forgiveness to the repentant, hope to the despairing. His friends gave him shelter, food, and love. He gave them of himself, his love, his service, his life. … We should strive to give as he gave. To give of oneself is a holy gift” (<span class="emphasis">The Wondrous Gift</span> [1978], 2).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p26" pid="AZobST9nQEm1crPCUIf9Iw" hash="T3L_aA">I’ve thought about this: “To give of oneself is a holy gift.” “We should strive to give as he gave.” What wise counsel! When we give our time, our energy, our commitment, our testimony to others, we are giving of ourselves. We are sharing intangibles, not easily left on the doorstep but easily deposited in the heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p27" pid="rtMzjr4MCUWgpuRTrh1IsQ" hash="6e1d-g">So it is with kindness. Nothing will bring the Spirit of the Lord into your meetings, your homes, and your personal associations more quickly than showing kindness. “Charity … is kind” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/13.4" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 13:4</a>). Kindness should be right at the top of everyone’s list of things to do. Write it down every day: “Be kind.” Kindness comes in many different packages. Be thoughtful to your neighbors. Be patient in a crowd. Be considerate of your children and your husband. Be honest with your sisters. Trust them and they will trust you. Go out and bring them into this grand circle of sisters we call Relief Society. As we increase our kindness, we add charity to our storehouse and we are strengthened.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p28" pid="JG0Tqh28v0a4OXPjr7BUNg" hash="JF58MA">A Relief Society sister who had moved to Texas to continue her education and then was moving again wrote to me this summer. She told of her experience with the sisters in her ward, of their quick action, willing hands, warmth, and kindness. But it wasn’t <span class="emphasis">what</span> they did that prompted her letter; it was <span class="emphasis">why.</span> They loved her, and she could feel it. As they shared with her, multiplying their gifts, she too was strengthened in charity. Listen to her story, because it represents all of you and your quiet goodness:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p29" pid="j3uMxXn-iECaux2lkSnD2A" hash="qY7y7A">“As I write these words, I have to squint at my computer screen and keep blinking away tears of gratitude. From the first day I attended the Austin Fourth Ward, I was touched by the spirit of love and caring I felt in the Relief Society. These sisters are very diverse. There are converts and lifelong members, native Texans and Mountain West transplants. They are married, divorced, and single, some with sufficient means, others with very few resources. Yet it doesn’t seem to make any difference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p30" pid="zwi2M0w0eUGbMxJwMvM45A" hash="om776A">“I can’t tell you of the untold kindnesses they’ve done for me. They aren’t earthshaking events, but an accumulation of small blessings: stopping by my apartment to take my dog for a walk, offering to take care of some mending, tracking down packing boxes for me, and including me in their personal prayers. This Sabbath day, the words of the hymn ‘As Sisters in Zion’ [<span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 309] keep running through my mind. I want you to know that the sisters are indeed ‘build[ing] up his kingdom with earnest endeavor,’ and ‘comfort[ing] the weary and strengthen[ing] the weak’” (letter from Katherine Boswell, 11 Aug. 1996).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p31" pid="In1tsJYsmkinnDhyafddRw" hash="s98hYg">Is there any question of the righteous influence of the women of this Church? In this tabernacle, in Texas, in tiny branches, sprawling wards, and stakes around the world, our efforts sound the theme “Charity Never Faileth.” What a promise! As it is heard here and recorded in heaven, may we remember, sisters, this is our theme and our message to the world. It isn’t what we do; it is the heart with which we do it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p32" pid="_s6wdy71vUCukpFXMlGvAg" hash="COaM9A">President Joseph F. Smith said of his responsibilities when serving in the First Presidency, “I am called to do good” (<span class="emphasis">Collected Discourses,</span> comp. Brian H. Stuy, 5 vols. [1992], 5:92). Such a simple, sincere statement. As followers of Jesus Christ, we too are “called to do good.” Sisters, you do great good; you are so very good.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p33" pid="rqKjp05PwUa6kqkLOb_rHA" hash="wgtePA">Belle Spafford, former general Relief Society president, stated, “Relief Society is only on the threshold of its divine mission” (<span class="emphasis">History of Relief Society</span> [1966], 140).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p34" pid="OtgJuzv5CU-W3gBGcXGvAQ" hash="o0mGgA">I echo that sentiment. Sisters, we are poised to stride across that threshold into a new era of spirituality and light. Can we, in our daily lives, draw others to Jesus Christ? Can our faith, hope, and charity be the critical forces of significant influence? Yes, a resounding yes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p35" pid="ZpXaMKIXsE6ehw7OFxOH-w" hash="CJJaBw">Sister Clyde has spoken eloquently of being steadfast and courageous in our convictions. With her special talent for teaching, Sister Okazaki has shown us how to choose hope in Christ. I add to their messages my conviction that we will be strengthened in charity. To all the sisters in this Church, I ask that our love of God be reflected in our willingness to serve and be served. May we in our homes teach concern for others, sacrifice, and service. I earnestly pray that we may share our gifts from God whether they be our minds, our music, our athletic ability, our leadership, our compassion, our sense of humor, our peaceful countenance, or our resilience and rejoicing. With charitable hearts may we do remarkable work in these last days. And then we will merit the pronouncement from Jesus Christ, “For this is Zion—<small>THE PURE IN HEART</small>” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/97.21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 97:21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity.p36" pid="7gJxmNv-j0m6eZionYVC-w" hash="yt3kjA">I bear you my testimony of the truths spoken here tonight and the significance of each of your lives. Jesus Christ is the head of this Church, and we are led by a prophet of God. I am grateful for that blessing and for priesthood leaders who work diligently and effectively in our behalf. They, too, bless lives with hearts full of charity. I leave you with the joy I feel in my heart for this glorious gospel and with my love for all of you. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1996/10/strengthened-in-charity</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/1996-general-relief-society-meeting/1996-09-0030-elaine-l-jack-64k-eng.mp3" length="7263027" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 1996 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Partakers of the Glories”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories?lang=eng</link>
      <description>On the plains of Paraguay sits the tiny village of Mistolar. It is located on a large stretch of land in a desolate area near the Pilcomayo River. There in this small farming community is a branch of the Church. In June of 1987, with the melting snow</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_96911_000_028" doc-version="2" hash="yA_lUQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="V78Zz8rUf0eephttAxsaOw" hash="Nte-tw">“Partakers of the Glories”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="C_WHjTa4YkyW3yWy76VSCQ" hash="9JKBXA">Elaine L. Jack</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e50.jpg" alt="President Elaine L. Jack" pid="e_4Jm46-nEif7mKQFfmZzQ" hash="Ra9gOA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p1" pid="EEU0JvvIAUawVe1MrAhadA" hash="wiud6A">On the plains of Paraguay sits the tiny village of Mistolar. It is located on a large stretch of land in a desolate area near the Pilcomayo River. There in this small farming community is a branch of the Church. In June of 1987, with the melting snows of the Andes, the river which was their lifeline for crops was also the source of their destruction. It overflowed its banks not once but twice, forcing the Saints to relocate and then relocate again. They lost everything: their chapel, their homes, their gardens and fences. For a month they waded in knee-deep water simply trying to stay alive.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p2" pid="lGKlHPrT3UigscbfI9twbg" hash="LrIdyw">The Area Presidency, hearing of their plight, dispatched supplies, and Elder Ted E. Brewerton of the Quorum of Seventy led the rescue party in a grueling two-day journey.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p3" pid="PiuXVMbvNk-Eh0lH172Qmg" hash="qZqRBg">When the group arrived they were warmly welcomed by the women and children because the men, for the most part, were away hunting and fishing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p4" pid="5E-GoBGI8EuSSsI2PiHFSQ" hash="z_Ielw">The people had little food and clothing to sustain them in that freezing winter weather, and their surviving livestock included three sheep, a few chickens, a goat, and a scrawny dog. At night their makeshift reed-and-stick homes offered very little protection.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p5" pid="02HLSG3AT0y-NKRhZs43-A" hash="CvyK4w">Clearly, their situation was bleak, yet the villagers were smiling. Their peace was a stark contrast to their destitute circumstances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p6" pid="4hpZHjJL2EilRw8KzWBFLw" hash="GjIojw">How were they sustaining their spirits under such difficulties? The answer came when Elder Brewerton asked the young branch president, “Do you have any sick among your members?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p7" pid="-h6x40HKwki0EeB5MSo6aw" hash="jmS78g">The young priesthood leader paused and said, “I don’t think so; let me ask the other brethren.” A few minutes later he answered, “There are thirty-nine of us who hold the Melchizedek Priesthood. We watch over and bless our people.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p8" pid="5FOWSmn3KEKBp4zz59p6ww" hash="i4KoGg">That evening at the branch meeting a sister offered a prayer, one Elder Brewerton will always remember. She said, “Father, we have lost our beautiful chapel, we have lost our clothing, we no longer have homes, … we don’t have any materials to build anything, we have to walk ten kilometers to get a drink of dirty river water and [we] don’t have a bucket. But we desire to express to thee our gratitude for our good health, for our happiness, and for our Church membership. Father, we want thee to know that under any conditions, we will be true, strong and faithful to the covenants we made to thee when we were baptized.” (See Heidi S. Swinton, <span class="emphasis">Pioneer Spirit</span> [1996], 8–11.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p9" pid="X48_fpmQu0OAyW5WtkD6rw" hash="O-O4Lw">When all around them had washed away, the Saints in Mistolar held firmly to the power of the priesthood and its spiritual blessings (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.18" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:18</a>). I can picture that Relief Society sister standing up to thank the Lord in prayer for all they had. They had practically nothing—not even a bucket. But they had their covenants, they had their Church membership, their commitment to Christ. They were blessed to become “partakers of the glories.” In the Doctrine and Covenants we read, “Blessed are you for receiving mine everlasting covenant, even the fulness of my gospel, sent forth unto the children of men, that they might … be made partakers of the glories which are to be revealed in the last days” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/66.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 66:2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p10" pid="6aOrwHNNZU2GSoU2Aln6Eg" hash="GxfWFw">I have a firm testimony of the power of the priesthood in the lives of all Church members. In the Doctrine and Covenants we are also told that the Melchizedek Priesthood holds “the keys of all the spiritual blessings of the church” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.18" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:18</a>). I know it is God’s power and authority on earth to bless our lives and help us bridge our earthly experiences to the eternities. When we receive the blessings of the priesthood, we are drawing on the power and grace of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p11" pid="mhUCJD-sIEGY0SVb0cdNkA" hash="FGxTTg">President Joseph Fielding Smith said, “Priesthood is given us for two purposes, first, that we may ourselves receive exaltation, and, second, that we may be the means of helping others to obtain like blessings” (<span class="emphasis">The Way to Perfection</span> [1932], 221–22).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p12" pid="4iEPipSeZkmSyq7VCB6AFQ" hash="9xlDYw">There is order to the work of God. In one of the first meetings of the Relief Society 154 years ago, the prophet Joseph Smith charged the sisters with helping to save souls (see Relief Society minutes, 9 June 1842, LDS Church Archives). Our purpose has not changed. It is significant to me that the women were organized under the authority of the priesthood. We sustain the priesthood and are sustained by its power. The sisters of the Church, like the one from Mistolar, treasure our opportunity to be full partakers of the spiritual blessings of the priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p13" pid="DGLsYIvsmkmZvUNa2i99MQ" hash="vsvIVw">Each of us can be directed and blessed in our eternal progression by receiving these blessings. The ordinances, covenants, sealings, and the gift of the Holy Ghost are essential for exaltation. There are a host of individual priesthood blessings as well. Priesthood blessings give us direction, they lift our sights, they encourage and inspire us; they prompt our commitment. We can all be partakers of these spiritual blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p14" pid="ZA6XSiQUZECYmxVbZBxegw" hash="tA8GWg">Baptism is the critical priesthood ordinance which opens the door to eternal life for each one of us. It is the benchmark from which we count our many blessings, because this is when our accountability to follow Jesus Christ and live his gospel begins. And then, each week as we partake of the sacrament we are reminded to “always remember him” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.79" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:79</a>). What a blessing this visual reminder is.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p15" pid="Vgjw2voCSkelmaOutwqaIw" hash="OPglnA">When we are confirmed, the heavens open and we receive the gift of the Holy Ghost. By and through the Spirit, blessings of the priesthood flow into our lives. The Holy Ghost to lead and guide us, to be with us, to bring us peace, to testify of truth, to bear testimony of Jesus Christ; these spiritual blessings direct the course of our lives. And the lives of those around us are richer in things of the Spirit, for blessings are magnified as they are shared.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p16" pid="xc71-3c__0abNf1lmviRaA" hash="n0s4WQ">When hands are laid on my head in a personal priesthood blessing, I feel enveloped in the love of the Savior. I know that the brother who is administering that blessing is acting in the name of the Lord. In Mistolar, 39 of the men held the Melchizedek Priesthood—and used it to bless their people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p17" pid="629IVhtXp0Ws0J4u7wO9ug" hash="u9tH_A">When I was a child I received a blessing of healing, which I attribute to the power of the priesthood and the faith of my believing parents. Several years later I distinctly remember the pressure of my grandfather’s hands on my head when, as a patriarch, he blessed me with a guide for my life, an account of promises for me, conditional on my faithfulness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p18" pid="QW3AVqG2vkmC92byfTxlwg" hash="koGXqA">I have found a distinct difference in my approach to a calling after I have been set apart. Some calls bring a feeling of total wonder. I wonder why they called me; I wonder what I should do; I wonder who should help me. I remember the peace that came when my counselors and I were set apart as general officers of the Relief Society by the First Presidency. The setting was formal, yet warm. I was addressed by my full name, and then came quiet concentration, personal direction, and wise counsel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p19" pid="OeSdPtVoOUO_WpLLoBVtzQ" hash="Tv7j2Q">I felt the same sweet spirit when my husband, Joe, was ordained a bishop and again when he gave our oldest son a father’s blessing before Dave left for the Persian Gulf. Then our son, in turn, blessed his wife and baby daughter. This brought such solace during a frightening time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p20" pid="R-Q8OYi_OEOoki5lHtdF6Q" hash="IsZthg">This morning I asked my husband for a special blessing to complete my preparation to speak to you. It is difficult to put into words what we feel in response to the Lord’s words, “Peace I leave with you, my peace I give unto you” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.27" class="scriptureRef">John 14:27</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p21" pid="P7q3PvIsWEq839rvSnZ6Wg" hash="RNuEaA">Spiritual gifts are powerful priesthood blessings. They increase our capacity as we develop them by drawing on the storehouse in heaven. One gift I value is discernment. When the Lord spoke to the woman at the well, He offered her living “water springing up into everlasting life.” He discerned her needs. His words startled her: “Go, call thy husband, and come hither.” She answered, “I have no husband,” and Jesus said, “Thou hast well said.” And “the woman saith unto him, … I perceive that thou art a prophet.” (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/4.14-19" class="scriptureRef">John 4:14–19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p22" pid="dtYHOJhdt0CfXY1dF_jbaQ" hash="hO7ttg">Many women have the gift of discernment. Often blessed with the power to know and understand beyond their experience, women draw on this strength as they visit monthly to teach in the homes or to assess needs as directed by the bishop. We use it as we nurture our children and teach them the gospel. We discern, by the power of God given to us through His Spirit that “one thing is needful” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.42" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:42</a>). Nothing we do is more important than the work of righteousness in our homes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p23" pid="HUFEAXzqXkeWWFq3Q_vxEA" hash="m38Kow">Discernment is critical for our times. President Boyd K. Packer has said, “We need women with the gift of discernment who can view the trends in the world and detect those that, however popular, are shallow” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1978, 8). That is exactly what we need.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p24" pid="7sqEapWYVk-eZNo4Zf_CpQ" hash="CfO7qA">The temple is the matchless setting for receiving priesthood blessings. In this holy house, we are endowed individually and then sealed together in families for eternity. Priesthood authority ensures that the covenants we make in the temple are everlasting. The gifts of exaltation deepen the partnership of men and women as they commit to covenants and share the blessings of the temple. And, when we attend the temple, we are blessed with knowledge of “things as they really are, and of things as they really will be” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.13" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p25" pid="2WCSK6v3Vk6E7GOjRhzVzQ" hash="npVUbA">A Relief Society president in Ghana understood the “glories” related to the temple. Talking to some visitors to her ward, she took a small folded piece of paper from her purse and said reverently, “I am a temple recommend holder.” It may be years before she can afford to go to the temple in London or Johannesburg, but she has a reminder that she is worthy and willing. The Lord asks no more. (See Don L. Searle, “Ghana: A Household of Faith,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Mar. 1996, 37.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p26" pid="jR3et6bhpE6bPruVwiPeqQ" hash="xVyEHg">We have been taught in this conference by prophets, seers, and revelators and General Authorities, who bear the priesthood of God. Their messages are for every member of the Church. When we have “ears to hear” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/11.15" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 11:15</a>), we can recognize the Lord is saying, “Whether by mine own voice or by the voice of my servants, it is the same” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:38</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p27" pid="7F8qYCBICU-Nm8kfiZUaCA" hash="0ZLfrA">I want to bear my testimony that I know this Church is led by a prophet of God, President Gordon B. Hinckley. Church administration on the general and local level is evidence of the blessing of the priesthood, for this is The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and He is directing the work. The Lord has said, “Let your hearts be comforted concerning Zion; for all flesh is in mine hands; be still and know that I am God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/101.16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 101:16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p28" pid="m_yxZeQVCUiIKXfWKkusdw" hash="R6mROg">The Saints in Mistolar knew God. They had a testimony of His gospel. They were partakers of the many spiritual blessings brought by the power of the priesthood, blessings described in section 84 of the Doctrine and Covenants:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p29" pid="110Du_19BUm2HJ8NQO4x8g" hash="b3Tg6Q">“And … all they who receive this priesthood, receive me, saith the Lord;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p30" pid="02Wdx1To7keb0Ru3hytjAA" hash="jM_-CQ">“For he that receiveth my servants receiveth me;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p31" pid="j19bQebDOEuRbTLYDFwzuw" hash="SuovCg">“And he that receiveth me receiveth my Father;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p32" pid="kl4MzJIVykGj5WGrVc0VlQ" hash="ZxgnOQ">“And he that receiveth my Father receiveth my Father’s kingdom” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.35-38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:35–38</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories.p33" pid="kKaek9EGwUucNSapubwlsw" hash="VdvBeg">That we may all be “partakers of the glories” in our Father’s kingdom is my prayer. And I say it in the name of Jesus Christ, my Savior, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1996/10/partakers-of-the-glories</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1996-general-conference/1996-10-5030-elaine-l-jack-64k-eng.mp3" length="6210548" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 1996 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“A Small Stone”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The time is past when we can merely believe in this gospel; we must be passionate in our belief and in our commitment to Jesus Christ and His plan.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_97905_000_031" doc-version="2" hash="wpQKcw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="j0XDN7Okb0KGlTgcI7GlFA" hash="dLj1UQ">“A Small Stone”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="N7OsFtBMmEGkobXs5btROQ" hash="9JKBXA">Elaine L. Jack</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="bchYvr8bUEahM_dC6qfKzw" hash="hDGP5w">The time is past when we can merely believe in this gospel; we must be passionate in our belief and in our commitment to Jesus Christ and His plan.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e50.jpg" alt="Elaine L. Jack" pid="IbjQILRT0EqBogT9ufIUgA" hash="Ra9gOA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p1" pid="r7N04ds88kOqIgK3lTUc5Q" hash="G-RxNA">I grew up just a stone’s throw from the Alberta Temple in Cardston, Canada. In this small Mormon community at the foot of the Canadian Rockies, a temple stood as a powerful symbol of the strength and grandeur of the gospel of Jesus Christ. I made my most meaningful covenants within the walls of that temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p2" pid="OgAjF2e8PkGdz1-RXDwxhw" hash="CnF2Ng">Those walls are very significant to me. My grandfather John F. Anderson, a skilled stonemason from Aberdeen, Scotland, was called to dress the white granite stone for this holy temple. In 1915 at the laying of the cornerstone, he had the honor of acting as the chief mason under the supervision of Elder David O. McKay. In 1923, before the temple was dedicated, my grandfather laid the very last stone. Then, in his journal he recorded, “It was not the capstone, but a small stone at the front gate entrance.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p3" pid="nUKZr2Re_E6slqy5RX0_jw" hash="wjGb6w">Today, I lay my small stone at the front gate entrance of Relief Society.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p4" pid="m4OXJVXWQk-uYZG4SsMu9Q" hash="BRMydQ">In the book of Omni, itself a small stone in the middle of the Book of Mormon, Amaleki writes: “I would that ye should come unto Christ, who is the Holy One of Israel, and partake of his salvation, and the power of his redemption. Yea, … and offer your whole souls as an offering unto him, and continue in fasting and praying, and endure to the end; and as the Lord liveth ye will be saved” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/omni/1.26" class="scriptureRef">Omni 1:26</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p5" pid="3YLp_RB6tkuDdHCwuO840g" hash="nbkidg">The Prophet Joseph Smith described offering “your whole soul” as serving God with all your “heart, might, mind and strength” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/4.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 4:2</a>). It is to put on the altar of God your time, talents, gifts and blessings, your willingness to serve, to do all that He asks. My grandfather offered to the Lord the stone he had placed so carefully. Today, I offer my years of service in the general Relief Society.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p6" pid="QD7GPGZ1MU-SE0LtHi1EDg" hash="1dnlzQ">In 1991, at the invitation of President Hinckley, I returned to my childhood home in Canada to attend the rededication of the Alberta Temple. I will always remember the power that filled the room as the session concluded and we stood to sing, “The Spirit of God like a fire is burning!” My heart was touched by the familiar words: “We’ll sing and we’ll shout with the armies of heaven, hosanna, hosanna to God and the Lamb.” (“The Spirit of God,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 2.) Hosanna is a righteous shout for joy, and this was a joyous occasion!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p7" pid="SJsVzFCa8UW4pPjk5PTW8w" hash="m5JS2Q">To our chorus the choir added the great “Hosannah Anthem.” The words were meaningful then as I reflected on my grandfather’s work to build the walls of that noble temple: “The house of the Lord is completed. May our offering by Him be accepted” (in <span class="emphasis">The Choirbook</span> [1980], 69–76). They strike me even more dramatically today as I complete my “house” for the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p8" pid="pohqwFgaeUGdaS1RlRYotw" hash="I90wgg">I find many parallels with building a temple and fulfilling a calling. We begin with bare ground, and we start to work. We survey the situation, pray for inspiration, thoughtfully formulate plans, send them for review, adjust, and plan again. We firm up a foundation and then add walls, a roof, and even gardens. Each administration builds on the solid bedrock of the past.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p9" pid="VIbZsLwFxkeQIUAvtPiutg" hash="e-iAPQ">For the past seven years this Relief Society presidency has been building. We have added a Churchwide literacy effort to our education focus; we have emphasized the principle of watching over and caring for our sisters through visiting teaching; we have continued to place home and family at the center of our attention and honored the divine nature of women as they nurture, sacrifice, teach, and inspire. Wonderful things have happened because of the women of this Church who have tended children and tended each other, taught self-reliance, and taught of the Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p10" pid="wVWQMLFk1EavmPoHXDB6fA" hash="viJMLQ">How I have loved working so closely with the wonderful women of this Church as they have offered their souls to the Lord. To their stones, I add my own. I pray that it may be accepted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p11" pid="0SapaSnoa0yR0T9kdGLtmA" hash="7LqDqA">One of my prized memories of these past few years was the sesquicentennial in 1992, when we celebrated the founding of Relief Society, one of the oldest, largest, and, in my eyes, the most successful women’s organizations in the world. It is still thrilling for me to remember the simultaneous broadcast to every continent of the world, linking sisters for the first time from Taiwan, Zimbabwe, Germany, Mexico, Korea, Australia, and America.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p12" pid="jGcQIGFxz0Gdceu3LS-VXA" hash="BwNfhQ">Emma Smith, the first president of this organization, said to the sisters, “We are going to do something extraordinary” (Minutes of the Female Relief Society, 17 Mar. 1842, LDS Church Archives). Our celebration was indeed “something extraordinary.” What began in 1842 with 20 women in Nauvoo, Illinois, now involves nearly four million women on every continent and in almost every country in the world. But what is significant is that it began with one woman, Margaret Cook, who offered to sew shirts for the men working on the Nauvoo Temple. She needed cloth and could not afford to buy it. Sarah Kimball offered the cloth, and within weeks the Relief Society was organized by the Prophet Joseph Smith under the inspiration of the Lord. It began with a small offering—at the front gate—and it has grown to a major force for good around the world, one stone at a time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p13" pid="7bF5QeocREi2r2fP6DDl1g" hash="s7EhDA">One of the things I recognize is that if we are obedient, faithful, and earnest, the Lord helps us prepare our offerings. We learn this from Nephi, who was told, “Thou shalt construct a ship, after the manner which I shall show thee, that I may carry thy people across these waters” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.8" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:8</a>). Nephi was not from a seaside community; he had never built a boat. But his response was so full of faith and accountability: “Lord, whither shall I go that I may find ore to molten, that I may make tools to construct the ship after the manner which thou hast shown unto me?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.9" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:9</a>). Without hesitation or question, Nephi began to prepare an offering to the Lord in the shape of a ship.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p14" pid="OCXbVqTdmUKuMbfCm2qKXw" hash="X5_4vQ">When I was called to serve in this assignment, I, like Nephi, went to the Lord for help. My tools came in the form of two strong and capable counselors, Chieko Okazaki and Aileen Clyde. As a presidency we have been fortunate to have a board of 12 noble women, whose contribution has reflected dedication and skill, and an office staff, whose service has been generously and patiently given. Together, we have done “this work with holiness of heart” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.12" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:12</a>). And we have been blessed with the prayers and goodness of Relief Society women in all parts of the world, good women who take seriously the Lord’s charge, “Be not weary in well-doing” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.33" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:33</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p15" pid="13Ayzdn0A0SBxoX4Shjuvw" hash="JgxoAg">I want to express my gratitude to the many priesthood leaders who have counseled and directed us. They have needed our confidence and support just as we have needed their understanding and priesthood power. The Lord has called men of valor, wisdom, and heart to lead this Church. I have seen God inspire our leaders; I have seen them act decisively, compassionately, and carefully. I trust them; they have trusted us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p16" pid="CVPAVKaZgk6XS8Ko-Fnx3A" hash="7Pn59g">I know I speak for the women of this Church when I say to President Hinckley, President Monson, President Faust, and the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles, we stand by you, we support you, we know you are latter-day prophets with the keys to the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p17" pid="jgnb3ivVI0alrrqgABvaJw" hash="qZzwBA">I also pay tribute to my husband, Joe, who has blessed me with his steadiness, his sense of humor and good judgment, and his righteous hands. My four sons have followed his lead as loyal supporters. I took it as the ultimate compliment when one of them said, “We’ve been training Mom to be a Relief Society president for a long time, and she finally got it right!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p18" pid="HKcuW-PtIUeDOnzzJtJ6hw" hash="KUqziQ">Our offerings embrace both the work we do and the heart with which we do it. The Lord calls this “a broken heart and a contrite spirit” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/9.20" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 9:20</a>). This union constitutes the soul. Amaleki spoke of offering “your whole souls” to Jesus Christ (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/omni/1.26" class="scriptureRef">Omni 1:26</a>). Brothers and sisters, the time is past when we can merely believe in this gospel; we must be passionate in our belief and in our commitment to Jesus Christ and His plan. We must know, unequivocally, that He is with us, that He will guide and direct us. In His name we shape our offering. For the past few years I have represented all the women of this Church, a far-reaching responsibility. I believe that the Lord will measure my efforts by my heart and my spirit, as He does yours.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p19" pid="nrYPlIIaIUmdRp8taXgaag" hash="kGlYgg">Today, Relief Society represents the hope expressed by President Emmeline B. Wells, who served in the early years of this century. Her guidance had helped Relief Society hold fast to its cherished traditions while going forward with faith in God and hope in the future. Fifty years later President Belle Spafford said, “Relief Society is only on the threshold of its divine mission” (in <span class="emphasis">History of Relief Society, 1842–1966</span> [1966], 140). Today, we are ready to step over that threshold into a new dimension of spirituality and light. I look forward with a perfect brightness of hope to the offerings of Relief Society sisters in the new century that is before us. Our joy in the gospel of Jesus Christ and our place in His plan will draw people to us and change lives. We will lift and inspire a world so desperately in need of goodness. This new presidency will build an even greater sense of purpose and contribution. I commit my full support to President Smoot and her counselors as they add new stones to the building of the kingdom of God. Surely the strength of today will serve as a foundation upon which the women of tomorrow will build.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p20" pid="OC9nWbcUmEeOZtabx-Ua2w" hash="2g-FOg">This Church has been built and will continue to grow through the steady efforts of the members who quietly do their part, who are struggling with daily challenges, who are humble, patient, and long-suffering. These are the hearts that fill with joy when they sing in dedication of their own offerings, “The Lord is extending the Saints’ understanding” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 2).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone.p21" pid="ygkPwFUzXEahE5Qq0vTpNg" hash="EyjUBg">My heart is full of gratitude and great joy. Rejoice with me in bearing testimony of the Savior: “Hosanna, hosanna to God and the Lamb.” In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1997/04/a-small-stone</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1997-general-conference/1997-04-5030-elaine-l-jack-64k-eng.mp3" length="5517702" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 1997 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
