<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Eldred G. Smith</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Eldred G. Smith.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Eldred%20G.%20Smith.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Eldred G. Smith.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>All May Share in Adam’s Blessing</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing?lang=eng</link>
      <description>After Adam and Eve were driven out of the Garden of Eden, they were taught the principles of the gospel and the plan of salvation—the plan by which they could return to their Father in heaven. They were also instructed to teach this gospel plan to th</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03006_000_7020" doc-version="2" hash="ozmmVQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="4cIhrSI3Q0y4UXRwGMlPGw" hash="z69PXg">All May Share in Adam’s Blessing</h1><p class="authorName" guid="2be8b653-7184-4f52-a6f1-6897138d78dc" pid="MNsR6ibiz0WRsV4VVYCquw" hash="f2lL9w">Eldred G. Smith</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="7c0da406-ff0b-4717-ac72-190f95bb28c4">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3104.jpg" alt="Elder Eldred G. Smith" guid="aa614ab4-8c7d-4aa3-8985-494a6f3fb9d0" pid="_1wGjui_Pkm3NBmkh_oVGA" hash="Bi433w" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p1" guid="8879661e-614f-48ca-8b76-e39675362af0" pid="eGRLS60GakW03IGdsm3ZTw" hash="DM15yA">After Adam and Eve were driven out of the Garden of Eden, they were taught the principles of the gospel and the plan of salvation—the plan by which they could return to their Father in heaven. They were also instructed to teach this gospel plan to their children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p2" guid="28dc4ad1-2954-40d7-b95a-3053532f8731" pid="vy-zTZKYrEicXyut6UKXcw" hash="Bt4nZw">His children generally did not accept his teachings—except Abel. Abel was killed; then, among other children, Seth was born, who did accept the teachings of Adam.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p3" guid="6bec52f2-3d9f-448d-ae5d-6e184c167cb0" pid="BPUP_rJMK0iT7USI9ChYUw" hash="khkfxw">The Lord promised Adam that he would have a righteous seed which would last to the end of the earth, which is recorded in the Book of Moses: “And in that day the Holy Ghost fell upon Adam, which beareth record of the Father and the Son, saying: … as thou hast fallen thou mayest be redeemed, and all mankind, even as many as will.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/5.9" class="scriptureRef">Moses 5:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p4" guid="d3596192-6729-4d27-ad78-c7bfb1c4802a" pid="iv2fOOAn9kamZBdVMqFD-w" hash="nY6mnw">In the next chapter we read: “Now this same Priesthood, which was in the beginning, shall be in the end of the world also.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p5" guid="3a664f70-6f64-47ce-98ad-c05cf7b835d3" pid="sKJl1fcOhU2VnHqVtKQVVg" hash="bVyD5A">“Now this prophecy Adam spake, as he was moved upon by the Holy Ghost, and a genealogy was kept of the children of God. …” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/6.7-8" class="scriptureRef">Moses 6:7–8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p6" guid="518bb259-40fb-46a3-a12e-35bf56f9db9b" pid="ZZAzvKYZ3UCANeu2CtCcOg" hash="ozCGUw">This became the record of the royal seed, which is a record in part, at least, of the fulfillment of this promise. This we have today, at least in part, which is known as the Bible.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p7" guid="8a05a95a-1251-4972-ab09-704b6942dcc9" pid="I2vXDc4dJE6RqLVp_JeDjw" hash="ibEwGQ">Modern revelation gives it to us thus:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p8" guid="0c3df349-100d-4405-ad64-e73e26e03de3" pid="cYPZ2nMGs0iCzW3kdubWcA" hash="G-czJg">“This order was instituted in the days of Adam, and came down by lineage in the following manner:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p9" guid="f80c5a5e-2014-4cb6-b8db-787d471317a2" pid="pxXtg1Gbg0yRm7Ao1yrAaw" hash="JL-yoQ">“From Adam to Seth, who was ordained by Adam at the age of sixty-nine years, and was blessed by him three years previous to his (Adam’s) death, and received the promise of God by his father, that his posterity should be the chosen of the Lord, and that they should be preserved <span class="emphasis">unto the end of the earth.</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.41-42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:41–42</a>. Italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p10" guid="6416ea35-5427-4fe3-85b8-6771629b3db9" pid="eg2RUg0IlEm1a2Eb5ePvbg" hash="HNU3Jw">This promise was repeated again to Abraham, who was Seth’s posterity:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p11" guid="e5742e39-1d91-4e1a-b888-6afbd66b1023" pid="3hqHF55AtUWCGWIYmgjRzQ" hash="4jemtw">“And I will bless them that bless thee, and curse him that curseth thee: and in thee shall all families of the earth be blessed.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/12.3" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 12:3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p12" guid="ecdac9c1-69e9-4eb3-9cf0-59d83362af2f" pid="Jnlx8d6fN0u33X7I61AXpQ" hash="5Ag3JA">“And in thy seed shall all the nations of the earth be blessed; because thou hast obeyed my voice.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/22.18" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 22:18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p13" guid="56bc6a59-8986-45c5-935c-d989be27a855" pid="uL0RWz4oV0Wa87bHMWiy2g" hash="Tm7Y1g">We have a choice record in the Pearl of Great Price, the Book of Abraham, describing how this blessing relates to us today. Speaking to Abraham, the Lord said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p14" guid="7ed68dec-bcd7-4126-b738-fa2312ab3870" pid="UF5TVuKXwEKSIidHnbKaGw" hash="7fDwJg">“And I will make of thee a great nation, and I will bless thee above measure, and make thy name great among all nations, and thou shalt be a blessing unto thy seed after thee, that in their hands they shall bear this ministry and Priesthood unto all nations;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p15" guid="e5a4bfed-c31a-43d7-87f5-069668fe1e8f" pid="4yDXKMwGTk6Esh5N73599w" hash="TT5Adg">“And I will bless them through thy name; for as many as receive this Gospel shall be called after thy name, and shall be accounted thy seed, and shall rise up and bless thee, as their father;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p16" guid="b3fe3146-3577-4d1b-859a-e13ee702a793" pid="nZH6zVSKuUqTtrV_NNOVag" hash="SBjhLA">“And I will bless them that bless thee, and curse them that curse thee; and in thee (that is, in thy Priesthood) and in thy seed (that is, thy Priesthood), for I give unto thee a promise that this right shall continue in thee, and in thy seed after thee (that is to say, the literal seed, or the seed of the body) shall all the families of the earth be blessed, even with the blessings of the Gospel, which are the blessings of salvation, even of life eternal.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/2.9-11" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 2:9–11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p17" guid="a350b10b-0da7-4811-9dcd-d77cc72c0e46" pid="LC1sFDq4REulIixvo_va9A" hash="ckCtQg">This blessing was renewed to Isaac, the son of Abraham, and then to Jacob, who became Israel, and then divided among his twelve sons, each becoming a tribe, referred to as the tribes of Israel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p18" guid="12a8b0b3-e59a-4521-897e-2c1b35d46010" pid="c0V9RdJzuESyxJLQbpBiwA" hash="gVjE3w">When a person receives a patriarchal blessing, he is entitled to receive a pronouncement of the blessings of Israel, or a declaration of the tribe of Israel through which his blessings shall come. This is the right to the blessings of those recorded in the book of remembrance started in the days of Adam.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p19" guid="9ccc9bc1-a5e4-48b7-a1fa-27d26cb893f9" pid="H7KDc9N-BkWJMBakbTYwKw" hash="3Zeh8g">This does not mean that all the nations of the earth will become literal descendants of Abraham, though his seed may be scattered in all nations, but as it says, all shall receive the blessings through those who are the seed of Abraham and shall be accounted his seed, and rise up and bless him as their father. (See <a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/2.10" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 2:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p20" guid="1d99552f-7c55-4560-89bf-cfe1c478cb8e" pid="k9ENHbprJkugigX9F-CgEA" hash="mD4BfA">If members of the Church are literal descendants of Abraham, they will receive such a blessing. If they are not literal descendants of Abraham and join the Church and receive the gospel, they shall receive the priesthood blessings, even eternal life, through those who are of Israel or which would be referred to as by adoption.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p21" guid="d6e348ca-9d32-40e7-8210-6fe6486122c4" pid="9IkWi1iXRUWWawNsytoSbw" hash="byTHmQ">Hence, all nations and families of the earth may receive the blessings of the gospel and eternal life through their faithfulness. To fulfill this promise given to Adam, then, the necessity is apparent of a renewing of priesthood leadership through a prophet of God at various intervals throughout time. These intervals have been called dispensations: from Adam to Seth—to Enoch—to Noah—to Abraham—to Moses—to Elias—to John the Baptist—to Jesus Christ—to the apostles Peter, James, and John.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p22" guid="536e0163-bebd-4ed1-bc3c-7361e29d436a" pid="a8LdQntmREmk_TVhZrwQYw" hash="atR13A">Each dispensation brings with it a reemphasis of the priesthood; a restrengthening of the opportunity given to man to receive the blessings of the gospel by proving himself in resisting the powers of the adversary.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p23" guid="20ccb169-af91-42f5-a0d9-272c460e681d" pid="ToMx27fI5UuPPvUfu0cMBg" hash="GS4guw">The last dispensation is to be the dispensation of the fulness of times. Apostle Paul described this in his epistle to the Ephesians:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p24" guid="8049cebc-a5f4-435d-b885-8d947e1ee43b" pid="oBWWTZLVmk6y7oLX3ZikFQ" hash="lxxREw">“Having made known unto us the mystery of his will, according to his good pleasure which he hath purposed in himself:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p25" guid="970b88db-0074-420f-ad79-a436a3f9690f" pid="A4ujw8_Rkk-NVnBNp1nNrg" hash="vdUIng">“That in the dispensation of the fulness of times he might gather together in one all things in Christ, both which are in heaven, and which are on earth; even in him.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/1.9-10" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 1:9–10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p26" guid="2732fd75-ce74-4513-876a-36fe7d190976" pid="PZKZwlFAv0u2yFGT3_1Z2g" hash="B7fofQ">The Prophet Joseph Smith put it this way: “… that the dispensation of the fulness of times is made up of all the dispensations that ever have been given since the world began, until this time” (Franklin D. Richards, <span class="emphasis">Compendium, </span>1898, p. 143), this being the time referred to as the end of time to prepare for the coming of the millennial reign of the Lord Jesus Christ on this earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p27" guid="f6cae9b4-7c25-4df5-8de6-77d54960741a" pid="Tr5SIonzAke5PNdWQETCbw" hash="ylU38A">I testify to you—this is that time. The gospel of Jesus Christ is here now, with all the keys of the priesthood, to open the way for his coming.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p28" guid="b823a226-2ee9-45c1-9f89-219df66017d8" pid="6hc5Bp-W8USQcsCQbpLFLw" hash="KNUtqA">Joseph Smith was called by revelation, as were the prophets of old. John the Baptist restored to him and Oliver Cowdery the keys of the Aaronic Priesthood, followed by Peter, James, and John, who restored the keys of the Melchizedek Priesthood. Elijah returned in the Kirtland Temple and restored the keys of the sealing blessings for the living and the dead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p29" guid="d62d4f24-54cc-4b0a-b4b6-43f53151f675" pid="TAJcRfJpC0-gCDWCgWgN7Q" hash="P40muQ">Joseph Smith bestowed all the keys upon the Quorum of Apostles before his death. These keys of priesthood authority have been thus preserved to this day and shall continue to usher in the millennial reign of our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing.p30" guid="2ae34b65-73e0-4908-969f-6e80c2348022" pid="otkPEZdW2UKsOMUtvP--NQ" hash="qin2MA">We invite all to hear, accept, and embrace this gospel. This invitation is to all the nations and families the world over, that all may receive the blessings of eternal life and be recorded in the Lamb’s book of remembrance and share the blessings of the royal seed of the righteous, even the blessings of eternal life. I testify that this is his kingdom, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/04/all-may-share-in-adams-blessing</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1971-general-conference/1971-04-7020-elder-eldred-g-smith-64k-eng.mp3" length="4338322" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decisions</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/10/decisions?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Let us go back together in our thoughts to the time before this earth was created—to the time of the great council in heaven, when you and I and all of us were instructed by our Father in heaven as to the purpose and opportunities of this earth life.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03012_000_1040" doc-version="2" hash="LnsWtA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="MvlNc6Vpw06Lnz_S9TWRkg" hash="H9V5vg">Decisions</h1><p class="authorName" guid="2be8b653-7184-4f52-a6f1-6897138d78dc" pid="tzDE235M2k2V0EV6w2xbgw" hash="f2lL9w">Eldred G. Smith</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="e2558bd4-73bb-4671-99e6-5c1b24255770">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3104.jpg" alt="Conference photo" guid="3f4ac8f8-69fc-4578-b40c-625de3de7b74" pid="JvXYwoDSR0C-4K35qnha_g" hash="Bi433w" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p1" guid="f8b7e24b-6aa7-4dac-902b-264580b505e0" pid="Sqdh11qm_ka6IfhYpQhSXA" hash="3Ui-9Q">Let us go back together in our thoughts to the time before this earth was created—to the time of the great council in heaven, when you and I and all of us were instructed by our Father in heaven as to the purpose and opportunities of this earth life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p2" guid="ef7afac1-aa12-462d-a426-71fb4e8c693f" pid="6bATs62Kg0CUWLOr2XcxWg" hash="qVYDSQ">“And there stood one among them that was like unto God, and he said unto those who were with him: We will go down, for there is space there, and we will take of these materials, and we will make an earth whereon these may dwell;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p3" guid="4c35a804-d796-49ec-bbe0-6d77f3add929" pid="LFlMVSmf5E-xCPyL2AI9cQ" hash="otfHCw">“And we will prove them herewith, to see if they will do all things whatsoever the Lord their God shall command them;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p4" guid="33625633-2b15-4266-81fa-d50ff9a1c5ae" pid="y7YlCfBlo02Pkge2HRMNJQ" hash="V8Sf8g">“And they who keep their first estate shall be added upon; and they who keep not their first estate shall not have glory in the same kingdom with those who keep their first estate; and they who keep their second estate shall have glory added upon their heads for ever and ever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p5" guid="d3173a23-ebd1-4258-b5b7-ee55d74b85a8" pid="-LC3qZDIO0ObeM1fBdtIBQ" hash="p13h5w">“And the Lord said: Whom shall I send? And one answered like unto the Son of Man: Here am I, send me. And another answered and said: Here am I, send me. And the Lord said: I will send the first.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p6" guid="d48ab25e-a6fb-4189-a131-b64108c54232" pid="1ehHgWDQCky1TV6Ueut_Fg" hash="0k9YKw">“And the second was angry, and kept not his first estate; and, at that day, many followed after him.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.24-28" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:24–28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p7" guid="d7d0c789-5738-46af-82dd-1600f9926498" pid="0woVMU3Ark2kl89ErQRX6Q" hash="2khxpA">Lucifer, who was another of our elder brothers, a son of the morning, must have made a very attractive offer. I can imagine his saying, “Follow me and I will give you a new plan—the old one is outdated; you don’t have to take a chance. I’ll guarantee that all will return; none shall be lost.” He was a good psychologist. He appealed to our desires for security. He made his plan so attractive that a third of the hosts of heaven followed him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p8" guid="0375e3bf-32b9-40e6-a2a9-3f2bf422e610" pid="-e5U5ozbS0-2DZZQOceK2w" hash="TNHkig">They gave up their right and claim to free agency. They didn’t learn of the full consequences of that decision. They lost their right to choose—the right to make their own decisions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p9" guid="a5053220-30eb-4a9b-9294-34820c11947f" pid="FLy3fsmuHEmR-ckJdp4zkg" hash="kfBFeQ">A war in heaven followed, and Lucifer and his followers were cast out. They were put here on earth to test us, and they are doing a good job of it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p10" guid="68c2e6cc-1aed-458e-933b-b6e20b1d8740" pid="MHPk3qdV5ECbMOGqLKnsQg" hash="5LNYAQ">Free agency requires that there must be a choice. There must be an opposing force. There is no growth, no movement, no accomplishment or progress without overcoming an opposing force.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p11" guid="f3223239-0de2-4528-a1ca-3b3df972ac2a" pid="HQPLPmDkakebXXPN9Z7MPA" hash="e7N5gg">Lucifer and his agents provided that opposing force, which made free agency possible for us in this life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p12" guid="c817d723-9782-47d2-96df-c6b637c595fc" pid="pZCzUsxVB0WrAzd_iAsLMw" hash="RYgwQA">The right to make a decision, then, is now ours, and it is the greatest asset we have on earth. The Lord will not, and cannot, and does not intend to take it away from us. He intends for us to use it. He is constantly advising us and teaching us how to use it for our own good and further growth, even to attain eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p13" guid="156decb5-0f61-4396-8975-ae598d838091" pid="cdL60Ae6pU6EWomuRZd68w" hash="Xd7zDA">I would think God would be very unjust to put Lucifer here with all his power, to test us and try us, if he did not give us power to resist or overcome him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p14" guid="392efb1f-6720-4785-a5c2-5db893e1a173" pid="B5U1tXHNy0ad77_2JtBJaw" hash="R1Onpw">Remember, Lucifer did not come here of his own choosing. He lost that war in heaven and was put here to do a job, and he is doing a good job.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p15" guid="95d68c06-dbe3-43aa-a979-0df11ed423e3" pid="YXxwKUSDRkqglMgg_UnwBA" hash="84qf9g">God is just. Lucifer, then, can do on this earth only what he is permitted to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p16" guid="e8e1d2aa-9fb2-472f-a304-f027742f4f4f" pid="A4aQw7wT3E2HePb2aRD6jg" hash="NECTJg">Remember the story of Job? In each trial Job was subjected to, Lucifer asked for permission to test Job. He was given permission to go just so far, one step at a time. Job lost his wealth on one test, his family on another, his health on another. Then the Lord gave Satan full control over Job, except he could not destroy his soul.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p17" guid="e0951318-a5f6-4292-8c53-4df39f8736a3" pid="-IDeKpYYTUitKmOj9PdggA" hash="G5Qw4A">One step at a time, Job became strengthened to withstand all. Then Job uttered that immortal testimony which we have heard referred to here today:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p18" guid="2b9676f3-7ac3-4609-9241-1af592a29586" pid="EVNxv5EqlUa36VOcZ4RWRg" hash="aPaKNw">“For I know that my redeemer liveth, and that he shall stand at the latter day upon the earth:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p19" guid="6c5df168-54d6-44f3-accc-8c7f0a9bfd08" pid="7ZRTm_QyCEGHjYaK9DSO1A" hash="XIVUDw">“And though after my skin worms destroy this body, yet in my flesh shall I see God:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p20" guid="eda93c08-c131-4f18-b558-347894a45b75" pid="wkezWILEmkC5bJ_H1xaLJg" hash="KYfi0A">“Whom I shall see for myself, and mine eyes shall behold, and not another; though my reins be consumed within me.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/job/19.25-27" class="scriptureRef">Job 19:25–27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p21" guid="24c9ba40-9ab3-4ec6-8aa4-ac8111eb3d02" pid="ZaMHW3kj2ESyQe5q11_8Ug" hash="V6JPzQ">If we are to attain a degree of perfection, we too must come to that stage where, if the Lord desired, he could loose Satan on us with his full power, except not to destroy the soul. If we withstand that, then we will have attained a stage of perfection, even exaltation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p22" guid="97c0a354-c613-46a2-9d08-0b73838f726b" pid="6m8x-HNbzEqDSsCbMfqRJQ" hash="ALprtQ">As with Job, so with us, the Lord will not permit Satan to try us beyond our ability to resist or withstand his efforts, if we will accept his help.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p23" guid="7e72cdc8-b508-40e6-8659-242b6ed9a6ad" pid="38JopLqPjE2eBUIb0f9KVA" hash="O-kZBA">Here, then, is a key to help us make correct decisions. The Lord told Oliver Cowdery when he tried to translate the record:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p24" guid="683cf9ba-9224-42bf-8d4f-c992b973a545" pid="0j2y1mWeDUmSOoYtxe7k0w" hash="-N_kFg">“Behold, you have not understood; you have supposed that I would give it unto you, when you took no thought save it was to ask me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p25" guid="ac9985a0-681f-4912-8d31-5581bf8546d6" pid="6MP2CC1VvkiNu30T3TfZKA" hash="oFCrQw">“But, behold, I say unto you, that you must study it out in your mind; then you must ask me if it be right, and if it is right I will cause that your bosom shall burn within you; therefore, you shall feel that it is right.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p26" guid="9d3d757c-fb69-4ac1-b7e5-d5702129b867" pid="R9yeSKCD2Eyz5ONurTkopA" hash="gwhi-w">“But if it be not right you shall have no such feelings, but you shall have a stupor of thought that shall cause you to forget the thing which is wrong; therefore, you cannot write that which is sacred save it be given you from me.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/9.7-9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 9:7–9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p27" guid="2778426d-060a-42ea-be4d-6e34425a062d" pid="n1cYXvSZDUyInEGmxTm8wA" hash="9Cwekg">The Lord has said, “Seek and you shall find. Knock and it shall be opened unto you. Ask and you shall receive.” (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.7" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 7:7</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/11.9" class="scriptureRef">Luke 11:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p28" guid="1da2cec5-6389-4223-a799-4c08b6ad446c" pid="p87gOMpSL02Gib965WNvbw" hash="akND-Q">It’s your decision. Each individual must make his own decisions. No one can live someone else’s life for him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p29" guid="c4af2a8f-6dba-41cf-9216-26225d60ebad" pid="RwMA2LZrSUmZwtnHun6M7w" hash="2ZVfmg">If you ask the Lord for help, he will give you strength, power, and ability to overcome Lucifer and withstand his efforts, and thus you will be strengthened and made more perfect. We must seek the Lord’s help in prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p30" guid="7103ba88-1560-4145-a08a-d64d5669cb44" pid="F72EBnXSiUqyvr9gCfKIXA" hash="KEOwww">The Lord has made no promise to those who try to go it alone. As soon as you think you can lick the devil alone, on your own, without the Lord’s help, you have lost the battle before you start.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p31" guid="23a926db-5b7c-4d4c-9fb8-10185b25081e" pid="hxMS5d76MU-7xPflW_RjzA" hash="CS09aQ">I have heard numerous stories of people who have tried to change their habits, to live the Word of Wisdom, or to pay their tithing, all on their own, without the Lord’s help, and have failed, but when they have asked the Lord for help, it has become easy, and then they have also received a testimony of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p32" guid="92971a3b-d54d-4799-93cc-5ab2420ad42b" pid="QP2_EYemn0ajojTZsNSpBg" hash="-9Ipkw">The Lord has given us many laws and commandments to follow. We must have his help to follow them. These are given for the most part to test our ability to make a decision on our own: to see if we will accept what is generally referred to as the first law of heaven, the law of obedience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p33" guid="7dd2b74a-37c6-4421-b817-41a37fc0ee46" pid="B-iGyCBKYUuDN5pNSoFQ4Q" hash="a5VRaQ">When you desire to do what the Lord wants you to do because he wants you to, then ask him for help; then keeping these laws and commandments becomes easy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p34" guid="4447093e-5aa1-4c33-b15b-841abff15fa0" pid="cOYJ2Z2ZzkK9rvxAOV8eVw" hash="1uYnkA">It is your decision!</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.f1" guid="c1a599b0-5152-4ffc-90c4-b7d50ef66c94">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="MHriCXieAkqseYP3dPr6yg" hash="PoVCOg">“Know this, that every soul is free</p>
          <p class="line" pid="s5inp4qRTU-0om8m3rYu4g" hash="UGe9_g">To choose his life and what he’ll be,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="S8aP_ZY1M0KvzA7k_VcJcA" hash="-1Bkvg">For this eternal truth is given</p>
          <p class="line" pid="QtkV-nja8kuW5esib0cmMA" hash="0SlKjw">That God will force no man to heav’n.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="RyKFG8AsG0-Ba67ijZIC3w" hash="1rZbbQ">He’ll call, persuade, direct aright.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="fCy4FbVlKk2AJ-HRDDPlug" hash="wVAJxg">And bless with wisdom, love, and light,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="3Rvxr_USSkSVz06ghgOoIQ" hash="De4ZKA">In nameless ways be good and kind,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="X82sJ9ZtPECwidvH7Gditg" hash="AranKg">But never force the human mind.”</p>
        </div>
        <p class="citationInfo" pid="1M2_SkSnwUKSW2GYJtIXTA" hash="Nwczhg">—<span class="emphasis">Hymns, </span>No. 90</p>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p35" guid="588edbff-4d60-4968-8a8d-b0f2453a58fa" pid="_f1TprjsAEClvWIyDz0rCg" hash="IVtJBw">I encourage all to realize the importance, and the great asset that is ours, of free agency, and learn to use it wisely by making decisions with the help of the Lord through prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/decisions.p36" guid="ea4fd9c2-5bee-44e1-9ec7-ae6c614dd8b3" pid="Ly5LiRcuGUSRJgYUBcR2pA" hash="gv5zLQ">I pray for the blessings of the Lord upon all who seek to do his will, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/10/decisions</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1971-general-conference/1971-10-1040-elder-eldred-g-smith-64k-eng.mp3" length="4212771" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 1971 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peace</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/04/peace?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In that upper room in Jerusalem where the Last Supper was held, Jesus gave his disciples considerable instructions. Among many things he taught them, he said: “Peace I leave with you, my peace I give unto you: not as the world giveth, give I unto you</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03020_000_7020" doc-version="2" hash="yIvmQw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="xwDBXsx-aU6tsrgE73ROgA" hash="If2o6w">Peace</h1><p class="authorName" guid="2be8b653-7184-4f52-a6f1-6897138d78dc" pid="39ObqAmGK02KPpptqJWIlQ" hash="f2lL9w">Eldred G. Smith</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="08cfe9c4-0ced-4207-a614-4afd69c3af26">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3104.jpg" alt="Elder Eldred G. Smith" guid="cdf5ce6e-b056-4707-b5e6-dece39b085ad" pid="8f9I9T2nQUOiLMsQJFkAFQ" hash="Bi433w" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p1" guid="0c3f4908-0b09-49cc-b715-b8899972dfea" pid="nINkQdbF302x0UeG4gzjzw" hash="YOyKGA">In that upper room in Jerusalem where the Last Supper was held, Jesus gave his disciples considerable instructions. Among many things he taught them, he said: “Peace I leave with you, my peace I give unto you: not as the world giveth, give I unto you. Let not your heart be troubled, neither let it be afraid.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.27" class="scriptureRef">John 14:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p2" guid="fa789527-8ee5-4668-946b-95758b4bef75" pid="Yh864rwwsUKCchUkZCh4hQ" hash="RUZOhQ">Again he said: “These things I have spoken unto you, that in me ye might have peace. In the world ye shall have tribulation: but be of good cheer; I have overcome the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/16.33" class="scriptureRef">John 16:33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p3" guid="16d0ced7-851c-4de5-9ffb-a0e2c9659f30" pid="glO_naZNsEyOQz9px0v0Cg" hash="xIO3CA">Peace is a much-used word nowadays. We hear it on every side, in every newspaper, in every magazine. Men are truly running to and fro all over the earth looking for peace. We think of it as a modern form of salutation, but it is as old as mankind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p4" guid="ca24ece7-f9de-4349-a3a6-f57cb45daefe" pid="OA4nsVpNFEKmfBQpNeUvyA" hash="YicD-g">The people of biblical lands have always greeted each other with “Peace be unto you” or “Peace be with you.” Yet that little section of the earth has always been torn by wars and by captivity and bondage for the people, under a succession of rulers. At the time of Christ, they were under the rule of the Roman Empire.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p5" guid="0f6a41ec-b842-4193-b155-e4555e1fca50" pid="nYikHWk7ikKjia4EE8xX5w" hash="gPP0QA">Naturally, the Jews expected a “Redeemer,” a “Savior,” and thought he was to release them from bondage. Isaiah wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p6" guid="75b5ef2b-ff8d-4d55-b69a-2943043167b1" pid="vSTcVyBORkqZFrH5qYOB8A" hash="QIRiIQ">“For unto us a child is born, unto us a son is given: and the government shall be upon his shoulder: and his name shall be called Wonderful, Counsellor, The mighty God, The everlasting Father, The Prince of Peace.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/9.6" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 9:6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p7" guid="28306985-d42b-44ac-8799-9ad495af36cc" pid="Txb3ie5HwEKhF6kDNhimEw" hash="truLFQ">Peace was not brought to this land called the Holy Land. Even today the hulks of old tanks and other war machines lie rusting on the sides of the roads. Ever-present soldiers keep vigilant watch along the borders. Nor has peace come to the rest of the world. Yet, in the Sermon on the Mount, Christ taught peace. He said, “Blessed are the peacemakers: for they shall be called the children of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.9" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p8" guid="f134eb4b-47e1-41a1-9507-5a62c88598f5" pid="5XV9OnMPZkSikT2cS1t7Lg" hash="CrgqyQ">Speaking to his disciples, Jesus said: “Peace I leave with you, my peace I give unto you: not as the world giveth, give I unto you. Let not your heart be troubled, neither let it be afraid.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.27" class="scriptureRef">John 14:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p9" guid="91346efb-f335-4736-a524-d26a821ed14a" pid="9ckaugndiUiV2iPtcq46pA" hash="IGrP7w">What kind of peace did Christ mean? I think his own acts explain what he meant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p10" guid="98b440b1-0952-44c7-b8e8-692df6673bca" pid="OnY7l-11ek6ojRRz_qOYGg" hash="CZUEEg">After the Last Supper, when Christ had finished his instructions to the apostles, John wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p11" guid="4d9cc3e7-9295-4e1d-8062-3563e0781c28" pid="iyhWtJe8QU2Bev0mKfh7BA" hash="RM0QKw">“When Jesus had spoken these words, he went forth with his disciples over the brook Cedron, where was a garden, into the which he entered, and his disciples.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p12" guid="ad63083a-48b3-4463-aee8-3ddc2b4d5e4c" pid="RxD1VT9jBUWRVPJFElJmQw" hash="RF0XjA">“And Judas also, which betrayed him, knew the place: for Jesus ofttimes resorted thither with his disciples.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p13" guid="4cdafc6b-e789-4769-8e00-ecff2b83154f" pid="tTm9B7_sk0egSb8DhDPvwg" hash="-JBwaQ">“Judas then, having received a band of men and officers from the chief priests and Pharisees, cometh thither with lanterns and torches and weapons.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p14" guid="a448d143-da18-47c0-bf35-896b8dbce46a" pid="8ekIYZQT-kKy9E_Kz2Hk7Q" hash="4ljq_w">“Jesus therefore, knowing all things that should come upon him, went forth, and said unto them, Whom seek ye?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p15" guid="c1cfcb47-3eb8-4708-83e0-b8d08131073e" pid="Fn8ofATo5EKF-_2D6ErsAQ" hash="yA-dLw">“They answered him, Jesus of Nazareth. Jesus saith unto them, I am he. And Judas also, which betrayed him, stood with them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p16" guid="dc9eb10d-2fb4-45a7-b795-f485600c62b8" pid="6cZeB6Qv00if4GjqQlsBAw" hash="wKR_YA">“As soon then as he had said unto them, I am he, they went backward, and fell to the ground.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p17" guid="16964fd0-116f-45f5-b0c3-b18d19006483" pid="853hV-9-Wk-zQj4DBLCDcg" hash="BmbP_Q">“Then asked he them again, Whom seek ye? And they said, Jesus of Nazareth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p18" guid="8ce83a7b-429e-4a36-ac21-d5292238a005" pid="Pznx8kD65EiZzmy8TDeHLA" hash="Q4iWpg">“Jesus answered, I have told you that I am he: if therefore ye seek me, let these go their way.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/18.1-8" class="scriptureRef">John 18:1–8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p19" guid="6d8dd471-5006-4c68-9e6e-22d12f1b40d1" pid="u_2shrQ5pk-Y__iNQ1SY8A" hash="kn8aTg">Can you match that display of calmness? of peace? Here they are coming to take a man they want to kill, and he as much as says, “Here I am, take me, but let my friends go.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p20" guid="8b55d829-1ed0-4df9-97a6-df442bf1bc84" pid="EPcE6zFc8kytvMDPD_EOoA" hash="3p-sbg">Then when he stood before Pilate, under the pressure of rigid questioning, Pilate could not raise his ire. In perfect peace, he answered his questions. Pilate found no wrong in him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p21" guid="5719f864-c388-4c7a-9b2c-c31c159625bf" pid="L_v53JQTdU-fzHFwCgdSHg" hash="Nuiapg">After he was crucified and then resurrected, his first message to his disciples was, “Peace be unto you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/20.21" class="scriptureRef">John 20:21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p22" guid="a471ce12-d57d-4126-901d-cd18919bcb4f" pid="ErxK1Yu54Ui2BhReeanJiA" hash="qUAOEw">How is it that we have not discovered the secret of peace when we have been looking for it all through the ages? I’ll tell you. We are looking for someone to create it for us—to bring it to us. Edna St. Vincent Millay said: “There is no peace on earth today, save the peace in the heart at home with God. … No man can be at peace with his neighbor who is not at peace with himself. …” (“Conversations at Midnight,” <span class="emphasis">Collected Poems, </span>Harper &amp; Row, Copyright 1937 and 1964.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p23" guid="829887d5-5093-4965-96bd-443bfd047f69" pid="_JhwYw9-MUuAMBgdMsLn6A" hash="vYpwdA">Have you experienced that peace within you because you helped your neighbor rake his lawn or mow his lawn? Have you felt that peace within because you helped your neighbor pick his fruit or harvest his crops? Have you witnessed that peace within because you shoveled the snow off your neighbor’s walks? Have you felt that peace which came because you helped someone solve a problem and get a new lease on life? Have you “cheered up the sad, and made someone feel glad”?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p24" guid="e34edc69-9eb4-4eb1-af14-91a04bec2838" pid="1tIXtyr0YkeLEYkIFHBACQ" hash="NlbkWQ">Did you ever have a guilty conscience? Do you know the turmoil and tumult it can bring to your very soul? It can cause mental and even physical illness. Do you know the blessed relief of rectifying whatever caused this feeling? It may have been an unkind word, a thoughtless act, or it may have gone deeper than that. Until you have adjusted whatever causes a guilty conscience, you cannot hope for peace of mind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p25" guid="d432f5d3-618a-452a-8f8d-be484e28c612" pid="6y4XPRlHdEaSaBwtfz_ExQ" hash="3aMlyw">Do you, at this time, have unkind feelings or less than love in your heart for a friend, a neighbor, or any of God’s children? Try doing something extra nice for that person, and keep it up until all the bitterness has gone from your heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p26" guid="ae9c6cfe-3d2b-44ae-b9d2-e0bc9a123386" pid="QkBAVj7VlUqRaFfqCjWdZQ" hash="V5Tvxw">Have you taught a Sunday School class and felt when you finished that you had really taught someone some principle of the gospel that had really helped him or given him a brighter look on life? Remember the feeling of peace and joy that followed? Have you ever taught someone the gospel and received that feeling of joy because he had accepted what you had been teaching? The thrill of missionary work!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p27" guid="62713471-7a3c-4c22-b6ad-aa3abedf2ccd" pid="fr9veeGwV0iUaSdBSk7PoA" hash="Kb8WMg">Have you sensed the thrill, the peace within your soul, that comes from a knowledge of the gospel and from accepting and living in accordance with the teachings of the gospel of Jesus Christ? Have you felt the peace from doing temple work, vicarious work for the dead?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p28" guid="90d2fb01-fe50-49b9-892c-5622ecba85e2" pid="6j5DqIYHbEyZ2plzIKwbrg" hash="2Lj0Pg">A key to peace, then, is service. Christ said: “But he that is greatest among you shall be your servant.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/23.11" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 23:11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p29" guid="db6c79f4-5253-4283-8c2f-29d90146689f" pid="Iz02p_tvSE2xWEXZGe6m2g" hash="1XIU5Q">Have you ever been aware that all the use of priesthood is service to someone else? Haven’t you always had a good feeling of peace within when you have been fulfilling your priesthood duty?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p30" guid="6a85c64a-9654-4020-9449-f2c9dcae40bb" pid="bWbdAgD6Q0etAxiI7slzfQ" hash="nUzWVg">Peace, then, comes from service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p31" guid="50de947b-f202-44be-933d-5c9adc675cd5" pid="_3gJtoadWEuinP0NC-OWvg" hash="nnggMQ">The Lord has said: “For behold, this is my work and my glory—to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p32" guid="d788baed-6f61-463e-869b-3f7c57a5b6a4" pid="G2bnwpybSUaNaQ1KxQjQKQ" hash="8B6k0Q">Is this not the ultimate of service? To become as God is, then, we must eliminate enmity, greed, and selfishness, and all our efforts must be in service to others. The Lord said: “… he who doeth the works of righteousness shall receive his reward, even peace in this world, and eternal life in the world to come.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p33" guid="5ade5918-19d4-400e-9056-c84838a0e237" pid="Omf9UyOFoU-yQY4uzDQ-nw" hash="D8Tz0g">Joseph Smith was an example of utmost peace in the face of tribulation. Though he had been arrested and acquitted thirty-seven times, he knew this time he would not return. On the way from Nauvoo to Carthage, Joseph Smith said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p34" guid="b7480c47-e3c6-41f4-9769-2679a2378950" pid="6DEIpXmx7Ued7aZMzRC9Dw" hash="OpCkBg">“I am going like a lamb to the slaughter; but I am calm as a summer’s morning; I have a conscience void of offense toward God and towards all men. I shall die innocent, and it shall yet be said of me—he was murdered in cold blood.” (<span class="emphasis">Documentary History of the Church, </span>vol. 6, p. 630.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p35" guid="248cf129-6f18-41fd-bdad-adaa2ab3de29" pid="HfmJGUwyvEGCE4brjAUmwg" hash="5P-hUQ">Then at Carthage, Joseph wrote to his wife, Emma, the following: “I am very much resigned to my lot, knowing I am justified, and have done the best that could be done. Give my love to the children … and all who inquire after me. … May God bless you all.” (<span class="emphasis">DHC, </span>vol. 6, p. 605.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p36" guid="e06c8883-e0e6-46c4-83bd-4ab1ccc12eb7" pid="IONbuhUDiE2-CEr6AKUMGQ" hash="yZZlyA">Isaiah says: “And the work of righteousness shall be peace; and the effect of righteousness quietness and assurance for ever” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/32.17" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 32:17</a>)—the assurance of knowing you are living in accordance with God’s will.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p37" guid="344478ec-6705-407f-b1eb-413eda3a4896" pid="ZJ4dnAG0JkS8NmlmGC3-Ew" hash="jilUYQ">Our guide on a recent tour in the Holy Land, who is a Jordanian Arab and a Greek Orthodox Catholic by the name of Sari Rabadi, taught us a little Arabian song: <span class="emphasis">“Havano, shalo, malechem,” </span>which translated means: “We bring you peace.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p38" guid="56cd019f-7197-4e1c-85bb-82d1af6053c7" pid="kKmYznwqrUWPV_pFc684sQ" hash="ZopfnA">Yes, Sari, we say to you and to all the world, we bring you peace. We bring you the peace of the gospel, that peace which Christ meant when he said, “… my peace I give unto you: not as the world giveth, give I unto you. …” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.27" class="scriptureRef">John 14:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p39" guid="9653abe6-82f7-4a9c-8ef7-ec66eec78f7c" pid="PeNXXMD59EmtH7Cte36g6w" hash="o3MuGQ">If each person would have peace within his soul, then there would be peace in the family. If there is peace in each family, then there is peace in the nation. If there is peace in the nations, there is peace in the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p40" guid="c68f54c1-9f5e-4e8b-9db0-c908b933bb5f" pid="4mBTj27vPUW0i_KBrWw1ZQ" hash="9NT4eQ">Let us not just sing, “Let there be peace on earth and let it begin with me,” but let us mean it. Make it my goal—your goal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p41" guid="b4e52d5f-23b5-4cd3-9362-6286cd40fc1a" pid="xg3iGfnGGkGOClWLejwH4w" hash="LXFJ6g">When the Savior comes again—and he will come—he will bring peace only as we will accept and follow his teachings of service to others and eliminate enmity and unrighteousness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p42" guid="d437c6eb-a429-4878-9b99-30ccecc9f14c" pid="GH4rErFOtUOotH_kZLZg9Q" hash="B14rrA">That angel which John saw “fly in the midst of heaven, having the everlasting gospel to preach unto them that dwell on the earth” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rev/14.6" class="scriptureRef">Rev. 14:6</a>) has already come. The gospel of Jesus Christ has been established on the earth, never again to be taken from the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/peace.p43" guid="ccc42f80-5d14-44c5-ac29-76e4a1d8f14c" pid="Nm0hDKaJeka_1ARQ-oKjbQ" hash="6ivoAQ">His kingdom is already here on earth and is growing rapidly to prepare for his coming. Yes, he shall surely come and bring peace to the earth, but only as we are willing to follow his teachings. This is his work, and his kingdom, which is the only way to world peace and eternal peace. I so testify in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/04/peace</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1972-general-conference/1972-04-7020-elder-eldred-g-smith-64k-eng.mp3" length="5556452" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Do Latter-day Saints Build Temples?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples?lang=eng</link>
      <description>It was a pleasure for me to sustain Brother Harold B. Lee as the President of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, and to sustain all of the other General Authorities this morning.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03027_000_2060" doc-version="2" hash="5DM8CA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="_ioDy_pezUO2IfI4tPz4YQ" hash="M7darw">Why Do Latter-day Saints Build Temples?</h1><p class="authorName" guid="2be8b653-7184-4f52-a6f1-6897138d78dc" pid="_qXxXh9s50G94724XAqzCQ" hash="f2lL9w">Eldred G. Smith</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="aeab4259-1b26-4b98-bcad-e48a0c53ff73">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p1" guid="9276fc15-8394-4d64-a197-1039a805b527" pid="YQb7-tla-Ey1qahOag5OYQ" hash="CmlSXA">It was a pleasure for me to sustain Brother Harold B. Lee as the President of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, and to sustain all of the other General Authorities this morning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p2" guid="da6a70ec-d697-4eab-8f80-354d897c02f5" pid="ffDEag9vl0qAthwun6ApPw" hash="5nq3MA">I wish to express appreciation for that sustaining vote in my behalf and pledge to all my leaders here my full support. I am willing to do all that is required of me to help build up the kingdom of the Lord upon the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p3" guid="a26481b3-8890-4e65-9416-9c840a28c415" pid="yBMId6xzUki8mUCo5CsSYg" hash="udvTUg">A question that is often asked by many and comes to the minds of many who are not members of our faith is: “Why do Latter-day Saints build temples?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p4" guid="d9554c63-8a98-42f3-9687-6462a1db8cc9" pid="D15qOc7vh0e_XtKhDvQbbQ" hash="h-cXwg">Our third Article of Faith is: “We believe that through the Atonement of Christ, all mankind may be saved, by obedience to the laws and ordinances of the Gospel.” [<a href="/scriptures/pgp/a-of-f/1.3" class="scriptureRef">A of F 1:3</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p5" guid="ba5d835d-41bb-4979-8bd1-f82be7d627c6" pid="_F1DpMoeHkWtrHg7YKRdGw" hash="C__MuA">The fourth Article of Faith follows: “We believe that the first principles and ordinances of the Gospel are: first, Faith in the Lord Jesus Christ; second, Repentance; third, Baptism by immersion for the remission of sins; fourth, Laying on of hands for the gift of the Holy Ghost.” [<a href="/scriptures/pgp/a-of-f/1.4" class="scriptureRef">A of F 1:4</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p6" guid="f8b9f566-2aed-4e24-b25a-36d0990c771b" pid="GtdaX2kPOUOkApa603xIWw" hash="3ZxDMQ">With God, all laws and ordinances must be complied with and obeyed. Christ said to Nicodemus, “Verily, verily, I say unto thee, Except a man be born again, he cannot see the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p7" guid="8385bf51-7469-4fbc-ba6a-b9d337cf82e1" pid="WPN1uj0u10CmNUarsxBYFA" hash="KWisAw">“Nicodemus saith unto him, How can a man be born when he is old? can he enter the second time into his mother’s womb, and be born?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p8" guid="e4c1b01e-c315-4107-b264-9f691313b16e" pid="Ih8mLzAfPUaEwV3ValJNNw" hash="gAtfgA">“Jesus answered, Verily, verily, I say unto thee, Except a man be born of water and of the Spirit, he cannot enter into the kingdom of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.3-5" class="scriptureRef">John 3:3–5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p9" guid="61dc39cf-e736-4b69-88bf-550f482688ab" pid="-GucPTL0ZUGX2rAkBUCksw" hash="5swjow">Christ had already confirmed the fullness and exactness of this law in his own compliance thereto, as recorded in Matthew: “Then cometh Jesus from Galilee to Jordan unto John, to be baptized of him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p10" guid="aeeb35e5-1912-405b-8778-e77da1600a80" pid="plsK7zwaZEOzyCXIDTCVKQ" hash="YNYc6w">“But John forbad him, saying, I have need to be baptized of thee, and comest thou to me?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p11" guid="f18b1274-9cb0-44cc-a1a8-b4c7a7b63016" pid="dIhE7t_DTUeG_fihS3qgLw" hash="etuspg">“And Jesus answering said unto him, Suffer it to be so now: for thus it becometh us to fulfil all righteousness. Then he suffered him.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/3.13-15" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 3:13–15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p12" guid="09ba7827-1683-4f96-ac47-a5edcfb28b26" pid="ZPZklMcTR0aebd3nn2dutw" hash="j4qN2A">Baptism, then, is for <span class="emphasis">all </span>mankind, even Christ, the very Son of God, who was perfect and without sin. Then it is all the more necessary for all of <span class="emphasis">us.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p13" guid="f45aa7dd-2812-44af-a61d-c7b5ff322d1d" pid="cajmGFQVmUyz1_n_272QrQ" hash="S6iiRw">If required for all mankind, then would a just God condemn for all eternity those who came to the earth at such time when, and such places where, such opportunities were not available—hence, impossible for them to comply with the law?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p14" guid="593f6424-2732-4a4c-ae27-53489ed06e7b" pid="aPHHqhhAREeUzCvYqkrmKw" hash="DIvyDw">Then if God is just, and we know he is, he must provide a way whereby all mankind may receive his ordinances, and they must be so performed as shall be accepted by him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p15" guid="2a402258-86ce-4a74-ac9e-859a22718d96" pid="4N21YfhqnE6qdvPFuH6ScQ" hash="mTs-Hw">Peter tells us in his First Epistle that between the time of Christ’s crucifixion and his resurrection, he was actively engaged in preaching to the spirits of those who had died:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p16" guid="262e1ac8-e54b-4b90-bd5f-6d750becdea1" pid="CFBApLJsY0mjo6pCX712dA" hash="VV7scg">“By which also he went and preached unto the spirits in prison;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p17" guid="8fb702d3-3181-4ae5-9987-94cfa1174867" pid="JE8tV410SkiJOaU6-_DLYw" hash="dzvWKQ">“Which sometime were disobedient, when once the longsuffering of God waited in the days of Noah, while the ark was a preparing, wherein few, that is, eight souls were saved by water.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-pet/3.19-20" class="scriptureRef">1 Pet. 3:19–20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p18" guid="9d9b92b7-3fea-480f-8143-5aa95c8fd049" pid="K4c602agRUikDa35cL3ouQ" hash="Kw93HA">This opened the way for all who did not have the opportunity to accept his gospel in this life to accept it after death. This does not provide the ordinance of baptism, which is a must for entrance into the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p19" guid="d32cf5d4-1977-40b7-bfff-52b656dd0aa5" pid="peGUJ5dDM0Cd9msBJYGsBA" hash="AAYRRw">Paul, preaching to the Corinthians, trying to convert them to the reality of a resurrection, asked them, “Else what shall they do which are baptized for the dead, if the dead rise not at all? why are they then baptized for the dead?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/15.29" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 15:29</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p20" guid="7f012211-0080-4493-aa5d-731773d0ea11" pid="uNdNrg5OoEGwnLO4mVQt6w" hash="WzroMA">Obviously, they were then practicing a vicarious ordinance of baptism for their kindred dead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p21" guid="ba67fc75-b6f7-4f7b-94e1-030e74763cdd" pid="JLOhmAxSLk-qzSzYoOXTXQ" hash="SwIN6w">Christ suffered vicariously for us; now he is giving us the opportunity to perform a vicarious act for our fellowmen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p22" guid="d56387a4-55f1-4dfd-a732-789e4e9d2657" pid="KJnOa0Bd0k-S7j2gXhO-hQ" hash="2zvGKg">There are yet other requirements needed. How can this vicarious work be done if the names of those who have died are not known?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p23" guid="adb7d273-4c82-4743-9f5d-f34ae1e15950" pid="VMCgJY6-T0ynrk76Cb4jOA" hash="YUeleQ">The necessity, then, is very apparent that records must be kept, researched, and obtained to do this work for each individual, separately.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p24" guid="908f647d-fb6f-4810-8dfc-1598b75a5cc2" pid="tGUi41I1EkKf8QpH23zyVw" hash="042pXg">In April 1836, at the completion of the temple in Kirtland, Ohio, several heavenly messengers appeared to Joseph Smith and Oliver Cowdery. Note—not to Joseph Smith alone, but to Joseph and Oliver. Two witnessed these visitations. Among them was Elijah the prophet, who ascended into heaven without tasting death.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p25" guid="adc7d29d-9b26-462c-9ff6-173b6c6a9281" pid="brK8mD272kmQkXCziO_5Ag" hash="yehpNg">Thirteen years earlier, Joseph Smith had been promised by a heavenly messenger by the name of Moroni that Elijah would be sent to him. The Prophet Joseph Smith described the keys Elijah bestowed upon them in these words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p26" guid="f4f3f78f-f3b0-4a8c-952b-d3b8ae39e821" pid="oKsnYSgwQ0yxGgIOw4gqBA" hash="47E4_g">“The spirit, power, and calling of Elijah is, that ye have power to hold the keys of the revelation, ordinances, oracles, powers, and endowments of the fullness of the Melchizedek Priesthood and of the kingdom of God on the earth: and to receive, obtain, and perform <span class="emphasis">all </span>the ordinances belonging to the kingdom of God, even unto the turning of the hearts of the fathers unto the children, and the hearts of the children unto their fathers, even those who are in heaven.” (<span class="emphasis">Documentary History of the Church, </span>vol. 6, p. 251. Italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p27" guid="91cc16f2-4068-4f02-bd25-c7d20c35e73e" pid="8xD7utL9VkiW6GfNMWlw3A" hash="BbbEsg">Our forefathers who did not have this opportunity were promised that this day would come. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.26-27" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:26–27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p28" guid="74f88508-5fe1-4193-a9ca-4e9eb140f71c" pid="t047pcMOMkGohSOuDE9rEA" hash="zr9PaA">Since the coming of Elijah the prophet to Joseph Smith and Oliver Cowdery in the Kirtland Temple, this work of gathering the names has taken on great proportions by people of all walks of life and in many nations. This is a miraculous undertaking. Think of the way the Lord has inspired the scientific minds of our day to provide machines of all kinds to speed up and make possible this great undertaking.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p29" guid="b7787906-a43b-4e36-9363-a5ddff90caed" pid="UmLxttnZikyGK4edX7faUA" hash="R5YkaA">Five years after Elijah’s coming, in a revelation to the Prophet Joseph Smith in 1841, the Lord directed his people to “build a house to my name, for the Most High to dwell therein.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p30" guid="c11dfcb2-2fe5-4ba0-84ad-8a696780200d" pid="hcIiw-dSFUKu0Sbt85jb0g" hash="07sJ3Q">“For there is not a place found on earth that he may come to and restore again that which was lost unto you, or which he hath taken away, even the fulness of the priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p31" guid="212ca75f-7180-4c47-9858-5fbcada7f0ff" pid="I0GwE3zwlU2n7A3SAvDR-A" hash="OkUbRw">“For a baptismal font there is not upon the earth, that they, my saints, may be baptized for those who are dead—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p32" guid="4b930824-11e1-4c4e-85be-2a4cd0ba8076" pid="FWHFTBOLdk-gHfuLdVhIhA" hash="Ks3-yA">“For this ordinance belongeth to my house, and cannot be acceptable to me, only in the days of your poverty, wherein ye are not able to build a house unto me.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/124.27-30" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 124:27–30</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p33" guid="0f374338-3558-4430-90ae-9995d0ff9eab" pid="tujuKHlVVEKDB4pAQInUyw" hash="ThgHIg">Then he tells of other sacred ordinances that are to be performed in his house, or a temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p34" guid="0ddf1f30-55fc-4190-8359-babd4a95f140" pid="6xld9VUYEU2_AT5QRG9NHw" hash="tbetHw">Thus it is necessary to build temples, houses of the Lord, sacred edifices in which may be performed the ordinance of baptism and other sacred ordinances vicariously for our dead ancestors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p35" guid="84f4b9b0-79ba-4250-a37a-68aeaa0af948" pid="KUsi5oaRsECe5oDPLwd57Q" hash="icST6Q">Elijah brought the keys to perform <span class="emphasis">all </span>the sacred ordinances belonging to the kingdom of God. All these most sacred ordinances necessary for man’s exaltation in the life to come, even eternal life, are accepted by God only when they are performed in his sacred house, a temple of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p36" guid="294782ac-4d4b-4b40-9597-554b109c25ef" pid="ZKP5rRh4rkeJquc-KI1PEg" hash="V7lFTQ">For this reason, the children of Israel constructed an “ark of the covenant,” which was portable, so they might have the blessings of the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p37" guid="c1a5ef17-c024-4869-b9db-4edc5469c1a0" pid="mC3J5hUYu0yERbSx9GFwRQ" hash="lOiC-g">To receive the fullness of the blessings of exaltation, even eternal life, man must receive <span class="emphasis">all </span>the law and the ordinances of God’s kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p38" guid="6efe79d6-ea17-4926-a1b8-e44a91dff3bb" pid="tNkoaBm1hE6Vt2bnCHUbSw" hash="XBYn9Q">Another requirement to fulfill all the law is <span class="emphasis">people.</span> We, as members of the Church, must so live as to be worthy to go into the house of the Lord to perform these most sacred ordinances, first for ourselves, then for our dead ancestors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p39" guid="c1392559-aba5-45f4-865a-e56949f6828b" pid="VVBT0yB93U2mqn9R-NpoXg" hash="NfM6lQ">The living come first. It is necessary for us to receive these ordinances first; then we may be privileged to do this work for our ancestors, to whom the promise was made that we would come to earth in this the dispensation of the fulness of times to do this work for them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p40" guid="8e5f355a-78e1-45d2-b123-d79d2866a4f8" pid="d9crjD4Zf0GSVrtKa7xHWw" hash="8XUdag">The time must come when temples will be found all over the earth, in many nations. This is most necessary for the salvation, exaltation, and eternal life of man. Then we should all be very diligent in gathering the family records and so live to be worthy of taking part in this work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples.p41" guid="8fe1fd17-249f-4439-a4ed-3bba664c024d" pid="ZT6PnX-1f0ilX39jr9Xb4w" hash="70oERQ">I pray the Lord to bless us to do this work, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/10/why-do-latter-day-saints-build-temples</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1972-general-conference/1972-10-2060-elder-eldred-g-smith-64k-eng.mp3" length="4985039" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opposition in Order to Strengthen Us</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In the heavens, before the earth was formed, the plan of this earth life was explained to all of us. We were then but spirit offspring of our Father and Mother in heaven.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03040_000_4030" doc-version="2" hash="o3LmcQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="zqK1eVfco0Ke74aZTp2DQA" hash="hPCzsA">Opposition in Order to Strengthen Us</h1><p class="authorName" guid="2be8b653-7184-4f52-a6f1-6897138d78dc" pid="Fsjckbp7nEmv4y5-LaOrjw" hash="f2lL9w">Eldred G. Smith</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="a243da1c-7d38-4d2b-ad2e-7fb52a2cc6a6">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p1" guid="eea7ed6d-5e99-4601-a2a2-0eabab1ff732" pid="-Og4geXDzU-_f8nVTOlRIA" hash="vifzoQ">In the heavens, before the earth was formed, the plan of this earth life was explained to all of us. We were then but spirit offspring of our Father and Mother in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p2" guid="1b516079-854c-498e-a74c-facf6a6bbab5" pid="GTD6NYHqQEixqWAX-FSQdg" hash="bh45lg">We all learned then that through this earth life experience we would have the opportunity of going through the same type of experiences they had done and so become as they are.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p3" guid="31616117-b748-480e-86ab-dc8b0ca574f5" pid="Y9sFgxdj_keDvEUIpIdlrg" hash="35Nfaw">The records tell us that we all shouted for joy at this glorious news.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p4" guid="df2a6c74-cd31-4eb6-9496-54e2be371233" pid="Q8gDMpgzTEStX5sDrWaQ6w" hash="ysSchg">We also learned that to attain such lofty goals, we would have to be found true and faithful in all things and withstand the trials and tests which would be put upon us by Satan. In spite of all the warnings, I’m sure we were still anxious to come to this earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p5" guid="21eadc00-3bc7-472e-9273-6a47de0304d4" pid="zxtxPYYSf0yQO37LgHGnQg" hash="vVdu4Q">Adam and Eve were the first to come. They were given their free agency without the capacity of knowing right from wrong until after they had partaken of the fruit of “the tree of knowledge of good and evil. …” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/3.17" class="scriptureRef">Moses 3:17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p6" guid="364079bd-088b-4d75-9ac7-3f8ef1e55360" pid="bDF6F5tU2k6N3S1rh9kSyg" hash="tT3vbw">In consequence thereof, the Lord declared to Adam: “… cursed shall be the <span class="emphasis">ground for thy sake. </span>…” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/4.23" class="scriptureRef">Moses 4:23</a>; italics added.) We often hear it said that Adam was cursed because he partook of the forbidden fruit. The record says “the ground” was cursed, not Adam. Then the Lord added “for thy sake.” This means for his benefit; also for your benefit and mine.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p7" guid="1896d397-0c92-49f2-9275-19d7bd5ca4ef" pid="buNJB-L7u0aCMpbUj1Nb-A" hash="WHuriA">Adam and Eve had been in a state of stagnation: no progress—no growth—no reproduction. Without a change, they would have remained in that state forever. It was necessary for a change to take place. This change meant that Adam and all his posterity would have to <span class="emphasis">work </span>and overcome obstacles to provide the necessities of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p8" guid="97ec659a-e701-4a71-a54e-d2cc467ddf2c" pid="eDWHvMF1CkSncjgkVJQREA" hash="sLPcFg">After Adam and Eve were driven out of the Garden of Eden, an angel of the Lord came and explained to them the gospel plan. He explained the plan of life and salvation. He told them of a Savior who would come and redeem all mankind so that all could return to our Father in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p9" guid="c3209d7b-70a6-4c07-9cb8-58daddd1df85" pid="f4579D90-UuPA9eeJTibEA" hash="ty2O3w">In the Book of Moses we read: “And Eve, his wife, heard all these things and was glad, saying: Were it not for our transgression we never should have had seed, and never should have known good and evil, and the joy of our redemption, and the eternal life which God giveth unto all the obedient.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/5.11" class="scriptureRef">Moses 5:11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p10" guid="3c0fb4c3-79cb-4868-ae60-65a75b88e79a" pid="tLwfiB76PkOEFxvn3-HFzw" hash="xAQRXA">Modern revelation tells us: “… it must needs be that the devil should tempt the children of men, or they could not be agents unto themselves; for if they never should have bitter they could not know the sweet.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/29.39" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 29:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p11" guid="19cbb9fa-84a1-431d-b222-aa49d6342967" pid="w1nzOpZxN0aD1OEPQWwZDA" hash="wJa-fg">So it is with us today, we must also have the bitter in order to know the sweet. Sometimes some of us think we have the bitter and not enough of the sweet. This is normal. We all have our trials of life to <span class="emphasis">strengthen </span>us. Each thinks he has the hardest or most severe trials. It may be that they are the most difficult only because they are the hardest or most difficult for you. The diamond is enhanced and made more valuable with polishing. Steel is made harder and more valuable through tempering. So also opposition builds the character of man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p12" guid="79fb4a4f-2609-491b-a3d2-75ba8c3117dc" pid="skpp6UtgT0eIN5oIxLvfVw" hash="gq3bEA">All progress is made by overcoming an opposing force. Lehi said to his son Jacob: “For it must needs be, that there is an opposition in all things. …” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.11" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p13" guid="87a768fa-7fbf-491f-ad40-e01711e40130" pid="jBvE_9EIJESpCYgTVJ214g" hash="uvXCEA">“Adam fell that men might be; and men are, that they might have joy.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.25" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p14" guid="a95e8cca-23f7-4f69-a889-2008e22d24bb" pid="hUvztYB_SUu7QHBVsY2OMA" hash="azXjDQ">“God … shall consecrate thine afflictions for thy gain.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.2" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:2</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p15" guid="8e5f8fd8-2e73-4395-8155-1c0b73a7e641" pid="jato5auPikeRJzzJKp1mtA" hash="jSz9gA">Opposition, then, is good for us as long as we don’t seek it for opposition’s sake.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p16" guid="0c320b01-6596-4cdd-b67e-729775d05b79" pid="PHj98Iig_0utjhVXOWYAvQ" hash="rTFEJg">This reminds me of one of President Lee’s favorite sayings: “It’s all right to pull the cow out of the mud on Sunday, provided that you don’t push him in on Saturday night.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p17" guid="420b93e0-d67f-44b6-8d77-e9d0c1f70a19" pid="zcDnV_M5rEyoJoXUCsAQrw" hash="P2A9Rw">Henry Kaiser, of the steel industry, said that if you want to find who your leaders are, load them up with work, pour it on. You’ll then find who the leaders are.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p18" guid="79878c24-af98-4553-ac97-f7113abb564d" pid="nn5QGnC82k-5Wx3hn5RRlA" hash="3EaWtQ">It may be that’s just what the Lord does with us. He too is trying to develop leaders.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p19" guid="fcffd167-0cb4-4841-9fc1-7cf7566c0af2" pid="RtmMlR5KMEuHitOvkUOu-A" hash="madE6g">I remember a brass plaque I had on the wall in my room when I was much younger. It depicted a tramp going over the top of a fence. A piece out of the seat of his pants was missing. A bulldog was in close pursuit with the missing piece of pants in his teeth. The verse read:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.f1" guid="eb97b42f-f585-4be8-a96c-699c151accf6">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="keOfCalXrk2Lb36KzVoAYQ" hash="QADldg">
            <span class="emphasis">“Tis easy enough to be pleasant</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="whMdNT5jY02mnI8guwuDGA" hash="2Qf5iw">
            <span class="emphasis">When life goes by with a song,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="AGRKwDriq0KCsLtQTpCc1A" hash="ck7h_A">
            <span class="emphasis">But the man worthwhile</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Lv9j_g6-uU-fR0EBry_TvA" hash="3zBJxg">
            <span class="emphasis">Is the man who can smile</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="FlySWTf30EucG0iY3idx6A" hash="RppkLg">
            <span class="emphasis">When everything goes dead wrong.”</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p20" guid="5cbadcef-90e9-48eb-9413-e1ec1ac6abc0" pid="F6yCRyHoFUKLYWnwuWnOWQ" hash="svX7Pw">God would be very unjust if he were to turn Lucifer loose to tempt man without giving him help to overcome. God will not permit Satan to have power over you, to tempt you beyond the strength He will give you if you will <span class="emphasis">seek </span>and accept His help.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p21" guid="6a858348-a2ab-40ff-9b3d-77f8396a87b8" pid="RpZAPnzCgEO1hcZz7_9YTg" hash="hRlOzw">In the beginning, an angel of the Lord taught Adam and Eve. He instructed them in all things so they would know the will of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p22" guid="dc5cb886-a04e-4519-bb6c-2da1b4f756dc" pid="PFf20y2qxEKGSwGufkiA_A" hash="GqcVfg">I think it is the same today. We must study the scriptures, learn what God’s plan is for us. We must learn the consequences of obedience and disobedience. He has provided prophets and teachers in each dispensation to teach us God’s will concerning us. He has provided us with scriptures—the Bible, the Book of Mormon, and modern-day revelations. He has restored the gospel with the fulness of the priesthood. He has given us the Holy Ghost to reveal to us the will of the Father and the Son and to enlighten us in all truth. He has given us temples and the keys to officiate in the ordinances thereof.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p23" guid="443b46ce-77ee-4d0c-8073-5d7ead71c8e6" pid="Ge09uOKNZ06Ae5HcC_xOwg" hash="8zAptQ">The Prophet Joseph Smith has said: “God shall give unto you knowledge by his Holy Spirit, yea, by the unspeakable gift of the Holy Ghost, that has not been revealed since the world was until now;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p24" guid="757fff04-e8dc-45cf-8361-32eef42ca23b" pid="QJxNdvJ8DkyTnLX_3OZvnQ" hash="nWzxFA">“Which our forefathers have awaited with anxious expectation to be revealed in the last times, which their minds were pointed to by the angels, as held in reserve for the fulness of their glory.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.26-27" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:26–27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p25" guid="fc3e7ad4-f83c-42d3-98b5-8dd770d31559" pid="_nCeKuOm_U-1BhI9aMoczQ" hash="czPP8A">This means that even our forefathers came ahead of us for our benefit, with a promise we would render a service to them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p26" guid="feaf01f4-2a9e-4a66-a69b-854825e69897" pid="_GqwCgWtF0i0JMadiEOtug" hash="mzVV4g">Yes, the Lord will help us, if we do our part. We must do something more than just resist Satan. We must render service to our fellowmen. Are you doing your part?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p27" guid="b5ea0a62-e005-4ad6-ac9b-4d5b8eec7f09" pid="FdQyr1qqv0CjzT-2I1VW6A" hash="I_1Yhg">God has said: “For behold, this is my work and my glory—to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p28" guid="14990aaa-9370-4306-87bf-0559f7399243" pid="y8PaNfaWh0yB52Ev7nxOvg" hash="QTqClA">Remember that this world was created and all the development and the progress on this earth from Adam till now have been primarily for <span class="emphasis">you </span>as much as anyone else.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p29" guid="381b5664-5c30-4719-8df9-4692084b846a" pid="WuUvAibW20eMN2V1ijyNJw" hash="LavQcw">Christ came to atone for <span class="emphasis">you.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p30" guid="d2df234e-047f-49c1-8130-1349ebfef4b4" pid="20wJVykqSEKdt0JORcK4SA" hash="Xyppwg">The gospel was restored for <span class="emphasis">you.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p31" guid="b89ede07-d334-4ec0-bff1-2dcee76044bd" pid="QQPT5wxgT0acuKVAXVBudg" hash="3VNOCQ">The Lord will answer <span class="emphasis">your </span>prayers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p32" guid="5c7e2d1e-20dc-42b0-b340-0b8f1627d30d" pid="4RAlqUxnEUaHK0GzdtlUvQ" hash="sFuMUQ">God is mindful of <span class="emphasis">you, </span>for<span class="emphasis"> you </span>are a son or daughter of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p33" guid="b0c9d896-987b-4a29-93ec-45bc5b77d54a" pid="DmUwI8LuSkOQ3WNkoX6t-w" hash="UOFubg">It is true—each has a different life to live and a different task to fill. Some tasks may be more important than others, but you—a son or daughter of God—are just as important to God as anyone else.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p34" guid="e0247129-e2b5-483c-b0f6-f93654c3d538" pid="zuCsqX0YVE6_9kaI0lxPRQ" hash="1qZOaw">I think the song written by William Clayton is as important for our encouragement today as it was to the pioneers.</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.f2" guid="a2c6d13e-cd5c-44fe-a31b-61e50a220997">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="WtsQonYNF0q-di37aEM7sQ" hash="p9SxMQ">
            <span class="emphasis">“Come, come, ye Saints, no toil nor labor fear;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="H5A2-k-rxEmKlSMKxi3tKw" hash="ioFHlw">
            <span class="emphasis">But with joy wend your way.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="f0X5axYi1EWdEAM0mQLk7Q" hash="Ghl6-w">
            <span class="emphasis">Though hard to you this journey may appear,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="LxFFHgUN30-KLY_MqzSF-g" hash="pXJeuA">
            <span class="emphasis">Grace shall be as your day.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="FIMiSCt7nkGv4e-21VI0lQ" hash="B3uZQw">
            <span class="emphasis">’Tis better far for us to strive</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="qiGwqH65Vk6gL8CeCVk-8A" hash="iZaZfg">
            <span class="emphasis">Our useless cares from us to drive;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="syTbzR9Q7kucoY-OwE3Kkg" hash="6rH7eA">
            <span class="emphasis">Do this, and joy your hearts will swell—</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="CIGUvpQC9EigaVy3BMJxGA" hash="90Zxjg">
            <span class="emphasis">All is well! All is well!</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="fJcSQJydN0qwW6rOLzpaNw" hash="KZwM_g">
            <span class="emphasis">“Why should we mourn or think our lot is hard?</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="46Oc0QXYx0W-NeXTgOW7HQ" hash="f7FYcg">
            <span class="emphasis">’Tis not so, all is right.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="_Y6pwPr4uk6hO85nVy8olg" hash="iE_BAQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Why should we think to earn a great reward,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="XlhRojZsj06jytUR4_BbTA" hash="u8syKg">
            <span class="emphasis">If we now shun the fight?</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="RU44mlSru0CxcPzXws7ISQ" hash="XclLkw">
            <span class="emphasis">Gird up your loins; fresh courage take;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="-416RGNZbkqQU2KPmbYy6w" hash="ZpvB6A">
            <span class="emphasis">Our God will never us forsake;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="ylMBphLZp0m_b-Uaoqs1Hw" hash="by86gg">
            <span class="emphasis">And soon we’ll have this tale to tell—</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="fghexJ3pSkmYSo3wnK0oqA" hash="90Zxjg1">
            <span class="emphasis">All is well! All is well!”</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <p class="citationInfo" pid="ntrwp42300S_jvPv7e0o3w" hash="phep-Q">
            <span class="emphasis">—LDS Hymns, </span>no. 13.</p>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us.p35" guid="15790aec-b3d5-44b7-be55-bfa09c030142" pid="Tk6gxjUPtUG27wD_vbqcRA" hash="GztUJw">May the Lord bless each one of you to accomplish your goal in life, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1973/10/opposition-in-order-to-strengthen-us</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1973-general-conference/1973-10-4040-elder-eldred-g-smith-64k-eng.mp3" length="4577320" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1973 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Days in the Tomb</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Last spring my wife and I had the wonderful privilege of visiting the Holy Land. On the last day of our stay in Jerusalem, we left the hotel early in the morning and walked to the Garden Tomb. To our great delight, we were alone in the garden. A feel</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03044_000_035" doc-version="2" hash="jaJLOw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="bksfwaoseUWXqrJghAD0QA" hash="BsQmdQ">Three Days in the Tomb</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="mQx5XSHNAUyC791wkI3bew" hash="f2lL9w">Eldred G. Smith</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p1" pid="P02M4wuWr0m1I0X9Rb9Qtg" hash="J7T72A">Last spring my wife and I had the wonderful privilege of visiting the Holy Land. On the last day of our stay in Jerusalem, we left the hotel early in the morning and walked to the Garden Tomb. To our great delight, we were alone in the garden. A feeling of awesome reverence filled our hearts. We gazed at the hill Golgotha, the place of the skull. We could imagine the three crosses there and the sign “This is Jesus—the King of the Jews” over the agonized figure of Christ. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/27.37" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 27:37</a>.) The thought comes, “Are we worth all his suffering for us?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p2" pid="7e1zDS0D50GPS7_H1UYLmw" hash="GXCNrA">Then we turned to the tomb—historically the property of Joseph of Arimathaea. Here Joseph and Nicodemus placed him, assisted by the women. His disciples had left him. The stone was rolled to cover the door, and everyone departed—all but Mary Magdalene and the other Mary. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/27.60-61" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 27:60–61</a>.) They sat huddled next to the sepulcher. Then a watch was placed at the tomb.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p3" pid="KOAL7G-EH0it0MhGospV2A" hash="a1LqKw">We are told there was great destruction in Jerusalem; the veil of the temple was “rent in twain.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/27.51" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 27:51</a>.) The destruction was much greater, however, on this continent. There were great convulsions of the earth. In three hours cities were destroyed, some buried, some burnt. Mountains appeared where cities had been. There was storm, then tempest, and a great dense darkness covered the entire land. At the conclusion of three hours of destruction, yet during the darkness, which lasted three days, a voice, only a voice, came to them. The voice identified itself as that of Jesus Christ, saying:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p4" pid="qRY5oTmxFUiArCJJmNw9WQ" hash="FRe4oA">“Behold, I am Jesus Christ the Son of God. I created the heavens and the earth, and all things that in them are. I was with the Father from the beginning. I am in the Father, and the Father in me; and in me hath the Father glorified his name.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p5" pid="RP07mrrBKkuDAcdXzY1b_Q" hash="bG8tUQ">“I came unto my own, and my own received me not. And the scriptures concerning my coming are fulfilled.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/9.15-16" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 9:15–16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p6" pid="SwrhcdKSTUSk5M_sWDnwPQ" hash="wf2ZRA">He told them the destruction had been because of their wickedness, and that only the more righteous had been spared. Possibly preparing them for his visit after his resurrection, he told them to repent and he would receive them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p7" pid="WKPefnQ2oUaPZDuoBC_gWA" hash="e0XwvA">The voice told them that the Law of Moses had been fulfilled by him. “And ye shall offer up unto me no more the shedding of blood; yea, your sacrifices and your burnt offerings shall be done away, for I will accept none of your sacrifices and your burnt offerings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p8" pid="LjcGwxk85E-yVItX-5XOsg" hash="jSAlNg">“And ye shall offer for a sacrifice unto me a broken heart and a contrite spirit. …” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/9.19-20" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 9:19–20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p9" pid="NgSf6EQJ6kapRhe5hcr1fw" hash="5f-WeA">On two separate occasions during his ministry he had said, “… I will have mercy, and not sacrifice. …” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/9.13" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 9:13</a> and <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/12.7" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 12:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p10" pid="zH5gG8hqq0u7hw0sooVh2A" hash="UJyVeA">Another main activity, while his body lay in the tomb, was to visit the spirits of those who had died. He said on one occasion, “Verily, verily, I say unto you, The hour is coming, and now is, when the dead shall hear the voice of the Son of God: and they that hear shall live.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.25" class="scriptureRef">John 5:25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p11" pid="C4V39Aw98EiOCe2DaOdeCQ" hash="m29i2Q">While on the cross, to the condemned, believing thief, he said, “… Verily I say unto thee, To day shalt thou be with me in paradise.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/23.43" class="scriptureRef">Luke 23:43</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p12" pid="oGZO4q9nI0qIeI3ler-tNQ" hash="meB40g">Peter tells us, “For Christ also hath once suffered for sins, the just for the unjust, that he might bring us to God, being put to death in the flesh, but quickened by the Spirit:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p13" pid="lvzhkGtKEEmQ_iK39iLd2Q" hash="VV7scg">“By which also he went and preached unto the spirits in prison;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p14" pid="w02B5GrxEkaqP3d2Q9u1yg" hash="UTu-0w">“Which sometime were disobedient, when once the long-suffering of God waited in the days of Noah, while the ark was a preparing, wherein few, that is, eight souls were saved by water.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-pet/3.18-20" class="scriptureRef">1 Pet. 3:18–20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p15" pid="lRL0MzFig0GSOnsLMW60mA" hash="r2nHow">This is a great principle of the gospel. This gives all mankind an opportunity to hear and receive the gospel, and to make further progress after death.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p16" pid="gGCsbrCUMEyIIWvfDNDTPA" hash="n8ErLQ">Peter also tells us that, “for this cause was the gospel preached also to them that are dead, that they might be judged according to men in the flesh, but live according to God in the spirit.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-pet/4.6" class="scriptureRef">1 Pet. 4:6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p17" pid="ELwKHLV7mUm1_Au33X7cPg" hash="Z_UovQ">So two great and marvelous things transpired while the body of Christ lay in the tomb. One, his voice was heard by the people on this continent preaching to them, declaring that sacrifices are no longer accepted. Remember, he was not yet resurrected. He returned after his resurrection and showed himself and taught the people. Two, he preached to the spirits in prison.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p18" pid="rFePMRMJ9EyULGBftxYTHw" hash="Py1t2g">On the third day, an angel came and rolled away the stone that closed the tomb. While walking in the garden that morning, my wife and I could easily visualize the stone that was placed there. The entrance to the tomb was cut into a perpendicular face of the hill. There was a small door, in front of which was a trough in which the stone would fit to be rolled into position to close or cover the door.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p19" pid="uqy2m6Z7O0CJ26HYmMVVGg" hash="JvsWRw">We remembered how Mary Magdalene and the other women had come early in the morning of the first day of the week with spices to prepare the body and found the stone rolled away. As they looked in, an angel told them He had risen. He told them to go to the disciples and tell them He had risen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p20" pid="PBuLB9REnk2z-7oi-yrnmg" hash="0B9Ovw">Mary found and told Peter and John. They came running. John, the younger, arrived first, looked into the tomb, but did not enter until after Peter had entered. The body was gone, but the linens were there, neatly folded. John and Peter then returned to their home. “For as yet they knew not the scripture, that he must rise again from the dead.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/20.9" class="scriptureRef">John 20:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p21" pid="cbYH9vBqvEiblgXkC0CWvw" hash="FJjA7g">“But Mary stood without at the sepulchre weeping: and as she wept, she stooped down, and looked into the sepulchre,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p22" pid="v2e-EFZBdUStyTvTqRPFrw" hash="Iuj1PA">“And seeth two angels in white sitting, the one at the head, and the other at the feet, where the body of Jesus had lain.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p23" pid="KwRUrDvb906mKPylYzZspg" hash="5h_DuQ">“And they say unto her, Woman, why weepest thou? She saith unto them, Because they have taken away my Lord, and I know not where they have laid him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p24" pid="9gJHtVoY40uDPEXsH3xzzQ" hash="Znx3Uw">“And when she had thus said, she turned herself back, and saw Jesus standing, and knew not that it was Jesus.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p25" pid="9LhjOTpbDk-qtR_dOnGNVA" hash="yEve8A">“Jesus saith unto her, Woman, why weepest thou? whom seekest thou? She, supposing him to be the gardener, saith unto him, Sir, if thou have borne him hence, tell me where thou hast laid him, and I will take him away.” In a voice so familiar to her she could not mistake it, “Jesus saith unto her, Mary. She turned herself, and saith unto him, Rabboni; which is to say, Master.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p26" pid="z2nDV1Z-9E-KgZLPH2uCZw" hash="F-A_3Q">“Jesus saith unto her, Touch me not; for I am not yet ascended to my Father: but go to my brethren, and say unto them, I ascend unto my Father, and your Father; and to my God, and your God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/20.11-17" class="scriptureRef">John 20:11–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p27" pid="icMPOymAwkCURC31pUwbZQ" hash="p844XA">The other women who had come to the sepulcher had been told by the angel to go tell the disciples that He had risen. Jesus met them on their way, “saying, All hail. And they came and held him by the feet, and worshipped him.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/28.9" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 28:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p28" pid="bG8vVIEOUUi_ijIO8E71GQ" hash="SlmY5g">They, too, were instructed to go tell his brethren.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p29" pid="96jFVc4h0kianiEJHO5ePQ" hash="r09cZw">He appeared to all the disciples except Thomas and Judas, who had hanged himself. Later he appeared to all the disciples including Thomas.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p30" pid="-d8Nooe2mEKab2z8J3C39w" hash="hYQJAw">“Jesus saith unto him, Thomas, because thou hast seen me, thou hast believed: blessed are they that have not seen, and yet have believed.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/20.29" class="scriptureRef">John 20:29</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p31" pid="SHUJ-FRR2UOxnoyoi9ez_w" hash="s8JeAg">He not only appeared to his disciples on several occasions and to 500 in Galilee, he also appeared to those on <span class="emphasis">this</span> continent. The Book of Mormon gives us this account.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p32" pid="KqwcBr7Gl0mtQIjFn4pXYw" hash="NFrBIw">As we wandered in the garden, Jeanne and I were alone. We walked into the tomb. There we witnessed a spirit of peace, as he had said, “Peace I leave with you, my peace I give unto you: not as the world giveth, give I unto you. Let not your heart be troubled, neither let it be afraid.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.27" class="scriptureRef">John 14:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p33" pid="WySvfPXh5ECkMM1O1Sns1A" hash="UOYspg">We received a witness there, and then, as he said to Martha, “… I am the resurrection, and the life: he that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/11.25" class="scriptureRef">John 11:25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p34" pid="j6GPK1QE80C9Irq0vgqR2w" hash="DaQXDw">Through his resurrection, eternal progress for all mankind has been made possible. He opened the way that we may go on and on and on forever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p35" pid="HDdzCmocuk-QzCq60lwOTQ" hash="sNd0Iw">I had the same feeling come over me when I first visited the Sacred Grove in western New York. As I walked into that grove early one morning all alone, the witness came to me that truly the Father and the Son did appear to the boy Joseph Smith just as Christ had appeared to Mary in the garden.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p36" pid="yjbY9RRcVUWP-j6THsQ1Kw" hash="UqPkZA">Truly he lives and has again established his kingdom upon the earth to prepare for his coming in glory to reign upon the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb.p37" pid="sUSHHybW7Ee4TY97gvoqrg" hash="ouHgpg">May God give us knowledge and understanding to know his will and give us the desire and strength to abide by his teachings, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/04/three-days-in-the-tomb</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1974-general-conference/1974-04-6040-elder-eldred-g-smith-64k-eng.mp3" length="5214934" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 1974 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Not Procrastinate!</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate?lang=eng</link>
      <description>A young man just under 18 years of age was visited by a heavenly messenger who stated that he was sent from the presence of God. This messenger, Moroni, was the last prophet in the Book of Mormon. The young man was Joseph Smith.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03050_000_010" doc-version="2" hash="VNOoGw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="RQhIb4uF00egBWnbKmXMrw" hash="HXiBRg">Do Not Procrastinate!</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="xag8S5pZ5Eeqhy1kl8qjRQ" hash="f2lL9w">Eldred G. Smith</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3104.jpg" alt="Elder Eldred G. Smith" pid="sXM9YWRLNU2mMkYAntxenQ" hash="Bi433w" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p1" pid="OoalLemPqk2Z3WlN7L8Qvg" hash="VDWIjw">A young man just under 18 years of age was visited by a heavenly messenger who stated that he was sent from the presence of God. This messenger, Moroni, was the last prophet in the Book of Mormon. The young man was Joseph Smith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p2" pid="KDR1__VLy0yLmlfRdXlj5g" hash="WKaSBA">Moroni quoted many passages of scripture, most of which declared that the time had come to prepare the way for the coming of Jesus Christ in his glory. He quoted Malachi: “Behold, I will send my messenger, and he shall prepare the way before me: and the Lord, whom ye seek, shall suddenly come to his temple, even the messenger of the covenant, whom ye delight in: behold, he shall come, saith the Lord of hosts.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/3.1" class="scriptureRef">Mal. 3:1</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p3" pid="ybAQRt-G0k2pAaVDJiUDIg" hash="bk2GOw">This emphasizes the fact that when the Lord comes again, he will come “to his temple,” which means there must be a temple on earth for him to come to.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p4" pid="1XvgffHBrk2ilzFzXHuBow" hash="7AWcVw">Moroni also quoted the fifth and sixth verses of chapter 4, which are slightly different from the Bible:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p5" pid="yE5Wx8Q6VU2uFQzNw-nEkw" hash="ra8qJA">“Behold, I will reveal unto you the Priesthood, by the hand of Elijah the prophet, before the coming of the great and dreadful day of the Lord. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p6" pid="sX5pmaYS5k-2nFlpO-P-Jg" hash="1FqwqA">“… and he shall plant in the hearts of the children the promises made to the fathers, and the hearts of the children shall turn to their fathers. If it were not so, the whole earth would be utterly wasted at his coming.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.38-39" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:38–39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p7" pid="B_B61PSZ_0alaqWflwPLvw" hash="pGcj0A">It seems very significant to me that, among the <span class="emphasis">first</span> instructions to the Prophet in the process of the restoration of the gospel, this work, which has to do with temples and the ordinances performed therein, was given. This must be very fundamental to the essentials of the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p8" pid="frz5__Ma9UqCi-IDrVxNFg" hash="bAgdtQ">To fulfill the requirements in this message, there must be a temple. Elijah must come with the authority of the priesthood, and there must be living members of the Church gathering the records of their ancestors and getting the work done to fulfill the promise made to them that their sealings would also be done.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p9" pid="FAt7jVfzBUi4febA1mTdxQ" hash="2j4BNQ">God himself established the first family—Adam and Eve. The family is not an institution developed by man to be outgrown and cast aside in the course of human progress. All that is nearest and dearest in our lives is associated with our families. Love has its center here, and where love is, there we find happiness also. Truly it is not good for man to be alone. The Lord in his wisdom has provided a way for man to be happy on this earth and to carry that joy on through all eternity. The greatest joy and happiness come through the family unit. It has been so through all mortality, so why will it not be so in the next life?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p10" pid="9MNUbijJ5EuWdD3kQqYQ1w" hash="ErESow">This family unit is so important that the Lord has made it known to us that by the time of the end of the Millennium all of Adam’s posterity who accept the gospel must be sealed together as one family by the power of the priesthood, which is the power to seal on earth and it shall be sealed in heaven, and to bind on earth and it shall be bound in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p11" pid="AJ_-KHps4UWPO8LZ7cCD4A" hash="yLvoVw">Every person who comes on this earth must have an opportunity to receive all the blessings of these sealings, if he will accept, sometime before the end of the Millennium. There could not be a just God if it were otherwise.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p12" pid="JwX-xtZ5I0e2xtsXl2ommg" hash="DldEwg">These sealing blessings are obtained first through the ordinance of baptism into the church of Jesus Christ. Then the wife is sealed to her husband for time and all eternity, and those children who are not born under the marriage covenant must be sealed to their parents, that they may receive all the blessings as though they were born under the new and everlasting covenant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p13" pid="JOHqKFIDYEO9n-x5PfQ-2Q" hash="Yg4xzQ">Those who have died without this law may have the privilege of receiving these blessings by proxy. <span class="emphasis">That</span> is where <span class="emphasis">our</span> responsibility comes in. We must first teach the gospel to the living. Then we must gather the records of those of our families who died without this law and get this great and important work done for them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p14" pid="JPVV56gOm0m8QwttX7qcYw" hash="3xtbCg">The promise was given to our forefathers that when the gospel is restored in the last days, “the hearts of the children shall turn to their fathers.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/2.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 2:2</a>.) This means we must fulfill the promise to our ancestors to do the ordinance work for them. If we do not, then our own salvation may be in jeopardy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p15" pid="sFENE48p6kCs6wH9XSY7rQ" hash="JcRfHA">Not only the ordinance of baptism, but also the sealing of families together as an eternal unit must be done on the earth. Hence, we must perform these ordinances ourselves first, then by proxy for our ancestors who have passed on to the spirit world. These most sacred ordinances must be performed in a holy temple erected and dedicated to the Lord for this very purpose.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p16" pid="Rg73iMIgQkyEG9TEYIPO5g" hash="t8vJhQ">In modern revelation the Lord commanded the Prophet Joseph Smith to “build a house to my name, for the Most High to dwell therein.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p17" pid="9pFQdtZVjkm9Iz5VPnOsUw" hash="8P2Ghw">“For there is not a place found on earth that he may come to and restore again that which was lost unto you, or which he hath taken away, even the fulness of the priesthood.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/124.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 124: 27–28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p18" pid="vIo-4FtQ_0Sy01nJ3ZRBfA" hash="aFtIlg">These temples are built for a special and most important purpose—where the living may receive their most holy ordinances, where families may be sealed together for all eternity. The family unit is the only eternal organization. The temples are beautiful buildings, and rightly should be, but are not just monuments for show alone. They are the only way whereby all the righteous, living and dead, can have the blessings of exaltation. The living come first. Then after they have performed these holy sealings, they should turn to their fathers and vicariously open the way for their ancestors to receive these same blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p19" pid="zjy3cb7d40KidaTCPb_Vbg" hash="E8y8Qg">For this purpose family research must be done. Many choice spirits have been held in reserve to come to earth at this time so they could accept the gospel and do the temple work for their ancestors. Over and over again, I find among converts husband or wife, or husband and wife, who are the only ones in the family who are members of the Church. In most cases they, or someone in their family, have a good record of their family genealogy. Some eagerly send these records to the temple for the work to be done. Many, however, have many names in their possession which are not being sent in. We must not delay! The time is getting shorter all the time. With more temples being built, more work can be done. With each new temple, approximately 3,000 more names each day can be done. Do not hold these records. Fill out the regular forms and send them in to the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p20" pid="cFkLD9Eu_Ua3osdZ_cLDqg" hash="NzvXkA">Even if the Lord has inspired people to preserve these records over the centuries, if the devil can persuade us to procrastinate and not get the temple work done, he will succeed in frustrating the Lord’s work. The story is told that Satan called a council of his agents and asked how they would combat the forces of righteousness. One said, “I’ll go and tell them it isn’t true.” Satan said, “No, that wouldn’t do.” The second said, “I’ll tell them it’s only half true.” “No,” Satan said, “that’s not enough.” The third said, “I’ll go and tell them it’s all true, but there is no need to hurry.” “Go,” Satan said. “That will get them every time.” Lucifer cannot win. We must do the Lord’s work for our ancestors or the earth would be “wasted at his coming.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.39" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:39</a>.) It seems that the destiny of this earth depends on whether or not we get this temple work done.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p21" pid="vmzTMScNF0KpCdytEWZf2Q" hash="K3qVzw">The gospel has been restored in these the last days never to be taken from the earth again, to bring the blessings of salvation and exaltation to all God’s children who prove their worthiness through their faithfulness. The purpose of this earth and our life here is to give each and every one of Adam’s posterity the opportunity to end this life as a family unit for all eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate.p22" pid="vVGO2i8EhUmD7wKkiGruPQ" hash="fJmwXA">I testify that this is the gospel of Jesus Christ, restored in these the latter days with all the authority and power of his priesthood to bring about the eternity of the family unit for each of us, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/10/do-not-procrastinate</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1974-general-conference/1974-10-2030-elder-eldred-g-smith-64k-eng.mp3" length="4846438" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 1974 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Family Research</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/10/family-research?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In the very beginning, God placed Adam on the earth and gave him dominion over the fish and the fowl and the cattle and over all the earth. Now this would seem like an exalted position for some people today, but even though Adam had dominion over all</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03063_000_044" doc-version="3" hash="Aho_zg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="8sDhZQcBkE-LRnoxZ1adxw" hash="S8f24A">Family Research</h1><p class="authorName" pid="D2B0VBNh4kWLhOpFg5Qzow" hash="f2lL9w">Eldred G. Smith</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3104.jpg" alt="Elder Eldred G. Smith" pid="2numHFXpiUulGVVOxckYKg" hash="Bi433w" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p1" pid="aEwz02Qi0kWMcy6dGFriHg" hash="A1TcTg">In the very beginning, God placed Adam on the earth and gave him dominion over the fish and the fowl and the cattle and over all the earth. Now this would seem like an exalted position for some people today, but even though Adam had dominion over all the earth, God said, “It is not good that the man should be alone,” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/2.18" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 2:18</a>) and he gave unto him the woman, Eve, to be a companion and a helpmeet. Then God gave unto them the first great commandment, to multiply and replenish the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p2" pid="h3zYUMMf9UClN-nGc9rvvw" hash="H3aY_Q">We are not told how long they lived in the Garden of Eden before they partook of the fruit of the tree of the knowledge of good and evil and were cast out of the garden to start their mortal existence. The point I want to make clear is that God himself established the first family unit. Marriage is not an institution developed by man which can be outgrown and cast aside in the course of human progress. All that is nearest and dearest in our lives is associated with our families. Love has its center here, and where love is, there we find happiness also.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p3" pid="yBLS3MQ6u0CympfL24Z68Q" hash="E3DgwQ">Truly it is not good for man to be alone. The Lord in his wisdom has provided a way for man to be happy on this earth, and to continue that joy on through all eternity; the greatest joy and happiness comes through the family unit. It has been so through all mortality. Then why will it not be so in the next life? This family unit is so important that the Lord has made it known to us that all the families of the earth must be sealed together. By the time of the end of the millennium, all of Adam’s posterity who accept the gospel must be sealed together as one family by the power of the priesthood, which is the power to seal on earth, and it shall be sealed in heaven, and to bind on earth, and it shall be bound in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p4" pid="fk0wEIyXFkKvQY-d3mcCmQ" hash="b4P8xg">Every person who comes to the earth must have an opportunity to receive all the blessings of these sealings if he will accept them, sometime before the end of the millennium. There could not be a just God if it were otherwise. These sealing blessings are obtained, first, through the ordinance of baptism into the church of Jesus Christ. Then the wife is to be sealed to the husband for time and all eternity, and those children who are born outside of this wedlock must be sealed to their parents, that they may receive the blessings as though they were born under the new and everlasting covenant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p5" pid="bL4OShjdUkuM2vj0U1rTLQ" hash="aiLFDw">Those who have died without this law may have the privilege of receiving this blessing by proxy. That is where our responsibility comes in. We must first teach the gospel to the living. Then we must gather the records of those of our families who died without the law, that this great and important work can be done for them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p6" pid="WR9ujcTLIUu88Ik2ZOoEdA" hash="NtlRWw">Let us quote the Prophet Joseph Smith in Section 128 of the Doctrine and Covenants:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p7" pid="OU20Ikt4j0KxMsChS_I_uQ" hash="vmM9Qg">“Let me assure you that these are principles in relation to the dead and the living that cannot be lightly passed over, as pertaining to our salvation. For their salvation is necessary and essential to our salvation, as Paul says concerning the fathers—that they without us cannot be made perfect—neither can we without our dead be made perfect.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/128.15" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 128:15</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/11.40" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 11:40</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p8" pid="QAz8qLXj-UunK5anMQFENg" hash="rITgtg">When Paul was teaching the principles of the resurrection to the Corinthians, he clinched his point by stating:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p9" pid="a-OXiMLj30eM4UE7KWkY4Q" hash="Tit1wQ">“Else what shall they do which are baptized for the dead, if the dead rise not at all? why are they then baptized for the dead?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/15.29" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 15:29</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p10" pid="1S4qMUUHxUWAodsFbJfVKA" hash="tjkGZg">This shows that in the days of Paul there was a practice of vicarious baptism for the dead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p11" pid="i2I2uavXp0SHzYOSp6F9fQ" hash="sW05zg">One of the first instructions given to the Prophet Joseph Smith by Moroni was the quotation from Malachi 4:5–6 [<a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/4.5-6" class="scriptureRef">Mal. 4:5–6</a>]. Moroni quoted it thus:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p12" pid="ruOTQL8zxk68xUnMM6F_Gg" hash="Yh471Q">“Behold, I will reveal unto you the Priesthood, by the hand of Elijah the prophet, before the coming of the great and dreadful day of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p13" pid="k1345t_N5kuZ0G07RuswtQ" hash="Iu9Qtg">“And he shall plant in the hearts of the children the promises made to the fathers, and the hearts of the children shall turn to their fathers. If it were not so, the whole earth would be utterly wasted at his coming.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.38-39" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:38–39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p14" pid="c_mYS-_VTkirtQ7MX3z21w" hash="vX4uFw">The Prophet Joseph Smith has said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p15" pid="S_Zmgn68VkmaMbOAVGts3A" hash="SKf5kQ">“The greatest responsibility in this world that God has laid upon us, is to seek after our dead.” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith,</span> p. 356.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p16" pid="9tEPO1cK9kKbFTZLZmM4Fw" hash="G8xziQ">This means that this baptism and sealing work must be done for all of God’s children who will accept it—not just for those who live on the earth now who are members of the Church, but for all of our ancestors and all who have lived on the earth who will accept the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p17" pid="_0ORInuf6karBBpeacH5xw" hash="QcroUw">The Lord is bringing about this great task by first restoring the keys and priesthood authority. This was done in the Kirtland Temple in April 1836, when Elijah restored the sealing keys to Joseph Smith and Oliver Cowdery. Then he has sent special spirits to earth who have been retained to come forth in this choice dispensation—valiant, strong spirits who would accept the gospel. These are now being sent into all parts of the earth. These choice spirits accept the gospel when it is presented to them. Then, from that nucleus, others of their families and friends accept the gospel. They come to the temples of the Lord and perform their own sealings, then vicariously do the sealing for their ancestors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p18" pid="v82b24Rhx02tViARFJAiKw" hash="uESR1w">However, the Lord is doing still more to assist this work. He has sent other choice spirits into the world who have been blessed with special knowledge and training to develop scientific means and equipment to speed up the work and make possible the otherwise impossible task of collecting, sorting, storing, and checking of names to prevent duplication and to organize this work. This is next to miraculous. Everything the Lord can do to make it easier for us is being done. Are you taking advantage of these helps?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p19" pid="KDh1jFMBckWfQJLGKuumIQ" hash="8_jqnw">Do we appreciate these blessings? Many converts would willingly spend great efforts and sums of money to obtain the opportunity of being sealed to their parents and consider it well worth the effort.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p20" pid="DAYtKW_ps0m9Ms4P-zyDKA" hash="zljEOQ">Then we need to gather all the records of our ancestors that we possibly can. I do not mean just a half-hearted attempt. Seek diligently, constantly, and prayerfully. Do not wait for a convenient time—a convenient time may never come. Do not put it off until old age when we are not able to do anything else. We never know what tomorrow will bring, and we must see that the work is done of completing the sealing of each family group. There is no one who can escape the responsibility of this work. We will not be excused because we thought an aunt or some other relative was doing the work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p21" pid="9dLWZLLEkEGg5uO8n8Esuw" hash="OvziFw">One young lady, a genealogist, was asked the question, “What if you find an undesirable character in your family tree, such as a pirate or convict or the like?” She answered, “My responsibility does not concern how he lived, but just that he lived and died. After all, I owe my existence to him, and my only way of paying that debt is to do the baptism and sealing work for him. It will be up to him to accept it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p22" pid="-k9uyRnovUWGTyVF6lp3CQ" hash="lH4d_Q">This is a responsibility for each of us. Not one of us can be made perfect without this work. I doubt if the Lord will accept the excuse that we are so busy with other church work that we cannot spend a part of our time in genealogy. Any part of this we do not do, which we should do, must be done by someone else, for it must be done. If we shirk our responsibilities, how can we expect to receive the blessings?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p23" pid="EfePezTOwEeeGZiY3XxboQ" hash="Yy-peQ">To those scattered around the world, may I say a word of encouragement? Be of good cheer, be diligent, trust in the Lord, and he will help you. You were probably placed where you are to do a special work in gathering records or to fulfill a special missionary assignment. If you will let him, the Lord will give you success in your work and much happiness in so doing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p24" pid="gbdzbxNAyUiqGKaV3-qHaQ" hash="zn3vdA">Many good members of the Church have many records lying on the shelf. They have gathered records but have not yet sent them in to have the temple work done for them. Get those records into the temples. Many may be waiting on the other side for that work to be done. Let’s follow President Kimball’s slogan, “Do It.” I think this could be a good slogan for this conference—“Do It.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-research.p25" pid="RsO53cNY_028Y-y1ImGDYQ" hash="6iLwTg">May His blessings be upon all those who are diligent in this work, that we may prepare the way for his coming, for I testify to you that this is His work, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/10/family-research</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1975-general-conference/1975-10-7050-elder-eldred-g-smith-64k-eng.mp3" length="4987961" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who Is Jesus?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Who is he who is called Jesus the Christ? Do you know him?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03070_000_031" doc-version="2" hash="4hpq8g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="LCDfSqSsykieK4oPFixCXw" hash="wOxyyw">Who Is Jesus?</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="dJ-F8kuPSUyUAzqbPaqdxg" hash="f2lL9w">Eldred G. Smith</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3104.jpg" alt="Elder Eldred G. Smith" pid="6h8GRoF7KkeecJECG2VRiA" hash="Bi433w" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p1" pid="Hh7aDLiqqkWCop1lKKj2kw" hash="sQP-YA">Who is he who is called Jesus the Christ? Do you know him?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p2" pid="Y33GQe65KUChPvm51USxqw" hash="F2VteA">When he was praying to the Father, just prior to his crucifixion, he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p3" pid="ZMogEFRZcUC-z528h2yJQw" hash="vdkAGQ">“And this is life eternal, that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17:3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p4" pid="jM81oJhN5kOPx6qinhbqzA" hash="Qywy4Q">In that council in heaven, the plan and purpose of this earth life was explained to all the spirits, and then “the Lord said: Whom shall I send? And one answered like unto the Son of Man: Here am I, send me. And another answered and said: Here am I, send me. And the Lord said: I will send the first.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.27" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p5" pid="osOlkv8tD0aKvnMt1rXWgg" hash="MdNIVA">He who was selected was Jehovah, the oldest, who had promised that in going he would honor the Father and give him all the glory.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p6" pid="NqZ0tDRNqU-R-spu6tuIpg" hash="t5M8Cg">The Father has declared: “This is my work and my glory—to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p7" pid="GF2WLOCyTk29GQ8Xqx8c5g" hash="MpZefw">Jehovah was, then, under the direction of the Father, the creator of this earth and many other worlds. Moses was shown in vision “many lands; and each land was called earth, and there were inhabitants on the face thereof.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.29" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:29</a>.) God declared to Moses; “By the word of my power, have I created them, which is mine Only Begotten Son, who is full of grace and truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p8" pid="nCofHcRxc0yvHQCJRDNpTA" hash="uRNaLg">“And worlds without number have I created; and I also created them for mine own purpose; and by the Son I created them, which is mine Only Begotten.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.32-33" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:32–33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p9" pid="L2Dt6CH1RUqrH7ztiCcscg" hash="gQsxTA">To get some idea of the magnitude of these creations: President J. Reuben Clark, Jr., said, “Astronomers now yield what they did not formerly yield, that there may have been many, and probably were, many worlds like ours. Some say there were in this galaxy perhaps from its beginning, one million worlds like unto this one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p10" pid="kb-COZpllEWT4plFYbyrFw" hash="Y-ibcQ">“‘Worlds without number have I created,’ through ‘mine Only Begotten Son.’ I repeat, our Lord is not a novice, he is not an amateur; he has been over this course time and time and time again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p11" pid="lq6-DsOZQE-UxWuEnx4IZg" hash="pDcCwQ">“And if you think of this galaxy of ours having within it from the beginning perhaps until now, one million worlds, and multiply that by the number of millions of galaxies, one hundred million galaxies, that surround us, you will then get some view of who this Man we worship is.” (J. Reuben Clark, Jr., <span class="emphasis">Behold the Lamb of God,</span> Deseret Book Company, 1962, pp. 16–17.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p12" pid="3Ak4M4_OU0airvd1z9Sz-g" hash="qabZVA">He was truly no novice, no amateur, in the art or skill of a creator. “Worlds without number” he has created.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p13" pid="rqF3QNegaEeL78KzqID7gw" hash="xgIeEQ">It was he, then, who came to this earth in the meridian of time, born of the virgin Mary—the literal Son of God the Father, “the Only Begotten Son.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p14" pid="MoTZIeUxLE-ktpMd1-gG0A" hash="29H5fw">He declared who he was. Throughout his life on earth, he repeatedly declared that he was the Son of God. At the age of twelve, he was found “in the temple” conversing with the “doctors.” In answer to his mother’s reproof, he said, “Wist ye not that I must be about my Father’s business?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/2.49" class="scriptureRef">Luke 2:49</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p15" pid="Tg3oxGlKkkuqYTLBRgYaSQ" hash="okBuGg">At the baptism of Jesus by John, as also at the transfiguration of Jesus, a voice from heaven declared, “This is my beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/3.17" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 3:17</a>, <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/17.5" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 17:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p16" pid="UGsRYXy67UCteYFEa4dbYQ" hash="TWPuxQ">When Jesus was about to raise Lazarus from the dead, “Martha saith unto him, I know that he shall rise again in the resurrection at the last day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p17" pid="IK3T97exgkuCMRsOmBa9Pg" hash="okWF4Q">“Jesus said unto her, I am the resurrection, and the life: he that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p18" pid="TCJGvJQvX0-oTRHc8RxWIQ" hash="-_WwAA">“And whosoever liveth and believeth in me shall never die. Believest thou this?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p19" pid="2BL-rNlPTkuUKaiqNuF8Rw" hash="GyVi0A">“She saith unto him, Yea, Lord: I believe that thou art the Christ, the Son of God, which should come into the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/11.24-27" class="scriptureRef">John 11:24–27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p20" pid="LFZMHytOg0aPYjjY6x5cmQ" hash="6M7_lQ">On another occasion, when Jesus stopped at Jacob’s well, he asked a Samaritan woman to draw water for him, and, in the conversation that followed, the Samaritan woman said to Jesus, “I know that Messias cometh, which is called Christ: when he is come, he will tell us all things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p21" pid="4yXF9DLLR02-X1iJRF6mYw" hash="JmdMlA">“Jesus saith unto her, I that speak unto thee am he.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/4.25-26" class="scriptureRef">John 4:25–26</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p22" pid="lUUNrWYYxkeqriPKVvx3_w" hash="L6Ja0g">Then again:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p23" pid="6zzt3Ib8tUqaahH1C4FQPw" hash="GODJ8g">“When Jesus came into the coasts of Caesarea Philippi, he asked his disciples, saying, Whom do men say that I the Son of man am?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p24" pid="hvWRL06ASkOBkEoAetJ7bQ" hash="j7ecPg">“And they said, Some say that thou art John the Baptist: some, Elias: and others, Jeremias, or one of the prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p25" pid="oCyJoHzViEuWElTI4_eryA" hash="zYTRdg">“He saith unto them, But whom say ye that I am?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p26" pid="WF8zOoB0ok6_8UGVgOp_fg" hash="3d-4RA">“And Simon Peter answered and said, Thou art the Christ, the Son of the living God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p27" pid="GR_yz3YuhUaweKz9SnPeAA" hash="tNK7fg">“And Jesus answered and said unto him, Blessed art thou, Simon Bar-jona: for flesh and blood hath not revealed it unto thee, but my Father which is in heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/16.13-17" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 16:13–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p28" pid="YJnIQ8J_iUigihbFaPm5lA" hash="k-q8vA">On numerous occasions, he declared that he was the Christ, the Son of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p29" pid="BGHUU1nwkE-1mohVS_-sfQ" hash="G3aF5A">Is it any wonder then that he, the Son of God, the great Creator, had power over the <span class="emphasis">elements</span> of this earth, even to violate the law of gravity by walking on the water?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p30" pid="nGH2fuJB7k-YPtoZtBLfGw" hash="D4kEPQ">I suppose it was quite simple for him, the Creator, when obligated to provide wine at the wedding feast to change the water to wine.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p31" pid="_QYHfD_T9EOKskQEZ4gAnA" hash="P8P3Hg">Nor was it a trick of the imagination when he fed five thousand plus the women and children with a few loaves and fishes, and on another occasion, four thousand plus the women and children. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/14.16-21" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 14:16–21</a>, <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/15.32-38" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 15:32–38</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p32" pid="bepRiFM3S0GEzQWY84gMCA" hash="zrhCGQ">He also showed his power over the elements when at his command to “be still,” the stormy sea was calmed. (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/4.39" class="scriptureRef">Mark 4:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p33" pid="5gh8c7gAr0WVavCE4QGFQg" hash="Js-0XQ">He demonstrated his power over the <span class="emphasis">animal</span> kingdom; on two separate occasions, at his command, a great catch of fish was made when they had had no success before. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/14.16-21" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 14:16–21</a>, <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/15.32-38" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 15:32–38</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p34" pid="ZxR1wiDqk0GCUUwV6DVsnw" hash="l-LVDw">He showed his power over the <span class="emphasis">vegetable</span> kingdom when he cursed the fig tree. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/21.19" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 21:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p35" pid="Rt-xkYYwsUWgDP7hnudgIQ" hash="qA-YSA">On each occasion, he was declared to be the Christ, the literal Son of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p36" pid="1XgEObKBmkW7vh-bd9_h3A" hash="KgrVJw">He healed all manner of illness or disease. At his command, the evil spirits departed, they, too, declaring who he was. He made the blind to see, the lame to walk. Yes, he even controlled life itself, for he restored Lazarus to life, who had been declared dead for four days. There were others, too.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p37" pid="Jiu2c4t2RUaVkFGIXDtPpA" hash="K-r5uw">Yes, “the earth is the Lord’s, and the fulness thereof.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/10.26" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 10:26</a>.) He had dominion over all the kingdoms of the earth—in the earth, on the earth, and in the heaven above the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p38" pid="brQXGvNH0k6MPX5dUOxCAg" hash="OhbZoQ">
        <span class="emphasis">All</span> he did was for others—his was a life of service. There was not one selfish act.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p39" pid="SeyWOjefK0uBsHIqfExJ4w" hash="rV8Xag">Approaching the finish of his mission here, he prayed to the Father: “I have glorified thee on the earth: I have finished the work which thou gavest me to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p40" pid="Lb3k1OxL2UigxWV-7jOQeg" hash="BM3z7Q">“And now, O Father, glorify thou me with thine own self with the glory which I had with thee before the world was.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.4-5" class="scriptureRef">John 17:4–5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p41" pid="7Gd0dfnOI0iUlibKsWbRrA" hash="Q9uD0A">He took upon himself the sins of all who shall repent, and gave his life that all might live. He brought about the resurrection for all. Do you realize that the creation of this earth, and all the work of Jesus and the prophets since the very beginning, was for <span class="emphasis">you</span>—that you might have immortality and eternal life—just as much as for anyone else?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p42" pid="EKCbj4TYU0OO6foYps2HIA" hash="keQO1Q">Finally, in preparation for the restoration of his kingdom on the earth, in these the last days, he said: “Therefore I command you to repent—repent, lest I smite you by the rod of my mouth, and by my wrath, and by my anger, and your sufferings be sore—how sore you know not, how exquisite you know not, yea, how hard to bear you know not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p43" pid="BE8QMV2CrUqvcDJPh-72xA" hash="1zQS0w">“For behold, I, God, have suffered these things for all, that they might not suffer <span class="emphasis">if they would repent;</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p44" pid="gVzWO9889EWwWGAA0kIXvw" hash="lQavKQ">“But if they would <span class="emphasis">not</span> repent they <span class="emphasis">must suffer even as I;</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p45" pid="kkS7zglIB0WNhHBn-yZ-tA" hash="UYmTrQ">“Which suffering caused myself, even God, the greatest of all, to tremble because of pain, and to bleed at every pore, and to suffer both body and spirit—and would that I might not drink the bitter cup, and shrink—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p46" pid="XjVElCzLNEizbV51nVMPyw" hash="fc4IQA">“Nevertheless, glory be to the Father, and I partook and finished my preparations unto the children of men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p47" pid="rnQu3er-NkerlUiLixeQBw" hash="v9MpsQ">“Wherefore, I <span class="emphasis">command</span> you <span class="emphasis">again</span> to <span class="emphasis">repent,</span> lest I humble you with my almighty power.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/19.15-20" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 19:15–20</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p48" pid="mp0-wuYqYE6SCRIlYbku7g" hash="7lK8Fg">Do you so think of him when partaking of the sacrament, and covenant to keep his commandments? To <span class="emphasis">know him is to keep</span> his commandments. Do you know him who was called Jesus?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p49" pid="O35_HLfuqU2l7_sXe4Fuxw" hash="QmYEwQ">Yes, this is he whom we worship. He is the Son of God; the Great Creator. He is our Savior and Redeemer. He is our advocate with the Father. It was he who made possible and brought about the universal resurrection. It was he, with his Father, who appeared to Joseph Smith in the Sacred Grove.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p50" pid="2ySi9KAMfkq6kTXoDJQoeg" hash="9F7YEg">And after a marvelous revelation given to Joseph Smith and Sidney Rigdon, they testified, “And now, after the many testimonies which have been given of him, this is the testimony, last of all, which we give of him: That he lives!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p51" pid="dtRb8lQJ8kaDuqrmDrNuWA" hash="E7qA3w">“For we saw him, even on the right hand of God; and we heard the voice bearing record that he is the Only Begotten of the Father—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p52" pid="Rs7t33grZkq0kFZHH2BMDg" hash="HuUMpw">“That by him, and through him, and of him, the worlds are and were created, and the inhabitants thereof are begotten sons and daughters unto God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.22-24" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:22–24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus.p53" pid="5pMU5iNPyECUGA_5ElKGVA" hash="JiYuuQ">I testify that God lives and that Jesus is the Christ, the Son of God, and that it was under his direction that the gospel of Jesus Christ has been restored in this dispensation for the last time. I so testify to these truths in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/04/who-is-jesus</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1976-general-conference/1976-04-5030-elder-eldred-g-smith-64k-eng.mp3" length="10551345" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1976 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1978/04/decision?lang=eng</link>
      <description>With these young people behind me, I’m tempted to do as Brother Monson did and tell some stories about young people. But thinking of the translators and the time allotted to me, I’ll resist that temptation.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03096_000_016" doc-version="2" hash="EtmP-A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="zySVdJzxsEmmOEcGt6S__Q" hash="xlC-6Q">Decision</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="6eByAL2Qz0-Eb8MuwTIA6A" hash="f2lL9w">Eldred G. Smith</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3104.jpg" alt="Elder Eldred G. Smith" pid="PuxTnZQDp0mVs5FLC8Pr-g" hash="Bi433w" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p1" pid="qOETQQdgMEikP2CJxF6w4A" hash="B80u-Q">With these young people behind me, I’m tempted to do as Brother Monson did and tell some stories about young people. But thinking of the translators and the time allotted to me, I’ll resist that temptation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p2" pid="hAsAKDm2IUK1qwOh2kbVnA" hash="04riMg">I would like to sum up my message today into one word. This one word is: <span class="emphasis">decision.</span> Decision, I would say, is the use of that God-given right of free agency.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p3" pid="DIlgOo2zBUO0h8NO9piWfQ" hash="UQOzzA">Some people want to force their decisions upon others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p4" pid="WX95iLwAUU2Hn0taIY56Og" hash="iyuh1g">Some don’t want to make their own decisions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p5" pid="cg3McwYlBk-54vFoKPRALg" hash="SyVOpA">Some have the gift of making quick and accurate decisions. Like all other gifts, the making of decisions requires practice. The more we do, the easier it gets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p6" pid="QfYLnKZvs0WXvy2VM4kxVQ" hash="V87S_Q">It’s a lot like the city boy who went to work on the farm. He was sorting potatoes when someone asked him how he liked working on the farm. He said, “I like the work all right, but these decisions get me down.” It is said that the character can be measured by what one does in his leisure time. That’s when he alone makes his own decisions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p7" pid="V0VimADGrUW550QDNb0EYA" hash="vEtTVw">One of the important purposes of this life of mortality is to learn how to make decisions. A good leader in business or in church or in the home is one who can make good decisions. Think of the decisions a bishop or stake president must make.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p8" pid="W12wW_WkE0GN3H65MUgTTg" hash="naoHww">The Lord has said: “This is my work and my glory—to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p9" pid="P7HjNDZfiE2zlkVicqLzGg" hash="csuzdg">When the gospel plan was explained to Lorenzo Snow, he put the whole plan in a nice epigram: “As man now is, our God once was; as now God is, so man may be.” (Lorenzo Snow, 11 January 1892, reprinted in <span class="emphasis">Latter-day Prophets Speak,</span> ed. Daniel H. Ludlow, Bookcraft, 1951, p. 72.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p10" pid="yW-Cpk38N0O-8dpM7ZJVbQ" hash="GpSC5g">Then, if man is going to become as God now is, he will have to learn to make decisions of great importance on his own initiative.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p11" pid="G58hIbOmd0OABKywj4RzHQ" hash="-8T_qQ">Many think that any problem will be answered by the Lord for us, either through prayer or a priesthood blessing. Some young people want the Lord to tell them what subjects they should study, which school they should attend, which profession to follow, and which job offer they should take. True, much help may be received through prayer or a blessing, but the final decision is yours.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p12" pid="sOCz4POMTkW3RRQF3dqq4Q" hash="foXR1Q">I have come to believe that the Lord is not so concerned about what we study or what profession we follow as long as it is an honest living. He is concerned about our immortality and eternal life—or exaltation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p13" pid="hB-TdwV6j0uNdXuaKnVeEg" hash="miYx9w">Everyone has inherent talents. From a study of your genealogy, find the talents you have inherited by the things you like to do, and do easily, that some of your ancestors have done. Then become an expert or a specialist in some phase of that field. The Lord will bless your efforts in your studies and in your daily work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p14" pid="sMN64RtzT0ylzJI1NRRkAA" hash="geqbXg">The Lord gave Oliver Cowdery the key to revelation:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p15" pid="S52gzLbF-kaLUwuNzMVEKQ" hash="y4Hf2w">“Behold, I say unto you, that you must study it out in your mind; then you must ask me if it be right, and if it is right I will cause that your bosom shall burn within you; therefore, you shall feel that it is right.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p16" pid="xYJ6mZA9L0uhNuAu1uwhAQ" hash="s64FiQ">“But if it be not right you shall have no such feelings, but you shall have a stupor of thought that shall cause you to forget the thing which is wrong.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/9.8-9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 9:8–9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p17" pid="JmoxK5CkHU-DfF7CZ3l44Q" hash="GZsmKA">This should be our guide in all our major decisions. We are making decisions constantly every day, either mentally or orally. This is what free agency is—the right to make a choice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p18" pid="bfE9TsHVi0CpSQIp6DB9mA" hash="lVMsHA">With the growth of the Church today, we see the wisdom of the revelation given back in 1831 in Jackson County, Missouri:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p19" pid="xO2VulNl1U6EfomcORqWvQ" hash="UtlNTQ">“For behold, it is not meet that I should command in all things; for he that is compelled in all things, the same is a slothful and not a wise servant; wherefore he receiveth no reward.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p20" pid="IeKaNvK7e0euUN5_Mdru1A" hash="UYOeuw">“Verily I say, men should be anxiously engaged in a good cause, and do many things of their own free will, and bring to pass much righteousness;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p21" pid="nB03pwA7tEG8W5gAcJCw5w" hash="H7NxJw">“For <span class="emphasis">the power is in them,</span> wherein they are agents unto <span class="emphasis">themselves.</span> And inasmuch as men do good they shall in nowise lose their reward.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.26-28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:26–28</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p22" pid="B5rd8FdnbEecELDDr0wezw" hash="pyjb8g">Thus we say today as did Moses when he came down off Mt. Sinai: “Who is on the Lord’s side?” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/32.26" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 32:26</a>.) And as did also Joshua cry: “Now therefore fear the Lord, and serve him in sincerity and in truth: … Choose you this day whom ye will serve.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/24.14-15" class="scriptureRef">Josh. 24:14–15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p23" pid="3lD0pJAZEk6ftlufCSOFDQ" hash="8OQVTA">Use your God-given free agency to choose honesty against dishonesty, to serve your fellowmen, and to build up the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p24" pid="L3C6TNcH9EK1vTxwm2CKcQ" hash="xZn8qQ">Decide early in life to go on a mission. Many young men who should go on a mission don’t go because they had not made the decision early enough to plan on a mission. Then other activities seem to them to be more important.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p25" pid="k0ONMrQrH0iwhGhd7dOTgA" hash="Ouj9qw">Decide to teach the gospel all your life, not just for two years. Going on a two-year mission usually just teaches us how to teach the gospel. Then we should spend the rest of our lives teaching the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p26" pid="4gW7eHwcu0qQAcPtYla_CA" hash="TV5EQw">Teach by your own actions. Live a good, clean life. Decide against immorality. Decide against pornography. Decide to live a clean life so you will be worthy to be married for time and eternity in the temple of the Lord. Choose not only to be worthy but decide to marry in the house of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p27" pid="63zYiK2LDkSE8qTATNIWrg" hash="duz1Jg">Choose to live the law of celestial marriage. The command in the marriage ceremony is to multiply and replenish the earth. In the Doctrine and Covenants when the Lord is referring to the blessings of celestial marriage (He is talking about husband-wife relationships), He makes this statement: “And if ye abide in my covenant, and commit no murder whereby to shed innocent blood,” and so forth. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/132.19" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 132:19</a>.) What do you think He’s talking about? Is it possible that He was referring to abortion? Think about it! Is there more innocent life than that of the unborn child? And why is murder referred to when the Lord is talking about marriage? Conception is a contract with God that you will create a body, and He contracts to put the spirit of life within it. Any covenant of the Lord cannot be broken without a penalty.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p28" pid="lvq5m9HFhUuMoq5vRTHGvQ" hash="cbBoEA">Choose to study the scriptures. Learn what the plan of the gospel is. Become a part of it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p29" pid="qoDj4C1dWUGRbDt-b1P1iA" hash="FWe9IA">Choose to keep the commandments of the Lord. Be a part of His kingdom in preparing for His coming.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/decision.p30" pid="8EFa1CJOc06D_Omj0AXMCA" hash="bG9juQ">Seek the guidance of the Lord in making decisions, but use that God-given right of free agency. Then you, too, will know, as I know, that this is His church, the church of Jesus Christ, and I so testify to you in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1978/04/decision</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1978-general-conference/1978-04-2080-elder-eldred-g-smith-64k-eng.mp3" length="3933722" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 1978 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
