<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By ElRay L. Christiansen</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by ElRay L. Christiansen.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/ElRay%20L.%20Christiansen.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by ElRay L. Christiansen.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Be Slow to Anger</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My brothers and sisters, I am in complete harmony with every word that Elder [Marion G.] Romney has just said to us, and with that which was said in the meeting this morning by our prophet leader, and by those who followed him in speaking the truth o</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03006_000_2020" doc-version="2" hash="S4_Hvg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="Z2GkGvTJeUmRWuEhlnJBpQ" hash="kZokNQ">Be Slow to Anger</h1><p class="authorName" guid="6cde9ade-b28b-4ffd-a745-68fef99233aa" pid="WJxyQr75l0KTNgBoEBhhbg" hash="2GhMEg">ElRay L. Christiansen</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="24326119-f1f6-4058-9560-15eb0ae807be">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-32a0.jpg" alt="Elder ElRay L. Christiansen" guid="d2ad86be-3294-457b-999f-41ab1187bd0e" pid="EjFf57g7TUuivw86wdN0Jg" hash="Qo2Pjg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p1" guid="afc92e9a-1577-4925-ab35-935233e9b740" pid="T6CQKT55i0OGdCOcWz53ag" hash="GMEOQg">My brothers and sisters, I am in complete harmony with every word that Elder [Marion G.] Romney has just said to us, and with that which was said in the meeting this morning by our prophet leader, and by those who followed him in speaking the truth of the everlasting gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p2" guid="474a9d1c-f79b-451f-8d03-45754091370c" pid="c2gtxSYfHE-Xjo7Fq3MduA" hash="UdEC6g">I desire now to speak, if I may, for a few minutes of a matter that concerns each and every one of us. This is a simple subject but it is one that bears our watching.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p3" guid="21d78749-a56f-402c-bfa8-21ad0f13d055" pid="Vt0QBxEPDU6E_VCv8A6UIQ" hash="KQ8QRg">When Solomon declared: “He that is slow to anger is better than the mighty; and he that ruleth his spirit than he that taketh a city” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/16.32" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 16:32</a>), he knew that individual spiritual development cannot be realized without self-discipline.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p4" guid="6a9faa60-3db3-4e67-a6f7-76a6fde6fec5" pid="Df2uT2TmU02Mfui-4hpGKQ" hash="NTQinA">Someone has said, “The size of a man may be measured by the size of the things that make him angry.” How true that is! To become upset and infuriated over trivial matters gives evidence of childishness and immaturity in a person.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p5" guid="67ca863a-8ebd-49ab-8262-fa689273225f" pid="EOFUrWJhSEew4ficIx46Xw" hash="BGOCGA">We are constantly exposed to irritations as we mingle with others—and even when we are alone. How we react to these irritations is a reflection of our personalities and temperaments. It would seem reasonable to believe that in order to develop a healthy, pleasing personality and to become useful and an influence for good, one must avoid being easily provoked to anger. Not only would we show, thereby, more maturity, but we would also be able to resolve disturbing situations more intelligently, because seldom, if ever, is any good accomplished while persons are in a rage. Anger does not contribute to good. It is a destroyer, not a builder.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p6" guid="762ee348-17d3-4724-b9d0-8e99d5112d4d" pid="Fd5RtHIQBkCbtDJivDfi3w" hash="n-yRqQ">Not only does intemperate anger affect us physically and mentally, in a negative way, but at the same time it also destroys wisdom and sound judgment. When we become upset, reason is suppressed, and anger rushes in. To make decisions while infuriated is as unwise and foolish as it is for a captain to put out to sea in a raging storm. Only injury and wreckage result from wrathful moments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p7" guid="1590411e-3382-405f-9485-23c9f5a12388" pid="oFyCrOcuUkGkFfVuo6FcbQ" hash="Ai11Lw">When anger rules, tempered judgment flees. Actually, the person who is composed has a distinct advantage over one who is angered. Somewhere I read this statement: “When one is in the right, he need not lose his temper; and when he is wrong, he cannot afford to.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p8" guid="ad9eebbc-e6fd-4668-b87c-6b469d7cea2a" pid="B3MwhhDJS0-3OfqoQycRSg" hash="lVEl1Q">Ungoverned anger is seen too often in daily life. President Spencer W. Kimball, in his excellent book <span class="emphasis">The Miracle of Forgiveness, </span>tells us in effect that anger is “a sin of thought” which, if not controlled, may be the forerunner of vicious and violent acts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p9" guid="ee3782c7-55bb-4568-808f-87d9d95d8993" pid="O6I1iych_kOFHJ4AYLHuSg" hash="IyWyjw">Anger against <span class="emphasis">things </span>is senseless indeed!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p10" guid="bac4b383-d89f-4281-9b59-7f2dfcdbee81" pid="NcWNVBdFmUmDIFC0nShV1g" hash="bfP5jA">Because a wrench slips and we bruise our hand is no reason for throwing the wrench halfway across a wheat field. Having a flat tire on a busy downtown street will not be remedied by a tirade of words.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p11" guid="a37b4664-47c2-4678-ac67-fe9cacfdbf23" pid="pMYuXHZybUujQwzqo7u9Og" hash="P1xrDg">Anger against <span class="emphasis">things </span>is bad enough, but when it is directed against people and it flares up with white-hot fury and caustic words, we have the makings of tragedy! For example, let some selfish driver cut in too close in front of another car as he passes, and then let the offended driver fail to reduce his speed and angrily “tailgate,” or do something else “to get even”; then a tragedy is in the making.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p12" guid="1d44993d-757b-41d5-8d14-e0a4f6c60528" pid="aAP5QTC8SEy9zy9XyC76cQ" hash="SrhNiw">Even in our families, situations may arise that could cause irritations. It is then that parents must be calm and exemplary. The man with an uncontrolled temper is like an undisciplined child—he expresses his emotions explosively or by sulking, and disregards the feelings of those about him. In the home, anger should be controlled and love should abound. When, in his most impressionable years, a child experiences ugly situations that result from uncontrolled tempers, when he hears unkind words exchanged between his father and mother, and when he sees contention crowd out an atmosphere of kindness and mutual respect—when these conditions make a child’s environment, what chance has he to become refined and noble? The minds of children are like the sensitive plates of a photographer; they record every incident, good and bad. Our children may forget what is said, but they never forget that which they are made to feel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p13" guid="87395d5f-ac0c-4a28-89f8-6951b5ddd86e" pid="BG_BI6t240mLLS8fg1KjfA" hash="41hPMQ">Someone has said:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.f1" guid="76a39af5-6ab4-4697-9805-b9d3ae77b40d">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="O0LBLN0gkk2gHjWXytFFFw" hash="HFt31g">“Parents may tell</p>
          <p class="line" pid="kbrRRU6c8ESPuZNV69qoCA" hash="td6Gzw">But never teach</p>
          <p class="line" pid="6ESIVKww7k-x9MlHOx-dXw" hash="3CMRbw">Unless they practice</p>
          <p class="line" pid="fvTxklo400is4A7ah_Sl6Q" hash="wyyESw">What they preach.”</p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p14" guid="9e316ffa-34e7-4422-9912-906f0e476b93" pid="4Dnig51v2kC122ycybizzg" hash="mGRFuw">The words of President Brigham Young ring out to us. In regard to this, he said, in appealing to husbands and fathers on behalf of their wives and children: “Cease your anger, and sullenness of temper. … Do not get so angry that you cannot pray. …” (<span class="emphasis">Discourses of Brigham Young </span>[Deseret Book Co., 1941], pp. 268–69.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p15" guid="29a852a3-eff6-4df6-b153-330fedfa2995" pid="xV2h1udnpUCUW6veIHmCqQ" hash="wZ0AxQ">And I think I have read somewhere where he also said, If you don’t feel like praying together, get on your knees and pray until you do feel like it. I believe that is good counsel. (See <span class="emphasis">Discourses, </span>p. 46.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p16" guid="203f802b-4390-4a39-b781-424ee33c0d28" pid="m6GkClMzjEmKn1mrVKCbVQ" hash="bXyQ-w">A few years ago, President David O. McKay made this appeal to fathers and mothers: “Never set an improper example before them [your children]. … Never let them hear a cross word. You should control yourself! He is a weak man who flies into a passion … whatever he may be doing. …” (<span class="emphasis">Improvement Era, </span>December 1964, p. 1082.)</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.f2" guid="22ea83ce-38a9-4493-8576-dac388355f01">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="t3JbS1qufE2eDRdRcQ4s5w" hash="mpDzVQ">“A little explained,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="Fu0I9uK4FU6uCJgFQ-c3xw" hash="uGHBlA">A little endured,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="3HXslsNjGkiI_yG2aUGNgg" hash="JLcumQ">A little passed over,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="MxDtxAQnPkWpeq1UVhiIMQ" hash="87_YjQ">And the quarrel is cured.”</p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p17" guid="321bdbbe-cf69-49b5-a162-c962681cb8aa" pid="LdHlf_U46Um6bqkxylj7aA" hash="8aTVlQ">Frustrations often offer us the means of progression, for by overcoming them harmoniously, we grow and become more Christlike.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p18" guid="18553de6-2211-482e-ac51-b46dcefbbd10" pid="dgxmQEJU1key4IifSdUuEQ" hash="y552Gw">As with most all strong emotions, anger is manifest both in righteousness and in unrighteousness. Righteous anger is an attribute of Deity, whose anger is everlastingly kindled against wickedness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p19" guid="c620809b-c83f-42d5-ad91-0adfc2acd74b" pid="nP1HN-0mC0CgE6zzk22KwQ" hash="ko0cAA">Likewise, an inspired man might be led to speak or act in righteous anger, as did Moses when he broke the tablets upon which the Ten Commandments were written by the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p20" guid="be9d2ac3-477a-4c53-8f83-e787323f4f5c" pid="MKLrUKSq9U6iyxM3I1iv0Q" hash="ESMhhg">But to lose our temper, to explode, to become ugly, punitive, and hateful when faced with frustrations is inexcusable!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p21" guid="50307914-5e9d-457f-8cfe-1dc03796b2d0" pid="Al48rblfykC0KXRjminkTg" hash="9TNAtw">Why is it inexcusable to explode with anger and become vindictive? Simply because the power has been given us to control and to overcome such tendencies. If not curbed, such tendencies soon lose for us the respect and love of others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p22" guid="55f14777-d03b-448f-aec5-9ff94f992781" pid="gvpS0cYSvEae-Vi_YOcvaA" hash="WhvIlA">Jesus set the example in personal conduct regarding anger when, although he had been falsely accused and made the subject of railings and mockery, he stood majestically and completely composed before the perplexed Pontius Pilate. He did not retaliate in anger. Rather, he stood erect, poised, unmoved. His conduct was divine. What an example for all of us!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p23" guid="b8e254ff-e348-44a8-baf3-098def3e4770" pid="SwJ_Hnzj2UuNAAQxpEjpFA" hash="4cYXSA">Listen to these marvelous words of the Savior, the master teacher:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p24" guid="5ae5c75e-9fb2-487c-90cc-9de4c656bf62" pid="g89tFMaPXkuENaeC3MpJIQ" hash="kk94-w">“Ye have heard that it hath been said, Thou shalt love thy neighbour, and hate thine enemy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p25" guid="89a4e94d-fab0-41ff-9093-16d1374f4622" pid="FnkxiVOxOkSzEVPFgAPJRQ" hash="JNpEmw">“But I say unto you, Love your enemies, bless them that curse you, do good to them that hate you, and pray for them which despitefully use you, and persecute you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.43-44" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:43–44</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p26" guid="ad329f71-2caa-4335-8364-7ec3d0edf460" pid="eqS2I9SiwEW_GqTtC47LFQ" hash="wkMl7w">I agree that this is not naturally easy to do, but, my brothers and sisters, we must each conscientiously work at it if we are to achieve our purposes in life.</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.f3" guid="0297dfc5-d269-44a3-8eef-9f1279c6bb85">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="7xivorwpRk6UkWZamppOVw" hash="SHU2CA">“Angry words, oh, let them never</p>
          <p class="line" pid="fENLZ5QomEy8wrx02_Dfuw" hash="0eoIcw">From the tongue unbridled slip;</p>
          <p class="line" pid="ACH7kFXzoEiYTYrwFJ3iuw" hash="_BPq_A">May the heart’s best impulse ever</p>
          <p class="line" pid="Wu3FSpSzokmFkVSdacyrhA" hash="aS-CPw">Check them ere they soil the lip.”</p>
        </div>
        <p class="citationInfo" pid="EVEQejv-LECqmYEsCsULjg" hash="88YPFA">(R. H. Palmer, <span class="emphasis">Deseret Sunday School Songs, </span>1909.)</p>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger.p27" guid="f657c556-fc49-496e-a7da-0318c8383b01" pid="h8TkwJ94w0e2tIOAjGY7cw" hash="VNK1JQ">If we will do this, we will be more greatly blessed as individuals and our homes will reflect the sweet spirit of love and harmony and peace. To this I testify, and pray for the help of the Lord in bringing this about, in the name of the Lord, Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/04/be-slow-to-anger</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1971-general-conference/1971-04-2020-elder-elray-l-christiansen-64k-eng.mp3" length="6121864" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sifting</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting?lang=eng</link>
      <description>At the moment I have one special prayer in my heart and that is, that I might say something that would give assurance and encouragement to those who stand in need of it, which is all of us.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03012_000_2020" doc-version="2" hash="cWi2Tw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="5VsM4YRVZ0mntaQ0p1u-rQ" hash="TXQKCQ">The Sifting</h1><p class="authorName" guid="6cde9ade-b28b-4ffd-a745-68fef99233aa" pid="bOsYbOr5Ukaa25CSc5NPdA" hash="2GhMEg">ElRay L. Christiansen</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="293c5d55-f151-491e-bf0c-c2ca3d732bf7">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-32a0.jpg" alt="Conference photo" guid="1001f5d8-69de-419a-9094-7ea608f88a92" pid="NNiAeREt1k-XL6Rr7FFTaA" hash="Qo2Pjg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p1" guid="35f55f5c-f1d0-4d2b-ac15-0b8268a55e87" pid="oncgTFpH40SaoakuBHVjfw" hash="2U2uQQ">At the moment I have one special prayer in my heart and that is, that I might say something that would give assurance and encouragement to those who stand in need of it, which is all of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p2" guid="6f644db9-d0fc-43c4-afd6-90bf55206944" pid="bW7Xv5MQHkCr601cx5WYVg" hash="jrZsog">We live in a wonderful world! A wonderful era! There are so many choice people, such lovely things, and so much that is desirable. Just to live a normal, useful life is a priceless blessing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p3" guid="450db7b1-3b06-4ac5-85c5-fd7ec0303b1d" pid="FdlzxfSMNk-Wd_cfpw3qAQ" hash="URb5ug">But it is also a time when certain God-given standards and true principles that have long been accepted and respected are being rejected by many. Indeed, it is a day when there is “distress of nations, with perplexity.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/21.25" class="scriptureRef">Luke 21:25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p4" guid="f0bf1e87-da53-4137-bac5-bb93189bfc3a" pid="BIo0hU3rA06us_KJIgLKeg" hash="uFzImg">The Lord speaks of a time when “the love of men shall wax cold, and iniquity shall abound.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/45.27" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 45:27</a>.) Has that time come?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p5" guid="720bbd26-f9f2-42dc-8742-39902946429b" pid="d3s9V_VWhUS3tLF0c3berA" hash="qFq9qg">It is most disturbing to learn of the degradation that exists today. Crime and contention are a daily diet to the reader and the listener of news. Crises and violence the world over are arising one after another, and they come to no satisfactory conclusion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p6" guid="3cd543fe-ef7c-46c2-af7f-2f17f392b5d6" pid="tUk2LQoM5kuLqKIR5bvv-Q" hash="eoWtoQ">Now the scriptures tell us that the devil is “the foundation of all these things; yea, the foundation of murder, and works of darkness …” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/26.22" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 26:22</a>), and that he has “great power, unto the stirring up of the people to do all manner of iniquity, and to the puffing them up with pride, tempting them to seek for power, and authority, and riches, and the vain things of the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/6.15" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 6:15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p7" guid="02bcce72-6839-44a6-9d3a-62e9db2697c2" pid="lFpWHuako0CU-sjlvkssJw" hash="2VyeJA">Such people “seek not the Lord to establish his righteousness, but every man walketh in his own way, and after the image of his own God, whose image is in the likeness of the world. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p8" guid="d61bc062-d9e3-47e6-b7a6-5c1837769914" pid="t0KUw2XCbke2jVpF6xvFEQ" hash="-JPKXw">“And they deny the power of God, the Holy One of Israel; and they say unto the people: Hearken unto us, and hear ye our precept; for behold there is no God today, for the Lord and the Redeemer hath done his work, and he hath given his power unto men.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/28.5" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 28:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p9" guid="02c75632-d851-4865-a78f-70709d02f37b" pid="zZzJjqgNtEGnUxQO30huVA" hash="LHutbw">So spoke the prophet Nephi long ago, looking to our day. However, Dr. James E. Talmage gives needed assurance in these words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p10" guid="7f1a53b1-01fb-4c73-8d21-a237a0711fe2" pid="a9rptxsA20qPPEevUIi9kg" hash="_M2VSw">“Yet in all these malignant doings, … [let us remember that the adversary] can go no farther than the transgressions of the victim may enable him, or the wisdom of God may permit; and at any time he may be checked by the superior power.” (<span class="emphasis">Articles of Faith, </span>p. 63.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p11" guid="0d2b43fa-8ec6-48ae-9087-2665ba018748" pid="ryCCfmOeBkO6laHg1gBunw" hash="pWh27g">Some may ask: “Why, then, does not God, with that superior power, put an end to all evil doings?” The reason is, of course, as has been decreed by God, that “it must needs be, that there is an opposition in all things. …” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.11" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p12" guid="b7d1f2f9-ea74-4722-bc26-650e1cf0c273" pid="2WIfzs2HCEuaO-3IwHR8ow" hash="IEjESw">The reason for such opposition is to enable us to evaluate the right against the wrong. All men have the right to direct the course of their own lives, and the Lord will not deny that right.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p13" guid="ed04b28c-86b1-4055-ba9e-204d17f51c98" pid="5qbEzvjOpUCgCBtD9QsroQ" hash="faWbQQ">The Lord’s purpose in this is to bring to all the opportunity to prepare for the greatest gift of God: eternal life. Man’s progress is to a great degree dependent upon his willingness to remain steadfast and immovable, especially when faced with opposition and adversity. Yet no person will ever be given more opposition than he has the potential to overcome or to endure. Some have a battle with infirmities, some with lust, some with addiction, some with envy or selfishness, some with sorrow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p14" guid="8e073f82-cc7b-469a-a84c-0bb8e2fc208a" pid="_d-CS2ofnEeWN9L6Q4qwqQ" hash="bMIqKA">As I noted that, I jotted down, as I remembered them, the words of that good old song which I like to hear, one verse giving us hope:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.f1" guid="7f5aebb4-fb05-4e22-9eb7-7e7ae1923d5c">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="_w_nP4vhaUOygN5oY8pXTg" hash="F_EMQg">“When through the deep waters I call thee to go,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="dKyRO-fKWkOIxz4h0kuS2Q" hash="RJLy9A">The rivers of sorrow shall not thee o’erflow,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="biYWjfUIbUCVUEHsV5WFjg" hash="V9KBVA">For I will be with thee, thy troubles to bless,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="uvNSxzqfmkub8-NAvgi3Qg" hash="rZtGqQ">And sanctify to thee thy deepest distress.”</p>
        </div>
        <p class="citationInfo" pid="zMF29BkivkSVWlV9JPH8ZQ" hash="zTcnNg">(“How Firm a Foundation,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns, </span>No. 66.)</p>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p15" guid="1fcea0ac-2a2d-4f47-927d-69b3c2bb50f4" pid="r9wVZsy6QEKQo9IrGZe7IA" hash="Eozw_A">All of us have the God-given right to accept the good or to reject it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p16" guid="bc88b673-f374-43f5-a940-4c19b09982dd" pid="obE8lUwqqkO8CUrMpLehAg" hash="KUZsxQ">As Paul said: “… God … will not suffer you to be tempted above that [which] ye are able [to overcome]; but [he] will with the temptation also make a way to escape, that ye may be able to bear it.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/10.13" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 10:13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p17" guid="f693ef94-923c-4edb-9895-e8ab9644b70c" pid="WxawVkmGK0K4_pJSQwJLXA" hash="3udueg">This is a time of sifting, a time when, more than ever in the history of the modern world, the adversary and his followers have shown themselves to be enemies of God. Yet as we heard our prophet and president say this morning, we need not fear the fiery darts of the adversary, because each of us has the power to avoid becoming entangled in sin more definitely than ever before. The time has come for each member of the Church to keep close to the Lord, to be steadfast by sustaining and upholding and following the counsel of his divinely appointed servants, avoiding, as the Book of Mormon says, the vainness, the frailties, and the foolishness of men. We must purify our lives and sanctify our homes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p18" guid="7717c66b-e6a9-4e3a-adbd-87fc1c1c2410" pid="sFqQm5QNokKefyISm_x6sQ" hash="cVo3sA">We must teach our children to be loyal, obedient, honest, to respect the law (and to appreciate protective laws), to have respect for all men, and a love of the Lord and his church. We must live and act with courage, espouse and uphold God-given truth and principles, because to follow the whims, enticements, and the faithless philosophy of men is to risk losing that which is most precious and desirable—peace, liberty, and salvation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p19" guid="c4d0a41c-ee64-43b7-a271-9caff9b75d64" pid="2hLZUPtDZEevCv-4YAJlAQ" hash="2t4CXQ">“Submit yourselves therefore to God. Resist the devil, and he will flee from you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p20" guid="f35ccff8-6edf-4945-8cab-050de112476f" pid="DNlVc8K-zkaeoM8XQiAPqw" hash="ZNIamQ">“Draw nigh unto God, and he will draw nigh unto you. …” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/4.title" class="scriptureRef">James 4: 7–8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p21" guid="47711927-a387-4d1c-9458-207ce29a27ee" pid="puqgX46A206GCCH7QvYL_Q" hash="KujfMQ">The safe thing is still “Come, follow me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p22" guid="f2e793c6-8f27-4a02-9ae0-6c64a3383c1a" pid="4jmTc4CvUkK7OEOK_x1mqQ" hash="LJBb_g">Yes, this is a wonderful era, primarily because in the restored gospel we have the light of truth which, if applied, will bring sweet peace and serenity into the lives of those who do so. The Lord has made the world a crucible for testing us, a place of sifting from which may come the blessings of a joyous life here and a glorious life to come!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p23" guid="544e048b-eaf6-4068-965f-ce230483bb67" pid="VHrUH67aRE-85P_STJxkwQ" hash="fGwQsQ">“Blessed is the man that trusteth in the Lord, and whose hope the Lord is.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/jer/17.7" class="scriptureRef">Jer. 17:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p24" guid="c1766a35-fbfe-4450-8957-0f801d52b9db" pid="CZFOyZITWk67LPySlRJxKg" hash="xOvqAg">He has given us the ingredients for successful living: his gospel as a perfect plan for happiness and success for all who live it, the Church with inspired leaders, and the promptings of the Holy Ghost to guide us and warn us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p25" guid="48f5d13b-83fd-4a61-89b3-92b9b4166b25" pid="TdPr4Qmol0KWRD30_ZDxWA" hash="Z6nTkw">We have all these to a greater extent than ever before in the history of man. Thus, we are living in a time that is unexcelled. Let us make sure that we do progress as we should; that we are “on board the good ship,” so to speak! For that ship, the Church, will never fail.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p26" guid="8f08b383-05f9-4937-b245-58dc1bcaf315" pid="V61DB2ClwkGabFTo7oKVNw" hash="s0JyQA">“The works, and the designs, and the purposes of God cannot be frustrated, neither can they come to naught.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p27" guid="9f550bea-5448-481a-987f-24d630b7f9cf" pid="ekA02UoNdUmdVYGBpH_2jg" hash="s9zkwA">“For God doth not walk in crooked paths, neither doth he turn to the right hand nor to the left, … therefore his paths are straight, and his course is one eternal round.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p28" guid="029c9b69-8c1d-4ad7-b384-6a3a4216e05f" pid="VBUHrr2mpEy59qZKDwrTzg" hash="_3pcqg">“Remember, remember that it is not the work of God that is frustrated, but the work of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/3.1-3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 3:1–3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p29" guid="eeb4239d-d18e-455e-990b-5213c6387cea" pid="zvP2TJK1FESzQxrPHv4NMQ" hash="lYYGOg">I conclude with this promise of King Benjamin:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p30" guid="5c8b0996-ad05-44d8-be14-ee1c68a5b77d" pid="9rENEIi9zEyEZFSjCc_-MA" hash="-MW00w">“And moreover, I would desire that ye should consider on the blessed and happy state of those that keep the commandments of God. For behold, they are blessed in all things, both temporal and spiritual; and if they hold out faithful to the end they are received into heaven, that thereby they may dwell with God in a state of never-ending happiness. O remember, remember that these things are true; for the Lord God hath spoken it.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.41" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2:41</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting.p31" guid="a7a3b8ca-0b65-47d6-a5fb-3de053426c75" pid="54sEuUUmLkyJpG8YxXkXhQ" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/10/the-sifting</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1971-general-conference/1971-10-2020-elder-elray-l-christiansen-64k-eng.mp3" length="11906569" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Successful Parenthood—A Noteworthy Accomplishment</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment?lang=eng</link>
      <description>First of all, my brothers and sisters, let me assure you that as far as ElRay L. Christiansen is concerned, God lives, and he is a compassionate, understanding Father; and his Son, Jesus Christ, came to earth, as the Bible tells us, and offered himse</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03020_000_2040" doc-version="2" hash="RU7-MQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="20G1C-igDkCmMxLqdT8DMA" hash="o6vQdQ">Successful Parenthood—</h1><p class="subtitle" pid="6d1BLxv0_UabpxpqQnQ3pg" hash="e6eDRQ">A Noteworthy Accomplishment</p><p class="authorName" guid="6cde9ade-b28b-4ffd-a745-68fef99233aa" pid="qhNaOrYpCEq9e_uWWIG1aw" hash="2GhMEg">ElRay L. Christiansen</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="0f12f66d-6c53-4845-982d-7588ae37cfb5">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-32a0.jpg" alt="Elder ElRay L. Christiansen" guid="0efa81d2-1028-41c4-91d0-cace9da3f71d" pid="jhwZPHIeJUCMsTL28NxhTg" hash="Qo2Pjg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p1" guid="2d405b93-fd00-4679-8e0c-a28891f31e8a" pid="hMwM7Kf4U0uMt9H3i03ANg" hash="iXCJ9w">First of all, my brothers and sisters, let me assure you that as far as ElRay L. Christiansen is concerned, God lives, and he is a compassionate, understanding Father; and his Son, Jesus Christ, came to earth, as the Bible tells us, and offered himself and actually gave his life that we might be redeemed from the grave and might have eternal life, salvation, which to us means exaltation in the celestial world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p2" guid="0a44e2ae-f033-402b-9e04-c45ecebc66bb" pid="sUAkpmeSQUaTot1nA2tHsA" hash="gKHJOA">I testify that Joseph Smith was selected by God and Jesus Christ to restore the gospel in this day and that Joseph Fielding Smith, whom we appreciate, is one of a succession of modern-day prophets, seers, and revelators.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p3" guid="206486b9-1134-4048-9514-96b90520ea08" pid="Z6i8J9cHP0yabbEpJ9ObDQ" hash="YqyCRw">Now, this is a world in difficulty and trouble, but we shouldn’t merely bemoan the fact. We should, as far as our powers can help us, be anxiously engaged in rectifying it. Just before we sang, I wrote this down: If you and I are to help restore this sick world to its spiritual health, we must begin at the proper place—that is, with ourselves and with our families. This we can do!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p4" guid="9834b79f-c07c-49b0-9281-31338aff9755" pid="wEnQdWF2UE2Osgo2vFxHIw" hash="7P7wwg">One of the most rewarding of all human undertakings is that of making a success of marriage and of rearing children in a manner acceptable to the Lord. It calls for the best in all of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p5" guid="ee164d82-d4ba-48b9-a32a-192c1711c78c" pid="GAHunChcDE-zzQlivboHjw" hash="Q8wb7A">While many, both in and out of the Church, are eminently successful in rearing their families, it is clearly evident that there are fathers and mothers who are divesting themselves of their sacred obligation to counsel their children and to give them the parental warmth and interest that they deserve. Some parents are quite willing to let others tend, and teach, and train their most precious possessions—their children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p6" guid="e03dede2-a581-4fa3-8dbf-122f667b1912" pid="XEn74OKONkyeYlEp4l4ttw" hash="uDzmTw">Did you hear the timely admonition of our president and prophet this morning, pleading for fathers to take their rightful places at the head of their households in righteousness?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p7" guid="472c355e-a67b-4c54-a7ba-3bc9b4da8e6e" pid="1SeyhZEzbkWMGxWL8Y1lDw" hash="bZniyw">An authenticated study shows that two million children in America live in homes where serious trouble exists between parents. Six and a half million children live with only one parent, and another million have been “farmed out” to relatives or friends or institutions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p8" guid="e14e6490-397d-435c-b7b2-f7c99ff3037b" pid="96UKGM8LykCSn5jNmptKTA" hash="T9J0Rg">Some worthy institutions have been developed to help improve the home and family life. But helpful as these agencies may be, I am convinced, and I believe you will agree, that there is not and never will be a better institution for improving the home than the home itself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p9" guid="e7dfabd2-f66e-48c4-a968-2c09aaf0f52f" pid="aME_9h-inEKtyRSIubhq9w" hash="MR8pOQ">Parents cannot, without regrettable consequences, shirk the responsibility of teaching and showing their children through their example the attributes of character that lead them unhesitatingly to appreciate and accept the good, the decent, the beautiful, and help them to develop the desire and the courage to turn from that which is coarse or crude or wrong.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p10" guid="da3743a0-21d2-4530-a762-a9b73e0a682c" pid="K_CPPiEAjECAvOrOvOJ9Vg" hash="Ey_a-Q">To help us develop desirable qualities in our children, we are provided with divinely given programs such as the family home evenings, and for the life of me I cannot understand why every single family in the Church doesn’t grasp the opportunities provided through family home evening—it costs nothing; it isn’t necessary to leave home; and yet it is one of the most effective ways of cementing the unity of our families that has ever come to us, and when consistently used, it has proven to be a marvelous means of making family life secure and meaningful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p11" guid="1f2d40e3-0d6f-441d-9500-640c883e007c" pid="Ez3ppM4Rgkuw0ZSb46lKQg" hash="XpvYzg">Parenthood is a sacred trust. It is an approach to the divine—a God-given privilege that, with its never-ending responsibilities, brings rich and lasting rewards.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p12" guid="e63a6089-25e5-4182-acf0-94f7ed5403bf" pid="BqKrJU1GC0qSZoco8DLuWQ" hash="ZYYRuA">President Joseph F. Smith made this significant statement: “The man, and the woman who are the agents, in the providence of God, to bring living souls into the world, are made before God and the heavens, as responsible for these acts as is God himself responsible for the works of his own hands. …” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Doctrine, </span>p. 342.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p13" guid="36c468b7-6276-4477-a0f4-d5176430f6c0" pid="24mVzPbRF0en9MhkdC3kYA" hash="h9GUXg">A home approved of God is not merely a place where children are born, but where their coming is received with joy and gladness by parents who strive with all their abilities to help their children develop such attributes as—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p14" guid="cc94c5b4-f5c7-4092-bc39-cd1337805481" pid="WtcM3E10bUCdeZGIIkIsMQ" hash="50rVIA">1. Faith in God, along with a desire to be obedient to his commandments,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p15" guid="9e69b7ef-fac6-483c-981f-c0ad18c9c6be" pid="TJs9gRvI1kqR22k5t7uoSA" hash="CDnFjQ">2. Respect for and obedience to the laws of the land,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p16" guid="b5bbdc71-1f60-4b66-bb43-373ffb4040b3" pid="nfrwpKyYh0miNsd1lzng8g" hash="ieVF1g">3. A determination to be truthful and honest, regardless of the circumstances,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p17" guid="64535fd9-7dbb-4073-886a-d06d8583a3fa" pid="xSSIyqh8lEOYR57SNb9WOw" hash="ZhPKcg">4. Unselfishness by teaching (mostly by example), along with courtesy, respect, refinement, and good manners, for surely they are part of our religion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p18" guid="560ff196-b3e9-485d-8440-c4b993b5ebfa" pid="R73xUTqs3U-PpuqSCwbqcw" hash="j5r44A">After all,</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.f1" guid="f711ba63-21ce-4666-a322-8de1daa961df">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="vDFkEEJV50ewDhzlxIWhPg" hash="hJMJbg">“The sermon for a teenage child</p>
          <p class="line" pid="HNcoNV2PsE-_2HE22Y3KuQ" hash="e60tiA">That proves to be most ample</p>
          <p class="line" pid="IquYxLcC70WFb_0a9BJ7kQ" hash="2ZEgfA">Is still the one that parents teach</p>
          <p class="line" pid="O5LTnTCv70qPVZqvsNTL_g" hash="fUBzNQ">By setting an example.”</p>
        </div>
        <p class="citationInfo" pid="uHx6sZSZsEOArAoLo0d4_A" hash="pMKyig">—Hal Chadwick</p>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p19" guid="6d0b5b2b-1215-4018-baec-9b9077f2442c" pid="goqTjh3eKUucs4GLd3zyIQ" hash="MYlr2g">Success in family life calls for parents who take time to enjoy their children; who read with them; who play with them; who let them participate in planning special occasions, seeking to make wholesome family traditions a proud part of family life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p20" guid="96f2cb9b-6bdb-41ed-af88-2daf91b4d2a0" pid="QoTM4xfL6kSGscXPiaNj1g" hash="IzTC4A">The case of a young man, the father of four children, whom we called upon to speak in a stake conference in eastern Utah, emphasizes the desirability of family traditions, special occasions, and warm family relationships.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p21" guid="b5f73edf-5850-4f6e-abd5-b2336c086769" pid="KKF1lW1pjU6Ogd90NxZxBA" hash="1HRjeA">On each anniversary of their marriage, this couple planned something special to do. Now they had looked forward as a family to observing their tenth anniversary. The father arranged his vacation to cover that period of time. But suddenly it became necessary for his wife to enter the hospital for surgery. He and the children felt sorry for her because she was in the hospital. At the same time she was sad, thinking that her husband and the children would be disappointed. But when she read the little note that came with a bouquet of flowers, she felt better, for it read: “Sweetheart, ten years with you have seemed like ten days, but ten days without you have seemed like ten years.” Signed, “Bill.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p22" guid="416bd7c0-4d2b-43e1-a511-c0c54518ce7b" pid="JBXdFJQT7US75YjZrOTHVA" hash="lEtuMQ">Another essential in successful parenthood is for fathers and mothers to avoid disputations. Such situations may seem harmless to the parents, but in the eyes of their children, the two most important people in the world are in conflict, and from their limited perspective, the whole world is in trouble. Situations thus created are an indication of immaturity and weakness on the part of those involved. Someone has said that one of the most important things a father can do for his children is to love and respect their mother.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p23" guid="bbe8dc4f-889b-4d94-921c-059f63792018" pid="78GMup3JFEKpb-gVDvJzDQ" hash="ecSa3Q">I plead with parents to rise above pettiness and to spare their children the inglorious and painful insecurity of having to endure petty disputations and offensive situations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p24" guid="904b710a-d028-45a6-a420-9cab3fdc67c2" pid="YRf1FWCriEm6khQZThTiBA" hash="b6UKiw">It is important also to keep the avenues of communication open. It is wonderful when a father or a mother will sit down with a son or a daughter and discuss a personal problem (and they have their problems, which, if we are wise, we will not minimize). There are pressures, and enticements, and even unjust accusations against which our sons and daughters need to be fortified. It is even more wonderful when, because of the love and closeness that exists, children feel no hesitancy in taking their problems to their parents.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p25" guid="e7d6306f-59ca-4e77-ad8f-a003bb888616" pid="qYiANWwW2kqKRtUXRUKVrw" hash="kwmqSA">In such heart-to-heart talks, parents will help to set objectives for their children, such as:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p26" guid="d034fb8a-19bb-49de-9444-b6e20b7f63c0" pid="mWEgNKr7Tk2Gni8uEE2kEA" hash="FZfyog">1. A desire and determination to live clean, virtuous lives</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p27" guid="89897cf4-9441-4be0-b8d2-71caecfb46de" pid="1fisGAb50k6dUBOXV-ZZow" hash="RMQHGw">2. A desire to associate with those who have their same high standards and ideals</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p28" guid="b9134ea7-a286-4ae2-bc75-16f63934e40d" pid="4CUw8mSLEUGN3QOlU9anog" hash="_7yGKA">3. A determination (for boys) to live so they may receive the priesthood in worthiness</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p29" guid="d639fff5-8d12-431a-a47d-44f56890202b" pid="Ilb7JQweP0CrEFqN3YuhpA" hash="xRgOdA">4. To prepare for and be worthy of being called on missions, perhaps establishing a savings account early in life for this purpose</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p30" guid="7711b04b-6090-4fe9-9439-0ec68e07bbbd" pid="WoAL6hBYhkeI_gb2BbbvOg" hash="_jYQhg">5. A determination to gain an education, to learn a trade or a profession, or to master a skill (and teach them the joy of working)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p31" guid="abe2f98b-2061-4258-b0d7-5886d2ac9b17" pid="lER7NIkMyUSZpEAVgTzoKA" hash="gBNidw">6. To prepare to be worthy and desirous of marriage in the temple, thus doing things the Lord’s way</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p32" guid="87c26ad5-f9cf-4832-b293-57e549836f86" pid="prGU1QIEUEaNL3tq6KKf5g" hash="EfdrSw">7. To prepare to become, in their own right, successful homemakers</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p33" guid="32330e8e-0491-441b-bf4a-6c6e27cfd6f5" pid="cVBYKN3a5U6mQOFb5Iks3g" hash="Te2XhA">We talk a good deal these days about security. My brothers and sisters, there is no security that we can give our children that is more essential than the security they gain in homes where families operate as families should, according to the gospel of Jesus Christ; where families kneel and offer prayers of thanksgiving and gratitude at the beginning and at the close of each day; where keeping the commandments of God is a part of daily life. In this way, they become fortified and enabled to meet the future without frustration and without fear.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p34" guid="3a12d416-215a-4e78-b970-85a1ae324c4e" pid="KVXUj433pUCaa8HGw1k6DA" hash="zo9gog">Historians almost without exception point out that one of the greatest contributing factors in the downfall of nations is the disintegration of the home and family life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p35" guid="d7d92e07-0202-4e8b-b432-38f3e990fca3" pid="wYdnfCPIVEKSpcuBJomREw" hash="vmuGwQ">A complete rebirth of satisfactory family life is needed. It is needed even in the so-called better homes. It must begin with proper love and respect between the husband and the wife and then, by their example, transferred to their children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p36" guid="e68f49bc-21b8-44c9-ada3-7a6059323e50" pid="hpqo6CbsIESQsBgLApH-eA" hash="HcOSVA">No nation can long endure unless the great majority of its families and its homes are made secure through faith in God—an active, living faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p37" guid="78f67bb6-dc61-4890-9820-48d0dac11611" pid="-0YT230v70Kpod3RieyO8g" hash="l8sPnA">In <span class="emphasis">The Scouter’s Minute </span>[YMMIA, 1969] I found these lines:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.f2" guid="0bf6f6b0-6b8a-41af-ab70-7f4d8002b71c">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="1tQaDAWix0qh9pY5E9X-zA" hash="gvHJsA">“So long as there are homes to which men turn at close of day;</p>
          <p class="line" pid="pflowNEOW02R3dOPzYWwZQ" hash="FHhYfw">So long as there are homes where children are, where women stay—</p>
          <p class="line" pid="I__4n5jRY0K5OdCoJ9UNBQ" hash="_cR2gQ">If love and loyalty and faith be found across those sills—</p>
          <p class="line" pid="kLYGvDi8uUe9nuqPfrzFrw" hash="_SrLzg">A stricken nation can recover from its gravest ills.</p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="XpCwQfnRqEOgZAEXtGkN1g" hash="umT-7g">“So long as there are homes where fires burn and there is bread [I think that means homemade bread];</p>
          <p class="line" pid="6AzTJmKHiUGfmO4Rk5vPGA" hash="AhCAWA">So long as there are homes where lamps are lit and prayers are said;</p>
          <p class="line" pid="tqlbkHIwjUKPRxXPyXvDyA" hash="38a3jg">Although a people falter through the dark—and nations grope,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="lmEnLBXQ2UOmIGEigPAc6Q" hash="-iVBOg">With God Himself back of these little homes, we have sure hope.”</p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment.p38" guid="e4d6f0e2-8aa0-483a-9b35-f720ae2b6be7" pid="6vS6crRINUu6MEg8TT9qXw" hash="UevUMg">To this I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, the Lord. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/04/successful-parenthood-a-noteworthy-accomplishment</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1972-general-conference/1972-04-2040-elder-elray-l-christiansen-64k-eng.mp3" length="7000125" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Have Made Covenants with the Lord</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord?lang=eng</link>
      <description>If what I say should need a title, it would be “We Have Made Covenants with the Lord—Let Us Keep Them.”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03027_000_2040" doc-version="2" hash="7gaseg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="zm20ZoujI0CDo4DKEMooLg" hash="rss6yA">We Have Made Covenants with the Lord</h1><p class="authorName" guid="6cde9ade-b28b-4ffd-a745-68fef99233aa" pid="dOD9Q_n8AkiRrDKDzj_r0Q" hash="2GhMEg">ElRay L. Christiansen</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="f7585564-3fb2-4a3d-bd1b-c2f8581076e9">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p1" guid="263a038c-1ca5-417c-bce9-12c16981bfc2" pid="ycNIXaSGeUqNgwoJ_5tiEw" hash="ImMUGQ">If what I say should need a title, it would be “We Have Made Covenants with the Lord—Let Us Keep Them.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p2" guid="ce20eb4f-eab0-4235-993a-bcb327c69086" pid="lfoxdLNYmkWPFsuBujnG6w" hash="ajK6hQ">In that inspiring session this morning, each of us had the privilege of making a covenant with the Lord that we would sustain, uphold, aid, and even defend these great men who have been chosen to lead this church at this time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p3" guid="024c8b88-33f6-4a3d-8f46-108bf31de19c" pid="wMOUtUeqNE2KTWeMyA2GVw" hash="idY7jQ">Making covenants with his people and with individuals has always been one of the principal ways in which the Lord deals with them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p4" guid="52502c50-48bb-4e9d-86f0-56a388c5dd3e" pid="lJlXJGX7V0yhlut5E47jFQ" hash="RJ6AlQ">The scriptures tell us that he made covenants with Adam, with Noah, with Enoch, Melchizedek, Abraham, and others, and that he also made covenants with Israel of old, with the Jaredites, and with the Nephites.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p5" guid="9db3055e-285b-4c74-97b9-37318f405b71" pid="3zdhg65O1U-yUNfPTC4kAg" hash="Oi21tg">Surely the Latter-day Saints are a blessed people, because in a similar way the Lord has made covenants with us individually and collectively.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p6" guid="d3b82f54-eeea-4f43-98be-d10c5b62fc43" pid="oyYZRSYsUUesHbzK7tpCmg" hash="kRhTuQ">A covenant is a binding and solemn agreement entered into by at least two individuals. It requires that all parties involved abide the conditions of the compact in order to make it effective and binding. Most people do not realize that sacred covenants made with earlier prophets and peoples have been restored to earth by a <span class="emphasis">new </span>covenant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p7" guid="1e17f650-d4d7-49d3-be4d-b714d3454a03" pid="X1-pFxBr5UKgaeWIvv6PSA" hash="DJKgBg">The Lord made clear the reason for establishing a new covenant:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p8" guid="9883f7d5-5367-4b4a-adf4-bf8b2da2e8c9" pid="j95rSAaxcUODpaCIeJ8MUg" hash="wqDWBg">“For they have strayed from mine ordinances, and have broken mine everlasting covenant;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p9" guid="fc3c0095-1aa2-4ff0-9d55-03d3d196c368" pid="tqjaFZ1VgUq9cF-LjTZZuQ" hash="sId69Q">“They seek not the Lord to establish his righteousness, but every man walketh in his own way, and after the image of his own God, whose image is in the likeness of the world, and whose substance is that of Babylon, even Babylon the great, which shall fall.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p10" guid="89d92b3e-f0d5-4871-afcf-cbc541a8aaad" pid="KGsHTPNWMkCnTlvxDCco6Q" hash="r7_Fqw">“Wherefore, I the Lord, knowing the calamity which should come upon the inhabitants of the earth, called upon my servant Joseph Smith, Jun., and spake unto him from heaven, and gave him commandments”—and so forth. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.15-17" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:15–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p11" guid="2573afe7-938f-41e0-bd8c-4cfdd448403b" pid="gd32Hjnfz0KtLax7iCHEDQ" hash="GVOxSw">As a result of this revelation, the Prophet Joseph became the instrument in the hands of the Lord in restoring the new and everlasting covenant, which is actually the fullness of the gospel and embraces within its powers, its terms, and its conditions every other covenant and commandment that our Father has ever given to men on earth. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/132.5-7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 132:5–7</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/33.5,7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 33:5, 7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p12" guid="d54e63a9-174f-4972-a750-c7057b8e6be7" pid="mylrDBY7WUGfarPDmINgZQ" hash="OJkLCQ">It provides the way to eternal life and even exaltation to all who accept the gospel and who endure to the end in living its principles and ordinances, for he has said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p13" guid="d59df02c-7a56-49ca-b691-fb824a52c42b" pid="koRaviCSLkeD0oOiQXVkDA" hash="70Ja1Q">“And even so I have sent mine everlasting covenant into the world, to be a light to the world, and to be a standard for my people, and for the Gentiles to seek to it, and to be a messenger before my face to prepare the way before me.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/45.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 45:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p14" guid="d8240001-7aca-4cbd-b5a5-d0b0d956f452" pid="GFr2klPX_UKqc9eeGyatCw" hash="H1pf3g">It is here, then, in its fullness with all its powers as a guide, a standard for us and for all men who will heed it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p15" guid="35e43a8c-6ab0-4d22-bcc1-5ca554f08f26" pid="yBr2Mhy1sk-44scLIIUSAA" hash="fYquVA">Since the love of God is extended to all mankind, he has said: “… O [ye] inhabitants of the earth: I the Lord am willing to make these things known unto all flesh; For I am no respector of persons. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.34-35" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:34–35</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p16" guid="0d7eb5e8-fc4b-473f-8cbd-d76177405785" pid="6cooVVdd9U2IoJ9JE4Y1ng" hash="uQweyA">And because of this we send missionaries by the thousands into all the world where it is permissible to teach the gospel of Jesus Christ and to baptize those who believe.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p17" guid="85de0052-aac0-4ffe-abb7-717593f49644" pid="IuAVSU07bki8nZc86w1xGQ" hash="Qq1YvA">Some may wonder why the Lord gives commandments and requires us to enter into covenants with him. Or, as one person asked: “If the Lord loves us, why does he give us commandments? If he loves us, why does he say ‘Thou shalt’ or ‘Thou shalt not’?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p18" guid="1664d90c-03ca-4a4f-a8d2-9a56803e2dd3" pid="ceB6KkA9w06hZosPCm5SUA" hash="wGPeAw">A simple answer to these questions is, he commands us because he loves us. He knows perfectly well what will bring us peace and success in our individual lives and in the world and what will bring the opposite.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p19" guid="447b363d-90d8-42df-9fdd-e32f51306e31" pid="13OzNCjve0uNfHA_FggB-Q" hash="Ol-54w">Just as any father would direct (or even restrict) his children if it would be a blessing to the children, so our Father in heaven gives us commandments, laws, and covenants, not for the sole purpose of restricting us or burdening us, but rather that we may, through obedience to correct principles, find peace and success.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p20" guid="3d4e5694-db44-4409-92d4-c62cf42e1fd7" pid="1ClXozEeH0Kkkd_ZYQ_fHQ" hash="nOE5lw">Actually, we do not <span class="emphasis">have </span>to do what the Lord commands us, but we cannot obtain the rewards and blessings he has promised unless we do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p21" guid="1d1eaaf0-f505-4263-b044-828762d70a61" pid="2cNpqdCdmUCMfogVQjF6tA" hash="-X37Qw">“For all who will have a blessing at my hands shall abide the law which was appointed for that blessing, and the conditions thereof, as were instituted from before the foundation of the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/132.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 132:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p22" guid="8185ceae-4197-44b8-ae2e-67931dd2b2c9" pid="2wGO9uNS4UmYKhnKCdpQ-Q" hash="tJBI5Q">Every member of the Church has made covenants with the Lord. These commandments and covenants are not grievous; they are not burdensome. On the contrary, they are enlightening, uplifting, assuring, and helpful. They are instruments of voluntary action on our part that help us to concentrate our efforts to accomplish the purpose of life and to reach our ultimate goal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p23" guid="2fb4d0a4-5024-44bc-bae5-774f8ab7337b" pid="cfA28M4j7Ee2yce2gW5Jjw" hash="y5gAqQ">Our first covenant is entered into when we are baptized and confirmed members of the Church. Both the conditions under which one becomes a candidate for baptism and the obligations of membership after baptism should be understood and impressed upon all, both young and old. The Lord makes these requirements and expectations rather definite and clear in these enlightening words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p24" guid="bc0b6103-6eff-4eb8-9c7b-07378f768d49" pid="GWKTYOoV7EKhiusQe1bQGQ" hash="V4gqWA">“… All those who humble themselves before God, and desire to be baptized, and come forth with broken hearts and contrite spirits, and witness before the church that they have truly repented of all their sins, and are willing to take upon them the name of Jesus Christ, having a determination to serve him to the end, and truly manifest by their works that they have received of the Spirit of Christ unto the remission of their sins, shall be received by baptism into his church.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.37" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:37</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p25" guid="9b983bcb-3e75-49c8-88cf-9d26d5e197c5" pid="IOFiV8IL2UOzvAPR5FSTGw" hash="iJOKLg">So, as one prepares himself for baptism, he must recognize that there are specific obligations and covenants associated with the receiving of this sacred ordinance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p26" guid="94722095-f47d-40fc-9795-4f545f79bf81" pid="-C5FOcvvPkmi8ydBK5_NIw" hash="-033gw">When we partake of the sacrament of the Lord’s Supper, we enter into a solemn covenant of obedience to keep his commandments and witness unto the Lord that we will take upon us his name and always remember him and keep the commandments which he has given us. Partaking of the sacrament should be done in sober solemnity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p27" guid="55c833f7-0750-4adf-8c7a-bfdfec56681b" pid="uDNQPjqI6k-Y_qnqzWMutg" hash="m9-fsA">Again, when we agree to have the priesthood conferred upon us, we thereby covenant with the Lord that we will honor it through righteous, decent living, and by magnifying the office given in service to others, always extending to all men kindness, consideration, courtesy, and love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p28" guid="20329d87-db51-4f83-adc7-3c917aff4e22" pid="aIExo-OR8Eyw_tN6UVEkBA" hash="AuENgA">Now, if we keep the covenant of baptism and honor the priesthood and its covenants and in other ways live in conformity with the principles of the gospel, we may then have the great privilege of entering a holy temple where we receive the higher ordinances of the priesthood and, in due time, enter into that order of the priesthood known as the “new and everlasting covenant of marriage,” with the promise given that if we remain faithful to the covenants made, we shall come forth with the just in the morning of the first resurrection and, with our companions, our children, our posterity, be permitted to live in a state of never-ending happiness, provided, of course, that they too keep the covenants that it will be necessary for them to make.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p29" guid="23a5edb8-b815-4c04-8844-6ad0a66e063a" pid="6uLLMuLqIEqx3_0JvK_mxA" hash="xUrbvQ">What hope, what comfort, what assurance and joy this promise should bring to the hearts of all who love their families! Surely it is true that “eye hath not seen, nor ear heard, neither have entered into the heart of man, the things which God hath prepared for them that love him.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-cor/2.9" class="scriptureRef">2 Cor. 2:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p30" guid="4ea9bf96-0123-4470-ac55-7ff51826d34c" pid="5D2_jMDR60GIC2gJ0qRiKA" hash="n4feuA">And, of course, he has said that they who love him keep his commandments and covenants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p31" guid="2c1f8cff-d67f-434e-ba15-e6344e5f0ac3" pid="pLW-ilP0OEGhYKdo0TCIYQ" hash="x7j71Q">President Joseph F. Smith reminded us that “we cannot neglect, slight, or depart from the spirit, meaning, intent and purpose, of these covenants … that we have entered into with our Father in heaven without shearing [or depriving] ourselves of our glory, strength, right and title to his blessings, and to the gifts and manifestations of his Spirit.” (<span class="emphasis">Improvement Era, </span>vol. 9 [August 1906], p. 813.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p32" guid="21c04b62-ce1c-41a8-946a-b6c9d22dcb17" pid="OjCehne4iE-5rYWR29AxYQ" hash="ZdF21Q">For God surely will not be mocked!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p33" guid="0cfa97d5-684b-4135-800e-49c5637a62f4" pid="9pZnPPZPdk-DLsum4omOGg" hash="gWmOrA">Let me repeat, each one of us has made covenants with the Lord and has agreed before God in sacred places that we will observe his laws, which, after all, are the principles by which we must learn to live in order to qualify ourselves for the greatest of all the gifts of God, which he says is eternal life, our life in the “family kingdom.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p34" guid="12bb3bd5-3900-4caa-9e6b-9534fd906706" pid="5yHrvIIOJESZRxFBofQ2kg" hash="nYaTvg">I testify to you, brethren and sisters, that I know that God lives and that he has, because of his love for us, condescended to make covenants with us, in order that we may be spared from failure, from sorrow, from regret, and that we may rise to the full heights of glory that are promised to those who are faithful and endure to the end.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord.p35" guid="b085ca7f-2129-4e67-9e31-4030424d63b2" pid="vZ4sZmStd02NZ95vWOmsrA" hash="ATw6Cw">My brothers and sisters, we are a covenant-making people. Let us also be a covenant-keeping people, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/10/we-have-made-covenants-with-the-lord</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1972-general-conference/1972-10-2040-elder-eiray-l-christiansen-64k-eng.mp3" length="6576460" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There Is Need for Repentance</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance?lang=eng</link>
      <description>So many timely subjects have been discussed today, beginning with the great address by President Lee, that I have been edified and I am sure that you have been as well. Now I humbly pray that I may not detract from but may add a little bit to your th</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03040_000_2030" doc-version="2" hash="oWMt_g"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="sgTkwcjX3keBUeZXoAsMEA" hash="KLlWUQ">There Is Need for Repentance</h1><p class="authorName" guid="6cde9ade-b28b-4ffd-a745-68fef99233aa" pid="nSySF04kF0-xenzXBdGVhQ" hash="2GhMEg">ElRay L. Christiansen</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="1bf58cde-edc1-48a8-9b07-ab653a869526">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p1" guid="29ff0856-8365-4065-83dc-be8fec06d7d5" pid="OreGCbaKb0ia5PUbHy9SBA" hash="CSRH0A">So many timely subjects have been discussed today, beginning with the great address by President Lee, that I have been edified and I am sure that you have been as well. Now I humbly pray that I may not detract from but may add a little bit to your thinking and doing as we consider the second great principle of the gospel. I feel there is need for it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p2" guid="6d66d4ef-2a7f-44f4-a8d6-4423396209a3" pid="W3pcu4IdREmecw3kP1EwsA" hash="XkxohQ">The primary purpose of the gospel and of the Church is to provide a pattern for living and a prescription for happiness and success—here and hereafter. President McKay declared on many occasions that next in importance to life itself is the privilege of directing that life. To direct one’s life is a privilege. It is also a real personal responsibility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p3" guid="904cc9e3-10ac-4d4e-b3ef-fe693428f7c7" pid="9E95bCjilU2nwOCe2Xhu9w" hash="l3hhrQ">Speaking to his sons, Lehi explained this by saying: “Wherefore, men are free. … They are free to choose liberty and eternal life, through the great mediation of all men, or to choose captivity and death, according to the captivity and power of the devil; for he seeketh that all men might be miserable like unto himself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p4" guid="9e277f42-e020-4225-8f70-449dd89ff0b7" pid="UI9Ijz7_AU2M4usgsUN5vQ" hash="CpRMpA">“And now, my sons, I would that ye should look to the great Mediator and hearken unto his great commandments; and be faithful unto his words, and choose eternal life, according to the will of his Holy Spirit;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p5" guid="39f04343-814a-4ff5-9c27-08cd23936276" pid="CNiiYWJ2LUeQ31oRqzdDWQ" hash="U72s6g">“And not choose eternal death, according to the will of the flesh and the evil which is therein, which giveth the spirit of the devil power to captivate, to bring you down to hell, that he may reign over you in his own kingdom.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.27-29" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:27–29</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p6" guid="ccd5862f-c91c-4d61-9981-b94824ea8c5f" pid="0LsVDHsmqkaRcwZa07ix3g" hash="bG17og">Because sin is such a devastating, destructive force, the great principle of repentance was provided by our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ, to extricate ourselves from the clutches of sin. Without the blessed privilege of repentance, we would have but little incentive to improve our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p7" guid="47439437-8503-4f1f-a921-024e966cfc76" pid="Abb6OJSEZ0CDoUfSOrBIrw" hash="KjJP0A">Repentance isn’t easy. It takes ability. It takes self-discipline and humility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p8" guid="29c9ccb8-0f47-43b5-bb0d-bbec69a7d9fb" pid="mkrP05cme0-Lu3V6Ptbk9A" hash="h0qHbQ">Repentance is not a negative teaching, but rather it is a positive process of building good character.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p9" guid="acf87a38-02e0-4a22-b2dd-9e3dd2d354a5" pid="9S2pMp3_-kiYCGS1M-d5Cw" hash="1bfd6Q">Repentance could become a remedy for most spiritual ills. However, it is not a mere superficial, shallow-rooted expression of regret.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p10" guid="06ce487c-2cec-4e90-9c3a-675ac4a08b2f" pid="JVkCSjocOEmQSDrfkj4IyA" hash="GyH_dg">What, then, is true repentance?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p11" guid="0112be3d-0ae1-4b56-9f9a-06298bcf1ac8" pid="siDZVcS6hkeEoBxjzdBUtg" hash="3QpBKQ">President Joseph F. Smith declared that: “True repentance is not only sorrow for sins, and humble penitence and contrition before God, but it involves the necessity of turning away from them [sins], a discontinuance of all evil practices and deeds, a thorough reformation of life, a vital change from evil to good, from vice to virtue, from darkness to light. Not only so, but to make restitution, so far as it is possible, for all the wrongs we have done, to pay our debts, and restore to God and man their rights—that which is due to them from us. This is true repentance, and the exercise of the will and all the powers of body and mind is demanded, to complete this glorious work of repentance; [only] then God will accept it.” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Doctrine, </span>p. 123.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p12" guid="2f7456e5-9e79-4d35-b7f6-4cb05fc59cbc" pid="bksqX1gYHkaBQHbIUaKqJw" hash="7ulkvA">If one truly repents, it will be manifested by his works, for, “By this ye may know if a man repenteth of his sins —behold, he will confess them and forsake them.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.43" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:43</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p13" guid="23513353-f0df-452f-980d-2665aec8086c" pid="SIOT3tfGXkCTebixsFafCA" hash="HdEWYQ">Thus repentance calls for a heartfelt sorrow for sin resulting not only in a cessation thereof but also in reformation of life. That’s the important thing—a reformation of life!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p14" guid="bf54d938-8a80-435d-ab08-6f1d1026d07d" pid="54NZn37Ank-tqN-0PYHe8g" hash="xhqlwA">To repent isn’t exactly popular these days. Yet the Lord expects each of us to repent, to improve, and to conscientiously reform our lives. In fact, he set for us a lofty goal, saying:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p15" guid="02cb6885-cf8e-4e6b-b123-be5aebf53554" pid="5WOMA6ieVkmbQ-TNNmgzXg" hash="gzE8mw">“Be ye therefore perfect, even as your Father which is in heaven is perfect.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.48" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:48</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p16" guid="59b72267-5bae-4087-8eda-141920405c5a" pid="jV3pc5fDpke0nXdfrthAhw" hash="yBGBBQ">Admittedly, this is an imperfect world. Nevertheless, each of us should be constantly striving toward perfection.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.f1"><ol class="number" guid="92676c47-ddc0-4a07-9dc6-e1d98341a3e8"><li guid="1ef34dd2-7257-46b4-9b00-ca91f3334a9a" pid="a91S_6M08E2E9uioV6E14Q" hash="fwn_ew">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p guid="9c5c5f54-3bd5-492b-aa1f-06b85031197d" pid="Xbe8xOfoMk-R55BqLFyQkA" hash="x_AvTA">“Let him that stole steal no more. …” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/4.28" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 4:28</a>.)</p>
        </li><li guid="d4bd5074-802e-43f9-9c77-09fbba191f33" pid="WXBfSqOhUkSWxu4GEYX2aA" hash="WHhVpw">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p guid="5f7d1631-50fd-4978-81e4-15970e2ca454" pid="J8GtbB4FmE2ZAVTHwFlNlQ" hash="TS7zWQ">“… let virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.45" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:45</a>.)</p>
        </li><li guid="3ca3ee55-02d3-478b-8355-0e3c7626213a" pid="gr35NKy_hE6pC6hOXb6Srg" hash="wUxb7w">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p guid="1db779d2-570b-435a-b988-832e125c808c" pid="e3vYFszR3EiIthxLFqx_Tw" hash="LPnT-A">“… pray for them which despitefully use you, and persecute you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.44" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:44</a>.) Destroy your enemies by making them your friends.</p>
        </li><li guid="15bb62c5-96f6-430c-a529-5d63adec959b" pid="ESh54z0YnEW3efWDNwnvPg" hash="IC6_zw">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p guid="11c13fde-f78e-4c47-a932-59ec28d399bd" pid="4Sl2GZsSbUuFMGymtFSgFQ" hash="UJKj7g">Let the unkind among us become considerate.</p>
        </li><li guid="34e203f5-9456-458d-a897-eb25c1215c7d" pid="toShOxF5zUm5XLmaSpgQkg" hash="vp7k4A">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p guid="e230f396-baa7-4b6d-a6c3-b9d3ce7e1098" pid="AJO_Iw3hpECCGyXOCU9jqQ" hash="tNCeOQ">Let the truth be spoken always, no matter what the consequences may be.</p>
        </li></ol></div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p17" guid="fcfd5241-6df3-4301-b2a2-5321ffb1f4f3" pid="_hQjGeVLak2LQWUow9HK5A" hash="4MLb6Q">I would like to add Brother Packer’s recommendation that we rid ourselves of the unmusical music and adopt some that does the soul and the heart good and which is pleasing to the Lord. We can at least do that in our own homes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p18" guid="bffce6ed-2eda-4ead-8ee2-566fcb1a2639" pid="9BPVkYJOY0OOoKgRbF_7jQ" hash="wec6KQ">To practice such virtues as these gives evidence of forsaking wrong. We ought not to let personal faults, bad habits, and moral weaknesses persist. They should be overcome and corrected without delay. I have often said: “You can’t repent too soon because you don’t know how soon it will be too late.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p19" guid="38265f7f-c60a-4c7c-9f70-73bb7b1bdb4c" pid="mAsSNXw-LUaOW87X07JrHA" hash="4RZ-lA">One of my distant Scandinavian relatives who was thriving financially in Denmark came with his family as converts to the Church to America and his family was directed to settle in Sanpete County. He was quite well-to-do, as I said, and he sold his lands, herds, and flocks for what he could and came without complaint. For a while he did well as far as the Church and his activities were concerned; and amazingly, even without the abundant rainfall and the water and the resources, he began to thrive again. He accumulated wealth again. He became so interested and involved in his possessions that he forgot about the purpose of his coming to America. They waited upon him as ward teachers. The bishop would call upon him and implore him to become active as he used to be, and he would promise them that in the future when he got certain things settled that he would do it. Finally he was growing old, and they came and said to him, “Now, Lars, the Lord was good to you when you were in Denmark. He has been good to you since you have come here. See all of the things that you possess. We think now, since you are growing a little older, that it would be well for you to spend some of your time in the interests of the Church. After all, you can’t take these things with you when you go.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p20" guid="62d9d84f-17e8-438d-b47a-6af896b6db5a" pid="86Bq4j9TRk6WkZst0WMCXg" hash="1Ppf_A">He stopped. He was shocked, and he said, “Vell, den, I vill not go.” But he did. And so will we. It is time today to begin the program and process of repenting!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p21" guid="3bb5bfa7-09a8-40ec-af7d-0747515dbac8" pid="kW8cp4yaNEKBQXh7SoofoQ" hash="fGg7Kw">Brothers and sisters, you know and I know that the power of the destroyer is persistently, relentlessly operating upon the minds and hearts of the children of men, young and old, in the Church and out of the Church, and too many are yielding to his evil enticements.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p22" guid="ff09c878-8d61-4b10-a7df-06431bcf3860" pid="WqITs4LqfU2UEAu3BdMKsQ" hash="nIpbOg">We have been warned by the Lord and by our leaders through the years to repent. President Lee this morning urged us to begin with ourselves and develop self-respect, and beginning there, set out on the real purpose of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p23" guid="f21cab5c-569c-44f6-bb57-01350a94919a" pid="M8LTG3ENa0mmi1-zmmvlug" hash="c3SFTw">We have been supplied with heaven-sent programs such as the family home evening program, to keep families secure and our homes intact. It has been predicted that in the last days men shall become “lovers of pleasures more than lovers of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/3.4" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 3:4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p24" guid="155d7dc2-5dfe-4b9d-8ea0-76c7ec7d431c" pid="q_m0ZPbnzUSKMhiMD_czkw" hash="8IhWDw">“For behold, at that day shall he rage in the hearts of the children of men, and stir them up to anger against that which is good.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p25" guid="27304d75-814c-4777-b5ac-271926ac8c64" pid="uwZlfMFbVUa0wpEHxltIZw" hash="uAF9uQ">“And others will he pacify, and lull them away into carnal security, that they will say: All is well in Zion; yea, Zion prospereth, all is well—and thus the devil cheateth their souls, and leadeth them away carefully down to hell.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/28.20-21" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 28:20–21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p26" guid="fe1ab26c-2eef-4f2a-8ac6-6fb6432a9414" pid="xFS1JYl8HUmZj26eha-NQw" hash="aRo2Nw">I like that word <span class="emphasis">carefully </span>because that is the way he operates. He never jerks. He never pulls—just misleads us gradually, step by step. Now in this situation and in the world today, let us remember the admonition of James:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p27" guid="6c96429a-527b-4550-88b6-802bbf90c96b" pid="2lZ3OgV3R0uTNQdIPzXsPQ" hash="2t4CXQ">“Submit yourselves therefore to God. Resist the devil, and he will flee from you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p28" guid="6e329a8a-bf1a-4b34-824b-a62c781ee97c" pid="-s7Bf5uFBECVtALNEkJytQ" hash="WvWKMA">“Draw nigh to God, and he will draw nigh to you. Cleanse your hands, ye sinners; and purify your hearts, ye double minded.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p29" guid="d3d1014c-d3ce-42af-af91-7975b2110cac" pid="J1NGeSECT0mpjMuu9baYmg" hash="igGTVw">“Humble yourselves in the sight of the Lord, and he shall lift you up.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/4.7-8,10" class="scriptureRef">James 4:7–8, 10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance.p30" guid="ec101931-7956-403f-bbae-a79f2c19d4b8" pid="htubRIxKrk6m8fO4Rpfc2g" hash="FZreyw">May we all repent and place our lives and our homes in order and in perfect harmony with the gospel of Jesus Christ, I pray, testifying to the truthfulness of the restored gospel and in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1973/10/there-is-need-for-repentance</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1973-general-conference/1973-10-2030-elder-eiray-l-christiansen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5910211" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 1973 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Important Questions</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I’m grateful, my brothers and sisters, for the much-needed down-to-earth counsel given us this morning by the Lord’s spokesman, President Spencer W. Kimball, as well as for the timely and helpful remarks of the other speakers who have preceded me. Ti</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03044_000_011" doc-version="2" hash="XJn7yQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="dLEzcPcoKUaKn8s9svJMPQ" hash="PeJqxQ">Three Important Questions</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="RFVB4VyOO0-56-STeE6e7w" hash="2GhMEg">ElRay L. Christiansen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p1" pid="XAE0PSNTyE6vnP7MKD9DbA" hash="rDLrIw">I’m grateful, my brothers and sisters, for the much-needed down-to-earth counsel given us this morning by the Lord’s spokesman, President Spencer W. Kimball, as well as for the timely and helpful remarks of the other speakers who have preceded me. Timely, because the Lord has said, “For I will raise up unto myself a pure people, that will serve me in righteousness.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/100.16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 100:16</a>.) “Purge ye out the iniquity which is among you; sanctify yourselves before me, … and ye shall be endowed with power.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/43.11,16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 43:11, 16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p2" pid="ujuoDFwy8EqWM8J9OAWbUA" hash="EF1nOw">Brothers and sisters, you will soon see that our subjects are not assigned. All I can say, since I will talk about the same things Elder Hinckley has talked about, is somebody here needs a double dose. On that premise, I shall proceed. And in what I shall say I also have in mind those of you particularly who have yet to answer and resolve three important questions:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p3" pid="wLjBPxlnB0CHn3Xvs0jqSg" hash="mkakbg">Whom shall I marry?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p4" pid="m0-4FVDLokai7LzxWRxqEg" hash="G2GSyQ">Where shall I marry?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p5" pid="gLUGcGWWRUW1U422Orc7jA" hash="7ynItA">By whom shall I be married?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p6" pid="dx8UkpJK1kOdTRGtkSUs7g" hash="0W6icg">There are different ways of doing things, but surely, in anything we do, there’s no better way than the right way—and the Lord’s way is the right way. Fortunately, his way has been made plain and is plainly revealed. Seldom is the problem one of knowing what to do; it’s a matter rather of having the wisdom and the will to do what we know is right.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p7" pid="Ujzos3aRs0aqJji9GoeitA" hash="RAvE7A">Probably the most consequential event in your lives takes place when you are united in marriage. It will have a far-reaching effect upon your future. Like the ripples caused by a pebble cast upon a placid pool, the decision you make in regard to where, with whom, and by whom this event will take place will affect not only you, but the lives of many others, especially your children. In fact, it will likely affect generations to come!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p8" pid="HPOlfOqD5EymFJ-S_S3bzA" hash="O4l58g">In a matter of such vast importance, it is imperative that sober thought be given to marriage long before it takes place.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p9" pid="YxGnCdnnZkeZgsWeznLXUg" hash="vQOxaw">We must realize that marriage is designed by the Lord for a divine purpose, whereby a servant and handmaiden of the Lord may prepare themselves in righteousness to receive chosen spirits coming from our Eternal Father, and give them bodies of flesh for their mortal probation, and then undertake with all the power at their command to lead these spirit children entrusted into their care back into the presence of God from whence they came. Such “… children are legal heirs to the Kingdom and to all its blessings and promises. …” (<span class="emphasis">Discourses of Brigham Young,</span> p. 195.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p10" pid="F0YI3fuLU0WwsI9xi39WOA" hash="1kzZNA">True love is not earthbound. It is as eternal as our spirits, which never die. A continuing association in this life, as well as in the next, with those we love, should be the great desire of every person. It is the ultimate. It is the great purpose of mortality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p11" pid="5oP8npsbO0OKx6ePJe9zag" hash="0N5YQA">Persons who are satisfied with a temporary legal arrangement which terminates at death, when it could be an everlasting contract, are basing their marriage on shallow and fleeting love. Such a marriage looks to the moment, not to the future. Under the stress of life, it is more likely to crumble and fall. True love pleads for endless association of those we love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p12" pid="xCZcc3albk2EQ8i_k68fQA" hash="Z4zq-A">But an eternal relationship of families does not come about automatically, as some suppose. It must not only be planned for; it must be earned. We must realize that only when we have lived in complete harmony with all the laws and ordinances of the priesthood, including those received in holy temples, should we expect to find ourselves prepared to dwell in what I sometimes refer to as the “kingdom of families”—the celestial world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p13" pid="ijC1AFDSsUyuDGhO1GOOmQ" hash="TB6dCQ">In a revelation given to the Prophet Joseph Smith, the Lord has said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p14" pid="Dk6mbK-_K0yyZ6wq1SQJug" hash="ik958Q">“And they who are not sanctified through the law which I have given unto you, even the law of Christ, must inherit another kingdom, even that of a terrestrial kingdom, or that of a telestial kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p15" pid="BBnyKcXp3EWnQHrrKq2bDg" hash="JaPGkA">“For he who is not able to abide the law of a celestial kingdom cannot abide a celestial glory.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.21,22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:21, 22</a>.) He would just not feel at home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p16" pid="DlmDanrYzUmR1ltMDbEWGw" hash="SeO6Bw">Surely then our desire and our goal should be to prepare ourselves, not for a fragment of joy but for the fulness thereof, which is to be found only in the celestial world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p17" pid="_O46RTO1I0KJJL7pyWgz1Q" hash="dTWSMg">How fortunate it is that, after its absence from the earth for hundreds of years, the Lord has revealed anew the principle of eternal marriage and has restored the divine authority to administer it. It is here. It is ours to embrace. And it is disappointing to see that in too many instances those who live close to these holy places pass them by and go the way of the world when it comes to the most momentous event in their lives. With the knowledge that it is the Lord’s way and, therefore, the right way, no Latter-day Saint with a concordant spirit would deviate from it. Some may say, “Why not try a civil marriage first, and then if it works out, we will go to the temple later?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p18" pid="rah1N6QD3EKegNPSHiXBkw" hash="pJ7zcA">Well, in my opinion, the time to be married right is when you’re married. Can we consign the Lord’s prescribed way to a secondary position? We cannot! When you consider the incomparable blessings and promises that may be realized in a marriage that may be perpetuated through the eternities ahead of you, as compared with a temporary association, your desire, your determination, should be to take hold of and ensure these blessings and promises. If ever there is a time to be realistic and to act in the light of things as they really are, if ever there is a time to use your heads, so to speak, and plan wisely, it is when the thought of marriage first enters your minds.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p19" pid="1TIMxLotIk6YHLfQueMmMg" hash="PdxPxA">When two souls have a true love for each other, a genuine, tender affection (not merely physical attraction), when they are really united in spirit, having the same lofty ideals, the same beliefs and standards, trusting each other, confiding in each other; when there is sincere respect one for the other along with virtue and purity of life; when such people are joined together through the sealing ordinances, their marriage (if continued on such a basis) should give them the assurance and comfort in the thought that even though death may separate them, yet in the resurrection shall they come forth and live in the family relationship forever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p20" pid="zU-dkDEBckKJBoErwHDnZg" hash="rGftYA">It is your earthly life that you are now living, my young friends. You will live it but once. There will be no reruns, no repeat performances. What you are in this life determines where you will be throughout eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p21" pid="yXrtr8pS5U2h8zu-yYmjow" hash="dkAFig">It is your future, your destiny that you are now molding.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p22" pid="miOnFOue0kChN73wh87TzA" hash="im9H7w">You made good in that pre-earth life. You were valiant there. You must not now “fumble the ball” on the 20-year line. When you do take the wrong course, you are undoing the work of your prior existence, for there you struggled for ages to prepare for mortality where you now are.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p23" pid="hP05wtVBe0S-LeqtTqP9SA" hash="yNJQ7Q">I urge you to carefully consider these things as you make preparations for the future.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions.p24" pid="kc_k1twu4keHUdnbZc2KFg" hash="XMN-6A">You who stand on the threshold of marriage, you who have been taught the eternity of life should strive with all your might to be worthy of entering a temple of the Lord there to be sealed to your companion for endless time in the right way, in the right place, by the right authority. I testify to the truths and the reality that these powers to seal on earth and to have them binding in heaven are with us. They have been restored by heavenly messengers and we have the power amongst us. Let us not pass it by. I testify to my knowledge that God lives, that he is our Father, that Jesus is the Savior of the world, and that the gospel has been restored in the fulfillment of prophecy, both of the Old and the New Testament prophets. And I do it in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/04/three-important-questions</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1974-general-conference/1974-04-2040-elder-elray-l-christiansen-64k-eng.mp3" length="11723518" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 1974 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Power Over Satan</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I am thankful, my brothers and sisters, for the truth that has been revealed through prophets of God, both in the past dispensations and in the present. We are blessed with ample truth regarding our origin, our mortal lives, and our destiny.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03050_000_009" doc-version="2" hash="BvlMZg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="mTEmjCsMMkWj7IJpwyPrEg" hash="t6qThA">Power Over Satan</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="oY5A7Mgl-kmLFloJKyzUMA" hash="2GhMEg">ElRay L. Christiansen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-32a0.jpg" alt="Elder ElRay L. Christiansen" pid="7UwcANbC0061ices_1oDKQ" hash="Qo2Pjg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p1" pid="w-CWE5v3jUSAuuqYfpJfrQ" hash="5XLzmg">I am thankful, my brothers and sisters, for the truth that has been revealed through prophets of God, both in the past dispensations and in the present. We are blessed with ample truth regarding our origin, our mortal lives, and our destiny.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p2" pid="fXRLNMeeMkmvpyOcEfZBPw" hash="dkhUzQ">The scriptures teach us that we lived in the spirit world before we were born into mortality. That is, we lived in the presence of God who is literally the Father of our spirits.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p3" pid="SL80z5rvxEidIvdeTrf_Qw" hash="RU7nYA">When the great council was held in heaven, in which all of us were involved, the Father presented his plan for peopling the earth, and for the salvation of man. Lucifer wanted to amend the plan. He proposed to destroy the agency of man and to save all mankind, that not one soul would be lost. This he would accomplish through outright force and coercion, denying all persons the right of choice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p4" pid="IhLh2XauiUa4q-JPc6-TrA" hash="KztoFA">Satan’s proposal of compulsion was rejected by the Father, and Lucifer “was angry, and kept not his first estate; and, … many followed after him.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.28" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p5" pid="dBSxM1iDkkCo2WkcIo1-Dw" hash="c4rEUA">We must have witnessed that tragic scene when Lucifer—brilliant, capable, yet lacking in intelligence to properly apply his knowledge (along with one-third of the hosts of heaven)—rose in hateful rebellion against God. And they were expelled from heaven, retaining the malignant powers to tempt and to persuade men to disobey God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p6" pid="Te8wc_tzcUiKH1u3RTqBpg" hash="memD6g">The Father’s plan, accepted by Jehovah, provided man the right of choice, that through its exercise he might become strong and advance in learning, wisdom, and righteousness by conquering weaknesses and by resisting the temptations to do wrong. Then God said: “We will take of these materials, and we will make an earth whereon these may dwell:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p7" pid="uJSH_3y6xUebYKn_12T4XQ" hash="Wrj8uA">“And we will prove them herewith, to see if they will do all things whatsoever the Lord their God shall command them.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.24-25" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:24–25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p8" pid="QP2FCoaalkOWMDjjQwc7fw" hash="hQEOMw">Now, God said also (and this is most important to you and to me):</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p9" pid="9udU8APczUW_WyRNUEBwkQ" hash="bVOLfQ">“Wherefore, because that Satan rebelled against me, and sought to destroy the agency of man, which I, the Lord God, had given him, and also, that I should give unto him mine own power; … I caused that he should be cast down;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p10" pid="tZ_F8g5W1kGJnDIOiYCPtg" hash="308ryw">“And he became Satan, yea, even the devil, the father of all lies, to deceive and to blind men, and to lead them captive at his will, even as many as would not hearken unto my voice.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/4.3-4" class="scriptureRef">Moses 4:3–4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p11" pid="C-lLimc_wkylIndcJS6CYA" hash="-ELFnw">Now, the truth is that Satan lives! Indeed, some have seen his satanic majesty in spirit form.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p12" pid="G8QlMc0NBUGpIHQxWMlV4Q" hash="6O5Ykw">President Harold B. Lee warned us to “make no mistake about his reality as a personality, even though he does not possess a physical body. Since the beginning of time, he, with his hosts … have waged relentless war to destroy the free agency of man.” Those who teach that there is no devil or who declare him to be a figment of the imagination used only to frighten people are either ignorant of the facts or they themselves are deceived.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p13" pid="wR-40-UA6k2t6tQUD-xkPQ" hash="gB320g">How does Satan operate? What are his tactics? Using his superior knowledge, his unique powers of persuasion, half-truths, and complete lies, the evil one uses the spirit children who followed him (which were many), plus mortal beings who have yielded to his evil ways, to wage war against Jehovah and his followers; and they will, if they can, influence us to become critical and to rebel against God and his work. Thus he destroys the souls of men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p14" pid="JXTcG6e7-kKW-moRSglGzA" hash="XnFbBg">The scriptures tell us: “Satan stirreth them up, that he may lead their souls to destruction.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/10.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 10:22</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p15" pid="14H_L3eP_UC_WnwaOLNVhw" hash="F6hSsg">“Yea, he saith unto them: Deceive and lie in wait to catch, that ye may destroy; behold, this is no harm. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p16" pid="imlwOXQczEawyhKUQK6B1w" hash="c-nIoA">“And thus he flattereth them, and leadeth them along until he draggeth their souls down to hell; and thus he causeth them to catch themselves in their own snare.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p17" pid="HYgQd1j3g0ucJvy_qB0pPQ" hash="8bCvwg">“And thus he goeth up and down, to and fro in the earth, seeking to destroy the souls of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/10.25-27" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 10:25–27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p18" pid="2n4MqJffvU-xhu78zHOUqw" hash="SRdw2Q">Now, the adversary knows that a little sin will not stay little, and he welcomes any and all into his kingdom by first trying to get us to lie a little, then helping us to try to justify ourselves in so doing or to cheat or to steal. Some folks are indeed induced to desecrate the Sabbath day until it becomes habitual with them. Some people begin with the use of liquor just to “relax a bit.” Also, drug abuse, evil speaking, disobedience to parents, or deceiving one’s own companions—these are means he has of getting us to digress from the proper course. He knows full well that, if continued, such diversions soon result in regrets, sorrows, and losses, because they lead us into greater sinfulness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p19" pid="lUWOXSVekUyqckcDvFzykA" hash="X8Dqtg">No doubt one of the most infamous snares set out by the adversary is that of unchastity. The power to bring children into the world is God-given, and if that power is guarded and held sacred, it will result in happiness and blessings beyond measure. But if it is desecrated and polluted through illicit use, it will bring sorrow, misery, and self-condemnation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p20" pid="u_3ygtVLtk-XPYAgrdyQGQ" hash="dIRG9g">The First Presidency of the Church a few years ago issued a warning to the Latter-day Saints and to all people generally against the dreaded sins of unchastity. Among other things, they said: “The doctrine of this Church is that sexual sin—the illicit relations of men and women—stands, in its enormity, next to murder. … you cannot … escape the punishments and judgments which the Lord has declared against this sin. The day of reckoning will come as surely as night follows day.” (<span class="emphasis">Church News,</span> 13 Feb. 1952, p. 16.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p21" pid="7OdhmXFeD0qGSpCvV09QgA" hash="F0Bukw">How, then, may we resist the evil one? In all his evil doings, the adversary can go no further than the transgressor permits him to go, and we can gain complete power to resist the evils caused by Satan through adherence to the principles of the gospel of Jesus Christ. Members of the Church may have the blessing of the Holy Ghost, the prompter, as a companion as well, and when the Holy Ghost is really within us, Satan must remain without. Study of the scriptures, prayer, faithful living of the commandments of the Lord, the discharge of church obligations and duties, being a considerate neighbor, and using the heaven-sent program of family home evenings can provide a basis for having the Holy Ghost as a constant companion and protector, which will result in peace and happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p22" pid="ctlHonKsN0mibYYrtzPhoQ" hash="MUi-HQ">I tremble when I realize how the children of God are being tempted today, especially the youth; yet we have confidence in them. They are choice spirits. But they must realize that Jesus, not Satan, is their best friend; that happiness can come only through obedience to the commandments of God. We must help them prepare for and achieve their divine destiny. Nevertheless, if they fall into the snares of Satan, parents, priesthood leaders, and teachers must lead them out of the pitfalls and on to higher ground through the process of repentance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p23" pid="GzAtSGv6NEWIM75H3ibXNA" hash="VG9dkA">Recently our beloved president, Spencer W. Kimball, speaking to a multitude of youth, assured them that an awareness of the existence, the power, and the plans of Satan—together with a compelling and vibrant testimony of God and of the gospel and of the plans of our Father given through Jesus Christ, his Son, and the living prophets—can help them achieve unprecedented accomplishments, which may affect their lives eternally.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p24" pid="ZrKwMEbWYU6l2xN3u_JMGA" hash="ONUvYA">Yes, brothers and sisters, Satan lives. He is real. He is cunning. But you may be assured that God, our Heavenly Father, reigns over all and is merciful and forgiving to those who truly seek him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan.p25" pid="4SKA1cLr_kKo5dUA8d6xUg" hash="tBz0gw">And every man receiveth wages of him whom he listeth to obey. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/29.45" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 29:45</a>.) To this I testify in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/10/power-over-satan</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1974-general-conference/1974-10-2020-elder-elray-l-christiansen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5343849" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 1974 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Laws of God Are Blessings</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I stand before you in deep humility, my brothers and sisters, and with a prayer in my heart that what I say may give encouragement to all who are here, or all who need that encouragement, and most of us do. I should like to base my remarks upon a div</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03057_000_012" doc-version="2" hash="KlPDlg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="wcngjSZk-0G94yVLZlfKpg" hash="Vk_Fsg">The Laws of God Are Blessings</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="VIhWxTZC7Em9zzmPRCMN8g" hash="2GhMEg">ElRay L. Christiansen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-32a0.jpg" alt="Elder ElRay L. Christiansen" pid="BhNfRqPdvUKiAVm_BPU-mQ" hash="Qo2Pjg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p1" pid="RF7Madyu6U6_lcU2sq_ynw" hash="H1x6oQ">I stand before you in deep humility, my brothers and sisters, and with a prayer in my heart that what I say may give encouragement to all who are here, or all who need that encouragement, and most of us do. I should like to base my remarks upon a divine truth that is found in the book of Proverbs. It reads as follows: “For the commandment is a lamp; and the law is light; and reproofs of instruction are the way of life.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/6.23" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 6:23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p2" pid="Eq_XjJ2ggUKbXREqJAlswg" hash="Ps2ZMQ">A commandment <span class="emphasis">is</span> a lamp to show us the right course, and indeed the law defines that course that we are to follow. Some people look upon laws in general as impediments to them—obstacles—and there are good people in every segment of life who believe that the laws of God, even the great Ten Commandments, are intended only for certain people—for those whom they describe as being extremely religious or for the less fortunate. They believe that while it is essential to observe the laws of the land, it matters little or none if one observes the laws of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p3" pid="K7ghdzeZ80ma_FcSMT4WMg" hash="C9aYNw">Some people feel that the laws of God inhibit freedom; and that they who are not religiously inclined are automatically exempt from the laws and commandments of the Lord; and that if one minds his own business and lives his own life, so to speak, he has sufficient religion for his own welfare; and that salvation and joy everlasting will somehow be forthcoming, even though they do not observe the laws and commandments of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p4" pid="rI-k5Ax4EU-dCcM8eibh0Q" hash="oxRj4g">Surely these are shortsighted views. Actually, the commandments of the Lord are principles upon which <span class="emphasis">our</span> lives must be built if we are to find happiness, success, and peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p5" pid="DibXhyXF4E2sP0ZhWC9Tjw" hash="iFH1BQ">We believe that through the atonement of Christ all mankind may be saved by obedience to the laws and the ordinances of the gospel; and that because of his great love for man, the Lord has granted each of us an opportunity to live in the flesh and through obedience to the laws of the gospel and through service to our fellowmen, to find happiness and peace and prepare to live hereafter in a state of “never-ending happiness” as the Book of Mormon describes it. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.41" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2:41</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p6" pid="QIo0kZNJfEOWrvgx8V1trA" hash="3UyiTg">But the Lord does his work according to eternal principles and eternal laws. While he is a God of love, he is also a God of order. He does not deviate from the established principles and laws, because they are right in the first place. And he and they are the same yesterday, today, and forever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p7" pid="yIptSRR_y0abk7LTGWIRFQ" hash="dE5eQw">The laws and conditions prescribed for the welfare of mankind cannot be changed nor circumvented, because they are divine and were established before the foundation of the world was laid. They are, in fact, the only means by which we can have peace of mind here and gain eternal life hereafter. This is expressed in a great revelation given to the Prophet Joseph, as follows: “For all who will have a blessing at my hands shall abide the law which was appointed for that blessing, and the conditions thereof, as were instituted from before the foundation of the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/132.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 132:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p8" pid="J-JM6vvN70yneJFIwMNQng" hash="wMdzOA">So, brothers and sisters, we need simply to remember that which is expected of us if we wish a blessing. The Lord will remember that which is expected of him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p9" pid="5x4zWNfj00OoV7CAgsIO1g" hash="KJZi9w">Now, his commandments are not grievous. They are not burdensome. They are not oppressive. We sing in one of our hymns, “How gentle God’s commands! How kind his precepts are!” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 67.) The laws of God are not given to us to burden us or to handicap us. They are not impositions. They are the statutes through which, if observed, the purpose of life and existence is to be realized. Even those who are called to go through trials, sorrow, tribulation, and adversity are promised that if they are faithful in tribulation and adversity, that “the reward of the same is greater in the kingdom of heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:2</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p10" pid="jQtkCM0hlkmbRatbXuWA0A" hash="PjZLkQ">It is comforting to read the words of the Lord in regard to this:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p11" pid="igYo_7m4bEyX3pav3SgjZA" hash="-3rhdQ">“Verily I say unto you, blessed is he that keepeth my commandments, whether in life or in death; and he that is faithful in tribulation, the reward of the same is greater in the kingdom of heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p12" pid="WjFRRqx2pkyOMckV4e0QEg" hash="1c8MTg">“Ye cannot behold with your natural eyes for the present time the design of your God concerning those things which shall come hereafter, and the glory which shall follow after much tribulation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p13" pid="Of5p7EMiiE-_hy7jnTSAjA" hash="TAHj9g">“For after much tribulation come the blessings. Wherefore, the day cometh that ye shall be crowned with much glory, the hour is not yet, but is nigh at hand.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.2-4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:2–4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p14" pid="NirRL56gKUO_PVYaG10nVA" hash="I4NjwA">Now if one is inclined to question the wisdom of observing the law—whether it be the laws of man, the laws of nature, or the laws of God—he should consider these words of the Lord: “Again, verily I say unto you, that which is governed by law is also preserved by law and perfected and sanctified by the same.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p15" pid="mYL-jvddC0Sude_4jtewVg" hash="4ocVKA">“That which breaketh a law, and abideth not by law, but seeketh to become a law unto itself, and willeth to abide in sin, and altogether abideth in sin, cannot be sanctified by law, neither by mercy, justice, nor judgment.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.34-35" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:34–35</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p16" pid="LbAHKBGPG0GHbfb-UMInSA" hash="zR34Pw">Observance of law brings harmony, peace, order; while without observance of law there is found confusion, and sorrow, remorse, failure—whether it be the laws of God or the laws of man, or whether it be nations or whether it be individuals, it is the same. There are those who ask (they have asked me, and really that is why I am speaking along this line), “If the Lord loves us, why does he then give so many commandments, some of them restrictive in their nature?” Well, the answer is he gives us commandments because he loves us. He wishes to save us from sorrow and remorse and failure, and the worst of all, regret, and from losing our blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p17" pid="b9yH3mgWF0ai0Oz2_hLeXw" hash="ma01-g">In the same way, wise parents often find it best to deny a child his wishes or to instruct him to act in a certain way, even though it is contrary to what the child desires. This is done because of parental love and is done in the interest of the child’s welfare. If he responds as he should, it results in lasting benefits and satisfaction for both.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p18" pid="t2weVv13SUu_XzTVoeW3yQ" hash="1IGKgA">Now, the Lord loves us enough to say, Thou shalt not lie, thou shalt not steal, thou shalt not commit adultery, thou shalt not covet, and so forth. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.18-28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:18–28</a>.) You know the laws, and President Kimball explained them so well this morning. The gospel of Jesus Christ is the perfect law of liberty, according to the apostle James. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.25" class="scriptureRef">James 1:25</a>.) God is its author. He set forth the conditions. He is its fountainhead. The gospel is a great system of laws, which laws are simply eternal principles by which our Father in heaven desires to save mankind, his sons and his daughters, not only to save them, but also to share with them all that the Father has—associations with those we love, honor, power, glory, dominions, even exaltation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p19" pid="pWfMs5_7L0GbixgF1N0MDg" hash="mah41Q">But while he gives us commandments, he also gives us the freedom and the liberty to reject them if we choose, as Brother Stapley has already explained to us. As he spoke to Adam and Eve in the Garden he told them that they could eat of every tree of the Garden. This they were free to do. However, he gave a commandment that they should not eat of the tree of knowledge of good and evil or certain blessings would be lost or denied them. They could eat the fruit if they desired, and if they insisted, but they must remember that he forbade it. They were at liberty to break the commandment; their liberty was not restricted; but if they did eat of the tree, they would have to pay the penalty.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p20" pid="30uCKd0wP0yF7XZ6DLXOtA" hash="UXeyhA">As it was with Adam and Eve, so it is with us. We have the divine right and also the individual responsibility to determine whether we will accept or whether we will reject the laws and principles and commandments of God. But my, how grateful we ought to be that these laws are given us and are plainly understood, given us to direct us, that we may not lose our way in this world of misunderstanding and by following the vain philosophies of the world. How thankful we ought to be for such truths as these:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p21" pid="VxSrWZhnUE2moxNBIEY4tg" hash="6fd_Nw">“Men are, that they might have joy.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.25" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p22" pid="aYqNCsS7wUeekDu4Abf2fw" hash="hbPFCQ">“I, the Lord, am bound when ye do what I say; but when ye do not what I say, ye have no promise.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/82.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 82:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p23" pid="Nnrr3l67n0Smps4cuNJvEA" hash="PtBJPA">“There is a law, irrevocably decreed in heaven before the foundations of this world, upon which all blessings are predicated—And when we obtain any blessing from God, it is by obedience to that law upon which it [that blessing] is predicated.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/130.20-21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 130:20–21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p24" pid="QO5pJBYnAkatHMYl_CHvFA" hash="QALCWg">And finally, this most beautiful statement by my friend King Benjamin in his address to his people. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p25" pid="sPLzGuYLy0iKT21vDRWFDQ" hash="iwldPA">“And moreover, I would desire that ye should consider on the blessed and happy state of those that keep the commandments of God. For behold, they are blessed in all things, both temporal and spiritual; and if they hold out faithful to the end they are received into heaven, that thereby they may dwell with God in a state of never-ending happiness. O remember, remember that these things are true; for the Lord hath spoken it.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.41" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2:41</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p26" pid="l4KY-QD6lESA13FaItemdg" hash="vulqGQ">We should be grateful for Spencer W. Kimball (and his associates), a great living prophet provided by the Lord to guide us in these difficult times and to teach us, and to speak the mind and will of the Lord in a day of confusion. I add my testimony to those many which have been borne today to the fact that God lives, that Jesus is the Christ, that the gospel has been restored in the fulfillment of prophecies and promises of ancient prophets, and that we have with us today a prophet of God to direct us, to help us, to warn us, and to reveal the mind and will of God unto us and unto the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings.p27" pid="EYCm6JST7ka6yv0AoHvxBw" hash="oamQkA">May the world take heed while the day yet lasts, for when the night cometh, no man can work, and the opportunity will be gone. This I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, the Lord. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/04/the-laws-of-god-are-blessings</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1975-general-conference/1975-04-2050-elder-elray-l-christiansen-64k-eng.mp3" length="7098703" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
