<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By F. Burton Howard</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by F. Burton Howard.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/F.%20Burton%20Howard.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by F. Burton Howard.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1978 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Be One with the Prophet</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1978/10/be-one-with-the-prophet?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My brothers and sisters, I am deeply grateful for the love and confidence of the First Presidency, and for the sustaining vote of this conference that has brought me here before you at this time. I love the Lord and I love his work.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/be-one-with-the-prophet" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03102_000_011" doc-version="2" hash="ZWHJ4Q">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/be-one-with-the-prophet.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="qj5-0pO_HU2WZXbep9HVfA" hash="nkUMAw">Be One with the Prophet</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ZfqG6XKbDU-86Fe_jPMzXQ" hash="P7QfHg">F. Burton Howard</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/be-one-with-the-prophet.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-28de.jpg" alt="Elder F. Burton Howard" pid="8831KrsQXEGwMKdAguVWgA" hash="buhzGQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/be-one-with-the-prophet.p1" pid="L5vLXRMg20GknYQhPGwEew" hash="hfctCw">My brothers and sisters, I am deeply grateful for the love and confidence of the First Presidency, and for the sustaining vote of this conference that has brought me here before you at this time. I love the Lord and I love his work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/be-one-with-the-prophet.p2" pid="X3R-Zl7_6Emv1MfLtAp3GA" hash="eY2HGQ">At the risk of being unduly personal, I would like to tell you how I feel about the gospel. I love it, not compelled by lack of choice or circumstance nor by the uncritical adoption of patterns commanded from afar; not manipulated, but acting consciously, constructively, purposely, giving a freewill offering of the heart. I want to be involved in the Lord’s work—humbly, totally, positively, and honestly; neither subordinating my soul to nor seeking dominion over others, but being freely one with those who are his, sharing and caring, thankful to be a part of the work wherever it may be, not to escape aloneness nor to fill life with self-deceptive activity, but rather knowingly and willingly doing what must be done; a grateful fellow servant, supporting, building, loving, lending heart and breath to a great cause.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/be-one-with-the-prophet.p3" pid="5nZADCUs5kuT8tqSNEMzSQ" hash="PCiuVg">I want to stand firm and fearless, not weakening—for weakness implies pressure from without—but radiating strength and charity truly from within; offensively—not defensively—enthusiastically, sweetly, faithfully, everlasting in harmony with the Lord. May we all become one with him and his prophet and bring harmony into the work that we are in charge of, wherever that may be, in whatever land, I pray for each of us, and most especially for me, as I acknowledge my weaknesses and stand before you to accept this great calling. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1978/10/be-one-with-the-prophet</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1978-general-conference/1978-10-2040-elder-f-burton-howard-64k-eng.mp3" length="1560459" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1978 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Saving Others We Save Ourselves</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves?lang=eng</link>
      <description>For many months I have been away from the headquarters of the Church. I have learned much and have come to understand better many things I had known before. I have observed firsthand the challenges which confront Church members as they endeavor to bu</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03135_000_031" doc-version="2" hash="aVLUiw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Gn61EkblBUGKXK2N46cT8Q" hash="F7C2Mw">In Saving Others We Save Ourselves</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="0x9W182ewUGrT-ZuhojckQ" hash="P7QfHg">F. Burton Howard</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-28de.jpg" alt="Elder F. Burton Howard" pid="piFwvKXy10SVkvp_D7qRFw" hash="buhzGQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves.p1" pid="10CqiH7euE-9z4NckKvkUA" hash="ChW10g">For many months I have been away from the headquarters of the Church. I have learned much and have come to understand better many things I had known before. I have observed firsthand the challenges which confront Church members as they endeavor to build the kingdom. I have seen the time and financial burdens borne by adults. I have sensed the preoccupation of parents for their children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves.p2" pid="PywBRwO2nEK4fItGSEuZBw" hash="C2IJFw">I have come to know that in this age of anxiety, and sometimes selfishness, there are not many of us willing to forego comforts or hard-earned security in order to concern ourselves with the welfare of others outside of our immediate circle of acquaintance. But <span class="emphasis">some</span> are—and some <span class="emphasis">do.</span> Everywhere I have been, I have met <span class="emphasis">some</span> faithful Saints who love, pray for, and watch over their fellowmen, both in and <span class="emphasis">out</span> of the Church. By means of a parable (I believe I can call it that), I would like to speak to that comparative handful of God’s children who have learned to <span class="emphasis">live</span> for others—and more particularly to those who have not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves.p3" pid="xfwz7ERQgkyqqvwE_-9kHQ" hash="EPnuXA">In a desert region one day, a number of travelers set out on a trip. It was hot and the journey was long. They had little in common except their shared desire to arrive at a distant city. Each carried provisions and water expecting to replenish their supplies along the way. Not long after leaving their homes, a great storm arose. Dust clouds darkened the sun, and the wind brought swirling sands which quickly filled the low places in the road. What at first had seemed a pleasant outing suddenly became a hazardous undertaking. The travelers soon realized that the question was not merely when they would arrive at the city, but whether they would arrive at all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves.p4" pid="MS_UlqNqY0yTOytEzIx6rA" hash="re3qqA">Confusion and doubt affected the company. Some sought shelter, while others attempted to turn back. A few moved onward through the storm. The end of the first day found them scattered, with inadequate provisions, wanting water, and lost in the desert. A new day brought hunger, thirst, and despair. The storm still raged. Hope was in short supply. Familiar landmarks were gone. The road, which had been narrow and hard to find, at best, was hidden by silt and debris. No one knew where to go to find it. Many claimed to know the way, but as they could not agree, each traveler wandered in his own way in search of water or the shelter of a settlement.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves.p5" pid="ERobbTz440yvOugRUnu45Q" hash="B4rDuA">At the end of yet another day, two of the group, half-blinded by dust and with their strength nearly gone, came unexpectedly, with something more than good fortune, upon an inn and way station. There in the sanctuary of walls and roof, they refreshed themselves and counted their blessings. There they replenished their stores and contemplated the remaining portion of their journey. The weather remained unsettled. The wind continued to blow. The poorly marked road wound ahead through hills where the sand piled deep and where it was said that robbers sometimes preyed upon unsuspecting travelers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves.p6" pid="fQvAtFmZmU-hQlqY1h1uvg" hash="Yu7z5Q">One of the two was anxious to reach his destination. He had important business in the city. He gathered his supplies and water and paid his account. Early in the morning he set out in haste in an attempt to cross the hill country by nightfall. But the windblown sand had blocked the road. He was forced to dig and detour. When night came, he was far from the city, exhausted and alone. When he fell asleep, thieves found him, took his supplies, and left him without strength and without water to face almost certain death.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves.p7" pid="5ETnVZvYYUC_gMyuNIfSrg" hash="1V-Emg">The second traveler was also desirous of reaching his destination. But he remembered the others in the desert behind him. They were lost and would soon perish without water and without hope. He alone knew where they were. He alone knew their condition and their need. He likewise arose early and paid his account. He glanced at the hills with their promise of the city beyond, and then turned back down the road whence he had come. The sky was a little lighter now. He recognized some of the landmarks. He knew about where he had left his traveling companions. He called out to them by name, for he knew them. After hours of patient searching, he found many of them. He shared with them life-giving water from his own containers. He told them he knew the way. He spoke as if he had authority, so they followed him, and he brought them to the way station with him. There they rested and regained their strength. They were given directions regarding how to reach the city. They renewed their provisions, filled their water containers, and went out again to face the storm.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves.p8" pid="wstErMaEMUO5jReirYhUow" hash="pe5qJg">The journey was still difficult. The wind still blew and clouds obscured the sun. The road still wound through the sometimes deep sand, and thieves were still in the hills. But this time the traveler was not alone. The group was large. When sand blocked the way, work parties were organized to remove it. When some faltered, the strong shouldered the burdens of the weak. When night came, there were watchmen to man the watch. After many days, the second man and his friends arrived safely at their destination.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves.p9" pid="94vk5glyBkil809Mgx_QuQ" hash="TRDDiQ">When they arrived there, those who had been rescued and given water gathered around the second traveler and said, “We could not have come to this place without you. We shall ever be grateful to you for searching for us, for finding us, for sharing your water and your bread. We know that you put aside your own journey and submitted to the hardships of the desert in order to help us when we were lost. What can we do to repay you?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves.p10" pid="LKLyYtwB6kGbzEUAUdPOuw" hash="gfuC8w">And the second man replied, “Thank me not, for by no power of my own did I find the way station. The water there would have been bitter had I not shared it with you. I know that I could not have arrived at the city without you. Your strength and encouragement enabled me to continue on. Your presence prevented robbers from attacking. I have come to realize that in order to save my own life, I had to save yours as well. I know now that it is not so much the haste of one’s journey but rather what he does along the way which determines whether he will arrive at his destination. Thank me not,” he said. “In truth, I have not brought you to this place, we have brought one another.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves.p11" pid="ooyI8apqiE-pwfg1gNZiTA" hash="3oUtRA">And so it is. None of us could have arrived at the point where we listen to and enjoy this great conference without others. Our testimonies, our greatest blessings, our membership and activity in Christ’s church—all of these we owe to the often unremembered and always unnumbered hundreds who gave of their time and their patience and their love to us when we were trying to find our way in the desert. They brought living water to us, or to our parents, or to our parents’ parents. Whether we know it or not, whether we like it or not, whether we are grateful or not, we are where we are because of others. We cannot say, indeed we must never say, “It was a difficult journey, but I have arrived. Let others get here as best they can. I don’t have time now to take water to those who are lost. I have no obligation to those in the desert.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves.p12" pid="Yii8SNFNd0e2Qch7JKu1SQ" hash="PfL6hg">The Lord is the director of the work in which we are engaged. He established the conditions upon which each man and woman will be privileged to return home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves.p13" pid="Ut13JjdsM0WrmNLNQ2Z8Og" hash="bImcCw">He knows that sometimes clouds block the sun and that the road is hard to find. He must know how difficult it is just to get there. Can He reasonably expect us to try to bring others who are lost with us as well?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves.p14" pid="ROsBXeqqK0itQO8ielAK5Q" hash="T5kYjw">The answer is clear. To what else did He refer when He said, “All things whatsoever ye would that men should do to you, do ye even so to them?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.12" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 7:12</a>.) Surely He had in mind our obligations to others when He spoke of lost sheep and living water. If the parable of the good Samaritan has application anywhere, it must apply to one who, having the gospel, encounters another in need without it. But lest there be any doubt, the Lord has directed plain language to the Latter-day Saints. His words in the Doctrine and Covenants are pointed: “The gospel is unto all who have not received it. But, verily I say unto all those to whom the kingdom <span class="emphasis">has</span> been given—from <span class="emphasis">you</span> it <span class="emphasis">must</span> be preached unto <span class="emphasis">them.</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.75-76" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:75–76</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves.p15" pid="mA4UMR8biUefMveKejRevQ" hash="SQAmQA">What directions has He given to help us arrive at our destination? Once again, He has clearly spoken through a modern prophet: “And now, behold, I say unto you, that the thing which will be of the <span class="emphasis">most</span> worth unto you will be to declare repentance unto this people, that <span class="emphasis">you</span> may bring souls unto me, that <span class="emphasis">you</span> may rest with <span class="emphasis">them</span> in the kingdom of my Father.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/15.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 15:6</a>; italics added.) For, as he spoke to the disciples of old, “As I have loved you, … love one another.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/13.34" class="scriptureRef">John 13:34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves.p16" pid="_Yo-PZbytk2CmBmx2XsYQA" hash="C8O-6w">My brothers and sisters, may we better understand the duties associated with our discipleship, I pray humbly in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1981/04/in-saving-others-we-save-ourselves</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1981-general-conference/1981-04-5040-elder-f-burton-howard-64k-eng.mp3" length="6598545" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 1981 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Repentance</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1983/04/repentance?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Let me ask each of you to picture two crystal goblets in your mind. They differ in size and shape. They are both of good quality and have been well used. One has been carefully kept in a china cupboard. It is clean and polished. It is warm and inviti</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03161_000_025" doc-version="2" hash="WcaFBA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="iA2LkZIxqkCbzEtpPZPmAQ" hash="aDChPA">Repentance</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="fUVWKXd8l06rgyNOmFeaaQ" hash="P7QfHg">F. Burton Howard</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-28de.jpg" alt="Elder F. Burton Howard" pid="AyhgYRe43kmUu-JR3dgSTw" hash="buhzGQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p1" pid="N5TNEq5qzEW79J8e2hyZIA" hash="JryMzA">Let me ask each of you to picture two crystal goblets in your mind. They differ in size and shape. They are both of good quality and have been well used. One has been carefully kept in a china cupboard. It is clean and polished. It is warm and inviting in appearance. It sparkles in the light and is filled with clear water.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p2" pid="Wydt1s2ulkuucjTXRffARA" hash="ToBOug">The other glass is coated with grime. It has not been in the dishpan for a long time. It has been used for purposes other than those for which it was made. Most recently it has been left outside in the weather and has served as a flowerpot. Although the flower is gone, it is still filled with dirt. It is dull and unbecoming in the light.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p3" pid="vjxQUIOS_kOVjRlMTKZm-w" hash="M-b6Xw">Is not each of us like a crystal glass? We vary in size and shape. Some of us radiate a special spirit. Some are dull and uninviting. Some fill the measure of their creation. Others do not. Each is filled with the accumulated experiences or debris of a lifetime.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p4" pid="Fy1GtvZzM0GkD32pmkIzVg" hash="DkpM1Q">Some contain mostly good things—clean thoughts, faith, and Christian service. These hold wisdom and peace. Others enclose dark and secret things. Over time they have filled with unclean thoughts, selfishness, and sloth. They often hold doubt, contention, and unrest.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p5" pid="F6dUVz9VpEKTm6eUgpOjQw" hash="N8geqQ">Many know they are not living up to their potential but for various reasons have procrastinated making changes in their lives. Some long for they know not what and spend their lives in a haphazard pursuit of happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p6" pid="Bs6Z4RotDkSVQs1PePrn_g" hash="wr_i8w">These, in a way, are like the crystal goblet which spent part of its existence filled with dirt. They sense that there is a higher purpose to things. They become dissatisfied and begin to search for meaning. First they look outside themselves. They sample the pleasures of the world. As they do they discover, much as did the snail who set out to look for its house, that after arriving at wherever they were going, they are no closer than before to the object of their search.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p7" pid="XV6M3BHankS-PIXe3IlDVA" hash="JRPtIA">Ultimately, they look within. They have really known all the time that this was where to find peace. Sin, you see, is not just a state of mind. Wickedness never was and never will be happiness. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/41.10" class="scriptureRef">Alma 41:10</a>.) They discover that if they are not righteous they can never be happy. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.13" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:13</a>.) They resolve to change. Then they are confronted, figuratively, with the problem of how to turn a weathered flowerpot into a sparkling crystal goblet. Questions are asked: Can I ever be forgiven? Is it really worth the effort? Where do I begin?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p8" pid="dN_eBWYZOEGFuhsAyc4DbQ" hash="wop4og">In the case of the glass it is easy to understand what to do. We begin by recognizing a better use for the crystal. A convenient place for dumping the unwanted contents is selected. The dirt is left there. The goblet is carefully washed with high quality detergent to remove the stains and residue. It is lovingly polished and placed once again in the company of other crystal glasses in the china cupboard. It is put back into use and cared for regularly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p9" pid="9kfVE1VFHUmbJfeVpcgYfw" hash="a_WsAA">There is a similar process whereby men and women are purified. The misuse of their lives is forgotten, and they are renewed and changed. This principle, of course, is repentance. When accompanied by authorized baptism, it provides not only an initial cleansing but an ongoing remission of sins as well. Participating in this purifying process is perhaps the most thrilling and important thing we can ever do. It has far-reaching, even eternal, consequences. Of more immediate interest, however, the rewards of repentance are peace and forgiveness in this present life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p10" pid="dOoLRJgkY0m1PyBIMsPEsg" hash="u30nLw">Let me illustrate what all of this means. A few years ago I was asked to speak to a group of young men. I don’t remember now exactly what was said, except that near the end I made the statement that no one, but no one, present had done anything for which he could not be forgiven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p11" pid="jbASk-TFLEWLzWApNjRGyg" hash="nmkYqA">After the meeting was over one of them came up to me and said, “I just have to talk to you.” Inasmuch as I soon had another appointment, I asked if it could wait or if someone else could answer his question. He replied that he had already waited many years and that it was very important to him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p12" pid="feSNHFjttEujZv0YJ_KNpw" hash="SkoL8w">So taking advantage of the few minutes available, we found a little unused classroom, went in, and closed the door. “Did you really mean it? Did you?” he asked.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p13" pid="lBGVbPX1OES9Qs7mlqOUQQ" hash="ZSjtcw">“Mean what?” I said.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p14" pid="SvyVePjBR0qOmywLCLBrVg" hash="S571MQ">“The part about how none of us had done anything that could not be forgiven,” he replied.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p15" pid="Ajed6YFh2E2G0WiY8td4Cg" hash="_G-I6g">“Of course I did,” I said.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p16" pid="em9l53RrqUaM4Avi1o12XA" hash="IU3tMA">Through his tears his story came. He was of goodly parents. All of his life his mother had told him that he was going on a mission. Before he turned nineteen he was involved in serious transgression. He didn’t know how to tell his parents. He knew it would break their hearts. He knew that he wasn’t worthy to serve a mission. In desperation, he began to look for an excuse not to go. He decided to take up smoking. He felt that his father could understand that better and would not probe for the real reason. Smoking would hurt his parents, he rationalized, but not as deeply as the truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p17" pid="Pg-u9eCgR0OwMNAUvx61Dg" hash="JoZhMw">He soon found, however, that the bishop wasn’t put off by his use of tobacco. The bishop told him to just stop it and go on a mission anyway. So to get away from the bishop, he entered the military service. There he fell under the influence of some good Latter-day Saints. He stopped smoking. He was able to avoid major temptations. He served his time, received an honorable discharge, and returned home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p18" pid="Hskha12zP0uhW7bTF1Pe4A" hash="h5G6zA">There was only one problem. He felt guilty. He had run away from a mission. He had run from the Lord and sensed somehow that gnawing discontent which comes when men do not live up to the purpose of their creation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p19" pid="qAGjyUmM60OwUlKIwMCbQQ" hash="IQHGyQ">“So there you have it,” he said. “I have not sinned again. I have attended my meetings. I keep the Word of Wisdom. Why is it that life seems empty? Why do I feel somehow that the Lord is displeased with me? How can I know for sure I have been forgiven?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p20" pid="E1xcP4jD90arUWl6duuRJg" hash="UopNdw">“Tell me what you know about repentance,” I said.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p21" pid="AOYyAxqPCUGPk9K0bfzGPA" hash="_8NAeQ">He had obviously done some reading on the subject. He spoke of recognition, remorse, and restitution. He had resolved never to sin again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p22" pid="_brIPsrlREuoJBRK_kIPpA" hash="f1IEqw">“Let’s see just how those principles apply to you,” I said. “Let’s begin with recognition. What is the best indicator that someone recognizes he has done wrong?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p23" pid="e3-7SnMd_kymJAodKvfKdQ" hash="KtA9Ug">“He will admit it,” was his reply.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p24" pid="Ds0sNC5PkEib36IO9CIQoQ" hash="N60nSw">“To whom?” I asked.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p25" pid="dt4YUjBYmEudPpvT2htM7g" hash="HJPTHQ">He was thoughtful. “To himself, I guess.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p26" pid="5rBZmW_vaU2IzGeoDPIbrA" hash="I72UeQ">“Men sometimes view themselves in a most favorable light,” I said. “Wouldn’t better evidence of awareness of wrongdoing be to tell someone else?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p27" pid="BcAtGTxYnkCkQVbT9Sxhng" hash="fmAi4A">“Yes, of course,” he answered.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p28" pid="CUk5CZ0XMkOfBp99Un6laA" hash="Ar_dIQ">“Who else?” I insisted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p29" pid="BtjMtmL8-k-Oy7zLuwa4Rg" hash="LMgNPA">“Why, the person wronged,” he said, “and … and maybe the bishop.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p30" pid="XnkTxJsBvkq5v1CKcurNCg" hash="bizXyg">“Have you done this?” I asked.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p31" pid="EPBepMsAjkaolFMf-7_-kg" hash="JSj_GA">“Not until now,” he replied. “I’ve never told it all to anyone but you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p32" pid="mQeAHfOtGU2ANHAlOQQpbQ" hash="6ticIQ">“Maybe that is why you have not ever felt completely forgiven,” I responded.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p33" pid="LnqTw0krm0-eudrr78TzIw" hash="r3-QDA">He didn’t say much.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p34" pid="qSw6_Jaz2kGL1L7jUOk7rQ" hash="kjqiMw">“Let’s look at the next step,” I said. “What does it mean to feel remorse?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p35" pid="DTa5M1M3iUG_jBMru1o51w" hash="FVRe6Q">“It means to be sorry,” he answered.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p36" pid="CQzilQInMESEmaL8CR--Og" hash="QUlfTw">“Are you sorry?” I asked.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p37" pid="wFysq-5jCEOFkvjbeyS-uA" hash="MZ6YgA">“Oh yes,” he said. “I feel as if I had wasted half my life.” And his eyes filled again with tears.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p38" pid="WkFkmf-MKEaY4rGlDFSU1g" hash="qnwDRw">“How sorry should you be?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p39" pid="Xe3uWDOFuEeT97-Ffjk9BA" hash="HXOklg">He looked puzzled. “What do you mean?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p40" pid="Tw96_MdR8U2dvEMM_VkMog" hash="NCuwQw">I said, “Well, in order to be forgiven, a transgressor must experience godly sorrow. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/2-cor/7.10" class="scriptureRef">2 Cor. 7:10</a>.) He must have anguish of soul and genuine regret. This sorrow must be strong enough and long enough to motivate the additional processes of repentance, or it is not deep enough. Regret must be great enough so as to bring forth a changed person. That person must demonstrate that he is different than before by doing different and better things. Have you been sorry enough?” I asked again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p41" pid="LQXAtQvzh0aCc9_oG5JklA" hash="-pDtnw">He hesitated. “I’ve changed,” he said. “I’m not the same as I was before. I keep all the commandments now. I would like somehow to make it up to my parents. I have prayed for forgiveness. I apologized to the person I wronged. I realize the seriousness of what I have done. I would give anything if it hadn’t happened. Maybe I haven’t been as good as I could be, but I don’t know what else to do. But I didn’t ever confess to anyone.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p42" pid="OUlb-rHv3UyPpRd8LjT6Yw" hash="Yv_s3w">I said, “I think after this meeting we can say you have even done that.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p43" pid="0c4Bt3Cmj0ywAB__0qtBAw" hash="TjAlLQ">Then he said, “But after all of that, how can I ever know the Lord has really forgiven me?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p44" pid="sBZP3VFnQkSX5bPxaedc9g" hash="hS82TA">“That is the easy part,” I replied. “When you have fully repented, you feel an inner peace. You know somehow you are forgiven because the burden you have carried for so long, all of a sudden isn’t there anymore. It is <span class="emphasis">gone</span> and <span class="emphasis">you know</span> it is gone.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p45" pid="-zenedrAtUu1LDjTlvikog" hash="8_KmWg">He seemed doubtful still.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p46" pid="1IIcA0ApyES7hJHGy8ASog" hash="WXuXaA">“I wouldn’t be surprised,” I said, “if when you leave this room, you discover that you have left much of your concern in here. If you have fully repented, the relief and the peace you feel will be so noticeable that it will be a witness to you that the Lord has forgiven you. If not today, I think it will happen soon.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p47" pid="cU5xjg9Cj0iLlGrVNYkTuA" hash="vRG5oQ">I was late for my meeting. I opened the door and we went out together. I didn’t know if we would ever meet again. The following Sunday evening, I received a telephone call at my home. It was from the young man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p48" pid="hM4z73WafkGk6rpEHBochw" hash="t_lY4w">“Brother Howard, how did you know?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p49" pid="z7GpL678v0K0BVpEnZcv9Q" hash="aZZNKA">“How did I know what?” I asked.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p50" pid="v55RfCnoZEmUGLcfGJ4siw" hash="z8dNsQ">“How did you know I would feel good about myself for the first time in five years?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p51" pid="QGVFxPVABEqDDgcY3pkK6Q" hash="wqRqHA">“Because the Lord promised he would remember no more,” I said. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/8.12" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 8:12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p52" pid="6Am_xPbqZUmN0OtfyNJbYg" hash="0np5fw">Then came the question: “Do you think the Church could use a twenty-four-year-old missionary? If they could, I would sure like to go.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p53" pid="_8HTnTp1VU2CXJbCitWjGw" hash="5TKRFQ">Well, that young man was like one of the glasses we spoke about. He had been out in the world and was partially filled with the wrong things. He was not content. Sin had clouded his vision and interfered with his potential. Until he could find a way to repent, he could never become what he knew he should be. It took time to change. It took prayer. It took effort, and it took help.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p54" pid="ZDuBsxyel0SmgZfuubhyUw" hash="g6mEDg">My young friend discovered that repentance is often a lonely, silent struggle. It is not a once-in-a-lifetime thing; rather, it lasts a lifetime. As President Stephen L Richards once said, it is an “ever-recurring acknowledgement of weakness and error and [a] seeking and living for the higher and better.” (in Conference Report, Apr. 1956, p. 91.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p55" pid="VkUevFc7oEeRcmOs89zk8A" hash="1fgGUw">This young man came to know that repentance is not a free gift. Just as faith without works is dead (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/james/2.17" class="scriptureRef">James 2:17</a>)—so repentance, too, demands much. It is not for the fainthearted or the lazy. It requires a complete turning away from wrongdoing and a set of new works or doings which produce a new heart and a different man. Repentance means work. It is not just stopping doing something. It is not just recognizing the wrong or knowing what should be done. It is not “a cycle of sinning and repenting and sinning again.” (Hugh B. Brown, <span class="emphasis">Eternal Quest,</span> Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1956, p. 102.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p56" pid="Z2vZ9bDglEOX82eT9wP95w" hash="GDQXBg">It is not only remorse; rather, it is an eternal principle which, when properly applied over sufficient time, always results in renewal, cleansing, and change.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p57" pid="3YNmbunqDEWsXH1jfoEMfQ" hash="-XsHvA">The young man we have spoken about discovered that where sin is so serious as to jeopardize one’s fellowship in the Church, the sinner must be willing to submit to the jurisdiction and judgment of the person who holds the custody of his Church membership and request forgiveness of him as well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p58" pid="_Ip9R0_LhEKrcy5y_S1HcQ" hash="nckbjg">Most important of all, he learned that repentance is an indispensable counterpart to free agency. Free agency in the plan of salvation contemplates that men and women are free to choose the direction of their lives for themselves. Repentance means that as imperfect beings sometimes make imperfect decisions, they may correct their course. By following the rules of repentance, and through the atonement of Jesus Christ, mistakes don’t count. The Lord agrees to “remember no more.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/8.12" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 8:12</a>.) Because of the miraculous gift of forgiveness, transgressions are forgiven—<span class="emphasis">and forgotten.</span> Men can be cleansed and return to the path of purpose and progress and peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/repentance.p59" pid="GJCDeviHnk6dpRKNcDFGSA" hash="0-MptQ">By repenting, my young friend became a new person. He was born again of the Spirit. He came to understand for himself, and that is the important thing, the meaning of the Savior’s words: “Come unto me, all ye that labour and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/11.28" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 11:28</a>.) I so testify, in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1983/04/repentance</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1983-general-conference/1983-04-4030-elder-f-burton-howard-64k-eng.mp3" length="6961344" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 1983 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Come Back to the Lord</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord?lang=eng</link>
      <description>From the beginning, prophets have called almost all men to repentance. Those who have not known about the gospel have been exhorted to abandon their sinful ways, keep the commandments, and join with the people of the Lord.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03206_000_030" doc-version="2" hash="cEm8uA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="oNZ6lD7ceUahVfk5vh6hYw" hash="fuAUGg">Come Back to the Lord</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="IeaLPJnD-k2Pn5D_-bX_bQ" hash="P7QfHg">F. Burton Howard</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-28de.jpg" alt="Elder F. Burton Howard" pid="GE49SVOsKkiUD3hHqwagrQ" hash="buhzGQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p1" pid="ZRYTEhqzsUC1b4ZUli9Lhg" hash="umZI3g">From the beginning, prophets have called almost all men to repentance. Those who have not known about the gospel have been exhorted to abandon their sinful ways, keep the commandments, and join with the people of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p2" pid="Jr7q2LFGD0WVETw7-ioAQQ" hash="BHugMg">But prophets have also pled with another group—those who were once believers, but who, because of pride or sin or something else, abandoned the faith. In this group are the less active, the critics, the uncommitted, and the rebellious. These are Church members who have grown away from God as they have grown older. To these, the invitation has always been to come back to the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p3" pid="Z0NHtxn-qUSP2w7tXUq69Q" hash="pqTenQ">As we think about members of the Church repenting and returning to activity, the stories of Saul or Alma may come to mind. Some may be waiting for a similar miraculous experience before committing themselves again. However, they will probably wait in vain. For, as the Savior taught his disciples, “if they hear not Moses and the prophets, neither will they be persuaded, though one rose from the dead” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/16.31" class="scriptureRef">Luke 16:31</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p4" pid="GrrrnuhcjkWlf7EVQao6Ag" hash="tS9qIA">Without some such incentive to change, others may wonder if it is possible to return to faith from doubt. Can the cynic ever really become as a little child? Can the slave of habit or passion become free again? Is there a way back? If so, is it worth the effort to find and follow it? Where and when does one begin?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p5" pid="ebqFqQM_RkKiynJTyCxi-w" hash="kZ0KgQ">There is a way—for surely prophets do not teach in vain. And, just as surely, the Lord hears the prayers of teachers and leaders and parents who pray for the return of those who are lost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p6" pid="uppv7-OfrEGVO4MB4d0qTw" hash="kZYazw">Some may think the way is not clearly marked, for in all of scripture there are but a few instances recorded of former believers ever repenting. Be that as it may, the fact remains that thousands have returned from inactivity. Let me tell you about some who did.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p7" pid="7Rofc1U0Q0ikMyJ3MKQ6ww" hash="Ug0xgw">When I was first called to be a bishop, I inherited a large ward. Many of the eight hundred or so members did not come out to church. I had never met them and resolved to do so.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p8" pid="LpLKtK6_lEik0Bj36fi1Qg" hash="C062aQ">One Sunday afternoon in November, I went to visit an inactive family. As I came up to the house, a woman was sweeping the porch. I introduced myself as the new bishop and asked if her husband was home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p9" pid="_SDr_YMt106_LpAOE8nI4A" hash="r_WsoA">“Yes,” she said, “but he won’t talk to you. We are tired of being bothered. My husband asked the other bishop to take our names off the records of the Church. We don’t want home teachers. We don’t want people collecting fast offerings. We just want to be left alone.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p10" pid="NuLe3idnnkqdB65YZTCiFg" hash="RpV1SA">She changed her grip on the broom. “Now get out,” she said. “Get off my porch, get out of my yard, and don’t come back.” The broom was coming at me as I backed down the steps. I stammered a few words of apology, which were ignored. “Git,” she said, and I did.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p11" pid="MPmpp--HMUWKty13KgDv_g" hash="Sqx57w">I didn’t sleep well that night. I had been humiliated. Worse still, it seemed, my office had been treated with disrespect. By Tuesday night, I had almost decided that the woman and her husband should be excommunicated. A wise counselor, and a careful reading of the instructions from Church headquarters, persuaded me otherwise.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p12" pid="JeZpJbj4x0yS0Dq2iZRcnA" hash="-YwAaQ">I said hello to them on the street occasionally after that, but I never returned to the home. However, we did assign a relative to visit there each month to watch over them. As far as I know, no gospel message was given, and no other significant Church contact was had with that family during the years I served as bishop.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p13" pid="wL1TalP0WUq4sQi57ZSKlw" hash="8FCW7w">After a time the ward was divided. I was released and was called to be stake president. On another Tuesday night some years later, one of our bishops came to the stake office and asked if I would be available later in the evening to interview an older couple for a temple recommend. He had been working with them for months, and they were finally ready to go to the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p14" pid="6DyS7broHU-TTpz4TRcqLg" hash="DxxupA">He said, “You may know them, President,” and he mentioned the name of the woman with the broom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p15" pid="wsg_KfEJEkiceu2J9urUYA" hash="6_HlBQ">I could hardly wait for that interview. About nine o’clock the bishop brought a well-dressed, elderly couple to my office and introduced them. I recognized them as the same people I had known before, but they were different somehow. I invited the good sister to come into the office first. I asked her if she knew who I was, and she replied, “Oh yes, you are the stake president.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p16" pid="PSUCVAE9fU2xpI8hQ84YWQ" hash="XoeGJg">“Do you remember a Sunday afternoon in November, thirteen years ago?” I asked. “A young bishop came to your door and wanted to know if you and your husband would like to become more active in the Church. Do you remember turning him away?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p17" pid="_lWYAUgGAUa79250R0_IaQ" hash="AB8swg">“I don’t remember anything like that,” she said. “I’m sure I would never have done such a thing.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p18" pid="CYlDaN2ugUadp8wXgae7Og" hash="wOGD3A">Then I said, “I have another question. Why have you waited so long to come back to the Church?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p19" pid="YCw_t8Z-wEC9oDW6sAUODA" hash="XNeuww">“Well, we always knew we would have to get active again someday,” she replied. “We wanted to. We just never got around to it. My husband used to smoke a lot, and he didn’t feel comfortable going to church. I prayed for years that he would quit. When he started to have health problems a couple of years ago, it just seemed like a good time to go back.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p20" pid="Uvs7p-HhM0eWSh3rt9IWEg" hash="qLHEPQ">I finished the interview and talked with her husband as well. They were completely worthy. Shortly afterward, they went to the temple to be sealed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p21" pid="0TDAHP4rkkOV7DTKPWFKTQ" hash="EmSE9Q">Now, did you notice the elements of their return? It wasn’t easy. They had always known. She had prayed for years. There was a lot of wasted time. Finally, before it was too late, they talked to the bishop, repentance took place, old attitudes and habits were forgotten, and they came back.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p22" pid="6LEaXcM2p0u0OFCMvZISjA" hash="TClq0g">Another who came back was Aminadab (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/5.title" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 5</a>). He had once belonged to the church of God, but he became critical and contentious. He evidently sympathized with the opposition, because he was present when two young missionaries named Nephi and Lehi were taken captive by an army of Lamanites.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p23" pid="sLmsdfsha0K6YDu8_MZlPA" hash="aDO1DQ">A cloud of darkness came upon him, and he heard a still, mild voice whisper, “Repent … and seek no more to destroy my servants” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/5.29-30" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 5:29–30</a>). Surprised, he turned around and looked at Nephi and Lehi. Their faces shone through the darkness, and they appeared to be lifting their voices to heaven (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/5.36" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 5:36</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p24" pid="yRqST0eHAkKJG3QJShiHEg" hash="ds58oQ">Aminadab then recognized them for what they were. In a loud voice he told the Lamanites that the young men were servants of God. As the army turned to look, they too became aware of the darkness which surrounded them. They asked Aminadab how to dispel it, and he, drawing on truth learned, I believe, at another time, said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p25" pid="xwzwOJJyOUSBG8kLxp0pOA" hash="FbZtDg">“You must repent, and cry unto the [Lord], even until ye shall have faith in Christ … ; and when ye shall do this, the cloud of darkness shall be removed from overshadowing you” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/5.41" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 5:41</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p26" pid="7h2qB99nnUa3NZWoNm96TQ" hash="DKU_dA">Now notice again, the scripture speaks of darkness overshadowing those who have abandoned the faith. The effect of darkness is to prevent one from seeing clearly. To find the way back, as Aminadab discovered, one must repent and pray until doubt and darkness disappear and important things can be seen again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p27" pid="DQA1LWyUS0i9Y8-i2shFMw" hash="pPby_A">One final story—once again from when I was a bishop. One night, while I was in a sound sleep, the doorbell rang. I stumbled to answer it and found a young member of my priests quorum at the door. I knew him well, well enough to have gone on outings with him, to have prayed with and about him, and to have taught him. I knew him as well as a good bishop knows any active eighteen-year-old priest, which was well enough for me to ask what he was doing at my front door in the middle of the night.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p28" pid="J4Kzaodq7kiT-oaRkWDxjg" hash="fPhXHA">He said, “I have to talk to you, bishop. I’ve just done something serious, and I can’t go home.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p29" pid="JpkFFDNb1UiXafbctmosIA" hash="vsbmJg">He was right. It was serious. I invited him in, and we talked. He talked and I listened, then I talked and he listened, until dawn. He had many questions. He had committed a terrible sin. He wanted to know if there was hope. He wanted to know how to repent. He wanted to know if repentance included telling his parents. He wanted to know if there was any chance of his going on a mission. He wanted to know many other things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p30" pid="RF6qmFwYEUSKWAUopefKdQ" hash="I0Bcmg">I didn’t have all of the answers, but I told him there was hope. I told him the way back would be difficult, but it was possible. I explained what I knew about the process of repentance and helped him see what he must do. I told him if he really wanted to go on a mission that that decision could only be made in the future after he had repented. Then I told him to go home, and he did.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p31" pid="_SzB_VQVMES8AnvaCFdHuQ" hash="vxVTLA">He made his peace with his parents. He asked forgiveness from those he had wronged. He put sin and bad company behind him and did everything he could to repent.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p32" pid="9iBbPwbPmUWISOYXq-kXYA" hash="pjTxlg">A year or so later, five young men from that quorum went on missions. He was one of them. I was close to them all. I attended each of their farewells. They all served honorable missions. Within a brief time after returning home, they all were married in the temple. My wife and I attended each of the ceremonies. I could take a piece of paper, even today, and write their names and the names of their wives and some of their children. That is how well I knew them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p33" pid="O3zCk8FIWkC2Z9s_aNpRTw" hash="VPPaJA">But now let me tell you something—something very private and very important. I cannot remember the name of the young man who came to my home in the middle of the night. I know he was one of the five, but I don’t remember which one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p34" pid="pYHw3RW9zEG2SZINlTtWsA" hash="SjgkYQ">There was a time I used to worry about that. I thought perhaps my memory might be failing. I consciously tried to recall who it was that had the problem, but I could not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p35" pid="HQRUocE6XkKT_ZfGUXExpQ" hash="OaDMhQ">I was eventually released, and I put the entire incident out of my mind. On a late evening walk some years later, I found myself in the ward where I had once been bishop. The shadowy quiet brought back many memories. I was deep in thought when I realized I was walking in front of a house where one of my priests had lived years before. Suddenly, the story of the young man I have mentioned came to mind, and again I tried to remember which of the five he had been. Had he lived in that house? I wondered. Why couldn’t I remember?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p36" pid="TnWms3LQMk6yjF_vaPK-Gw" hash="_Y1BFA">As I continued on my way, something happened—something difficult to explain, but real to me. I seemed to hear a voice which said: “Don’t you understand, my son? I have forgotten that. Why should you remember?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p37" pid="CdIqfdts6kyJfuZer4-YWw" hash="1HEdYg">I was chagrined. There was no satisfactory answer to the question. I have never wondered about it again. And I knew more surely then than I had ever known before that the Lord is pleased when his children return to him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p38" pid="pmBSWz_Ec0OA-AOAnEmG_Q" hash="_8mkUg">All who are shepherds and all lost sheep should note this one last thing. The Lord really meant it when he said, “He who has repented of his sins, the same is forgiven, and I, the Lord, remember them no more” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:42</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p39" pid="wX-vZU8I9kKV4pU2qAbGTA" hash="QcYc-w">Some years ago it was fashionable in certain circles to use the phrase, “You can never go home again.” That is just simply not true. It is possible to return. It is possible for those who have ceased to pray, to pray again. It is possible for those who are lost to find their way through the dark and come home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord.p40" pid="EnD60xwpMkCqlncFB4xx_w" hash="Bnj0Pw">And when they do, they will know, as I know, that the Lord is more concerned with what a man is than with what he was, and with where he is than with where he has been. I so testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1986/10/come-back-to-the-lord</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1986-general-conference/1986-10-5050-elder-f-burton-howard-64k-eng.mp3" length="5992453" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 1986 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Repentance</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1991/04/repentance?lang=eng</link>
      <description>While you will not remember, the last time I stood at this pulpit I spoke about repentance. I have elected to do so again.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_91905_000_008" doc-version="2" hash="nwzc5g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="E9P6yYrohUa9PumkewUPYg" hash="aDChPA">Repentance</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="T3xcUzAf-Uet8LUpWpmxFg" hash="P7QfHg">F. Burton Howard</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1f0c.jpg" alt="Elder F. Burton Howard" pid="0vR9mZa9JEepDNdR4pWU8g" hash="Uk2uTw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p1" pid="7BeFB3Lmd0qkXCN5AzHzgg" hash="TpQs9Q">While you will not remember, the last time I stood at this pulpit I spoke about repentance. I have elected to do so again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p2" pid="axK-phxdOE6ifG0agU-fIQ" hash="kDEjZA">In a school yard game, young boys sometimes form a circle, and one hits another on the shoulder and says, “Pass it on.” The one who receives the blow obediently transmits it to the next in line and says, “Pass it on.” The third recipient promptly punches a fourth, and each in succession thereafter, by “passing it on,” tries to rid himself of his pain, and the responsibility for it, by inflicting it on another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p3" pid="SoOxO7JlKka2KFm69gpvXw" hash="FmxUjQ">Many of us are like these schoolboys. Perhaps without realizing it, as adults we continue to play the same childish game and risk far more than a bruised shoulder in the process. Let me explain what I mean.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p4" pid="n6_X6CdjvkWDdTkJEIcrwA" hash="Hdha4Q">Unwillingness to accept the responsibility for and consequences of one’s actions is an all too common condition in today’s world. Who has not heard of the drunken driver who sues his host for allowing him to get drunk, or of the accident victim who claims damages from the physician who tries to help him? Perpetrators of the most heinous crimes often plead guilty by reason of insanity or claim that they are victims of society’s ills. The homeless blame alcohol. Alcoholics blame genetic deficiencies. Abusers and adulterers blame the broken homes of their childhood. And there are enough who agree with them to ensure that no one need feel terribly guilty for long if they don’t want to.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p5" pid="O1mqt8Ny2UituNmO_BzBYw" hash="rt9XKg">The habit of shifting the burden of guilt onto someone else, while perhaps understandable in a secular setting, has more serious consequences in a spiritual one. There too it has an ancient but not honorable tradition.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p6" pid="4TCWmkMGgkidOfssMh2vpQ" hash="NmCXuw">Cain blamed God when his sacrifice was not accepted. “I was wroth,” he said, “for his offering thou didst accept and not mine.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/5.38" class="scriptureRef">Moses 5:38</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p7" pid="uZLydAZ5AE-ZqRuKuNNMFA" hash="nqbrqw">Laman and Lemuel blamed Nephi for nearly all their troubles. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/16.35-38" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 16:35–38</a>.) Pilate blamed the Jews when he condoned the crucifixion of the Savior, in whom he found “no fault.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/23.4" class="scriptureRef">Luke 23:4</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/27.24" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 27:24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p8" pid="bWqZcpWrHU2WQiZmQCxClg" hash="wJfevg">Even the very elite have sometimes succumbed to the temptation to blame others for their disobedience or their failure to receive blessings. Aaron blamed the children of Israel when Moses charged him with bringing a great sin upon them by making a molten calf. (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/32.19-24" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 32:19–24</a>.) And Martha may have blamed Mary for depriving her of the Savior’s presence on that indelible day in Bethany. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.40" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:40</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p9" pid="jh4FEePR0U2CeXQCch8Zsw" hash="qPjdMA">Today the practice continues. We hear at every hand phrases such as “My wife just doesn’t understand me,” “Loosen up—everybody does it,” or “It wasn’t really my fault.” The second great commandment (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.35-40" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:35–40</a>) is breached routinely by those who say, “He started it” or “She deserved it.” Teens and adults alike jokingly attempt to justify behavioral lapses by saying, “The devil made me do it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p10" pid="tWYBRj0JsEWGoA86uVnT0A" hash="3JkQgQ">When faced with the consequences of transgression, rather than looking to ourselves as the source of the discomfort which always accompanies sin, many of us tend to blame someone else. Rather than getting out of a vicious and senseless circle, we fault our neighbor for our pain and try to pass it on. But to repent we must leave the circle.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p11" pid="DXsmNXiwVE64t72v1lDSHw" hash="iNss9g">The first step in the repentance process has always been simply to recognize that we have done wrong. If we are so hedged about by pride, rationalization, machismo, or a misdirected sense of self-esteem as to prevent us from ever admitting that we are part of the problem, we are in trouble. We then may not even know of our need to repent. We will have no idea whether the Lord is pleased with us or not and may become “past feeling.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.45" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:45</a>.) But all men, everywhere, must repent. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.32" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:32</a>.) To fail to do so is to perish. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/13.3" class="scriptureRef">Luke 13:3</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/7.28" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 7:28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p12" pid="ZaxJCU3h_UuD1OIh6L87zA" hash="BE2EtA">To excuse misconduct by blaming others is presumptuous at best and is fatally flawed with regard to spiritual things, for “we believe that men will be punished for their own sins, and not for Adam’s transgression.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/a-of-f/1.2" class="scriptureRef">A of F 1:2</a>.) This not only means that we will not be punished for what Adam did in the Garden, but also that we cannot excuse our own behavior by pointing a finger to Adam or anyone else. The real danger in failing to accept responsibility for our own actions is that unless we do, we may never even enter on the strait and narrow path. Misconduct that does not require repentance may be pleasant at first, but it will not be for long. And it will never lead us to eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p13" pid="mbwA9KmEEECQsd1XM-5_MA" hash="xJOEcw">Just as foolish as believing that we can “pass it on” is the idea that the satisfaction of being in the circle, whatever that may be, can somehow excuse any wrongs committed there. This notion is widely shared and is most often expressed by the phrase, “The end justifies the means.” Such a belief, if left undisturbed and unchecked, can also impede the repentance process and cheat us out of exaltation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p14" pid="YkMSxhaZ5EeVevfsxOo4vw" hash="8PUuWQ">Those who teach it are almost always attempting to excuse the use of improper or questionable means. Such people seem to be saying, “My purpose was to do good or to be happy; therefore, any little lie, or misrepresentation, or lapse of integrity, or violation of law along the way is justified.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p15" pid="Kef95zE3kEKyt23dk9UlIQ" hash="HwBowA">In certain circumstances, some say it is “okay” to conceal the truth, to dig just a small pit for an adversary, to pursue an advantage of some kind—such as superior knowledge or position—against another. “This is just common practice,” or “I’m just looking after Number One,” they say. “All’s fair in love and war,” or “That’s the way the ball bounces,” they say. But if the means which prompt the saying of these things are wrong, no amount of rationalization or verbal whitewash can ever make them right.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p16" pid="Q7TxDxgNNUGXgcgfyZZwFw" hash="scGAtg">To those who believe otherwise, Nephi said: “Yea, and there shall be many which shall teach after this manner, false and vain and foolish doctrines, and shall be puffed up in their hearts, and shall seek deep to hide their counsels from the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/28.9" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 28:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p17" pid="Bo1DhKlpKkCyS7kL5rbE8A" hash="QPV7gw">Some seek to justify their actions by quoting scripture. They often cite Nephi’s killing of Laban as an example of the need to violate a law to accomplish a greater good and to prevent a nation from dwindling in unbelief. But they forget that Nephi twice refused to follow the promptings of the Spirit. In the end, he agreed to break the commandment only when he was convinced that “the <span class="emphasis">Lord</span> slayeth the wicked to bring forth <span class="emphasis">his</span> righteous purposes” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/4.13" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 4:13</a>; italics added) and also (I believe) when he knew that the penalty for shedding blood had been lifted, in that one exceptional case, by Him whose right it is to fix and waive penalties.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p18" pid="x6Kq9Zgb9kK2-ZaxBwz2vg" hash="B4HYPQ">The truth is that we are judged by the means we employ and not by the ends we may hope to obtain. It will do us little good at the last day to respond to the Great Judge, “I know I was not all I could have been, but my heart was in the right place.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p19" pid="jyTU156z-E6XRJrUC_Urww" hash="9eoENA">In fact, there is danger in focusing merely on ends. To some who did, the Savior said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p20" pid="6jxIQ0JStUasS7yRBWu-kg" hash="pU5iWg">“Many will say to me in that day: Lord, Lord, have we not prophesied in thy name, and in thy name have cast out devils, and in thy name done many wonderful works?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p21" pid="LT3oH7-B6keYAvYot4vwGw" hash="_ET8-g">“And then will I profess unto them: I never knew you; depart from me, ye that work iniquity.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/14.22-23" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 14:22–23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p22" pid="E0EoViaPcEiNT2ed9c1ljg" hash="N1Od_Q">The war in heaven was essentially about the means by which the plan of salvation would be implemented. It forever established the principle that even for the greatest of all ends, eternal life, the means are critical. It should be obvious to all thinking Latter-day Saints that the wrong means can never attain that objective.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p23" pid="dXDPZg_o30mCp-AvcOiwHg" hash="hbMOgw">The danger in thinking that the end justifies the means lies in making a judgment we have no right to make. Who are we to say that the Lord will pardon wickedness done to attain a perceived “greater good.” Even if the goal is good, it would be a personal calamity to look beyond the mark and fail to repent of the wrong we do along the way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p24" pid="dtdYL2ERd0iQje86AAoNMA" hash="mHRGbQ">Of course we have the right to strive for happiness. But as we do we should pause every now and then and look to ourselves. We should remember that “wickedness never was happiness.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/41.10" class="scriptureRef">Alma 41:10</a>.) And the sweet peace the gospel brings never comes at all when we justify our misconduct or blame others for our unhappiness. But there is a way out. We need only remember a pointless, irresponsible childhood game, and quietly walk away. Face up, quit, get out, confess, apologize, admit the harm we have done, and just plain walk away.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p25" pid="Pai9CzV9qUGS6oCmFDy58g" hash="VzaAQg">There are so many important things for us to do in mortality. There is not much time to waste on games. We must obtain essential ordinances. We must enter into and keep sacred covenants. We are to “live by every word which proceedeth forth out of the mouth of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/98.11" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 98:11</a>.) We must love and serve one another. We are to be proved in all things. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/98.14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 98:14</a>.) Even little things like means. There will be trials. There will likely be other circles we will have to leave. How we respond to all of this will turn out to be the real measure of our salvation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p26" pid="2TqAlcRx40eErWvyv0a5QQ" hash="inmM2g">So to those, including myself, who from time to time have said, “I am not at fault—I was compelled by circumstances to do what I did,” I say, “That may be so, but there is grave danger here. If there is any doubt at all, let us simply repent.” For, in the words of Job, “If I justify myself, mine own mouth shall condemn me: if I say, I am perfect, it shall also prove me perverse.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/job/9.20" class="scriptureRef">Job 9:20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p27" pid="Y4KyNp7pd0abLFM8Z8j-sQ" hash="FeTWoA">And to those who say, “I may have done a little wrong, but my purpose was good and I believe God will justify my behavior,” my response is, “Maybe so, but don’t count on it.” For in the 137th section of the Doctrine and Covenants, verse 9, we read:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p28" pid="TrQ8Ix3PcEuNd0aGqzOZRA" hash="M303WQ">“For I, the Lord, will judge all men according to their works, according to the desire of their hearts.” [<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/137.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 137:9</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/repentance.p29" pid="-4gb4BXYwkySCo23WjRoRQ" hash="R4EpkA">May the Lord bless us to see ourselves as we really are and to repent as needs be, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1991/04/repentance</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1991-general-conference/1991-04-1060-elder-f-burton-howard-64k-eng.mp3" length="5502434" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 1991 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commitment</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1996/04/commitment?lang=eng</link>
      <description>When my wife and I were first married, my parents lived in another state. During a break in our university schedule, we decided to go visit them.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_96905_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="PZ9EBw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="UMFScFy0nUeO2PlWiKBSKA" hash="lOIoBg">Commitment</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="hINiVWtsjkWSpx6ZXcx33w" hash="P7QfHg">F. Burton Howard</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1f0c.jpg" alt="Elder F. Burton Howard" pid="pWCSvazptE-9vTQfdBKxzA" hash="Uk2uTw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p1" pid="GmB44EzXQEyofSeEemXNMQ" hash="wlvGZQ">When my wife and I were first married, my parents lived in another state. During a break in our university schedule, we decided to go visit them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p2" pid="lTN60ZWsU0eAKHiRqmyIMw" hash="xc-1tw">We made sandwiches, packed the car, prepared a bed in the backseat for our young son so that he could rest during the 10-hour trip. After a full day in the car, we were beginning to get on each other’s nerves. The preschooler never slept and seemed to gather energy as the day wore on. We knew that if he would just close his eyes and be quiet for a while, he would fall asleep.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p3" pid="GvTbUfwdFkaDB_onHMoNrw" hash="TXHDbA">After sundown, with two hours of travel still to go, we decided to play a game. The purpose of the game was to try to get an exhausted youngster to sleep. We called it hide-and-seek. Have you ever tried to play hide-and-seek in a car? Let me tell you how we did it. We said to the small boy in back, “Let’s play hide-and-seek.” He enthusiastically agreed. We said, “Close your eyes and don’t open them until we call you. We need time to hide.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p4" pid="4qm8YjbA8U-ec1l_7joUaw" hash="hlTOAw">The game started. A front-seat passenger would crouch down in the seat and 10 or 15 seconds later would call, “OK.” Our son would bound over the seat and say, “Aha, I found you!” We would say, “Next time we will hide better. Close your eyes again.” A minute or more would go by. Then we would call, and again he would energetically climb over the seat to find us. Finally we said, “We have a really good place to hide this time. It will take longer. Close your eyes and we will call you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p5" pid="aRtkY0xT9k68-lS8UGoUpg" hash="cPJIxQ">A minute, two minutes, five minutes went by. We drove along in silence. The tranquillity was marvelous. We must have traveled 15 miles before we began to whisper quiet congratulations to ourselves on the success of our devious game. Then, from out of the backseat, came the sobbing voice of a heartbroken little boy. “You didn’t call me, and you said you would.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p6" pid="PWbDezHMsU6f-MgHKSMKzg" hash="rpNoXg">“You didn’t do what you agreed to do.” What a terrible accusation. It was a defining moment in our lives. We knew that we could never play that game again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p7" pid="Hvh61iQePUqnE1gEPXZJaw" hash="bpsq3g">Church members commit to do many things. We agree to serve one another, to mourn with those that mourn, to comfort those that stand in need of comfort. We promise to visit each other. We make covenants. We agree to share the gospel and do vicarious work for the dead. And just like that incident in the car so many years ago, we sometimes fail to do what we have agreed to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p8" pid="srjwV_ajx0ih_y8yVMSXAQ" hash="VOfotQ">Our justifications are many. We say we will do it later. We have something more important to do right now. We don’t feel well or we don’t feel qualified or we don’t want to be fanatical about it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p9" pid="tJ1dyu_i30aiQGe8ILobvw" hash="cg4JqA">When I think of those who want to postpone performance until another time, I remember a question someone once asked at a stake conference. A man said, “Brother Howard, do you know why we can never get more than 83 percent home teaching in the Church?” I said, “No, why?” He said, “Because no one wants to go on Halloween and New Year’s Eve.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p10" pid="CQf3JJwFVUqrxYTigYE_6w" hash="sVReiA">When I hear someone say they can’t serve because they don’t feel well, I remember a stake I once visited in Mexico. The stake president spoke about a lesson he learned from his wife. He said that a week before the conference, he had scheduled some home teaching visits but came home from work and didn’t feel well. He told his wife that he guessed he wouldn’t go home teaching because he was sick. Her reply to him was, “Go sick!” And he went.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p11" pid="n5vlDSyhNkGMCx1pptsfHA" hash="j_8JDQ">I once talked with a man who said, “I know I could do a little more, but no one wants to be a fanatic.” His statement reminded me of a definition I heard once: “A fanatic is a person who does what he thinks the Lord would do if only He had all the facts.” But He who really does know all things isn’t a fanatic; neither are those who do what He would have them do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p12" pid="cuDWGxFGUkKdSKhEAYGEjQ" hash="oyC_Jg">When I listen to people say they have something more important to do, I wonder what it could possibly be. What could be more important than keeping a commitment we have made with the Lord?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p13" pid="7n7TQBVO30W_RKaOOg2sEw" hash="_y19eA">As I travel the Church I often ask stake presidents what their concerns are and what they perceive to be their greatest need. Frequently the reply is, “We have wonderful people. Some of them just need to be more committed and more dedicated. They need to be more anxiously engaged in the work.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p14" pid="vdqPI4E6C0qkUQwjzAEJZA" hash="l26F3A">The Church does have many needs, and one of them is for more people who will just do what they have agreed to do, people who will show up for work and stay all day, who will quietly, patiently, and consistently do what they have agreed to do—for as long as it takes, and who will not stop until they have finished.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p15" pid="SEcAZQhFy0SrNCVoKvKbbg" hash="RRuAsw">One of my heroes has always been the servant of Abraham who was sent to find a wife for Isaac. We do not know his name. We do not know much about his life, but we know a great deal about his character. It was he who governed everything that Abraham had. He was trustworthy and he was trusted. The day came when Abraham put into the care of this servant the most important matter of all—the exaltation of his son.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p16" pid="yo7IzqvxqUqh1qgL2rL5pg" hash="XIH46w">He wanted Isaac to be an heir of the covenant which he had made with the Lord. He knew that the blessings of that covenant could not be realized if Isaac didn’t marry a good and worthy woman who believed in God. No woman in the land of Canaan was capable of being the mother of Israel. So Abraham asked his servant to promise that he would not permit his son to marry a Canaanite. Instead Abraham sent him to the land of his fathers to find a wife for Isaac.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p17" pid="7n3ytacJAUWpNvZpP0lHhA" hash="g_ufig">The servant accepted the commitment and set out on his journey. He traveled many days. He must have encountered trials and hardships. When he finally arrived at his destination, he found many young women there. He devised a test to see which of them was foreordained to be Isaac’s wife. By exercising his faith, he met Rebekah and arrived at the home of her family and was befriended by them. They invited him to dinner. After days in the desert, and despite his hunger and thirst, this faithful servant said, “I will not eat, until I have told mine errand” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/24.33" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 24:33</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p18" pid="SfnVaj6QY0KKcfqyK6zS6A" hash="QX2RWw">So it was. He explained the purpose of his journey and his oath to Abraham. One simple statement conveyed his faithfulness and humility. “I am Abraham’s servant,” he said (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/24.34" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 24:34</a>). The kinsfolk wanted a 10-day celebration. The servant replied, “Hinder me not, seeing the Lord hath prospered my way; send me away that I may go to my master” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/24.56" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 24:56</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p19" pid="xEAxfozhEE-kMgPbRaQt8Q" hash="Vyz8Jw">Many would have tarried. Others would have justified unwinding a little by saying that the journey had been long or that they were tired or hungry or thirsty. Some, not wanting to appear too zealous, would have stayed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p20" pid="81k7zv2KjEWqFCCDcKXrmw" hash="_L5Fig">A few, not understanding the significance of the errand, might have tried to talk Abraham out of the assignment, claiming that it was foolishness to travel so far in search of a wife. Some would not have had the faith necessary to discover which of all of the young women of the city was the chosen one. Yet this servant did. He knew how to magnify his calling and accomplish that which he had promised his master. He understood a very important truth. Promises are not just pretty words. Promises have eternal consequences.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p21" pid="yd2_wipzPEGr0ZfqeezwIA" hash="JMYynQ">We are a covenant people. If there is a distinguishing feature about members of the Church, it is that we make covenants. We need to be known as a covenant-<span class="emphasis">keeping</span> people as well. Making promises is easy, but to follow through and do what we have promised is another matter. That involves staying the course, being constant and steadfast. It means keeping the faith and being faithful to the end despite success or failure, doubt or discouragement. It is drawing near to the Lord with all our hearts. It is doing whatever we promise to do with all our might—even when we might not feel like it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p22" pid="jj-EF9LrbEKAITRZz8r9AA" hash="U5Hzaw">I once attended a funeral service with Elder M. Russell Ballard. A statement he made there has remained with me to this day. He said, “Life isn’t over for a Latter-day Saint until he or she is safely dead, with their testimony still burning brightly.” “Safely dead”—what a challenging concept. Brothers and sisters, we will not be safe until we have given our hearts to the Lord—until we have learned to do what we have promised.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/commitment.p23" pid="YTKKBxZHCkmDGts3OdPw7w" hash="7BVC1A">May we do so is my prayer in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1996/04/commitment</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1996-general-conference/1996-04-2060-elder-f-burton-howard-64k-eng.mp3" length="4929296" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 1996 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eternal Marriage</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage?lang=eng</link>
      <description>If you want something to last forever, you treat it differently. … It becomes special because you have made it so.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030371_000_034" doc-version="2" hash="KC2n4g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="AAagiFqlP0-XOMmkMms0PQ" hash="Ju6NEw">Eternal Marriage</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="AiiQE6PfxE-FuE5cilWA6w" hash="P7QfHg">F. Burton Howard</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="4gDbcGIbGEeXrHBqnPg6Ig" hash="XPqrew">If you want something to last forever, you treat it differently. … It becomes special because you have made it so.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-aa1.jpg" alt="Elder F. Burton Howard" pid="RVy2mtxN0Umed5xtaZ-kSQ" hash="zJ_L_w" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p1" pid="JBuDGEueFE2iDKvPtWe9bA" hash="wn5aRA">A number of years ago my wife and I went to a garden wedding reception. Earlier that day we had been to the temple, where two young people we knew had been married for time and all eternity. They were much in love. The circumstances of their meeting had been almost miraculous. Many tears of happiness were shed. We stood in the reception line at the end of a perfect day. Ahead of us was a close friend of the family. As he approached the couple, he stopped and in a beautiful, clear tenor voice sang to them the stirring words from the book of Ruth: “Whither thou goest, I will go; and where thou lodgest, I will lodge: thy people shall be my people, and thy God my God: Where thou diest, will I die” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ruth/1.16-17" class="scriptureRef">Ruth 1:16–17</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p2" pid="Ag6uU18QTkOjlNrCUsi8bQ" hash="JXAHvQ">We were deeply touched and felt reassured about their prospects for happiness—this in part, I suppose, because my wife and I have had these same words on the wall of our home for many years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p3" pid="k4kzbdiX80-hNV7AI6i6mw" hash="vDeNdw">Sadly, the significance of these beautiful words is subsiding. Far too many marriages today end in divorce. Selfishness, sin, and personal convenience often prevail over covenants and commitment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p4" pid="BbdZigKOOkCpeIC9g-Vi7A" hash="Ii-qKg">Eternal marriage is a principle which was established before the foundation of the world and was instituted on this earth before death came into it. Adam and Eve were given to each other by God in the Garden of Eden before the Fall. The scripture says, “In the day that God created man, in the likeness of God made he him; Male and female created he them; and <span class="emphasis">blessed</span> them” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/5.1-2" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 5:1–2</a>; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p5" pid="aBC6KR3bpkOKXv3npEU6Ow" hash="2xktGQ">The prophets have uniformly taught that the consummate and culminating element of God’s great plan for the blessing of His children is eternal marriage. President Ezra Taft Benson stated, “Faithfulness to the marriage covenant brings the fullest joy here and glorious rewards hereafter” (<span class="emphasis">The Teachings of Ezra Taft Benson</span> [1988], 533–34). President Howard W. Hunter described celestial marriage as “the crowning gospel ordinance” and clarified that “while it might take somewhat longer [for some,] perhaps even beyond this mortal life,” it would not be denied to any worthy individual (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of Howard W. Hunter,</span> ed. Clyde J. Williams [1997], 132, 140). President Gordon B. Hinckley has called eternal marriage a wonderful thing (see “What God Hath Joined Together,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1991, 71) and a “gift, precious beyond all others” (“The Marriage That Endures,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1974, 23).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p6" pid="C3L-tJG3rkOiEmuaGevfAA" hash="DH7G1w">However, notwithstanding the grandeur and glory of the gift, it is not free. In fact it is conditional, and having been given, it may be withdrawn if we do not keep the conditions of the covenant which accompanies it. Section 131 of the Doctrine and Covenants tells us that “in the celestial glory there are three heavens or degrees; And in order to obtain the highest, a man [that means a woman too] must enter into this order of the priesthood [meaning the new and everlasting covenant of marriage]” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/131.1-2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 131:1–2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p7" pid="pRggbq9WRkule_zhotc0cQ" hash="vJk74g">A covenant is a sacred promise. We promise to do some things, and God binds Himself to do others. To those who keep the covenant of marriage, God promises the fulness of His glory, eternal lives, eternal increase, exaltation in the celestial kingdom, and a fulness of joy. We all know that, but sometimes we don’t give much thought to what <span class="emphasis">we</span> have to do to receive these blessings. The scriptures seem to clearly say that at least three obligations are inherent in this covenant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p8" pid="vB8owBaoZkOX1SB3OA08qg" hash="aZjjqA">First, an eternal marriage is eternal. <span class="emphasis">Eternal</span> implies continuing growth and improvement. It means that man and wife will honestly try to perfect themselves. It means that the marriage relationship is not to be frivolously discarded at the first sign of disagreement or when times get hard. It signifies that love will grow stronger with time and that it extends beyond the grave. It means that each partner will be blessed with the company of the other partner forever and that problems and differences might as well be resolved because they are not going to go away. <span class="emphasis">Eternal</span> signifies repentance, forgiveness, long-suffering, patience, hope, charity, love, and humility. All of these things are involved in anything that is eternal, and surely we must learn and practice them if we intend to claim an eternal marriage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p9" pid="AJlG4b3fPESuegi3ER_VxA" hash="KL3M_Q">Second, an eternal marriage is ordained of God. This means that the parties to the marriage covenant agree to invite God into their marriage, to pray together, to keep the commandments, to keep wants and passions within certain limits that the prophets have outlined. It means to be equal companions and to be just as true and pure outside the home as inside the home. That is part of what <span class="emphasis">ordained of God</span> means.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p10" pid="YjngWEIWPUeBK9S4dl1tyw" hash="Kj3zqg">Third, eternal marriage is a kind of partnership with God. He promises a continuation of lives to those who are sealed together in the temple. There is a oneness with the Creator implied in the commandment given to Adam and Eve to multiply and replenish the earth. There is an obligation to teach children the gospel, for they are His children too. Thus we have family home evening and scripture study, gospel conversations, and service to others. There would seem to be an obligation to support and sustain each other in callings and roles that each is given to perform. How can we claim to be one with God if we cannot sustain one another when the wife is called to serve in the Primary or the husband in the bishopric?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p11" pid="AU1Aok9G-Ee_t44ZiOk3gw" hash="4hioJg">So the covenant of marriage implies at least these things and probably others. I may miss the mark, but I don’t think by far, when I say that those who verbally or physically abuse their wives or husbands or those who degrade or demean or exercise unrighteous dominion in a marriage are not keeping the covenant. Nor are those who neglect the commandments or who fail to sustain their leaders. Even those who merely decline callings, neglect neighbors, or moderately adopt worldly ways are at risk. If we are not keeping our part of the covenant, we have no promise.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p12" pid="29s1at7NskyojJaBxW05PQ" hash="l2fvIg">Most of all, I think eternal marriage cannot be achieved without a commitment to make it work. Most of what I know about this I have learned from my companion. We have been married for almost 47 years now. From the beginning she knew what kind of marriage she wanted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p13" pid="2CCXw_e_b0qjqLPJvyC3QA" hash="X5dN-Q">We started as poor college students, but her vision for our marriage was exemplified by a set of silverware. As is common today, when we married she registered with a local department store. Instead of listing all the pots and pans and appliances we needed and hoped to receive, she chose another course. She asked for silverware. She chose a pattern and the number of place settings and listed knives, forks, and spoons on the wedding registry and nothing else. No towels, no toasters, no television—just knives, forks, and spoons.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p14" pid="4U3Uvi6-W0yP8zj_wJFQtQ" hash="Y_g4-A">The wedding came and went. Our friends and our parents’ friends gave gifts. We departed for a brief honeymoon and decided to open the presents when we returned. When we did so, we were shocked. There was not a single knife or fork in the lot. We joked about it and went on with our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p15" pid="SV0mCR8zmECu7LsGGNazCw" hash="IhCwpw">Two children came along while we were in law school. We had no money to spare. But when my wife worked as a part-time election judge or when someone gave her a few dollars for her birthday, she would quietly set it aside, and when she had enough she would go to town to buy a fork or a spoon. It took us several years to accumulate enough pieces to use them. When we finally had service for four, we began to invite some of our friends for dinner.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p16" pid="DsyL135v10231_2i7CsNjg" hash="sG8eYA">Before they came, we would have a little discussion in the kitchen. Which utensils would we use, the battered and mismatched stainless or the special silverware? In those early days I would often vote for the stainless. It was easier. You could just throw it in the dishwasher after the meal, and it took care of itself. The silver, on the other hand, was a lot of work. My wife had it hidden away under the bed where it could not be found easily by a burglar. She had insisted that I buy a tarnish-free cloth to wrap it in. Each piece was in a separate pocket, and it was no easy task to assemble all the pieces. When the silver was used, it had to be hand washed and dried so that it would not spot, and put back in the pockets so it would not tarnish, and wrapped up and carefully hidden again so it would not get stolen. If any tarnish was discovered, I was sent to buy silver polish, and together we carefully rubbed the stains away.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p17" pid="5rDr5BDYEkKwhIPTTw9N5g" hash="Tl7hPw">Over the years we added to the set, and I watched with amazement how she cared for the silver. My wife was never one to get angry easily. However, I remember the day when one of our children somehow got hold of one of the silver forks and wanted to use it to dig up the backyard. That attempt was met with a fiery glare and a warning not to even think about it. Ever!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p18" pid="ADzZDG1wY0y0yk0XI5hWrA" hash="Aj2pvg">I noticed that the silverware never went to the many ward dinners she cooked, or never accompanied the many meals she made and sent to others who were sick or needy. It never went on picnics and never went camping. In fact it never went anywhere; and, as time went by, it didn’t even come to the table very often. Some of our friends were weighed in the balance, found wanting, and didn’t even know it. They got the stainless when they came to dinner.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p19" pid="ro6ekejcjEGfhL-Sr_dkVg" hash="J2t0rQ">The time came when we were called to go on a mission. I arrived home one day and was told that I had to rent a safe-deposit box for the silver. She didn’t want to take it with us. She didn’t want to leave it behind. And she didn’t want to lose it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p20" pid="67Na8FYVY0CIi5fcJaVlYA" hash="88aiSQ">For years I thought she was just a little bit eccentric, and then one day I realized that she had known for a long time something that I was just beginning to understand. <span class="emphasis">If you want something to last forever, you treat it differently.</span> You shield it and protect it. You never abuse it. You don’t expose it to the elements. You don’t make it common or ordinary. If it ever becomes tarnished, you lovingly polish it until it gleams like new. It becomes special because you have made it so, and it grows more beautiful and precious as time goes by.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage.p21" pid="0f_wPVtS4kW_1nPDdX8Bvg" hash="wfOIKQ">Eternal marriage is just like that. We need to treat it just that way. I pray that we may see it for the priceless gift that it is, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2003/04/eternal-marriage</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2003-general-conference/2003-04-5050-elder-f-burton-howard-64k-eng.mp3" length="5802692" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2003 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
