<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Gary J. Coleman</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Gary J. Coleman.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Gary%20J.%20Coleman.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Gary J. Coleman.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Oct 1992 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 1992 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Jesus Christ Is at the Center of the Restoration of the Gospel</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My brothers in the gospel, I come before you this night to express the feelings of my heart. I want you young men to know that there are sure anchors for our life in these troubled times. There are rock-solid foundations upon which we can build to gu</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_92911_000_020" doc-version="2" hash="wwH9ng">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="GrdOyeG850eU06NRVY4wsA" hash="JYWWjA">Jesus Christ Is at the Center of the Restoration of the Gospel</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="mZj4FOzPAUqPHGXA8UsxSw" hash="qVb65A">Gary J. Coleman</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-244a.jpg" alt="Elder Gary J. Coleman" pid="ULtrZfvjP0m1McH7eUqGgQ" hash="4i9taw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p1" pid="SdEyacxygk609WmrJCJtHw" hash="HrdOBA">My brothers in the gospel, I come before you this night to express the feelings of my heart. I want you young men to know that there are sure anchors for our life in these troubled times. There are rock-solid foundations upon which we can build to guide us through the devastating storms of the latter days. Today we can enjoy the fulness of the gospel with careful attention to basic principles and practices. Living these concepts will aid our joyful completion of the course that leads to eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p2" pid="UAeiH1r4m0qrFmYh24O-3Q" hash="5SdCaQ">While a young man, I walked paths of life that were different from those taught in The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. I lived by a mingling of the doctrines and commandments of men, having a form of godliness but with a lack of God-given truths and the power thereof. Religion was a vital part of my life as a youth. A religious home was at the core of our family life. Yet something was missing; something fundamental about the purpose of life was clouded and uncertain. While in my young adult years I was fortunate enough to become acquainted with kind Latter-day Saints who opened new gospel doors to me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p3" pid="Fxlw8wBdRUmAcGIFXBlATg" hash="_zoXQw">The doctrines of the restoration of the gospel of Jesus Christ have become my path to eternal life and the fulness of joy here in mortality. Few things in life have become more dear to me than a knowledge of the reality of the Godhead. We are the literal spirit offspring of God the Father. The life and mission of His Only Begotten Son, Jesus Christ, affects my life daily. The influence of the Holy Ghost from day to day is a great comfort.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p4" pid="Wehb_SA_X0-wL3-bdLsGkg" hash="dB4-cQ">I came into this Church because God has revealed Himself to latter-day prophets and they have testified of His reality. Upon asking God if the things of this gospel are true, I have received a witness more powerful than sight, more soul-assuring than words. The sweet witness by the power of the Holy Ghost that the truths of the restored gospel are upon the earth today has come to me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p5" pid="I2rOXdJ88kCGT-2NiHFh5Q" hash="pzuc0g">It has been my profound blessing to become a convert to this Church and to know without a doubt of the divinity of Jesus Christ as the Son of God. This resurrected, perfected being stands at the head of this Church. It is He upon whom we must build. It is He who is the chief cornerstone of our foundation. He is the rock of our salvation, the rock upon which not only the Church will be built, but our personal testimonies as well. No man, yea, no other name under heaven will suffice for our foundation. The prophet Helaman spoke of this sacred foundation most powerfully when he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p6" pid="s4-Z3ZvolUCZJ0GepH7osw" hash="e9H30w">“And now, my sons, remember, remember that it is upon the rock of our Redeemer, who is Christ, the Son of God, that ye must build your foundation; that when the devil shall send forth his mighty winds, yea, his shafts in the whirlwind, yea, when all his hail and his mighty storm shall beat upon you, it shall have no power over you to drag you down to the gulf of misery and endless wo, because of the rock upon which ye are built, which is a sure foundation, a foundation whereon if men build they cannot fall” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/5.12" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 5:12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p7" pid="EPXlFV4oHU2WNwfSzoe7sQ" hash="yorYug">Not only must we build upon the sure foundation of Jesus Christ, but the prophet Jacob identified Him as the “safe foundation”! This stone, he said, shall be “the great, and the last, and the only sure foundation” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.15-16" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:15–16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p8" pid="4ZhI5BbRskWiSfjXEWWXtw" hash="LhkxzA">I agree with all the conviction of my being that Jacob’s testimony is true. When the Apostle Peter boldly declared of Jesus, “Thou art the Christ, the Son of the living God,” Jesus replied, “Blessed art thou, Simon Bar-jona: for flesh and blood hath not revealed it unto thee, but my Father which is in heaven” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/16.16-17" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 16:16–17</a>). Christ will be revealed to us through the same process that God used with Peter. Christ is always the rock upon which each of us must build, even the rock of revelation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p9" pid="ddYQrhIXDE6j1WPciVY2KQ" hash="HB_u3g">I have come into this Church because latter-day prophets have been called by God to do His work. I remember the year, the month, the day, and even the very moment when my heart encompassed the testimony that Joseph Smith was a prophet of God. He did the work of a prophet, and he was an instrument in the hands of God to make His will known on this earth again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p10" pid="qbtbxWj75E2Wd0ZZKCySEw" hash="rk58kA">God continues to raise up latter-day prophets, and I rejoice in the principle of continuous revelation for our day. I welcome the opportunity to sit at the feet of the First Presidency and the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles—men whom we sustain as prophets, seers, and revelators. Of these men, the Lord himself has said in our day, “What I the Lord have spoken, I have spoken, and I excuse not myself; and though the heavens and the earth pass away, my word shall not pass away, but shall all be fulfilled, whether by mine own voice or by the voice of my servants, it is the same” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:38</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p11" pid="D27Gdkug6UaCdUWMuSfWXA" hash="rVTKGw">As members of this Church we are, as the Apostle Paul testified, “No more strangers and foreigners, but fellowcitizens with the saints, and of the household of God; And are built upon the foundation of the apostles and prophets, Jesus Christ himself being the chief corner stone” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/2.19-20" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 2:19–20</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p12" pid="s8qcvElzDEKwzbTpfXXSTw" hash="4Frr7A">I rejoice exceedingly at the restoration of the books of scripture for our use and training today. Of course the Book of Mormon is true! It talks of Christ; it speaks of those who rejoice in Christ; it is full of preachings of Christ; it prophesies of Christ and testifies to us and our children as to the source of our remission of sins. Of course it is another testament of Jesus Christ! Of course God speaks to men in these latter days as He did in former days! It is a certainty that revelation is in constant operation in this Church!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p13" pid="TE7y6C-eeUa0mQ91qzLFvA" hash="nc17KQ">The authority of God upon this earth resides in the authorized priesthood holders of this Church. Without question, therefore, all the ordinances of salvation and eternal life are in this Church. That which is bound by true priesthood authority on earth is also bound in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p14" pid="9V6T4QTBdUWhnQm2WjRfhg" hash="DKBlsA">Yes, the Restoration has brought to earth again the true doctrines and ordinances of the gospel of Jesus Christ. The Restoration affects every fiber of our being. It consumes every part of our mortal journey. It keeps us focused on which path we should walk upon in our daily search for meaning to life. There truly is a strait and narrow path which leads to eternal life by following the Savior and the living prophets. <span class="emphasis">We must accept them as the inspired trainers for our race of life.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p15" pid="HYKUZo-kv0mDLPQHeP6dow" hash="anqY6w">“Wherefore,” the prophet Nephi says, “ye must press forward with a steadfastness in Christ, having a perfect brightness of hope, and a love of God and of all men. Wherefore, if ye shall press forward, feasting upon the word of Christ, and endure to the end, behold, thus saith the Father: Ye shall have eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p16" pid="knzZVhgOPU-Oq3jrYRO35w" hash="2Xt2tQ">“And now, behold, my beloved brethren, this is the way; and there is none other way nor name given under heaven whereby man can be saved in the kingdom of God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.20-21" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:20–21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p17" pid="XdxEoh2dD0G3OZgcwONNtw" hash="-1G9IQ">Part of our mortal training is to walk by faith, repent of our sins, and call upon the Lord in daily prayer. We rejoice in the moments when promptings by the Holy Ghost are kindly given, and we are urged along the proper path of life. But each of us faces many difficult times here in mortality. All sorts of voices are screaming at us from the stadiums of public opinion. Our course will never be the popular way of the world. There are obstacles strewn in our path upon which we may sprain an ankle or stub a toe. But we must keep going. We move on in the strength of the Lord, each accountable for our own performance at the end of our mortal race. We must be able to declare with Paul:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p18" pid="cogNJG26kUa60g340nv__w" hash="PYl1-g">“I have fought a good fight, I have finished my course, I have kept the faith:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p19" pid="D750lHfZd06Wwi6wgDIR1w" hash="CnfncA">“Henceforth there is laid up for me a crown of righteousness, which the Lord, the righteous judge, shall give me at that day: and not to me only, but unto all them also that love his appearing” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/4.7-8" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 4:7–8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel.p20" pid="DEa5LJ4DSkuL8mk08ThE4A" hash="9qm-PQ">I am so grateful for my eternal companion and for the second generation of Latter-day Saints in our family who have also taken up the cause of Christ. May God help all of us to partake of the fulness of the restoration of this sacred gospel, I pray humbly in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1992/10/jesus-christ-is-at-the-center-of-the-restoration-of-the-gospel</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1992-general-conference/1992-10-3030-elder-gary-j-coleman-64k-eng.mp3" length="4264627" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 1992 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Are You Still Here?”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I have learned from the scriptures and the living prophets that this life is the time to prepare ourselves to meet God and one day enjoy eternal life with Him.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10033256_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="12mvWQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="lo2Y9zAggUaNmTnYkCjmEw" hash="f-wNBQ">“Are You Still Here?”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="bTGhopxN_ECy0XwTLcZmjQ" hash="qVb65A">Gary J. Coleman</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="ToCl3ir92E26j-1I6weCVA" hash="9fhNGA">I have learned from the scriptures and the living prophets that this life is the time to prepare ourselves to meet God and one day enjoy eternal life with Him.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-e7f.jpg" alt="Elder Gary J. Coleman" pid="C2Da07R-OUySkxWfpEjLbQ" hash="x2FV0g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p1" pid="g4xKzwJ45UWB3U3xxWCyGw" hash="nEMohA">Now let us rejoice that we are here in a worship setting with living prophets who now walk the earth and see beyond the seen, hear heaven-inspired words above the din of the day, and know our God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p2" pid="23IBhIIAikm4gfuP1BGaQA" hash="ki162g">There is a divine plan. It is called the plan of our Heavenly Father.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p3" pid="AdkqkTKjJU6Gx-a_IGkPAg" hash="WFzXHw">We believe in God. We know that He lives and we can have faith in Him. The scriptures testify that we are the children of God, His literal spirit offspring.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> We lived with Him before we came to this earth. We are created in His image, and He is our Heavenly Father. Therefore, we are all brothers and sisters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p4" pid="VTyWNFaEfUqjG7XuSkUETw" hash="cIuA5g">Because our Heavenly Father loves us, He has prepared a plan for us as we live here in mortality. Before joining this Church, I remember my first experiences associated with this wonderful plan as I began to learn of the restored gospel. I became acquainted with latter-day scripture that teaches the importance of our premortal training in the spirit world and indicates that we received many lessons there to prepare us for our time here on earth.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> I have learned from the scriptures and the living prophets that this life is the time to prepare ourselves to meet God and one day enjoy eternal life with Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> The prophet Jacob exclaimed while referring to this eternal plan, “O how great the plan of our God!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> I know that God lives and wants to help us return to live with Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p5" pid="GggxBEd0zkCOJKm2yEd8Xw" hash="ts72tQ">The great plan of God provided a Savior for us. All accountable persons sin and must pass through the experience of death at the end of our mortality. Therefore, God sent Jesus Christ to fulfill the plan by helping us overcome sin and death. Jesus is our Savior and Redeemer. Through His atoning sacrifice for each of us, He helps us overcome sin through repentance and baptism. Through His Resurrection, He makes it possible for everyone to overcome death and the grave. We have faith to follow Jesus and become more like Him. O how we love our Friend, the Lord Jesus Christ, the only “name under heaven … whereby [we] may be saved.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> I know that Jesus saves us from the effects of sin and death.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p6" pid="tZk1HdEyikajgZAF0isVBQ" hash="BkMMlg">We thank God for revealing His plan and the mission of Jesus through His chosen witnesses, the prophets and apostles. God gives these witnesses authority to act for Him. Their testimonies of the truths of the gospel are written in sacred books called scriptures. When people hear and read these teachings of the prophets, they can know they are true by the power of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p7" pid="sA426a81QECQJ8V7Pa6IiQ" hash="y-q5fA">Nearly 28 years ago I desired to attend a general conference of the Church and drove 14 hours to be in Salt Lake City for the conference. I entered Temple Square at 8:00 <small>A.M.</small>, where the line outside door number 10 was all the way across Temple Square and halfway down the south side of the Assembly Hall. I was nearly 300 feet from my goal. The usher called out that the Tabernacle was full. People dropped out of line, and I inched forward.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p8" pid="0NLY9nO1aE2pj0xCvyDErA" hash="QTo9WQ">At five minutes before 10:00 I was the only person standing in front of my chosen door. The door opened, and the usher said, “Are you still here?” He closed the door, and my heart sank. As the choir began to sing the opening hymn at 10:00 sharp, the door opened one more time, and the usher beckoned me inside. He placed me on half a seat and behind a post, but a welcome seat it was! I was able to sustain the Lord’s chosen leaders and hear their counsel that special day, just as we have done here this afternoon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p9" pid="GbxE5M-kTk-_keAat0tP2w" hash="txbVLQ">In our day, or the latter days, God has continued His pattern for revealing truth. He chose a young man named Joseph Smith to learn about the eternal plan of salvation. Joseph was confused about the different religions in his community, but the scriptures led him to ask God what he should do.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> In answer to his prayer, God the Father and Jesus Christ appeared to him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Through this and other experiences, Joseph Smith was called as a prophet, like unto Moses and other biblical prophets.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Because Joseph saw and talked with the Savior, his work was to restore the truth about the great plan of God and the divine mission of our Lord. I know that Joseph Smith is a prophet of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p10" pid="thcrvR4uUkeV6Tx2ZydKdw" hash="jpdGqA">The Prophet Joseph received authority to teach the gospel and bring forth additional scripture. He was commanded to translate writings of ancient prophets from The Book of Mormon: Another Testament of Jesus Christ. The Book of Mormon prophets also knew about the plan of salvation and the sacred mission of Jesus Christ. The appearance of the resurrected Christ to the ancient people of the Americas is recorded in this sacred book.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> He taught them His gospel and established His Church among them. I know that the Book of Mormon is another testament of the divinity of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p11" pid="qWauB6BVKUW8fVY-N5XiVQ" hash="3gwubQ">God has promised that the Holy Ghost will testify to each of us that sacred truths have been restored and that Joseph Smith was called by God to be a special witness of Christ and His gospel. We may come to know the truth of all things God has revealed, through the power of the Holy Ghost.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p12" pid="ikaYVsEkkEeuPeO82Sfc2w" hash="11_QHQ">Millions of converts to this Church initially accepted the truths proclaimed by our missionaries in the first discussion. They then opened their hearts to all the discussions taught by the missionaries. They were invited to be baptized, confirmed, become “fellowcitizens with the saints,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> and continue on the gospel path to additional sacred covenants made in the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p13" pid="QVdDtp_G2EW8zmH-aYqczg" hash="U5xagw">A young couple with four children who were neighbors to a Latter-day Saint family accepted invitations to share activities and gospel-centered experiences. After the first missionary discussion, the father asked his LDS friend next door, “Would it be possible for you to baptize us on New Year’s Eve? We would like to start the new year off right.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p14" pid="ZmnCFBnBCEC47VVaRqqjQw" hash="JiRr7w">A young adult was seen near an institute of religion building, and he was asked if he had LDS friends. He responded, “Yes, and they are all on missions for the Mormon Church!” He was invited to be taught the gospel. He joined the Church. And one year later he was serving his own mission for the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p15" pid="xZhhAKIDTE-_0mHP5hxmXg" hash="7d7ieQ">A wonderful mother and wife in a beautiful nonmember family was asked if her spouse and children would be together for the eternities. Her answer was, “Yes, we will, won’t we?” A few weeks later the mother, her husband, and the two oldest children were baptized because the answers to life’s questions are found in this, the true Church of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p16" pid="eJEGlkzGPkqL0FW_UDAaSw" hash="oObhdg">A nonmember father whose son was serving a mission was asked, “Will you be baptized on Father’s Day?” He was baptized, with four former bishops of his family in attendance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p17" pid="kQdWTJrHc0SsssfUJ_3aew" hash="2NzV-A">It is the power of the Spirit that convinces the investigator to pray about our message, to attend church, read the Book of Mormon, schedule further discussions, be baptized into the Lord’s Church, and continue to be “nourished by the good word of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> We invite all people to come unto Christ through the door of faith, repentance, baptism, and receiving the gift of the Holy Ghost. This is the door to eternal life. The Holy Ghost will help all of us stay on the path to God’s presence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p18" pid="zvG_gM49yEGWmkDjHdjBWA" hash="dnlS7Q">Promptings from the Holy Ghost will also guide us to others who seek the true gospel. The Lord has said, “I will be with you; and in whatsoever place ye shall proclaim my name an effectual door shall be opened unto you, that they may receive my word.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p19" pid="bQ33pQx6T0GLC65R0HXWRg" hash="3XOh6A">A few years ago I drove to Temple Square in Salt Lake City to meet an acquaintance of the missionaries. Their guest did not keep the appointment. My response to the missionaries was, “The Lord will provide someone for us to teach.” In less than two to three minutes, two adult men walked through the front door of the North Visitors’ Center and directly up to us. They spoke Spanish, and we did not! We assured them the best we could that someone would be able to help them. In moments, the only Spanish-speaking sister missionaries in the entire mission arrived at the visitors’ center because they felt impressed to come there that morning!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p20" pid="FDWuYmufZ0SPoXFWuKqnlg" hash="y0l8nw">Over a period of several weeks the missionary discussions were taught to those men, and they asked to be baptized. The Lord was true to His word. “An effectual door” was opened in the very moment it was needed for this beautiful experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p21" pid="-TwC7yH_OkWRaknmQgE9uA" hash="HszvkQ">We invite all who have been baptized and perhaps drifted away from the Lord to come back and renew your covenants with Him. With Jesus we say to all Israel, “Come home.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> Come home to the truths and ordinances of eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here.p22" pid="e9IfIJfQzE6ztZUt0dpGgQ" hash="7xJjEQ">Before I was a member of this Church, I asked God, the Eternal Father, in fervent prayer, about the truths of the Restoration. I know today, even as I knew that day, that hour, that moment 37 years ago, by the power of the Holy Ghost, that the principles and doctrines of the restoration of the gospel are true. God lives. Jesus is the Christ. Joseph Smith was the prophet of the Restoration of the true gospel. The Book of Mormon is a record of holy prophets and another testament of the living Christ, who stands at the head of this Church. President Gordon B. Hinckley is the Lord’s prophet for our day. He and 14 other Apostles are special witnesses of Christ in the only true Church on the earth. I pray that all of us will be able to answer the question “Are you still here?” and enter through the proper door to all the blessings of the gospel, now and forever. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2000/04/are-you-still-here</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2000-general-conference/2000-04-2070-elder-gary-j-coleman-64k-eng.mp3" length="5418605" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Mom, Are We Christians?”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/04/mom-are-we-christians?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I am a devout Christian who is exceedingly fortunate to have greater knowledge of the true “doctrine of Christ” since my conversion to the restored Church.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/mom-are-we-christians" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008333_000_035" doc-version="2" hash="kovvDg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/mom-are-we-christians.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="6b4-l2fzkUCvXsGxQLauZg" hash="aKGo0w">“Mom, Are We Christians?”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="b8Xj5Zjxek6fBR2w52lcMw" hash="qVb65A">Gary J. Coleman</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="of7Tb02zEUifc7m5LPln-g" hash="4BIoZg">I am a devout Christian who is exceedingly fortunate to have greater knowledge of the true “doctrine of Christ” since my conversion to the restored Church.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/mom-are-we-christians.t1">
      <img src="ColemanGJ_all.ob.jpg" alt="Elder Gary J. Coleman" pid="Ntp5TvxXbEOSYeYqFBDBJQ" hash="2gNLKw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/mom-are-we-christians.p1" pid="tAKdNlDVbUKnRyEKXoH8MQ" hash="EIfM0w">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="92"></span>Christianity celebrates the life and ministry of Jesus Christ, the Only Begotten Son of God the Eternal Father. Christian churches with great variations of doctrine dot the land the world over. When 14-year-old Cortnee, a daughter of a mission president, entered a new high school as a freshman, she was asked by classmates if she was a Christian. They scoffed at her response that she was a Mormon, a common reference to The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. Upon arriving home she asked her mother, “Mom, are we Christians?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/mom-are-we-christians.p2" pid="c4UBUIrT-UOjPjdx3vTpWg" hash="kRFkqw">Growing up in my family, we lived as devout members of another Christian faith. I was baptized a member of that church shortly after my birth. Our family went to church each week. For many years my brothers and I assisted the pastors who conducted our Sunday services. I was taught the importance of family prayer as our family prayed together each day. I thought that someday I would enter the full-time ministry in my church. There was no question in our minds that we could define ourselves as devout Christians.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/mom-are-we-christians.p3" pid="9t06SVwe60imEnTsg-Snjg" hash="ErHE1Q">When I was a university student, however, I became acquainted with the members and teachings of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, a Christian faith centered on the Savior. I began to learn about the doctrine of the Restoration of the gospel of Jesus Christ in these latter days. I learned truths that I had not known before that changed my life and how I viewed the gospel. After much studying, prayer, and faith, I chose to embrace beautiful restored truths found only in this Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/mom-are-we-christians.p4" pid="AHmTDy_4akmMQrIR0U_NAQ" hash="4nhS2w">The first restored truth that I learned was the nature of the Godhead. The true Christian doctrine that the Godhead consists of three separate beings was known in biblical times. God bore witness of Jesus, His Only Begotten Son, on several occasions. He spoke at Jesus’s baptism: “This is my beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Jesus Himself testified of God, His Father, when He said, “And this is life eternal, that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> After Jesus’s death and Resurrection, we learn that Stephen, “he, being full of the Holy Ghost, looked up stedfastly into heaven, and saw the glory of God, and Jesus standing on the right hand of God, and said, Behold, I see the heavens opened, and the Son of man standing on the right hand of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> What a dramatic testimony of the Godhead from that disciple of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/mom-are-we-christians.p5" pid="mWq4mkzYvk6Ey9Yyl7yTtA" hash="uYUQEg">The knowledge of God and His physical separateness from His Son and the Holy Ghost was lost after the death of Christ and His Apostles. Confusion and false doctrines about the Godhead were fashioned out of the Nicene Creed and Constantinople councils, where men declared that instead of three separate beings, the Godhead was three persons in one God, or the Trinity. Just as Christian Protestant reformers struggled with these creeds of men, I did as well. The teachings about the Trinity that <span class="pageBreak" page-number="93"></span>I learned in my youth were incomprehensible to me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/mom-are-we-christians.p6" pid="X3-BwFpkqkWK1m_wSoMNxw" hash="K-bxwg">However, when I was introduced to the glorious truths of the First Vision experienced by the Prophet Joseph Smith, it was a stunning awakening for me to finally understand the truth about the nature of God the Eternal Father and His Only Begotten Son. Joseph declared: “I saw two Personages, whose brightness and glory defy all description, standing above me in the air. One of them spake unto me, calling me by name and said, pointing to the other—<span class="emphasis">This is My Beloved Son. Hear Him!</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> This heavenly vision restored the wondrous yet plain and precious knowledge of God and His Son to the earth again, dispelling at once the teachings I had learned about the Trinity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/mom-are-we-christians.p7" pid="EiBcbhzFuEilStlQ8JrAGw" hash="u6ZU8A">I know that heaven-sent revelations have replaced the gross errors of man-made doctrines concerning the Godhead. I know that God is our Heavenly Father. His Son, Jesus Christ, is my Savior. The Holy Ghost testifies of the Father and the Son. I express my profound gratitude to God for introducing the resurrected Lord Jesus Christ to mankind in these last days. The Savior lives; He has been seen; He has spoken; He directs the work of His Church through apostles and prophets today. What magnificent truths He has taught as the Good Shepherd who continues to look after His sheep.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/mom-are-we-christians.p8" pid="82qvSDlZPk-4z6SQrnrA0Q" hash="DUkbJg">The second restored truth I learned as an investigator of this Church was the reality of additional scripture and revelation. The prophet Isaiah saw in vision a book that he proclaimed was part of “a marvellous work and a wonder.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> I testify that the Book of Mormon: Another Testament of Jesus Christ is that book. It is a sacred record written by prophets of God to persuade all people to come unto Christ, and it helps to reveal the gospel of Jesus Christ in its fulness. The Book of Mormon tells of prophets and other faithful members of the Church who took upon themselves the name of Christ, even before the Savior’s birth.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> This book tells of the resurrected Christ teaching men what they must do to gain peace in this life and eternal salvation in the world to come. What could be more Christian than seeking to take His name upon ourselves and follow His counsel to become like Him?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/mom-are-we-christians.p9" pid="WrRF45YwM06xrF7eQL6F9w" hash="iIv3Dw">President Gordon B. Hinckley has said, “I cannot understand why the Christian world does not accept this book.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> I first read the Book of Mormon at the age of 21. I then asked God if it was true. The truth of it was manifested unto me by the comforting power of the Holy Ghost.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> I know that the Book of Mormon is a second testament of Jesus Christ. I join my testimony with the prophets of this sacred book to declare that “we talk of Christ, we rejoice in Christ, we preach of Christ, we prophesy of Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> I am deeply grateful for every word that He <span class="pageBreak" page-number="94"></span>has spoken and for every word He continues to speak as He quenches our thirst with living water.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/mom-are-we-christians.p10" pid="Zj9gpObthkKMCEC0qmo9Mw" hash="heWFKg">Another restored truth of the gospel I became acquainted with was the restoration of priesthood authority, or the power to act in God’s name. Former prophets and apostles, such as Elijah, Moses, John the Baptist, Peter, James, and John, have been sent by God and Christ in our day to restore the holy priesthood of God. Every priesthood holder in this Church can trace his priesthood authority directly to Jesus Christ. Men now possess the keys to establish the Church so that we can come unto Christ and partake of His eternal ordinances of salvation.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> I testify that this is the Church of Jesus Christ—the only church authorized with true priesthood authority to exercise the keys of salvation through sacred ordinances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/mom-are-we-christians.p11" pid="h9UenAysn0GAdNv7nTJcYg" hash="Zp1VFw">Cortnee asked, “Mom, are we Christians?” As a member of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, you are a Christian, and I am too. I am a devout Christian who is exceedingly fortunate to have greater knowledge of the true “doctrine of Christ”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> since my conversion to the restored Church. These truths define this Church as having the fulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ. Like other members of the Church, I now understand the true nature of the Godhead, I have access to additional scripture and revelation, and I can partake of the blessings of priesthood authority. Yes, Cortnee, we are Christians, and I testify of these truths in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/04/mom-are-we-christians</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2007-general-conference/2007-04-5030-elder-gary-j-coleman-64k-eng.mp3" length="4631218" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
