<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Gayle M. Clegg</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Gayle M. Clegg.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Gayle%20M.%20Clegg.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Gayle M. Clegg.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2002 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Language of Love</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Every child needs regular reports affirming, “You are known. You are valued. You have potential. You are good.”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029598_000_026" doc-version="2" hash="ZpjV-Q">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="QW3kNcThjk-KCkQR1WucAA" hash="M-hXEQ">The Language of Love</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Nu6FJSSGCUukZslBTAhvJQ" hash="VNIJvg">Gayle M. Clegg</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="5ghDke0qoU6VMVxlsGGWKQ" hash="gVf7rg">Every child needs regular reports affirming, “You are known. You are valued. You have potential. You are good.”</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-5ef.jpg" alt="Gayle M. Clegg" pid="t9M0Fw-U7EieVr1duSIl6w" hash="C_TTVg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p1" pid="BwwtwTlkiUu15ZxBE6_lXA" hash="NmBr-g">When I was a young mother, my husband and I found ourselves taking our five children under the age of eight to live in South America. Although none of us spoke the language, my six-year-old had the greatest difficulty learning a new language. We decided to put her in preschool with four-year-olds, even though she should be starting first grade. Our hope was that interaction with younger children would be less intimidating to her and might facilitate her ability to communicate in Portuguese.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p2" pid="X7ZELA3Yb0myELe0s0tqjQ" hash="HMVnsQ">But the reality for my daughter was that she was as foreign to the children as they were to her. Each day was a struggle, and I anguished for her every morning as I walked her to school and then waited for her to return, dejected, at the end of the day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p3" pid="DwbYtaEG6Ui7mwdVb3JREA" hash="oEVN4A">One day, some children were particularly unkind to her. A few even threw rocks and bullied her, laughing rudely at recess. She was scared and hurt and decided she couldn’t go back into class. Sitting alone while the playground emptied, she remembered what we had taught her about loneliness. She remembered that Heavenly Father is always close to His children and she could speak to Him at any time, not just before bedtime. He would understand the language of her heart. In a corner of the playground, she bowed her head and said a prayer. She didn’t know what to pray for, so she asked that her father and mother could be with her to protect her. While returning to the classroom, a Primary song came into her mind.</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="ld7TPsgEu0-062y3HG-NNg" hash="8axlZA">
            <span class="emphasis">I often go walking in meadows of clover,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="qgpAZEblwEuTUVCKYL1aEA" hash="aoZ_jA">
            <span class="emphasis">And I gather armfuls of blossoms of blue.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="e8Fkjw4cKkWr-FD-hRh4kA" hash="ZnSzLg">
            <span class="emphasis">I gather the blossoms the whole meadow over;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="W70UzJ0w-Uer8kHQHc8ZdQ" hash="L8g3Wg">
            <span class="emphasis">Dear mother, all flowers remind me of you.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p4" pid="2tGMsOyi60-fsIUSTn1ssA" hash="voxkrg">As she opened her eyes, she noticed one little flower growing between the cracks of the cement. She picked it up and put it into her pocket. Her troubles with the other children did not disappear, but she walked back into the school feeling that her parents were with her.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p5" pid="hnvU5dM6jU-JNZJPXoPCPQ" hash="KXqegQ">Each of us, like my six-year-old daughter, have felt lost or alienated in a foreign land. Perhaps your foreign land was learning the language of algebra or chemistry. Maybe you thought you had come to a foreign shore when you joined the Church, even if you joined in your native country. Put yourself in the place of a new convert. Words like <span class="emphasis">calling, Presiding Bishopric,</span> even <span class="emphasis">General Authority</span> require a glossary entry.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p6" pid="woBQbQHWJ0-a31RWFPyTnw" hash="8Uky3g">What about our missionaries who have understood and responded to the promptings of the Holy Spirit that the Church is true, but then have the challenge of learning both the gospel and a foreign language at the same time? I marvel to think of their courage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p7" pid="m_8eWfh33U-3hwqHcPNJ9w" hash="HRL9DQ">Our lives are filled with many instances of the frustration of learning a foreign tongue. Nevertheless, there is one language that is universal. But “dear mother, all flowers remind me of you” spoke to the heart of a young girl. A Primary song and a wildflower were the familiar language of an answered prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p8" pid="z6c9Zgd-6U2FeX6kTTrcAA" hash="-eadCQ">After Jesus had been teaching for some time at the temple in Bountiful, He perceived the people might not have understood all the words He spoke. He asked them to go to their homes and ponder and pray with their families and prepare for Him to come the next day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p9" pid="tBNoky_eIEq-aH3H1_tV9A" hash="hn5TnA">But when “he cast his eyes round about again on the multitude, [he] beheld they were in tears, and did look steadfastly upon him as if they would ask him to tarry a little longer with them. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p10" pid="Zyl-l_FxuUOQb0IztoC7RA" hash="WqGBKg">“He took their little children, one by one, and blessed them. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p11" pid="L8kCIOA_KEyQ6vYkz0h7XQ" hash="b62h6A">“And he spake unto the multitude, and said unto them: Behold your little ones.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p12" pid="Z0U3Fm-cHk251Oiyl4RLFA" hash="-QhViw">“And as they looked … they saw angels descending out of heaven as it were in the midst of fire; and they came down and encircled those little ones about, … and the angels did minister unto them” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.5,21,23-24" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:5, 21, 23–24</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p13" pid="aXwM9F7Dz02ad4WwQ-iEhg" hash="PeGRIg">To “encircle” with the fire of our testimony is a language all of us must learn to speak and understand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p14" pid="r_X7FUtk90Styc1qtU4ZVQ" hash="PAKzww">The first lesson taught to every child in the world attending Primary is “I Am a Child of God.” Children as young as 18 months might be pointing to themselves acting out this finger play:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.f3">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="sFNrsGeo_Ei1FcrYyc72Kg" hash="H9243g">
            <span class="emphasis">Heavenly Father knows me</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="HawUOQOYCUS1Xo4kPpj_pw" hash="C4wJ2w">
            <span class="emphasis">And what I like to do.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="ekbDR5XwIEyy6quqZkeK4w" hash="faUIsg">
            <span class="emphasis">He knows my name and where I live.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="NmlQL4OtWUmaZUBe9ZnXeQ" hash="WgjqfQ">
            <span class="emphasis">I know He loves me, too.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p15" pid="zb8Yakcjo0ar5H9AGYodZw" hash="Qzzz0w">When I was teaching sixth grade a number of years ago, a 14-year-old boy dressed in gang attire was marched into my classroom. He was two years older and four years larger than the other 30 students. Quickly I discovered Brian did not read, had not attended school with any regularity, and had lived with a variety of guardians in a number of cities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p16" pid="49GI6NzlT06S_bRMmyg2Rg" hash="twXedQ">Report card time was coming up, and I came to school on my day off to finish recording the children’s work and mark the report cards. As I entered the classroom to gather up the records, I could see Brian had the class in an upheaval. I suggested to my grateful coteacher that I would take Brian with me. With some first-grade primers filled with pictures, we headed to the library, talking a little football on the way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p17" pid="Xx7Oxxq6yEClI-cOm8ftdw" hash="slJEqg">We settled ourselves at a table where I was marking report cards. I asked him if he had ever had a report card.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p18" pid="ZtyYegoI0E2PUbqWN6nqfQ" hash="nHyJHQ">He shook his head and said, “No.” I asked if he would like a report card.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p19" pid="eGPWhhdn3EWUWNgutRPraw" hash="ltFi1A">He looked directly at me. “Only if it said I was a good boy.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p20" pid="-6kvDPbDHUCZwj7EIjxNxA" hash="RnNylg">I made out a special card for him, emphasizing his strengths. I wrote his full name on it and his ability to include everyone and make people laugh. I specifically mentioned his love of sports. It was not a traditional report card but seemed to please him. Not too long after that, Brian disappeared from our school, and the last I heard of him, he was living in another state. I hoped he had my report card saying that he was a good boy in his pocket, wherever he was.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p21" pid="Z37eGgapwkq8cfXpx-Rz9w" hash="l1hW-A">Someday we will all be given final report cards. Maybe we will be graded on how well we have reported each other’s goodness. Every child needs regular reports affirming, “You are known. You are valued. You have potential. You are good.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p22" pid="YpZYsrFF8kud9kmOaLVi1A" hash="CSWeeQ">I love the stories of pioneer children. We always hear about their parents walking to the Salt Lake Valley. But in the words of a Primary song:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.f4">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="fc3m_v1SSUi09-x-sH7y8g" hash="KpkbUw">
            <span class="emphasis">Whenever I think about pioneers,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="g9bdwvcPGU6uLvcliCW9yQ" hash="QWqn4Q">
            <span class="emphasis">I think of brave women and men.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="xDPLDRCU6kmzdOLTaRbGvw" hash="wQD2ZA">
            <span class="emphasis">I like to remember that children came, too;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="gKKStMmj2EyX6Wu1fIA3mw" hash="INbdkQ">
            <span class="emphasis">I would like to have been a child then.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p23" pid="bXk4Ax66mUyfyBXHQS2blA" hash="v72_7Q">Susan Madsen tells the story of Agnes Caldwell in the Willie Handcart Company. They were caught in heavy storms and suffered terrible hunger and cold. Relief wagons came to deliver food and blankets, but there were not enough wagons to carry all the people. Even after rescue, the majority of the people still had to trudge on many more miles to the safety of the valley.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p24" pid="p3iOef4eXUW3ZTbQcANSdw" hash="uC5kMw">Little nine-year-old Agnes was too weary to walk any farther. The driver took notice of her determination to keep up with the wagon and asked if she would like a ride. She tells in her own words what happened next:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p25" pid="yuzDzCi3-ki5c4XnwJJvyQ" hash="JVwCIw">“At this he reached over, taking my hand, clucking to his horses to make me run, with legs that … could run no farther. On we went, to what to me seemed miles. What went through my head at that time was that he was the meanest man that ever lived or that I had ever heard of. … Just at what seemed the breaking point, he stopped [and pulled me into the wagon]. Taking a blanket, he wrapped me up … warm and comfortable. Here I had time to change my mind, as I surely did, knowing full well by doing this he saved me from freezing when taken into the wagon” (in <span class="emphasis">I Walked to Zion</span> [1994], 59).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p26" pid="pvTtt5-9-EWGVbno4VF8-Q" hash="0A4lBg">The driver of that relief wagon made the little girl run as far and as fast as she could to push blood back into her frozen feet and legs. He saved her legs, possibly her life, by letting her help herself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p27" pid="JtItgZ0HX0K-mQxzLC600g" hash="jXiWmg">Our children today have journeys as terrible and taxing as the westward migration. They are faced with every calamity along the trail. We need to build their backs to bear their burdens and legs for dancing under starry skies. Sometimes we must run to keep up with our children’s faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p28" pid="-x4269MkJEyrDoHJ-C-lyg" hash="4WPQaA">Another time in 3 Nephi when Christ was blessing the disciples, “his countenance did smile upon them, and the light of his countenance did shine upon them” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/19.25" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 19:25</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p29" pid="C0VDM9yClkqhBPBSfFv5qA" hash="tqn0sA">A smiling countenance says you are good. Children are trying to be like Jesus. They want to be like someone who smiles. They want to be with someone who responds to them joyfully.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p30" pid="bpyNsqmI_06ziWtEYSlPOw" hash="_kTprQ">President Hinckley has said: “Children need sunlight. They need happiness. They need love and nurture” (“Save the Children,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1994, 54).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p31" pid="3VoPzcmckEiUXU_KFoh9IQ" hash="TqlGQw">This should be the language of gospel instruction to our children. Whatever your mother tongue, learn to teach and speak in the language of heartfelt prayers and joyful testimony so that angels, earthly and heavenly, can encircle and minister to us. We need gospel mentors who speak the language of praise and friendship. We need to give regular spiritual report cards that affirm our goodness in each other’s eyes. It is a blessing to allow children to run as far as they can under their own power, to build strength for their own testimonies, and we should smile upon them and wrap them in the blanket of our affection throughout the great journey in the universal language of love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love.p32" pid="k6KOrXsA1EW-569Svmk7wQ" hash="IaxRyw">I give thanks for the great blessing to “behold [our] little ones.” I like to remember that children come, too, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2002/04/the-language-of-love</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2002-general-conference/2002-04-4040-gayle-m-clegg-64k-eng.mp3" length="5328951" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2002 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Finished Story</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We have to keep writing, keep walking, keep serving and accepting new challenges to the end of our own story.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10031248_000_007" doc-version="2" hash="OfELDw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="RDwI8psnKE2TboXgFKWXvg" hash="uh2k8g">The Finished Story</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="qqZ8n1671U-wzbPwVSDijw" hash="VNIJvg">Gayle M. Clegg</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="ad4OpltyTUW2-PByniFTsA" hash="S6eSrQ">We have to keep writing, keep walking, keep serving and accepting new challenges to the end of our own story.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-5ef.jpg" alt="Gayle M. Clegg" pid="ocYpxCJDV02jhBPWlrBgNA" hash="C_TTVg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story.p1" pid="LrpnghM2gECmvdxaGnukeg" hash="jJmWFw">Some time ago I found a large white envelope in my mailbox. Inside was a story written by a boy I had taught years before when he was in sixth grade. I remembered the student and the assignment his class had worked on for months. I also remembered that he loved to write and would sit and think and think. Sometimes only a word or two found their way to the page. At times he worked during recess, but when the due date arrived, his story still had a chapter to go. I told him just to turn it in as it was, but Jimmy had a different vision and wanted to turn in a finished story. The last day of class he asked if he could finish during the summer break. Again I told him just to turn it in. He pleaded for more time, and finally I sent him on his way with a stack of wrinkled and smudged papers, complimenting him on his determination and assuring him of my confidence in his ability to complete a great story.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story.p2" pid="vULJjvupO0GxYrbNnl6jsg" hash="tlGebQ">I thought about him that summer, but the assignment left my mind until years later when I found his completed project in the mailbox. I was amazed and wondered what made Jimmy finish his story. What kind of vision, determination, and effort had been required in this task? Why do any of us finish a hard task, especially if no one demands its completion?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story.p3" pid="7c0VL4l7lEefwPJtM_Xafw" hash="R6tm_g">My husband’s great-grandfather Henry Clegg Jr. was a finisher. He joined the Church with his family when the first LDS missionaries went to Preston, England. Henry had a view of his destination in his mind as he and his wife, Hannah, and their two young boys immigrated to Utah. Henry left his older parents, who were too feeble to make such a long and arduous journey, knowing he would never see them again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story.p4" pid="GQAuioeGFkeQaE4Wa9loxw" hash="t5ImIg">While crossing the plains, Hannah contracted cholera and died. She was laid to rest in an unmarked grave. The company then moved on, and at six in the evening, Henry’s youngest son also died. Henry retraced his steps to Hannah’s grave, placed his young son in his wife’s arms, and reburied the two of them together. Henry then had to return to the wagon train, now five miles away. Suffering from cholera himself, Henry described his condition as being at death’s door while realizing he still had a thousand miles to walk. Amazingly he continued forward, putting one foot in front of the other. He stopped writing in his journal for several weeks after losing his dear Hannah and little son. I was struck with the words he used when he did start writing again: “Still moving.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story.p5" pid="eOE7uiO74kqjKIKVkOtltg" hash="BfBBxg">When he finally reached the gathering place of the Saints, he began a new family. He kept the faith. He continued his story. Most remarkably, his heartache over the burial of his sweetheart and son gave birth to our family’s legacy of moving forward, of finishing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story.p6" pid="NnJy4x-GyEafsXg8vNm0KQ" hash="3EEaoQ">I have often wondered as I have heard pioneer stories like the one of Henry Clegg, “Could I ever do that?” Sometimes I fear this question, knowing our pioneer legacy lives on today. I recently visited West Africa and witnessed everyday pioneers walking forward, joining a new church, leaving behind centuries of traditions, even leaving behind family and friends, as did Henry. My admiration and love for them is as great as for my own forebears.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story.p7" pid="0AT210EwSkaaPal-HtpcZA" hash="-gfbig">Do the challenges of others appear more difficult than our own? We often look at someone with tremendous responsibilities and think, “I could never do that.” Yet others might look at us and feel exactly the same way. It is not the magnitude of the responsibility but rather how it feels to be the one in the middle of the unfinished task. For a young mother with many children at home, caring for them through the day and then through the night could feel like a thousand miles yet to walk. Giving a lesson in Relief Society to women who are older or younger, more experienced or more educated could feel difficult, especially when the topic is one you are struggling to understand and live yourself. Teaching a class of 10 active six-year-olds can be daunting, especially when your own six-year-old is in the class and you haven’t quite figured out how to teach him one-on-one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story.p8" pid="5yC6vymkRUOr_LS-q6Eefw" hash="JUYYiw">What do we learn from young Jimmy, from early pioneers, and from modern pioneers around the world that will help us in our specific challenges? Jimmy spent years writing on his own for no deadline, Henry Clegg marched on alone and without heart even to write in a journal, and African Saints lived worthy of a temple they could not have imagined would one day rise in their own nation. To keep going, to stay faithful, and to finish had to be its own reward.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story.p9" pid="q9IKGncbIEyCLns9QjaRqA" hash="v7FA0A">Years ago one of our daughters asked me to come outside and play tetherball with her. She told me to sit down and watch as she hit over and over again a ball on a rope that wound itself around a pole. After watching several windings I asked what my part was in the game, and she said, “Oh, Mom, you say, ‘Good job, good job,’ every time the ball goes around the pole.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story.p10" pid="D685vrJce0Cs7gMRlfqPZw" hash="pgS9nA">“Good job!” helps the journey seem possible. It might sound like a phone call from a mother of one of the six-year-olds in that Primary class, calling to let the teacher know that her son carefully helped his little sister into the car seat without being asked, acknowledging the Primary teacher’s lesson as the impetus for this new behavior. It might look like a husband getting the children off to nursery and Primary as his wife sets up her lesson for Young Women. It might be as simple as a smile, a hug, or a long walk to sort things out with a friend, a husband, or a child.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story.p11" pid="PvmhVDHNFkK8vm_bzPjxOA" hash="EFHtHg">We each must find and finish our own story, but how much sweeter the telling when encouragement is called out, when arriving at our destination is valued and celebrated, however long ago the journey commenced.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story.p12" pid="m_VVqkU_XkSXRreReAqHyQ" hash="j79Fxw">The greatest mentor and advocate we have said: “I will go before your face. I will be on your right hand and on your left, and my Spirit shall be in your hearts, and mine angels round about you, to bear you up” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.88" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:88</a>). Can any of us afford to leave this piece out of our individual journey?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story.p13" pid="Bly6QSJkEUGMnQy04oa7xA" hash="66ewbA">Henry Clegg was still moving forward to live among the faithful Saints, to take his place, to raise a righteous family, to serve his neighbor. He had that picture in his mind even when his heart was breaking. I heard a Primary child from Ghana answer the question “What does it mean to choose the right every day?” with, “It means to follow the Lord and Savior every day and do your best even when it is hard.” This modern pioneer boy knew President Hinckley’s admonition. He knew about keeping commandments every day. He understood that his own story would unfold simply by putting one foot in front of the other, one day at a time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story.p14" pid="Inn_ZIZzhkWprjpehSp1lQ" hash="jTicdA">Last fall I found myself with a wonderful but challenging opportunity to develop and teach Primary training through a video made entirely in Spanish. At one time in my life I was a Spanish speaker, but recently I had been speaking Portuguese and knew what it would take to relearn Spanish. I did all the things each of you do to complete a task that feels extremely difficult. I found help from capable and dedicated Hispanic sisters. Together we studied, prayed, fasted, and worked long hours. The day arrived to go and do the thing the Lord had asked, and we not only were fearful but felt our work was inadequate. We had worked up to the moment of delivery, and nothing more could be done. I wanted to start over.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story.p15" pid="GrwjT-62sUiNc_11tSIoXg" hash="kG2isg">Each of our husbands gave us priesthood blessings, and peace and calm started to come. Like angels, help came in the form of a sweet husband who set the alarm on his watch so he could pray for me every half hour during the recording, a cameraman whose eyes radiated “Good job,” and Primary leaders who had confidence in the workings of the Spirit and were able to communicate that with power. We ended up with a finished film that was helpful for our Spanish-speaking leaders. All who participated in it were partly surprised and entirely grateful for its success. We walked as far as we could go, and when we thought we might abandon our carts and drop by the wayside, angels somehow pushed from behind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story.p16" pid="6Kv3P1R4xEWy9mKwbuMfgg" hash="POsnBA">What did we learn from this task? The same lesson Henry Clegg Jr. and Jimmy learned and the same thing all faithful modern-day pioneers are learning. With the Lord, nothing is impossible (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/1.37" class="scriptureRef">Luke 1:37</a>), but we each have to finish our own story. He sends His Spirit, we call out encouragement to each other, but we have to keep writing, keep walking, keep serving and accepting new challenges to the end of our own story. “Still walking” is the fundamental requirement in the journey of life. He wants us to finish well. He wants us to come back to Him. I pray that each of our stories will end in the presence of our Heavenly Father and His Son, our Savior Jesus Christ, the authors and finishers of our faith. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2004/04/the-finished-story</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2004-general-conference/2004-04-1050-gayle-m-clegg-64k-eng.mp3" length="5489397" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2004 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
