<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Gene R. Cook</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Gene R. Cook.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Gene%20R.%20Cook.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Gene R. Cook.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 1975 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Let All Thy Doings Be unto the Lord</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/10/let-all-thy-doings-be-unto-the-lord?lang=eng</link>
      <description>That’s a long, long walk. My brothers and sisters, my heart is full. I believe more than anything else I would like to truly express my love for my Father in heaven. I thought this morning of my wife as she said to me early, “Are you ready for today?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/let-all-thy-doings-be-unto-the-lord" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03063_000_014" doc-version="3" hash="PDDveA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/let-all-thy-doings-be-unto-the-lord.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="WcJr9O0vXkWwnGey7l8oWw" hash="Utajgg">Let All Thy Doings Be unto the Lord</h1><p class="authorName" pid="25wOj9BBAUuf4l4vJnm8wg" hash="jRdRpw">Gene R. Cook</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/let-all-thy-doings-be-unto-the-lord.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a6c.jpg" alt="Elder Gene R. Cook" pid="3OgDP0h4IkS5cjM8iHhAGA" hash="i_yMEA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/let-all-thy-doings-be-unto-the-lord.p1" pid="uHTIRSQeNEOZcWsaRcx0gw" hash="3z9YKg">That’s a long, long walk. My brothers and sisters, my heart is full. I believe more than anything else I would like to truly express my love for my Father in heaven. I thought this morning of my wife as she said to me early, “Are you ready for today?” Those words have seemed to ring in my mind all day as I’ve realized that if I’m not ready, it’s too late. I have begun to realize more fully that this last thirty-four years has represented the time for preparation—not today, but that which has gone before, the many, many yesterdays. The preparation has come from those persons who have been close to me and my family—priesthood leaders, mission presidents, these good Brethren of the First Council of the Seventy for whom I have worked for a number of years—I realize that it’s in those yesterdays, those many early mornings, those many long hours, as has been described here today, that most of the battles are fought and won.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/let-all-thy-doings-be-unto-the-lord.p2" pid="7_ROs6KnMkyV-2Amd0Cp5Q" hash="j-5wrQ">I would just share this one thought with you this afternoon, my brothers and sisters. I’ve had going through my mind something that Brother Sill said that was a paraphrase from Alma, expressed in a little different way, when Alma said the following:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/let-all-thy-doings-be-unto-the-lord.p3" pid="hPMOI9Vj40WYI1w-96Rx5g" hash="7KOjxQ">“Preach unto them repentance, and faith on the Lord Jesus Christ; teach them to humble themselves and to be meek and lowly in heart; teach them to withstand every temptation of the devil, with their faith on the Lord Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/let-all-thy-doings-be-unto-the-lord.p4" pid="ruYAbxVSyU217tqHhW-xOA" hash="hZz-8w">“Yea, and cry unto God for all thy support; yea, let all thy doings be unto the Lord, and whithersoever thou goest let it be in the Lord; yea, let thy thoughts be directed unto the Lord; yea, let the affections of thy heart be placed upon the Lord forever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/let-all-thy-doings-be-unto-the-lord.p5" pid="JYEjW6dnj0yJOoiHqCHAfw" hash="dWpYmA">“Counsel with the Lord in all thy doings, and he will direct thee for good; yea, when thou liest down at night lie down unto the Lord, that he may watch over you in your sleep; and when thou risest in the morning let thy heart be full of thanks unto God; and if ye do these things, ye shall be lifted up at the last day.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.33,36-37" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:33, 36–37</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/let-all-thy-doings-be-unto-the-lord.p6" pid="3HjSdrD_PkKwCtmv0ZDPyA" hash="IYz24w">My brothers and sisters, I bear witness to you that this is the church of Jesus Christ, that he is at the head, that he is the rock of our salvation, that our affections must be totally placed, all of them, upon the Lord. And I bear witness that if they are placed elsewhere, we will not receive that promise to be lifted up at the last day. I bear my witness with a surety that goes beyond words of those promptings that come that this is the true church of Jesus Christ, the only one upon the face of the whole earth, because the Lord has so declared it. I bear witness that President Kimball is a prophet of God and want to express to these good Brethren in front of me that I pledge all of my efforts, my time, and talents, and resources, and all that I have, for as long as they’re desired by the Lord or by these Brethren, to do whatever they would have me do. And I bear this witness in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/10/let-all-thy-doings-be-unto-the-lord</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1975-general-conference/1975-10-2070-elder-gene-r-cook-64k-eng.mp3" length="4139812" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are You a Member Missionary?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My brothers and sisters, the Lord has greatly blessed the proceedings of this conference. You have heard the Brethren speak by the power of the Holy Ghost, and if you were listening by that Spirit you have been edified and strengthened in your resolv</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03070_000_046" doc-version="2" hash="0qgjvA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="R8ouOvsACkm79J-edZiN0g" hash="YF8nJQ">Are You a Member Missionary?</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="BwzPOi6hrkOZ9NlIkioLXw" hash="jRdRpw">Gene R. Cook</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a6c.jpg" alt="Elder Gene R. Cook" pid="xlnoG2Wf6EyhpJmmMcGiKQ" hash="i_yMEA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p1" pid="1LtHCC460U-SggTP0RqBJw" hash="boE_Xg">My brothers and sisters, the Lord has greatly blessed the proceedings of this conference. You have heard the Brethren speak by the power of the Holy Ghost, and if you were listening by that Spirit you have been edified and strengthened in your resolve to keep the commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p2" pid="HZHylGklM0uaT3vMzvBlKg" hash="e6tf5Q">We have heard much said about the missionary program, and I now ask all who are here today this question: Who is really responsible to do missionary work? President Kimball has indicated that every member should be a missionary. It has been suggested that all should be preparing all the days of their lives to be missionaries, preparing not only to serve full-time missions, but also preparing themselves to teach the word of God to all those who do not yet know the truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p3" pid="r-VCQ5r6a0CjSqItXR91OA" hash="mrmmAw">The Lord said in the Doctrine and Covenants, section 38, verses 40 to 41, the following:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p4" pid="siBPNBLjw0WTLmVtdX94CQ" hash="WvUG5g">“And again, I say unto you, I give unto you a commandment, that every man, both elder, priest, teacher, and also member, go to with his might, with the labor of his hands, to prepare and accomplish the things which I have commanded.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p5" pid="tdc_ul0xGUeKCXe70pejGA" hash="WxPPxA">“And let your preaching be the warning voice, every man to his neighbor, in mildness and in meekness.” [<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.40-41" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:40–41</a>] It is evident to me that the Lord expects every man, <span class="emphasis">every man,</span> to lift up his voice and preach the gospel of Jesus Christ in mildness and meekness. It is also clear that priesthood leaders throughout the Church have the responsibility to assist the members of the Church in fulfilling this missionary responsibility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p6" pid="FweLW6kZeEO9Xp4CKZz8TA" hash="7HS3Rg">Many members ask, “Elder Cook, it’s easy to say, but how do I do it? What can I specifically do now to fulfill my missionary responsibility to warn my neighbors?” May I provide you with two general suggestions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p7" pid="vZtSi-3YXkuwBgtgCZ2v2Q" hash="AzTV2w">First, you can stand up for the truth wherever you are, at all times, and in all places. Sometimes our members are fearful to speak up for the truth in clubs, associations, or even, at times, among members of the Church. As the Lord has said, it should be done with boldness but not overbearance. Speak out for the Lord and for his prophet on the vital issues of the day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p8" pid="e_HarSalc0qsegson_uUXA" hash="_04DzA">For example, I know of a woman, a good woman, who found herself in a very challenging situation. She was at a luncheon with a number of members of the Church; some were active and some inactive; and also a few nonmembers were present. The subject turned to abortion and birth control, and one of the nonmembers voiced for about five minutes some very strong feelings concerning these issues. She indicated, erroneously, that she felt that there is nothing wrong with an abortion, and that there should never be any kind of restriction placed on a man or a woman concerning birth control itself. This good sister in the Church was faced with a difficult challenge of whether to talk about the weather or some other noncontroversial subject, or whether to really speak out and state the truth. This choice woman chose to do the latter. After explaining what the Lord had said concerning both of those issues, she bore her testimony as to her personal feelings. As you might expect, the luncheon concluded rather abruptly. However, afterwards one of the inactive women came over to this good sister and explained that she had never before understood the Lord’s view on those issues and had felt the truth being spoken on that day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p9" pid="Ys3vduyxMkm1SfEO3QQmFQ" hash="Mr_A1g">Feel free, when prompted, my brothers and sisters, to bear your testimony of those principles that you know to be true. Sincere feelings conveyed from heart to heart by means of testimony convert people to the truth where weak, wishy-washy, argumentative statements will not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p10" pid="8cRkHZwzqEmJe01UzArJfA" hash="YW8K1Q">You could provide friends or others you meet at your work, on airplanes, in stores, or other places you go with a tract, a copy of the Book of Mormon, or other Church literature which would help them in becoming prepared to eventually receive the missionaries and be taught the gospel. How many members desire to be missionaries but go about in their daily activity without any kind of missionary aid, like a tract, Book of Mormon, or other missionary tool?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p11" pid="ValxJW_yFEW-_q5cvDmY5w" hash="DVhj0w">The Lord seemed to have this particular challenge to his members in mind when he gave to the prophet Alma, at the waters of Mormon, the baptismal covenant that every member of the Church takes upon himself, part of which reads as is recorded in <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:9</a>, “Yea, and are willing to mourn with those that mourn; yea, and comfort those that stand in need of comfort, and to stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things, and in all places.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p12" pid="9J164A8kH0alA2xInXziXA" hash="LF-chw">We ask you to do just that, to set aside your fear, and to take strength in the Lord, and to bear your witness to the world of the truthfulness of this gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p13" pid="wG_oTt4c9EaSPsbugO8N7g" hash="0QVpMA">Now a second suggestion: President Kimball has asked each of us to <span class="emphasis">prayerfully</span> select a family that we might friendship. Listen to his words: “By working together as families, much great work can be accomplished. Father, you are to take the lead. With your family, prayerfully select one or two fine families to friendship. Decide who of all your relatives or friends you will introduce to the Church. Then, as a family, contact them. Perhaps you could plan a family home evening with them on a night other than Monday, or get together with them in any of a number of ways. Then, when these families show interest, arrange through your ward or branch mission leader to invite them and the missionaries into your home to share the message of the restoration. If you will follow this simple procedure, you will bring a number of fine families into the Church.” (<span class="emphasis">Go Ye into All the World,</span> filmstrip.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p14" pid="UJiqnBMoqEy7ua1KTSXV_w" hash="P18UrQ">Did you notice that President Kimball said to <span class="emphasis">prayerfully</span> select a family or families?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p15" pid="CWCltKcNnkGvpzN7PmhtQA" hash="tMxRXw">I recall what the Lord said through Alma the Younger in <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/6.6" class="scriptureRef">Alma 6:6</a>. “Nevertheless the children of God were commanded that they should gather themselves together oft, and join in fasting and mighty prayer in behalf of the welfare of the souls of those who knew not God.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p16" pid="83RcMfh2IESgnu0bHjobcQ" hash="1V8oHA">Are you praying for those who, as Alma said, “knew not God”?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p17" pid="lbb19DYvT0yRiqLgYmXRBA" hash="XEIczg">When we are performing the Lord’s work, we must do it the Lord’s way. I suggest to you that if you prayerfully approach this work and ask your Father in heaven to reveal to you the means by which you might be an instrument in his hands in bringing individuals into the Church, the way will be provided for you to do just that.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p18" pid="rpJeO3UkgkOKAGmCvYtXRQ" hash="db-DnQ">Now to those of you who may be listening to the proceedings of this conference who are not yet members of the Church, we say, search out prayerfully the doctrines of this church. Pray about them and you will come to know, as do I, that this is the only true church upon the face of this earth. Talk with members of the Church and learn about the kingdom of God on earth today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p19" pid="V_HbAg7fdkW_fFriuco67A" hash="0R9TWw">May I remind you all once again what the Lord said to that great Prophet Joseph Smith: “Our missionaries are going forth to different nations, … the Standard of Truth has been erected; no unhallowed hand can stop the work from progressing; persecutions may rage, mobs may combine, armies may assemble, calumny may defame, but the truth of God will go forth boldly, nobly, and independent, till it has penetrated every continent, visited every clime, swept every country, and sounded in every ear, till the purposes of God shall be accomplished, and the Great Jehovah shall say the work is done.” (<span class="emphasis">History of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints,</span> 4:540.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary.p20" pid="LsjRW5xsuUiSPBLznrHETg" hash="84_H-A">I bear my testimony that the gospel will be sounded in every ear. This is the only true and living church upon the face of the whole earth. Because the Lord has so declared it, I bear witness that there is a living prophet upon the earth today, and that there is a real urgency, a real urgency, my brothers and sisters, for us as members of the Church to lift our warning voice to all the inhabitants of the earth. May the Lord give us the power to accomplish this purpose as we, with full purpose of heart, obey him. I pray in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/04/are-you-a-member-missionary</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1976-general-conference/1976-04-7060-elder-gene-r-cook-64k-eng.mp3" length="10107339" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1976 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seek Out Your Spiritual Leader</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Several months ago while traveling by air in the Andes area, I had the opportunity to explain to the man sitting next to me why I was living in South America.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03096_000_031" doc-version="2" hash="S4W0Cw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="BQHsWPBuJkeqb7XyTQ2Rsg" hash="yaiMZA">Seek Out Your Spiritual Leader</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="TmdMfCOmmk2c9aO4YPzaDA" hash="jRdRpw">Gene R. Cook</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a6c.jpg" alt="Elder Gene R. Cook" pid="yhUXEVsrR06GYEa1aIAkUQ" hash="i_yMEA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.p1" pid="WQMZuAWhYUq6pQCD11PxaQ" hash="U5A4ZA">Several months ago while traveling by air in the Andes area, I had the opportunity to explain to the man sitting next to me why I was living in South America.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.p2" pid="NnShsJv9ck6NJSUri_7OLA" hash="Tt-X2Q">After coming to understand something about the Church, its doctrine, and my role as a General Authority, he finally said, “How can you give your entire life to <span class="emphasis">another man,</span> like this Mr. Kimball, and stay in this country as long as he tells you to stay here? I could never do that.” I responded, “I could not either, if he were <span class="emphasis">just a man,</span>” and then bore testimony of the true role of the prophet on the earth, and that “for the Lord, through him, I would do anything.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.p3" pid="DGnBaJpeyEuCZmJJyG7NOw" hash="4EcpLw">A few years ago I took a person who was not yet a member of the Church to a meeting to hear one of the General Authorities speak. I had told him previously that this was one of the Lord’s anointed. After the meeting the man responded, “Well, he is nothing but <span class="emphasis">a man.</span>” I suppose that he expected to see an angel, a demonstration of the gift of tongues, or something like that as a physical evidence of the General Authority’s divine call.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.p4" pid="lfhpHcuf0k-RW2Av08Q5tA" hash="p0zYpQ">I have often wondered how many of us might have been deceived had we been in the very presence of Jesus Christ, the Son of God, in the meridian of time. The great majority saw Jesus as nothing more than <span class="emphasis">a man.</span> The <span class="emphasis">few</span> with spiritual discernment knew who he really was. If one is to make judgments with only his natural senses, he will never perceive the truth of the spiritual world. Have you listened, my brothers and sisters, really listened, to the inspired counsel of these good brethren who have spoken to you during this conference? Are you willing to obey and follow their counsel and the counsel of your local leaders as well?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.p5" pid="He0ItkD5MkSj_Xucoeklqw" hash="KK_GKg">Where do you stand on this important matter of spiritually seeing your leaders the way the Lord sees them? Our response to that question ought to be like the faithful Israelites’ response to Joshua:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.p6" pid="McbrMj5bKEewakO40AmdUA" hash="YpVjaA">“And they answered Joshua, saying, All that thou commandest us we will do, and whithersoever thou sendest us, we will go.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.p7" pid="0xpMXa68RkiSHDgUZBjkKw" hash="YIL5bA">“According as we hearkened unto Moses in all things, so will we hearken unto thee.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/1.16-17" class="scriptureRef">Josh. 1:16–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.p8" pid="BW3FG4Efz02lAZgkbsApBQ" hash="l7rPQA">Sometime ago another man asked, “Do the General Authorities really know what is going on in the outlying areas? I am sure that they do not know of these detailed problems with which we are faced.” Another good sister said, “If the bishop knew what I know about the difficulties in the Relief Society, I know he would act differently. It’s too bad he doesn’t consult more with us and obtain all of our opinions about how to run the ward.” Another said, “I don’t go to my branch president for direction because he sees things differently than I do. Our personalities are too different. We just don’t seem to be on the same wavelength.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.p9" pid="RhBrwMTZR026OBCnx0vHlg" hash="GxjBmQ">May I suggest, my brothers and sisters, that the General Authorities, your stake president, bishop, and priesthood quorum leaders do know what is going on <span class="emphasis">with respect to the governing principles, the matters that really count,</span> and that the rest will be resolved in their due time. This is the Lord’s church. It is directed by him through a definite priesthood power line of revelation. We believe in a God of miracles, and he does not cease to work spiritual miracles through his priesthood leaders.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.p10" pid="WcLAWaxlI0aeprPM8A1z1g" hash="rRoZMg">We recognize that in any presidency or bishopric the president or bishop may obtain counsel from his counselors, and perhaps from some others, before he, by inspiration, makes the decision. However, we do not in the Church subscribe to a participative-management type of direction, wherein the opinions of all are gathered in, weighed and measured, a consensus drawn, and then a decision made according to the majority. There may be some few exceptions to that statement, but generally speaking that type of approach is representative of the way the world manages its affairs. Many other churches are in the same category because they have nothing better. All the world can do is to dispute an issue, share an opinion, exchange an experience, and then try to draw the best conclusion from the given amount of facts available on the subject.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.p11" pid="qs9459XS9kiwvrb1Cx2Yfg" hash="xQWeZg">In The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, the leaders at all levels of administration rely on revelation from God to direct their particular stewardships. There are many people, too many, who seek out the wrong individuals for counsel, too many who would rather <span class="emphasis">give</span> counsel than <span class="emphasis">receive</span> it. Remember that others might share with you their experience, or broaden your understanding on a given issue, but if you are desirous of receiving revelation pertaining to your particular stewardship, it must come from the Lord. It may come directly through an interchange with him on your part or as revelation to you through your immediate priesthood leader.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.p12" pid="Da9lQeSo4Eiiu2TcRWHxoQ" hash="mhjAeQ">One of the great blessings of this church is that everyone has a spiritual leader to whom he should direct himself. In the case of a father, his children and wife will want to consult him as the spiritual leader in their home. If the matter needs further attention, the wife and children do not go to a priesthood quorum leader, as the husband might on some priesthood matters. They counsel with the bishop or branch president. If there is a problem in the marriage, the husband and wife go to their bishop for he presides over <span class="emphasis">both</span> of them as the bishop and presiding high priest over the ward. They need not go elsewhere, unless otherwise directed by the bishop, for additional guidance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.p13" pid="DaViLTerRkazke6thLVjRw" hash="11mkMw">After enumerating various spiritual gifts, the Lord provides this counsel concerning <span class="emphasis">your</span> bishop or any other presiding priesthood leader: “And unto the bishop of the church, and unto such as God shall appoint and ordain to watch over the church and to be elders unto the church, are to have it given unto them to discern all those gifts lest there shall be any among you professing and yet be not of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/46.27" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 46:27</a>.) It is abundantly clear that presiding priesthood leaders are given the gift of discernment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.p14" pid="lddRE4HcKU6Y3w0HLjJIlQ" hash="WUl92g">Remember that at times your local priesthood leader may truly see things differently than you do. Disagreements seem to come over details and methods for performing given tasks, but almost never are based in differences over gospel principles. Your leader has a right to function with his own unique personality and in his own realm of experience, and it may be in <span class="emphasis">detail</span> somewhat different in practice from the <span class="emphasis">exact way</span> you would perform. <span class="emphasis">Nevertheless,</span> counsel from a priesthood leader in the proper spirit is <span class="emphasis">of the Lord and binding.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.p15" pid="XzOjs3Dev0qNmljB5mvLAQ" hash="keSrFQ">We live in trying times. When we receive counsel from our leaders that is difficult to comprehend, may we say in our hearts, “Father, I believe what I have been told. And when it is the right time, and I have paid the proper price to know, let me understand <span class="emphasis">why.</span>”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.p16" pid="xW1_1l8QCEKgKEXzdXTL3Q" hash="OSE5Yg">It is a gift from the Spirit to believe on the words of your priesthood leaders. I seem to hear them say: “<span class="emphasis">Believe me,</span> because the view from up here is much clearer than where <span class="emphasis">you</span> now are. <span class="emphasis">Trust me,</span> because I can clearly see beyond the next hill.” If one will listen to wise parents and priesthood leaders, he will perceive that they counsel with long lenses of eternity and not with cheap, nearsighted spectacles. He can then learn vicariously, through the spiritual vision of others, without having to participate in every type of activity to learn for himself good from evil.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.p17" pid="IKloE8agMUGuUQKTOpknXQ" hash="QHCLiA">Remember, last of all, we do not desire blind obedience in the Church. We desire that every individual may know for himself that the counsel he receives from his leaders comes from the Lord. He has the right and the great privilege to know for himself of the Lord that he has been counseled aright. If he will be patient and wait upon the Lord, he will find that his priesthood leaders truly do counsel in righteousness, thus enabling him to walk upon safe ground.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader.p18" pid="6DOabmMzj0KHjMXwRUeXkA" hash="4yQoiA">I pray that each of us might be more humble and desirous of receiving and obeying counsel. May each of us seek not to counsel the Lord, but seek counsel from his hand and from his inspired priesthood leaders, <span class="emphasis">as it is the same.</span> In the name of Jesus Christ, Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1978/04/seek-out-your-spiritual-leader</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1978-general-conference/1978-04-5020-elder-gene-r-cook-64k-eng.mp3" length="4638938" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 1978 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miracles among the Lamanites</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Why should that be so? Why are changes in that people occurring so dramatically? The title page of the record their ancestors gave to the world, entitled the Book of Mormon, indicates that the book was “written to the Lamanites, who are a remnant of </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03128_000_029" doc-version="2" hash="_fjNGw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="JPFat4Aru0uR2uILfS6xkQ" hash="HlucAQ">Miracles among the Lamanites</h1><p class="authorName" pid="WPCD3a0Rkku3GuCWXZZJQQ" hash="jRdRpw">Gene R. Cook</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a6c.jpg" alt="Elder Gene R. Cook" pid="OM8pQuZbdU6EYJu2ShUkVg" hash="i_yMEA" />
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.f2"><p pid="B2OyvqRvYUKtt1VNgGuAuw" hash="4VBZDg">My family and I are presently living in South America among the Lamanites—the children of Lehi, the people of the Book of Mormon, a people of great promise. For a number of years we have been witnesses to spiritual miracles among that people:</p><ol class="number"><li pid="H4R82PEMo0Wm-GeI4IOEBQ" hash="Qz6E2w">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="2r3WVHd3kk22Lx7XYGIUQw" hash="qbbnhw">We have seen thousands converted to the Lord who had his law put into their minds and written in their hearts (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/8.10" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 8:10</a>).</p>
        </li><li pid="7jkaXjlw2kujq3JJmGK6lg" hash="5Rp70g">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="31cossRy1kazUNeDYvuv0w" hash="cqsMtQ">We have seen them organized into numerous stakes of Zion.</p>
        </li><li pid="OJzLonXQekSb3YCxFQWOuw" hash="zWeAWg">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="Iu9QR8V4BEKcuoDygouYgQ" hash="WHp0Cg">We have truly seen them “blossom as the rose” as prophecy has been fulfilled through them (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/49.24" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 49:24</a>).</p>
        </li><li pid="f6eH5DO2vkSQJtu4AVhKvQ" hash="Zo2r0Q">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="enjOHUEMk02CweXhiBbneQ" hash="oNTmMA">We have literally seen the Lord perform miracles among them by their faith.</p>
        </li></ol></div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p1" pid="_L5BUnT0E0KEsMiGFvkPMA" hash="LOBSfA">Why should that be so? Why are changes in that people occurring so dramatically? The title page of the record their ancestors gave to the world, entitled the Book of Mormon, indicates that the book was “written to the Lamanites, who are a remnant of the house of Israel.” In the last chapter of the book, the prophet Moroni gives to the Lamanites farewell instructions, a portion of which contains the conditions on which individual testimonies of the truth may be obtained. The record is for all men, but from cover to cover the book is filled with prophecies concerning the Lamanites, indicating “that the promises of the Lord [would] be fulfilled, which he made to his people” (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/3.18,19" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 3:18, 19</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p2" pid="uCydWAIIVUWHtP8zPL2_nw" hash="WszG1w">The promises were not exclusively given to the Lamanites but to all nations who would possess these lands. The land was blessed: “And thus they did leave a blessing upon this land in their prayers, that whosoever should believe in this gospel in this land might have eternal life” (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/10.49,50" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 10:49, 50</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p3" pid="VYHm2bKMb0Wzz6X6ynT8SA" hash="WDQccw">“And the gospel of Jesus Christ shall be declared among them; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p4" pid="QbWxl7JTKUW3CpvY_M-7gg" hash="rZbAmg">“And then shall they rejoice; for they shall know that it is a blessing unto them from the hand of God; and their scales of darkness shall begin to fall from their eyes.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/30.5-6" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 30:5–6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p5" pid="_iwPWJhdvkGM-sCXw-jXKQ" hash="axvRtw">There is even direction to us in our day from President Kimball and the scriptures: “Go unto the Lamanites and preach my gospel unto them; and inasmuch as they receive thy teachings thou shalt cause my church to be established among them” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/28.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 28:8</a>). Our living prophet has also said, “It is a people who … call for assistance from those who can push and lift and open doors. It is a people who pray for mercy, for forgiveness, and beg for membership in the kingdom with its opportunities to learn and do.” (Spencer W. Kimball, in Conference Report, Apr. 1954, p. 107.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p6" pid="MBInmVdGwki0Jdu7R9qW6A" hash="UU2-iA">How the Lord has blessed his people, this remnant of the house of Jacob. His words have been fulfilled. Where there was once a barren field, today they stand strong and truly “blossom as the rose” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/49.24" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 49:24</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p7" pid="yQVqhXvWYUqJgbp9Ao_dOg" hash="1DiJKg">What a miracle to behold! Only in <span class="emphasis">part</span> of the Lamanite world, in Latin America alone, there are over 600,000 members of the Church, with 7,000 baptized nearly every month; 181 stakes at present with almost 2,400 congregations of Saints and 2,500 Latin missionaries serving; thousands and thousands of priesthood holders—Regional Representatives, mission presidents, patriarchs, bishops—faithful sisters, and faithful children of a powerful generation yet to come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p8" pid="ETaH3ZU-FU61KPDqJFUg9A" hash="d5eH7A">Yes, the descendants of Lehi have learned much from us, the Church in general, as we have established the Church among them. They appreciate the fulfillment of the prophecy indicating “that every man shall hear the fulness of the gospel in his own tongue, and in his own language” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/90.11" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 90:11</a>). Thanks belong to you who serve or have served in these countries, and to the parents who worried about you but sent you anyway, trusting in the Lord, and who found that their sons and daughters received far more in their service to this people than they were capable of giving.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p9" pid="4Q3V6nUwCUGMMIqn4UEaEQ" hash="zq-zQQ">They appreciate the fulfillment of these words of the Lord also: “I will consecrate of the riches of those who embrace my gospel among the Gentiles unto the poor of my people who are of the house of Israel” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.39" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:39</a>). Thanks belong to the thousands of you who have contributed generously and enabled the work to go forth. You have given much for which the Lord will bless you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p10" pid="XGMSEX5EDkGxyWBEcKvYmQ" hash="5VfZkA">You have also received much, as many of you have a personal debt to the Lamanites’ forefathers for your own testimony obtained from their diligent record-keeping in the Book of Mormon. We are all blessed to participate with them in making latter-day history and assist in the fulfillment of prophecy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p11" pid="gy17WQB3akOLTrNkPxY0ig" hash="3J6G8Q">Now, what can the rest of the Church learn from this people? They would not have you think they are any better than anyone else. However, because of the prophetic nature of their role in the last days, because the Lord has pre-prepared their hearts, one is able to see the Lord’s handiwork in their very lives and understand why they are so susceptible to the gospel. This very understanding ought to teach all of us much about the sacred conversion process. Their lives teach of the basics of the gospel—godly traits—traits that we could do well to emulate in our progress toward exaltation. Repayment of temporal resources to the Church may never be made by them. However, the additional spiritual insight obtained from them may well represent an overpayment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p12" pid="rAB5-CanAkmEuaZ7t0WEIA" hash="oqt3rA">Their lives teach of simple truths like faith, confidence, trust in God. For example, a small village of Aymara Indians is converted within a matter of a few weeks—the entire village. Missionaries learn through the gift of tongues to speak Spanish, Aymara, Quechua, and many other Indian dialects. Lamanite Saints accept in faith instructions to become self-sufficient when the vision of that concept in their world seems to be totally impossible. They believe anyway and are on their way to making that become reality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p13" pid="YR-Rec87skefBsJgAZEWLw" hash="Oaf1mw">Their lives emanate the basics of the gospel, like repentance and love unfeigned. New leaders enter the Church from many kinds of worldly conditions but come forth cleansed and, in but “moments,” stand tall as the Lord’s leaders. They quickly learn by the Spirit that all can lead, even though many can’t even read. A man who has not spoken for many years repents, is baptized, and speaks his first words as he leaves the baptismal font.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p14" pid="vDYyRZZ5OkOo1SZo58MSoA" hash="BT6TeA">Their lives teach the simple truths of humility, meekness, teachableness. May I share another example? A Lamanite missionary baptizes eighteen souls in a matter of three weeks, where all last year none had been baptized. There are few problems with respect to teachableness among this people. They are teachable, meek, open in their hearts, and, in this respect, much like submissive children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p15" pid="l2gd65KWEkmbrlZq_ieTmg" hash="sRebxg">When nonmembers are first taught gospel truths, with little or no difficulty they believe. They believe in the Savior of the world. They believe in prophets. It seems as though they always have. The premortal existence seems to be common knowledge. The Joseph Smith story is believable and reasonable. They are not the least bit astonished by the coming of angels. They truly do hearken unto the voice of the Good Shepherd and thus truly do come unto God (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/26.21" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 26:21</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.47" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:47</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p16" pid="rSrsFW1vakSwCO9P5BQTxw" hash="L3n4Tw">Their lives teach the basics of prayer, fasting, priesthood blessings. A sister unable to have children has a daughter, receiving that gift indirectly through a blessing given to her husband in which the promise was extended to her. A sick sister is raised at the very moment from her sick-bed by a priesthood blessing. The devil openly opposes the work and as needed is controlled by the priesthood. Servants of the Lord partake of food and water that is poison to them and receive no harm. A sister, as a young girl thousands of miles from her present home, is promised in a patriarchal blessing that one day General Authorities will be served at her humble table. Today she is married to a Lamanite stake president with the prophetic statement fulfilled.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p17" pid="WQdguChnskWSv5R0llsKdw" hash="t5yO5g">Their lives emanate basic truths of kindness, long-suffering, and sacrifice. A man sells his only watch to purchase gasoline for his car so that he might find a man the Brethren desire to interview. A leader who struggles for years to own a car sells it that he might take his family to the temple. Men, women, and children give rings, watches, corn, grain, animals, and even the gold from their teeth that they may show the Lord their desire to help him raise up in their lands a temple to the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p18" pid="oi11j8VBqkutNT7yjG7B9g" hash="SvrWzg">Even though the Spirit has manifested itself in the lives of these people in many miraculous ways, the common way—the most effective way—continues to be by the still small voice simply going forth, converting them “in their inward parts” by the thousands (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/jer/31.33" class="scriptureRef">Jer. 31:33</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p19" pid="QHVv-oZA8EW_u5eApWDhHg" hash="ZLkg0w">These are the children of Lehi, the children of the prophets, great in many respects but blessed, as are all the children of God, according to their righteousness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p20" pid="-gQnbXdULkeySDf_4d_Z3g" hash="eigzhw">None of us would ever boast in our own strength nor in our own wisdom, but as Ammon said about the Lamanites:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p21" pid="XYz9C7oaDE-x5GhDUdVQUg" hash="499OHw">“[Our] joy is full … and [we] will rejoice in [our] God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p22" pid="S4KVV26UYE6U1cnRjvWtwg" hash="USH7JQ">“… For in his strength [we] can do all things; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p23" pid="V7JWLAqwBE62gan3GeiDiQ" hash="Wtgjzg">“… Behold, who can glory too much in the Lord? Yea, who can say too much of his great power, and of his mercy, and of his long-suffering towards the children of men? Behold, [we] say unto you, [we] cannot say the smallest part which [we] feel.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/26.11-12,16" class="scriptureRef">Alma 26:11–12, 16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites.p24" pid="FxDIgR6tbUGfJuk37Wzxew" hash="9jT8eA">My brothers and sisters, we must do all that we have been counseled to do here in this conference. Let us not forget the simple truths—those godly traits, the weightier matters of the law, that have been described (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/23.23" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 23:23</a>). They are the very basics, the essence of the gospel, and possession of them in great abundance by Latter-day Saints will be in the end the greatest miracle of all. Yes, miracles have not ceased. Today is a day of miracles. We believe in miracles. The Latter-day Saints may expect miracles according to their faith in Jesus Christ, the only being under heaven whereby we and all mankind may be saved (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:23</a>), in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1980/10/miracles-among-the-lamanites</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1980-general-conference/1980-10-5030-elder-gene-r-cook-64k-eng.mp3" length="10707025" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 1980 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spiritual Guides for Teachers of Righteousness</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Last summer on a lonely stretch of desert highway, we saw ahead what appeared to be the road covered with water. My children would have wagered their entire savings on that fact. But within a few minutes we were at the distant spot and saw not one dr</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03148_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="2qA3mw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="8WbAgH_G_kGCpEWIe2xxuw" hash="S4vYxA">Spiritual Guides for Teachers of Righteousness</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="AymxZCbHIkmJV-paFOAuGQ" hash="jRdRpw">Gene R. Cook</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a6c.jpg" alt="Elder Gene R. Cook" pid="GmfMl9ljBE6EeNLnhl14Ag" hash="i_yMEA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.p1" pid="D8rW7DinMUKne5XrKaT2AA" hash="F52IYQ">Last summer on a lonely stretch of desert highway, we saw ahead what appeared to be the road covered with water. My children would have wagered their entire savings on that fact. But within a few minutes we were at the distant spot and saw not one drop of water. What an illusion!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.p2" pid="A0k0SWuZnk2lTgosd0WaMg" hash="pUsBKA">How many things there are in this life that appear to be one way and all of a sudden are the reverse. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/62.41" class="scriptureRef">Alma 62:41</a>.) Satan operates that way. He is the master of illusion. He creates illusions in an attempt to detour, dilute, and divert the power and the attention of the Latter-day Saints from the pure truth of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.p3" pid="gtoozaN1_UKVYyK4z-aoJg" hash="qBV4yQ">He is particularly effective at creating spiritual illusions that cause a counterfeiting of spirituality, a spiritual instability, a self-deception—spiritual illnesses sowed in the heart little by little to harden the hearts of men and to lead them into sin and away from God. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/12.17" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 12:17</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/6.15" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 6:15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.p4" pid="4-qZw0maK0e8y0tYkemSnw" hash="5eoh8w">May I share a few of Satan’s cunning illusions which undermine spirituality. Satan, with an illusion, leads a man to puff himself up with pride to say, “I am my own man. I know the Lord lives, but he expects me to handle this particular matter on my own and not bother him with any details.” Not being familiar with the scriptures, the man may not know that Satan teaches the world there is no God. But to the Saints he simply says, “There is a God, but he is only <span class="emphasis">generally</span> involved in your life. He would not <span class="emphasis">specifically</span> help you today.” Or he teaches the world not to pray, but to the Saints he simply says, “Don’t pray now. You don’t feel like praying right now.” (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/32.8-9" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 32:8–9</a>.) The net effect is the same.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.p5" pid="KORMyfkl8E2ViJSFoQRwMw" hash="CiAMJw">Satan, in another illusion of vain imagination, teaches a man that the man is spiritual and humble. He begins to believe it and then acts in the eyes of the people as if he were. He begins to drift but full well believes, because of the illusions being created, that he is still on the strait and narrow. He develops a holier-than-thou attitude, but in his heart he is hardened, “past feeling” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.45" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:45</a>), and prideful. The master of illusion teaches men to honor the Lord with their lips, while their hearts are far from the Lord. (See <a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.19" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.p6" pid="qEdXUPEE20mxGiKDdZKDlA" hash="GBSbFw">With others he disguises truth and equates spirituality with knowledge, with little or no emphasis on application of truths in personal lives. The man goes along his own way imagining himself to be learned, leaning on his own understanding (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/3.5" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 3:5</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/9.28" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 9:28</a>), seeking the honor and esteem of men, and feeling it is sufficient to teach and not to do. The knowledge then, in and of itself, becomes an illusion and a stumbling block to maintaining the Spirit of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.p7" pid="RtsA0eZo1EWaOdI2eZyoPQ" hash="gL2yDQ">Still others the Lord blesses with great material blessings. But then Satan cunningly creates illusions and reverses the use of these blessings. He leads one to set his heart on the things of this world. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.35" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:35</a>.) The man begins not to esteem his brethren as himself, but creates divisions, inequalities, or status distinctions among the people. Yes, Satan has been a liar from the beginning; he is “the author of all sin. … He doth carry on his works of darkness … as he can get hold upon the hearts of the children of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/6.30" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 6:30</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.p8" pid="MKegSf0Yr0aAT5sPpn7w-g" hash="03Swqg">In this world of illusions, Satan sows selfishness, unbelief, fear, doubt, greed, spiritual instability, and a general concern for self into men’s hearts. He is a master builder of spiritual detours to waste time, divert attention from that which is good, and diminish spiritual receptivity. Satan especially desires to deceive the Latter-day Saints, those who know the truth about him, those who can particularly influence others in their teaching and living of the gospel in the home, in the classroom, from the pulpit, and in the world. In these days of increasing deception, and more to come, one must be aware of Satan’s spiritual snares and be sure of his own discernment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.p9" pid="uc3WYTeGH0mQeYAgE8dg-A" hash="PLanDA">I would like to suggest eight standards against which a person can measure his own teaching of the gospel as well as the doctrines taught by others, to help him unravel illusions and discern the truth. These standards might be entitled “Spiritual Guides for Teachers of Righteousness.”</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.f2">
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="vjxbnDZmt0yHsVS7k16vYA" hash="09doPA">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="QJRDU7ZOS0Oz4t-dbGgY_g" hash="vd-4rg">Not only will the teacher teach the truth, but the Spirit of the Lord will accompany the truth <span class="emphasis">and</span> the teacher. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/50.17-22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 50:17–22</a>.) Both should be subject to spiritual confirmation at any time. The teacher will not teach without authority nor speak independently for himself, knowing that even the very elect can be deceived. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/24.24" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 24:24</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="cmXaP720K0-k5S11XVx4Qg" hash="eIcmvA">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="BBp-oT4s6UatPBJVcg3KrA" hash="u_1gTA">The teacher will be in accord with the General Authorities as a group and with his local leaders, knowing they are guides to safety. He will have desires to follow and conform to their teachings and example in all their spiritual and temporal declarations, knowing the Lord gives them the gifts of discernment. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/46.27" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 46:27</a>.) He will not complain, criticize, or speak evilly of the Lord’s anointed, knowing that such a practice is an early warning sign of apostasy.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="bi10RWEhz0Oa5Td8X3R5ag" hash="jJalzQ">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="ktMV91Pq0kC6wwUT2H8icw" hash="837b_Q">The teacher of righteousness will teach from the holy scriptures and will teach that which is taught and confirmed by the Holy Ghost. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/52.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 52:9</a>.) He will not “teach for doctrines the commandments of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.19" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:19</a>.) He will not mingle the history and opinions of men with the scriptures nor spend religious instruction time teaching speculation or the philosophies of the world, thereby giving Satan’s views exposure. He will not teach “doctrines” upon which the Lord’s prophet has not spoken. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/28.2-3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 28:2–3</a>.) He knows that the scriptures lead one to faith on the Lord and unto repentance, which bring a change of heart. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/15.7" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 15:7</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.8" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:8</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="IsfwwoGbq0S265xRmpakxw" hash="mdbNHA">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="l27i_A4Rr0SwcAzVijmyKQ" hash="Che0Jg">The teacher will teach in simplicity, according to the true needs of the people, basic gospel doctrines like faith, repentance, and prayer, which all men—all men—can apply. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/19.31" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 19:31</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/26.22" class="scriptureRef">Alma 26:22</a>.) He will not look beyond the mark by exaggerating, by teaching in the fringe areas, by expanding on the scriptures, or by teaching exotic extremes in any principle, like excessively lengthy prayers, false doctrines about the Savior or about Adam, or extremes in diet, or politics, or investments. He will remember that Satan works in the extremes. He knows of the exactness of the Lord’s doctrine, but also of “temperance in all things.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/12.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 12:8</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="XhvwaLSgG0C0hfGI6xjZPA" hash="MQXWPw">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p pid="7iHP_ydTEkWWnrBQ0kFs9Q" hash="CCawFQ">The teacher will speak in the light of day. (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.15,18-19" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:15, 18–19</a>.) He will not speak of secret doctrines, of special elite groups “in the know,” or of secret ordinations. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.13" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:13</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.11" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:11</a>.) Whatever he does will be in the plain view of the people. He knows that doctrines and ordinations are subject to the open view and vote of the Saints.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="FFRQaSODBk6zW6D6t7RpUA" hash="TkXAow">
          <span class="label">6.</span>
          <p pid="kYF7e4Mt9UeT0VjVGFi9ww" hash="s-agCQ">The teacher will treat all those being taught as like unto himself, not esteeming himself above his brethren. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/2.17" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 2:17</a>.) He will seek excellence before the Lord, but not to excel over his companions in the work. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.40-41" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:40–41</a>.) He knows that “none is acceptable before God, save the meek and lowly in heart.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.44" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:44</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="4rja__Yi5026Q6T1ZXgggA" hash="MZfeLQ">
          <span class="label">7.</span>
          <p pid="WlxCfbXxpkqSDrN_dp1v1g" hash="AhczsA">The teacher of righteousness will be anxious to glorify the Lord. He will refuse to assume any glory unto himself. He will not practice priestcrafts—that is, preaching and holding himself up as a light to the world for gain or for the honor of men. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/26.29" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 26:29</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.26" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:26</a>.) He will be a preacher of righteousness speaking forcefully against sin, having an eye single to God, not to personal gain, honor, or popularity among men. He knows worldly aspirations leave the door open wide to apostasy.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="cBlLNvQ9Pk2d40xWW_0sJw" hash="KxFKLQ">
          <span class="label">8.</span>
          <p pid="cxLNsLeYQkC5EW0piaEP4g" hash="AWT_SA">The teacher himself will be in the process of continual personal repentance. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/8.26" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 8:26</a>.) He will be an example of meekness, charity, pure motives, dependence on the Lord. He will not just be teaching the doctrine, but also applying it. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/41.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 41:5</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/52.15-16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 52:15–16</a>.) All in all, it will be evident whom he represents.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.p10" pid="BGi29V0lBk2Li-Z-kLj0gg" hash="N-IvQQ">In summary, then, how does one keep himself from falling, as some have, into teaching and living semi-truths? Is it not by maintaining his own spirituality? What is true spirituality? Is it knowledge, intellect, academic learning? Perhaps more than anything else it is an ongoing, purifying condition of the heart. It is an eye single to God. It is a broken heart and a contrite spirit. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/9.20" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 9:20</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/136.32-33" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 136:32–33</a>.) It is a “full purpose of heart.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.p11" pid="tLHY8yPedEWkQAs8RVMigw" hash="_YYJJw">As I have had opportunity over the years to be among the Brethren, the one distinguishing characteristic that seems to be found in all of them, as well as in other spiritual leaders, is their intense desire to take upon them the name of the Lord with “full purpose of heart,” a desire to serve the Lord above all else, at any cost. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.27-28,38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:27–28, 38</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.p12" pid="7YoRTeRf0kWR7JklrgQeWQ" hash="jzFCJQ">It should not surprise one to see that the Lord’s requirements to serve him in church callings are conditions of the heart (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/4.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 4</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/12.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 12:8</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/41.11" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 41:11</a>), nor that the Lord has said, “I, the Lord, will judge all men according to their works, according to the desire of their hearts.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/137.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 137:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.p13" pid="mYodOGArlUepwopO4nNFDA" hash="AsmE-Q">Brothers and sisters, no Latter-day Saint will go astray if he will follow the inspired counsel of the Lord and his servants. I testify that if a man will maintain his own spirituality—</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.f3">
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="A6qviQVq90CHOmYCy6V8bw" hash="BKUUpw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="XAEdxRRveE6aua-womrFOg" hash="3YM3fA">by praying without ceasing,</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="7s1qObxYdk6arQ_m_E4d-g" hash="fplLuA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="603t58mIRECPn6nVqUP4cg" hash="sZuYyw">by studying and pondering the scriptures continually, and</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="AbU8VSEfIEia1akHYJezBQ" hash="-vUKIw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="a2R2NzkdB0aGaQkBqiDs3Q" hash="IHcivg">by obeying his leaders and the light and truth that he presently understands—</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.p14" pid="WAGWhahEfEuWzCX0LHB7tg" hash="10Wccg">He will not be deceived.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness.p15" pid="4KMy2O9EVkmrvFgMSHfE0Q" hash="-48WGA">May the Lord bless all of us not to be fooled by illusions created by the devil. May we maintain our spiritual fine-tuning by yielding our hearts to God, becoming firmer and firmer in the faith (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/3.35" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 3:35</a>), is my prayer in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1982/04/spiritual-guides-for-teachers-of-righteousness</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1982-general-conference/1982-04-2060-elder-gene-r-cook-64k-eng.mp3" length="5522822" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1982 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home and Family: A Divine Eternal Pattern</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Thank you, Sister Smith, from all the sisters of the Church, and certainly all the brethren as well. We appreciate your service and that of Sister Cannon.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03174_000_016" doc-version="2" hash="35Raow">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="43xWLl5fv0Kne0_pfjrFcQ" hash="aLFF5Q">Home and Family:</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="io-CrVsJEkuENXrow6WhSQ" hash="37N0RA">A Divine Eternal Pattern</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="6I8Ixt5SIUenu59lVIniXA" hash="jRdRpw">Gene R. Cook</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a6c.jpg" alt="Elder Gene R. Cook" pid="IApkhJIt2EWh2_w9eb_nkg" hash="i_yMEA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p1" pid="NNqFwXZqrEyuUXjDQkBhcA" hash="YFXm7A">Thank you, Sister Smith, from all the sisters of the Church, and certainly all the brethren as well. We appreciate your service and that of Sister Cannon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p2" pid="Orbu1ab3DEqRvWCFMheP6g" hash="SoooTg">Some years ago a fire erupted in the middle of the night and completely destroyed a family’s home. A neighbor came by to console a seven-year-old, not knowing that he was about to be taught a great principle. “Johnny, it’s sure too bad your home burned down.” Johnny thought a moment and then said, “Oh, that’s where you’re mistaken, Mr. Brown. That was not our home; that was just our house. We still have our home, we just don’t have any place to put it right now.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p3" pid="a4-m_pnhlUGI24OjLen67g" hash="I2qLtw">What a great principle taught by a child about home. What does that word bring to your mind—<span class="emphasis">home?</span> To some, an edifice. To others, a place to sleep, a place to eat, a place where worldly goods are stored.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p4" pid="6zW43XGslUOw6pDRIht4WQ" hash="RILFpw">Yet to others more spiritually inclined, it might mean where family is, where my heart is, a sacred place, a peaceful place, an escape from a wicked world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p5" pid="jQOpUFYgzkWr22oKZmGsaA" hash="Kti8Gw">The still small voice whispers yet a deeper meaning. Home is heaven. We are strangers here on earth. My real home is not here, but there. My challenge is to learn how to bring about a home here on earth similar to the celestial one I left. The Lord said that we were taught “even before [we] were born.” We “received [our] first lessons in the world of spirits and were prepared to come forth … to labor in his vineyard for the salvation of the souls of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/138.56" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 138:56</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p6" pid="k28D-c78bkmXqcFRer5B9Q" hash="W57Ifw">Thus, we were taught to labor in the vineyard, a good part of which, perhaps the most important part, was to know how to labor at home. We were taught by the Lord, by the best of all teachers. Perhaps, therefore, the relearning here on earth, with our agency, is to largely experience and rediscover the teachings in the flesh.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p7" pid="CddWhZthsE25yQgZrbcqqg" hash="HA9D4g">How might I remember and rediscover what I once knew? The Lord answers, “Pray and I will make known unto you things from the foundation of the world according to your faith and holy works.” (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/12.30" class="scriptureRef">Alma 12:30</a>.) “I will bring all things back to your remembrance, whatsoever I have said unto you” (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.26" class="scriptureRef">John 14:26</a> and <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/12.30" class="scriptureRef">Alma 12:30</a>) “and will enlarge the memory of this people.” (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.8" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p8" pid="cpFp0NLPFEu8Eyq6fYj-LQ" hash="3ZX1RA">At times when one speaks of home and family, some who are single, widowed, a single parent, or a grandparent might be tempted to feel these teachings don’t apply to them. But may I remind all that when the Lord sent us here for our individual growth, he sent us to live with and be nurtured spiritually and temporally by a family. The Lord organized the whole earth this way. There is no other way to enter mortality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p9" pid="h9eSs1K6-EOboIyldUFK-Q" hash="UNpU-w">Yet some still say, “I don’t have a family. I’m all alone.” May I remind you that you always were and ever will be a member of the family of God. You are his son or his daughter. It doesn’t matter if your <span class="emphasis">parents</span> or <span class="emphasis">spouse</span> or <span class="emphasis">brothers</span> or <span class="emphasis">sisters</span> are <span class="emphasis">members, nonmembers, living,</span> or <span class="emphasis">dead,</span> they are still your family. And if you are righteous and faithful to the end, no matter what your present status, you ultimately will be blessed as part of a family unit. Thus, it behooves all of us to learn and live, to the degree we can in our present situation, the principles governing family life in preparation for exaltation, whether we’re a parent, grandparent, brother, sister, uncle, aunt, or a child—whether we are <span class="emphasis">single</span> or <span class="emphasis">married.</span> This is the Lord’s pattern, His expanded view of the word <span class="emphasis">family.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p10" pid="dRBGdZ1EmkS7C59Hn2dRJA" hash="EooV6w">Thus, hearken all ye families of the earth, immediate and extended families, yea, every living soul, and the Lord will teach you of the sacredness of that heavenly organization called <span class="emphasis">family,</span> called <span class="emphasis">home.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p11" pid="HyTQewRqFEi7Y1ZYoTMB7w" hash="fr_hQw">Brothers and sisters, for just a moment, please imagine yourselves as if you were in the premortal existence, in that council in heaven, yes, even a council of the Father’s own family. Could the Father not have spoken words such as these to all of us: “My children, my children,</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.f2">
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="d_QsU-u_60ik4i-aBTSugQ" hash="0psZuQ">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="CRGfHtEeH0Goq04Kp7IAMw" hash="65HhJQ">“Marriage on earth will be ordained of God unto man.” (See D&amp;C 49:15–16; D&amp;C 131:1–4.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="WYInazscZUGS2GHDuy6t7Q" hash="524BpQ">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="Otq0W_-cYkSkWk2LXf7gAw" hash="bxqF6g">“By divine decree, you will be copartners with God in bringing children to earth.” (See Gen. 1:22, 28; 2 Ne. 2:22–23; D&amp;C 132:63.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="N5T1Em9bV0m8qmfBvOlxDA" hash="UmscAw">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="rPRWZ6HInUOUEa8QEcKVKA" hash="o5ZtZw">“The family unit will be the principal agency for the spiritual and temporal nurturing of the individual.” (See Mosiah 4:14–15; D&amp;C 68:25, 28.)</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p12" pid="YrdfRrRpcUSVogWnuQdiiQ" hash="asMFBg">The Father, perhaps continuing, might have said: “When you go to earth—</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.f3">
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="ZjnYTq9dIEKUzZm0-vlrSg" hash="QYWJ7A">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="qlnFxWR5NUG9oszAF0dNxQ" hash="c3bgYg">“Teach your children to love the Lord thy God with all thine heart” (see Deut. 6:5–7),</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="IfeD8c7Wa0GUBlMwdH-KuQ" hash="VfvVdw">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p pid="TexZMLXA8ESYbTKt4cAw6A" hash="-VHoog">“And to love and to serve one another.” (See Mosiah 4:15.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="xmX_81OXDkm5M0gSE4VDrg" hash="ebvQYA">
          <span class="label">6.</span>
          <p pid="6d9tDJrkREuHcatGdxvtFw" hash="cwdRkw">“Pray in your families, both morning, mid-day, and evening, and I will quicken your memory of these teachings.” (See 3 Ne. 18:21; Alma 34:21, 27; D&amp;C 68:28.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="uugF3Q9hw0u0r-NhlNu04A" hash="tcoCiA">
          <span class="label">7.</span>
          <p pid="F_wz1tZrTUeRINTKwuR-tw" hash="tEleCg">“On earth, teach them repentance, faith in Christ, baptism, the gift of the Holy Ghost, priesthood covenants, and temple ordinances.” (See D&amp;C 68:25, 27; D&amp;C 132:19.) Grandparents, uncles and aunts, you can help.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="e8NbkZly00W2PFQnMalPsw" hash="1YHcCw">
          <span class="label">8.</span>
          <p pid="qux4FydcD0KgwNTVg_EhsA" hash="8KIlnQ">“Consecrate your family resources to the Lord. Be free with your substance.” (See D&amp;C 42:30–31; Jacob 2:17; D&amp;C 119:1–7.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="YTZ6055vpkmq74vw9S5DRg" hash="9NRU1A">
          <span class="label">9.</span>
          <p pid="B-EQFjbRGEm9_08TvKY9YA" hash="T3zGTg">“Provoke not your children to wrath” (see Eph. 6:4),</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="l1kdeclPLEiOzfhqBjEdVA" hash="s1Zb4Q">
          <span class="label">10.</span>
          <p pid="23Px12iCuUypxACrO6zupg" hash="wlBTeg">“Neither suffer that they fight and quarrel one with another, thus sowing seeds of contention.” (See Mosiah 4:14.)</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.f4">
	<p pid="qp1JyZeZ20O5vzsApS1s4Q" hash="rtEklA">Perhaps He continued, saying:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="BD-gL8waOEG3Zh4eJeWDYw" hash="Uo-v8g">
          <span class="label">11.</span>
          <p pid="D3P2NfAaXkGcryxddKU_nA" hash="2XCV8Q">“Fathers to be, you will learn what true spiritual leadership is mostly at home, not so much in the world.</p>
          <p pid="MxBQRzgqn0-sbgIJcbZJQg" hash="khSN0g">“<span class="emphasis">Mothers,</span> yours will be a sacred call unlike any other, <span class="emphasis">to raise these little children so that they will be like I am.</span> Unless you all become as little children, you will not be able to return home to me.”</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="yQpN90njjkm6kDc7qlCZzg" hash="BZ-lLA">
          <span class="label">12.</span>
          <p pid="aNB5t-ErbEu24VMvKJtgWg" hash="nNgOFw">“Learn your duty from living prophets and from the scriptures.”</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="3ZrbhnDAN0qbl-0fAcn75w" hash="aiXUeg">
          <span class="label">13.</span>
          <p pid="-sly1VY0UUi6tDJ6i9d_rw" hash="KfJqfA">“Lastly, because of the sacred nature of parenthood, I will personally teach you, through the Holy Ghost, those things that matter most. Stay close to me; humbly ask for help.”</p>
          <p pid="RbP4bykZ80-YDcYib5_V_Q" hash="clmXNg">Perhaps the Father continued, saying, “My children, there are also a number of cautions I would give you, because the influence of the world will be so strong.”</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.f5">
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="ypwTbLDkckaV8L9G06Hp0w" hash="5KO6yw">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="BN09hKNK-E-W3-HAMJwHHw" hash="mIpebQ">“There will be heavy influence to maintain families small. However, remember, ‘As arrows are in the hand of a mighty man; so are children. … Happy is the man that hath his quiver full of them.’” (Ps. 127:4–5.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="bl7TgCuHSEWrWuVu0wqQDg" hash="RXndSg">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="ZcD6LaYQakmVbAHJYE83lw" hash="Wbg40Q">“On earth, remember to keep your family responsibilities as a priority. There will be many who will want to encroach upon your responsibility for teaching and providing activities for your family. Never forget that yours is the primary responsibility and that your ultimate success in all other endeavors will be in direct proportion to the attention given these divinely appointed relationships.” (See D&amp;C 88:119.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="JC9gWsz8hke-YEagUBBf7A" hash="hOb1-A">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="ETJoZgKock-l0lTHlXaGmA" hash="x0HcBg">“Strive to be together. Avoid activities and those that would pull you apart. Remember, where love runs deep, so can hurt feelings and frictions, as love may become frustrated.” (See 2 Ne. 1:14, 21.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Zhc1EVtw6kafNP8MtaYb5A" hash="xnQAdQ">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="rV5Twk7Ack-wQC5ABT9UhA" hash="edAiRA">“As children, be sure to give heed to your father and mother, remembering that I, the Lord, have placed them over you. Honor them.” (See Ex. 20:12.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="0WmYri9W-EuU4EPCcVCp0w" hash="r1kIYA">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p pid="GcIU4O8S2ki1tfjghyVB7A" hash="yGBvIg">“When you go to earth, children, remember that once you are a parent you will always be a parent. Whether it be a grandparent, a great-grandparent, or a parent as I am. Your responsibilities to preside go on through the generations to assist in turning the hearts of the children to their fathers. Resist the temptation to be uninvolved, retiring from your family and doing your own thing. As grandparents, your wisdom and vision will allow you to draw together your whole family which I, the Lord, have given you.” (See Mosiah 2:5.)</p>
          <p pid="LCSctvNQtkKV6XCJaYRVdQ" hash="a62iZw">Brothers and sisters, perhaps he concluded,</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="bAWw4x39VE2duiJF8P-ixw" hash="FacLFQ">
          <span class="label">6.</span>
          <p pid="GJOZPPkJikGMghf4vrIETg" hash="2VVi1w">“My children, don’t be too concerned about remembering these things. You will find that when these things are taught to you they will seem strangely familiar, as if you always knew them. You did, because you experienced it all here in your heavenly home.” (See 1 Ne. 15:8, 11.)</p>
          <p pid="SXnox6iebECajO-EbbMDUA" hash="X9Xsvg">“You will suffer affliction with your children in allowing them to grow and develop, just as I have suffered affliction with you. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/133.52-53" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 133:52–53</a>.) But don’t be afraid; I have given mine angels charge concerning you. Those sent from my very presence to be round about you, to bear you up. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.42,88" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:42, 88</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/133.53" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 133:53</a>.) This is your opportunity to experience what we have taught you. Follow the promptings. We love you.”</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p13" pid="9H1NNli8qUifTIAQFUYPFQ" hash="9pAYWA">Brothers and sisters, in conclusion may I say, where possible:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p14" pid="HpIma1NThkWzJnqc4Nherg" hash="_0OtDw">Parents, whatever you are doing, <span class="emphasis">return home.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p15" pid="_IxyjtH-ukWHfGm_oXcb4g" hash="4n7-CA">Children, wherever you are, no matter what your failure, problem, or sin, you will always be loved by your family. <span class="emphasis">Go home.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p16" pid="H7KQ1u5raUi97uuqppEJTg" hash="grxfQA">Grandparents, brothers, sisters, uncles, aunts, draw your families together. <span class="emphasis">Return home.</span> May the concept of home be exalted, because the Lord so organized it in the beginning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p17" pid="ZTF604ft506uLis7dOne0g" hash="WB9_xw">I pay tribute to my grandparents, to my parents, especially to my wife, and to my children, in having made my home the best place in all the world. There’s no place in all the earth I would rather be than at home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p18" pid="fB-stBT8i0etEsKE9YfdlA" hash="J_iMaw">And lastly, may the day come when these praises about home and family we will all sing:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.f6">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="CF4buI_FuEqn0_su5oeCkQ" hash="cwVjYA">
            <span class="emphasis">O my Father, Thou that dwellest</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="oRlGNVuGpUWxbSMmkbiVNA" hash="IuTLbg">
            <span class="emphasis">In the high and glorious place,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="FX1ooNF9HE6fo6WSoSTW6Q" hash="8PqqUA">
            <span class="emphasis">When shall I regain thy presence,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="ulRSDMxcq0SPSBYnOYqCUg" hash="FC-xMQ">
            <span class="emphasis">And again behold Thy face?</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="M3U_9YHrOESzKjAYwbNhLQ" hash="Pyr04w">
            <span class="emphasis">In the heavens are parents single?</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="lZUS4ZjT8kaadKF4ofAsZw" hash="RAMP9g">
            <span class="emphasis">No; the thought makes reason stare!</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="gkflgYS6fU69pLCIAkns3Q" hash="q_KmjQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Truth is reason, truth eternal</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="pQ2DpMXP9kWoHzaF8eES_Q" hash="_b34mw">
            <span class="emphasis">Tells me I’ve a mother there.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="uoBI-dkk00SKb8sKaQpHuw" hash="ZkIXsg">
            <span class="emphasis">When I leave this frail existence,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="LLDxOyz0iU67N9dxXlx-bw" hash="8Xww9Q">
            <span class="emphasis">When I lay this mortal by,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="wg0zeGtVHU2OVdPAHqPT2A" hash="thyJDw">
            <span class="emphasis">Father, Mother, may I meet you</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="zjNgQnFjK0GQw2HNtL1BQQ" hash="QEZS0w">
            <span class="emphasis">In your royal courts on high?</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="CO5TByxQCkmPCkQo4NMnJg" hash="chfEPA">
            <span class="emphasis">Then, at length, when I’ve completed</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="dOCferadnUqOxk51s1O6jQ" hash="AlGBlg">
            <span class="emphasis">All you sent me forth to do,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="BvByZKjwOEWvGIwwgKgO9Q" hash="mzgo6w">
            <span class="emphasis">With your mutual approbation</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="9WE27o_6G02POo7zD2qPyA" hash="6Q9Aqg">
            <span class="emphasis">Let me come [home] and dwell with you.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern.p19" pid="GEL2gle6lkCgFVAklC2icA" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1984/04/home-and-family-a-divine-eternal-pattern</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1984-general-conference/1984-04-2080-elder-gene-r-cook-64k-eng.mp3" length="5400965" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 1984 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inviting Others to “Come unto Christ”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Dear brethren of the priesthood, I greet you this evening in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ with the sacred injunction, “Come unto Christ.” (.)</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03232_000_016" doc-version="2" hash="uKDmfg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="jyylXPMb0kiyXe3fgWFThg" hash="HqBzAg">Inviting Others to “Come unto Christ”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="8BtD6WHukEGBrAW3YToe-g" hash="jRdRpw">Gene R. Cook</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1f08.jpg" alt="Elder Gene R. Cook" pid="-aK_oipBLEymhyCRlOjPRQ" hash="RPfV-A" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.p1" pid="tgbdPdNFo0SyJQRpJ1z1qQ" hash="2NzhYA">Dear brethren of the priesthood, I greet you this evening in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ with the sacred injunction, “Come unto Christ.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.32" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:32</a>.)</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="X5xMa7aghkKgkzSOXdgZwA" hash="kPDM3g">A Divine Commission to Bring Souls to God</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.p2" pid="ImmsF3mWoEylSqZFBdEY-A" hash="_Ygfvw">I testify that the Lord expects us to bring souls unto Him by inviting all men to come unto Christ, and by so doing, find Him ourselves. It truly is “the thing … of the most worth unto you.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/15.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 15:6</a>.) In fact, your very ordination is “to preach faith and repentance and remission of sins, according to [his] word” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/53.3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 53:3</a>), “that you may bring souls unto [him].” It is the greatest offering that man can give to God. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/15.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 15:6</a>; see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/29.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 29:7</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/17.11" class="scriptureRef">Alma 17:11</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/29.9" class="scriptureRef">Alma 29:9</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/31.34-35" class="scriptureRef">Alma 31:34–35</a>). In fact, you “received [your] first lessons in the world of spirits and were prepared to [labor] for the salvation of the souls of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/138.56" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 138:56</a>.) You cannot fail. That counsel applies to you young men as well.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.p3" pid="Qy2Rpa65_ECjSz245rn4_Q" hash="_0KokQ">Perhaps we are at the time in our ministry when, in preparation for the Lord’s second coming, when with renewed emphasis, <span class="emphasis">in love,</span> we must call men to repentance. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:9</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/11.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 11:9</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:14</a>.) We must invite them to “come unto Christ” testifying boldly in His name to bring the “mighty change” into the hearts of our people. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/5.2" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 5:2</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.14" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:14</a>.)</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="1OUjBBqDnkSQ_7X-ZV9dXA" hash="cNwTGw">The Purpose of Visits to Homes</h3>
        <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.f2">
	  <p pid="FSzvSWZUSka50-74KOQuqg" hash="75Jmsg">As Aaronic and Melchizedek Priesthood brethren, we are commissioned with a purpose to “visit the house of each member,” (D&amp;C 20:47) to:</p>
	  <ol class="symbol">
	    <li>
	      <p pid="M6Ll_c9-DEWjVVeacIzsMg" hash="I2lXlg">—</p>
	      <p pid="5FVoRqGQHE2-DHGAqOxtBA" hash="jMQtrw">To exhort them “to pray vocally and in secret” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.47" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:47</a>);</p>
	    </li>
	    <li>
	      <p pid="xcBMcMK3Yk-HEayF8ze_Qw" hash="I2lXlg1">—</p>
	      <p pid="iodFTNrDC0OmZWXPfshBjw" hash="wV5iJA">“To stir them up in remembrance” of God (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/4.19" class="scriptureRef">Alma 4:19</a>); and</p>
	    </li>
	    <li>
	      <p pid="8tnu9EFskEGPQSyRqIMalg" hash="I2lXlg2">—</p>
	      <p pid="E-o_Nj69mEGYktwk6Edb2A" hash="fv3vvA">“To turn [them] to the Lord with full purpose of heart” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/7.33" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 7:33</a>).</p>
	    </li>
	  </ol>
	</div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.p4" pid="2d5sw2U3EUSv6-I7S7lXMA" hash="Hdsm8A">We do not visit the active just to “visit,” or the less active just to get them out to church, although that may be part of what happens. In essence, we visit to help the heads of those homes, male or female, to become the spiritual leaders in their homes, to lead their families to Christ, to pray, to fast, and to read the scriptures together. If that happens in our visits, all else will take care of itself.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="Y-1FtfEugUqggAFhoVTvYA" hash="C90U6g">“A Preparation to Hear the Word” (Alma 32:6; Alma 33:22–23; Alma 34:3)</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.p5" pid="Itz8JGc0zEO2_Z8tRIZV-w" hash="NBjVfA">How can we make such visits with power and authority, as described in the scriptures, especially to the less active? The most important element in our preparation is to humble ourselves mightily before God. We must be believing. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/90.24" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 90:24</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/morm/9.27" class="scriptureRef">Morm. 9:27</a>.) We must not doubt nor fear. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:36</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.p6" pid="6ZMTnCGHy0O7I6wP5_OWSg" hash="wxhuHQ">We must pray fervently throughout our visits that we may “speak the thoughts that [the Lord] shall put into your hearts, and you shall not be confounded before men; for it shall be given you … in the very moment, what ye shall say.” Even “that portion that shall be meted unto every man.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/100.5-6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 100:5–6</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.85" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:85</a>.)</p>
        <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.f3">
	  <p pid="fpjHjKuhw0mCAxqrsXg5EA" hash="XZVNKQ">The results of these kinds of visits testify of themselves. For example:</p>
	  <ol class="symbol">
	    <li>
	      <p pid="tSlmfCyhRkGMxIhW5mM3Mg" hash="I2lXlg3">—</p>
	      <p pid="hMvfXx5QeEegGCcEQi3fQA" hash="3_pDzQ">On a first visit, a man quits smoking after twenty-five years and prays to God to know the next step.</p>
	    </li>
	    <li>
	      <p pid="mCBGQqxYz0aGj3NB4SM-FQ" hash="I2lXlg4">—</p>
	      <p pid="NO6xVU0yuEWkOWvX4CX8CA" hash="GD2NEw">A less-active man says, “I’ve been waiting for you.”</p>
	    </li>
	    <li>
	      <p pid="NJzCCOLdkEm62N1Y_QA3yw" hash="I2lXlg5">—</p>
	      <p pid="N1VZRr02XUGp1fuZdwBzaw" hash="10Fjjg">A wife tells of her less-active husband’s dream that “messengers would be sent” and says, “We will believe whatever you tell us.”</p>
	    </li>
	    <li>
	      <p pid="r9sckaG_0k2epRj7lNv92Q" hash="I2lXlg6">—</p>
	      <p pid="Y139C3MGxkGa1tD9sHHZ_A" hash="r0UeVg">An unscheduled phone call is made at a critical moment, touching a woman who was turning to inactivity.</p>
	    </li>
	  </ol>
	</div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.p7" pid="W8rL7sutFEiQFhxanUw3Ow" hash="11Mpog">Someone said, “Coincidences like these are God’s little miracles wherein he desired to remain anonymous.”</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="QLNo6g6XOU26rgjYGgO56w" hash="bPex9w">The Visits—Suggestions for Preparing Men’s Hearts</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.p8" pid="k38eNKIyjE6CSKxpb5xMIg" hash="pzzpvQ">Remember, not only the teacher but the learner must have the Spirit of the Lord. You, as the teacher, must do all in your power to <span class="emphasis">prepare the hearts of men</span> so the Spirit can teach. May I suggest seven scriptural performances (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/31.10" class="scriptureRef">Alma 31:10</a>) that, if humbly employed, will immediately invite the Spirit into your heart and the hearts of others. You may want to write them down.</p>
        <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.f4">
	  <ol class="number">
	    <li pid="KZDYoJpgNU2hj8qJ5qLxkA" hash="QBozpg">
            <span class="label">1.</span>
            <p pid="ElhE0RXjd0GGRYA095Wk9Q" hash="3TZNYw">
              <span class="emphasis">Pray. </span>Pray for the Spirit. Ask those you teach to pray for you and for themselves while you are teaching. Ask for discernment to understand the needs of those you visit. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.2-3" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:2–3</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/20.1" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 20:1</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/136.29,32" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 136:29, 32</a>.) For example:</p>
            <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.f5">
		<ol class="symbol">
		  <li>
		    <p pid="ECyCn2yJf02RdUHD5SYiAA" hash="I2lXlg7">—</p>
		    <p pid="cWxCxfyGQ02IiqSb_igQrg" hash="Sty07g">During a visit, upon bended knee, two priesthood leaders pray that a wayward daughter will be blessed. Her parents are touched by the prayer and repent that very evening. They begin to attend church and a temple preparation seminar and now have been sealed as a family.</p>
		  </li>
		  <li>
		    <p pid="oRFvzO4zO0KHc1Hnxi2yfA" hash="I2lXlg8">—</p>
		    <p pid="r1fELi1SX0Cu-w4_cSCxVw" hash="B09DNg">A seven-year-old responds to his less-active father, who says he won’t pray, with “Please pray, Dad. Take Mom and me to the temple.” That family has since been sealed.</p>
		  </li>
		</ol>
	      </div>
          </li>
	    <li pid="by24EobatE6fWyRXrr_KQQ" hash="TN8Ebw">
            <span class="label">2.</span>
            <p pid="UMqTQfTUi0y6Ky_SJayqtg" hash="vDa9yA">
              <span class="emphasis">Use the Scriptures. </span>They are the words of the Lord to us, and the Spirit of the Lord will speak through them to all, both young and old. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/32.3" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 32:3</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/31.5" class="scriptureRef">Alma 31:5</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/32.4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 32:4</a>.) For example:</p>
            <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.f6">
		<ol class="symbol">
		  <li>
		    <p pid="mhOo-PRt40SI_8Ox7a5X8A" hash="I2lXlg9">—</p>
		    <p pid="jABBvjn0qkGXexXbx4g5xQ" hash="7FSC4Q">In one of the visits, a testimony is given of a verse relating to baptism. An investigator says, “I do believe God sent you. I’ll be baptized.”</p>
		  </li>
		  <li>
		    <p pid="ixfy8niS4E2wnWyeTN8PoQ" hash="I2lXlg10">—</p>
		    <p pid="V8H5LfTQiUCLDTOeIPtkwQ" hash="wzcRQw">A scripture is read on another visit about multiplying and replenishing the earth. A young couple with one child humbly confesses their unrighteous decision to have no more children.</p>
		  </li>
		</ol>
	      </div>
          </li>
	    <li pid="EhnIWb2ROUmmkuGmagKiNA" hash="vpWprQ">
            <span class="label">3.</span>
            <p pid="S3KKquu210KEZnes0l4bCg" hash="H0GRCA">
              <span class="emphasis">Testify. </span>If you follow His promptings, the Lord will direct you to testify frequently throughout these visits. Testify that the Lord has sent you. As you do, “the Holy Ghost carrieth it unto the hearts of the children of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/33.1" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 33:1</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.44-47" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:44–47</a>.) Let me again illustrate:</p>
            <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.f7">
		<ol class="symbol">
		  <li>
		    <p pid="ZbTrryJkd0aCQPNcxoRaYQ" hash="I2lXlg11">—</p>
		    <p pid="AI2UGhM15U20MjRWciYhTg" hash="AK202A">In his testimony, a priesthood leader unknowingly quotes a sentence verbatim from a sister’s patriarchal blessing.</p>
		  </li>
		  <li>
		    <p pid="OU8l7XLt3UGJ3Pbsb7u5tg" hash="I2lXlg12">—</p>
		    <p pid="iHPkXwHUIUSv6Bjlh8-y0A" hash="8t6KVA">Another visit: one member testifies to a couple of life after death from the scriptures only to learn later of the recent loss of their little one.</p>
		  </li>
		</ol>
	      </div>
          </li>
	    <li pid="Z7mZBYBcrUOssng6LZ1xwg" hash="K9lgAQ">
            <span class="label">4.</span>
            <p pid="3PJnH0smQE6M0EMboyUBqA" hash="eG8hNQ">
              <span class="emphasis">Use music. </span>Using recorded hymns or singing the songs of Zion with or to the Saints in their homes, as prompted, will always bring the Spirit of the Lord. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/25.12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 25:12</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/26.30" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 26:30</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/col/3.16" class="scriptureRef">Col. 3:16</a>; <a href="/scriptures/ot/1-sam/16.23" class="scriptureRef">1 Sam. 16:23</a>.) For example:</p>
            <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.f8">
		<ol class="symbol">
		  <li>
		    <p pid="_8g-DtccR02YHU0QWoTJJg" hash="I2lXlg13">—</p>
		    <p pid="VDSFzB_vfESboS8fxgY-8Q" hash="amLwWQ">A priesthood leader said with a smile, “I could never sing. I have a terrible voice. But we were prompted to do so. My voice was as the voice of an angel.” The less-active man wept and returned to the Church.</p>
		  </li>
		  <li>
		    <p pid="GcBeHAsRy0mnNeqhAVhGig" hash="I2lXlg14">—</p>
		    <p pid="N8-p-nGUvUCUNfz_vXxANA" hash="MlQsbQ">A home teacher said, “I sang with his children. The crusty old fellow cried and humbled himself for the first time in years.”</p>
		  </li>
		</ol>
	      </div>
          </li>
	    <li pid="n6DjorNMCEymo61CoBKFpA" hash="vIChPQ">
            <span class="label">5.</span>
            <p pid="mU2EQcD09kaas9vwQH5DAw" hash="X9z-Ww">
              <span class="emphasis">Express love and gratitude to God and man. </span>Express love openly for God and for His children, and the Spirit will be felt profoundly. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/13.34-35" class="scriptureRef">John 13:34–35</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/11.21-23" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 11:21–23</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.47-48" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:47–48</a>.) Let me illustrate:</p>
            <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.f9">
		<ol class="symbol">
		  <li>
		    <p pid="3vJmpSAelUiuUPqHeQstew" hash="I2lXlg15">—</p>
		    <p pid="QFuLTSxF5ESE5Jw1q7zy-Q" hash="5C8HUQ">Touched by the spirit of a visit, a less-active teenager expresses love for his parents, by whose love his heart is turned to God.</p>
		  </li>
		  <li>
		    <p pid="kr-z8ZIl0U2L3e5oGuhWEg" hash="I2lXlg16">—</p>
		    <p pid="ivfV59BMyEeNuP-yeoyiqQ" hash="FzjHyQ">A priesthood leader expresses love to a dissident group of less-active members, and twenty return to sacrament meeting that same day.</p>
		  </li>
		</ol>
	      </div>
          </li>
	    <li pid="uAW_131lGE2x5D51MWodoQ" hash="bBR4gQ">
            <span class="label"></span>
            <p pid="ZwsP3KpBDUuMq3MxyU8Nrw" hash="Pp-GPA">
              <span class="emphasis">Share spiritual experiences. </span>Spiritual experiences have great impact upon men’s souls. Share them as prompted by the Spirit. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/50.21-22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 50:21–22</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.25-37" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:25–37</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/26.1-32" class="scriptureRef">Acts 26:1–32</a>.) For example:</p>
            <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.f10">
		<ol class="symbol">
		  <li>
		    <p pid="mDQ11UzaNk6SZkaqelGeoQ" hash="I2lXlg17">—</p>
		    <p pid="R15t1FypxEGHhIMPERV6eQ" hash="yz28Fw">A less-active husband tells two priesthood leaders of last night’s dream. He repents that very evening as he recounts the experience.</p>
		  </li>
		  <li>
		    <p pid="CTCbGlUQL0-NRhqUXfZ7Zg" hash="I2lXlg18">—</p>
		    <p pid="NEHWEf4Kj02jOyoC-RP5xw" hash="fXGCNg">Two priesthood leaders tell an inspiring missionary story. As a result, two less-active sons are now serving missions.</p>
		  </li>
		</ol>
	      </div>
          </li>
	    <li pid="S8OD2aP50kOr1BbHzHYDZg" hash="W4jcAg">
            <span class="label"></span>
            <p pid="Nst8bqtMc0K0ajUieCRUuA" hash="buOq1Q">
              <span class="emphasis">Perform priesthood ordinances. </span>“In the ordinances … , the power of godliness is manifest.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.20" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:20</a>.) Bless the Saints. Bless the sick. Bless the homes of the Saints. Encourage others to seek for priesthood blessings. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/20.2-9" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 20:2–9</a>.) For example:</p>
            <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.f11">
		<ol class="symbol">
		  <li>
		    <p pid="A_8zaxqlQkq5oG7Eop-i5w" hash="I2lXlg19">—</p>
		    <p pid="HX4ROWIGXEiTK-WKPS-gvA" hash="4Vd4Hw">In an unscheduled visit by an institute director, a blessing is received by a college woman who has strayed into transgression. She is caused to remember God and returns to the institute.</p>
		  </li>
		  <li>
		    <p pid="gvtjby6MtEOAkGhXh4kQzA" hash="I2lXlg20">—</p>
		    <p pid="Fdn7bXSonUW3myw0zCq3pg" hash="KSVr9A">Another man is raised directly from his sickbed.</p>
		  </li>
		  <li>
		    <p pid="zRvfuOExsUOtynZsamUS2A" hash="I2lXlg21">—</p>
		    <p pid="TPmRJGJQmEuMccnRTZlvnQ" hash="Dsfy8A">A daughter receives a priesthood blessing and finds the peace that has eluded her since her father’s death.</p>
		  </li>
		</ol>
	      </div>
          </li>
	  </ol>
	</div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.p9" pid="SC0k6PmiVUyApjDNzsjRpA" hash="cGmqlA">Brethren, these seven suggestions—one or more as needed—will always bring the Spirit of the Lord into your visits. Are these not some of the <span class="emphasis">spiritual gifts</span> that Christ gave that prepared the way for the Holy Ghost to testify and <span class="emphasis">change men’s hearts?</span> Spiritually give of yourself and your visits will not then be routine, but you will discern the needs of the Saints. You will commit them in the Spirit to act. They will repent and come unto Christ.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.p10" pid="Lo-yXgEwAke2FSufQlwvkg" hash="xUjGEw">Yes, it’s true, there are a few sheep who will not respond to their Master’s voice, who are not willing at this time—and I repeat, <span class="emphasis">at this time</span>—to respond, because Jesus taught that He could only “<span class="emphasis">bring</span> all <span class="emphasis">men</span> unto him, on <span class="emphasis">conditions of repentance.</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:12</a>; italics added.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.p11" pid="HYRMTrKogUyMEtigtbaVdA" hash="-VK33g">With those souls, we just go on loving them and try again at a later time when they may have a more repentant heart and will respond to the Spirit. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.32" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:32</a>.)</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.t6">
        <h3 class="title" pid="sTJNCy7EzUaDhOii_1-Rmw" hash="jAxwGw">A Sister’s Visits</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.p12" pid="cpBl3GXFDkCJWcB_xeBURw" hash="PY6FnA">May I share a personal experience of my wife. While on a stake conference assignment with me, she accompanied a Relief Society president on such a visit. As shepherds and servants of the Lord, they had tremendous success.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.p13" pid="Hsd1CayPF0uglCT9C0Pa5w" hash="Xf6gkA">Then, about a year later while I was teaching some priesthood brethren how to make such visits, a 35-year-old man told me of my wife’s visit a year ago and said: “May I tell you a secret? My entire family had decided the day before your wife came to visit that we were leaving the Church, offended, never to return. I bear witness to you that we felt the Lord speak through her as she stirred us up in remembrance of God and our ordinances. I’m a member of a bishopric now. I would not be here today if it were not for her.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.p14" pid="cNCZL-bZj06Nl6Nz_Er8xA" hash="GJwBkg">He then smiled and said, “How I wish now that I had more carefully watched her invite the Spirit upon me and my family, as it now falls upon me to go out tonight and do my very first home visit.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.p15" pid="9OViLnwsVUexmKJGWqG6iA" hash="9bQbmg">Yes, brethren, the sisters can assist in this work also.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.t7">
        <h3 class="title" pid="UAasoemhxE6hJleDuxLehQ" hash="Rqiktw">In Summary: The Divine Motivation</h3>
        <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.f12">
	  <p pid="0-at-VHwWEWXeVL_g1HGCg" hash="HP4Qag">May I then summarize:</p>
	  <ol class="number">
	    <li pid="8hfCh30iJUap020HkHgNZA" hash="Goiwfg">
            <span class="label">1.</span>
            <p pid="r9jONMRqIUOZQ6HrLIUklg" hash="6x_LTQ">We are to be instruments in the Lord’s hands to bring souls to Christ. Perhaps this is the greatest gift one man can bestow upon another.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="mYTwkJFYUkOCPh3nbBun6w" hash="tquf0w">
            <span class="label">2.</span>
            <p pid="8_raljrjUES8tKDlJWYPBw" hash="kauFiQ">We must better <span class="emphasis">relearn</span> how to invite the Spirit of the Lord for such an endeavor, even humbling self “to the dust.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/138.56" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 138:56</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/34.38" class="scriptureRef">Alma 34:38</a>.)</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="SlvsF6UsPkazfT2pZgq9DA" hash="FbisWw">
            <span class="label">3.</span>
            <p pid="zWjgI67oc0uQfU3Eh-wcXw" hash="ChZFBA">The process described works for all men, young and old, who qualify with “faith, hope, charity and love, with an eye single to the glory of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/4.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 4:5</a>.) You young men, encourage your fathers and companions to hold such visits. You have a right to be shown how, and to motivate and teach us as well.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="NutRoKAIDU-iDMIn0YcNGQ" hash="V9HfYw">
            <span class="label">4.</span>
            <p pid="hyoVRTa1HUeB2mZ4tLWDyw" hash="rmylGQ">Remember, these suggestions are not meant to change the processes for home teaching, visiting teaching, or auxiliary visits, but are a suggested <span class="emphasis">means</span> for bringing the Spirit into all such visits.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="PGNHVlowRUaBSMytFnGhHA" hash="jRivwA">
            <span class="label">5.</span>
            <p pid="oFn2-YuU_0OON2WDmvP0Og" hash="YGu_-w">The process described for inviting the Spirit works the same with:</p>
            <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.f13">
		<ol class="symbol">
		  <li>
		    <p pid="S3iAb0kTOkWX_CT0v8N9Ig" hash="I2lXlg22">—</p>
		    <p pid="RsWiUoi6_0GAeLPa7kfIrw" hash="k7fhJg">a rebellious child at home</p>
		  </li>
		  <li>
		    <p pid="Fp_o4KpckUOc1lDIminQvQ" hash="I2lXlg23">—</p>
		    <p pid="NHU3UNYm1E-yvB0CAlFkvQ" hash="YbIh2Q">a discouraged individual</p>
		  </li>
		  <li>
		    <p pid="qpBVwqciHUSkIU8Qw1aYKw" hash="I2lXlg24">—</p>
		    <p pid="8Qwo0yKzFkiG8KlHnNMdBQ" hash="6ahCDQ">an associate and</p>
		  </li>
		  <li>
		    <p pid="jWrKEQDGeUejZeUcEEbzJA" hash="I2lXlg25">—</p>
		    <p pid="2QifiKQwaUKIz--Rw3HEkw" hash="0zKoIg">even yourself</p>
		  </li>
		  <li>
		    <p pid="f3hVXMEFmkK4eX_Y-7j3Jw" hash="I2lXlg26">—</p>
		    <p pid="DKRb1jDZpUOmtHw1Iom9CA" hash="zZhtYw">as well as in visits to homes.</p>
		  </li>
		</ol>
	      </div>
          </li>
	    <li pid="gxDNG06qvk2uQ34AcUsXJQ" hash="1japfw">
            <span class="label">6.</span>
            <p pid="GyMbNV-1k0qbDwNPk10ABw" hash="vQn04w">Let us commit as one leader did: “There will not be one less-active member who has turned from God in my quorum or class. I will do all in my power to see that mighty change come into his heart.”</p>
          </li>
	  </ol>
	</div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.p16" pid="GPzWAOP9E0-RSAf83WShew" hash="JpKb5w">In conclusion, may I remind each of us that our motivation must not be just for duty, for the Church, or as a result of a calling we have, but our <span class="emphasis">divine motivation</span> must be for the love of God. Then will the miraculous results occur.</p>
        <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.f14">
	  <p pid="rfN6DqTTaUOxutUEiRrAGg" hash="vQvphw">I bear witness from the Book of Mormon that for our labor, we will:</p>
	  <ol class="symbol">
	    <li>
	      <p pid="CXvP3fK_KUSceBdHmm-ntg" hash="I2lXlg27">—</p>
	      <p pid="geX4CRC11EesGc72QxtLTQ" hash="WurDTw">“Wax strong in the Spirit … ;</p>
	    </li>
	    <li>
	      <p pid="F6sL3pihI0O8jSZLzhrblA" hash="I2lXlg28">—</p>
	      <p pid="GMt8W4mjtkKPCESIvVC4GA" hash="yFRA_w">“Teach with power and authority from God;</p>
	    </li>
	    <li>
	      <p pid="_5jkrQeqVUmGLaqJvZk1Qw" hash="I2lXlg29">—</p>
	      <p pid="ntUVqmuFU0GRHFkkeVuhBw" hash="FhDQjA">“Receive the grace of God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.26" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:26</a>); and</p>
	    </li>
	    <li>
	      <p pid="yWguyrvQikK_xyFlzR0xlQ" hash="I2lXlg30">—</p>
	      <p pid="jjOaGqruxEe_BOGIhrs8CQ" hash="mrQ2kg">Be restored unto the grace we once had. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.26" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:26</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/12.24" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 12:24</a>.) And then</p>
	    </li>
	    <li>
	      <p pid="8TAYcKeCJUS8oU-GQHU54A" hash="I2lXlg31">—</p>
	      <p pid="BEpR_QNMJE6FiPpGXGhyZw" hash="7RHf-A">With that grace or enabling power of God, we might thereby obtain charity (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.34,36" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:34, 36</a>), “even the pure love of Christ” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.47" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:47</a>).</p>
	    </li>
	  </ol>
	</div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ.p17" pid="33bu26h6t0a3_zn3Bd6YRw" hash="11bzzw">May that gift, even charity, be ours. May we give of ourselves to the spiritually needy the spiritual gifts Christ gave. I know of no greater joy that can come to man than “the soul that repenteth.” (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.13-16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:13–16</a>.) May the Lord bless us to learn how to bring men to Christ, and, in the process, <span class="emphasis">find Him ourselves,</span> I humbly pray, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1988/10/inviting-others-to-come-unto-christ</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1988-general-conference/1988-10-3020-elder-gene-r-cook-64k-eng.mp3" length="5904887" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 1988 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Receiving Divine Assistance through the Grace of the Lord</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, I bear witness this afternoon of the divinity of the Lord Jesus Christ and specifically of the doctrine of grace that He extends to all mankind. (See .) In so doing, I humbly recognize the great gift the Father has besto</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_93905_000_031" doc-version="2" hash="806uig">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Nfm0c7k4T02SittHmhSmAg" hash="NEmkaQ">Receiving Divine Assistance through the Grace of the Lord</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="h4dHV4qkTE6zCTys55QH0A" hash="jRdRpw">Gene R. Cook</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1f08.jpg" alt="Elder Gene R. Cook" pid="wLjNyI7ukUq_hnbBuVgE0w" hash="RPfV-A" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p1" pid="_CSlzLW16k2Y2XOdh6CyqQ" hash="nainag">My dear brothers and sisters, I bear witness this afternoon of the divinity of the Lord Jesus Christ and specifically of the doctrine of grace that He extends to all mankind. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.6-7" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:6–7</a>.) In so doing, I humbly recognize the great gift the Father has bestowed upon us because He “so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.16" class="scriptureRef">John 3:16</a>.)</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="efnvijEIzUuHtbn2Q9631A" hash="o6DufQ">Seeking the Gift</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p2" pid="iCfq_8RKvUmMXoo-wgCb2Q" hash="bRKoIQ">Perhaps some of us have not received or known how to use the great gift of grace the Father has given to us through the Atonement of His Son, Jesus Christ. “For what doth it profit a man if a gift is bestowed upon him, and he receive not the gift?” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.33" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:33</a>.) The prophet Zenock even said, “Thou art angry, O Lord, with this people, because they will not understand thy mercies which thou hast bestowed upon them because of thy Son.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/33.16" class="scriptureRef">Alma 33:16</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p3" pid="QiGXfxFAskq1VTOqEG-RhA" hash="-g1pEQ">How many of us, at times, try to resolve life’s challenges ourselves, without seeking the intervention of the Lord in our lives? We try to carry the burden alone.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p4" pid="EYnyNPygVkyy4F3SGe5ncw" hash="3TWRhQ">As some are faced with trials and afflictions, they say, “Why won’t God help me?” Some have even struggled with doubts about their prayers and their personal worthiness and say, “Perhaps prayer doesn’t work.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p5" pid="QEOVYKGGrkWUt6txHZ2QFw" hash="ZH2BKg">Others who have suffered with sickness, discouragement, financial crisis, rejection, disappointment, and even loss of loved ones may say, “Why won’t the Lord heal me or help me with my son? Why didn’t He prevent her death? Does life have to be this unhappy?”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p6" pid="d5YiqyXoOk24qdb2Vbdqyg" hash="5W4P8w">Yes, one might even cry out, “O God, where art thou? … How long shall thy hand be stayed?” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.1-2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:1–2</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p7" pid="o-_QTQ0-aUWpJtbBzX-SQA" hash="E7YXYw">Jesus taught that we pass through all these trials to refine us “in the furnace of affliction” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/20.10" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 20:10</a>), and that we should not bear them unaided, but “in [the] Redeemer’s name” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/138.13" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 138:13</a>). In spite of our feeling, at times, that He has forgotten us, He testifies, “Yea, they may forget, yet will I not forget thee …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p8" pid="xcIdn9JWRk6pymvFJZ9WKA" hash="RlHuYA">“Behold, I have graven thee upon the palms of my hands.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/21.15-16" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 21:15–16</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p9" pid="rmBWwXVMEUmLPbThA6b9UQ" hash="Xpfa-g">I testify that the Lord, through His grace, can continually assist us in our daily lives and in our physical and mental sickness, pain, transgressions, and even in all of our infirmities. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/14.5" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 14:5</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/7.11-13" class="scriptureRef">Alma 7:11–13</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/34.31" class="scriptureRef">Alma 34:31</a>.)</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="J7e1moRvw0GarpxfWJctHg" hash="q4mJoA">Being Centered on Christ</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p10" pid="Q2AHqdMCTUyit6SKmyA_8A" hash="2M8FWw">However, to pass successfully through the trials we encounter, we must keep our eyes and our hearts centered on the Lord Jesus Christ. Because “since man had fallen he could not merit anything of himself” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/22.14" class="scriptureRef">Alma 22:14</a>); therefore, we needed an advocate, an intercessor, a mediator to assist us. “And it is <span class="emphasis">because of thy Son</span> that thou hast been thus merciful unto [us].” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/33.11" class="scriptureRef">Alma 33:11</a>; emphasis added.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p11" pid="eesA8AnmZ0Wk-x9LdtkClQ" hash="329Ceg">We should have great hope in knowing, however unworthy we may feel or weak we may be, <span class="emphasis">that if we will do all we can,</span> He will come to our aid and provide for us whatever we may lack. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/2-cor/12.9" class="scriptureRef">2 Cor. 12:9</a>.) That statement, to some degree, defines grace.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="1b278m6SY0a2hDh7mHnzqQ" hash="BolpNA">Understanding Grace</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p12" pid="Vyc5vCYPHUC--BQG3yH5og" hash="dLn5yA">Grace is a “divine means of help or strength, given through the bounteous mercy and love of Jesus Christ.” It is “an enabling power.” (Bible Dictionary, p. 697.) The doctrine of the grace of the Father and the Son and how it affects us is so significant that it is mentioned more than two hundred times in the standard works.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p13" pid="Spcil8t6-UuNRL9CyrodpQ" hash="Yw6S9A">If we can obtain the grace of the Lord Jesus Christ, that divine enabling power to assist us, we will triumph in this life and be exalted in the life to come.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p14" pid="u1cDWdw9OkqFvjR1vrm80Q" hash="_cM-qA">Let me share with you five principles that may help us obtain that divine intervention in our own life or perhaps vicariously assist in the life of another. These principles are simple to understand but most challenging to apply. You already know all of them. However, you may not have considered how directly related they are to obtaining grace.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p15" pid="qKlIWAVyBkKrE9U-T6iwNw" hash="DDm3KQ">The first principle is <span class="emphasis">faith.</span> “Therefore being justified by faith, we have peace with God through our Lord Jesus Christ:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p16" pid="edVYwyyrX0qzzS_ZgCuJOg" hash="z7JwDw">“By whom also we have access by faith into this grace.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/5.1-2" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 5:1–2</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p17" pid="voQVnZ8ZzUWaRJdPULznNQ" hash="d0eO5Q">It is evident that this grace, or enabling power, is accessed by faith. No wonder faith in the Lord Jesus Christ is the first principle of the gospel.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p18" pid="S0HoL2Uq50q2NLZu79WVPQ" hash="CZ4C9w">How clear Christ’s question was to a sinking Peter, after he had walked on the water: “O thou of little faith, wherefore didst thou doubt?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/14.31" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 14:31</a>.) The moment Peter doubted and took his eyes off the Savior, he severed himself from the power of Jesus Christ that had sustained him on the water.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p19" pid="sLlbmnMQPk-x6MOQ4F2zKQ" hash="ACEWDw">How many times, likewise, as we have prayed for assistance or help with our problems, have we severed ourselves from the power of God because of doubt or fear, and thus could not obtain this enabling power of God? (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:36</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/67.3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 67:3</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p20" pid="r0PQdSDEEE6u-04LqaCu4w" hash="QV_bPw">
          <span class="emphasis">Repentance</span> is the second principle. The grace of the Lord through the Atonement can both cleanse us of sin and assist us in perfecting ourselves through our trials, sicknesses, and even “character defects.” We are both sanctified and justified through the grace of the Lord. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.30-31" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:30–31</a>.) Truly, “as a man his sins confess, Christ, in mercy, manifests.” (Gene R. Cook and Holly Cook, “I Am a Healthy Man,” unpublished hymn; see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/24.10" class="scriptureRef">Alma 24:10</a>.) Remember, Christ can repair our flaws and failings that otherwise are not repairable. (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/18.14" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 18:14</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/9.23-24" class="scriptureRef">Mark 9:23–24</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p21" pid="Tdl_IBBKF0q_iq5eQpJzQg" hash="VEj8sQ">That great truth ought to fill us all with hope, as long as we are quick to remember that the effect of grace in our lives is conditioned upon repenting of our sins.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p22" pid="2-7n_J6cIkagSnQUI9xj_g" hash="YIOtaQ">“Therefore, blessed are they who will repent. …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p23" pid="WyBRpm9vmEG3ddJSMbhugQ" hash="OUUc3A">“And may God grant … that men might be brought unto repentance and good works, that they might be restored unto grace for grace, according to their works.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/12.23-24" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 12:23–24</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p24" pid="WxMzsWFkZkOqnZ6EPvB5uA" hash="bMRl2Q">A repentant heart and good works are the very conditions required to have grace restored to us. When someone pleads fervently in prayer for an answer, the answer may be more conditioned on repentance of personal sins than on any other factor. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/101.7-8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 101:7–8</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/11.23-24" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 11:23–24</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p25" pid="7lLWX_LSMUq43fcgkpR-BA" hash="DoNTLw">The third principle is <span class="emphasis">humility.</span> “But he giveth more grace. Wherefore he saith, God resisteth the proud, but giveth grace unto the humble.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/4.6" class="scriptureRef">James 4:6</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p26" pid="9RH2MhVM5kCdsp_fUYZhVA" hash="fiEhsQ">“And if men come unto me I will show unto them their weakness. I give unto men weakness that they may be humble; and my grace is sufficient for all men that humble themselves before me.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.27" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:27</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p27" pid="LE3fZnnVsUidBEyBTrNz-Q" hash="CzZwYg">Humility is an essential condition to obtaining this divine assistance.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p28" pid="6unGxdwDMkaETP0fEdJCaA" hash="dHS5IA">
          <span class="emphasis">Doing all in your own power</span> is the fourth principle. Truly did Paul teach, “By grace are ye saved through faith; and that not of yourselves: it is the gift of God:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p29" pid="B_2z-Bfnc06nW6xBR9rL8Q" hash="5FV1uQ">“Not of works, lest any man should boast.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/2.8-9" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 2:8–9</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p30" pid="tLSXOXl7T0yGNNSLLlJePA" hash="55fRZQ">Yes, works alone cannot bring that divine gift, but they are a key condition upon which the gift is received. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/10.23-25" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 10:23–25</a>.) “For we know that it is by grace that we are saved, after all we can do.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/25.23" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 25:23</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p31" pid="cHZ-vw0lQ0GNUOyyyaOAHw" hash="bbEbCA">Thus, unless one has done all in his own power, he cannot expect the grace of God to be manifest. What a glorious principle to understand: the Lord’s assistance to us—whether we have strong faith or weak faith; whether a man, a woman, or a child—is not based just on what we know, how strong we are, or who we are, but more upon our <span class="emphasis">giving all that we can give</span> and<span class="emphasis"> doing all that we can do</span> in our present circumstance. Once one has given all he can, then the Lord, through His grace, may assist him. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/123.17" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 123:17</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p32" pid="kBjL6RORJE-XpSNe-OtLjw" hash="NVon2g">Clearly, the Lord’s role and our role in our receiving divine help come into clear perspective in these inspired words: “I can do all things through Christ which strengtheneth me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/philip/4.13" class="scriptureRef">Philip. 4:13</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p33" pid="4t8BZ5Q8wUeOV3RyzLUhDg" hash="qfBhJQ">The fifth principle, <span class="emphasis">keeping the commandments,</span> surely is a condition for receiving the grace of the Lord. “If you keep my commandments you shall receive of his fulness … ; therefore, … you shall receive grace for grace.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.20" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:20</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:28</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p34" pid="I5VjvUCav0mlLvcmxy1dxw" hash="im20pw">To obtain grace, one does not have to be perfect but he does have to be trying to keep the commandments the best that he can. Then the Lord may allow him to receive that power.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p35" pid="0VBDcB8joEy2ohGjLjDAKg" hash="udfLaw">Moroni sums up the doctrine of grace succinctly: “If ye shall deny yourselves of all ungodliness, and love God with all your might, mind and strength, then is his grace sufficient for you, that by his grace ye may be perfect in Christ; …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p36" pid="2nJSOrzok0WyObWQ7wrDGA" hash="lWhgtQ">“Then are ye sanctified in Christ by the grace of God, through the shedding of the blood of Christ.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.32-33" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:32–33</a>.)</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="_PeAHychbkSwSMlzG7K5GA" hash="qiLLTw">Hope through Jesus Christ</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p37" pid="LvAfeQ3qC020qFdfK259IQ" hash="ecCgtw">What glorious gospel news is an understanding of this doctrine of grace, which persuades us to more fully center our faith and hope upon Jesus Christ. Through the grace of the Father, we will better know how to come unto the Son. (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/15.14-15" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 15:14–15</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p38" pid="Zp9ZOZb-m0uFcoyq95h01Q" hash="58JJhg">Let us be submissive to the Father’s will, recognizing that His will is preeminent. How thankful we ought to be to submit to His will, because He and His Son will never do anything “save it be for the benefit of the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/26.24" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 26:24</a>.)</p>
        <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.f2">
	  <p pid="U7P2r3c_gEyUvnFvFJI-2A" hash="wBdM6g">By seeking the intercession of the Lord more fully in our lives:</p>
	  <ul class="bullet">
	    <li pid="zBrO9JqAN0e0IGA5WMe_Tw" hash="hx7Ssw">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="OYbEmyaewkaXrjMBlHlodA" hash="eZ3CkA">We will “grow in grace and in the knowledge of the truth.” (D&amp;C 50:40.)</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="DWkhLZlqP0KmIK-D9V6dog" hash="BfscCg">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="r9N7O80UOUW2cTeZuECV3g" hash="d69hzw">We will “teach … diligently and [His] grace shall attend [us].” (D&amp;C 88:78.)</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="zX6AOBB5EkCTgoPBhZ8Cjw" hash="kTQgUQ">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="TvBKo6R7gEqc4ZAnHUcq-g" hash="xeamUQ">For our labor, we will “receive the grace of God, that [we] might wax strong in the Spirit, … that [we] might teach with power and authority from God.” (Mosiah 18:26.)</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="akSx9a-31kG6H7Qz1RZNLw" hash="2oYjIw">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="dz1luIWu7EqFID_XnFuRkg" hash="qAsPCQ">We will not “fall from grace.” (D&amp;C 20:32.)</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="mwmRSkKFbU-Aq16N6fSu9Q" hash="OxYcSg">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="l0PukNkOb0WIl3pCxXHHeA" hash="br-xXw">We will “receive grace for grace” (D&amp;C 93:20).</p>
          </li>
	  </ul>
	</div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p39" pid="Ob6OnUdzJUi63hUI7AnSrg" hash="gYIfMA">“Let us therefore come boldly unto the throne of grace, that we may obtain mercy, and find grace to help in time of need.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/4.16" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 4:16</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p40" pid="FHJL-QyqzE-J-OdpyQR1zg" hash="M_IDYg">I bear witness that if we will seek the grace of God, He will come to our aid and the aid of our loved ones in times of need. Let us obey the Lord in all things and offer to Him the ultimate sacrifice of “a broken heart and a contrite spirit.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/9.20" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 9:20</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/12.19" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 12:19</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p41" pid="5j-rldTuO0e0GQk1-wo1Fw" hash="tpvslg">Now, as one of the Lord’s Seventy and as an especial witness of Christ to bear witness of His name in all the world and “to prepare a way before [His] face” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/124.139" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 124:139</a>), I bear witness of the majesty of the Father and of the Son.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p42" pid="skZT3rpqk0CNnOUk8pDIoA" hash="6TunLA">I testify that Jesus Christ lives, that He is as capable of intervening in the lives of men today as He was in the days of old when He walked among men.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p43" pid="PcAzIznS8kmI5H-ilQx_qQ" hash="EhVQWg">I bear personal witness before the Church of the touch of the Master’s hand in my own life in healing me from an incurable illness. I bear testimony also of His personal direction in my life, through a loving and yet chastening hand of correction, to refine my soul, deepen my feelings, grant a remission of my sins, and fill my soul with the love of God.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p44" pid="1y87bJKV1USMtf-Uq6o24A" hash="ika2xg">Let no trial or affliction, my brothers and sisters, ever separate us from the love of God and the true love of Christ. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/8.31,35-39" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 8:31, 35–39</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord.p45" pid="GWZ6Ckw520eRLZ1eNjADHA" hash="0pLIew">May we “seek this Jesus of whom the prophets and apostles have written, that the grace of God the Father, and also the Lord Jesus Christ, and the Holy Ghost, which beareth record of them, may be and abide in [us] forever.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.41" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:41</a>.) May the grace of God always be with you (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/16.20" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 16:20</a>), I pray, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1993/04/receiving-divine-assistance-through-the-grace-of-the-lord</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1993-general-conference/1993-04-5020-elder-gene-r-cook-64k-eng.mp3" length="5314001" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1993 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charity: Perfect and Everlasting Love</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As we increasingly think and act like Him, the attributes of the natural man will slip away to be replaced by the heart and the mind of Christ.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029598_000_032" doc-version="2" hash="BcGN1g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Y5FpBp9HrUepTf6sFa8GqQ" hash="rCD-qg">Charity:</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="p6RGjDWKhkaaE6B-zRewdw" hash="A4Dy0w">Perfect and Everlasting Love</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Z8nZbq_bfk6JBzQnpoWfoQ" hash="jRdRpw">Gene R. Cook</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="eTcgeSeozk-0mGkDP28RRw" hash="Z0i6JA">As we increasingly think and act like Him, the attributes of the natural man will slip away to be replaced by the heart and the mind of Christ.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-edd.jpg" alt="Elder Gene R. Cook" pid="bXnrVsZRkkGJbVAvQ1r2pw" hash="-_gKxQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p1" pid="1sMMXjFHsE2ZKQQteEsJFw" hash="x_FBFQ">My dear brothers and sisters, I desire more than anything this hour to bear witness, a personal witness, of the love of God for me, for you, and for all mankind. What man is sufficiently adequate to be able to express the depth of his gratitude in recognition of the love of God? How blessed I have been for so many years to be with you and to have found the pure love of Christ emanating from you. I am deeply indebted to you and to God.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="WX1IOxSbd0Sh19CmbIlhrg" hash="TroWFA">Defining Charity</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p2" pid="TGRrGA1IqkaIogW95zciFA" hash="nxvVJA">The Lord said that charity is “the pure love of Christ,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> that which is “most joyous to the soul,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> “the greatest of all the gifts of God,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> “perfect” and “everlasting.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p3" pid="hGW-tj3bek-LkELBzNXJfA" hash="b4sVyA">As difficult as charity is to describe, it is rather easily recognized in the lives of those who possess it.</p>
        <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.f2">
	  <ul class="bullet">
	    <li pid="V-1USle3nkOHqjGhoK_Frw" hash="iatocQ">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="Q2tVSGZDQ0u907GsqpQ2Qg" hash="PzO7oQ">An aged, crippled grandmother who subscribes to an afternoon newspaper, knowing it will bring her delivery-boy grandson to her home every day where, at her knee, she teaches him to pray.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="hI5c9lMZy0iLLsFt-I99dQ" hash="ndv50w">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="V2n6GioNsUGYiasCcxV2og" hash="JX6YHg">A mother who, in hard economic times and scarcity of meat, seems to savor only chicken wings, to the puzzlement of all.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="X8TpJj-1NUav7or0ocxsnw" hash="nzKkSQ">
            <span class="label">•</span>
            <p pid="Nh5f9Z7lKk2Zuda5v9ungg" hash="ZScELQ">A man who suffers an undeserved public chastisement, but humbly receives it anyway.</p>
          </li>
	  </ul>
	</div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p4" pid="MbJyaxV_H0O2yEoacxrBWw" hash="-cViqg">Is not the common thread in these examples charity, a selflessness, a not seeking for anything in return? All of our divine attributes seem to flow from and be encompassed by this one.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> All men may have the gift of love, but charity is bestowed only upon those who are <span class="emphasis">true</span> followers of Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p5" pid="3jBtVQfppEyKw-EBPfbuYw" hash="4kKg1w">The very power of God is found in His attributes of godliness.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> The power of the priesthood is maintained by these attributes.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> We seek these attributes, especially charity, the pure love of Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="0RFWD8dgIkiBccQ_hdFgMQ" hash="nWLGSA">Destroyers of Love and Peace</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p6" pid="YYPP-z1kEECZi2UPhUMuLA" hash="AA1eGg">Yet there stands the devil, the destroyer of this love, replacing it with anger and hostility.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> My friend William felt that way: hostile. It seemed that whatever happened, it was the Lord’s fault—an illness, a death, a wayward child, a personal weakness, an “unanswered” prayer—all of which hardened his heart. His inner anger, which could flare up in but a moment, was directed toward God, his fellowman, and himself. From his heart emanated unbelief, stubbornness, pride, contention, and a loss of hope, love, and direction. He was miserable!</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p7" pid="udkHPFTj00mIK8LN2xGk6g" hash="PMXTRg">These destroyers of peace<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> blinded William to God’s feelings for him. He could neither discover nor<span class="emphasis"> feel</span> God’s love. He did not see, especially in those dark moments, that God was richly blessing him even still. Instead, he returned anger for love. Have we not all felt that at times? Even when we have merited love the least, He has loved us the most. Truly, He loves us first.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="XaaCRsCa4kiPvizi9wXXhA" hash="yoXbRA">Suffering with Purpose: Charity Is Empowering</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p8" pid="u00fEEUXYUC0jWrBuuivrA" hash="jVFhUg">Now, my Christlike friend Betty was just the opposite. She encountered many of the same difficulties as did William, but because she <span class="emphasis">felt</span> God’s love, she suffered tribulation in the Savior’s name,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> partook of His divine nature,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> and thus gained a deeper faith in and a love for God, along with the strength to handle whatever might come.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p9" pid="R5b3ncIZzEugFrwOt46w4g" hash="lUQnsA">Her love for others increased. She seemed to even forgive others<span class="emphasis"> in advance. </span>She learned how to cause them to <span class="emphasis">feel </span>her love. She learned that love shared is love multiplied.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p10" pid="UjZ7Rc2GfkCpeG_SITvf2Q" hash="TYLZPQ">Finally, she learned to love herself more, being more kind, gentle, and long-suffering. She stopped her struggle for self-esteem and started loving herself the way God loved her. Her image of herself became His image of her.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="2_KMNm7dTkiINmUeRCpSGg" hash="nKbUug">Recognizing, Receiving, and Conveying God’s Love</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p11" pid="ma3yYVlomEGmPHSOWoT16A" hash="ayN_2A">How, then, can we better “clothe [ourselves] with the bond of charity … of perfectness and peace”?<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> May I share with you three suggestions.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p12" pid="j1arcHQqQ0m6Z9h5pIFMpw" hash="YRZQsg">
          <span class="emphasis">1. Recognize His love.</span> “Pray … with all the energy of heart”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> for this gift. Do so in meekness with a broken heart, and you will be filled with hope and love from the Holy Ghost Himself. He will reveal Christ to you.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p13" pid="FNUxC29ELEeI8MsPSj73Rw" hash="-yAsYg">It is part of the gift of charity to be able to recognize the Lord’s hand and feel His love in all that surrounds us. At times it will not be easy to discover the Lord’s love for us in all that we experience, because He is a perfect, <span class="emphasis">anonymous</span> giver. You will search all your life to uncover His hand and the gifts He has bestowed upon you because of His intimate, modest, humble way of granting such wonderful gifts.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p14" pid="VH6r497TTEuaEa4Dq4I2xw" hash="N-Za_A">Ponder with me a moment the following majestic gifts: the glories of all creation,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> the earth, the heavens; your feelings of love and joy; His responses of mercy, forgiveness, and innumerable answers to prayer; the gift of loved ones; and finally the greatest gift of all—the Father’s gift of His atoning Son, the perfect one in charity, even the God of love.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p15" pid="nUeBhywaXUCHSf42bryLPw" hash="p-uc8Q">
          <span class="emphasis">2. Receive His love in humility.</span> Be grateful for the gift and especially for the giver of the gift.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> True gratitude is the ability to humbly see, feel, and even receive love.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> Gratitude is a form of returning love to God. Recognize His hand, tell Him so, express your love to Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> As you come to truly know the Lord, you will find an intimate, sacred relationship built on trust. You will come to know He understands your anguish<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> and will, in compassion, always respond to you in love.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p16" pid="A3Nmy7bIjESVN5iTDMiw4w" hash="vdCAfg">Receive it. <span class="emphasis">Feel</span> it. It is not enough just to know that God loves you. The gift is to be <span class="emphasis">felt</span> continually day by day.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> It will then be a divine motivator throughout your life. Repent. Remove any worldliness from your life,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span> including anger. Receive a continual remission of your sins,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26">26</span> and you will bridle all your passions and be filled with love.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_27">27</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p17" pid="hC7XHwITh068h4dNXXbDyg" hash="Dr3HaA">
          <span class="emphasis">3. Convey His love. </span>The Lord’s response to us is always filled with love. Should not our response to Him be in kind, with <span class="emphasis">real</span> feelings of love? He gives grace (or goodness) for grace, attribute for attribute. As our obedience increases, we receive more grace (or goodness) for the grace we return to Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_28">28</span> Offer Him the refinement of your attributes, so that when He does appear you will be <span class="emphasis">like</span> Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_29">29</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p18" pid="_tq7vmd_jkK97d0WtLiyIA" hash="pobC3w">As a man first immerses his thoughts in love and conveys those feelings to God, man, or self, a magnified portion of that attribute will surely follow from the Spirit. That is true of all godly attributes. Righteous feelings generated by a man seem to precede the increase of those feelings from the Spirit. Unless you are feeling love, you cannot convey true love to others. The Lord has told us to love one another as He loves us,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_30">30</span> so remember: to be loved, <span class="emphasis">truly</span> love.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_31">31</span></p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.t6">
        <h3 class="title" pid="Bc55-Ztm8ki3plBYeaYTpA" hash="NdF3CQ">The Fruits of the Gift of Charity</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p19" pid="ehO5YEzxzUyXFmKPUN6yhA" hash="KENbeQ">Brothers and sisters, as an especial witness of Christ, I bear testimony to you again of the overwhelming love of God for each of us personally. Magnifying that gift from God will bring a new heart, a pure heart, and ever-increasing love and peace. As we increasingly think and act like Him, the attributes of the natural man will slip away to be replaced by the heart and the mind of Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_32">32</span> We will become like Him and then truly receive Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_33">33</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love.p20" pid="GfP7zx9xuU-qmezLkWxJvA" hash="EJLG0Q">The prophet of the Lord here before you loves you, as do all these, my Brethren. May the Lord bless us to always have “the affections of [our] heart … placed upon [Him] forever.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_34">34</span> “That [our] burdens may be light, through the joy of his Son”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_35">35</span> is my prayer in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2002/04/charity-perfect-and-everlasting-love</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2002-general-conference/2002-04-5040-elder-gene-r-cook-64k-eng.mp3" length="4355601" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2002 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
