<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By George P. Lee</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by George P. Lee.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/George%20P.%20Lee.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by George P. Lee.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>My Heritage Is Choice</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Brothers and sisters, I finally realized how General Custer must have felt. …</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03063_000_041" doc-version="3" hash="7upHwQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="erzet9hqX0-STBUtBcHq8Q" hash="yWWZAA">My Heritage Is Choice</h1><p class="authorName" pid="aRhrJYsRnkywAV8gOmsqtw" hash="TGLSmQ">George P. Lee</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-29c6.jpg" alt="Elder George P. Lee" pid="CFQYqKUzikeo4vtuG4Ezpw" hash="TgIVRw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.p1" pid="c9m0QoUH00STjj7nh6vcPQ" hash="OLJv8Q">Brothers and sisters, I finally realized how General Custer must have felt. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.p2" pid="hNgxV_yo4ke-hNuADU6VGg" hash="BVDjBQ">I want you to know that it is a great honor and privilege to be in your presence today, and in the presence of our Prophet, and all those that assist him in the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.p3" pid="qNN_GBXH8kSysbNY1wihIA" hash="NicpZA">I am proud to declare to you today, brothers and sisters, that I am a descendant of Lehi, Nephi, and all the great Book of Mormon prophets. I am proud to be a child of the Book of Mormon people. I have found my true heritage; I have found my true identity. I am a son of God, a child of God, a child of the Book of Mormon, a child of Lehi, a rich heritage that extends all the way back to my Heavenly Father, through Moses, and Abraham, and other great prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.p4" pid="m3LrtpdjMk2POxVQn8ObFw" hash="8zKbBw">I am also proud to be a descendant of great Indian chiefs of our country. I am proud to be a descendant of Red Cloud, Sitting Bull, Chief Joseph, Chee Dodge, Chief Crazy Horse and all these great Indian chiefs that did so well as leaders of their people. I want you to know that these men were great. I wouldn’t be surprised if they are all in paradise; and I wouldn’t be surprised if some of them are converted, and maybe some of them are on the fourth missionary discussion. I am proud of my rich heritage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.p5" pid="GCTwfVNDjUmfJ5mGGjEdtg" hash="L4b3hQ">To you my people, the Lamanite people, on Indian reservations and in the cities of our country and through the islands of the sea, I want you to know that Jesus Christ is our Elder Brother. He is our Savior. He is our Redeemer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.p6" pid="S0oTfnsfIUKTIYvDHR4Gog" hash="mcK57A">We have a choice heritage. I want you to know, you Lamanite people, that Heavenly Father loves you. Jesus Christ, your Elder Brother, loves you. He has died for you. He has sacrificed his life to overcome our sins. He conquered death for each of you and every man on earth. He lives and is God of this earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.p7" pid="myXD65NRs0qvesWotF5_Fg" hash="BBOb4Q">To you in the Church throughout the world I declare that the time has come to lay aside our differences, to join hands as children of God. We have a great job to do, to bring many more choice spirits of our Heavenly Father into his kingdom, all over the world. The time has come for all of us to be 365-days-a-year Latter-day Saints, and seven-day-a-week Latter-day Saints, and not just Saints on Sunday only. The Lord has need of every Latter-day Saint to be a missionary, to bring others into his Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.p8" pid="-gX6lAVm2UKcb5kQZQM1qw" hash="cGA-Sw">The time has come, brothers and sisters, to realize that we have no guarantee to the celestial kingdom. Just because we are members of his Church does not give us a guarantee to the celestial kingdom—only if we endure to the end and are faithful until he comes again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.p9" pid="zeEZ5ZcAzEm3kn3rbu6Sow" hash="XyIiIQ">To you, my brothers and sisters in the world, who are still searching for truth, who deny the existence of God, I give you two challenges. I challenge you to find another church, another organization, another way of life that has twelve apostles, that has a prophet, that is run by revelation, that baptizes by immersion and one that has priesthood. You will find there is no other church, there is no other way that is like the church we have. We have the same church that Jesus Christ organized anciently on this very soil and also in the Bible lands.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.p10" pid="IjgRvnpQiUyonedLst8wTg" hash="8pqZsw">That is my first challenge to you. My second challenge to you is to look around you. What do you see? You see a beautiful creation, the handiwork of Jesus Christ, our Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.p11" pid="PRBqp7XZ10igOt_081MOYw" hash="SSCh4Q">He has done so many wonderful things for us. How can we deny, as intelligent as we are, the existence of a God, and Jesus Christ? The greatest witness of Jesus Christ is right before your very eyes—the trees, the grass, the universe, the moon, the sun.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.p12" pid="MKh3XPGErEu5Jq8XgtXzSw" hash="dgEnnQ">Can any mortal man create human beings?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.p13" pid="hpOu0d__EUe40i6Y37N4Rg" hash="ZrbBsA">Can any mortal man create the grass, the universe, the sun, the moon, the rain, the snow, the trees, the very food we eat?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.p14" pid="SU9t_LIOsUeO6ydDxXf4Yg" hash="99Xejw">Can any mortal man create such a beautiful world as we see and live in today?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.p15" pid="MjweXY2jRES2xDa4AVssVA" hash="ynLLbg">How can we as scientists and learned men deny the existence of God and Jesus Christ when right before our very eyes we see existing a beautiful creation with order, precision, and exactness? No mortal man can duplicate what we see. This is enough to tell all of us that there is a divine God, a divine Christ—even Jesus Christ. He lives! He is the Creator of this world. The gospel is his plan. This is his way of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.p16" pid="sftlW0iErUSihg6F197TgA" hash="yxczaw">All of us must realize that when we die and go to paradise, if we make it there, that as Americans you will not find United States in paradise.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.p17" pid="wd5TKLSacUuiSEUrY_de_w" hash="uYxc1Q">You might as well realize that we are all going to the same place. As an Indian I will not find an Indian reservation in paradise. As a Hopi, you will not find a Hopi reservation. As a Japanese you will not find Japan in paradise. As Chinese, you will not find China in paradise. Let’s live together as children of God. We are all brothers and sisters. We will all go to the same place if we are righteous, and if we endure to the end. There is no United States, there is no Navajo reservation, nor any way of life, except God’s, in paradise.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice.p18" pid="1x5CUfgTFEeN0YOVkYcs9g" hash="ceLUWg">God lives. Jesus Christ lives, brothers and sisters. In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/10/my-heritage-is-choice</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1975-general-conference/1975-10-7020-elder-george-p-lee-64k-eng.mp3" length="4383942" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“But They Were in One”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, I am happy, thrilled, and delighted to be with you once again. I am greatly strengthened again, my brothers and sisters, by the energetic, vibrant, and humble spirit of President Kimball and all those who have spoken. Pr</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03070_000_044" doc-version="2" hash="NtIy-w">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="GsvwypRnsEeGGQhNVWHLqQ" hash="v4EBoA">“But They Were in One”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="_pJanHy05EeBSOB8X8JNUg" hash="TGLSmQ">George P. Lee</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-29c6.jpg" alt="Elder George P. Lee" pid="uMTm7UHmDkW8X8MzbTTsvw" hash="TgIVRw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p1" pid="eqS_2W-yhEe9To0RPmz9ng" hash="Jb-tfw">My dear brothers and sisters, I am happy, thrilled, and delighted to be with you once again. I am greatly strengthened again, my brothers and sisters, by the energetic, vibrant, and humble spirit of President Kimball and all those who have spoken. President Kimball is not only a great leader but a great man. His faith and works are incomparable. In my estimation he is as great as any prophet that preceded him since the time of Adam. I know that he is one of the great and noble ones the Lord referred to while conversing with Abraham. (See <a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.22" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:22</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p2" pid="GciW9tuS2kmaOLBbvmoxKw" hash="8WFF_Q">In Fourth Nephi, verses 15 and 17, my brothers and sisters, we read:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p3" pid="b-GGcDVSf0e4ouEskv_8Bg" hash="zGCc-w">“There was no contention in the land, because of the love of God which did dwell in the hearts of the people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p4" pid="SauBgOcbrkqSkWDHu_Ia_Q" hash="6trn7Q">“There were no robbers, nor murderers, neither were there Lamanites, nor any manner of -ites; but they were in one, the children of Christ, and heirs to the kingdom of God.” [<a href="/scriptures/bofm/4-ne/1.15,17" class="scriptureRef">4 Ne. 1:15, 17</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p5" pid="RmnQ347IEEeYMFCT7jeG_Q" hash="Yxd6yA">As I look at you today, I can’t help but feel warm and thrilled inside to see a similar atmosphere of love and compassion, unity and warmth among you as was among my forefathers. I see brown faces and white faces together, sitting shoulder to shoulder. I see big nations side by side with small nations. I see American faces with Lamanite faces. I see German faces next to French faces. I see Mexicans next to Chinese. I see Japanese faces next to Polynesians. My brothers and sisters, what I am seeing today demonstrates to me the true gospel in action. As I look over the audience today, I do not see Mexicans, or whites, or Japanese, or Chinese. What I see are children of God. To me you are all children of God. In fact, today I see a glimpse of heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p6" pid="_MFzjSsKykuGvEw8--7CwQ" hash="2Hr7vA">As I look at you I know there is no hate or animosity among you because of the love of God which is swelling in your hearts. There is great evidence of loving your neighbor among you today. But let me ask you, brothers and sisters, you in this tabernacle and all those listening, what about when you leave this conference? And you in this building, when you leave this building, will you have the same feeling? Will you have the same love and regard for everyone and for anyone? The Lord said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p7" pid="TCGVa9DSSkeKKxdCFpPOQA" hash="aZeI9w">“Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p8" pid="kqutL39IakKHNxSK649QPw" hash="pLnaTg">“This is the first and great commandment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p9" pid="FtVNCZWfUEmGYiMkPex7Pg" hash="pIRHZA">“And the second is like unto it, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.37-39" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:37–39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p10" pid="gJafD9uF9km8ES0YavfC6w" hash="MPphag">Of all the great commandments given to us by our Heavenly Father, he rates these number one and two. My brothers and sisters, you cannot live one without the other; both must be lived and practiced if we are to be found with Him in the celestial glory. In this church there is no place for hate, animosity, or prejudice. Nor are they found in the celestial kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p11" pid="WFKoZCbpvUinHYxrn5Yd_Q" hash="ADqNvA">Again we read in Fourth Nephi:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p12" pid="Crc16HkV1EqRwU-g53-D2Q" hash="pLVUTg">“And they had all things in common among them; therefore there were not rich and poor, bond and free, but they were all made free, and partakers of the heavenly gift.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/4-ne/1.3" class="scriptureRef">4 Ne. 1:3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p13" pid="altq1-WZskSlYtxnnuCkEg" hash="BeRjnw">In like manner, my brothers and sisters, among you today there are really no rich, no poor. To me you’re all equal in the sense that you are all Latter-day Saints and that you are all rich spiritually. What I see in the audience today are people from all walks of life. I see doctors and lawyers sitting next to common men. I see a farmer next to a professional person. I see professional people, educators, and teachers side by side. I see composers, musicians, and artists—all kinds of people from all walks of life, sitting together side by side. And this is as it should be, because if you want to know what the celestial kingdom looks like, you are witnessing today a glimpse of the celestial kingdom and heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p14" pid="uLNYF4SVv0iNmxTarpuh3w" hash="TYzqSQ">My brothers and sisters, the Lord has commanded us to love each other, and to be one in Jesus Christ, and to become perfect as he is. But let me ask you again, brothers and sisters, what will happen after you leave this building and return home? Will you be common with all and listen to the cries of the poor, the deprived, and the oppressed? The Lord said, “Inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.40" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:40</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p15" pid="C60a_Hn9AUyWyXhSy2-dxQ" hash="_Lz8JQ">The mission of this church is to focus on others. The Lord has instructed us to give meat to the hungry, give drink to the thirsty, clothe the naked, visit the sick and those in prison. Again Nephi said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p16" pid="nI-ZHHM0_kyeFhGbHovqLA" hash="gnhDnA">“The people were all converted unto the Lord, upon all the face of the land, both Nephites and Lamanites, and there were no contentions and disputations among them, and every man did deal justly one with another.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/4-ne/1.2" class="scriptureRef">4 Ne. 1:2</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p17" pid="YKmzgf6j30udG_orSTDBDw" hash="58uNQQ">In like manner today, as I look at you, you are all converted to the Lord and there is no disputation among you. You are all willing and capable of dealing justly with your neighbor. But again I must ask you, what will happen when you leave this building? What will happen when this conference is closed? Will you go out of this building and out into the world and deal justly with your fellowmen? Will you still be converted? Or will you compromise gospel principles and standards? Will you still be willing to deal justly with your fellowmen?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p18" pid="127S10RL0EiB1RB-vMF_EQ" hash="K8n5Ag">Again we read from Nephi’s account the following:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p19" pid="qaUxqi5F00GUKMJGu_lT7A" hash="VhzjxA">“And there were no envyings, nor strifes, nor tumults, nor whoredoms, nor lyings, nor murders, nor any manner of lasciviousness; and surely there could not be a happier people among all the people who had been created by the hand of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/4-ne/1.16" class="scriptureRef">4 Ne. 1:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p20" pid="_eF5WpABPUmMtUnN_itT9Q" hash="E7wcMw">This passage of scripture, my brothers and sisters, describes the happy and beautiful estate of my Book of Mormon ancestors. They lived in peace and happiness for 200 years without hate or wars or contentions. What a glorious and superb record of righteousness!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p21" pid="0OxMju6kQEKBk41fzuFkQQ" hash="0nSJMA">Can those of us in this room today, and those of us listening in, duplicate this record of righteousness? I challenge you, my brothers and sisters, as we celebrate the birth of our country, as we celebrate 200 years of our country’s history, I challenge you that between now and when you come back next fall to general conference that you love each other as children of God and not as different races and cultures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p22" pid="FjauemFlVUyxJ7VZDLXadQ" hash="xbZsOw">When we are baptized and confirmed as members of this church, we become one in Jesus Christ. In other words, my brothers and sisters, we commit ourselves to follow him. Our attitudes, thoughts, deeds, and actions should conform to his. If we will truly be faithful and righteous, we will truly be called children of Christ, children of God, and we will be entitled to his kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p23" pid="CBwQHVmzeU60mie0whjpdg" hash="9c1PEA">I want all of you to know that I love my Heavenly Father. I love the Lord Jesus Christ. I love people. This has been one of my greatest assets—loving people. I’m grateful for this attribute that my Heavenly Father has blessed me with.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p24" pid="kl71d-ovKUaZFn2df_sYYw" hash="pN3-gQ">I know that Jesus Christ lives and that we fought beside him in the preexistence, those of us in this room and those of us listening in. We were side by side with him in the war in heaven as we stood with him and fought Lucifer. And today he has chosen us to come in these last days to stand beside him again, and again to fight Lucifer, Satan, who controls the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p25" pid="gV7ELHiGyESYhIbF9KnnDw" hash="8sbzRg">I have a testimony of the Book of Mormon, the history of my forefathers. America was founded so that the gospel could be restored and so that this sacred record could be brought back to my people and to anyone who will listen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one.p26" pid="iWpClP7-BU-qmfB3cizxOw" hash="ZBCwpw">I know that Joseph Smith really was a true prophet of God, that God the Father and Jesus the Christ actually and really came down and visited with him. It’s no myth, no legend, no fairy tale, no make-believe. It really happened. And with us today is a living prophet, President Kimball. I love him; I sustain him; I respect him. In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/04/but-they-were-in-one</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1976-general-conference/1976-04-7030-elder-george-p-lee-64k-eng.mp3" length="11908515" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1976 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Staying Unspotted from the World</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1978/04/staying-unspotted-from-the-world?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My beloved brothers and sisters, I should like to address my remarks to the young people of the Church, the youth of the Church. I love the young people of the Church. I sincerely believe that the young people of today are some of the choicest young </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/staying-unspotted-from-the-world" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03096_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="RqmZpA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/staying-unspotted-from-the-world.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="x0jnOgDGEU6y1u8xd3OQ1g" hash="93Rocg">Staying Unspotted from the World</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="jHGVK5rh2UOyWkPsLSpZuA" hash="TGLSmQ">George P. Lee</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/staying-unspotted-from-the-world.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-29c6.jpg" alt="Elder George P. Lee" pid="k0gBWOwYqECY6absTyY-zw" hash="TgIVRw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/staying-unspotted-from-the-world.p1" pid="qLpjDb-rrUiSWbYVaRmx5Q" hash="ZuqX4w">My beloved brothers and sisters, I should like to address my remarks to the young people of the Church, the youth of the Church. I love the young people of the Church. I sincerely believe that the young people of today are some of the choicest young people who ever lived on earth. One of the reasons why I know this is because of the choice, dedicated missionaries that I preside over in the Arizona Holbrook Mission. Missionaries of today are coming out more prepared, more mature, and more spiritual than ever before.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/staying-unspotted-from-the-world.p2" pid="Yf2GQlpQEEqRTUl1N6LXoQ" hash="9dm2Gg">You young people are among the most valiant, among the cream of all the spirits in the premortal life; and God has reserved you to come forth in these perilous times, the last days, for a divine purpose. The choice spirits coming to earth today were choice in the premortal existence before they came here. The reason they were choice in heaven is that they were obedient, valiant, and lived with exactness. In heaven, you young people, you lived by sight; in other words, you saw with your spirit eyes, you saw God, you saw Jesus Christ, your elder brother, and you saw Satan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/staying-unspotted-from-the-world.p3" pid="qNMSu24bp02Bgpa1blpHJA" hash="deBRSQ">When Satan rebelled in the war in heaven and tried to persuade you to follow him, you stood up for the Lord. You were true and faithful. You lived with exactness and did exactly what the Lord wanted you to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/staying-unspotted-from-the-world.p4" pid="yJRh_N34l0W8Qt8D6f99qA" hash="24cepg">And now, in these last days, in these crucial, perilous times, young people, your Heavenly Father needs you again to carry on his work. He needs you who have passed the test in heaven, you who have been tried, you who were true and faithful, you young people that he hopes will resist every appearance of evil on this earth so that you will be just as true and faithful here as you were before, and carry on his work in preparation for the coming of his Only Begotten Son, Jesus Christ, your elder brother, your Redeemer and Savior.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/staying-unspotted-from-the-world.f2">
	<p pid="CQvDgFnGoECRDDx2YbK0SQ" hash="PZRB9w">To help you prepare for the Lord to use you, may I offer the following suggestions to assist you to be unspotted from the world:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="wt4dEvRAYUKHrtMxtDzs9w" hash="ciILmQ">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="73rYyZjeFk2XRGrD15kVpw" hash="eFz_dQ">Beloved youth, it is the will of God that you be virtuous. You are very elect, you are choice, you are sons and daughters of God. You can be virtuous. The Lord said: “Let virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.45" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:45</a>.)</p>
          <p pid="nGNlidbzikq3BKWQ7xLXlQ" hash="Ewdz8Q">Of all the possessions that you have, young people, virtue is the most important. It is a pearl of great price. People can strive, toil, and sweat all their lives for fame and wealth, but your greatest wealth and fame will come from virtuous living. The wealth and fame that come from virtuous living are peace with yourself, your fellowmen, and with God, the joys and happiness of righteous living. The fame of having your name recorded in Heavenly Father’s book of life as one who is true and faithful and loves the Lord is far more important than being honored with the praises and glories of the world.</p>
          <p pid="SV2IQCsefESRx9QO4Z9bww" hash="vm9vwQ">Let virtue and purity be your shield and armor, and you will be invincible. As priceless as virtue is, wear it openly and do not keep it in a vault like crown jewels.</p>
          <p pid="8ACdjGUEIkS01l4isA8ktQ" hash="CdAaHA">Paul declared, “If any man defile the temple of God, him shall God destroy; for the temple of God is holy, which temple ye are.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/3.17" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 3:17</a>.)</p>
          <p pid="AeC-yKlGp0Cvt9vvb8zI0w" hash="3uC0aw">Do not mock God, young people. Virtue is the law of God.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Wfoz1Hw3q0eHvpIRFnQzDQ" hash="aKQQFg">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="hgbQo0A3JUi00Ab8dMat3g" hash="h6_5Zw">Young friends, it is the will of God that you pray unceasingly. As a young boy on the Navajo reservation, many times I found myself on my knees in our small humble hogan. Many times I’ve been tried and tested. In those moments I asked my Heavenly Father for faith, strength, and courage to withstand temptations. Many times, as I was on my knees, my own brothers made a game of me, laughing and sneering and shouting through the cracks of the hogan, but I was not bothered by them.</p>
          <p pid="yLgxj2D1hE28zcAAPdO3vw" hash="jRuVaQ">The young people who kneel down and ask God for faith and courage to resist temptation very early in life will find that temptation loses much of its luster, and temptation is very unattractive. You cannot receive a full-grown testimony that God lives and that the Church is true any more than you can come into the world fully grown. You start small, but grow with consistency.</p>
          <p pid="Tr6H8ysGH0Wr0x2gsVQwSA" hash="s3AlIw">Your faith needs nourishment through prayers. Exercise the muscle of the faith until it is one of such strength that it will sustain you. Beloved youth, get on your knees. The Lord has a testimony just for you—one that fits your size and needs—but you have to ask for it.</p>
          <p pid="gleXNERGyUqiQiZEXS2YOQ" hash="GdFBHQ">Every young man and young woman should pray before going out on a date. A Navajo boy, coming from very simple, humble, poor circumstances, because he was on his knees, became a polished instrument of God. A praying young man becomes a praying man; and a praying man becomes a god.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="xzL0h2zxoUCn8Qw_7kFEog" hash="-cvojQ">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="1fYjcUyvG06VY5R-geDA9A" hash="_j652g">My young friends, it is the will of God that you stand up for the Lord Jesus Christ, the Church, and his righteousness. Joshua made a stand and then stood on it when he said, “Choose you this day whom ye will serve, … but as for me and my house, we shall serve the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/24.15" class="scriptureRef">Josh. 24:15</a>.)</p>
          <p pid="Knq8NhXoFUKkujlnchvF_A" hash="YKLrUw">Beloved youth, you must do the same. You must make the same stand. With each new temptation, you should already know what your decision or reaction should be—that is, you should serve the Lord. You should seek the praises of God and not the praises of man.</p>
          <p pid="p3nAnKOf2EG79H1rjGVcFA" hash="eSNomQ">Again, as a young Navajo boy growing up on a reservation and as the only Mormon in my family, I was tempted many times by friends whose values were not as lofty as my own. Even my own flesh and blood, my own brothers and sisters, tried me.</p>
          <p pid="YRLgpR3LE0G1EGrz8BVwAQ" hash="eX1yxA">Two, three, four of my brothers were so determined for me to live their way that one day they attacked me and attempted to bind my arms and legs. When I became helpless, they would pour wine and beer into me. But the plan didn’t work. I resisted. I fought back with all the strength and courage I had. I managed to escape and run away from them. But I still loved them and asked Heavenly Father to forgive them.</p>
          <p pid="stJVihFS7Ue-st1w8l_qCQ" hash="byJzyQ">Beloved youth, you must do the same; you must stand up for the Lord, even against your own flesh and blood, even against your own brothers and sisters, even against your own loved ones and friends.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="djncRMYVP0CLISuflvJUwQ" hash="imDpHw">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="o8qEhRh_9EeFxhYgJwSdgg" hash="rVFg-w">Beloved youth, it is the will of God that you serve him only and not go after the image of your own God. The Lord said, “They seek not the Lord to establish his righteousness, but every man walketh in his own way, and after the image of his own God, whose image is in the likeness of the world, and whose substance is that of an idol.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:16</a>.)</p>
          <p pid="UkPN0t2pNEaeoBjKtN9e0Q" hash="JLwMgQ">Beloved youth, you cannot hold hands with Satan and God at the same time. You have to let go of one or the other. When you worship hard rock music or any other worldly idol more than spiritual things, you are holding hands with Satan and are walking in darkness. You will become insensitive to the things that are spiritual; you will lose interest and motivation to attend church or to go on a mission. Doubts and fears will cloud your minds. You will begin to walk in your own way, after the image of your own god, “whose image is in the likeness of the world, and whose substance is that of an idol.” The image of some sports stars, movie stars, rock stars, money, and sports cars is in the likeness of the world, and their substance is that of an idol. Do not worship them.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="gOxYJzdNg0aEDwlEb6wRpA" hash="bQJgEg">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p pid="5weHQeBhzEa6dcpC1Cy1Aw" hash="w5ZFYA">Beloved youth, it is the will of God that you be obedient. Discipline yourselves to become obedient to your parents, to your priesthood leaders, and to the Lord. Obedience leads to success and happiness; disobedience leads to rebellion and spiritual decay. If your parents counsel you not to go dating until you are sixteen, listen and follow. If your priesthood leaders counsel you to be chaste, listen and follow. If the Lord counsels every young man to go on a mission, listen and obey. Again, the Lord said, “I, the Lord, am bound when ye do what I say; but when ye do not what I say, ye have no promise.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/82.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 82:10</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="5j8JnxwqLEKG3pf1_0TFRQ" hash="aNLuZQ">
          <span class="label">6.</span>
          <p pid="PHXmpzXuHESj_w1MtmFhxA" hash="dvh-lA">Young friends, it is the will of God that you search the scriptures diligently. Learn to love the scriptures early in life. Have your own standard works. Scriptures enlighten the mind and bring strength, courage, peace, and calmness. Unwholesome worldly literature brings darkness to the mind.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/staying-unspotted-from-the-world.p5" pid="j8TL8S-jiEG33agEFF9aYQ" hash="4Q72Bw">The scriptures will prepare young men for missions and help them to fulfill successful missions. Scriptures will prepare young women for motherhood and help them to become sweet, tender, loving mothers in Zion. Scriptures, more than anything else, will assist you to overcome the world and enable you to become gods and goddesses, kings and queens in the celestial world. The Lord said,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/staying-unspotted-from-the-world.p6" pid="tNdXaz5ksk2YECwVUXd3Yw" hash="K3jMUQ">“What I the Lord have spoken, I have spoken, and I excuse not myself; and though the heavens and the earth pass away, my word shall not pass away, but all shall be fulfilled, whether by mine own voice or by the voice of my servants, it is the same.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:38</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/staying-unspotted-from-the-world.p7" pid="3r76oDWeWEKdNDrNhmHeWg" hash="FhYXww">Young people, whatever the temptation may be, take a stand and stand up for the Lord. You’re too choice, you’re too innocent, you’re too sweet and too pure to lose. Avoid bringing temptations upon yourselves. The worst kind of temptations are the ones you plan and make arrangements for. If the world hates you and calls you a “square,” remember what the Lord said. “If the world hate you, ye know that it hated me before it hated you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/staying-unspotted-from-the-world.p8" pid="c8B2AQw3h0Gq7pukEL8GPg" hash="Gmngfg">“If ye were of the world, the world would love his own: but because ye are not of the world, but I have chosen you out of the world, therefore the world hateth you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/15.18-19" class="scriptureRef">John 15:18–19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/staying-unspotted-from-the-world.p9" pid="IM_9hMpODE2y3tuk4MV2JA" hash="hGP5dg">Do not do what the world does, young people. Be a “square” to the world. It’s fun to be “square,” to be “weird,” to be “peculiar” to the world. Your mission is to overcome the world, to overcome sin, overcome hate, overcome prejudice, overcome discouragement, overcome the carnal man and be true and faithful again, the same as you were in the premortal existence. In the premortal existence you passed a test. You were valiant, you were obedient. The Lord expects you to be the same here on earth in mortality—to be obedient, to be valiant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/staying-unspotted-from-the-world.p10" pid="mVi7zxh9O0uuUnm-1sOazg" hash="KdgzrQ">Someone said, “No man goes to hell in a single jump.” My young friends, I pray that you will be equal to any temptation that might come to you and that you will avoid and be careful with the first appearance of evil. Today you are beautiful, choice, sweet, and pure, but tomorrow is up to you. Your future is bright and full of blessings. Youth is power. The greatest single resource that the Church has is youth, and the greatest single important resource that the country has is youth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/staying-unspotted-from-the-world.p11" pid="8d27y_EKhUKskVt3qoZ6tw" hash="5nCcSQ">God loves you. I love you. I thank God every day for young people like you. And I pray that he will always watch over you forever in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1978/04/staying-unspotted-from-the-world</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1978-general-conference/1978-04-2070-elder-george-p-lee-64k-eng.mp3" length="5962892" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 1978 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Acquaint Thyself with Him, and Be at Peace”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Charles Dickens once wrote: “It was the best of times, it was the worst of times, it was the age of wisdom, it was the age of foolishness, … it was the season of Light, it was the season of Darkness, … we had everything before us, we had nothing befo</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03128_000_028" doc-version="2" hash="gtnqUg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="ZcETmA7yDkmo47SA6eNlgw" hash="txrBsQ">“Acquaint Thyself with Him, and Be at Peace”</h1><p class="authorName" pid="pDhiUNoYG0u-FUjioqFpsA" hash="TGLSmQ">George P. Lee</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-29c6.jpg" alt="Elder George P. Lee" pid="opKjUmEDkkqA9hfP-8nbaA" hash="TgIVRw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p1" pid="pCBtmb0KYUC03MgqkPrEBQ" hash="FrMatQ">Charles Dickens once wrote: “It was the best of times, it was the worst of times, it was the age of wisdom, it was the age of foolishness, … it was the season of Light, it was the season of Darkness, … we had everything before us, we had nothing before us” (<span class="emphasis">A Tale of Two Cities,</span> New York: Washington Square Press, n.d., p. 3).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p2" pid="WJ64RFvpB06NXO8HxZNtuQ" hash="f1fYrA">This description of a period of time in his day reminds us of some of the conditions of our day. We live in a great age of miracles and wonders. We have a higher standard of living and more education than any generation of the past. We enjoy the greatest comforts and the finest luxuries. We have more goods and better services than any other people have ever had. Our nation is the most prosperous and powerful ever known. Indeed, this is the best of times.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p3" pid="L_5Jq552tUyLmtbOWmY7vA" hash="pJuuBQ">But this is also the very worst of times. We are confronted by bigger problems and greater dangers than man has ever faced before. Delinquencies, crime, destructive wars, immorality, and other sins are scoring new highs. Serious disturbances are taking place in nature. We constitute the most wicked age.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p4" pid="ZuqOWWDamEGHY4NAHMse0A" hash="w72SEw">The most important responsibility that the Lord has ever laid upon us is that of making the best and the most of our lives. If we make the worst of times the best of times, we will be going directly toward heaven, but if we make the best of times the worst of times, we will be going backwards. We all know and are quite aware of the Lord’s miracles, teachings, and doctrines. We know of his example; yet sometimes we live far away from that example. We live in the very best of times, yet we may be far from living his teachings and doctrines.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p5" pid="qubrXK12c06aT6Xt8E1A_Q" hash="c_s5UQ">The scriptures clearly compare our day with the days of Noah, when the people of his time brought destruction upon themselves. It must be clear to each of us that the problem then and now is our poor relationship with the Lord. From the very beginning the Lord has tried to get man to follow divine counsel aimed at peace, prosperity, and happiness for all of us. Unfortunately, man’s responses to his efforts have almost always been negative, and we continue to follow our own devices and wisdom in leading each other astray.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p6" pid="64mn-WuoOkaM6HOmjH5H6g" hash="EpdWHg">Jeremiah wrote, “Thus saith the Lord; Cursed be the man that trusteth in man, and maketh flesh his arm, and whose heart departeth from the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/jer/17.5" class="scriptureRef">Jer. 17:5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p7" pid="jgT0NvD510Ovnr9faGR2zw" hash="h8kahw">Both our past and our present prove that of ourselves we lack the ability to solve our own problems. More than anything else and more than ever before, we need direction from the Lord. Jesus diagnosed our problems when he said: “Ye hypocrites, well did Esaias prophesy of you, saying,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p8" pid="0GkSsOMDcUqrI9aMgIIddw" hash="Nqekmg">“This people draweth nigh unto me with their mouth, and honoureth me with their lips; but their heart is far from me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p9" pid="hgYau8JdNU6Cjc6-rJwRlA" hash="_e82Yg">“But in vain they do worship me, teaching for doctrines the commandments of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/15.7-9" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 15:7–9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p10" pid="G9or39etE0uMRebQywRO0w" hash="z5qB7w">Again he said, “My doctrine is not mine, but his that sent me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/7.16" class="scriptureRef">John 7:16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p11" pid="XAvy9be7REGVi9MTnEms7w" hash="5ZTyIw">His divine instructions gave us all the answers to any problems that might confront us. But his doctrines and teachings did not go over very well with the people in his time, nor are they going over very well in our time. They fell on deaf ears. Many people in his time, like many of us who live in this the dispensation of the fulness of times, chose to follow the false doctrines of man. This program of substituting the doctrines of man for those taught by the Lord has been very harmful and extensive.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p12" pid="sQ8PYOIb1E6ObZSfTkhyVg" hash="hARIIA">Today in America, it is against the law to talk about God in the schools of some states. In these schools, one must not read the Bible, one must not sing Christmas carols, and prayer is prohibited because someone’s sensibility might be offended. Atheism may be taught in the schools, but not the word of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p13" pid="bz-ykCpBYUyRKlWXrr12vg" hash="OuMNQw">The sin and evil that the Lord came to free us from are, in many places, now running unchecked in many places throughout our nation and the rest of the world. Crime is at an all-time high. Sin is at an all-time high. Immorality, among the youth and the adults, is at an all-time high. Jesus came as our example. He lived a sinless life and furnished us with a working model of righteousness. His simple message was “Follow me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/9.59" class="scriptureRef">Luke 9:59</a>). He asked us to follow him in his teachings, to follow him in his righteousness, and to follow him in his love for others. Unfortunately and sadly, many have not followed him; rather, they have followed those who could find no room for his teachings, his miracles, or his doctrines. Many have made no room for him because their lives are loaded down with sin and pleasures. Others have made room for their physical comforts; they have made room to expand their educational opportunities; but they have crowded him out. Some have made room to work more hours to accumulate material possessions; still others have made room to multiply their luxury and increase their leisure time and have made room for more sports and entertainment, but they have made no room for him. They have made room for many violations of the Sabbath day, but they have made no room for the Savior of the world—our Redeemer and Master.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p14" pid="ARs3K9SWsEWGC0bokeCBsA" hash="uKz-DA">Today the Lord is pleading with us through the spoken word, through the scriptures, through the Spirit, through his prophets, through the witness of faithful parents, friends, and teachers; but we still have no room for him. We have no room for his teachings and doctrines because most of us are looking for a religion of convenience—one that takes no time, costs no money, requires no effort, and fits our lives without any required changes. It is no wonder the Lord said, “The foxes have holes, and the birds of the air have nests; but the Son of man hath not where to lay his head” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/8.20" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 8:20</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p15" pid="MhiI668zykGJB5uk4GwJxA" hash="Ubjumg">As we watch our government hopelessly grapple with the mighty problems of the day, perhaps we should take a look at the way the Lord would handle the problems of our day. The world in general works on the effects and results of the problems, while the Lord zeroes in on the roots and the causes. The Lord advocates preventive measures, while man attacks the problems after they have arisen. Man’s answer to crime is better law enforcement, bigger and better locks on doors, bigger and better prisons, bigger and better rehabilitation, and bigger and better arms and weapons. But the Lord’s answer is to love your neighbor as yourself and do good to others as you would have them do to you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p16" pid="nG3Y16aCA0K1e4fiXVL3xQ" hash="1Vbhig">Man’s answer to poverty is public welfare through food stamps, loans, guaranteed income, publicly financed housing, and other things. The Lord’s answer is to teach self-reliance, to help people help themselves. Man’s answer to the problem of immorality is birth control pills, homes for unwed mothers, venereal disease clinics, sex education, and divorce counselors. The Lord’s answer is to teach the virtues of chastity, love, and purity. The Lord’s approach to problems and his approach to resolving them probably would not make headlines or the six o’clock news; but nevertheless, his approach would solve our nation’s problems as well as the world’s problems, and it would revolutionize our world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p17" pid="gMDYQCMnBki80jGyzlS-Og" hash="nTUzQw">Paul tried to teach the Ephesians how to be good Christians and good people. The lesson is also a good one for us. He said: “Finally, my brethren, be strong in the Lord, and in the power of his might.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p18" pid="dVXRupFoCEOhREmZhiaUoQ" hash="hY0jLg">“Put on the whole armour of God. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p19" pid="r8ZLv_ZSSkC12nq3yKzdfg" hash="TJKWgg">“Stand therefore, having your loins girt about with truth, and having on the breastplate of righteousness; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p20" pid="eClj9j8g3kO94rJcj-PxaQ" hash="aUYMtw">“And take the helmet of salvation, and the sword of the Spirit, which is the word of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/6.10-11,14,17" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 6:10–11, 14, 17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p21" pid="2BwAphTkdk2dpu4or-suHA" hash="9ME4Ng">This is not only great counsel for all of us, but it is also a great success formula. It is a great philosophy of life which all of us need if we are to become bigger than the problems to be solved in our day. Man’s attempts to solve his problems by legislation, bribery, force, or education have always failed. All of his problems could easily be solved by a return to the true religion of Christ. As members of his true Church, we should lead the way in fighting for God and country, for law and order, for health and strength, for industry and courage, for truth and righteousness, and for each other.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p22" pid="_HAA_4HgjkmEJQyjXwEFYw" hash="sxzilw">We need to take the time to worship, to meditate, and to develop a more personal relationship with the Lord. We need to get acquainted with his teachings. We need to fill our hearts with the things of the Spirit. We need to be more practical and to begin to think today what Jesus thought. We can fill our minds with our Heavenly Father’s purpose and our hearts with an understanding of his ways. We can open the door of our soul and make room for the Savior to come in. The door of our heart can still be opened from within. Our invitation to the Lord to enter our hearts must come from the inside. The inspired counsel from the prophet Job should be ringing in our ears. He said, “Acquaint now thyself with him, and be at peace” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/job/22.21" class="scriptureRef">Job 22:21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p23" pid="sQ5WCUQweUiBwQ8AyCBJZQ" hash="UsVYUw">The Lord is still saying to us as he did in his time when he declared: “Behold, I stand at the door, and knock: If any man hear my voice, and open the door, I will come in to him, and will sup with him, and he with me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p24" pid="wUcO7CwUa0ye58And0QFaA" hash="lWNqGg">“To him that overcometh will I grant to sit with me in my throne, even as I also overcame, and am set down with my Father in his throne.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rev/3.20-21" class="scriptureRef">Rev. 3:20–21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace.p25" pid="nVc8w2w1fEue5bjHEWrCvA" hash="9leThg">My prayer, my brothers and sisters, is that we will make the worst of times the very best of times by making room for the Redeemer of the world in our personal lives. I testify that he is the living bread which came down from heaven. He is the promised Messiah and Savior of the human race. He is the eternal judge of the souls of men and conqueror of death and sin. He is our deliverer. He is our all because he gave his all for us. He is our salvation from sorrow and sin. He is Jesus the Christ! He lives! In his name, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1980/10/acquaint-thyself-with-him-and-be-at-peace</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1980-general-conference/1980-10-5020-elder-george-p-lee-64k-eng.mp3" length="11551044" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 1980 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Behold My Beloved Son, in Whom I Am Well Pleased”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In our world of skepticism, confusion and wickedness, to know the truth, to have a deep, humble, and solemn conviction that Jesus is the Christ, the Son of the living God, is a very precious thing. I have received the witness of the divinity of my Sa</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03154_000_031" doc-version="2" hash="68QvvA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="GocD_uCTzkyT_aK1Q5fMrQ" hash="H21sqQ">“Behold My Beloved Son, in Whom I Am Well Pleased”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="cd8xKdkMm0SzDkJP42JvjA" hash="TGLSmQ">George P. Lee</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-29c6.jpg" alt="Elder George P. Lee" pid="Y50ag74JoEC-GztCKoxXtg" hash="TgIVRw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p1" pid="aJaNapalB06Xg0UIE16IUA" hash="ooYLhQ">In our world of skepticism, confusion and wickedness, to know the truth, to have a deep, humble, and solemn conviction that Jesus is the Christ, the Son of the living God, is a very precious thing. I have received the witness of the divinity of my Savior through the sweet influence and power of the Holy Ghost. I have received this witness in my own heart, which exceeds all other evidences. It bears record to me, to my very soul, of the existence of my Redeemer, Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p2" pid="wZA8nVqOakG0L7GzZL3hyg" hash="Wk_mvw">This silent, sweet conviction came early in my youth, while I was on my knees in deep supplication in our humble hogan, and at other times, after reading the Book of Mormon while tending the sheep out in the hot desert on the reservation. Just as I know that my life did not begin when I was born, just as I know that it will not end when I die, likewise I know for certain that the life of Christ did not begin at Bethlehem; neither did it end on Calvary. Of himself, the Lord Jesus Christ said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p3" pid="oFGo43eVCUarNLLDTJA5kg" hash="zmFwDw">“I have glorified thee on the earth: I have finished the work … thou gavest me to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p4" pid="yMmJPNVX3Ue7qDzOGr6BHw" hash="M9dPwg">“And now, O Father, glorify thou me with thine own self with the glory … I had with thee before the world was.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.4-5" class="scriptureRef">John 17:4–5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p5" pid="xQIaafU7Okuh6xYAdxTiNA" hash="mRgQ6Q">I bear testimony that Jesus Christ was the first begotten Son of God in the Spirit. Like the Father himself, he was a personage of great power and intelligence in the universe. For ages before this world was created, he lived and ruled with his Father in Heaven in the premortal existence on a spiritual basis. The Lord Jesus had much to do with our growth and training prior to our birth on earth. Under the direction of the Father, he created this earth and accepted the appointment to come here and to be its redeemer. It was he who came forth in the Grand Council in Heaven and said: “Here am I, send me.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.27" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p6" pid="uwTxvfpwvU2y2GAmsuN75Q" hash="2A6hlw">“Father, thy will be done, and the glory be thine forever.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/4.2" class="scriptureRef">Moses 4:2</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p7" pid="ID2pfrxEsE62-UeBf_-4Og" hash="zXpJgQ">Of his beloved Son, our Heavenly Father has declared, “And worlds without number have I created; and I also created them for mine own purpose; and by the Son I created them, which is mine Only Begotten.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.33" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p8" pid="3dcoOmHsuUK7sVEvsGpPyw" hash="YkaYMA">There was no other good enough to pay the price of sin. He was the only one that could unlock heaven’s gate and let us in (see <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 201), because he was and is the only one suited, eligible, worthy, able, willing, perfect, and qualified for this great supreme sacrifice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p9" pid="Ns7f8xWXsUewhs6azkOk0Q" hash="HM1k9Q">I bear testimony that our Redeemer’s birth in Bethlehem was announced by a great concourse of angels and by an angel of great authority and power who had come from the presence of God, saying, “I am Gabriel, that stand in the presence of God; and am sent to speak unto thee, and to shew thee these glad tidings.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/1.19" class="scriptureRef">Luke 1:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p10" pid="wEljCACJQUS4BbgIo4esAw" hash="jf4ycg">Ancient prophets from the time of Adam down knew of his coming. He was known by name, character, and his good works long before his birth. Before his birth, he was a personage of spirit. After his birth, a body of flesh and bones was added. After he conquered death and after resurrection, he became a person with an indestructible glorified body, inseparably joined together with his immortal spirit. His whole mortal life was devoted to bringing peace and blessings to others. He lived a perfect life in the midst of evil and wickedness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p11" pid="xELfBHdG9EqRvkMTX6ptPw" hash="MNUhDA">His excruciating agony in the Garden of Gethsemane was not only physical and mental anguish, but also a spiritual agony that only a god was capable of experiencing. In that hour of tremendous anguish the Savior took upon himself the burden of the sins of the world from Adam down to the end of the world. Then they hanged him on the cross and crucified him in the most inhumane and cruel method of execution. A spike was driven through his hands and feet as was the method at that time. Of his suffering he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p12" pid="nu6Oy9572k-UgKbWifYAmQ" hash="1zQS0w">“For behold, I, God, have suffered these things for all, that they might not suffer if they would repent;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p13" pid="NM1EsTEank2PeuchIQPYuQ" hash="lQavKQ">“But if they would not repent they must suffer even as I;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p14" pid="91RgGdlKZEuQo1HoPi2_Cg" hash="ahp0TQ">“Which suffering caused myself, even God, the greatest of all, to tremble because of pain, and to bleed at every pore, and to suffer both body and spirit.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/19.16-18" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 19:16–18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p15" pid="aGx-aupiSUKlq4bBC9a8vg" hash="Vk2lMQ">In his infinite love and mercy he prayed for the very people that crucified him. He prayed and asked Heavenly Father to bless and forgive those that ridiculed, mocked, and insulted him. In pain and anguish he cried, “Father, forgive them; for they know not what they do.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/23.34" class="scriptureRef">Luke 23:34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p16" pid="dWtC4fdzwku5oZecYEE50Q" hash="MXhkMA">I bear testimony that this same crucified Christ arose on the third day from the tomb, after having met and mingled with others in the spirit world, his spirit was reunited with his body. After being among men on earth, he ascended to his Heavenly Father as a resurrected and glorified being. An angel, speaking of Jesus, said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p17" pid="oFV5uv7jqUCwS0IPaHivUw" hash="GhHCPA">“He is not here: for he is risen, as he said. Come, see the place where the Lord lay.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p18" pid="spgyTc_qqEejtOMy3gBfdA" hash="-OkJBQ">“And go quickly, and tell his disciples that he is risen from the dead; and, behold, he goeth before you into Galilee; there shall ye see him.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/28.6-7" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 28:6–7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p19" pid="TRBDxOa_-kmv2scErE8kkw" hash="kvwmQg">For thousands of years from the time of Adam up to Christ’s crucifixion, millions of people had entered the dark grave and suffered death and the end of life. For thousands of years, no one had ever returned. When our Redeemer arose from the tomb with his resurrected and immortal body, he robbed death of its sting and the grave of its victory. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/15.55" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 15:55</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/16.7-8" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 16:7–8</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/morm/7.8" class="scriptureRef">Morm. 7:8</a>.) Man was freed from sin’s dark prison. Death was conquered; Christ won the victory. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/15.8" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 15:8</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/morm/7.5" class="scriptureRef">Morm. 7:5</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/27.28" class="scriptureRef">Alma 27:28</a>.) He had opened heaven’s gate.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p20" pid="sa21Qf5eXEuUYsv-D_7kmA" hash="gUX6kQ">Immediately following his resurrection many others were resurrected. In Matthew we read:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p21" pid="mHTNFoGQWEaGaLMJWKZH1w" hash="VteHmw">“And the graves were opened; and many bodies of the saints which slept arose,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p22" pid="g4eDHa7a1U2m3SuiZCGyIQ" hash="kRKN4w">“And came out of the graves after his resurrection, and went into the holy city, and appeared unto many.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/27.52-53" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 27:52–53</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p23" pid="fJPGEg2xRU2Zhc4LoqVbMw" hash="PgzgCg">Thus, our risen Lord removed the last barrier in our march toward perfection and eternal life. Just as it is said of him “He is not here: … he is risen” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/28.6" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 28:6</a>), so it will be for each of us, because the empty tomb of the Lord Jesus is not only a symbol but also a guarantee of our own resurrection and immortality. It would be a serious mistake and a tragedy for anyone to assume that Jesus was just a great teacher and just a great humanitarian. Because of him, life continues throughout eternity. There is no other name under heaven whereby man will be saved and exalted. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/4.12" class="scriptureRef">Acts 4:12</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/25.20" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 25:20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p24" pid="POYYncWS5keTrGCyA-nHfQ" hash="fBNU4Q">I bear testimony that our resurrected Lord, clothed in glory, personally manifested himself to the Nephites and the Lamanites in ancient America as they were gathered around their temple in the land Bountiful. God our Eternal Father said unto them:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p25" pid="1hji1fMmZEKO_UqLGqPRwg" hash="PMsQyg">“Behold my Beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased, in whom I have glorified my name—hear ye him.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.7" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p26" pid="d_ZnchO48EqTgiy6uSmgwQ" hash="k1YMCg">They saw the Lord Jesus Christ, clothed in a white robe, coming down out of heaven; and he descended until he stood in their midst. He said unto them:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p27" pid="vQNtP5H3rE-ULsijpkEoiA" hash="20pE4g">“Behold, I am Jesus Christ, whom the prophets testified shall come into the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p28" pid="7WfYa_tyY0e6OULgsgVa6w" hash="WVegjw">“And behold, I am the light and the life of the world; and I have drunk out of that bitter cup which the Father hath given me, and … glorified the Father in taking upon me the sins of the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.10-11" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:10–11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p29" pid="wWDckXZW2EmB5N780bx8qA" hash="JYkdlg">The multitude fell at his feet and worshiped him. They then arose and came to him at his invitation to see and feel the prints of the nails in his hands and feet. They also saw and felt the spear wound in his side, and they did fall at his feet, overwhelmed and overjoyed. Their own eyes and hands were witnesses. Words cannot describe their heartfelt joy and gratitude. It was a glorious manifestation and spiritual feast for all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p30" pid="vZ3fFoy3O0SjpGxAelc5oA" hash="_xmh1w">I bear testimony that this, the last great dispensation of the fulness of times, was ushered in by the voice of God our Eternal Father, saying: <span class="emphasis">“This is My Beloved Son. Hear Him!”</span> (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.17" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p31" pid="N5NdmJ0ezU-vueO70E-fdA" hash="4W7Z6w">In the spring of 1820, God our Eternal Father and his Son, Jesus Christ, revealed themselves to the boy-prophet Joseph Smith. The darkness of the long night of the apostasy was lifted. This glorious manifestation illuminated the world. Other divine visitations by heavenly messengers and personages were made to the Prophet Joseph Smith. Many revelations were given to him. The giver of these revelations was none other than our risen Lord, Jesus Christ. The gospel was restored with all of its former blessings, keys, rights, privileges, and holy priesthood with authority to minister in the name of God. The Church, bearing his name and founded upon the rock of revelation, was restored.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p32" pid="XGF6wJq_tkiYIKtDMeFDfA" hash="i-snsQ">The gospel principles and laws that the Lord restored in our day are not that much different from those that he revealed in the times past. Latter-day Saints are expected, as were the Saints in the past, to seek first the kingdom of God and his righteousness. The Savior’s divine formula for success and perfection has always been the same: “Seek ye first the kingdom of God, and his righteousness; and all these things shall be added unto you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.33" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 6:33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p33" pid="tPft-0oCjE2-rqWngBTYjA" hash="I8foWg">The Lord Jesus wants us to build the necessary character, righteousness, industry, and godliness into our lives first. Then we are to do the same for others. That is, to assist him in teaching, baptizing, and perfecting individuals and families throughout the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p34" pid="uVY_bm-zVEOOahGsMLOJgQ" hash="g4bgPA">Even in our own day and age we can perfect ourselves in many areas. For example, we can become perfect in abstaining from the use of coffee, tea, tobacco, and liquor. We can become perfect in the paying of our tithing. We can become perfect in our sacrament meeting attendance. We can become perfect in honesty, in morality, in charity, in punctuality, in dependability, and in many other virtues. If we can live one gospel principle perfectly today, we can live two principles perfectly tomorrow. Perfection in one thing can act as a stepping-stone to perfection in something else.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p35" pid="ALscMMEceE-GpRdytsphtg" hash="Uq6XLw">I bear testimony that our risen Lord and Redeemer will return to earth a second time in his resurrected, immortal body of flesh and bones, and in celestial glory and power. When he came the first time he was misunderstood, condemned, and ridiculed and was a man acquainted with much grief. (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/53.3" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 53:3</a>.) When he came the first time, he atoned for the sins of the world. But when he comes the second time he will come as a triumphant King of kings and a glorious Lord of lords. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/rev/17.14" class="scriptureRef">Rev. 17:14</a>.) He will stand in judgment of sinners who have not repented. He will come as the Almighty God to cleanse the earth and to inaugurate his glorious millennial reign. (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/a-of-f/1.10" class="scriptureRef">A of F 1:10</a>). The Lord Jesus and the resurrected Saints will reign upon the earth during the thousand years of millennium. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/29.11" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 29:11</a>.) Satan will be tied and will have no power to tempt any man. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/43.31" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 43:31</a>.) Then after the end of the thousand years, Satan will be loosed again for a little season, and then will come the end of the earth. Satan and his forces will be banished forever and ever. Every person will be resurrected and stand before God to be judged. Our Lord, Jesus Christ, will be crowned with the crown of his glory to reign forever and ever. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.108" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:108</a>.) Those that have endured until the end and have achieved eternal life will abide with him and Heavenly Father forever and ever in the celestial kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased.p36" pid="xN0mJ8uDD0OfcXzdSjFgWQ" hash="xsT1Dw">I testify that he is the creator of “all things bright and beautiful, All creatures great and small” (Cecil Frances Alexander, in <span class="emphasis">Masterpieces of Religious Verse,</span> ed. James Dalton Morrison, New York: Harper and Brothers Publishers, 1948, p. 17). He is the master over ocean, earth, and skies. He is the promised Messiah. He is the victor over death and the grave. He is the Prince of Peace. (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/9.6" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 9:6</a>.) He is the same yesterday, today, and forever. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/13.8" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 13:8</a>.) Everlasting is his name. Eternal is his name. He is Jesus the Christ. I so testify, in his holy name, amen.</p>
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2cb2.jpg" alt="The Quorum of the Twelve, 1973" pid="HFSwXFi1s0SQYlKJOOlcEg" hash="_uLd7w" />
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1982/10/behold-my-beloved-son-in-whom-i-am-well-pleased</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1982-general-conference/1982-10-5050-elder-george-p-lee-64k-eng.mp3" length="13279395" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 1982 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can There Any Good Thing Come Out of Nazareth?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The true gospel of the Son of God has always been opposed by those who are caught within the throes of sin. For many, there is simply too much light, too much truth, and too much intelligence. Others who resist the gospel have found its principles to</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03193_000_010" doc-version="2" hash="P46Fgw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="hRBZKg7A_UicfTA3yQ7PHw" hash="5dGZCQ">Can There Any Good Thing Come Out of Nazareth?</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="2_tQ4dIyi0yUl6XgZSEP6A" hash="TGLSmQ">George P. Lee</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-29c6.jpg" alt="Elder George P. Lee" pid="i6x40ibmfke5NezYfkuzRg" hash="TgIVRw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p1" pid="_Ijdx6C9AUSn8pyQi5qf7A" hash="NsIoqA">The true gospel of the Son of God has always been opposed by those who are caught within the throes of sin. For many, there is simply too much light, too much truth, and too much intelligence. Others who resist the gospel have found its principles too pure, too noble, and much too elevating to accord with their chosen life-style. In all ages of the world since Adam’s time, the gospel of Jesus Christ has always met opposition whenever and wherever it has been proclaimed. This negative spirit challenges the truths of God and concerns His servants, even today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p2" pid="wyoyJLZI6kKDd21K0Z4EqA" hash="4oEGqQ">The heavens have been opened to holy men of various ages. In each case, the receiver of the vision has been rejected by his fellowmen. Sometimes his life has been sought and he has had no peace upon the earth. Prophets and Apostles, even the Lord Jesus Christ, have met such adversity and challenges. The true gospel of Christ is very unpopular with the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p3" pid="Galc9RE1AEqaVOC-NekNbw" hash="Acriyg">If there is anyone listening who is deeply troubled by the apparent criticism thrown against us periodically, let me say that we have a glorious array of predecessors who have been persecuted and who have met opposition time and time again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p4" pid="msUQ3AQsAUG2NU2xtM5eZg" hash="5d8WTQ">It is a source of consolation and encouragement that we do not stand alone in this respect. In former times, Saints of God have been challenged and scorned for no other cause than for preaching the truth in its fulness and purity, and for standing up in defense of holy and pure principles revealed from God. In fact, the trials they have been called upon to pass through, instead of being an evidence against, are evidence in favor of the truth of the work they were engaged in.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p5" pid="VzzWu3RKhUahwktxGQM29Q" hash="fD8ULA">The Lord Jesus said, “Woe unto you, when all men shall speak well of you!” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/6.26" class="scriptureRef">Luke 6:26</a>.) He warned His disciples of the danger when their names were honored and when all men spoke well of them. In a real sense, we as Latter-day Saints are also being warned. When our names are being honored in connection with all men speaking well of us, we need to renew our humility, dedication, and commitment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p6" pid="vudo2SnTg0iq8hUnhc7pHg" hash="BjLVhw">My beloved Saints of God, let us remember the warning from our prophets: “Others will he pacify and lull them away into carnal security, that they will say: All is well in Zion” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/28.21" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 28:21</a>.) If anyone finds himself in that position, it is time for renewed humility, commitment, and dedication.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p7" pid="l5vbxxKy4U-K6X8PKs-wSg" hash="_XYvpw">When the Lord came to Jerusalem, He was rejected and despised by many from the day of His birth until His Golgothic death. He spoke and taught as none had ever done before. He worked as none had ever done. He performed miracles and wonderful works among men. But what kind of treatment did He receive? He was rejected by those who were supposed to have loved Him. He was buffeted, scourged, mobbed, and led like a lamb to the slaughter. Jesus, a being in whom there was no guile, bore a rough-hewn cross—that cruel instrument of death which tore at His back as He hung in agony. The scribes, Sadducees, and Pharisees did not welcome Him with open arms. Nor did the learned, the wise, and the noble hail Him. Then need we expect the world to embrace and welcome us with open arms?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p8" pid="20PWxb4njkiZFxojspb4DA" hash="6n3Xzg">Joseph Smith knew and understood by the teachings given unto him of God and angels what he had to do. He was called of the Lord and raised up for this very purpose. He, too, was not popular among men, nor did the world clamor for his wisdom. Until the day of his death, he was persecuted and reviled for living and teaching the gospel. His blood sealed his testimony.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p9" pid="fDuPaowUYEq0GGmZcuxHKw" hash="GBkQUg">In the Lord’s own day, the proclamation was, “Can there any good thing come out of Nazareth?” (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/1.46" class="scriptureRef">John 1:46</a>.) Likewise, the life and teachings of Joseph Smith did not appeal to those with worldly thoughts. Joseph’s teachings came into conflict with man-made traditions and prejudices. The cry in Joseph Smith’s day was much the same as in the day of the Savior: “Can anything good come out of Palmyra? Can anything good come from Joseph Smith?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p10" pid="BMp5NijNzky5iGoc-ckrSQ" hash="742P5g">Today we hear a similar cry: “Can anything good come from the Mormon people? Can good be wrought by The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints?” Falsehoods are spoken about the true Saints of God. These will continue to abound until the coming of the Son of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p11" pid="ipFYZcZgLUOlt64NeHHhfA" hash="M5j9bw">Saints of God in all ages have passed through these tests of opposition. Those of today find themselves in no different position. Until evil is bound, this shall ever be the case. This is one of the legacies left to the elect Saints while here in mortality. Opposition may be our companion, and adversity our fate until the Lord comes in a cloud of glory. Latter-day Saints, this is our legacy. We may depend on it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p12" pid="55r6__gKVkKdrC9zLH8mug" hash="U60zrg">Said Jesus, “I have chosen you out of the world, therefore the world hateth you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/15.19" class="scriptureRef">John 15:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p13" pid="JnO4ihKcmkqIoK0sQLsd0g" hash="0mVvTQ">“If the world hate you, ye know that it hated me before it hated you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p14" pid="7h16OnFopkqdpFEg_8LFRQ" hash="uzvgiQ">“If ye were of the world, the world would love his own.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p15" pid="xAH7H8at4UuOIqy8hyJ-1g" hash="iTcGaA">“If they have persecuted me, they will also persecute you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/15.18-20" class="scriptureRef">John 15:18–20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p16" pid="LNhjr2vBBk-qJ9jbahRKFQ" hash="jqViLw">What if some of us have to sacrifice all that we have for the gospel and testimony of Christ? The Saints have done this in the past, and I am sure the Saints of today have the faith and courage to do whatever the Lord asks them to do. Should we complain or murmur if we are asked to sacrifice in defending the true gospel of the Son of God?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p17" pid="lHXOv2lbtEu2kk4ljTZi6g" hash="jK6tZw">The Lord, Jesus, was poor from the manger to the cross. He descended below all things that He might rise above all. Should we complain if we face challenges ourselves? As an individual, as one who has walked the path of poverty and trials, I am beginning to learn the value of such experiences. The Lord has always been my faith, strength, and courage. I want nothing but the best for my family and others. I desire salvation and eternal life for my family and for my fellowmen. I will pray for our critics and enemies. I will be patient and long-suffering toward them and will return kindness, prayer, and righteousness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p18" pid="QCZ4kbkVi0ODpdpL14kmiQ" hash="jNWSzg">There is no stopping the true work of God. Some men may resent it. The world may reject it. They may use every means and all their power against this work, but the work of God will roll forth and will gather every honest soul throughout the earth sooner or later. We have the promise of God that this is His work and it shall never be overthrown in this, the dispensation of the fulness of times.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p19" pid="p5njNUXY9kCMPwklLV7IYg" hash="d2ZSQw">Are we ready, as the Saints of God, to endure all things for the sake of the souls of our fellowmen? We have gone from continent to continent, from land to land, from island to island, wherever there was a door open to preach the gospel. We have left our homes, families, wives, and children. Some have sacrificed their lives for the salvation of their fellowmen. Some have gone without purse or scrip. Some have faced shame and ridicule, even persecution. We shall continue to do this until we have taken this beloved gospel to the ends of the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p20" pid="Hmdm5yyg4UKDSUUZD-e9yg" hash="pOAz3g">This message of salvation and eternal life has been entrusted to us. All mankind shall hear the glad tidings of salvation. They shall receive the blessings of God, or His condemnation, according to their willingness to receive or their determination to reject the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p21" pid="nekCb9PNP0-Oj-xAXaDbVA" hash="NqN6JQ">This work is a never-ending work which we have taken upon ourselves. It will never terminate until this earth shall be redeemed, until the power of Satan shall be subdued, until wickedness shall be banished from the earth, until Christ shall reign, whose right it is to reign, and until every knee shall bow and every tongue confess that Jesus is the Christ, the Son of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p22" pid="AV3P0JF5OkWGLz55j3nwPA" hash="30dGZA">In due course of time, all will be redeemed who may be redeemed. God, our Heavenly Father, desires that we should be long-suffering and patient toward those who seek to afflict and oppress us, just as He is long-suffering toward all of His children, in spite of their wickedness and waywardness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p23" pid="cD_y3gYVB0yi88fZJ2tAtA" hash="ErTOZw">Men of God who hold the holy priesthood are the head and heart of the Lord’s true church. We do not have the priesthood for self-aggrandizement or to be used to oppress anyone. There is no priesthood of the Son of God that authorizes any one man to oppress another or to intrude upon his rights in any way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p24" pid="dHLOVjlIVkWiVZHpiI3SCA" hash="rddkPg">We ought to be a brother and a friend to all men everywhere. We ought not to entertain a “Big I” and a “Little You” feeling toward our neighbors and fellowmen. Men of God who are approachable and compassionate are putting honor upon the holy priesthood of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p25" pid="PNhHzZ6KAkKmr3JDDDOLYg" hash="j8crqg">If there are any in our own flock who err, let us try to reclaim them by kindness and long-suffering. If there are any among us who have a bad spirit, let us show them a better spirit. If there are any among us who do not do right, let us do right ourselves and say to them, “Come, follow me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p26" pid="Alo9BowC3UuIibAcOzNv0Q" hash="8simdg">Amen to the priesthood or the authority of any man of God who exercises control, dominion, or compulsion upon a fellow being outside of the Church or upon a fellow member in the Church in any degree of unrighteousness. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.37" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:37</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p27" pid="JUlqjqQqAEKUFwPWcBeMOQ" hash="LOVN-w">I pray that our conduct day by day will be such that it will bear examination and scrutiny by our fellowmen, and also by our Heavenly Father. I pray that we will be willing to stand by this gospel, this testimony, and this work in life and death, in time and eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p28" pid="hLWBuaYeCk6AkvMHIrMTug" hash="DymLLA">I pray that every Latter-day Saint will let his prayers ascend into the ears of our Father in Heaven day and night, whether praying in family circles or in private places, for the Lord to sustain His leaders and people as we work to build up a Zion and to fulfill His promises. I pray that every Latter-day Saint will pray for the First Presidency of this Church and pray for His Apostles and leaders. Let us uphold them by our faith, works, and hopes. History will record one day that President Gordon B. Hinckley was one of the strongest counselors the Church ever had. Let us uphold him by our faith and by our prayers. President Hinckley carries a tremendous burden today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p29" pid="hg-py9sya06eT5Mol4mDLg" hash="i9cBdA">I bear testimony in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ that this work is true. I know that no earthly power can destroy it. Even the combined forces and powers of all the nations in the world cannot stop or retard this work because the Great Elohim and Jehovah have spoken it. I bear testimony that the principles of the gospel will live on, even if the earth wastes away. There is no power beneath the heavens that can hinder, stop, or destroy the progress of truth and the decrees of God, our Eternal Father in Heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p30" pid="RyIeh_Qxlkm5nv8lwtavmA" hash="4tnu3w">I bear testimony that the destiny of every individual, every prince, every emperor, of every king, president, statesman, or ruler under heaven is in the hands of God. He made the world and all that is in it. They may not go further than the Master permits. Adversity will purify Zion. Opposition will make us stronger in our courage and firmer in our faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p31" pid="xMaIAeHVlEW3Z9IpOmDMNQ" hash="RrBbfQ">I bear testimony that this work will continue to roll forth in strength and power throughout all the earth until all things which have been predicted by the prophets are fulfilled.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth.p32" pid="wlVXU2a1iEavqbCiF25Dpg" hash="qrPy6w">May the Lord bless all the Saints of God throughout the world. May He bless all the house of Israel, all of the dispersed of every tribe, all the righteous, the pure, the holy and good in every nation, is my humble prayer, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1985/10/can-there-any-good-thing-come-out-of-nazareth</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1985-general-conference/1985-10-2020-elder-george-p-lee-64k-eng.mp3" length="7680381" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 1985 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
