<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Gerrit W. Gong</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Gerrit W. Gong.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Gerrit%20W.%20Gong.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Gerrit W. Gong.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Temple Mirrors of Eternity: A Testimony of Family</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family?lang=eng</link>
      <description>An eternal perspective of gospel conversion and temple covenants can help us see rich blessings in each generation of our forever families.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021411_000_2060" doc-version="2" hash="qlwj7A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="rJALMdwv3UOV1oPX41kTbg" hash="CBEB5A">Temple Mirrors of Eternity: A Testimony of Family</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="fSDC_Qir4E616pHJi5UCIQ" hash="4O-Mxg">Gerrit W. Gong</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="kKg5ZlJztkWGNq0qgDqdwA" hash="NAUYtQ">An eternal perspective of gospel conversion and temple covenants can help us see rich blessings in each generation of our forever families.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p1" pid="rWIuPcL0vkGnkX-uon40hw" hash="j5Oviw">Dear brothers and sisters, when our son was in the Provo Missionary Training Center, Sister Gong mailed fresh-baked bread to him and his missionary companions. Here are some of the missionary thank-you notes Sister Gong received: “Sister Gong, that bread was a taste of home.” “Sister Gong, all I can say is wow. That bread is the best thing to enter my mouth since my mother’s enchiladas.” But this is my favorite: “Sister Gong, the bread was wonderful.” He then jokingly continued, “Keep me in mind if things don’t work out between you and Mr. Gong.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p2" pid="ugeGfJL4M0ax1LhKKwnYdA" hash="utGEnw">We love our missionaries—each elder, sister, and senior couple. We are eternally grateful to that special missionary who first brought the restored gospel of Jesus Christ to our family. I gratefully testify that an eternal perspective of gospel conversion and temple covenants can help us see rich blessings in each generation of our forever families.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p3" pid="dTQs1JmXyE-Q9VDxvhxUlg" hash="MRBqkw">The first convert in our Gong family to The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is our mother, Jean Gong. As a teenager in Honolulu, Hawaii, she listened; she knew; she was baptized and confirmed; she is continuing in faith. Faithful Church members helped my mother so that she had gospel friends, Church callings, and continued nourishment by God’s good word. In today’s parlance each new convert, young single adult, those returning to Church activity, and others bless generations when they become fellow Saints in the household of God.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p4" pid="ozdVT-YmJkaWJGgLSjLiYw" hash="cStPOQ">One family who nurtured my mother was that of Gerrit de Jong Jr. A linguist who loved the language of the heart and Spirit, Grandpa de Jong tickled my little boy imagination by sayings like “Blackberries when red are green.” Today, speaking of electronic handheld devices, I tell young friends, “Blackberries read in Church make green bishops blue.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p5" pid="G7OLfT571UiV3HsbmZlqGw" hash="aIXS9g">My parents, Walter and Jean Gong, were married three times: a Chinese ceremony for family, an American ceremony for friends, and a sacred ceremony in the house of the Lord for time and eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p6" pid="g-su8hssqkWmeqFxVm-XRg" hash="IPmlOw">Our Primary children sing: “I love to see the temple. I’m going there someday.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Our youth pledge to “receive the ordinances of the temple.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p7" pid="lUjXhDSvZ0KC5NY-5WtXAQ" hash="RxevPQ">I recently stood in a house of the Lord with a worthy couple there to receive blessings by covenant. I invited them to make their first honeymoon last 50 years, then after 50 years to begin their second honeymoon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p8" pid="zLa0eBEtM0uB7h_fOOwAJA" hash="fctJMQ">I found myself looking with this beautiful couple into the temple mirrors—one mirror on this side, one mirror on that side. Together the temple mirrors reflect back and forth images that stretch seemingly into eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p9" pid="LXd9uwpHsUCZz9g6a8FJAg" hash="c36Khw">Temple mirrors of eternity remind us that each human being has “divine nature and destiny”; that “sacred ordinances and covenants available in holy temples make it possible for individuals to return to the presence of God and for families to be united eternally”;<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> and that, growing together in love and faithfulness, we can give children roots and wings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p10" pid="dZwPJHnLVka6cBKS8Y_DGw" hash="_lt4Og">In temple mirrors of eternity, I reflected on First Dragon Gong, born <span class="smallCaps">a.d.</span> 837 (late Tang dynasty) in southern China and the succeeding Gong family generations to my father, our family’s 32nd recorded generation. My brother, sister, and I are in our family’s 33rd generation; my sons and their cousins, the 34th generation; our grandson, the 35th recorded Gong family generation. In temple mirrors of eternity, I could not see a beginning or end of generations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p11" pid="mlm7ePsR_UysbCeUatgUXg" hash="JvI7dQ">I then imagined not only a succession of generations but also a succession of family relationships. In one direction I saw myself as son, grandson, great-grandson, back to First Dragon Gong. In the mirrors in the other direction, I saw myself as father, grandfather, great-grandfather. I could see my wife, Susan, as daughter, granddaughter, great-granddaughter and, in the other direction, as mother, grandmother, great-grandmother.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p12" pid="RkotICz3mUuYLoU4VtVLuA" hash="yvPkjA">In temple mirrors of eternity, I began to understand my wife and myself as children of our parents and parents to our children, as grandchildren of our grandparents and grandparents to our grandchildren. Mortality’s great lessons distill upon our souls as we learn and teach in eternal roles, including child and parent, parent and child.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p13" pid="0ihAX6sOQEax-mnvvmPI7w" hash="DgZ5xQ">Scripture describes our Savior as “the Father and the Son.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Having dwelt in flesh and subjected the flesh to the will of the Father, our Savior knows how to succor us, His people, in our pains, afflictions, temptations, sicknesses, even death.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> Having “descended below all things,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> our Savior can bear our griefs and carry our sorrows. “He was wounded for our transgressions, … bruised for our iniquities … ; [with our Savior’s] stripes we are healed.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p14" pid="l31yyvRPl0e7XL1U1uxFmA" hash="8V7UyQ">From the councils in heaven, our Savior sought only to do His Father’s will. This pattern of Father and Son can help explain the paradox “He that loseth his life for my sake shall find it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> The world pursues enlightened self-interest. Yet the power is not in us to save ourselves. But it is in <span class="emphasis">Him.</span> Infinite and eternal,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> only our Savior’s Atonement transcends time and space to swallow up death, anger, bitterness, unfairness, loneliness, and heartbreak.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p15" pid="JZxWjVQTQU6XTsTN5QfxKg" hash="adWheQ">Sometimes things go wrong even though we have done our very best. A Lamb innocent and pure, our Savior weeps with and for us. When we always remember Him,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> He can stand with us “at all times and in all things, and in all places that [we] may be in.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> His “faithfulness is stronger than the cords of death.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> In drawing us to Him, our Savior also draws us to our Father in Heaven. While some things are imperfect on earth, we can trust our Heavenly Father to complete “redemption’s grand design, where justice, love, and mercy meet in harmony divine!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p16" pid="F0j_UqgqC0Kw0P21d-__ZA" hash="N_0u2Q">A miracle of the images we discern in temple mirrors of eternity is that they—we—can change. When Jean and Walter Gong entered the new and everlasting covenant, they opened the way for ancestors (such as First Dragon Gong) to be sealed and for posterity to be born in the covenant. Please remember: as we reach out to each sister or brother, we bless generations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p17" pid="exnNEodGLEiaaHyn-BHb_g" hash="SagOCA">The world is in commotion,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> but in His “only true and living Church,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> there is faith and no fear. In the words of the Apostle Paul, I also solemnly testify:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p18" pid="BlVS8fvM4EOwtBh1KO2_qw" hash="nTetpA">“For I am persuaded, that neither death, nor life, …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p19" pid="R4gatzszcEGWxzHtL5OrNw" hash="GE6AXA">“Nor height, nor depth, nor any other creature, shall be able to separate us from the love of God, which is in Christ Jesus our Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family.p20" pid="6lH0RfBGS0K_Ij-nZxD2xg" hash="sowmxw">I humbly witness: God lives. He “shall wipe away all tears from [our] eyes”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span>—except the tears of joy when we see through temple mirrors of eternity and find ourselves home, pure and clean, our family generations sealed by priesthood authority in love, to shout, “Hosanna, hosanna, hosanna.” In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/10/temple-mirrors-of-eternity-a-testimony-of-family</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2010-general-conference/2010-10-2060-elder-gerrit-w-gong-64k-eng.mp3" length="4348707" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Always Remember Him</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13285_000_62gong" doc-version="3" hash="GVBSfw"&gt;
	
	&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.head1"&gt;
		&lt;h1 class="title" pid="5iotwlaM_U-9aedBGpdaHA" hash="i6yPfw"&gt;Always Remember Him&lt;/h1&gt;
		&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p2" pid="mIUQVPqgiUqSMtdCbXa5_g" hash="ypclVQ1"&gt;By Elder Gerrit W. Gong&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p3" pid="4uSmjnO2FkWFkWClC_pp1A" hash="hptprg"&gt;Of the Presidency of the Seventy&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=tKgnCSrpC0mzvAwCH5P9EQ"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" altText="Elder Gerrit W. Gong" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255534/d993544951f749a8b7bc76a3facd2289/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255534/d993544951f749a8b7bc76a3facd2289/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255534/d993544951f749a8b7bc76a3facd2289/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x279="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255534/d993544951f749a8b7bc76a3facd2289/200x279.jpg" data-src-320x446="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255534/d993544951f749a8b7bc76a3facd2289/320x446.jpg" data-src-460x641="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255534/d993544951f749a8b7bc76a3facd2289/460x641.jpg" data-src-640x892="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255534/d993544951f749a8b7bc76a3facd2289/640x892.jpg" data-src-1024x1428="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255534/d993544951f749a8b7bc76a3facd2289/1024x1428.jpg" data-src-2048x2857="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255534/d993544951f749a8b7bc76a3facd2289/2048x2857.jpg" data-src-3791x5289="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255534/d993544951f749a8b7bc76a3facd2289/3791x5289.jpg" webURL="gerrit-w-gong-first-quorum-seventy_1255534.jpg" pid="tKgnCSrpC0mzvAwCH5P9EQ" hash="AAAAAA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="kicker" pid="iAH8_T-bskipdWSVVfxfRA" hash="m4GyXQ"&gt;I humbly testify and pray that we will always remember Him—in all times, all things, and all places we may be in.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="authorName" pid="kQVgzV4PAkGsz6D5OUhXGA" hash="ypclVQ"&gt;By Elder Gerrit W. Gong&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class="bodyBlock"&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p5" pid="GtR2vs0i9ECc1zLFHiSFnw" hash="oMNfrw"&gt;Dear brothers and sisters, when I served in Asia, people sometimes asked, “Elder Gong, how many people live in the Asia Area of the Church?”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p6" pid="liPYkk40A0un_PHwSXYjww" hash="hFyibA"&gt;I said, “Half the world’s population—3.6 billion people.”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p7" pid="tZkhCXv3VES00Tz90oHQBw" hash="OXOgPg"&gt;Someone asked, “Is it hard to remember all their names?”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p8" pid="U4FmFck3Nka3rhAPBkWNMg" hash="kNXO_g"&gt;Remembering—and forgetting—are part of everyday life. For example, once, after looking everywhere for her new mobile phone, my wife finally decided to call it from another phone. When she heard her phone ring, my wife thought, “Who could be calling me? I haven’t given that number to anyone!”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p9" pid="40JgozR1vEWEEpmOb8oezQ" hash="4IqgKw"&gt;Remembering—and forgetting—are also part of our eternal journey. Time, agency, and memory help us learn, grow, and increase in faith.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p10" pid="9TuZN5VmX0ey5ehupeExuA" hash="CwXKmQ"&gt;In the words of a favorite hymn:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;div class="poetry"&gt;
			&lt;div class="stanza"&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p11" pid="riAB9QXoMUeX5gbB69uBGg" hash="YNc7Zg"&gt;We’ll sing all hail to Jesus’ name,&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p12" pid="zMGRxagZAUWGVqq1qmB9EA" hash="WI3QMw"&gt;And praise and honor give. …&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p13" pid="R6_7jl4ExUejtOSLglffKw" hash="uibnmA"&gt;Ye Saints, partake and testify&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p14" pid="oJDMnIoQ0EqAPCORjlBDUQ" hash="LtVamQ"&gt;Ye do remember him.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p15" pid="El5NlDnswEWNEDRQuQUi_Q" hash="ebwPWQ"&gt;Each week, in partaking of the sacrament, we covenant to always remember Him. Drawing on the nearly 400 scripture references to the word &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;remember,&lt;/span&gt; here are six ways we can always remember Him.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p16" pid="PeuNi-hYfEe_IbzCzchlzQ" hash="aVgOHA"&gt;First, we can always remember Him by having confidence in His covenants, promises, and assurances.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p17" pid="nVoD2cNXCEm3ZSmoiJYLrw" hash="sXZUjQ"&gt;The Lord remembers His everlasting covenants—from Adam’s time to the day Adam’s posterity “shall embrace the truth, and look upward, then shall Zion look downward, and all the heavens shall shake with gladness, and the earth shall tremble with joy.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p18" pid="UsjsyBBpd0COEAl_bn8x7w" hash="margyA"&gt;The Lord remembers His promises, including promises to gather scattered Israel through the Book of Mormon: Another Testament of Jesus Christ and promises given to every member and missionary who remembers the worth of souls.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p19" pid="hwaR7yIFWUqwU6NcS5R5JA" hash="ebCZAg"&gt;The Lord remembers and assures nations and peoples. In these days of motion and commotion,&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; “some trust in chariots, and some in horses: but we will remember the name of the Lord our God,”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; who guides “the future as he has the past.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; In “perilous times,”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt; we “remember that it is not the work of God that is frustrated, but the work of men.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8"&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p20" pid="zjRa-vWOQk6--ytsPoOjxA" hash="SeH1mw"&gt;Second, we can always remember Him by gratefully acknowledging His hand throughout our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p21" pid="RsJCYs3A9UGt1EKa9_gloQ" hash="CB5FoA"&gt;The Lord’s hand in our lives is often clearest in hindsight. As Christian philosopher Søren Kierkegaard put it: “Life must be understood backward. But … it must be &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;lived forward&lt;/span&gt;.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9"&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p22" pid="t8PmRX14FEOsrGsbmBLQsA" hash="lQaL7Q"&gt;My dear mother recently celebrated her 90th birthday. She gratefully testified of God’s blessing at each major juncture in her life. Family histories, family traditions, and family ties help us savor remembrance of things past while providing future patterns and hope. Priesthood lines of authority and patriarchal blessings witness of God’s hand across generations.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p23" pid="ZdKqonOU_U-bW9_qmB0OoQ" hash="69Ir8Q"&gt;Have you ever thought of yourself as your own living book of remembrance—reflecting what and how you choose to remember?&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p24" pid="rQQ53DsCNUiVdT5EaH-8JQ" hash="6joL2w"&gt;For example, when I was younger, I really wanted to play school basketball. I practiced and practiced. One day the coach pointed to our 6-foot-4-inch (1.93 m) all-state center and our 6-foot-2-inch (1.88 m) all-star forward and said to me, “I can put you on the team, but you’ll likely never play.” I remember how kindly he then encouraged, “Why not try out for soccer? You’d be good.” My family cheered when I scored my first goal.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p25" pid="6Kt-LgGifkCJFa97oQkO2A" hash="KEB3YA"&gt;We can remember those who give us a chance, and a second chance, with honesty, kindness, patience, and encouragement. And we can become someone others remember when they most needed help. Gratefully remembering the assistance of others and the Spirit’s guiding influence is a way we remember Him. It is a way we count our many blessings and see what God hath done.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p26" pid="BYd_yT90JU-xeR4jTMnfsg" hash="9HqVwg"&gt;Third, we can always remember Him by trusting when the Lord assures us, “He who has repented of his sins, the same is forgiven, and I, the Lord, remember them no more.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11"&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p27" pid="zyrmFHx1I0OeXk6YTEBEIg" hash="q9gKLQ"&gt;When we fully repent, including by confessing and forsaking our sins, we ask with Enos, as our guilt is swept away, “Lord, how is it done?” and hear the answer “Because of thy faith in Christ”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12"&gt;12&lt;/span&gt; and His invitation to “put me in remembrance.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p28" pid="su6zjxZegE6yszebwviTgg" hash="iVJxoQ"&gt;Once we repent and priesthood leaders declare us worthy, we need not continue to confess and confess these past sins. To be worthy does not mean to be perfect. Heavenly Father’s plan of happiness invites us to be humbly at peace on our life’s journey to someday become perfected in Christ,&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14"&gt;14&lt;/span&gt; not constantly worried, frustrated, or unhappy in our imperfections today. Remember, He knows all the things we don’t want anyone else to know about us—and loves us still.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p29" pid="RjlSQHVXikuRr6yPnFc1BA" hash="rIyQVA"&gt;Sometimes life tests our trust in Christ’s mercy, justice, and judgment and in His liberating invitation to allow His Atonement to heal us as we forgive others and ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p30" pid="l4KnCo_FfEOWoGqN7SJhHQ" hash="YFlApw"&gt;A young woman in another country applied to work as a journalist, but the official who assigned jobs was merciless. He said to her, “With my signature, I guarantee you will not become a journalist but will dig sewers.” She was the only woman digging sewers in a gang of men.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p31" pid="r6EXcDseE0qIcNLZjF3Bcw" hash="Kb2KUg"&gt;Years later this woman became an official. One day a man came in needing her signature for a job.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p32" pid="9NktNSiYFkun1I88zbz7Xg" hash="CrEXeQ"&gt;She asked, “Do you remember me?” He did not.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p33" pid="EL6Mf8qs4UOitG39qp7Rlg" hash="O5Op9A"&gt;She said, “You do not remember me, but I remember you. With your signature, you guaranteed I never became a journalist. With your signature, you sent me to dig sewers, the only woman in a gang of men.”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p34" pid="Ot03f1wf8EeHdOGnai2hxA" hash="Q5SgzA"&gt;She told me, “I feel I should treat that man better than he treated me—but I do not have that strength.” Sometimes that strength is not within us, but it can be found in remembering the Atonement of our Savior, Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p35" pid="sjbiVTr2N0K5lgr3OsiU3w" hash="hFp_nA"&gt;When trust is betrayed, dreams shattered, hearts broken and broken again, when we want justice and need mercy, when our fists clench and our tears flow, when we need to know what to hold onto and what to let go of, we can always remember Him. Life is not as cruel as it can sometimes seem. His infinite compassion can help us find our way, truth, and life.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15"&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p36" pid="ximhByfC6EKyM8yn_EnIUg" hash="kMi4MQ"&gt;When we remember His words and example, we will not give or take offense.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p37" pid="P-5yzuMS-kuIgxenTg5Vig" hash="vA3FFg"&gt;My friend’s father worked as a mechanic. His honest labor showed even in his carefully washed hands. One day someone at a temple told my friend’s father he should clean his hands before serving there. Instead of being offended, this good man began to scrub the family dishes by hand with extra soapy water before attending the temple. He exemplifies those who “ascend into the hill of the Lord” and “stand in his holy place” with the cleanest of hands and the purest of hearts.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16"&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p38" pid="6Llfw4RZgEmsO-lWyRXOpA" hash="KfXcYQ"&gt;If we have unkind feelings, grudges, or resentments or if we have cause to ask forgiveness of others, now is the time to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p39" pid="hctNACt_W0a_ryFQpAtCWQ" hash="jyoRMA"&gt;Fourth, He invites us to remember that He is always welcoming us home.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p40" pid="Ze6GW8sqLEiBucckyM9PFg" hash="PEatKg"&gt;We learn by asking and searching. But please do not cease exploration until you arrive—in the words of T. S. Eliot—“where [you] started and know the place for the first time.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17"&gt;17&lt;/span&gt; When you are ready, please open your heart to the Book of Mormon, again, for the first time. Please pray with real intent, again, for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p41" pid="vuaPPNY4ZUSEKQaYxNalmg" hash="D2ZiTA"&gt;Trust that early or faint memory. Let it enlarge your faith. With God, there is no point of no return.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p42" pid="SzKQuSKAuEedPqtxKIkNLg" hash="ln9Wtw"&gt;Prophets ancient and modern implore us not to let human foibles, faults, or weaknesses—others’ or our own—cause us to miss the truths, covenants, and redeeming power in His restored gospel.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18"&gt;18&lt;/span&gt; This is especially important in a church where we each grow through our imperfect participation. The Prophet Joseph said, “I never told you I was perfect; but there is no error in the revelations which I have taught.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19"&gt;19&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p43" pid="xmCReRD4VkafdAyOE7SwCw" hash="cQRuEg"&gt;Fifth, we can always remember Him on the Sabbath through the sacrament. At the end of His mortal ministry and the beginning of His resurrected ministry—both times—our Savior took bread and wine and asked that we remember His body and blood,&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20"&gt;20&lt;/span&gt; “for as oft as ye do this ye will remember this hour that I was with you.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21"&gt;21&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p44" pid="catBdaK8zkKGtw8UJ33Xxg" hash="BRAnqQ"&gt;In the ordinance of the sacrament, we witness unto God the Father that we are willing to take upon us the name of His Son and always remember Him and keep His commandments, which He has given us, that we may always have His Spirit to be with us.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22"&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p45" pid="5rtNONa5skumq4xBePoCoA" hash="NgMp9Q"&gt;As Amulek teaches, we remember Him when we pray over our fields, our flocks, and our households and when we remember the needy, the naked, the sick and afflicted.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23"&gt;23&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p46" pid="cLeEGzz9DUmSRy_Zdm4r1w" hash="-sbWsA"&gt;Finally, sixth, our Savior invites us to always remember Him as He always remembers us.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p47" pid="ePaakzrib0eBN99PH0JeaQ" hash="kPeCsQ"&gt;In the New World, our resurrected Savior invited those present to come, one by one, to thrust their hands into His side and to feel the prints of the nails in His hands and in His feet.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24"&gt;24&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p48" pid="xtCEWzjPg0-EUgiTSL56SQ" hash="1wOS6w"&gt;The scriptures describe resurrection as “every limb and joint shall be restored to … their proper and perfect frame,” and “even a hair of the head shall not be lost.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25"&gt;25&lt;/span&gt; That being so, please consider how it is that our Savior’s perfect, resurrected body still bears the wounds in His side and the nail prints in His hands and feet.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26"&gt;26&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p49" pid="21bL_dfXdUGAImij9CtxsQ" hash="FyDreQ"&gt;At times in history, mortal men have been executed by crucifixion. But only our Savior, Jesus Christ, embraces us still carrying the marks of His pure love. Only He fulfills the prophecy of being lifted up upon the cross that He might draw each of us, by name, to Him.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_27"&gt;27&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p50" pid="UQKZUhlZ40uSiSj1As5oEg" hash="l-gnKw"&gt;Our Savior declares:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p51" pid="m7b-jEA_T0qyiI6C1GbrlQ" hash="PcxREw"&gt;“Yea, they may forget, yet will I not forget thee.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p52" pid="ZfA6j0LhoES-gmEFkKbVlw" hash="DE8NIw"&gt;“Behold, I have graven thee upon the palms of my hands.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_28"&gt;28&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p53" pid="JsiCCQ2Yw0igCa7_Q7yghg" hash="Vl-2Jw"&gt;He testifies: “I am he who was lifted up. I am Jesus that was crucified. I am the Son of God.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_29"&gt;29&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him.p54" pid="Xs8b78sYsU2HtuUMgVA4EA" hash="dh78uA"&gt;I humbly testify and pray that we will always remember Him—in all times, all things, and all places we may be in.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_30"&gt;30&lt;/span&gt; In the sacred and holy name of Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/04/always-remember-him</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2016-general-conference/2016-04-5020-gerrit-w-gong-64k-eng.mp3" length="5779735" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
