<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Gérald Caussé</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Gérald Caussé.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/G%C3%A9rald%20Causs%C3%A9.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Gérald Caussé.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Even a Child Can Understand</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand?lang=eng</link>
      <description>God … has ensured that the truths regarding God are understandable to all His children, whatever their level of education or intellectual faculty.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00009501_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="HY6lSg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="KRM4C5hVykKzuDFvJgHkbQ" hash="4KR8LQ">Even a Child Can Understand</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ZPY6KC30gE2OBehZ90rEaQ" hash="4LS3rA">Elder Gérald Caussé</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="TcALQHd8_0qEIpYFU-w6tA" hash="bigKvg">God … has ensured that the truths regarding God are understandable to all His children, whatever their level of education or intellectual faculty.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p1" pid="nEbY6MLAUUmrYXrrsr2XQA" hash="qotBaw">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="32"></span>Parents are often taken aback by the replies their children make to questions from grown-ups. One evening, when my wife and I were away, our children’s babysitter, intrigued by the prayer she heard them saying, asked them this question: “But what is the difference between your religion and mine?” The reply from our eight-year-old daughter was immediate: “It’s almost the same, except that we study a lot more than you do!” Far from wanting to offend her babysitter, my little daughter just wanted to underline in her own way the importance that Latter-day Saints attach to the search for knowledge.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p2" pid="sPlO-NDfj02wDJOr0S6QDA" hash="SdJunA">Joseph Smith declared, “It is impossible for a man to be saved in ignorance” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/131.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 131:6</a>). He added, “The principle of knowledge is the principle of salvation … ; and every one that does not obtain knowledge sufficient to be saved will be condemned” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 5:387). This knowledge is founded on understanding the nature of God and Jesus Christ and the plan of salvation that They have prepared to allow us to return to Their presence. “And this is life eternal, that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17:3</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p3" pid="tWXOFTrR6kWlgtp21hBtuw" hash="mxQkOQ">The principle of knowledge has often been misinterpreted by men. “The glory of God is intelligence” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:36</a>). It surpasses all we can ever understand with our intellectual capacities. People who try to find God sometimes think that they have to look for Him in intellectually complicated concepts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p4" pid="uzZYDzr26EuB_rXPIJnhwA" hash="51iUeA">However, our Heavenly Father is always available to us. He adapts to our level of understanding. “If He comes to a little child, He will adapt himself to the language and capacity of a little child” (Joseph Smith, in <span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 3:392).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p5" pid="43yijd4VMUmiMe5Rjrd_Kw" hash="wuwZbQ">God would indeed be unjust if the gospel were only accessible to an intellectual elite. In His goodness, He has ensured that the truths regarding God are understandable to all His children, whatever their level of education or intellectual faculty.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p6" pid="x2fdcZ0f60W57z37LSdWDQ" hash="rx4-DA">In reality, the fact that a principle can be understood even by a child is proof of its power. President John Taylor said, “It is true intelligence for a man to take a subject that is mysterious and great in itself and to unfold and simplify it so that a child can understand it” (“Discourse,” <span class="emphasis">Deseret News,</span> Sept. 30, 1857, 238). Far from diminishing its impact, purity and simplicity of expression allow the Holy Spirit to witness with greater certainty to the hearts of men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p7" pid="51_s-wg520SWJ2qOQxgSrw" hash="8D4SDw">During His earthly ministry, Jesus constantly compared the simplicity and authenticity of His teachings to the tortuous logic of the Pharisees and other doctors of the law. They tried time and again to test Him with sophisticated questions, but His replies were always crystal clear and childlike in their simplicity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p8" pid="-06B2QNA6E6Uxez-TCKiGw" hash="R2-TCg">One day Jesus’s disciples asked Him the following question: “Who is the greatest in the kingdom of heaven?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p9" pid="UeZdU8pUFku0Rqtp5OnaAQ" hash="FOTkOg">Jesus, having summoned a little child, set him in the midst of them and said, “Verily I say unto you, Except ye be converted, and become as little children, ye shall not enter into the kingdom of heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p10" pid="v0eTXvozskmnQ4sWUDd2nA" hash="mEEn0Q">“Whosoever therefore shall humble himself as this little child, the same is greatest in the kingdom of heaven” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/18.1,2-4" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 18:1, 2–4</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p11" pid="z3RG3xZQd0CUVLH16l_Icg" hash="sLxM3Q">On another occasion Jesus said, “I thank thee, O Father, Lord of heaven and earth, that thou hast hid these things from the wise and prudent, and hast revealed them unto babes” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.21" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p12" pid="3QAUP9d9O0ejPKHXaFTNdg" hash="74pi8A">The Bible has probably been the subject of more interpretations and philosophical debates than any other book. However, a child reading this book for the first time will have at least as much, if not more, chance to <span class="pageBreak" page-number="33"></span>understand the doctrine as the majority of those doctors of the scriptures. The Savior’s teachings are adapted to everyone. At eight years of age a child can have sufficient understanding to enter the waters of baptism and make a covenant with God with complete understanding.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p13" pid="ne8GTuher0KSJHISt5DwBQ" hash="yMgTDw">What would a child understand from reading the story of the baptism of Jesus? Jesus was baptized in the river Jordan by John the Baptist. The Holy Ghost descended upon Him “in a bodily shape like a dove.” A voice was heard: “Thou art my beloved Son; in thee I am well pleased” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/3.22" class="scriptureRef">Luke 3:22</a>). The child would have a clear vision of what the Godhead is: three distinct persons in complete unity—God the Father; His Son, Jesus Christ; and the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p14" pid="yoHmw7hK9Ei5fyXNWxW53w" hash="1z6jMQ">Rejection of the principle of simplicity and clarity has been the origin of many apostasies, both collective and individual. In the Book of Mormon, the prophet Jacob denounced those in ancient times who “despised the words of plainness, and killed the prophets, and sought for things that they could not understand. Wherefore, because of their blindness, which blindness came by looking beyond the mark, they must needs fall; for God hath taken away his plainness from them, and delivered unto them many things which they cannot understand, because they desired it” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.14" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:14</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p15" pid="lSAWOs3W3k64IzM7uKBJbQ" hash="D8PfGw">Sometimes we may be tempted to think, “It’s too easy,” just like Naaman, the Syrian captain who, constrained by his pride, hesitated to obey the counsel of Elisha, which was too simple, in his eyes, to cure his leprosy. His servants led him to see his folly:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p16" pid="jC7ggoHywEeJCWWj59XcBQ" hash="QU4Bmg">“My father, if the prophet had bid thee do some great thing, wouldest thou not have done it? how much rather then, when he saith to thee, Wash, and be clean?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p17" pid="c3mP5LZfNEmZ0kiaN1--Qw" hash="1atJaA">“Then went he down, and dipped himself seven times in Jordan, according to the saying of the man of God: and his flesh came again like unto the flesh of a little child, and he was clean” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/2-kgs/5.13-14" class="scriptureRef">2 Kings 5:13–14</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p18" pid="ov8vwHdfNEqVdrurDgO4Xw" hash="ZoMPng">His cleansing was not only physical; his spiritual flesh also was cleansed when he accepted this beautiful lesson in humility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p19" pid="BNYzWksrgECoKd9-69b5Kg" hash="ysTS4w">Little children have a marvelous disposition to learn. They have total trust in their teacher, a pure spirit, and great humility—in other words, the same qualities which open the door to the Holy Spirit. He is the channel through whom we gain knowledge of the things of the Spirit. Paul wrote to the Corinthians, “Even so the things of God knoweth no man, but the Spirit of God” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/2.11" class="scriptureRef">1 Corinthians 2:11</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p20" pid="AL20TG8QgkeHchyKcXnkOg" hash="m2Tb6g">And he added, “But the natural man receiveth not the things of the Spirit of God: for they are foolishness unto him: neither can he know them, because they are spiritually discerned” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/2.14" class="scriptureRef">1 Corinthians 2:14</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p21" pid="lxtbvVicL06W2WfwSev1gQ" hash="NNLAHQ">We know that the carnal or natural man is “an enemy to God … unless he yields to the enticings of the Holy Spirit.” For that, he must become “as a child, submissive, meek, humble, patient, full of love, willing to submit to all things which the Lord seeth fit to inflict upon him, even as a child doth submit to his father” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/3.19" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 3:19</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p22" pid="siHfVo6WPUm5YLasm19Ztw" hash="KjQoSg">In his philosophical short story <span class="emphasis">The Little Prince,</span> Antoine de Saint-Exupéry describes the confusion of a little boy who, on discovering a field of roses, perceives that the flower he has, which he has tended with such love, is not unique but very ordinary. Then he comes to the realization that the thing that makes his rose unique is not its outward appearance but the time and the love he has consecrated to taking care of it. He exclaims:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p23" pid="hbkV_wmG0Ey_SJyjq-MdWQ" hash="zngjHg">“Men … raise five thousand roses in the same garden—and they do not find in it what they are looking for. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p24" pid="Co0dvJznEkKRoG7RgM26fQ" hash="6xyAPQ">“And yet what they are looking for <span class="pageBreak" page-number="34"></span>could be found in one single rose, or in a little water. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p25" pid="2qMXmBojo0Sc-uPrqEjOZg" hash="G-Vb-g">“But the eyes are blind. One must look with the heart” ([1943], 79).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p26" pid="2YhDJ8tngkSR9TVu9GAqgA" hash="J7TF6A">In the same way, our knowledge of God does not depend on the amount of information we accumulate. After all, all the knowledge of the gospel which is meaningful for our salvation can be summarized in a few points of doctrine, principles, and essential commandments, which are already there in the missionary lessons we receive before baptism. Knowing God is a matter of opening our hearts to gain a spiritual understanding and a fervent testimony of the truth of these few fundamental points of doctrine. Knowing God is having a testimony of His existence and feeling in one’s heart that He loves us. It is accepting Jesus Christ as our Savior and having a fervent desire to follow His example. In serving God and our neighbor, we witness of Christ and allow those around us to get to know Him better.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p27" pid="EBJ6J74siE-_88eB_c2NBA" hash="BbLzIw">These principles find concrete application in the teaching which is given in our wards and branches. For you teachers of the Church, the principal goal of your lessons is the conversion of hearts. The quality of a lesson is not measured by the number of new pieces of information that you give your students. It comes from your capacity to invite the presence of the Spirit and to motivate your students to make commitments. It is by exercising their faith by putting into practice the lessons taught that they will increase their spiritual knowledge.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand.p28" pid="y-9XrxhttEKii79ki3OFkQ" hash="JGtOnQ">I pray that we will know how to open our hearts like a little child and take pleasure in hearing and practicing the word of God in all the power of its simplicity. I bear testimony that if we do this, we will gain the knowledge of the “mysteries [of God] and [the] peaceable things—that which bringeth joy, that which bringeth life eternal” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.61" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:61</a>). In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2008/10/even-a-child-can-understand</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2008-general-conference/2008-10-2040-elder-gerald-causse-64k-eng.mp3" length="5616771" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ye Are No More Strangers</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In this Church there are no strangers and no outcasts. There are only brothers and sisters.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10791_000_32causse" doc-version="9" hash="5Ecmqw">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="N9kHXOHIyUeCLzMTuG4IMQ" hash="kIvpAg">Ye Are No More Strangers</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="watBRab-QUCexrgmnHQ0nQ" hash="sXYXVw">By Bishop Gérald Caussé</p>
		<p class="kicker" pid="kXfItIlWt0qrWe4lDtBDvA" hash="4s_54w">In this Church there are no strangers and no outcasts. There are only brothers and sisters.</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="tTZkItrbBk-tlADnMqc3rg" hash="d9isQg">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p5" pid="hJE3t3DlqEmRgSJwnnkQnw" hash="jEtbqQ"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="49"></span>Most of us at one time or another have been in a situation that was new to us, where we felt strange and insecure. This situation happened to our family about five years ago after President Thomas S. Monson extended the call to me to serve as a General Authority of the Church. This call necessitated our family’s move from the beautiful place we had enjoyed for more than two decades. My wife and I still remember the instant reaction of our children when they learned about the change. Our 16-year-old son exclaimed, “It is not a problem at all. You may go; I will stay!”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p6" pid="HGw2FYdXS0urG9WEHCwk-w" hash="QXjREw">He then quickly resolved to accompany us and faithfully embraced this new opportunity in his life. Living in new environments over the past few years has turned out to be an enjoyable learning experience for our family, especially due to the warm reception and goodness of the Latter-day Saints. As we have lived in different countries, we have come to appreciate that the unity of the people of God throughout the earth is something real and tangible.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p7" pid="G1ac_DiHSUC1zUqFSVxMXg" hash="wqfnTg">My calling has led me to travel to many countries and has given me the choice privilege to preside in many meetings. As I look out over various congregations, I often see members representing many countries, languages, and cultures. One marvelous aspect of our gospel dispensation is that it is not limited to a geographical area or a group of nations. It is global and universal. It is preparing for the glorious return of the Son of God by gathering “his children from the four quarters of the earth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p8" pid="UVlxIGx_t0aOfO_RA0HP7A" hash="MPPLIQ">Though the membership of the Church is increasing in its diversity, our sacred heritage transcends our differences. As members of the Church, we are admitted into the house of Israel. We become brothers and sisters, equal heirs to the same spiritual lineage. God promised Abraham that “as many as receive this Gospel shall be called after [his] name, and shall be accounted [his] seed, and shall rise up and bless [him], as <span class="emphasis">their</span> father.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p9" pid="huJjQHB3E02pOgbnTXY2ZA" hash="FowyzA">A promise has been made to everyone who becomes a member of the Church: “Now therefore ye are no more strangers and foreigners, but fellowcitizens with the saints, and of the household of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p10" pid="47UHiTiJTUa3i_Cv9mJuag" hash="N1faAg">The word <span class="emphasis">stranger</span> comes from the Latin word <span class="emphasis">extraneus,</span> which means “exterior” or “from the outside.” Generally, it designates someone who is an “outsider” for various reasons, whether it be because of origin, culture, opinions, or religion. As disciples of Jesus Christ who strive to be in the world but not of the world, we sometimes feel like outsiders. We, better than many, know that certain doors can be closed to those who are considered to be different.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p11" pid="xHU-_bV8Wk-Ey5fF8pKD-w" hash="ZojXuA">Throughout time the people of God have been commanded to care for all individuals who are strangers or who may be seen as different. In ancient times a stranger benefited from the same obligation of hospitality as a widow or an orphan. Like them, the stranger was in a situation of great vulnerability, and his survival depended on the protection he received from the local population. The people of Israel received precise instructions on this subject: “But the stranger that dwelleth <span class="pageBreak" page-number="50"></span>with you shall be unto you as one born among you, and thou shalt love him as thyself; for ye were strangers in the land of Egypt.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p12" pid="GeV2vToUsE25ujNc1yGcsA" hash="aOMk6Q">During His earthly ministry, Jesus was an example of one who went far beyond the simple obligation of hospitality and tolerance. Those who were excluded from society, those who were rejected and considered to be impure by the self-righteous, were given His compassion and respect. They received an equal part of His teachings and ministry.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p13" pid="TrrjiE0CBku__9Vikzk3WA" hash="bCTsxw">For example, the Savior went against the established customs of His time to address the woman of Samaria, asking her for some water. He sat down to eat with publicans and tax collectors. He didn’t hesitate to approach the leper, to touch him and heal him. Admiring the faith of the Roman centurion, He said to the crowd, “Verily I say unto you, I have not found so great faith, no, not in Israel.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p14" pid="lN-ChRLE_kqUsHlHzyQdHQ" hash="OvyAhg">Jesus has asked us to observe the law of perfect love, which is a universal and unconditional gift. He said:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p15" pid="GYsoKqSWY0qd2i5mZilGnw" hash="5QnbCg">“For if ye love them which love you, what reward have ye? do not even the publicans the same?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p16" pid="pLe6NUMskEKnPRUuinCH-g" hash="2p4b6Q">“And if ye salute your brethren only, what do ye more than others? do not even the publicans so?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p17" pid="pAdz6-pGIUuMbj8Vdb7FkQ" hash="idMzlg">“Be ye therefore perfect, even as your Father which is in heaven is perfect.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p18" pid="o-B-ymFAEE21QfEE18W3oA" hash="OrwIHg">In this Church there are no strangers and no outcasts. There are only brothers and sisters. The knowledge that we have of an Eternal Father helps us be more sensitive to the brotherhood and sisterhood that should exist among all men and women upon the earth.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p19" pid="XaaYWVyi306GAJe41GPGMw" hash="8L_HHg">A passage from the novel <span class="emphasis">Les misérables</span> illustrates how priesthood holders can treat those individuals viewed as strangers. Jean Valjean had just been released as a prisoner. Exhausted by a long voyage and dying of hunger and thirst, he arrives in a small town seeking a place to find food and shelter for the night. When the news of his arrival spreads, one by one all the inhabitants close their doors to him. Not the hotel, not the inn, not even the prison would invite him in. He is rejected, driven away, banished. Finally, with no strength left, he collapses at the front door of the town’s bishop.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p20" pid="BUsi981M506PRN5_GuwewQ" hash="ILPfwQ">The good clergyman is entirely aware of Valjean’s background, but he invites the vagabond into his home with these compassionate words:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p21" pid="_gC-PDYX4UaR_u7S2js7Ow" hash="lgBCPA">“‘This is not my house; it is the house of Jesus Christ. This door does not demand of him who enters whether he has a name, but whether he has a grief. You suffer, you are hungry and thirsty; you are welcome. … What need have I to know your name? Besides, before you told me [your name], you had one which I knew.’</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p22" pid="vuuVWKFcRkWvmaNl7o5-_A" hash="eIxYYg">“[Valjean] opened his eyes in astonishment.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p23" pid="Z2dU0bywlkW2ZXt5JD0dUA" hash="jyFr6g">“‘Really? You knew what I was called?’</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p24" pid="6K3TNbsnVUaDm6ZLvcjTPA" hash="q4z_1A">“‘Yes,’ replied the Bishop, ‘you are called my brother.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p25" pid="Ih8pPe7fGUacOLX1_RFmMQ" hash="DkcejA">In this Church our wards and our quorums do not belong to us. They belong to Jesus Christ. Whoever enters our meetinghouses should feel at home. The responsibility to welcome everyone has growing importance. The world in which we live is going through a period of great upheaval. Because of the increased availability of transportation, speed of communication, and globalization of economies, the earth is becoming one large village where people and nations meet, connect, and intermingle like never before.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p26" pid="tXf5pPWFDE-YvkxbDr-LMg" hash="urf-SA">These vast, worldwide changes serve the designs of Almighty God. The gathering of His elect from the four corners of the earth is taking place not only by sending missionaries to faraway countries but also with the arrival of people from other areas into our own cities and neighborhoods. Many, without knowing it, are being led by the Lord to places where they can hear the gospel and come into His fold.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p27" pid="xWQkfxSKKkqysEXAeb0rjw" hash="fn8j1A">It is very likely that the next person converted to the gospel in your ward will be someone who does not come from your usual circle of friends and acquaintances. You may note this <span class="pageBreak" page-number="51"></span>by his or her appearance, language, manner of dress, or color of skin. This person may have grown up in another religion, with a different background or a different lifestyle.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p28" pid="jw-eFPmtQUOS4TIo0qomPQ" hash="B9EbBA">Fellowshipping is an important priesthood responsibility. Aaronic and Melchizedek Priesthood quorums are to act in concert with the sisters under the direction of the bishop to ensure that each person is welcomed with love and kindness. Home teachers and visiting teachers will be watchful to ensure that no one is forgotten or ignored.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p29" pid="Nl9cn8JhqkCLTW---7wWPg" hash="Brtc0Q">We all need to work together to build spiritual unity within our wards and branches. An example of perfect unity existed among the people of God after Christ visited the Americas. The record observes that there were no “Lamanites, nor any manner of -ites; but they were in one, the children of Christ, and heirs to the kingdom of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p30" pid="VMCFsyrZJkKGChnqcZF7Uw" hash="KAsMEw">Unity is not achieved by ignoring and isolating members who seem to be different or weaker and only associating with people who are like us. On the contrary, unity is gained by welcoming and serving those who are new and who have particular needs. These members are a blessing for the Church and provide us with opportunities to serve our neighbors and thus purify our own hearts.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p31" pid="CXVwjz1-ZEmdV4QHVnGRpw" hash="UO_1cA">So, my brothers, it is your duty to reach out to anyone who appears at the doors of your Church buildings. Welcome them with gratitude and without prejudice. If people you do not know walk into one of your meetings, greet them warmly and invite them to sit with you. Please make the first move to help them feel welcome and loved, rather than waiting for them to come to you.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p32" pid="jXxS1BV7a06TdQeqrN1uVQ" hash="i_tXLQ">After your initial welcome, consider ways you can continue to minister to them. I once heard of a ward where, after the baptism of two deaf sisters, two marvelous Relief Society sisters decided to learn sign language so they could better communicate with these new converts. What a wonderful example of love for fellow brothers and sisters in the gospel!</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p33" pid="s6EDeTDUCUi2H8_hbgsbkQ" hash="GeGu3Q">I bear witness that no one is a stranger to our Heavenly Father. There is no one whose soul is not precious to Him. With Peter, I testify that “God is no respecter of persons: but in every nation he that feareth him, and worketh righteousness, is accepted with him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p34" pid="Vf-Fkacle0C7AZvLFQGBBw" hash="faw1dg">I pray that when the Lord gathers His sheep at the last day, He may say to each one of us, “I was a stranger, and ye took me in.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p35" pid="wj-hNYrJ-06w6oFV8XEx6g" hash="5R9mVg">Then we will say to Him, “When saw we thee a stranger, and took thee in?”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p36" pid="pvxvKdRrzEC9ZFenhXhJQg" hash="haUzCA">And He will answer us, “Verily I say unto you, Inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers.p37" pid="sBIjTT8YWUmD8p5UdgyKrw" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2013/10/ye-are-no-more-strangers</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2013-general-conference/2013-10-3020-bishop-gerald-causse-64k-eng.mp3" length="5856642" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is It Still Wonderful to You?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Bishop Gérald Caussé invites us to always remember the wonders of the gospel of Jesus Christ.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_12565_000_44causse" doc-version="5" hash="K03aaw">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="jBt9KVj-mUq4wMwiBWx2bQ" hash="nY3N0A">Is It Still Wonderful to You?</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p2" pid="LWfAtcq7R0qtT3kPyy1dDA" hash="sXYXVw">By Bishop Gérald Caussé</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p3" pid="IMYraVDjb0ODF4XtXtxBVQ" hash="BSOiaA">First Counselor in the Presiding Bishopric</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=-5c-1cy48kSRjqvaFVxjkQ"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" type="jpg" uri="gerald-j-causse-10.jpg" translate="no" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255503/dc3fd4be53be441cbcc288585a9e681d/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255503/dc3fd4be53be441cbcc288585a9e681d/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255503/dc3fd4be53be441cbcc288585a9e681d/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x279="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255503/dc3fd4be53be441cbcc288585a9e681d/200x279.jpg" data-src-320x446="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255503/dc3fd4be53be441cbcc288585a9e681d/320x446.jpg" data-src-460x641="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255503/dc3fd4be53be441cbcc288585a9e681d/460x641.jpg" data-src-640x893="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255503/dc3fd4be53be441cbcc288585a9e681d/640x893.jpg" data-src-1024x1428="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255503/dc3fd4be53be441cbcc288585a9e681d/1024x1428.jpg" data-src-2048x2857="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255503/dc3fd4be53be441cbcc288585a9e681d/2048x2857.jpg" data-src-3883x5418="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255503/dc3fd4be53be441cbcc288585a9e681d/3883x5418.jpg" pid="-5c-1cy48kSRjqvaFVxjkQ" hash="zySL1A"></img></a>
		</div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="iSjiqeRQH0uWQyqW26_1DQ" hash="KVr1YQ">To marvel at the wonders of the gospel is a sign of faith. It is to recognize the hand of the Lord in our lives and in everything around us.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="Kbq_if0dbEiGndNOCgJFWA" hash="sXYXVw1">By Bishop Gérald Caussé</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="OpqKo-c9BkOh3i6Y89hbcw" hash="toiuqg">
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p5" pid="XhwxRC6OREWanKHqGv7AuA" hash="Cj-BrQ">My wife and I had the great joy of rearing our five children near the magnificent city of Paris. During those years we wanted to offer them rich opportunities to discover the marvelous things of this world. Each summer, our family took long trips to visit the most significant monuments, historic sites, and natural wonders of Europe. Finally, after spending 22 years in the Paris area, we were getting ready to move. I still remember the day when my children came to me and said, “Dad, it’s absolutely shameful! We’ve lived here all our lives, and we have never been to the Eiffel Tower!”</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p6" pid="mT1W1SbvJE2iCa-S3AG_PQ" hash="aD0fXw">There are so many wonders in this world. However, sometimes when we have them constantly before our eyes, we take them for granted. We look, but we don’t really see; we hear, but we don’t really listen.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p7" pid="looe24aqikCbdt6T7WPhCg" hash="fhtngg">During His earthly ministry, Jesus said to His disciples:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p8" pid="srBl7-YxuUKLkBcS9NSD_Q" hash="6PyOKg">“Blessed are the eyes which see the things that ye see:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p9" pid="dwjbOpnkn0ihKHLNj31elw" hash="jKcDSw">“For I tell you, that many prophets and kings have desired to see those things which ye see, and have not seen them; and to hear those things which ye hear, and have not heard them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p10" pid="ICHBlVQ_506aoL7kRSrlRA" hash="2CXZaw">I have often wondered what it would have been like to live at the time of our Savior. Can you imagine sitting at His feet? feeling His embrace? witnessing as He ministered to others? And yet so many who met Him failed to recognize—to “see”—that the very Son of God was living among them.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p11" pid="gNKBdyR3B0SLWiZdbRrKgw" hash="Z5F2VQ">We too are privileged to live in an exceptional time. The prophets of old saw the work of the Restoration as “a marvelous work … , yea, a marvelous work and a wonder.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> In no previous dispensation have so many missionaries been called, so many nations been opened for the gospel message, and so many temples been built throughout the world.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p12" pid="HvWwyd4RFkqmFG61A9EhYw" hash="GYIobA">For us, as Latter-day Saints, wonders also occur in our individual lives. They include our own personal conversion, the answers we receive to our prayers, and the tender blessings God showers upon us daily.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p13" pid="xrw0m2sxiE6UNHIiF2Rdtg" hash="LItbVA">To marvel at the wonders of the gospel is a sign of faith. It is to recognize the hand of the Lord in our lives and in everything around us. Our amazement also produces spiritual strength. It gives us the energy to remain anchored in our faith and to engage ourselves in the work of salvation.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p14" pid="vRLl5-m-L0m4jKedTrBkDA" hash="t-uXDg">But let us beware. Our ability to marvel is fragile. Over the long term, such things as casual commandment keeping, apathy, or even weariness may set in and make us insensitive to even the most remarkable signs and miracles of the gospel.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p15" pid="yuwBOZdK_0G8loS_utrFCw" hash="5lPsVQ">The Book of Mormon describes a period, very similar to our own, that preceded the coming of the Messiah to the Americas. Suddenly the signs of His birth appeared in the heavens. The people were so stricken with astonishment that they humbled themselves, and nearly all were converted. However, only a short four years later, “the people began to forget those signs and wonders which they had heard, and began to be less and less astonished at a sign or a wonder from heaven, … and began to disbelieve all which they had heard and seen.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p16" pid="4MaPO7KQUUyQmQhGMY8ZCA" hash="1LeAoA">My brothers and sisters, is the gospel still wonderful to you? Can you yet see, hear, feel, and marvel? Or have your spiritual sensors gone into standby mode? Whatever your personal situation, I invite you to do three things.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p17" pid="bExob-F9BkusIvENwgwprg" hash="C7Nzsg">First, never tire of discovering or rediscovering the truths of the gospel. The writer Marcel Proust said, “The real voyage of discovery consists not in seeking new landscapes but in having new eyes.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Do you remember the first time you read a verse of scripture and felt as if the Lord was speaking to you personally? Can you recall the first time you felt the sweet influence of the Holy Ghost come over you, perhaps before you even realized it was the Holy Ghost? Weren’t these sacred, special moments?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p18" pid="4EpV_0Sr30Ku8ONSSXLiMw" hash="wGfw_g">We should hunger and thirst every day after spiritual knowledge. This personal practice is founded on study, meditation, and prayer. Sometimes we might be tempted to think, “I don’t need to study the scriptures today; I’ve read them all before” or “I don’t need to go to church today; there’s nothing new there.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p19" pid="gNe6haggpUSFe9biCO18wg" hash="QxrAQQ">But the gospel is a fountain of knowledge that never runs dry. There is always something new to learn and feel each Sunday, in every meeting, and in every verse of scripture. In faith we hold to the promise that if we “seek, … [we] shall find.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p20" pid="MiwnMgtqHEiav8kEtm1P1Q" hash="j0xZlA">Second, anchor your faith in the plain and simple truths of the gospel. Our amazement should be rooted in the core principles of our faith, in the purity of our covenants and ordinances, and in our most simple acts of worship.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p21" pid="e2fH7Xnu6EKArR1VWgWqPQ" hash="52y2NA">A sister missionary told the story of three men she met during a district conference in Africa. They came from an isolated village far away in the bush where the Church had not yet been organized but where there were 15 faithful members and almost 20 investigators. For over two weeks these men had walked on foot, traveling more than 300 miles (480 km) over paths rendered muddy by the rainy season, so they could attend the conference and bring the tithes from the members of their group. They planned to stay for an entire week so they could enjoy the privilege of partaking of the sacrament the following Sunday and then hoped to set out on the return trip carrying boxes filled with copies of the Book of Mormon on their heads to give to the people of their village.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p22" pid="hNlf39foTE2bBUu6Erwu2A" hash="zczYGQ">The missionary testified how touched she was by the sense of wonder these brethren displayed and by their wholehearted sacrifices to obtain things that for her had always been readily available.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p23" pid="pISCfKPdzEuIei3SxA1kwg" hash="-uw5QA">She wondered: “If I got up one Sunday morning in Arizona and found that my car wasn’t working, would I walk to my church only a few blocks away from home? Or would I just stay home because it was too far or because it was raining?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> These are good questions for all of us to consider.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p24" pid="DjfVomABwUupv0tl5EtWRA" hash="vIJz0w">Finally, I invite you to seek and cherish the companionship of the Holy Ghost. Most wonders of the gospel cannot be perceived by our natural senses. They are the things that the “eye hath not seen, nor ear heard, … the things which God hath prepared for them that love him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p25" pid="44HSlp2xpUG2A9p9Q7smyA" hash="WZVNqA">When we have the Spirit with us, our spiritual senses are sharpened and our memory is kindled so we cannot forget the miracles and signs we have witnessed. That may be why, knowing Jesus was about to leave them, His Nephite disciples prayed fervently “for that which they most desired; and they desired that the Holy Ghost should be given unto them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p26" pid="dpIaYvjhYUm5LUzGDF26og" hash="InUlUg">Although they had seen the Savior with their own eyes and had touched His wounds with their own hands, they knew that their testimonies might dwindle without being constantly renewed by the power of the Spirit of God. My brothers and sisters, never do anything to risk the loss of this precious and marvelous gift—the companionship of the Holy Ghost. Seek it through fervent prayer and righteous living.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p27" pid="7C9uu8nc7UqcHPlpKpKfJA" hash="8I5TOg">I testify that the work in which we are engaged is “a marvelous work and a wonder.” As we follow Jesus Christ, God bears witness to us “with signs and wonders, and with divers miracles, and gifts of the Holy Ghost, according to his own will.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> On this special day, I bear witness that the wonders and marvels of the gospel are anchored in the greatest of all of God’s gifts—the Savior’s Atonement. This is the perfect gift of love that the Father and the Son, united in purpose, have offered to each one of us. With you, “I stand all amazed at the love Jesus offers me. … Oh, it is wonderful, wonderful to me!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you.p28" pid="GsCGgwYUYUWv4buyaUxC2w" hash="fws6dg">That we may always have eyes that see, ears that hear, and hearts that perceive the wonders of this marvelous gospel is my prayer in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/04/is-it-still-wonderful-to-you</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2015-general-conference/2015-04-4040-bishop-gerald-causse-64k-eng.mp3" length="4911211" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prepare the Way</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Bishop Causée urges Aaronic and Melchizedek Priesthood holders to work together in leading, in serving others, and in accomplishing the work of salvation.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60003501_000_43causse" doc-version="1" hash="LLWOZw">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="Lf-_vVe3bUaIWuwiDfCaNg" hash="TVO9TQ">Prepare the Way</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p2" pid="O1NcGbEK_kqOlPZ0qclVqQ" hash="sXYXVw1">By Bishop Gérald Caussé</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p3" pid="65Nr5bUtCU-bBaS3Ik4JbA" hash="oW2ZWg">Presiding Bishop</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="SwPw4xRof0uMPs42owvWJg" hash="INOM4g">Even though they are vested with different missions and authority, the Aaronic Priesthood and the Melchizedek Priesthood are inseparable partners in the work of salvation.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="JbgCLJtqWUKl7hW1XGMDGg" hash="sXYXVw">By Bishop Gérald Caussé</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p5" pid="EVatkQ98M0OB0_9t3RQ7jg" hash="ZVet7Q">When I was 30 years old, I began working for a retail group in France. One day the company president, a good man of another faith, called me into his office. His question startled me: “I just learned you are a priest in your church. Is that true?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p6" pid="oBTQJxA4bEGy6zBSXhYj5A" hash="pFJ7qg">I replied, “Yes, that is correct. I hold the priesthood.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p7" pid="yK3Zx7mM6U6Rci7bWdXAZA" hash="vaUJxQ">Visibly intrigued by my response, he further inquired, “But did you study at a theological seminary?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p8" pid="jChK1bcmWUeTvsHzDPhfQw" hash="epUUJA">“Of course,” I answered, “between the ages of 14 and 18, and I studied seminary lessons nearly every day!” He almost fell off his chair.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p9" pid="23yUWSQa10ecUQKQ_KhFLQ" hash="Jjc8Pw">To my great surprise, several weeks later he called me back to his office to offer me a managing director position in one of the group’s companies. I was astonished and expressed my concern that I was too young and inexperienced to hold such an important responsibility. With a benevolent smile, he said, “That may be true, but it doesn’t matter. I know your principles, and I know what you’ve learned in your church. I need you.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p10" pid="tSI-QOJF1UCufgQcW9ASTA" hash="so07MA">He was right about what I had learned in the Church. The years that followed were challenging, and I don’t know if I could have had any success without the experience I acquired by serving in the Church from the time I was a young man.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p11" pid="MMT93oHxqkmA8I-JEZNjjw" hash="oji1-Q">I had the blessing of growing up in a small branch. Because our numbers were few, the youth were called upon to actively participate in all aspects of the branch. I was very busy and loved feeling useful. On Sundays I officiated at the sacrament table, served in my priesthood quorum, and functioned in various other callings. During the week I often accompanied my father and other adult priesthood holders as we home taught members, comforted the sick and afflicted, and helped those in need. No one seemed to think I was too young to serve or even to lead. For me, it all seemed normal and natural.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p12" pid="EMlDssevXUemp7aGsEAf_Q" hash="jtZ9SA">The service I rendered during those teenage years helped me build my testimony and anchor my life in the gospel. I was surrounded by good and compassionate men who were committed to using their priesthood to bless the lives of others. I wanted to be like them. In serving with them, much more than I realized at the time, I learned to be a leader in the Church and also in the world.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p13" pid="VbgLzKwh5Umb2UwoLwboaQ" hash="m9hu6g">We have many young men attending or tuning in to this meeting tonight who hold the Aaronic Priesthood. As I look out at this audience, I see many of you sitting next to mature men, perhaps your fathers, your grandfathers, your older brothers, or your priesthood leaders—all holders of the Melchizedek Priesthood. They love you, and in large part, they came here tonight to be with you.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p14" pid="DScLFAq9k0GPpjPOWeLxqA" hash="40S7Ng">This gathering of generations offers a marvelous vision of the unity and brotherhood that exist between the two priesthoods of God. Even though they are vested with different missions and authority, the Aaronic Priesthood and the Melchizedek Priesthood are inseparable partners in the work of salvation. They go hand in hand and have great need of each other.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p15" pid="aX1Yn0C2JEGSO__JHx3qTA" hash="FBnkhw">The perfect model of the close relationship that exists between the two priesthoods is found in the interaction between Jesus and John the Baptist. Can one possibly imagine John the Baptist without Jesus? What would the Savior’s mission have been like without the preparatory work performed by John?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p16" pid="16iOZun76EWh_UASB_k8eQ" hash="Vdi29Q">John the Baptist was given one of the most noble missions to ever exist: “to prepare the way of the Lord,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> to baptize Him with water, and to make ready a people to receive Him. This “just … and … holy [man],”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> who had been ordained to the lesser priesthood, was perfectly aware of both the importance and the limits of his mission and his authority.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p17" pid="p8YauC8t20iE2_NDRGy5vQ" hash="3pOxBw">People flocked to John to hear him and be baptized by him. He was honored and revered in his own right as a man of God. But when Jesus appeared, John humbly deferred to One greater than himself and declared, “I baptize with water: but there standeth one among you, … who coming after me is preferred before me, whose shoe’s latchet I am not worthy to unloose.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p18" pid="lMv3lxJ5g0edULpEzF5Tww" hash="kuiRCA">For His part, Jesus the Christ, the Only Begotten of the Father, who held the higher priesthood, humbly recognized the authority of John. Of him, the Savior said, “Among them that are born of women there hath not risen a greater than John the Baptist.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p19" pid="TM3plyAXyEWkdscAYe2aUg" hash="1sigJw">Just think of what would take place in our priesthood quorums if the relationships between the holders of the two priesthoods were inspired by the pattern established by Jesus and John the Baptist. My young brethren of the Aaronic Priesthood, like John’s, your role is to “prepare the way”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> for the great work of the Melchizedek Priesthood. You are doing this in many different ways. You administer the ordinances of baptism and of the sacrament. You help prepare a people for the Lord by preaching the gospel, by “[visiting] the house of each member,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> and by “[watching] over the church.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> You provide assistance to the poor and needy by collecting fast offerings, and you participate in taking care of Church meetinghouses and other temporal resources. Your role is important, needful, and sacred.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p20" pid="-TSFJaCew0OsfbjsapwAjA" hash="pVUkHQ">My adult brethren, whether you are fathers, bishops, Young Men advisers, or simply holders of the Melchizedek Priesthood, you can follow the Savior’s example by turning to your brothers who hold the lesser priesthood and inviting them to labor with you. In reality, this invitation comes from the Lord Himself. He said, “Therefore, take with you those who are ordained unto the lesser priesthood, and send them before you to make appointments, and to prepare the way, and to fill appointments that you yourselves are not able to fill.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p21" pid="XjdmvHEwL0KqELSc1G8e4w" hash="fBEkJg">As you invite your younger brothers to “prepare the way,” you help them recognize and honor the sacred authority they hold. By doing so, you help them prepare their own way as they prepare for the day that they receive and exercise the higher priesthood.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p22" pid="WP4m9GL0JU2-baP7GOQEbg" hash="z6Aijw">Allow me to share the true story of Alex, a quiet, thoughtful, and bright young priest. One Sunday, Alex’s bishop found him alone in a classroom in a state of great distress. The young man explained how painfully difficult it was for him to attend church without his father, who was not a member. Then he tearfully said it would probably be better for him to leave the Church.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p23" pid="obCMF19TmEmXj5XGCT9HUA" hash="lSHS3g">With genuine concern for this young man, the bishop immediately mobilized the ward council to help Alex. His plan was simple: to keep Alex active and help him develop a heartfelt testimony of the gospel, they needed to “surround him with good people and give him important things to do.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p24" pid="ZR72u_eMdEmDd4TO3UYzOQ" hash="y-AV_A">Quickly the priesthood brethren and all the ward members rallied around Alex and expressed their affection and support. The high priests group leader, a man of great faith and love, was chosen to be his home teaching companion. Members of the bishopric took him under their wings and made him their closest associate.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p25" pid="Syp17gZ01kubY6zTjrLEAA" hash="56HLpA">The bishop said: “We kept Alex busy. He ushered at weddings, ushered at funerals, assisted me at graveside dedications, baptized several new members, ordained young men to Aaronic Priesthood offices, taught youth lessons, taught with the missionaries, unlocked the building for conferences, and locked up the building late at night after conferences. He did service projects, accompanied me on visits to elderly members in hospices, gave talks in sacrament meeting, administered the sacrament to the sick in hospitals or in their homes, and became one of only a very small handful of people that I could totally rely on as bishop.”</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=9j5ITA8-Wk649zwTRJ7ZZA"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912022/60f28b2ee7e145379d086537b6402131/100x124.png" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x62="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912022/60f28b2ee7e145379d086537b6402131/50x62.png" data-src-100x124="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912022/60f28b2ee7e145379d086537b6402131/100x124.png" data-src-200x248="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912022/60f28b2ee7e145379d086537b6402131/200x248.png" data-src-320x397="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912022/60f28b2ee7e145379d086537b6402131/320x397.png" data-src-460x571="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912022/60f28b2ee7e145379d086537b6402131/460x571.png" data-src-640x795="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912022/60f28b2ee7e145379d086537b6402131/640x795.png" data-src-1024x1272="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912022/60f28b2ee7e145379d086537b6402131/1024x1272.png" data-src-1449x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912022/60f28b2ee7e145379d086537b6402131/1449x1800.png" altText="Alex and his bishop" pid="9j5ITA8-Wk649zwTRJ7ZZA" hash="AAAAAA"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p26" pid="TK7o28ZTWEm09yzgEkvjKw" hash="9nq6Wg">Little by little, Alex changed. His faith in the Lord increased. He gained confidence in himself and in the power of the priesthood that he held. The bishop concluded: “Alex has been and will always be one of my greatest blessings in my time as bishop. What a privilege it has been to associate with him. I genuinely believe that no young man has ever gone into the mission field more prepared by his priesthood service.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p27" pid="LuMI4tpanU-jDH4ztRpCpA" hash="eAi6nA">My dear bishops, you have, included in your ordination and setting apart as bishop of your ward, the sacred calling to serve as president of the Aaronic Priesthood and of the priests quorum. I am aware of the heavy burdens you carry, but you should make your duty toward these young men one of your highest priorities. You cannot neglect it or delegate your role in this responsibility to others.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p28" pid="FXNWroUuaEyKjk48GtWD4Q" hash="NWVz9Q">I invite you to reflect upon each of the young Aaronic Priesthood holders in your ward. Not one of them should ever feel left out or useless. Is there a young man whom you and other priesthood brethren could help? Invite him to serve alongside you. Too often we try to entertain our young men and relegate them to a spectator role, when their faith and love for the gospel can be best developed by magnifying their priesthood. By actively participating in the work of salvation, they will be connected with heaven and they will gain awareness of their divine potential.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p29" pid="8NqCj2M4XE2YXrzHF0IxHw" hash="3gndVA">The Aaronic Priesthood is more than just an age group, a teaching or activity program, or even a term to designate the young men of the Church. It is power and authority to participate in the great work of saving souls—both the souls of those young men who hold it and the souls of those they serve. Let us put the Aaronic Priesthood in its rightful place, a choice place—a place of service, preparation, and accomplishment for all the young men of the Church.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way.p30" pid="IGalxW16c0KRNvltVMkx4g" hash="vai5vw">My dear brethren of the Melchizedek Priesthood, I invite you to strengthen the essential link that unites the two priesthoods of God. Empower your Aaronic Priesthood youth to prepare the way before you. Tell them with confidence, “I need you.” To you young holders of the Aaronic Priesthood, I pray that, as you serve with your older brethren, you will hear the voice of the Lord telling you: “Thou art blessed, for thou shalt do great things. Behold thou wast sent forth, even as John, to prepare the way before me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2017/04/prepare-the-way</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2017-general-conference/2017-04-3030-gerald-causse-64k-eng.mp3" length="5869302" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
