<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Gregory A. Schwitzer</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Gregory A. Schwitzer.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Gregory%20A.%20Schwitzer.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Gregory A. Schwitzer.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Developing Good Judgment and Not Judging Others</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Good judgment is needed not only in understanding people but also in facing decisions that often lead us to or away from our Heavenly Father.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021388_000_040" doc-version="2" hash="uhs4Sw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="iXcnagWiB0iQgZll2QDIHw" hash="blsDOw">Developing Good Judgment and Not Judging Others</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Ii-hoSpreEi0J4qIPfwHEA" hash="PNLMAg">Gregory A. Schwitzer</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="RobuooqLSUiKYpjkXUehsA" hash="ZjIimw">Good judgment is needed not only in understanding people but also in facing decisions that often lead us to or away from our Heavenly Father.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p1" pid="8i37dRkaDEaVuwvhqJhk7A" hash="jVGYWg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="103"></span>We live in a world in which many situations require us to make judgments that are often difficult. Yet the Savior gave the commandment to “judge not” our fellowman.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> How can we do this and still exercise good judgment in a world full of deception and corruption? We must judge well when making critical decisions in each phase of our life, such as choosing friends, finding an eternal companion, or choosing an occupation that will allow us to care for our family and serve the Lord. Although the Savior asked us not to judge others, He still expects us to use excellent judgment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p2" pid="vcPYofxyNEeTAU6DUawz4Q" hash="d0lrKg">We may often find ourselves making quick judgments about people, which can change or redefine our relationships with them. Often incorrect judgments are made because of limited information or because we do not see beyond that which is immediately in front of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p3" pid="Tv3JSIgbYkWBmOt9QOUEaw" hash="Qosaog">By way of illustration, the story is often told of the time when Jesus visited the home of Mary and Martha, who lived in Bethany with their brother, Lazarus. It was a welcome place for the Master, where He could rest and enjoy the surroundings of a righteous home. During one of His visits, Martha was busy preparing a meal and Mary elected to sit at the Master’s feet to receive His instruction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p4" pid="j1x8OWLMq0-PFTf0SrLZKA" hash="YIApDA">“But Martha was cumbered about much serving, and came to him, and said, Lord, dost thou not care that my sister hath left me to serve alone? …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p5" pid="STrB8rp6F0uSBdhRWMj6zA" hash="v3fEAg">“And Jesus answered and said unto her, Martha, Martha, thou art careful and troubled about many things:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p6" pid="YckTOonmRE-Zlrnago24gg" hash="XUpWBg">“But one thing is needful: and Mary hath chosen that good part, which shall not be taken away from her.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p7" pid="4evexmH7B0CYzE1AqRHN1Q" hash="4l4qXg">Many Sunday lessons have been taught using this story which have cast Martha in a lesser position in terms of her faith. Yet there is another story of this great woman, Martha, which gives us a deeper view of her understanding and testimony. It happened when the Savior arrived to raise her brother, <span class="pageBreak" page-number="104"></span>Lazarus, from the dead. On this occasion it was Martha whom we find going to Jesus “as soon as she heard” He was coming. As she meets Him, she says that she knows that “whatsoever [He would] ask of God, God [would] give [Him].”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p8" pid="M97a4XqYz0ORvM5yCsMr2g" hash="uCG0gQ">Christ then shared with Martha the great doctrine of the resurrection, saying:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p9" pid="487kHAkHD0mkk3prHONw-Q" hash="iSy8UA">“I am the resurrection, and the life: he that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p10" pid="Ufl_252EN0-j9M3v_ofN9g" hash="-_WwAA">“And whosoever liveth and believeth in me shall never die. Believest thou this?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p11" pid="xPxlI96auk2LQU6V7BxBzA" hash="LGT8Yg">She responded with her powerful testimony: “Yea, Lord: I believe that thou art the Christ, the Son of God, which should come into the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p12" pid="1JWpf0IzaEiVhuaj0qyi5g" hash="S8hR8A">How often has Martha been misjudged as being a person who cared more for the deeds of doing than for the Spirit? However, her testimony in the trial of her brother’s death clearly shows the depth of her understanding and faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p13" pid="HLO1S5Dhukigy7BZ4Zw_BQ" hash="8GQGag">Many a sister has often heard the first story and wondered if she were a Mary or a Martha, yet the truth lies in knowing the whole person and in using good judgment. By knowing more about Martha, we find she was actually a person of deep spiritual character who had a bold and daring testimony of the Savior’s mission and His divine power over life. A misjudgment of Martha may have caused us not to know the true nature of this wonderful woman.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p14" pid="mnRNWw0ClkClMuiDVZjIJg" hash="SMifZw">On a personal level, as a young physician I learned a great lesson about making quick judgments. While I was working a midnight shift in an emergency department, a young man and his wife came in because she was suffering some severe pain. From their dress and hygiene, it was easy to see that theirs had been a rough life. His hair was ill kempt and very long. Their clothing had not been washed for some time, and the effects of a rough life were written on both of their faces.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p15" pid="QyJZ2TOz3kGibbFUOZ1FXA" hash="B922ig">After an examination, I sat down with him to explain the problem and discuss the treatment. This man looked at me with a deep clarity of love that is rarely experienced and asked with all the love of a caring husband, “Doctor, will my dear wife be all right?” At that moment, I felt the Spirit testify that he was a child of God and saw in his eyes the evidence of the Savior. This man truly projected love for another, and I had misjudged him. It was a lesson that left a lasting impression.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p16" pid="kHtfbmZy0kGBG4_BigfuJQ" hash="BfONcA">Good judgment is needed not only in understanding people but also in facing decisions that often lead us to or away from our Heavenly Father. As I look back over my own personal life, I can see many instances in which a slight change of course based on poor judgment would have led me far from where the Lord wanted me to be—decisions like having a family while obtaining an education, being active in all aspects of the gospel, paying tithes and offerings when income was severely limited, and accepting callings at difficult times, which helped me to understand more about sacrifice. Many blessings in life are missed because worldly judgment was applied <span class="pageBreak" page-number="105"></span>to what was really a spiritual decision.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p17" pid="GZKr4J4jcEGIG6dX4loH8w" hash="V2nzMw">There are many characteristics of people who have developed good judgment. I would offer four guides for developing such judgment in making important decisions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p18" pid="6jZVwE-KPUmXQHaMUbQRXQ" hash="Zko5Ag">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">First, put your own personal standards in alignment with the gospel of Jesus Christ.</span>
</span> A person can never be a good judge without the gospel of Jesus Christ as a reference. The gospel has a long and successful record of guiding people to happiness. Some of the world’s ideas leave mankind adrift to try to define their own standards. Because of this, we hear phrases like “a new morality.” This phrase is deceptive! The standards of morality are eternal and have not changed; neither should we try to discover a new interpretation of them. For the youth these standards are written in the pamphlet <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth.</span> These standards are clearly aligned with the gospel of Jesus Christ and are intended to continue through adult life. Perhaps it would be good for us as adults to study and apply this pamphlet to our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p19" pid="iumJu-lBW0SNbG_cM_kxXA" hash="Lba_jw">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">Second, listen to the messages of the living prophet.</span>
</span> How many poor financial judgments would have been avoided had we listened to the years of advice given through our prophets about avoiding risky speculation and following a careful budget to avoid consumer debt? How many marriages would have been saved by using good judgment in avoiding media that lead to pornographic addiction and heartache? Each general conference and Church magazine contains advice from the prophets which, if applied, will lead us to good judgment. We are left without excuse when we ignore them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p20" pid="o0IPeN0jxEiaTopj99FsxA" hash="hTO0tA">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">Third, cultivate with the Holy Spirit a relationship of listening.</span>
</span> We are given the gift of the Holy Ghost after our baptism, but often we leave this gift on the shelf, forgetting that He will help us in the most important judgments of our lives. The Lord gave us this gift, knowing we would face difficult decisions in life. Listening to this voice is vital in developing good judgment. A relationship of listening often requires a quiet environment in which we can take time to ponder and hear the still, small voice. This peaceful environment is both external and internal. Therefore, it is more than shutting off the music of the world or the blare of other media; it is also shutting off the noise of sin that is internal to our soul. This will open the communication with the Spirit, which is so badly needed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p21" pid="7GPnVUMzy0CaKNDb036Iqw" hash="TRUi3g">Christ said: “Peace I leave with you, my peace I give unto you: not as the world giveth, give I unto you. Let not your heart be troubled, neither let it be afraid.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> The peace that comes from listening to the Holy Spirit removes the fear of making a poor judgment in life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p22" pid="BWaiEOKD2E-_jMPxAWg-3A" hash="MqBIgg">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">Fourth, keep the commandments.</span>
</span> The willingness to keep God’s commandments opens to us many promised blessings. The Book of Mormon, in addition to being another testament of Jesus Christ, is a book about the results of keeping and not keeping commandments. The Lord said to Nephi in the second chapter of his first book, “Inasmuch as ye shall keep my commandments, ye shall prosper.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p23" pid="oskakfnsXkyZAygIuxurOA" hash="iUv8Ag">This same promise was repeated by almost every major prophet in the Book of Mormon. A thousand years of history is then recorded which bears witness that these things are true. And the same message applies to us today. Good judgment is best learned and practiced within the bounds the Lord sets by giving us commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others.p24" pid="S_O_W1-oREedZbuF_CAiig" hash="A6NukQ">I testify that when we face difficult decisions and follow these guidelines, we can know better how we should judge. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/04/developing-good-judgment-and-not-judging-others</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2010-general-conference/2010-04-5050-elder-gregory-a-schwitzer-64k-eng.mp3" length="5066622" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let the Clarion Trumpet Sound</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Gregory A. Schwitzer encourages Latter-day Saints to testify boldly and clearly in defense of Jesus Christ’s Church and doctrine.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13768_000_55schwitzer" doc-version="2" hash="sUL5Rg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="N-wEL78dE0W8LfZzWuZivw" hash="GJpoWQ">Let the Clarion Trumpet Sound</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p2" pid="rpXPMIZYl0S2VZuC6fG3_g" hash="8zSreA">By Elder Gregory A. Schwitzer</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p3" pid="Ni-zJjWxbEC79B-H5jqgAQ" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=0j7rpTmYxE2pWTt8PQ1v8A"><img xmlns="" alt="Elder Gregory A. Schwitzer" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255577/91ff1cc065574ce785c6923c52a501a1/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255577/91ff1cc065574ce785c6923c52a501a1/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255577/91ff1cc065574ce785c6923c52a501a1/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x279="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255577/91ff1cc065574ce785c6923c52a501a1/200x279.jpg" data-src-320x447="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255577/91ff1cc065574ce785c6923c52a501a1/320x447.jpg" data-src-460x643="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255577/91ff1cc065574ce785c6923c52a501a1/460x643.jpg" data-src-640x894="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255577/91ff1cc065574ce785c6923c52a501a1/640x894.jpg" data-src-1024x1431="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255577/91ff1cc065574ce785c6923c52a501a1/1024x1431.jpg" data-src-2048x2863="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255577/91ff1cc065574ce785c6923c52a501a1/2048x2863.jpg" data-src-3532x4938="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255577/91ff1cc065574ce785c6923c52a501a1/3532x4938.jpg" pid="0j7rpTmYxE2pWTt8PQ1v8A" hash="qHtXHQ"></img></a></div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="iHvo3T7r80azCD_JJzp8LQ" hash="DEuBTQ">The world needs disciples of Christ who can communicate the gospel message with clarity and from the heart.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="sYv3huT0mES5saMwYj6-7A" hash="PNLMAg">Gregory A. Schwitzer</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p5" pid="E-yfUbU0Lk2vpUB4SQP0zQ" hash="wfst9g">This past summer my wife and I had two of our young grandsons staying with us while their parents participated in a pioneer trek activity in their stake. Our daughter wanted to be sure that the boys practiced the piano while away from home. She knew that a few days with the grandparents makes it a little easier to forget about practicing. One afternoon I decided to sit with my 13-year-old grandson, Andrew, and listen to him play.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p6" pid="3g4sI07fokqNMQU1wQov5Q" hash="-0jULA">This boy is full of energy and loves the outdoors. He could easily spend all of his time hunting and fishing. While he was practicing the piano, I could tell that he would rather be fishing on a nearby river. I listened as he pounded out each chord of a familiar song. Every note he played had the same emphasis and meter, making it difficult to clearly identify the melody. I sat beside him on the bench and explained the importance of applying just a little more pressure on the melody keys and a little less on those notes that accompany the melody. We talked about the piano being more than just a mechanical miracle. It can be an extension of his own voice and feelings and become a wonderful instrument of communication. Just as a person talks and moves smoothly from one word to another, so should the melody flow as we move from one note to another.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p7" pid="-Qo1WZ6gFkSgfmhoXf0xfg" hash="9Tpycw">We laughed together as he tried again and again. His dimpled-cheek smile increased as the familiar melody began to emerge from what was previously a wild set of sounds. The message became clear: “I am a child of God, and he has sent me here.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> I asked Andrew if he could feel the difference in the message. He responded, “Yes, Grandpa, I can feel it!”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p8" pid="M1rII0Pg70KPZUmF22_laQ" hash="mdWc6w">The Apostle Paul taught us about comparing communication to musical instruments when he wrote to the Corinthians:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p9" pid="TlvByu7m10if258QHYli7A" hash="EEtlvg">“And even things without life giving sound, whether pipe or harp, except they give a distinction in the sounds, how shall it be known what is piped or harped?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p10" pid="DyNbJZv3JEKPTHqNmhy4IQ" hash="TJvQuw">“For if the trumpet give an uncertain sound, who shall prepare himself to the battle?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p11" pid="NvMWZ9FlI0aSPZnTyVixTA" hash="m-8sLw">If ever there was a time when the world needs disciples of Christ who can communicate the message of the gospel with clarity and from the heart, it is now. We need the clarion call of the trumpet.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p12" pid="gNTdPZ-f_UaP6nFdpSD2iw" hash="jHtS2w">Christ was certainly our best example. He always demonstrated courage to stand up for what was right. His words echo through the centuries as He invites us to remember to love God and our fellowman, to keep all of God’s commandments, and to live as lights to the world. He was not afraid to speak against the earthly powers or rulers of His day, even when such were opposing His mission given to Him by His Heavenly Father. His words were not designed to confuse but to move the hearts of men. He clearly knew His Father’s will in all He said and did.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p13" pid="Wh1Uc00-X0SaIw0UluGXNQ" hash="yNu7yw">I also love the example of Peter, who confronted the men of the world with courage and clarity on the day of Pentecost. On that day people were assembled from many countries criticizing the early Saints because they heard them speak in tongues and thought they were drunken. Peter, having the Spirit rise in his soul, stood up to defend the Church and the members. He testified with these words: “Ye men of Judea, and all ye that dwell at Jerusalem, be this known unto you, and hearken to my words.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p14" pid="g1FsRzy6hUm7zLX_aPLulg" hash="ye9JRg">He then quoted from the scriptures containing the prophecies of Christ and bore this straightforward testimony: “Therefore let all the house of Israel know assuredly, that God hath made that same Jesus, whom ye have crucified, both Lord and Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p15" pid="KNuywytf3kClG-gG2wxQpQ" hash="qdof-w">Many heard his words and felt the Spirit, and 3,000 souls joined the ranks of the early Church. This is powerful evidence that one man or woman who is willing to testify when the world seems to be going in the opposite direction can make a difference.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p16" pid="Isx4cIgeM06AmLrj4jAJMg" hash="zga3EA">When we as members make the decision to stand up and powerfully witness for God’s doctrine and His Church, something changes within us. We take His countenance upon us. We become closer to His Spirit. He in turn will go before us and be on “[our] right hand and on [our] left, and [His] Spirit shall be in [our] hearts, and [His] angels round about [us], to bear [us] up.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p17" pid="2lVsyK6BCkG0ZMyxtM2IxA" hash="_iRheA">True disciples of Christ are not looking to make excuses for the doctrine when it doesn’t fit the world’s current concepts. Paul was another valiant disciple, boldly proclaiming that he was “not ashamed of the gospel of Christ: for it is the power of God unto salvation to every one that believeth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> True disciples represent the Lord when it may not be convenient to do so. True disciples desire to inspire the hearts of men, not just impress them.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p18" pid="bD-xY_SsWkSM6bnAsao34w" hash="NykwYA">Often it is not convenient or comfortable to stand up for Christ. I am sure that was the case with Paul when he was called before King Agrippa and was asked to justify himself and tell his story. Paul, without hesitating, proclaimed his belief with such power that this intimidating king admitted he was “almost” persuaded to be a Christian.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p19" pid="pmVHrDp_KkeMis44hYCd-A" hash="qmilDQ">Paul’s response witnessed of his desire for people to understand <span class="emphasis">absolutely</span> what he had to say. He told King Agrippa that it was his desire that all who heard him would not “almost” be Christians but rather would “altogether” become disciples of Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> Those who speak with clarity can bring this to pass.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p20" pid="ygEEqy_X2kappliJ71ajNw" hash="It6VgQ">Over the many years that I have studied the story of Lehi’s dream in the Book of Mormon,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> I have always thought of the great and spacious building as a place where only the most rebellious reside. The building was filled with people mocking and pointing at the faithful who had held on to the iron rod, which represents the word of God, and had made their way to the tree of life, which represents the love of God. Some could not bear up under the pressure of the people mocking them and wandered off. Others decided to join the mockers in the building. Did they not have the courage to speak boldly against the criticisms or messages of the world?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p21" pid="uoLA43p3l0a_Tzv4wsHJ0A" hash="_dHhxw">As I watch the current world moving away from God, I think this building is growing in size. Many find themselves today wandering the halls of the great and spacious building, not realizing that they are actually becoming part of its culture. They often succumb to the temptations and the messages. We eventually find them mocking or chiming in with those who criticize or mock.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p22" pid="76XoL8dB0E2ZOnh0cKdLug" hash="_XGdIg">For years I thought the mocking crowd was making fun of the way the faithful live their lives, but the voices from the building today have changed their tone and approach. Those who mock often try to drown out the simple message of the gospel by attacking some aspect of the Church’s history or offering pointed criticism of a prophet or other leader. They are also attacking the very heart of our doctrine and the laws of God, given since the Creation of the earth. We, as disciples of Jesus Christ and members of His Church, must never let go of that iron rod. We must let the clarion trumpet sound from our own souls.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p23" pid="4XV6gZdYrkai6VjWxlFLTg" hash="m_5x-Q">The simple message is that God is our loving Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ is His Son. The gospel is restored in these latter days through living prophets, and the evidence is the Book of Mormon. The path of happiness is through the basic family unit as originally organized and revealed by our Heavenly Father. This is the familiar melody of the message that many can recognize because they have heard it from their premortal life.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound.p24" pid="uq0UXAenSkuavgeAWgCe0A" hash="aBhpnQ">It is time for us, as Latter-day Saints, to stand up and testify. It is time for the notes of the melody of the gospel to rise above the noise of the world. I add my testimony to the message of the Savior and Redeemer of this world. He lives! His gospel is restored, and the blessings of happiness and peace can be secured in this life by living His commandments and walking in His path. This is my testimony in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/10/let-the-clarion-trumpet-sound</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2015-general-conference/2015-10-4060-elder-gregory-a-schwitzer-64k-eng.mp3" length="4775574" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
