<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By H. David Burton</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by H. David Burton.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/H.%20David%20Burton.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by H. David Burton.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1993 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1993 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Heroes</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1993/04/heroes?lang=eng</link>
      <description>One of my heroes, Nephi, often used the phrase “My soul delighteth.” Tonight my soul delighteth to be part of the many thousands who have gathered to learn more about our priesthood responsibilities.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_93905_000_022" doc-version="2" hash="cK1vKg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="DvFkVzsGOE6sTrnXvzzKEg" hash="Ka1o4A">Heroes</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="bJ2-Vptv1Eu7IxukSRqcPw" hash="XulAoA">H. David Burton</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1dba.jpg" alt="Bishop H. David Burton" pid="gtuPhjD1EEeSDvfmoCBQYw" hash="PD71Fw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p1" pid="npyNdkwgOkGas-89Va6WPQ" hash="vaQgKg">One of my heroes, Nephi, often used the phrase “My soul delighteth.” Tonight my soul delighteth to be part of the many thousands who have gathered to learn more about our priesthood responsibilities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p2" pid="t__Nq0FwCkCUBKa2A7aVvg" hash="3W3Psw">Next Monday the w    ords “Play ball!” will ring out in major league baseball parks throughout the United States and Canada. I am saddened because one of my heroes, pitcher Lynn Nolan Ryan, Jr., recently announced this baseball season would be his last.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p3" pid="jj4sxVYZkUuwqyFcpvw86Q" hash="ANpamQ">Nolan will likely be elected to the Baseball Hall of Fame the first year he is eligible. He will be remembered for his record twenty-seven major league seasons. His 95-mile-an-hour fastball is legendary; 5,600-plus strikeouts is a record that will stand for a very, very long time. Nolan Ryan is not only a great baseball pitcher, he is a wonderful, sensitive human being.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p4" pid="YO4EYnGi40SXMB4WtQETxA" hash="BelsLw">A successful baseball pitcher is able to hurl the ball with velocity and accuracy. <span class="emphasis">His</span> pitches are disguised in order to deceive the batter. A pitcher, by changing his grip on the ball or the way he releases it from his hand, makes the ball curve, slide, drop, wobble, or slow down as it approaches the batter. In baseball, good pitchers, like Nolan Ryan, are masters at deceiving batters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p5" pid="vHSXNQxII0qnB9lRzwA9pA" hash="mgh6yQ">In life, he who is the greatest deceiver of all has tremendous influence. He has many names but is best known as Satan, or the devil. And he knows that “ye are a chosen generation, a royal priesthood.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-pet/2.9" class="scriptureRef">1 Pet. 2:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p6" pid="wt6WCxk4FUWU5ZvLn6QZiQ" hash="u8FLxQ">Make no mistake about it, my young brethren, Satan is the commander in chief of deception. He is not satisfied with just taking prisoners; he wants the souls of men. One of his insidious strategies is to progressively soften our senses regarding what is right and wrong. Satan would have us convinced it is fashionable to lie and cheat. He encourages us to view pornography by suggesting that it prepares us for the real world. He would have us believe immorality is an attractive way of life and that obedience to the commandments of our Father in Heaven is old-fashioned. Satan constantly bombards us with deceptive propaganda desirably packaged and carefully disguised. Satan creates false heroes which, if emulated, will lead us to the depths of sin.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p7" pid="O8hsbqYnlUi0gU_AqodFhQ" hash="r2uYGA">On the other hand, carefully selected heroes can give us a pattern for our lives and serve as our role models. They can give us courage to walk the road of life righteously. I have several heroes other than Nephi and Nolan Ryan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p8" pid="et8U8tNlcUmInd6sKfhuMA" hash="5Kdomg">One evening I was working late in the Church Office Building. When I called for an elevator to go home, my mind was preoccupied. In my absentmindedness, I began to enter the elevator when a hand shot out to shake my hand and a voice firmly said, “I’m Spencer Kimball. Who might you be?” In my surprise, I could not remember who I was. There stood one of my heroes; I finally mumbled something vaguely resembling my name. When I think of President Kimball, I think of <span class="emphasis">The Miracle of Forgiveness,</span> I think of lengthening our stride, “do it now,” the priesthood for all worthy males, and, most of all, conquering adversity. He will always be one of my heroes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p9" pid="cHlEnMxcDEOutIhOH8JQFA" hash="C8hv5g">Alma, the high priest of the church of God, unsuccessfully attempted to preach repentance to his Nephite brethren in the city of Ammonihah. He left that city very, very discouraged. An angel appeared to him and said, “Behold, I am sent to command thee that thou return to the city of Ammonihah, and preach again unto the people of the city; yea, preach unto them. Yea, say unto them, except they repent the Lord God will destroy them.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/8.16" class="scriptureRef">Alma 8:16</a>.) Alma returned as commanded.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p10" pid="PU8pfDnkmkulYj354kVKBg" hash="0WDHkQ">Amulek lived in that city of Ammonihah. He told of this experience: “As I was journeying to see a very near kindred, behold an angel of the Lord appeared unto me and said: Amulek, return to thine own house, for thou shalt feed a prophet of the Lord; yea, a holy man, who is a chosen man of God; for he has fasted many days because of the sins of this people, and he is an hungered, and thou shalt receive him into thy house and feed him, and he shall bless thee and thy house.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/10.7" class="scriptureRef">Alma 10:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p11" pid="DWgYD4tdxEywm8jFfjUy5w" hash="OAwpYA">Amulek returned and took Alma into his house to eat and to rest. Amulek was called to be Alma’s missionary companion. On one occasion they were bound, beaten, and thrown into prison for preaching repentance. In response to their pleas, the Lord caused the walls of the prison to fall, killing those who had imprisoned them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p12" pid="wRfb9AEPbUeIuDEuyDJZsQ" hash="o8z0mw">Alma and Amulek listened to the angel. They responded to the call to missionary service, and they preached repentance. They stood tall in the face of adversity and imprisonment. They are heroes whose lives are worthy of emulation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p13" pid="SSiOG7zBBkmY6iUUljrksQ" hash="ucAY8Q">Through the years, each of my bishops has been a hero to me. Our current bishop, Bishop Stephen G. Stoker, is a hero to our family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p14" pid="2Mb6rrfcvkyyfx64ainHpQ" hash="t3JQJg">I am grateful to bishops who helped me as a young man prepare to receive the Melchizedek Priesthood. One patient, loving bishop helped me understand that missionary service was far more important than perfecting my golf game, which had been the chief ambition of my teen years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p15" pid="Ub3-G4M3nUSj0Lkt1_bIKQ" hash="yy9HEA">Today I enjoy playing golf with my sons and sons-in-law. When the boys are playing well, they extend a challenge. With nimble bodies, they hit the ball much farther than I. Because they haven’t yet mastered the notion that the shortest distance between two points is a straight line, I remain competitive. In their eagerness to hit the ball hard, they often drive it off the fairway or out of bounds.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p16" pid="9usKM2_R_0mZoZdT7Qzq-g" hash="-s5fjQ">Young men, place your faith and trust in your bishop. Let him help you live close to the straight line of righteousness and stay within the bounds our Father in Heaven has set. If you have strayed from that straight line, let your bishop help you change your course before the deceptive practices of Satan have you firmly in their grasp. I hope the Lord has reserved a special place in the eternities for good bishops.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p17" pid="M_fp5LuPvUCtIS9cw9SAow" hash="qcTPJA">Heavenly Father knew that <span class="emphasis">this</span> strong-willed son needed a good father. He picked out a great one for me. My dad’s devotion to his children and grandchildren consumed much of his time. He loved the Lord and was about the Lord’s errand throughout his days. He was not only my dad; he was one of my heroes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p18" pid="iFrPKE_Ma0e2Nav9Funu9g" hash="cM_xAQ">Dad was the president of my priests quorum and bishop of our ward during my teenage years. You who have been a bishop’s son know that sometimes performance expectations tend to be a little high for bishops’ sons.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p19" pid="vx5k1DXCn0aSSjPP234hjw" hash="daz1fg">During Dad’s tenure as bishop, a new meetinghouse was built in our area. Local financial shares were partially fulfilled by providing labor. Often I arrived home to find a note on the kitchen table inviting me to join Dad in working on the new building. These invitations were not always received with great warmth and enthusiasm. It seemed to me that the bishop’s son received more than his fair share of invitations to work on the new meetinghouse.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p20" pid="-iM4bWxm8kiWdt-p_SAzzw" hash="UaqxTA">As the building neared completion, landscaping commenced. The priesthood brethren were extended a work opportunity in hauling fertilizer to the site. Because the bishop was a part of the expedition, the bishop’s son felt an obligation to respond. We drove to a mountain sheep corral. Into a large truck we shoveled very finely ground, dry, sheep fertilizer. The wind blew much of what we threw back to us. This unsavory material gathered in our eyes, throats, noses, ears, and down our backs. I can’t ever remember being more uncomfortable. I’m afraid I verbalized my feelings with emotion. When we arrived back at the meetinghouse to unload the material, I found my new bike had been <span class="emphasis">stolen.</span> My complaining was loud. Why would the Lord permit someone to steal my bike when I was about His work?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p21" pid="u38HTl-CiEyadI6PpBtVWQ" hash="buhUwQ">When Dad and I arrived home, we showered and sat down to an evening meal. My complaining about the day and my lost bike continued. As we knelt in prayer, Dad thanked Heavenly Father for the opportunity of the day’s service and expressed love for me. He asked forgiveness for the person who had taken the bike. He noted his sorrow for the loss but expressed gratitude that it wasn’t his son who had committed the theft. Dads make great heroes. I pray that if you are fortunate enough to have a father close by, he can be your hero. Dads, live in such a way that your sons and others can look up to you as heroes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p22" pid="c0FFw46veEu8r--Fih9q0w" hash="kj0ihA">Exceptional baseball batters have the gift of superb eyesight as well as exceptional eye-to-hand coordination. They can even see the strings on the baseball and detect the direction the ball is rotating. The batter can then better attempt to respond to the deception of the pitcher. Our Heavenly Father has given each of us such a gift to help identify and withstand the deception of Satan. It is the gift of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p23" pid="DCEe8cbuA0aTFmYa_XBx8A" hash="aDAN2A">I pray that you proud bearers of the Aaronic Priesthood will listen and respond to the promptings of the Holy Ghost and bond with righteous heroes in standing tall against the evils espoused by the master of deception.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/heroes.p24" pid="zIQRbLsgTUuMMzhvm30O8w" hash="O3OmOA">I know that our Father in Heaven lives and that His Son is our Savior and Redeemer. I know they love us and want us to be successful. Of this I bear testimony in His holy name, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1993/04/heroes</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1993-general-conference/1993-04-3040-bishop-h-david-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5906316" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1993 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Courage to Hearken</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I know that Bishop Edgley joins me this day in expressing our appreciation for the many years of service we have had with Elder Hales. We deeply love and appreciate him, and we feel like we’ve been taught at his feet for a number of years. We look fo</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_94905_000_028" doc-version="2" hash="3ViT7w">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="NPGn8Ty-mUmyItfT2I-qCA" hash="ZtxiBw">Courage to Hearken</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="2QK1S0mAmEGtbwx8M8WGKQ" hash="XulAoA">H. David Burton</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1dba.jpg" alt="Bishop H. David Burton" pid="VF6MgjnpCEutZsN2LHKn-Q" hash="PD71Fw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p1" pid="DJhTQ_4CfU-vw2KFN1eZfQ" hash="x_bG3A">I know that Bishop Edgley joins me this day in expressing our appreciation for the many years of service we have had with Elder Hales. We deeply love and appreciate him, and we feel like we’ve been taught at his feet for a number of years. We look forward to laboring in service with Bishop Bateman.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p2" pid="DynJQvyFEUO-MgmkN2H_vw" hash="2sE7Rw">I was thrilled this morning, as I’m sure all of you were, to see and to hear President Hunter, a loving and gentle Apostle of the Lord Jesus Christ who is an exceptional example of one who repeatedly displays extraordinary <span class="emphasis">courage</span> in <span class="emphasis">hearkening</span> to the will of his Father in Heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p3" pid="lCwkoNiQNkS_7fDD79Wj8A" hash="f_FK2A">President Hunter has sons who served their missions in Australia at the same time I served there. During this time, President Hunter received his call to the holy apostleship. Numerous of these missionaries have regarded him as “our Apostle.” He is one of my heroes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p4" pid="5utndGnDwke6jd4iDK37bQ" hash="3DdbvQ">On this Sabbath day, a Sunday set aside to celebrate Easter, Christians should remember, with thanksgiving, the events surrounding the most momentous Sunday the world has ever known—the Sunday the Savior burst his three-day prison, completing victory over death. Descriptions of these events are vividly etched in my heart and mind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p5" pid="S11g1FHszUenpNcORauBBA" hash="8EBqjA">I can envision Jesus bearing the heavy crossbeam as the procession winds its way along the narrow streets of Jerusalem, through the massive wall at the city gate, to a place called Golgotha. I can hear women weeping and Jesus offering words of warning: “Daughters of Jerusalem, weep not for me, but weep for yourselves, and for your children” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/23.28" class="scriptureRef">Luke 23:28</a>). The Savior knew destructive events would shortly come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p6" pid="xNOsj2nZC0ays_1X0_4v3g" hash="v3-SAg">In my mind’s eye I can see the executioners going about their abhorrent, heartless tasks. I can hear the Savior, in the spirit of compassion, appealing for his crucifiers as he uttered, “Father, forgive them; for they know not what they do” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/23.34" class="scriptureRef">Luke 23:34</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p7" pid="Aa8IaXs7AE-EtGu2hzi5XA" hash="qKEKJw">As this brutal incident proceeded, one of the thieves also suffering crucifixion discerned something divine in the Savior’s demeanor and said to Jesus, “Lord, remember me when thou comest into thy kingdom.” Jesus responded with a promise only he could make: “Verily I say unto thee, To day shalt thou be with me in paradise” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/23.42-43" class="scriptureRef">Luke 23:42–43</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p8" pid="4HFiaenmMUaXVcKbgxHBwA" hash="GaZt_Q">Picture in your minds a weeping mother and a devoted disciple invited past the centurion to the foot of the cross. Jesus, in his agony, looked down upon them and said to Mary, with an economy of words, “Woman, behold thy son!” and, looking steadily at John, said, “Behold thy mother!” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/19.26-27" class="scriptureRef">John 19:26–27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p9" pid="tueUHnXCpEa17MSZh_sM4w" hash="-baizQ">Who can forget the pleading voice calling out at about the ninth hour through the oppressive darkness that gripped the land, “My God, my God, why hast thou forsaken me?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/15.34" class="scriptureRef">Mark 15:34</a>.) The Father seemingly withdrew, allowing the Savior of mankind to complete his victory over death and sin.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p10" pid="dLIKlYFwYE6QV85QA5AB-w" hash="NjMAOw">I can imagine the bitter taste of the vinegar that was pressed to his lips when he said, “I thirst” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/19.28" class="scriptureRef">John 19:28</a>), his one recorded response to physical suffering.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p11" pid="UL8ieT2JBEG86nVBQ-dkNg" hash="xWxXiw">When the atoning sacrifice had been accepted, Jesus declared in a loud voice, “It is finished” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/19.30" class="scriptureRef">John 19:30</a>). And then in final petition he said, “Father, into thy hands I commend my spirit” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/23.46" class="scriptureRef">Luke 23:46</a>). His body sagged on the cross; Jesus gave up his life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p12" pid="eJdV4cv7C0urkSln6dOmXw" hash="y7VQoQ">In the early morning darkness of the third day, Sunday, the first Easter, the earth began to quake. An angel rolled away the stone blocking the tomb and announced: “Fear not ye: for I know that ye seek Jesus, which was crucified.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p13" pid="R6w0IUxHY0OHC9x0dGAfcg" hash="h3YyCg">“He is not here: for he is risen, as he said” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/28.2,5-6" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 28:2, 5–6</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p14" pid="-WHFzNy5EkmppdpWEHE6nA" hash="y2tRlw">Later in the morning, the grieving Mary Magdalene returned to the cold, dreary, empty tomb. She heard a familiar voice call, “Mary.” Turning, she saw the Lord and reached out to him. In a worshipful greeting, she lovingly declared, “Rabboni.” Jesus responded, “Touch me not; for I am not yet ascended to my Father: but go to my brethren, and say unto them, I ascend unto my Father, and your Father; and to my God, and your God” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/20.16-17" class="scriptureRef">John 20:16–17</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p15" pid="uQhSF_D0iUiiRr-2y_BgIQ" hash="-TcgYQ">During the following forty days, the Savior frequently taught and ate with his Apostles. He concluded with the glorious charge: “Go ye therefore, and teach all nations, … teaching them to observe all things whatsoever I have commanded you: and, lo, I am with you alway, even unto the end of the world. Amen” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/28.19-20" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 28:19–20</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p16" pid="iWDJ8afB1UGUs2C-evMFqw" hash="jeMhzA">Jesus Christ is <span class="emphasis">the</span> magnificent example of courage in hearkening to the will of the Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p17" pid="Y0Go-WnAGk-noHrDa1KvYw" hash="uBY2KQ">The wise Psalmist said, “Be of good <span class="emphasis">courage,</span> and he shall strengthen your heart, all ye that hope in the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/31.24" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 31:24</a>; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p18" pid="927Tz4IcwkCkxTLAbsEnOA" hash="NCsASw">President Thomas S. Monson explained <span class="emphasis">courage</span> by saying, “Courage becomes a living and attractive virtue when it is regarded not as a willingness to die manfully, but the determination to live decently” (in Conference Report, Apr. 1972, p. 72).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p19" pid="BZdtNUuV6kObQho1jATLhg" hash="KDTTuw">In latter-day scriptures, the Lord often uses action words in the first sentences of his revelations. Interestingly, <span class="emphasis">hearken</span> is used a number of times in this fashion. We are counseled by the Lord, through the Prophet Joseph Smith, to <span class="emphasis">behold,</span> to <span class="emphasis">hearken,</span> to <span class="emphasis">listen,</span> to <span class="emphasis">hear,</span> in over sixty revelations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p20" pid="B4avCfRAeEuSGJljjzwkbQ" hash="bT6iwg">May I tell you about a young man who had the <span class="emphasis">courage to hearken.</span> Elder Marion D. Hanks introduced us to Jay nearly twenty years ago at general conference. Elder Hanks described a twelve-year-old deacon whose body suffered from muscular atrophy. His loving father carried him as he passed the sacrament, gathered fast offerings, and went about his Scouting activities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p21" pid="6a0udtlCGkW96ZUS6EdbPQ" hash="_UoNBw">The remainder of Jay’s story exemplifies inspiration and <span class="emphasis">courage.</span> His body continued to suffer the ravages of his disease while his mind continued to be inquisitive and very bright. Because of his disease, Jay was unable to attend high school but rather had home study. He loved seminary and attended regularly. He was one of the speakers at his seminary graduation, addressing his classmates from his wheelchair. Jay’s positive approach to life and his cheery, radiant disposition were uplifting. Jay loved to attend dances. He made his wheelchair dance. He enjoyed music and often sang the hymns of the Restoration in beautiful, clear, melodic tones.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p22" pid="RFmO35JZT0GZe4a1IndUCQ" hash="xcQABw">More than anything, Jay loved the Lord. When he turned nineteen, he wanted to <span class="emphasis">hearken</span> to the prophet’s request that every young man serve a mission. By this time, Jay spent much of his time on a soft mat on the living room floor of his home. Much of the muscle tissue of his body had wasted away. He desperately wanted to serve a mission. He found a way to serve in spite of his handicap. While lying on his back on the floor, he painstakingly prepared, with the help of some friends, over 150 copies of the Book of Mormon with his picture and testimony. They were sent to friends serving missions around the world for distribution. Jay received a letter from President Kimball expressing gratitude for his service and <span class="emphasis">courage</span> in <span class="emphasis">hearkening</span> to the call to missionary service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p23" pid="7OiKtXj4x0C7GXieHzkUHQ" hash="Hsz15A">Thanks to “angel” parents, Jay attended college. He was pushed by his dad from class to class. At times it was necessary for him to lie on a table at the rear of the classroom. He was an excellent student, receiving distinguished grades in difficult courses. Jay passed away three years ago, but his splendid example of one who <span class="emphasis">courageously hearkened</span> lives on.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p24" pid="2G7ap7HzlUGYn75BVCBRBA" hash="o6KIqQ">Someone once said that the <span class="emphasis">courageous</span> man finds a way, and the ordinary man finds an excuse. Recently I learned of some <span class="emphasis">courageous</span> young people who <span class="emphasis">hearkened</span> to the counsel of their stake presidency.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p25" pid="PXVg9Zq8GUyFle8TXx5FBA" hash="ZN2WIA">In the Boise Idaho North Stake, a loving stake presidency helped their youth have a better understanding of the pitfalls of being continually bombarded by the degrading lyrics of many of today’s popular songs and the indecent images portrayed in some movies and videos. They were taught that these mediums can produce much that is positive, inspiring, uplifting, and attractive; or they can also desensitize the mind and make what is wrong and evil look normal, exciting, and acceptable.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p26" pid="bzVrhq5P50aC2A398HrBIg" hash="ieV04A">Many of the young people hearkened to their stake presidency and courageously destroyed their tapes, discs, and videos which were not “virtuous, lovely, or of good report or praiseworthy” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/a-of-f/1.13" class="scriptureRef">A of F 1:13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p27" pid="_OPCYqQJ1UmAdq1PqVpFVg" hash="tXt9xg">Young people, please don’t listen to music that contains ideas that contradict principles of the gospel. “Don’t listen to music that promotes Satanism or other evil practices, encourages immorality, uses foul and offensive language, or drives away the Spirit” (<span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth,</span> Salt Lake City: The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, 1990, p. 14).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p28" pid="G1U7SDcRYEO1jCXnVApurw" hash="lfIxeA">Some may feel they are too intelligent or sophisticated to be influenced by the craftiness of Satan. What a tragic miscalculation. Nephi warned us of the perils of this misjudgment when he said: “O that cunning plan of the evil one! O the vainness, and the frailties, and the foolishness of men! When they are learned they think they are wise, and they <span class="emphasis">hearken</span> not unto the counsel of God. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p29" pid="ShtmMteapUOIeCHUOr_fnA" hash="yBA3oQ">“But to be learned is good if they <span class="emphasis">hearken</span> unto the counsels of God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/9.28-29" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 9:28–29</a>; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p30" pid="GpIqSu8jrEiQ7RmQ0v4cpg" hash="izffgA">President Hinckley said: “One of the great tragedies we witness almost daily is the tragedy of men of high aim and low achievement. Their motives are noble. Their proclaimed ambition is praiseworthy. Their capacity is great. But their discipline is weak. They succumb to indolence. Appetite robs them of will” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1979, p. 65).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p31" pid="dlQ2aho4qkeFIsZ0tDqqxg" hash="rKI5mg">Perhaps the greatest obstacle to our ability to <span class="emphasis">hearken courageously</span> to the word of the Lord involves our egos, vain ambitions, and pride. It seems that the proud find it burdensome to hear and accept the instruction of God. We are told in Proverbs that “pride goeth before destruction” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/16.18" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 16:18</a>). The proud are more anxious about man’s judgment than they are of God’s judgment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p32" pid="Q81Yj2ZgQEeDZvzOahmq-w" hash="d7aCaQ">You may remember a story about a ship’s captain who had a problem with his pride. One night at sea, this captain saw what looked like the light of another ship heading toward him. He had his signalman blink to the other ship: “Change your course 10 degrees south.” The reply came back, “Change <span class="emphasis">your</span> course 10 degrees north.” The ship’s captain answered: “I am a <span class="emphasis">captain.</span> Change <span class="emphasis">your</span> course south.” To which the reply came, “Well, I am a seaman first class. Change <span class="emphasis">your</span> course north.” This so infuriated the captain, he signaled back, “I say change <span class="emphasis">your</span> course south. I am on a battleship!” To which the reply came back, “And I say change <span class="emphasis">your</span> course north. I am in a lighthouse” (adapted and used with permission, HOPE Publications, Kalamazoo, Michigan).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p33" pid="lIfA6vFJhU2VqErcbSxvgA" hash="HUyj2w">Like the captain, if we fail to modify our course and purge ourselves of pride, we may find ourselves shipwrecked upon the shoals of life, unable to <span class="emphasis">courageously hearken</span> to the beckonings of the Savior to “come unto me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/11.28" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 11:28</a>). I like what Edgar A. Guest said in a few lines of his poem entitled “Equipment”:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="6pTa_GDaj0OjHm16TZYO7Q" hash="uTBC6g">
            <span class="emphasis">Two arms, two hands, two legs, two eyes,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="MpFp5PLftUyXw3ZQlxsptQ" hash="pJo2Ow">
            <span class="emphasis">And a brain to use if you would be wise.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="eZrjX_CcYUKx5wjSoTHO6A" hash="WWuahA">
            <span class="emphasis">With this equipment they all began,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="V9a8VzvTR0OZPwqoFNE4fg" hash="nyYP8A">
            <span class="emphasis">So start for the top and say, “I can.” …</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="Pow3IJ1TvEOA2ug3vH-NNQ" hash="Cuvgvw">
            <span class="emphasis">You are the handicap you must face,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="FJnL4N1NvEKc7OcDD0qP0w" hash="1JmVSg">
            <span class="emphasis">You are the one who must choose your place,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="J7OX6qiNrUiUc-KKDtDA_A" hash="NshCEQ">
            <span class="emphasis">You must say where you want to go,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="FsVYqesx7UyY-12S9fidEQ" hash="1wzbNw">
            <span class="emphasis">How much you will study the truth to know.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="7Z5YMkrbbkyt1NJLAJpWNA" hash="AcOxYA">
            <span class="emphasis">God has equipped you for life, but He</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Krsm3LYNB0q9FHlJxPpDPw" hash="3NgCVQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Lets you decide what you want to be. …</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="8RP2qfu-ZUKXSIdg6xEW-g" hash="QV9tOg">Courage<span class="emphasis"> must come from the soul within,</span></p>
          <p class="line" pid="Ln3foN3s0kCPk-P_08m6ag" hash="mX5xPg">
            <span class="emphasis">The man must furnish the will to win.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="nNaBU7Q2VkiRfWzatV1q3w" hash="_j9wdA">
            <span class="emphasis">So figure it out for yourself, my lad,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="ZUJDPwlMGk-znsiurOwl3g" hash="zxzdTg">
            <span class="emphasis">You were born with all that the great have had,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="4CmdWM_Uok6FKYppL3RqJw" hash="7t1MtA">
            <span class="emphasis">With your equipment they all began.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="OXmbp_nqD0qtNuSgAQQZag" hash="TiIYjw">Get hold of yourself, and say: “I can.”</p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken.p34" pid="wCWkKxtHsUK1W1BhYQeLhA" hash="NMkrxA">May we all “get hold of [ourselves],” as Edgar Guest so beautifully suggests; and say, “I can be courageous in hearkening to the invitation of the Lord.” “Live in such a way that people who know you but don’t know Christ will want to know Christ because they know you” (author unknown). In the holy name of him for whose glorious resurrection and atoning sacrifice I express my deepest appreciation this Easter Sunday—even Jesus Christ—amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1994/04/courage-to-hearken</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1994-general-conference/1994-04-4040-bishop-h-david-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="6823290" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 1994 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“I Will Go”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Brethren, I am honored and humbled to share this historic podium with others of the General Authorities, particularly the fifteen prophets, seers, and revelators seated behind me, whom I love and revere. I bear witness that these mighty men of God, t</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95911_000_020" doc-version="2" hash="E_Hz5A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="hqjOqes1xU2-txvs37M_YA" hash="9FQRTw">“I Will Go”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="imtnibmB9UeR7IvZ_ZLbow" hash="XulAoA">H. David Burton</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1dba.jpg" alt="Bishop H. David Burton" pid="kgMWGy88t06m650tYfWYPQ" hash="PD71Fw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.p1" pid="WilqViFf5kyV9EdRPO7fjQ" hash="-hPnWQ">Brethren, I am honored and humbled to share this historic podium with others of the General Authorities, particularly the fifteen prophets, seers, and revelators seated behind me, whom I love and revere. I bear witness that these mighty men of God, the First Presidency and Quorum of the Twelve Apostles, have been prepared, refined, tested, and called to preside over and to give direction to this expansive priesthood labor.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.p2" pid="8d20RIAqQ0y3Nsy2xIEijg" hash="9wThSA">There is a sign prominently displayed in a shopping mall in Manila, the Philippines, that reads, “Your ‘I will’ is more important than your ‘IQ.’” As I ponder the meaning of that short phrase, there comes to mind the chorus of the great Primary song based on <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 3:7</a>: “I will go; I will do the thing the Lord commands. I know the Lord provides a way; he wants me to obey” (“Nephi’s Courage,” <span class="emphasis">Children’s Songbook,</span> pp. 120–121). I also find myself humming and whistling the refrain from the celebrated hymn of the Restoration: “I’ll go where you want me to go, dear Lord, … I’ll say what you want me to say, … I’ll be what you want me to be” (“I’ll Go Where You Want Me to Go,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> 1985, no. 270).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.p3" pid="fSENhYIPrECW0T19VcIAuA" hash="8d3jvg">Far too many who have been blessed with great ability and exceptional intellect fail to have an “I will” attitude when it comes to going, doing, saying, and being what the Lord commands.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.p4" pid="LCeoZa_jjUurnOd9flhA8w" hash="gqHYEg">
        <span class="emphasis">I will go, I will do, I will say, I will be</span> all convey determined obedience. Our third article of faith states, “We believe that through the Atonement of Christ, all mankind may be saved, by obedience to the laws and ordinances of the Gospel.” Certainly the most magnificent act of obedience was accomplished in Gethsemane. You may recall the heartfelt plea of the Savior: “Father, if thou be willing, remove this cup from me: nevertheless not my will, but thine, be done” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/22.42" class="scriptureRef">Luke 22:42</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.p5" pid="ji-fZYmpk0i3Ve-c8_8J-g" hash="y323dw">For us who bear the priesthood of God, there are many important “I wills”: <span class="emphasis">I will</span> be loyal to the oath and covenant of the priesthood; <span class="emphasis">I will</span> be responsive to my quorum president; <span class="emphasis">I will</span> exhibit perfect fidelity to the covenants made in holy places; and, <span class="emphasis">I will</span> serve with excellence in my Aaronic Priesthood ministry, preparing myself for further priesthood service. Possibly the most significant “I will” we all could commit to this night is <span class="emphasis">I will</span> follow the living prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.p6" pid="yKQoMblLmkOGN5vFEH0nuw" hash="bo_etA">Brigham Young said, “You cannot destroy the appointment of a prophet of God, but you can cut the thread that binds you to the prophet of God, and sink yourselves to hell” (in Conference Report, May 1963, p. 81). Elder John A. Widtsoe said: “The most important prophet in any age is the living prophet. … To follow the living prophet, the interpreter of the past, is the essence of wisdom. The very strength of the Church lies in the doctrine of continuous revelation through a living prophet” (<span class="emphasis">Evidences and Reconciliations,</span> 3 vols. in 1, arr. G. Homer Durham, Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1960, p. 352).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.p7" pid="AwxQ-cDiu0KW6P_F005Olw" hash="q0kjsw">President Wilford Woodruff recalled a meeting at which the Prophet Joseph Smith said to Brigham Young, “Brother Brigham I want you to take the stand and tell us your views with regard to the written oracles and the written word of God.” Brigham Young is reported to have laid the scriptures, one by one, before him and then indicated he felt the words of the living prophet were more important than the writings before him because the words of the living oracles convey the word of God to us in our day. President Woodruff went on to say, “When he was through, Brother Joseph said to the congregation: ‘Brother Brigham has told you the word of the Lord, and he has told you the truth’” (in Conference Report, Oct. 1897, pp. 22–23).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.p8" pid="fSYcGDklr0KGH06VvqvN5Q" hash="mXylZA">How are we doing in obeying the living prophets? Do you recall their counsel just six months ago in the last general priesthood meeting? For example, do you remember President Faust saying, “There is no greater responsibility than that of being a husband and a father, from which there is no release. … ‘Love thy wife with all thy heart, and … cleave unto her and none else’ [<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:22</a>]”? (In Conference Report, Apr. 1995, p. 63.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.p9" pid="7jDpCcPjV06oEq5eeOF36Q" hash="w-WPIA">Can you remember President Monson’s fervent request, “Brethren of the priesthood, the world is in need of your help. There are feet to steady, hands to grasp, minds to encourage, hearts to inspire, and souls to save. … Yours is the privilege to be not spectators but participants on the stage of priesthood service”? (In Conference Report, Apr. 1995, p. 67.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.p10" pid="0ESSwAFYDkqFkZ62GV86qQ" hash="NFpgDg">Young men, oh I hope the magnificent counsel of President Hinckley continues to ring in your ears: “You cannot indulge in any unbecoming behavior without injury to the beauty of the fabric of your lives. Immoral acts of any kind will introduce an ugly thread. Dishonesty of any kind will create a blemish. Foul and profane language will rob the pattern of its beauty” (in Conference Report, Apr. 1995, p. 73).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.p11" pid="AMdMYL6jXEy9-_m8QuaaYg" hash="US81Iw">Young men who hold the priesthood of Aaron, may I offer an “I will” for your serious consideration? It is <span class="emphasis">I will</span> become very well acquainted with the noble prophet Nephi through studying, pondering, and feasting upon the first two books of the Book of Mormon. My young friends, I promise that when you come to really know Nephi, you will be so impressed with his determination, courage, and desire to be obedient to the “things the Lord commands” that you will have a strong desire to incorporate his attributes into your own lives. Then when you are tempted by the adversary, as you may be nearly every day, to deviate from the counsel of the prophets, the wishes of your parents, or what “the Lord commands,” you can immediately have the words of stalwart Nephi automatically come to your mind: “I will go and do the things which the Lord hath commanded” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 3:7</a>). And when someone with whom you associate suggests you participate in something that is not as “the Lord commands,” you can think of the courageous plea Nephi made to his elder brothers: “Let us be faithful in keeping the commandments of the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.16" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 3:16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.p12" pid="c9i_PzvQe0upYWeyMp956Q" hash="QrbeNQ">I am aware of a group of courageous young men who followed the example of Nephi. After winning a baseball state championship for their age group, their team, made up mostly of Aaronic Priesthood holders, was invited to represent their state in a tournament to be held in a distant location. Upon arriving at the tournament site, they learned that some of the games were scheduled to be played on the Sabbath day. Each of these young men had to make a difficult personal decision: would he support the team, including several nonmember team members; or if scheduled on Sunday, would he follow what “the Lord commands” in keeping the Sabbath day holy? Their honoring the Sabbath day could mean the team would forfeit their chances of winning the tournament. One by one they quietly approached the coaches, and following the example of Nephi they independently chose to decline participation on the Sabbath day. As it turned out, when Sunday arrived the team’s record, coupled with adverse weather conditions, interrupted the schedule. I have had occasion to closely follow these young men over the years. They have continued to pattern their lives after the sterling example of Nephi. They have gone on missions, and they continue to strive to do and say what the Lord has commanded.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.p13" pid="ZzF6biSyd0yJy2bZno1b4g" hash="-XIyKg">A few weeks ago I, like perhaps many of you, witnessed on television a long-standing baseball record broken. A record once thought unbreakable. Tears rolled down my cheeks as I watched this fine athlete who broke the record stand on the field with his family and receive accolades of the public and his team. Although I am impressed with this young man’s ability to hit and field a baseball, I am far more impressed with the attributes he displayed in achieving that feat. He demonstrated great perseverance, constancy, sacrifice, courage, and determination in reaching his goal. These are some of the attributes we need to help us be successful in going, doing, and saying as “the Lord commands.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.p14" pid="gZsiviNXy0q7pUEO02uMZw" hash="cJuKyQ">You adult brethren, may I suggest an “I will” for us which has been repeatedly emphasized by modern prophets? It is of critical importance in today’s world, where the influence of the adversary is intensifying and the foundation of our society, the family, is disintegrating. It is <span class="emphasis">I will</span> resolve that the leadership of my family will be my most important and sacred responsibility; and <span class="emphasis">I will</span> not leave the teaching and governance of my family to society, to the school, or to the Church. We are reminded in the Doctrine and Covenants that fathers and mothers are held accountable by the Lord to teach their children about faith, repentance, baptism, the Holy Ghost, and the need to pray and walk uprightly before the Lord (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.25,28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:25, 28</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.p15" pid="YO1OyBsIp0igzcBURPv4ZA" hash="WSi0XQ">Perhaps you have heard some say, “I am so busy with living and providing that I have little time to devote to my family, but I make an effort to see that my limited time is quality time.” Brethren, this type of rationalization is severely flawed. Effective family leadership requires both quantity and quality time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.p16" pid="4pHgdfJIsUi7ZhCnJNvrQA" hash="nUxk-Q">When I was called to be bishop of our ward, our young four-year-old son inquired of me, “Are you the guy they give those envelopes of money to?” I answered, “Yes, I am the one,” realizing that we needed a little lesson on tithing. Brandon clapped his hands and exclaimed, “Oh goody, we’re going to be rich!” We later learned he was thinking that Dad no longer would have to work and would therefore have lots more time for him!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.p17" pid="pK7jboTTtEyfNBolbMLbgA" hash="NNhYJA">If giving your family quantity time means focusing less on providing the “wants” in life or putting aside nonfamily involvement with fishing poles, golf clubs, boats, trips, and so on, those things should be done immediately. Brethren, we need desperately to recommit to this extremely important “I will.” May we never be too busy to do the things that matter most: to preside in righteousness in our homes and follow, unconditionally, the counsel of living prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go.p18" pid="VettIQXNAU2BKG_vzWKZ1w" hash="bFVI8A">Brethren, I pray we may often recall, and perhaps even hum and sing, that simple but infectious Primary song, “I will go; I will do the thing the Lord commands. I know the Lord provides a way; he wants me to obey.” May we focus and align our “I wills” with his will. I testify that the Lord wants us to obey the living prophets. I further testify that our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ lives. He is our Savior and our Redeemer. He has, upon the principles of our repentance, atoned for our sins. I testify that this is so, in the holy name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/10/i-will-go</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1995-general-conference/1995-10-3030-bishop-h-david-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="6168105" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1995 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Go, and Do Thou Likewise”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise?lang=eng</link>
      <description>[Can we] set aside our love of substance and hear the cry of the hungry, the needy, the naked, and the sick?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_97905_000_032" doc-version="2" hash="5ZDYQQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ixPJFcZ4MkGq726UQkym1g" hash="IRo2bA">“Go, and Do Thou Likewise”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="rO9ccJimiUuxHtY-d0esnw" hash="XulAoA">H. David Burton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="rMz_HWY0nkGFeXTgaZgfPw" hash="AdWDkg">[Can we] set aside our love of substance and hear the cry of the hungry, the needy, the naked, and the sick?</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1dba.jpg" alt="Bishop H. David Burton" pid="mbG1QWBUtEietWnfaBiy-w" hash="PD71Fw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p1" pid="BRDJ3feV8EO9zGWcBUWggA" hash="zxh1zQ">All of our lives have been blessed through the great service of Sister Jack and her counselors. I’m sure I represent each of you in expressing our thanks.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p2" pid="JTY5yx3tw0qkWOOAG_jDIA" hash="HLv-bQ">Faithful disciples following the Savior heard gospel principles taught by thought-provoking short stories known as parables. After hearing many parables, “the disciples came, and said unto him, Why speakest thou unto them in parables?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/13.10" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 13:10</a>). The Savior responded: “Therefore speak I to them in parables: because they seeing see not; and hearing they hear not, neither do they understand” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/13.13" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 13:13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p3" pid="Xu4lCE2XPkiaoJBHoy_-Wg" hash="pkRsVg">A lawyer chose to challenge the Savior on a point of doctrine. Attempting to entrap Jesus, he asked, “Master, what shall I do to inherit eternal life?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.25" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:25</a>). Jesus responded with a question of his own: “What is written in the law? how readest thou?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.26" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:26</a>). The response of the lawyer, as recited from the law, was perfect: “Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy strength, and with all thy mind; and thy neighbour as thyself” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.27" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:27</a>). Jesus acknowledged the answer and then replied: “This do, and thou shalt live” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.28" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:28</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p4" pid="PHUmhv-vEEO5nf_douueoQ" hash="y0wgnw">Having failed to confound the Master, the lawyer was embarrassed. He sought justification by making a further inquiry, “And who is my neighbour?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.29" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:29</a>). We should be very grateful for the lawyer’s second question. From it came one of the most insightful of the Savior’s parables.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p5" pid="2E5KbbgDIUG72bu8VAxEzw" hash="CS6zZQ">You remember the setting: “A certain man went down from Jerusalem to Jericho, and fell among thieves, which stripped him of his raiment, and wounded him, … leaving him half dead” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.30" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:30</a>). Since our Primary days, we have heard about this certain man. We wonder at the failure of the priest and the Levite to render aid, and we say: “Surely, I would have helped. Surely, I would have stopped. Surely, I would not have looked the other way.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p6" pid="gsFZNDWsUkGmEBJDYk_EoA" hash="BSx0vw">The parable continues: “But a certain Samaritan, as he journeyed, came where he was: and when he saw him, he had compassion on him” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.33" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:33</a>). The prophet Moroni was granted a vision of our day. The Book of Mormon record states: “For behold, ye do love money, and your substance, and your fine apparel … more than ye love the poor and the needy, the sick and the afflicted. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p7" pid="osfDkLdNhECKAcJTWIHkkA" hash="h0PhKQ">“Why do ye adorn yourselves with that which hath no life, and yet suffer the hungry, and the needy, and the naked, and the sick and the afflicted to pass by you, and notice them not?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/morm/8.37,39" class="scriptureRef">Morm. 8:37, 39</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p8" pid="79KEx_3Sf0SD2EAP91zQSA" hash="gqsQQA">Moroni was troubled by what he saw. Are we troubled enough to set aside our love of substance and hear the cry of the hungry, the needy, the naked, and the sick? Can we say, “I would have responded if I had seen a person in need, as did the Samaritan”?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p9" pid="doylwJFeAEm9erqWgYbJgQ" hash="77AyfQ">The parable continues: “And [he] went to him, and bound up his wounds, pouring in oil and wine, and set him on his own beast, and brought him to an inn, and took care of him” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.34" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:34</a>). Upon completing the parable, the Savior asked the lawyer, “Which now of these three … was neighbour unto him that fell among the thieves?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.36" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:36</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p10" pid="EAvrTiBvtUGnPES_uIG95g" hash="cEX7Gw">He quickly identified the one who had shown mercy—the kind and caring traveler from Samaria. Jesus admonished the lawyer to <span class="emphasis">“go, and do thou likewise”</span> (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.37" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:37</a>; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p11" pid="EUBz13uEZUWbN-1uA2CDdA" hash="HEwpmw">May I tell you about several of the many Samaritans who are “pouring in oil and wine” to ease the plight of the needy around the world?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p12" pid="CAbDs2Js2EqPEk8O0MfGXg" hash="ALGbIg">In March of 1996, a volunteer team consisting of a radiologist, two technicians, and a biomedical engineer installed a mammography machine and a film processor in a hospital in Poland. The equipment was purchased by the Church with funds generously contributed for humanitarian assistance. Physicians and technologists came from area hospitals to be trained in the use of the machines. Since observing the benefits of the machines, the Polish government has purchased 45 more. Many lives will be saved and much suffering avoided by early detection of abnormalities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p13" pid="DeQVr0SKtUK_2AUmaGX5HA" hash="LhIlBQ">Cambodia has suffered nearly 30 years of war. Thousands perished, and survivors have experienced misery and deprivation. In 1994, following an emergency food donation by the Church, an offer was extended to assist Cambodians in becoming more self-reliant in basic food production and processing. Several skilled volunteer couples have established a small cannery and a poultry feed mill. Technical courses have been developed and taught to many. A new era in agriculture is being born through the unselfish efforts of modern good Samaritans.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p14" pid="EaLnJswnu06wB_hR9CKipw" hash="ppTN4g">Many of us regularly <span class="emphasis">“go, and do … likewise”</span> when we dispatch our surplus clothing to Deseret Industries. In 1996, over 8.5 million pounds of clothing were sorted and distributed to those in great need. Much clothing has been sent to needy populations in Russia—coats to provide warmth in freezing weather; gloves to prevent frostbite; dresses, shirts, and sweaters. A Russian official wrote, “We do thank God and each one of you for the great help you have been to our people.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p15" pid="-JO2kmcH7UGA0RBY9vtLhw" hash="wIUpew">The prophet Alma, in describing his day, said, “They did impart of their substance, every man according to that which he had, to the poor, and the needy, and the sick, and the afflicted” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/1.27" class="scriptureRef">Alma 1:27</a>). Even when they prospered, “they did not send away any who were naked, or that were hungry, or that were athirst, … they were liberal to all, … whether out of the church or in the church, having no respect to persons as to those who stood in need” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/1.30" class="scriptureRef">Alma 1:30</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p16" pid="ndeeQ__7fUCIiN-tuwRBJQ" hash="9SFRAQ">Good Samaritanism is contagious. Providing in the Lord’s way humbles the rich, it exalts the poor, and sanctifies both (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/104.15-18" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 104:15–18</a>). The giver helps those in need by sharing what he has received. The receiver accepts the offering with gratitude. As the receiver rises to his full potential, he then is able to reach out to help others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p17" pid="JR8J0tfV1EOQFOkBCNfNQg" hash="qOldIA">Good Samaritanism starts in the home as parents teach children by example and precept. Acts of assistance, kindness, and concern among family members reinforce the desire to <span class="emphasis">“go, and do thou likewise.”</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p18" pid="JOhSTG2RSUadyBO8rBW4Gg" hash="Gck6aw">Tucked away in the Uintah Basin of eastern Utah are several small communities. Jedadiah lives in one of these friendly towns. He is a handsome, blond 11-year-old. Jeddy loves academics and is extremely interested in sports. He is excited to soon be eligible to receive the Aaronic Priesthood. Jeddy’s body cannot do the many things that he would like it to do. The cystic fibrosis that exists in his lungs makes breathing rather difficult.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p19" pid="Kgd12US_U0qiEuDh0SoUoQ" hash="YVUAwQ">Amanda, Jeddy’s big sister, is a lovely 16-year-old who displays her love for him in a host of ways. She is a source of comfort when times are difficult. She is his link to school, seeing that assignments are brought home daily. A neighbor said, “Amanda is a real heroine in her family.” She understands the significance of<span class="emphasis"> “go, and do thou likewise.”</span> Jeddy only travels to Salt Lake City to go to the hospital. For a special reason he is looking forward to October general conference. It is a family tradition that Grandfather takes his grandsons to Salt Lake for general conference following their 12th birthday. Jeddy can hardly wait; neither can Grandpa.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p20" pid="Q3rIBm8D9UK7M1TbjUF-9A" hash="kXgvRQ">Recently, a sweet 93-year-old sister joined her eternal companion on the other side of the veil. They were blessed with four devoted children. This couple shared their musical talents on thousands of occasions. Many saddened spirits were uplifted in times of mourning as these good Samaritans blended their voices in strains of hope and encouragement. Many children will feel the love of the Savior as they sing Primary songs composed by this sweet sister. As her health declined, loving children spent much time and energy and emotion in meeting her needs. A valiant daughter devoted herself to her mother’s care. They will continue to<span class="emphasis"> “go, and do thou likewise.”</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p21" pid="0o4GnbZd6E63pOO_tVix1g" hash="mA-2cw">In a mountain valley, a small community is the home of a monastery with a declining number of aging monks. A stake Relief Society president, with many other compassionate service responsibilities, regularly checks on the well-being of the monks. She is the first to deliver goodies on days when they are permissible. She cares about their welfare just as she does about the members of her stake.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p22" pid="T0YX9zPRCUOTavmdEBriCA" hash="TnPf5w">Bishops regularly call upon volunteer labor to grow and process commodities to fill bishops’ storehouses. Last year, nearly 270,000 days of labor were volunteered in keeping shelves filled and available for use by bishops. Many of us have fond remembrances of our time volunteering on welfare projects. I can still hear a farm manager’s cries of anguish as he observed the damage done to several acres of sugar beets because we had mistaken newly emerging beet plants for weeds. The blessings we received for our service turned out to be a “Scotch blessing.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p23" pid="JxfdvX0K10SHKbCCSGifDw" hash="ojTqTw">President Monson said, “We have a responsibility to extend help as well as hope to the hungry, to the homeless, and to the downtrodden both at home and abroad” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1990, 4).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p24" pid="FWefj35HmkC1YBnEWkMNUA" hash="UtYrHA">Picture a small, one-room apartment which is home for a family of six. The room is dirty and cluttered. The family has not been to church in years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p25" pid="H7DkW9h6_0SG-D6g63hVag" hash="QiP3jQ">As the ward welfare committee discussed the family’s needs, there was a feeling of discouragement, for bishops, over the years, had helped the family often. In the discussion, a new idea began to dawn. Perhaps, if the committee called upon the resources of the Lord’s storehouse—the talents and skills of ward members—even this difficult situation could be assisted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p26" pid="zoXvsoKoW0edkgtUMvdTHw" hash="EATpkQ">The committee first focused on future possibilities as well as immediate needs. As possibilities turned to reality, hope and optimism replaced gloom and depression. Filled with hope, the family committed to help improve their own situation. The committee also went to work. A hairstylist gave the family haircuts. A dentist volunteered, and for the first time in years, a mother was not embarrassed to smile. A new pair of glasses allowed this mother to once again read to her children. A financial specialist worked with the family in budgeting their funds. A three-year-old received much needed physical therapy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p27" pid="sj0aRqSn4kO0t5wBR2Riyw" hash="5rHlfw">Slowly the family began to believe their life could be different. The apartment, once dirty and disorganized, began to show signs of order and cleanliness. Curtains went up on the windows. Just a year later invitations were extended by this family to an open house for their three-bedroom home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p28" pid="JXG-jgc6oUCytc2q9680cw" hash="AfhVag">A wounded family was found by the side of the road, a family suffering just as much as the traveler from Jerusalem in Jesus’ day. The family’s cries were heard, and their wounds were bound. The modern good Samaritans followed the divine injunction to <span class="emphasis">“go, and do thou likewise.”</span> Spiritual lives were also rescued. Today, this family is active in the Church and preparing to receive the blessings of the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p29" pid="MjzrW9h0g0uAeof9P-bHnw" hash="ddfn6A">Bishops use consecrated fast offerings to supply needs beyond those which can be provided by the storehouse. President Hinckley suggested we think “of what would happen if the principles of the fast day and the fast offering were observed throughout the world. The hungry would be fed, the naked clothed, the homeless sheltered. … The giver would not suffer, but would be blessed by his small abstinence. A new measure of concern and unselfishness would grow in the hearts of people everywhere” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1991, 52–53).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p30" pid="Keh9nE0cw0-6hDgKo0CoVQ" hash="jDHF-w">To help relieve suffering is to cultivate a Christlike character. We are charged, as were those who listened at the feet of the Savior 2,000 years ago, to <span class="emphasis">“go, and do thou likewise.”</span> The Prophet Joseph Smith taught that it is our responsibility “to feed the hungry, to clothe the naked, to provide for the widow, to dry up the tear of the orphan, to comfort the afflicted, whether in this church or in any other, or in no church at all, wherever he finds them” (<span class="emphasis">Times and Seasons,</span> 15 Mar. 1842, 732).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p31" pid="90hlt3IOIUOtJ1RJJktWZw" hash="S4xrKw">May we be generous with our time and liberal in our contributions for the care of those who suffer. May we commit to the principles of Good Samaritanism and be ever mindful of the need to <span class="emphasis">“go, and do thou likewise,”</span> I pray in the holy name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1997/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1997-general-conference/1997-04-5040-bishop-h-david-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="6817920" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 1997 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Season of Opportunity</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity?lang=eng</link>
      <description>It is a season to reach out to touch the life of someone, a season to commit to keeping the Sabbath day holy, and a season to help keep the lights of our temples burning brightly.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_98911_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="Jcv5zg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="X505U5fa2UaHeSUkfTp4Rg" hash="rdeJpQ">A Season of Opportunity</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="CLcIrpNsQEG2i9ggZYvorQ" hash="XulAoA">H. David Burton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="ofIjenOZHEO3MYS_uXEXgg" hash="f89-YA">It is a season to reach out to touch the life of someone, a season to commit to keeping the Sabbath day holy, and a season to help keep the lights of our temples burning brightly.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1dba.jpg" alt="Bishop H. David Burton" pid="YW8qyx6uxE6rNv-sFm0jBw" hash="PD71Fw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p1" pid="iWiCYR4UdEiADf-kBr3OZQ" hash="6g_qWg">In a recent sacrament meeting, a lovely young lady suggested that a good talk should begin with a little tasteful humor or an outrageous falsehood. My ability to convey humor is virtually nonexistent, but I can say with deep sincerity that I feel perfectly comfortable and free of fear as I stand at this podium.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p2" pid="63R53PW4AEuyuTvv-AlhDg" hash="8bvqpQ">As our recent sesquicentennial celebration concluded, our beloved prophet refocused our attention when he said: “The time has now come to turn about and face the future. This is a season of a thousand opportunities. It is ours to grasp and move forward. What a wonderful time it is for each of us to do his or her small part in moving the work of the Lord on to its magnificent destiny” (Gordon B. Hinckley, in Conference Report, Oct. 1997, 90–91; or <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1997, 67).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p3" pid="HNKM_KzkiEmG1_Vn-ncbbQ" hash="qtlnGw">All of us face challenges in our daily lives. Yet in challenges lie some of our greatest opportunities. As we recognize and act on our opportunities, progress, happiness, and spiritual growth follow. We need to be involved in moving the Lord’s work forward. Though the opportunities available to us are endless, may I suggest just a few.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p4" pid="tZ-Yrcwu60aeJy6dmV1edg" hash="J08HDQ">Over and over again we have been reminded from this pulpit to fully observe the Sabbath day. If we are not keeping the Sabbath day holy, today is a wonderful time to commit to seize that opportunity, to receive the promised blessings that come from Sabbath day observance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p5" pid="LvkCmQd3REiNf_4Or8uPjw" hash="zrs4Mw">Many have come to feel that the terms “Sabbath day” and “play day” are synonymous. A friend who manages several small retail outlets in predominantly LDS communities tells me he can precisely tell when Sunday worship services conclude because customer counts increase dramatically. Recreation in its various forms has become “king of the Sabbath day.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p6" pid="0GGHx8NGHUO_d5LYNw7Fxw" hash="w1CDqw">When Sister Burton and I were first married, we lived in the southeast part of the Salt Lake Valley. On occasion, as we purchased groceries from a small neighborhood store, we observed President and Sister Joseph Fielding Smith in the same store making their purchases. After several such observations, I finally mustered the courage to inquire of President Smith why it was he traveled all the way from downtown, past a dozen grocery stores, to shop at this particular store. Looking over the tops of his glasses he emphatically said: “Son! [He had my immediate attention.] Sister Smith and I patronize establishments that keep the Sabbath day holy.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p7" pid="hR64iMLKoEK0_O-dE3crHQ" hash="WcDgrw">The need to reverence the Sabbath day is not new counsel. We are only being told today what prior generations have been told by the prophets of their day and reconfirmed countless times by the prophets of our day. Latter-day scripture contains the following admonition:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p8" pid="LjxrJ5-3c06Gaa3ucK0-GQ" hash="Q3O1ag">“And that thou mayest more fully keep thyself unspotted from the world, thou shalt go to the house of prayer and offer up thy sacraments upon my holy day;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p9" pid="eUehP4BFiEW8J2qWSg_Ejg" hash="JjTBOA">“For verily this is a day appointed unto you to rest from your labors, and to pay thy devotions unto the Most High” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.9-10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:9–10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p10" pid="Cr4mq-3MjESGtKSxfo5SIQ" hash="6bRZgg">Now, I know it’s hard, particularly for our young people, to choose to observe the Sabbath day when athletic teams on which they so much want to participate regularly schedule games on Sunday. I too know it seems trivial to many who are in need of just a few items on the Sabbath to quickly stop at a convenience store to make a Sunday purchase. But I also know that remembering to keep the Sabbath day holy is one of the most important commandments we can observe in preparing us to be the recipients of the whisperings of the Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p11" pid="DY6MbZkDf0uZAyV67hHCgw" hash="LRLHxA">This is the season of opportunity for families to stand tall and be counted among the faithful who obey the fourth great commandment:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p12" pid="HyotwQz9wE-n2LvHC3oC5A" hash="DcNtSw">“Remember the sabbath day, to keep it holy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p13" pid="y7LFIp8DKUqfcY9RaNyYnw" hash="NlI92A">“Six days shalt thou labour, and do all thy work:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p14" pid="ApN3FyPdeUeqyvzmk7GQtg" hash="kcmLnw">“But the seventh day is the sabbath of the Lord thy God” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.8-10" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:8–10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p15" pid="cUr6gXDXQkeQQuAEX6ipQg" hash="M6SE4A">A few years ago, President Hinckley responded to an observation concerning the number of temple dedications or rededications in which he had participated during his tenure as a General Authority. He indicated that it was his desire to continue to be involved in dedicating temples at least until we have 100 operating temples. As I heard this statement, I couldn’t help doing a little simple math and realized that the sum of the number representing current operating temples and the number representing the temple projects then in design or construction was far less than 100. Because the Presiding Bishopric has the responsibility to oversee the construction of temples as they are announced, I remember very vividly saying to the prophet, “President, I pray the Lord will bless you with great longevity.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p16" pid="1VJl15nzK0iRdF-u4SifaQ" hash="b3kaUw">Little did I know that perhaps even at that time our prophet was being prompted from the heavens to consider ways to provide more opportunities for worthy Latter-day Saint families to participate in the blessings associated with temple worship. I wept and rejoiced as you did last April in general conference when we heard President Hinckley say:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p17" pid="tTPNBhSkeUqhQAvQJn3pog" hash="of5R2w">“In recent months we have traveled far out among the membership of the Church. I have been with many who have very little of this world’s goods. But they have in their hearts a great burning faith concerning this latter-day work. They love the Church. … They love the Lord and want to do His will. They are paying their tithing, modest as it is. They make tremendous sacrifices to visit the temples. They travel for days at a time in cheap buses and on old boats. They save their money and do without to make it all possible.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p18" pid="NCOvsbSWX0OPXN2fS4UbHQ" hash="bQnt3Q">“They need nearby temples. … Accordingly, I take this opportunity to announce to the entire Church a program to construct some 30 smaller temples immediately. … These will be in addition to the 17 buildings now going forward. … This will make a total of 47 new temples in addition to the 51 now in operation. I think we had better add 2 more to make it an even 100 by the end of this century” (in Conference Report, Apr. 1998, 115; or <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1998, 87–88).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p19" pid="ZugBcmY0wEG8zpAQ4nHHIQ" hash="QyXnkw">Early in this dispensation, our forefathers were blessed with the opportunity of sacrificing mightily to build temples. They offered generously of their meager financial means as well as the fruits of their physical labor. As temples were completed in Kirtland and later in Nauvoo, the sacrifice of the Saints was great. They were blessed as they responded. After the migration of the Saints to the tops of the mountains, temples began to appear in a number of locations in the West. Each temple project represented great sacrifice. Divinely promised blessings awaited those who availed themselves of the opportunity to participate in building temples.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p20" pid="wca69MqPrUC5z-BjNktNQQ" hash="e2X6kQ">The season of opportunity that awaits us today, in temple service, is different from that of the past. We are not expected to pound nails, carve stone, mill lumber, pour concrete, or physically participate in the construction of temples. We are, however, extended a marvelous opportunity to faithfully pay our tithes so temple construction and the work of the Lord may go forward. We are also challenged to be worthy to offer ourselves in the service of providing sacred saving ordinances for those who have preceded us. Very simply stated, the great opportunity of Latter-day Saint families is to see that the lights of our temples burn early and late in the day. Perhaps we could create the need for them to burn all night as they do presently on weekends in several temples.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p21" pid="E7BXenMpo0GFWVdIM6u13g" hash="yArX6w">A few years ago a major communications company used in their advertising the phrase “Reach out and touch someone.” President Hinckley has reminded us repeatedly of the many opportunities to reach out and touch someone. In speaking of those who have recently joined with us, he described a need to reach out and touch them with love and fellowship; to those who are estranged, a touch of encouragement, unconditional love, and a full measure of forgiveness if required; to our neighbors, associates, and friends who are not of our faith, the blessing of being touched by the Holy Spirit because of our words and deeds.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p22" pid="8PIqGvG9CEWVKInnE6PLjg" hash="WPmPEA">In a recent training meeting for stake and ward councils held as a part of a stake conference I attended, well-prepared presentations centered on the opportunities to be “inclusive” rather than “exclusive” in reaching out and touching new and less-active individuals, as well as those not members of our church. Sister Laura Chipman, a stake Young Women president, suggested five I’s to help us to be inclusive in our outreach. They are: (1) <span class="emphasis">Introspection</span>—Are we inadvertently communicating an exclusionary attitude? (2) <span class="emphasis">Identify</span>—Do we know the recently baptized, the less-active, or nonmembers who reside in our neighborhoods and communities? (3) <span class="emphasis">Individualize</span>—Do we seek to know the interests, talents, and skills of those we wish to fellowship? (4) <span class="emphasis">Invite</span>—Do we include neighbors and friends in appropriate activities? (5) <span class="emphasis">Involve</span>—Are there ways we can utilize the skills, talents, and abilities of those we wish to include?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p23" pid="mT0ujSOr5kKiiSB_9MYSlQ" hash="pBLPRQ">I recently attended the funeral for one of my boyhood friends. This brother was genetically challenged from birth. He could understand concepts quite well but could not read or write. His speech was limited to a very few identifiable words, along with a jargon all of his own. Some in our group could recognize a few words he spoke. However, we could usually tell from the tone of his words whether he was expressing his concerns or his great capacity to love. Much of Lynn’s early life was spent in a special school away from home. He spent his summers and many holidays at home with his family. For the past 17 years, Lynn, who outlived all of his family, lived in a care center where his many needs could best be met.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p24" pid="Un5XVvX25U64zvmZ_DDJjg" hash="icv1MA">Upon Lynn’s death, one of his special friends arranged a funeral to be held in the meetinghouse we attended as boys. Present at the funeral were his dear friends, the staff from the care center, a few ward members who remembered him from many years ago, and about a dozen boyhood friends and their families. Several brethren who had stayed close to Lynn during his long, often lonesome stay at the care center offered tender remarks.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p25" pid="P3LScgN650umU3b8IoIhrQ" hash="UaHWvw">All of our memories were refreshed during the course of the service. One friend recalled that on one occasion our Sunday School teacher invited us to bear our testimonies in class. As he sequentially called upon us, he passed over Lynn, perhaps feeling he could not respond with understanding. With all the righteous indignation Lynn could muster, he let the teacher know he expected his opportunity to express himself. Though we didn’t understand much of what he said, we felt his love and the depth of a great spirit tragically locked in a body that could not fully function. The spirit in that class was very strong!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p26" pid="Lm4R6wU-ekqp-Nwoo5Hnsw" hash="nPW3Aw">As the staff and the special friends from the care center expressed their unconditional love, it was very evident that Lynn, in his humble way, had reached out and touched their lives. During the course of the funeral, it was apparent that at least three of our boyhood friends and their families had reached out to minister to Lynn in ways that included regular visits, long automobile rides, invitations to dinners on special occasions, and birthday parties.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p27" pid="aIa_mLzGhkWct43KBYm9Vg" hash="nsAX2Q">When the stories and recollections were complete, we all realized that our physically challenged, loving angel of a friend had given us and the wonderful compassionate families who reached out so often in love, far more of real value than he had ever received.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity.p28" pid="rGJE_3cfzkCf8m6bBdUaZg" hash="M3sTkQ">Yes, today is, indeed, a season of many opportunities. It is a season to reach out to touch the life of someone, a season to commit to keeping the Sabbath day holy, and a season to help keep the lights of our temples burning brightly, to name justa very few. I testify of a living Father in Heaven and of His Son, our Savior and our Redeemer, both who love us unconditionally and are anxious for us to seize the many opportunities They have provided. I acknowledge and express my love to our dear prophet, who, with great devotion, carries our banner with courage and majesty. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1998/10/a-season-of-opportunity</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1998-general-conference/1998-10-1030-bishop-h-david-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="6808426" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 1998 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Honoring the Priesthood</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Priesthood isn’t something we take off during the week and put on for Sunday. It is a 24-7 privilege and blessing—that is, 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10033256_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="TJ6OQQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Tizaq2URw0ubA97tJi9efg" hash="Oj-JTA">Honoring the Priesthood</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="eRLNT6pr50iLvtHgRG1IpA" hash="XulAoA">H. David Burton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="bcz5y2NbS0q3Y69lObXm3g" hash="9Xug4w">Priesthood isn’t something we take off during the week and put on for Sunday. It is a 24-7 privilege and blessing—that is, 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-64d.jpg" alt="Bishop H. David Burton" pid="-4Ajgv_LmEytqf-twi7fMg" hash="onVBPw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.p1" pid="O6ZNrUduh0aeAHTjGo9whg" hash="-cbrKA">Good evening, brethren. For months we have worried about this building’s readiness for general conference. A miracle has been accomplished—a miracle made possible because professionals, as well as common, garden-variety men and women, have displayed uncommon devotion, sacrifice, and inspiration far beyond normal industry standards. I express deep appreciation to my counselors and to all individuals who have shared their talents on this project.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.p2" pid="OCvIa4spVUeODYTzf4-cLA" hash="gY0zJA">I’ve been in this building many times during its construction; but as I see it filled with priesthood holders tonight, I marvel at its size and beauty. For you who follow international soccer (football), the distance from where I stand to the very last row of the balcony is about three-fourths the length of one field. The distance is the equivalent of three basketball courts placed end to end or nearly four tennis courts fashioned in the same manner. A golfer would probably select a nine iron to hit the ball over the last balcony row, and a world-class sprinter could run the distance in about nine seconds. To use a word I often hear, it is awesome!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.p3" pid="RT8mtKp0bEq02483JXVt8A" hash="r6mS2g">On occasion I enjoy participating in or viewing sporting events. My wife suggests the time between occasions is too short. In many sports, if a participant or coach places the outstretched fingers of one hand in a perpendicular position to the palm of his other hand, it is a signal for time-out. The contest is temporarily halted while coaches and players discuss strategy. The term <span class="emphasis">time-out</span> is also used by some parents to describe to their children a state in which they will be placed if they continue on a course contrary to their parents’ wishes. Time-out offers a person a chance to think about their behavior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.p4" pid="yksIpa3Pf0WSZq1_QR6w_A" hash="ju_l7Q">My Aaronic Priesthood colleagues, let’s place ourselves in time-out this evening to discuss a few priesthood issues.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.p5" pid="4a1gK7IhSU2M1zoWDtLDOg" hash="JTukiA">Several weeks ago I was talking with my 16-year-old granddaughter. I asked her what she would tell the young men of the Aaronic Priesthood if she could speak to them. She said, “Grandpa, I would ask them to show respect for the priesthood and to be priesthood holders seven days a week rather than just one day, Sunday. Some guys do not show respect for the priesthood because they use profanity; some are involved in pornography; and a few are into drugs.” I’m certain, my young brethren, that you’ll agree that profanity, pornography, and drugs should not be a part of the life of a priesthood holder.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.p6" pid="S-Tw5KSFgEaAYv7HChvExQ" hash="awNtxQ">The priesthood isn’t something we take off during the week and put on for Sunday. It is a 24-7 privilege and blessing—that is, 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.p7" pid="Hekq-B7DK0S-pg-KJ20xuQ" hash="XvUWBw">Profanity and crudeness have become commonplace and are accepted by many as a normal part of their speech. Our sense of right and wrong has been dimmed by a constant bombardment of profanity and crudeness. It is rampant in music, schools, sports, shopping malls, and in our workplaces. Much everyday conversation is laced with crude terms and sprinkled with outright profane expressions, sometimes under the guise of humor.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.p8" pid="A16wIxn92EuLwb4R20gOcw" hash="6H5c7Q">Recently I was in a department store trying on shoes. Four young men were looking at what they labeled missionary shoes. It was evident at least two of the young men had received mission calls and were there to find shoes suitable for missionary service. I was surprised by a barrage of crude terms with a few profanities which seemed to routinely roll off their tongues. When they noticed there was someone else nearby, I heard one say, “Hey, guys, we better clean up our language,” as he motioned with his head in my direction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.p9" pid="29kAedYFgUGsFzuwP26iaA" hash="OIT7OQ">President Hinckley has said: “Conversation is the substance of friendly social activity. It can be happy. It can be light. It can be earnest. It can be funny. But it must not be salty, or uncouth, or foul if one is in sincerity a believer in Christ” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of Gordon B. Hinckley</span> [1997], 494). Profanity and priesthood are not compatible. Neither is profanity compatible with missionary service. Profane and crude terms, if part of our conversation, need to be eliminated from our vocabularies. Conversation is one of the windows to our souls.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.p10" pid="uCY8_-ARD0akuiXKDXd9Aw" hash="j80sWg">During time-out let’s talk about pornography. In recent years pornography has spread like wildfire. We are exposed to it daily. Pornography is as addictive as many substances we would not even consider taking into our bodies. The consequences of pornography are catastrophic. Keep in mind Satan does not want us to be happy or successful in our Aaronic Priesthood ministry. Make no mistake, he wants us to be miserable. His goal is to capture our hearts by enticing us to participate in terrible things such as pornography. Stay away from it. We must discipline ourselves to avoid books, magazines, music, pictures, videos, DVDs, movies, Internet sites, television programming—anything that contains pornography or sensual material. Pornography and priesthood are not compatible. Respect the priesthood; call a permanent time-out to any pornographic influence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.p11" pid="GCaabzI0eUacPiNj5YDRqg" hash="L6O5Eg">President Hinckley has reminded us that the “modern drug scourge has become as a plague on the world. … In most cases, it follows a long period spent in misery and pain and regret. Unlike the plagues of old, from which there was no known defense, the defense is clear and relatively easy in the case of illicit drugs. It lies in simply refraining from touching them” (“The Scourge of Illicit Drugs,” in <span class="emphasis">Speaking Out on Moral Issues</span> [1992], 127). We would not place our lives in jeopardy by playing with a venomous snake. Drugs are just as dangerous as the reptile’s deadly venom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.p12" pid="9RHbtu2nZkyKx2FoVZXscA" hash="pH526g">Our son returned to his home recently to find his son was sitting at the kitchen table with elbows on the table and his chin in his hands. Another son exhibited a sad countenance as he sat in the living room staring out the window. Their mom was not visible. Our son asked the boys where she might be. They pointed to the bathroom. He quietly knocked on the door and asked, “Honey, are you in there?” She replied, “I’ve put myself in time-out.” Adults need an occasional time-out.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.p13" pid="3N8hj-OkwE-PFiNEqZiKGw" hash="JrC7kg">Melchizedek Priesthood holders, please join us in time-out. In the battle of daily living, it is easy to lose focus on our ministries as fathers and priesthood holders. If we are not careful, our vocations, hobbies, recreation, and even perhaps our Church service can adversely impact our responsibility as fathers and husbands.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.p14" pid="Q-dQUM8ve0yVqzeJ6DjnLA" hash="Tp5IAA">President Howard W. Hunter had only one opportunity to address a general conference priesthood meeting while he was President of the Church. On that occasion, October 1994, President Hunter entitled his talk “Being a Righteous Husband and Father.” In that masterful address, he outlined a number of standards and expectations for all who hold the Melchizedek Priesthood. I commend the entire address for your review. Tonight, I mention just two. President Hunter said: “A man who holds the priesthood regards the family as ordained of God. Your leadership of the family is your most important and sacred responsibility. The family is the most important unit in time and in eternity and, as such, transcends every other interest in life” (in Conference Report, Oct. 1994, 68; or <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1994, 50).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.p15" pid="nTyjqLGf1UGbCsHoGAGv7Q" hash="bJ013g">President Harold B. Lee said, “The most important of the Lord’s work you and I will ever do will be within the walls of our own homes” (<span class="emphasis">Stand Ye in Holy Places</span> [1974], 255). We need to honestly search and plumb the depths of our souls. Are we doing all we should do to give our families gospel instruction and governance, or are we leaving this responsibility to others? Leadership in the family often requires us to reorder our priorities in order to find the necessary time. Quality and quantity time are essential.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.p16" pid="ptULwjAxPU67XddEMZkkFg" hash="gu7WSw">President Hunter also reminded us, “A man who holds the priesthood leads his family in Church participation so they will know the gospel and be under the protection of the covenants and ordinances” (in Conference Report, Oct. 1994, 69; or <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1994, 51). For us to accomplish this we must make certain our personal lives are in order. Hypocrisy has never worked, and it will not work today. We are required to lead out in righteousness and encourage our families to follow our examples. Lead out in family home evening. Lead out in scripture study. Provide priesthood blessings. Lead out in personal and family prayer. President Monson said, “Remember that a man never stands taller than when he is upon his knees” (in Conference Report, Apr. 1964, 130).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.p17" pid="7Nfkqw2VJEicdbwaCvDZvQ" hash="LlwHxw">A time-out usually concludes with a little pep talk. Brethren, we can prevail and ultimately win the contest. We can honor and respect the priesthood on a seven-day-a-week, 24-hour-a-day basis. We can banish profanity, pornography, and drugs from our lives as well as any other unwholesome or unclean activity. We can provide our families with the priesthood leadership and the spiritual direction they require. We can do all this and much more if we will draw near to the Savior, honor the sacred priesthood we hold, and be faithful to the covenants we have made.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood.p18" pid="vBKoBN5CtE6zBF69W6oV4Q" hash="MLEGQw">I testify we are on the Lord’s errand. He is our Savior. He is our Redeemer. He has atoned for our sins. He is our Advocate with the Father. He lives. He loves us unconditionally. We are bearers of His priesthood. I love President Hinckley, his counselors, the Twelve, and my fellow General Authorities, and I testify of their goodness, their greatness, and their authority. I love you, my fellow holders of the priesthood, and pray for our success. In the holy name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2000/04/honoring-the-priesthood</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2000-general-conference/2000-04-3020-bishop-h-david-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5229565" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Standing Tall</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Jesus Christ is our perfect example of one who always stood tall. He is the one who personifies integrity, strength, and courage.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029371_000_026" doc-version="2" hash="qhIfIQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="SAQGFbHnNkeqKs4h02VprQ" hash="48IDRg">Standing Tall</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="gW8yGcchU02zJJNiVGc7gQ" hash="XulAoA">H. David Burton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="BPW7d5a-F0i_qHU43KRPdA" hash="AWVozw">Jesus Christ is our perfect example of one who always stood tall. He is the one who personifies integrity, strength, and courage.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-64d.jpg" alt="Bishop H. David Burton" pid="4q3LV5sDNUit0kWaZvT4ag" hash="onVBPw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall.p1" pid="QrXH93pZVUGm-YvsLxIvpw" hash="FdSSAw">A man of wisdom often offered this simple piece of advice: “David, stand tall.” My dad did not expect that I would add inches to my stature or rise up on my tiptoes. He meant that I should be courageous in my decision, not compromising principles, not violating spiritual values, and not shrinking from responsibility. When I have followed his advice, life has been very good. When I have failed to stand tall, life has usually been unpleasant. I recently asked my two young grandsons what it would mean to them if Heavenly Father asked them to stand tall. I noticed one inadvertently raised himself to his tippy-toes so as to seem a little taller. And then they quickly said in unison, “He wants us to do what is right.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall.p2" pid="GDgemBzrukC--X2Wh1JuSQ" hash="h1wNag">Out of the deep anguish and turmoil of September 11th have come many instances of men, women, and nations standing tall. Foes and friends have come together against a common enemy. Uncommon acts of bravery have become commonplace. Humanitarian response seems to know no bounds. Men and women, regardless of race or creed, have reached out to victims and their families. Countless prayers have been offered. The forces for good are standing tall against the forces of terror and senseless mayhem.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall.p3" pid="0DoYPRp4102FlXWcztjq7w" hash="xBj75Q">It is said that a fence-sitter eventually has to come down on one side or the other. If we are sitting on the top of life’s fences, now is the time to muster the courage to stand tall on the side of righteousness and shun the shackles of sin.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall.p4" pid="RL6CgiCQMUKGhtjPHXNOtw" hash="3o_O_g">The life, ministry, and teachings of our Savior, Jesus Christ, provide a template for introspective assessment. Jesus Christ is our perfect example of one who always stood tall. He is the one who personifies integrity, strength, and courage. I would like to use three examples from the Savior’s ministry.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall.p5" pid="k13ZXCKlAk6lRayPE_K3Qg" hash="wlkgxw">First, after His baptism, Jesus was prompted to remove Himself to commune with His Father. For 40 days He chose not to eat in order that His mortal body might be subjected to His divine spirit. In this weakened state, He was visited by the tempter, who suggested that the Savior use His great power to perform extraordinary feats. To the tempter’s request that He turn stones to bread to relieve His hunger, the Savior stood tall by replying, “It is written, Man shall not live by bread alone, but by every word that proceedeth out of the mouth of God” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/4.4" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 4:4</a>). To the notion that He throw himself from a high place to be saved by the hands of angels, He triumphantly stated, “Thou shalt not tempt the Lord thy God” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/4.7" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 4:7</a>). To the proposition that the Savior fall on His knees and worship the devil in exchange for the wealth and splendor of earthly glory, He valiantly replied, “Thou shalt worship the Lord thy God, and him only shalt thou serve” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/4.10" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 4:10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall.p6" pid="D8bcG2QtEEmrLEru2c2-nA" hash="W6qN8w">The tempter’s insidious ways continue unabated. The quest for “things” has enticed some to depart from principle. Failure to distinguish between needs and wants has muddied men’s minds. Families are starving for the affection, recognition, and leadership of parents. Many are resorting to unethical, immoral, and, on occasion, illegal methods to acquire more and more material goods.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall.p7" pid="ZraAJE3ACUmDTPDfikBI6w" hash="7ZaMUw">If you find yourself entrapped in the pursuit of material things, now is the time to courageously stand tall. If you worship the items that money can buy more than you cherish the love of God, now is the time to stand tall. If you have been blessed with abundance beyond your needs, now is the time to stand tall in sharing with those whose needs remain unfulfilled.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall.p8" pid="NT14Uc56t0eLF1aSMFq4hQ" hash="yKtxwQ">The second example—on one occasion, the Savior called together His followers and said, “Hear, and understand: Not that which goeth into the mouth defileth a man; but that which cometh out of the mouth, this defileth a man” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/15.10-11" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 15:10–11</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall.p9" pid="11XppbQSBUClOPOTv20BGw" hash="Jh2YuQ">As a normal part of everyday language, many people take the name of God in vain. Among our youth, vulgar and crude terms seem to come easily as they describe their feelings. My young friends, now is the time to stand tall in eliminating these words from your vocabulary. You know the words to which I refer. Unfortunately, you hear them used over and over again in your schools, music, and sports. Will it take courage to stand tall? Of course it will. Can you muster the courage? Of course you can. Seek strength from your Heavenly Father to overcome it. The Savior said, “Pray always, and I will pour out my Spirit upon you, and great shall be your blessing” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/19.38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 19:38</a>). It has been said, “You reach the greatest heights while on your knees” (“Standing Tall,” <span class="emphasis">New Era,</span> Oct. 2001, 19). Profanity and crudeness do not exalt; they defile. My wife and I have attended hundreds of youth sporting events. Too often we hear profanity expressed by coaches and other adults who should be role models. Adults need to stand tall in eliminating crude and profane language.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall.p10" pid="_3rgNtMi7kGmNpfBB28H2g" hash="LA0TnA">You have heard the phrase “Your actions speak so loudly, I cannot hear your words.” Our actions indeed speak volumes about us. We need to stand tall in following the counsel of the prophets to attire ourselves modestly. “Immodest clothing includes short shorts and skirts, tight [form-fitting] clothing, shirts that do not cover the stomach, and other revealing attire” (<span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth</span> [2001], 12). Clothing that is modest, neat, and clean uplifts. Immodest clothing degrades. If there is any question, ask yourself, “Would I feel comfortable with my appearance if I were in the Lord’s presence?” (<span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth,</span> 13). Mothers, you can be our examples and conscience in this important matter. But remember, young people can detect hypocrisy as easily as they can smell the wonderful aroma of freshly baked bread. Parents, counsel your sons and daughters and then join with them in standing tall against immodesty.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall.p11" pid="RLEOztqbi0i7961k43QZQw" hash="LGBNnA">Third, you will recall that in response to the lawyer’s question about who is our neighbor, the Savior recounted that a certain man traveling from Jerusalem to Jericho fell among thieves and was beaten, robbed, and left for dead. The first to come his way was a priest, who looked away and passed by on the other side of the road. Likewise, the next to discover his plight stopped to look but passed without rendering aid. The third, a Samaritan, bound up his wounds and made arrangements for his care. Then Jesus asked which of them was the neighbor. The lawyer responded that the neighbor was he who showed mercy. In response the Savior said, “Go, and do thou likewise” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.37" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:37</a>; see <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.30-37" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:30–37</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall.p12" pid="48Hsdd-pt0Ki7CQkAuqrPA" hash="OOPoAA">As we reach out to our neighbors, are we sensitive not only to their needs but also to their feelings? Is our neighborliness selective and confined to those of our faith, or is it all-inclusive regardless of faith, color, or any other perceived differences? To the Savior there was no reservation in the definition of <span class="emphasis">neighbor.</span> Sometimes our unique Church language can be misinterpreted and appear insensitive or even condescending to our neighbors. As Elder Ballard suggested yesterday, I too feel uncomfortable with the term <span class="emphasis">nonmember.</span> When we refer to others as nonmembers, they might wonder if we feel they are not members of our community, city, or even the human race. We are quick to say we are accepting and inclusive in our neighborly relationships, but to some we too often come across as barely tolerating. Love of neighbor comes only after love of self and God. Let us stand tall in extending unequivocal love and respect to our neighbors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall.p13" pid="t2P2cJvJRUKrewiqgisqhg" hash="FkGedQ">A dear family friend passed away a few years ago. He and his wife enjoyed hiking together in the mountains. One fall afternoon, they hiked several miles up a steep mountainside to a beautiful waterfall. While descending the trail, several hikers making the climb upward asked the question, “Is it worth it?” Our friends’ reply was always in the affirmative. Later, they observed that the effort was worth it only if you enjoyed the fresh air, alpine beauty, exercise, and loving companionship.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall.p14" pid="o6ZU54QPUE2s9eoCXsSYZw" hash="b9kZzg">Feeling the intense pressure from peers and the need to be accepted, some may ask the question, “Is it worth the effort to stand tall?” To that question I respond, “If life eternal is important to you and if you want to experience real joy in this life, then standing tall is worth the determination and tireless daily effort it requires.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall.p15" pid="WNxk5xxiD0udNLTIqUdV0w" hash="aZK_vQ">May we all stand tall on the side of righteousness, I pray in the sacred name of our Lord and Master, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2001/10/standing-tall</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2001-general-conference/2001-10-4030-bishop-h-david-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="4928752" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2001 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>And That’s the Way It Is</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We need to achieve and maintain standards in order to participate in the important spiritual events of life.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030371_000_020" doc-version="2" hash="KCMi2g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="4dMt5Pp_aEKWhUDngjsjaA" hash="wq5fTA">And That’s the Way It Is</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="0zvikAyNhkORUmdokEmSVQ" hash="XulAoA">H. David Burton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="B7dJmdSsmkSlHC2ziliKFQ" hash="Bi_nhA">We need to achieve and maintain standards in order to participate in the important spiritual events of life.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-64d.jpg" alt="Bishop H. David Burton" pid="jKE0M9nN4E-7qjV7UXr_2Q" hash="onVBPw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p1" pid="Qf-qVMwkL0mP4q4jvut8yQ" hash="NlZ2Kg">Good evening. I love to gather with bearers of the priesthood of God and enjoy the worldwide brotherhood we share and cherish. A special spirit arises from the expectation we will be instructed in the plain and precious parts of the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p2" pid="FDOyrAxiFUCLjn20B0prTA" hash="QLOrCw">This evening my remarks will be directed to the young men of the Church. You who find yourselves in a different age category are welcome to listen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p3" pid="kEbsxoZA_Uy0wPNCkChlPQ" hash="QE7KcA">During this past Christmas season, news correspondent Walter Cronkite participated with the Tabernacle Choir and the Orchestra at Temple Square in their Christmas concert. “He … spent 19 years as the anchorman for the ‘CBS Evening News’ … [Mr. Cronkite] earned the reputation as ‘the most trusted man in America.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> When asked how he would want to be remembered, his response was, “Oh, as a fellow who did his best.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Over his distinguished career, Mr. Cronkite concluded each news report with the phrase, “And that’s the way it is.” Tonight, let’s talk about the way it is.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p4" pid="xuj1-Km0bECkTgS8eCfp5Q" hash="9D0P0Q">At a recent stake conference, the stake president shared a story with me. He asked his son what was discussed at a recent Sunday evening fireside. The young man replied, “Raising the bar.” He then informed his father he was weary of the theme because it was the subject of every recent class and meeting. My first thought was, “That’s great; the prophet’s message is being discussed, heard, and acted upon.” My second thought related to the young man’s feelings concerning repetitive reminders. Repetitive reminders can be an irritant when we are trying hard to do our best.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p5" pid="uc3E-Z4DZkSUDyVi5k0ywQ" hash="c43Mdw">As a youth I would tune out my mother’s repetitive reminder: “David, remember who you are.” The reminder always brought some interesting comments from my friends. Irritation set in when my father repeatedly pointed out President George Albert Smith’s home as we traveled along 13th East in Salt Lake City and reminded me that a living prophet of God who loved me lived there. Today I am most grateful for those repetitive reminders.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p6" pid="plFveUG2yUO7XLjm812snA" hash="8qdvCQ">The term “raising the bar” is often used in the world of sports to describe achieving higher levels of performance. The use of a sports metaphor may help describe why it is critical to respond to what President Hinckley asked us to do last conference when he said: “I hope that our young men, and our young women, will rise to the challenge [Elder Ballard] has set forth. We must raise the bar on the worthiness and qualifications of those who go into the world as ambassadors of the Lord Jesus Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p7" pid="96jSzD-Qu0ObE5aVqFHD0A" hash="yCretg">A year ago we experienced a wonderful Winter Olympics in Salt Lake City. For most Olympic events, athletes must attain minimum levels of achievement in order to qualify to compete. Our lives are similar to the Olympic qualification process in that we need to achieve and maintain standards in order to participate in the important <span class="emphasis">spiritual</span> events of life. World-class athletes have a disciplined daily routine. They master the skills demanded by their sport. Only then can they qualify to participate in the contest. And that’s the way it is.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p8" pid="c6OQfDI9yUWq2eYRTBX_Yw" hash="kFpdJg">Young men, if you want to be world class and qualified to be participants in the really important events of life like priesthood ordinations, blessings of the temple, and missionary service, you too must develop a disciplined daily routine of honesty, virtue, study, and prayer. And that’s the way it is.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p9" pid="O_eAfpJN3kayxdp0FhoIqQ" hash="yLTFKA">Olympians know and understand the <span class="emphasis">rules</span> that govern their sport. Broken rules can bring severe penalties and even disqualification. At the last Olympics, failure to observe rules associated with performance-enhancing drugs brought medal forfeiture. One of the harshest penalties levied on an athlete occurs in the game of golf. Just signing a scorecard with an incorrect score entered for any one of the 18 holes brings <span class="emphasis">disqualification.</span> There is <span class="emphasis">zero</span> tolerance. It doesn’t matter if the error benefits or hurts the individual; the penalty is the same—<span class="emphasis">disqualification.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p10" pid="akQL9zrNhU-0qNlG4E_mag" hash="6jld7Q">After more than 50 years, I can still hear the words of a tournament official: “Sorry, son, we must disqualify you for signing an incorrect scorecard.” My disqualification came as a result of my mentioning to the official that I needed to correct my score. For weeks I said to myself: “Why didn’t I remain silent? Besides, the error was an innocent mistake. The total score was correct.” Though my performance was good enough to find me in the winner’s circle, I left the awards presentation empty-handed. And that’s the way it is.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p11" pid="Cbi-fWMpdUuiKm7KUCnxOg" hash="A2bfIg">My young friends, rules are important, even critical. In life there are also penalties, perhaps even disqualification, if rules are broken. Our participation in life’s important events may be jeopardized if we fail to follow the rules contained in our Father in Heaven’s commands. Involvement in sexual sin, illegal drugs, civil disobedience, or abuse could keep us on the sidelines at key times. You would do well to view rules as <span class="emphasis">safety restraints,</span> not as <span class="emphasis">chains that bind. </span>Obedience builds strength. And that’s the way it is.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p12" pid="E-djzC6HykmZf-Yb6FPnvg" hash="WYP_Pw">In 1834 the Prophet Joseph Smith recorded, “No month ever found me more busily engaged than November; but as my life consisted of activity and unyielding exertions, I made this my rule: <span class="emphasis">When the Lord commands, do it.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p13" pid="VOn3_ca-3EOpptzwvZAudQ" hash="YSaUMg">For some, sports are a business. The difference between winning and losing can be a substantial amount of money. Athletes hire agents to handle their business affairs. Agents, personal trainers, coaches, and managers assist the athlete to enhance performance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p14" pid="yQmvgw5InkS1tEBEcw4M2Q" hash="355wFQ">Our Father in Heaven has provided His precious young sons with a superb support team more than equal to the one used by the athlete. Our parents make <span class="emphasis">superb agents.</span> They look after our interests. They are not only interested in us, but because they love us, they are terrific consultants as well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p15" pid="DF4yPFWljUWQjx0th_hq3Q" hash="5PIlOA">The Apostle Paul in teaching the Colossians said, “Children, obey your parents in all things: for this is well pleasing unto the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/col/3.20" class="scriptureRef">Col. 3:20</a>). In addition to our parents, think about the vast support network that has been provided to enhance our <span class="emphasis">spiritual</span> performance. Our bishops serve as <span class="emphasis">personal trainers</span> and use their sacred priesthood keys to bless our lives. Seminary teachers, quorum advisers, and home teachers round out the support team which has been assembled by the Lord to help us prepare for the big games of life. As you follow and obey, your performance will steadily improve. When the Lord commands, do it. And that’s the way it is.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p16" pid="5rPq372yx0SYkl8ciAiuvg" hash="ywXTrQ">One of the defining differences between the good and the great is what sports psychologists call “focus.” Competitors who have the ability to set aside the unimportant and be completely attentive to that which is critical are able to improve their performance. Focus is a critical success factor.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p17" pid="3plGrudKFE6Wc1zUA_jT8g" hash="BrEN0Q">I overheard a conversation between golfing great Arnold Palmer and a young caddie he was using for the first time. The young caddie, while handing Mr. Palmer his club, told him the distance to the flag was 165 yards, there was an unseen stream on the left, and a long and treacherous rough on the right. In a very kind but firm way, Mr. Palmer reminded the young man that the only information he required was the distance to the hole. He further suggested he didn’t want to lose focus by worrying about what was on the right or left.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p18" pid="h5izTFdKwE2Ef3FdptgcBw" hash="8Ta9iA">It is easy to lose sight of the really important objectives of life. There is much to distract us. Some are floundering in the water hazards on the left, and others are finding the long, treacherous rough on the right insurmountable. Safety and success come when focus is maintained on the important opportunities found by driving the ball straight down the middle—priesthood advancement, temple worthiness, and missionary service. And that’s the way it is.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is.p19" pid="ckdUmWGr-0i14RD-YGlIoQ" hash="mm11Sg">May our Father in Heaven bless each one of you. I testify to one and all that Jesus is the Christ. He lives, and His love for us is perfect. I’m grateful for a great prophet who helps us understand that when the Lord commands, do it, because that’s the way it is. In the name of our Savior and Redeemer, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2003/04/and-thats-the-way-it-is</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2003-general-conference/2003-04-3030-bishop-h-david-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5154136" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2003 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Holiness Give Me</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me?lang=eng</link>
      <description>It is important for families and individuals to aggressively seek more of the virtues which go beyond this mortal life.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030208_000_033" doc-version="2" hash="75JMYQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="owrTMnGvHEefEpGp8JU_1A" hash="SrQ3IA">More Holiness Give Me</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="zojoqgy-xkulvpoLSHQTcg" hash="XulAoA">H. David Burton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="5o9_NHgoA0S2fsTxrdLNQA" hash="Pc6DOg">It is important for families and individuals to aggressively seek more of the virtues which go beyond this mortal life.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-64d.jpg" alt="Bishop H. David Burton" pid="-0cRGU0FyUel4JUxDtTMdg" hash="onVBPw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p1" pid="x-VBmEyD1kG7MOazyx1FLQ" hash="LPSwEA">Sister Burton and I were interviewed prior to our marriage by Elder Richards’s father. We know of what Elder Richards has spoken in this session of conference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p2" pid="q-9mfdLFckGO6nLl2SFbeA" hash="KaeqXQ">At a recent stake conference, a young lady came up to me at the conclusion. As we were shaking hands, she said, “Bishop, you could improve your general conference talks by smiling.” I wanted to tell her about fear and smiling, but I didn’t have time. But I’ll try and hope for the best.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p3" pid="dOT3y2t0iEq9_ral3sDoLQ" hash="GBYeog">At the conclusion of every general conference, I experience a longing for more—more of the serenity of the occasion, more of the companionship of the Spirit, more of the nurturing that has brightened and blessed my soul.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p4" pid="sJCVC52UyE6Zzcm_IZi0mA" hash="L8WVFw">The current conventional wisdom is that more is better and less is usually undesirable. For some, the pursuit to acquire more of this world’s goods and services has become a passion. For others, more of this world’s wealth is necessary just to sustain life or raise living standards to a minimum level. The unbridled desire for more often has tragic consequences. For example, President Boyd K. Packer reminded us: “We could be like a father determined to provide everything for his family. He devotes every energy to that end and succeeds; only then does he discover that what they needed most, to be together as a family, has been neglected. And he reaps sorrow in place of contentment” (“Parents in Zion,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> Jan. 1999, 25; <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1998, 22).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p5" pid="jY7mMfOh5kqanzcH95alIg" hash="ytbRqg">Parents who have been successful in acquiring more often have a difficult time saying no to the demands of overindulged children. Their children run the risk of not learning important values like hard work, delayed gratification, honesty, and compassion. Affluent parents can and do raise well-adjusted, loving, and value-centered children, but the struggle to set limits, make do with less, and avoid the pitfalls of “more, more, more” has never been more difficult. It is hard to say no to more when you can afford to say yes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p6" pid="mcqmW1fFxkyb8hTebLsHPg" hash="QUtfKA">Parents are rightfully anxious about the future. It is difficult to say no to more sports equipment, electronics, lessons, clothes, team participation, et cetera, when parents believe more will help children thrive in an increasingly competitive world. Young people seem to want more, partly because there is infinitely more to catch their eye. The American Academy of Pediatrics estimated that American children see more than 40,000 commercials a year.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p7" pid="Bj-OPlJK_UK9Wb5rIPUwXw" hash="BHgy7w">Fewer and fewer parents ask their children to do chores around the house because they think they are already overwhelmed by social and academic pressures. But children devoid of responsibilities risk never learning that every individual can be of service and that life has meaning beyond their own happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p8" pid="95g9HCms2UyX5NdRUYJ4jw" hash="vLgIHg">In her book <span class="emphasis">My Grandfather’s Blessings,</span> Dr. Rachel Remen tells of becoming good friends with a couple and their young son, Kenny. When she visited, she would sit on the floor with Kenny and play with his two Hot Wheels cars. Sometimes she would have the one without a fender and he had the one with a door missing and sometimes vice versa. He loved those cars!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p9" pid="279WwQ2I2UanaylJXrJa8Q" hash="BGubyQ">When a gas station chain offered a Hot Wheels car with every fill-up, she recruited the staff at her clinic to go to that particular station and collect the cars. As soon as she had all of the models, she wrapped them in a big box to take to Kenny. She hoped she wouldn’t offend his parents, who lived quite meagerly. Kenny excitedly opened the big box and took out the cars one by one. They filled the windowsills and even extended to the floor. What a collection! Later, while visiting the family, Rachel noticed Kenny just staring out the window. When she asked Kenny, “What’s the matter? Don’t you like your new cars?” he looked down very sheepishly. “I’m sorry, Rachel. I guess I just don’t know how to love so many Hot Wheels.” (See “Owning” [2000], 60–61.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p10" pid="p9QdiYQGZkylA_LBNtP5jQ" hash="lNtFgQ">We have all heard children, after they have opened many Christmas or birthday gifts, say, “Isn’t there more?” With all the challenges present in this “more generation,” there remains divine counsel to teach our children “to understand the doctrine of repentance, faith in Christ the Son of the living God, and of baptism and the gift of the Holy Ghost, … to pray, and to walk uprightly before the Lord, … [and to] observe the Sabbath day [and] keep it holy” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.25,28-29" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:25, 28–29</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p11" pid="3X0oUfkyXUiaRgJ-DaSnQw" hash="D54Y9g">The meaning of <span class="emphasis">more</span> and <span class="emphasis">less</span> is not always crystal clear. There are times when less is in reality more and times when more can be less. For instance, less pursuit of materialism may enable more family togetherness. More indulgence of children may result in less understanding of life’s important values.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p12" pid="Blp_9Ckn20Gd9_zLbz1UAw" hash="D5bkEg">Some aspects of life can be significantly enhanced by the notion that more is better. The sacred hymn “More Holiness Give Me” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 131) brings to our remembrance the virtues worthy of more of our attention. Jesus Himself described what it requires to be “more, Savior, like thee.” He said, “I would that ye should be perfect even as I, or your Father who is in heaven is perfect” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/12.48" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 12:48</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p13" pid="S_9siLoMAE2cCpGoSW2Bhg" hash="C-WC6A">Meekness is vital to becoming more Christlike. Without it one cannot develop other important virtues. Mormon indicated, “None is acceptable before God, save the meek and lowly in heart” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.44" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:44</a>). Acquiring meekness is a process. We are asked to “take up [the] cross daily” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/9.23" class="scriptureRef">Luke 9:23</a>). Our lifting should not be an occasional exercise. More meekness does not translate to weakness, but “it is the presentation of self in a posture of <span class="emphasis">kindness</span> and <span class="emphasis">gentleness.</span> It reflects certitude, strength, serenity; it reflects a healthy self-esteem and a genuine self-control” (Neal A. Maxwell, “Meekly Drenched in Destiny,” in <span class="emphasis">Brigham Young University 1982–83 Fireside and Devotional Speeches</span> [1983], 2). More meekness will allow us to be tutored by the Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p14" pid="TBCVonlDYEqzLNdyyXeMvA" hash="VqoHUQ">The virtues expressed in “More Holiness Give Me” fall into several groups. Some are personal goals, like more holiness give me; more strivings within; more faith, gratitude, and purity; more fit for the kingdom; more purpose in prayer; and more trust in the Lord. Others center on adversity. They include patience in suffering, meekness in trial, praise for relief, strength to overcome, freedom from earth stains, and longing for home. The rest firmly anchor us to our Savior: more sense of His care; more pride in His glory; more hope in His word; more joy in His service; more tears for His sorrows; more pain at His grief; more blessed and holy; and more, Savior, like Thee. More of these virtues is better. Less is not desirable.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p15" pid="0hhbGWvosUqrL6K9x4m6TA" hash="Bl-Jtw">Many experience joy in His service by teaching the gospel of Jesus Christ and its Restoration and testifying of the Savior and His life, ministry, and Atonement.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p16" pid="i8XM0clMpEeiWNBAgYoVdw" hash="vP24tw">A missionary district leader was wondering why Elder Parker, who was about to conclude his mission, was successful in spite of his inability to memorize the discussions. To understand, he teamed with Elder Parker to give a discussion. Elder Parker’s presentation was so disorganized that by the end of the formal lesson, the district leader was confused and surmised that the family being taught felt the same way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p17" pid="djkWodkdkU6VCsa9RJIeyw" hash="_jqyAw">It was then that “Elder Parker leaned forward and put his hand on the arm of the family’s father. He then looked him straight in the eyes, told him how much he loved him and his family, and bore one of the most humble and powerful testimonies that the district leader had ever heard. By the time he finished, every member of the family, including the father, and both elders had tears running down their cheeks. Next Elder Parker taught the father how to pray, and they all knelt down while the father prayed that they might receive testimonies of their own and thanked Heavenly Father for the great love that he felt. Two weeks later the whole family was baptized.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p18" pid="ejtxe8fOgECGU1SNOvPW5Q" hash="Is7SVw">Later, Elder Parker apologized to his district leader for not knowing the discussions. He said he struggled with memorization, even though he spent hours each day working on it. He said he knelt in prayer before teaching each family and asked Heavenly Father to bless him when he bore his testimony so that people would feel his love and the Spirit and know they were being taught the truth (see Allan K. Burgess and Max H. Molgard, “That Is the Worst Lesson I’ve Ever Heard!” in <span class="emphasis">Sunshine for the Latter-day Saint Soul</span> [1998], 181–83).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p19" pid="fyyJ29KISk-0_tA7TQBmdw" hash="45QDmA">What can we glean from this simple story? Do you think Elder Parker felt the need to strive more to learn the discussions? Is it possible Elder Parker came to understand the need to offer prayers with a purpose? Do you suppose his prayers were laced with pleas to garner more strength to overcome? Might the inability to memorize have brought patience in suffering and meekness in trial? Did he demonstrate great faith in the Savior and trust in the Lord? Most certainly he did!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p20" pid="odqAfOxbT0yu3BvvjVovtQ" hash="kDpYkw">Over the last seven weeks, four major hurricanes have come ashore in Florida and along the Gulf of Mexico. Most nations of the Caribbean have experienced extensive devastation. Food, clothing, and shelter are in short supply. Large masses of debris clog roads and yards. Local infrastructure has been destroyed or needs major repair.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p21" pid="dA9G3j_PRUaL3LacoMWLIw" hash="JjqJXg">Last week I was in Tallahassee, Florida, and received many expressions of appreciation for the aid furnished by the Church during these emergencies. Florida Governor Bush, Lieutenant Governor Toni Jennings, partners like the Red Cross and Salvation Army, along with federal and state emergency personnel expressed gratitude that I pass on to you who performed the labor to ease the burden of cleanup and to those who have contributed to the Church’s Humanitarian Fund. Thank you. I trust you have felt more joy and more used in His service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p22" pid="lEEli--ArkaWDVM7AGxt-A" hash="yf_gtw">Following the pattern of previous weekends at different locations, over 2,000 volunteers from all over the southeastern United States gathered in Pensacola, Florida, last weekend to help with the aftermath of Hurricane Ivan. They rolled out their sleeping bags on meetinghouse floors, in other churches, and in members’ homes. They responded to thousands of work orders to assist wherever they were needed. Missionaries participated by covering the roof of the local Methodist church with the ever-present blue tarps. First responders, the firemen and the policemen, expressed appreciation that the Latter-day Saints had been assigned to help their families in their absence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p23" pid="YWgMh1hYq0yEASdJAcJB_g" hash="miWZiA">All of this was accomplished at the same time Hurricane Jeanne was coming ashore after causing much distress in Haiti and other Caribbean locations. Thanks again to those of you who give of your means and those whose hands have lightened the load of so many. I salute you for your desire to be more blessed and holy and more like the Savior. This weekend 2,500 will be helping with the aftermath of Hurricane Jeanne.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me.p24" pid="VOcG9HzWHUKS1lFo9zIMnw" hash="aIu1Ww">In discussing our various longings for more, I’m not suggesting we adopt Scrooge as a role model for good parenting. I am suggesting that it is important for families and individuals to aggressively seek more of the virtues which go beyond this mortal life. A prayerful, conservative approach is the key to successfully living in an affluent society and building the qualities that come from waiting, sharing, saving, working hard, and making do with what we have. May we be blessed with the desire and the ability to understand when more is really less and when more is better. In the holy name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2004/10/more-holiness-give-me</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2004-general-conference/2004-10-5050-bishop-h-david-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="7091399" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2004 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tender Hearts and Helping Hands</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands?lang=eng</link>
      <description>To each of you whose tender hearts and helping hands have eased the burdens of so many, please accept my heartfelt gratitude.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006561_000_004" doc-version="3" hash="b1NL6A"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="3mb47SeVh0Gz3Tnu24hsaQ" hash="6PbZhA">Tender Hearts and Helping Hands</h1><p class="authorName" uuid="844716ff-979f-4db2-ac5e-a83949fd2437" pid="HXxvMdw5P0iyZ4bSujyYGA" hash="XulAoA">H. David Burton</p><p class="kicker" pid="1UUoYIT3VkeNRcdiXhxcQw" hash="sjapKA">To each of you whose tender hearts and helping hands have eased the burdens of so many, please accept my heartfelt gratitude.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" uuid="7889e79c-c700-488f-83e9-672fda3fdbb0">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.t1" uuid="">
      <img src="en2006lp.nfo-o-c9.jpg" alt="Bishop H. David Burton" uuid="1fb8b7f0-5a99-4268-bc8e-fd400db097ee" pid="5l1a4YNldkeAWdBpEjAfBg" hash="UIsUGg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p1" uuid="bc6feccc-075e-49c4-8bed-4639105d4630" pid="h2cmG0KaZky9iinnlSDUKQ" hash="GCFdHQ">Last evening Sister Burton and I were enjoying a little Chinese food. Embedded in my fortune cookie was the message, “The stress you are experiencing will soon be relieved.” True story.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p2" uuid="8db2ac1c-ada4-45c1-8a36-f0564901fd04" pid="v-sD4xS1WkGd9p2kivqbQQ" hash="GH4K5w">A group of men were talking with the Prophet Joseph Smith one day when news arrived that the house of a poor brother who lived some distance from town was burned down. Everyone expressed sorrow for what had happened. The Prophet listened for a moment, then “put his hand in his pocket, took out five dollars and said, ‘I feel sorry for this brother to the amount of five dollars; how much do you all feel sorry?’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> The immediacy of the Prophet’s response is significant. Last year millions of you responded to the sorrow of others with your means, tender hearts, and helping hands. Thank you for your wonderful measure of generosity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p3" uuid="57736844-0341-48e5-aedd-f61b85d2e416" pid="n3A15xqqzkyopW29yXzj-A" hash="8c9RDQ">Compassion for others has always been a fundamental characteristic of members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. The prophet Alma said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p4" uuid="9f3a9abd-abbe-4f8e-a646-ea85667f0b8f" pid="sVrvg_QhA06wZC0wrVoFiA" hash="wFMqQw">“Ye are desirous to come into the fold of God, and to be called his people, and are willing to bear one another’s burdens, that they may be light; yea, and are willing to mourn with those that mourn; yea, and comfort those that stand in need of comfort.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p5" uuid="8b043d11-2c53-410f-b7cd-eb0de393db11" pid="lIJ5SGDAaEqc0jlCsNBX0g" hash="xNQt2w">The Savior asks us to “succor the weak, lift up the hands which hang down, and strengthen the feeble knees.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p6" uuid="b3ec55a6-9557-47b0-a857-b4db626fe7b3" pid="7ZUOv_4ZK06acapKBCVNFw" hash="98jGVQ">I have witnessed firsthand the commitment of Latter-day Saints and others not of our faith who have tender hearts and helping hands, who “bear … one another’s burdens.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> I have been deeply sorrowed as I have seen massive devastation and visited victims who are without hope.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p7" uuid="91b2eae9-f5c5-45ba-b241-c9ebf6250a33" pid="tUjOYo48REKRz_iG5XkiEg" hash="HwzouQ">In recent years, Mother Nature has displayed her vengeance and supremacy in unusual and powerful ways. Late December 2004 brought a terrible earthquake off the coast of Indonesia creating a deadly tsunami that killed thousands and shattered the lives of those who remained behind. Under the direction of local priesthood leaders and adult missionary couples, help was mobilized immediately, providing urgent assistance to hospitals, first responders, and communities in Indonesia, Sri Lanka, India, and Thailand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p8" uuid="9d22430d-1cf1-454d-a945-4a4f82cdac31" pid="8urR9vgF6kSXZItHAaD3nQ" hash="fInRkg">Within a short time, several Church members traveled to one of the hardest-hit areas—Aceh region in northern Sumatra. Sister Bertha Suranto, a district Young Women president from Jakarta, Indonesia, and her associates drove trucks filled with needed items that would save lives and provide comfort to those who had lost so much.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p9" uuid="4ae31d40-a32f-4898-a674-9e54f0852fc6" pid="g6D7R4tO6UCB0osQ3s1cbg" hash="PMjYOA">“Every time we came into a village,” Bertha said, “the people surrounded us and offered food to distribute—even when they only had a little rice and some fish they had caught in the ocean. From the mosques, community leaders announced that another donation from the Jesus church had arrived.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p10" uuid="87c9a801-d891-4efb-a207-3e9a8a1223c0" pid="zpm7gV3mjkaBUs-HZAUumg" hash="cq4ERg">As immediate needs were met, longer-term projects were undertaken. Plans to assist in building well over a thousand permanent houses and restoring hospitals and schools are being implemented. Villagers were assisted in replacing fishing boats and nets. Looms and sewing machines were distributed to help families return to self-reliance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p11" uuid="cf8a526e-2d34-45e6-9e79-b715e70ec70c" pid="utlwasoIzEeAm926HbiHgQ" hash="JC7n8A">Northern Pakistan and India experienced the strongest earthquake in the region in a hundred years, with thousands of lives lost and many left without homes. Because of the extreme winters in the area, concern was extended not only for the injured but also for those left without shelter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p12" uuid="01b1821e-7381-45ca-bc56-b6690a186c4d" pid="iH87wE6A0k6hkOMSqERIjQ" hash="_M3l5w">Four days after the earthquake, the Islamic Relief Agency provided a Boeing 747 cargo plane, which was quickly filled to capacity with blankets, tents, hygiene kits, medical supplies, sleeping bags, coats, and tarps from the bishops’ storehouse. Large containers with more supplies and winter tents for over 75,000 people were shipped by air, land, and sea.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p13" uuid="35c8ba82-5402-41b7-8fef-d8a288fe21d5" pid="s183-4ork02q7YUXnIou7g" hash="2AAN6A">When floods hit Central America, meetinghouses were opened to provide temporary shelter for evacuees. In areas where vehicles couldn’t go, Church members strapped supplies upon their backs and walked over flooded streams and treacherous terrain to bring relief to those in distress.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p14" uuid="5003f2a9-00c7-4b13-84a9-3c6ea3cf780b" pid="chq2jQxz9EWrNKmZuI7MEg" hash="rloofQ">Following a period of civil unrest in the Sudan, more than a million people have fled their homes and villages, seeking safety. Many refugees walked hundreds of miles through unfriendly terrain to arrive at refugee camps, seeking to reconnect with their families and regain their health.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p15" uuid="7ef55f97-c167-4e3c-b952-65c5ccbe0f09" pid="fuBO6lNI4Eq3_u2IAGag_Q" hash="XLeIyA">Atmit, a vitamin-fortified porridge that has proven effective in saving the lives of starving children and the elderly, was provided. Medical supplies and thousands of hygiene and newborn kits were also supplied.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p16" uuid="bd67dd99-c8fa-43b3-bc36-87d587aaf73c" pid="hp5nXqzcikOcJRlKadP13A" hash="8sq5kg">The Church has joined with other prominent charitable organizations to help vaccinate millions of African children in a campaign to eradicate measles. Two thousand faithful African Church members volunteered many hours in advertising, gathering children, and providing help as the shots were given.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p17" uuid="9ba0b443-1107-455e-8957-044da03631da" pid="2sQNFSskY0m3FAGllpjayw" hash="_QbUxw">The 2005 hurricane season in the southern United States and the western Caribbean was the costliest and most devastating on record. Storm after storm lashed at homes and businesses from Honduras to Florida. Thousands of priesthood-directed volunteers were there each time a hurricane struck, providing the necessities to sustain life. Hygiene and cleaning kits, food, water, kitchen sets, bed linen, and other commodities helped clean homes and establish temporary housing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p18" uuid="2b4beed0-d16e-46e0-971e-82029ca28b60" pid="C1ncF4zjFEWQzGE55be_lA" hash="cpd8Fw">Brother Michael Kagle took a convoy of trucks loaded with equipment from his own company to Mississippi. Many employees, who are not of our faith, volunteered to go with him every weekend to give assistance in the storm-stricken areas. Walkie-talkies were used for communication along the way. Mike’s high priests group leader, while driving along with them in his pickup truck, said he had white knuckles from driving so fast. Trying to slow the convoy down, he got on the walkie-talkie and said, “Gentlemen, do you realize we are going 80 miles per hour?” One of the truck drivers came on and said, “Well, you have to understand that’s all these big trucks will do. We can’t go any faster.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p19" uuid="e694fa70-3b8d-4d3c-a6f3-f0aa72a83cd7" pid="RyJIsTVkGUSMHxLH37JHpg" hash="XaaW4g">Hundreds of letters of gratitude have been received. One woman, a nurse from Mississippi, wrote: “I was speechless. Had God answered my prayers so quickly? Tears immediately began to roll down my cheeks as men in hard hats and boots, with chainsaws of all shapes and sizes, appeared out of the debris. It was absolutely, unequivocally, one of the most supreme sacrifices that has ever happened to me personally.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p20" uuid="9dbd4d6a-f25b-4b14-827f-1cc9016389a7" pid="1NgV95www0eeeZEdhoioQA" hash="Z6ZHJw">May I express thanks to the nimble fingers that have produced thousands of beautiful blankets and a special thanks to the not-so-nimble fingers of our more senior sisters who have also crafted the much-needed quilts. One 92-year-old great-grandmother has produced several hundred blankets. In her case, both the creator and receiver have been blessed. As her son admired her handiwork, she asked, “Do you think anyone will ever use one of my blankets?” A letter from a young mother in Louisiana answers that question:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p21" uuid="936f0b21-2d98-44ed-8fb7-60645407c22e" pid="xG1gpAO6X0S0d_qZYz8xUw" hash="4jvtaw">“I live in Louisiana, and I go to a local health unit for my children. While I was there, they gave me some outfits, diapers, wipes, and two beautiful baby blankets. One blanket has a yellow backing with footprints and handprints on the front, and the other blanket is tan with zebras. They are beautiful. My four-year-old loves the zebra one, and of course my seven-month-old can’t say much. I just wanted to say thank you to you and your Church members for your generosity. God bless you and your family.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p22" uuid="1b44f826-dda4-46d4-90cb-c703545746d4" pid="HSALEny2vEW5Yjqd6-UBSw" hash="naOr8Q">In response to the recent mudslides in the Philippines, the Saints in the area assembled hygiene kits and food boxes and distributed these with blankets to those in need.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p23" uuid="7b8456fb-49a8-4f5d-b8e4-3be2ca6f2602" pid="9QLS01YtrkqTrH6Q6QWjjA" hash="8X4ksQ">Welfare principles of work and self-reliance are maintained and taught as relief is given throughout the world. During 2005 many villages received clean water through new wells. Villagers were taught how to dig wells, install pumps, and make repairs when needed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p24" uuid="8cacf078-115d-4c78-bf10-beaede528c92" pid="2DhVLKxCh0iZrtrB-KF9Uw" hash="9LfH9Q">Training and equipment provided by local volunteers and ever-so-devoted missionary couples allow families to supplement their diets with homegrown, nutritious food.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p25" uuid="59be0569-7248-40b3-8cd5-f6a25d20b429" pid="Y9qlASSUREaY3_7dx5elKw" hash="heDQWg">Many wheelchairs have been supplied that allow the disabled to become self-reliant. Thousands of medical personnel have been trained to save the lives of newborns. Medical professionals have performed cataract surgery, restoring the vision of many. Tender counseling has been provided worldwide by LDS Family Services.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p26" uuid="609c3235-9989-424d-b3df-0059cbdc74a8" pid="NT5A4z5M5ESuGZtRoRAWcw" hash="vvG5WQ">Bridges of understanding and respect have been built in many nations as we collaborate with other established and trusted agencies.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p27" uuid="3bfcacb4-a111-4da6-af17-f6ebdcb7fa41" pid="KGK4w8-ctEKaReRGUIKctQ" hash="7YTfJw">Dr. Simbi Mubako, former African ambassador to the United States, has said, “The work of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is all the more impressive because it is not limited to just the members of the Church, but it spreads to all human beings of different cultures and different religions because [they] see in every person the image of Jesus Christ.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p28" uuid="c30530f1-00ed-4253-ae45-e07bf9fca29e" pid="AXOfuBpi9UiIZxiPjN8iyg" hash="ARdPkA">Our beloved President Gordon B. Hinckley has been instrumental in the development of this great humanitarian work. “We must reach out to all mankind,” he has said. “They are all sons and daughters of God our Eternal Father, and He will hold us accountable for what we do concerning them. … May we bless humanity with an outreach to all, lifting those who are downtrodden and oppressed, feeding and clothing the hungry and the needy, extending love and neighborliness to those about us who may not be part of this Church.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p29" uuid="40fde24e-7b19-429c-b693-f795bb8274a4" pid="304GApZfjUSk1qxaDTqFIg" hash="QBdjhw">This modern-day humanitarian effort is a wonderful manifestation of the charity that burns within the souls of those whose hearts are tender and whose hands are ready to help. This selfless service truly demonstrates the pure love of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p30" uuid="e05ad196-0f5b-4712-b3da-e54e5ff72cd4" pid="grF4Aex4IEi7R9pbTCVfsQ" hash="uLpoIg">The Savior promises great blessings to those who give of themselves: “Give, and it shall be given unto you. … For with the same measure that ye mete withal it shall be measured to you again.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p31" uuid="1b20ce67-d447-4b39-87b7-1e95c46c14a1" pid="8do8k3exwUmaqdJX_vFAxg" hash="YfT5jQ">The things I have spoken of today are not even a hundredth part of what is happening in villages and nations throughout the world. Everywhere I travel, expressions of profound gratitude are received. On behalf of the First Presidency, the Quorum of the Twelve, and the Church Welfare Executive Committee, whose assignment it is to guide this work, may I express our deepest appreciation and admiration.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands.p32" uuid="2b60d293-29e0-440d-b15e-fd980c508753" pid="N3e_9bYNV0i2i-aosMrtVA" hash="1U4zPQ">It is impossible for me to find the words to adequately express the sacred feelings burning within my soul. The simple word <span class="emphasis">thanks</span> seems almost trite. To each of you whose tender hearts and helping hands have eased the burdens of so many, please accept my heartfelt gratitude. I invoke the Lord’s choicest blessings to be with you and your families as you continue to remember those with heavy hearts and hands that hang down, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/04/tender-hearts-and-helping-hands</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2006-general-conference/2006-04-1020-bishop-h-david-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="7132977" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If These Old Walls Could Talk</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk?lang=eng</link>
      <description>For more than a century, words of the latter-day prophets, seers, and revelators have gone forth from this podium to the world.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008333_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="CIir8g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="uPvNhfxUWkC40jMnmq5qlQ" hash="mJzh8g">If These Old Walls Could Talk</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="fV8OhSLhq0eUSrDweFjFfw" hash="XulAoA">H. David Burton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="NSz4kNT6ukKMcQ2VIiE_pQ" hash="An-QUg">For more than a century, words of the latter-day prophets, seers, and revelators have gone forth from this podium to the world.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.t1">
      <img src="BurtonHD_all.ob.jpg" alt="Bishop H. David Burton" pid="WAswdUExR02782b8uNZgIA" hash="qavAfA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p1" pid="U7Vzg39zaUusakwlJlANUg" hash="o1uqcw">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="32"></span>President Gordon B. Hinckley said in an October 2004 press conference: “I respect this building. I love this building. I honor this building. I want it preserved. … I want the old original Tabernacle, its weak joints bound together … and strengthened and its natural and wonderful beauty preserved.” Then he looked at me and said, “Don’t you do anything you shouldn’t do, but whatever you do, do well and do right.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p2" pid="P1YOuwMAMEqSNXSshK4-uQ" hash="QrTAKw">With those stirring but intimidating words, a charge was extended to preserve, strengthen, and return the old original Salt Lake Tabernacle, revitalized and ready for another period of distinguished service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p3" pid="A3rfbQsl7Ey1cRJWLjMmcA" hash="o_GtLA">Today, dear President, we present this senior citizen of a building, all attired in a fresh new finish, fitly framed together in its historical elegance—although a bit more comfortable. The Presiding Bishopric, along with more than 2,000 craftsmen, proudly return the “old original Tabernacle,” along with a 100-year warranty.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p4" pid="0X8n91HF50eH6iq9bcqr_w" hash="jl5PBg">President Hinckley’s request to return the “old original Tabernacle” became the standard for making difficult architectural and construction decisions. The phrase was used to express the essence and objective of the project. It served as the equivalent of Captain Moroni’s title of liberty in that it was, in effect, “hoisted upon every tower” and raised in “whatsoever place”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> was necessary.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p5" pid="2US63bbbU0WX8GnkemsKzg" hash="4oS8Hw">If these old walls could talk, they would join in expressing sincere appreciation to FFKR Architects, Jacobsen Construction company, and most important, the entire Church project team, along with the many whose skills have made a complex endeavor possible. One senior team member remarked, “As we counseled together, the Lord was able to give us capability beyond our own natural means.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p6" pid="aR20voSBGECqU2YdWpwvCg" hash="erMcuA">Project members felt great reverence for the beauty of the Tabernacle, for its original builders, and for the quality of their work. They marveled that for more than a century, words of the latter-day prophets, seers, and revelators have gone forth from this podium to the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p7" pid="7idnFMtwgEG8sUeJYgeqKQ" hash="6Yofaw">If these old walls could talk, I’m confident they would express appreciation for their new firm foundation. These old walls would be delighted with their new steel belt, which holds them tall and erect. These old walls would say thank you for scraping 14 layers of paint from the ceiling, then patching and applying a beautiful new coat.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p8" pid="wL8INZUdC0aE-iSlKqhrRA" hash="MB1zNQ">These old walls would express gratitude for the protection and beauty of a shiny new aluminum roof and would join with the benches in enjoying the smiles on faces of patrons as they discover the slightly modified seats and a few more inches of knee room.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p9" pid="DJqi9FGYo0-hihqdgW8IFg" hash="POoLsg">New facilities to better accommodate the strains of inspirational music would be welcomed and appreciated by these old walls.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p10" pid="a6gmJASAEEmWW-JJ3AdUnQ" hash="bAfE8Q">One can only imagine what these old walls could recall about the many sermons they carefully listened to over the years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p11" pid="Rf_t_LTDQk2azb58qhj_NQ" hash="WqK5sQ">These old walls, if they could talk, would shout, “We were here!” when President Joseph F. Smith rose from a prolonged illness to attend a session of general conference in October 1918. In the opening session, with a voice filled with emotion, he said, “I will not, I dare not, attempt to enter upon many things that are resting upon my mind this morning, and I shall postpone until some future time, the Lord being willing, my attempt to tell you some of the things that are in my mind, and that dwell in my heart.” He continued: “I have not lived alone these five months. I have dwelt in the spirit of prayer, of supplication, of faith <span class="pageBreak" page-number="33"></span>and of determination; and I have had my communication with the Spirit of the Lord continuously.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> We later learned that on the day before conference started, President Smith received a manifestation recorded as the vision of the redemption of the dead, which later became section 138 of the Doctrine and Covenants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p12" pid="4gGXPl4pC0G4gsV1B6lhuA" hash="sCasaA">If these old walls could talk, they would remind us of the bleak, dark days of the Great Depression. They would recall the April 1936 general conference, when President Heber J. Grant announced the Church would inaugurate a Church security plan, later known as the Church welfare plan. Six months later he explained: “Our primary purpose was to set up … a system under which the curse of idleness would be done away with, the evils of a dole abolished, and in-dependence, industry, thrift and self respect be once more established amongst our people. The aim of the Church is to help the people to help themselves. Work is to be re-enthroned as the ruling principle of the lives of our Church membership.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p13" pid="frNdT4f1Vkq9cefNFz-mpw" hash="nbivMw">In October 1964, by assignment from President David O. McKay, Elder Harold B. Lee spoke about parental responsibilities. These old walls remember Elder Lee stating he would read from a 1915 letter to the Church signed by the First Presidency. But before starting, he remarked, “I suppose it is something like Mark Twain said about the weather: ‘We talk a lot about the weather, but we don’t seem to do anything about it.’” Elder Lee then read from the 50-year-old letter:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p14" pid="ZepN9S3duE-W9hJ-iHqY0g" hash="GY981g">“We advise and urge the inauguration of a ‘Home Evening’ throughout the Church, at which time father and mother may gather their boys and girls about them in the home, and teach them the word of the Lord.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p15" pid="1_ahLuu8oEyG1NXuAFbz9w" hash="0Pg-lA">And then this promise:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p16" pid="H9dNY_X_i0yK2NbKvZB46w" hash="GvNrYg">“If the Saints obey this counsel, we promise that great blessings will result. Love at home and obedience to parents will increase. Faith will be developed in the hearts of the youth of Israel, and they will gain power to combat the evil influences and temptations which beset them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p17" pid="ploIYMaVMkGPac0eUjlTcA" hash="yHu3Gw">These old walls remember the profound silence that came over the Tabernacle in 1985 when it was announced that Elder Bruce R. McConkie would address the conference. These old walls felt a deep spirit of reverence as Elder McConkie concluded his remarks with these electrifying words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p18" pid="p508bFCz20yr5mW_l3Tpcg" hash="m-_lXg">“And now, as pertaining to this perfect atonement, wrought by the shedding of the blood of God—I testify that it took place in Gethsemane and at Golgotha, and as pertaining to Jesus Christ, I testify that he is the Son of the Living God and was crucified for the sins of the world. He is our Lord, our God, and our King. This I know of myself independent of any other person.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p19" pid="ZxREdPcwpE-UosDZsKd91g" hash="dgULIQ">“I am one of his witnesses, and in a coming day I shall feel the nail marks in his hands and in his feet and shall wet his feet with my tears.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p20" pid="ruzaXTzUtk2NaUzWzWLegg" hash="rqwdkA">“But I shall not know any better then than I know now that he is God’s Almighty Son, that he is our Savior and Redeemer, and that salvation comes in and through his atoning blood and in no other way.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p21" pid="to5VeNeozka0yuOXFxoQ4Q" hash="eDZQ-Q">In 1995 President Gordon B. Hinckley said to the women of the Church, “With so much of sophistry <span class="pageBreak" page-number="34"></span>that is passed off as truth, with so much of deception concerning standards and values, with so much of allurement and enticement to take on the slow stain of the world, we have felt to warn and forewarn.” He then proceeded to read:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p22" pid="YMqeTmDI4UCbJ9qxSVPWxw" hash="vwp05w">“We, the First Presidency and the Council of the Twelve Apostles of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, solemnly proclaim that marriage between a man and a woman is ordained of God and that the family is central to the Creator’s plan for the eternal destiny of His children. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p23" pid="qjiMCYMJf0i26caOMskVGw" hash="dOPIlQ">“Husband and wife have a solemn responsibility to love and care for each other and for their children. ‘Children are an heritage of the Lord’ (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/127.3" class="scriptureRef">Psalms 127:3</a>). Parents have a sacred duty to rear their children in love and righteousness, to provide for their physical and spiritual needs, to teach them to love and serve one another, to observe the commandments of God and to be law-abiding citizens wherever they live. Husbands and wives—mothers and fathers—will be held accountable before God for the discharge of these obligations.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk.p24" pid="lqMIfCHjmkacvvknZY-gJA" hash="X_IFOQ">I’m grateful for this extraordinary building. It stands as a sacred monument to our past and a magnificent ensign of hope for the future. I testify to the divinity of our Father in Heaven and of our Savior’s abundant love for each of us. We are greatly blessed to be led by a prophet of God. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/04/if-these-old-walls-could-talk</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2007-general-conference/2007-04-2030-bishop-h-david-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5286039" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2007 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>And Who Is My Neighbor?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We express our deep appreciation to the many individuals … who are the good Samaritans of today.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00009475_000_020" doc-version="2" hash="1wBssA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="WRQd3A-3NU-yQAdMMLqclg" hash="X8vwJQ">And Who Is My Neighbor?</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="tR24mX0H102JZ5BMwm-3eA" hash="9iAu-Q">Bishop H. David Burton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="rjaYq1-ihUCzL6-PQoBI5g" hash="TNtUPQ">We express our deep appreciation to the many individuals … who are the good Samaritans of today.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.p1" pid="K3Rhu5iHF0-Z5sHhf31g3Q" hash="rYTl7w">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="51"></span>Good evening. Tonight the scripture passages “As ye have done it unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.40" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 25:40</a>) and “Remember in all things the poor and the needy” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/52.40" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 52:40</a>) take on special meaning as we review highlights of humanitarian endeavors during the past year.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.p2" pid="G69Vc4wOEkigooK2qmciVg" hash="iRKs7w">A briefing on humanitarian assistance was recently given to the General Welfare Committee of the Church. The committee chair, then President Gordon B. Hinckley, expressed profound gratitude for the generosity of members and those not of our faith who have made this outreach possible. In behalf of the General Welfare Committee, we express our deep appreciation to the many individuals, families, quorums, and Relief Society and Young Women groups who are the good Samaritans of today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.p3" pid="2D77f41ekkaWzt_CZ0Ssgg" hash="SbCmRg">In 2007 the Church responded to major earthquakes in 5 countries, massive fires in 6 countries, hunger and famine in 18 countries, and flooding and severe storms in 34 countries. In total the Church and its members responded to 170 major events—nearly one every two days for the entire year. It was a busy year with many opportunities to serve.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.p4" pid="cTR2_1UeXkm9BPZ8YJRaBQ" hash="goeqUA">In addition to responding to natural disasters, we undertook thousands of public health initiatives during the year. Over 1 million people benefited from Church-sponsored clean water projects in 25 countries. More than 60,500 people received wheelchairs in 60 nations. Early this year Sister Burton and I, with the South America North Area Presidency, participated with the First Lady of Colombia in a wheelchair presentation. Tears came easily as receivers and their caregivers expressed their appreciation. In 11 countries, over 54,000 individuals now enjoy improved vision. Over 16,500 health-care professionals in 23 countries were trained in infant neonatal resuscitation; they, in turn, will train many others. In a quest to eliminate measles, 2.8 million children and youth in 10 countries received immunizations. The combined effects of these outreach endeavors directly touched nearly 4 million people in 85 countries.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.p5" pid="PD6ibrUG2EOd5xGoogGL1g" hash="sWDATQ">In August a major 8.0 earthquake killed 520 people and destroyed more than 58,000 homes in southern Peru. In a marvelous display of love and concern, each of the 29 stakes in Lima, Peru, provided basic assistance to ward areas in the devastated region.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.p6" pid="tb_gkLGfIUyuG00OpQnktw" hash="yUMZ9g">With the wonderful assistance of missionaries, a plan is under way to help individuals rebuild their homes and lives and replace several schools. As many as 400 homes may ultimately be built, with individuals, friends, and family doing much of the work. Supervision, coordination, and training are under the direction of Elder and Sister Alan Layton.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.p7" pid="MBOJeBaGn0qEIt2IMuRwFw" hash="mnpEUw">Late in the year a combination of dry weather and high winds fueled wildfires in southern California. These wildfires forced over one million people from their homes. At least 1,500 homes were destroyed. In response the Church provided cleaning kits, blankets, hygiene kits, and food. Over 5,000 Mormon Helping Hands along with missionaries cleaned, cooked, comforted, and cared for those affected.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.p8" pid="-knB-Fh87EmU_U2nFeKOfw" hash="i9eCpQ">One note of appreciation said: “Please forward a great big thank you to all the Latter-day Saints who have been working so hard in my neighborhood. The Mormons have been here constantly with meals, hugs, prayers, and helping to repair and clear property. They … uplift my community, heal hearts, and repair homes in the San Diego hills.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.p9" pid="PQkGrdLWt0G4TZqi_wmV6A" hash="d1jvYw">Reflecting on the experience, one stake president said: “One of our projects was to assist cleaning up around the local Baptist church. … <span class="pageBreak" page-number="52"></span>We assigned 25 youth. … The Baptists said that they would have lots of donuts and coffee for us. We told them the coffee would go stale, but our youth could handle as many donuts as they could provide!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.p10" pid="c7ngV14CjEuybTzHfGwOKA" hash="W6E-Ew">Heavy rains triggered flooding across the midwestern United States, Oregon, and Washington. Volunteers came with supplies from the bishops’ storehouse to provide help to those in need.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.p11" pid="wJmvcEsCYki26Nlusi0O-Q" hash="od5TLg">When Church representatives in Findlay, Ohio, presented a donation to the local Red Cross chapter, a passerby spotted them in their yellow Mormon Helping Hands T-shirts. She walked in and held up her camera phone with a picture of four Helping Hands and exclaimed, “They just saved my home!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Then she hugged everyone in sight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.p12" pid="1xDWBgGp-U2Rwf-EX4b89A" hash="93rQUQ">A shipment of food was delivered to a local food bank. When it arrived, the manager had a startled look on his face and said, “How did you know? I just gave out my last loaf of bread and planned to lock the doors. How did you know?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.p13" pid="BMUbTrIVEkSno2oWJ4wt8g" hash="zgiiOw">Working with the World Health Organization to eliminate measles as a killer of almost a million children each year, over 54,000 Church members volunteered to help organize the effort. A Church member in Nigeria wrote: “I called our labor the ‘rescue of the innocent.’ We went house to house and village hall to village hall. A woman told us she had lost three children to measles. She told her story with such grace and passion that there was not a dry eye in the house, mine included.” Our volunteer observed, “The things you do for yourself are gone when you are gone, but the things that you do for others remain as your legacy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.p14" pid="YAkZrhW6xkaURwD1zfAmiw" hash="VtYFTA">Our four-year effort to help those devastated by a tsunami in Indonesia and southern Asia also continued. Funding was provided to help build 902 homes, with 3 community centers, 24 village water systems, 15 schools, and 3 medical centers. A community leader said: “Community members feel happy and blessed to have the community center. … It is a place [where] we can pray … and teach the children. … Thank you to [the Church] for building this center for our people. … We will pray to God to give [the Church] blessings and success in the future. Thank you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.p15" pid="mFye1V55Bk2dOciTl32O8A" hash="f3cJgQ">In Ethiopia, communities helped to access clean drinking water. The Church drilled wells and constructed storage tanks. Communities organized a water committee and dug the trenches needed to pipe the water from the storage tanks to each village. In some cases this was a distance of over three miles (5 km).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.p16" pid="7OFvILGX3USfapAvXW4Eew" hash="vyC7RA">Some communities struggled to meet their commitments for trenching. The soil was hard, dry, and full of clay, making digging very difficult. In one community a school of 1,500 students suspended normal school activities for a period of time, and everyone participated in digging the remaining sections of the trench. As they worked, other members of the community joined in. At one point there was over a mile-long line of people digging.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor.p17" pid="zgdPFq-s-EW8g96D5eUSvg" hash="ONk17g">Thank you for your compassion, your goodness, and your generosity. May we press forward to lighten the load of neighbors, encourage and assist the downtrodden, open our purses to assist the poor, and extend our helping hands. I bear witness of the divinity of the Lord Jesus Christ and His gospel and pray that we may continue to enjoy the blessings of true discipleship as we quietly reach out to others. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2008/04/and-who-is-my-neighbor</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2008-general-conference/2008-04-3020-bishop-h-david-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="4642563" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2008 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let Virtue Garnish Your Thoughts</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We need to stand tall and be firmly fixed in perpetuating Christlike virtues.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50019113_000_026" doc-version="2" hash="mXImtQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="zKezv-eYFk6uGuIWbAuEWw" hash="L76YJQ">Let Virtue Garnish Your Thoughts</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="L1EyVMgSVkSPlYTsJYvInA" hash="XulAoA">H. David Burton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="DSqd15dMok2ibATHlk3Wrg" hash="wbhnWA">We need to stand tall and be firmly fixed in perpetuating Christlike virtues.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.p1" pid="7sY6cnDtIkuRiAQyImFoUg" hash="kx7mlA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="76"></span>Thank you, Elder Pace, for that beautiful invocation, for listeners and speakers particularly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.p2" pid="4tnf5lhrfk692t-l5LBvCQ" hash="XeFzJA">“Let virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly; then shall thy confidence wax strong in the presence of God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.45" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:45</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.p3" pid="64P95aDXd0av7bf9_k0rLg" hash="tis5Cw">As I neared my 12th birthday, there were several requirements to be completed before I could graduate from Primary. One was to recite the thirteen Articles of Faith in the prescribed order. The first twelve articles were relatively easy, but the thirteenth was much more difficult. It was remembering the order of the virtues that presented the challenge. Thanks to a Primary teacher who was patient and persistent, I finally completed the memorization.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.p4" pid="1C71zew0iEqzVVmj-hCElg" hash="aNPVhw">Years later my wife and children and I moved into our first home. We were surprised to learn that my former Primary teacher would be our neighbor. For the 40 years we have lived in the same neighborhood, she has kept our little secret concerning my learning disability.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.p5" pid="qjVHxpSAKUyDG66HSDyA2g" hash="Obl-9w">“We believe in being honest, true, chaste, benevolent, virtuous, and in doing good to all men; indeed, we may say that we follow the admonition of Paul—We believe all things, we hope all things, we have endured many things, and hope to be able to endure all things. If there is anything virtuous, lovely, or of good report or praiseworthy, we seek after these things” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/a-of-f/1.13" class="scriptureRef">Articles of Faith 1:13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.p6" pid="WTwX1lbum0mldagZRRzP7g" hash="T8X1ig">Today I wish to speak about personal traits we call virtues. Virtuous traits form the foundation of a Christian life and are the outward manifestation of the inner man. The spelling in English of many individual virtues concludes with the letters <span class="emphasis">ity:</span> integrity, humility, charity, spirituality, accountability, civility, fidelity, and the list goes on and on. Relying on literary license, I refer to the virtues ending in <span class="emphasis">ity</span> as the “ity” virtues. “Ity” is a suffix that means quality, state, or degree of being.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.p7" pid="rfcX6t4GGE6YEPQTauQXTA" hash="tc4YEQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="77"></span>We need only look around us to see what is taking place in our communities to realize that personal traits of virtue are in a steep decline. Reflect on the behavior of drivers on crowded highways; road rage happens all too often. Civility is all but absent in our political discourse. As countries around the world face financial and economic challenges, fidelity and honesty seem to have been replaced with greed and graft. A visit to a high school will often subject you to crude language and immodest dress. Some athletes display poor sportsmanship and seldom show humility unless publicly exposed for legal or moral infidelities. A large segment of our population feel little personal responsibility for their own temporal well-being. Some in financial distress blame bankers and lenders for loaning sums to satisfy insatiable wants rather than affordable needs. On occasion our generosity in support of good causes wanes as our appetite to acquire more than we need prevails.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.p8" pid="FI_Vu3AHk0KIu44rjE3P7w" hash="TbrfAQ">Brothers and sisters, we need not be a part of the virtue malaise that is penetrating and infecting society. If we follow the world in abandoning Christian-centered virtues, the consequences may be disastrous. Individual faith and fidelity, which have eternal consequences, will diminish. Family solidarity and spirituality will be adversely impacted. Religious influence in society will be lessened, and the rule of law will be challenged and perhaps even set aside. The seedbed for all that plagues the natural man will have been planted, to the sheer delight of Satan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.p9" pid="IEcaTTj5SUeit0aaMp-jJw" hash="-O-O5g">We need to stand tall and be firmly fixed in perpetuating Christlike virtues, even the “ity” virtues, in our everyday lives. Teaching virtuous traits begins in the home with parents who care and set the example. A good parental example encourages emulation; a poor example gives license to the children to disregard the parents’ teachings and even expand the poor example. A hypocritical example destroys credibility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.p10" pid="Jr7lY1ii8ES5rDG6SmjiGQ" hash="HU5huA">Eight-year-old Megan enjoys playing the piano. Recently her piano teacher offered a reward of a doughnut for faithful daily practice. The teacher said she would be “dialing for doughnuts” and would call Megan sometime during the week. If she had practiced that day, she would earn the reward. When Megan was called, she was not at home to give her report. At her weekly lesson, the teacher asked Megan if she had practiced, to which Megan responded that she thought she had and took the reward. When Megan’s mother saw the doughnut, she questioned Megan and helped her understand that she needed to be honest. An apologetic phone call to her teacher was made with her mom’s encouragement. As teacher and student visited, it was discovered that Megan really had completed her music theory writing; hence, she fully qualified for the reward. Thanks to wise, concerned parents, valuable lessons will be remembered for a long while.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.p11" pid="5qn47H6p2EGzrOXSNwjkJg" hash="MQCYnA">Our 15-year-old grandson, Ben, is a big-time ski enthusiast, having competed in several meets and done very well. Prior to one such competition in Idaho, his parents reminded him that his grades in school would determine whether or not he would be able to compete. A condominium in Sun Valley, Idaho, was reserved, his grandparents were planning to attend, and Ben was feverishly trying to achieve the lofty academic goals both he and his parents expected. However, at the end of the day, he fell just short of his goal. Ben missed the ski meet and lost points toward qualifying for the Junior Olympics, but Ben gained a valuable appreciation for responsibility and accountability. By remaining <span class="pageBreak" page-number="78"></span>steadfast, parents so very often suffer and agonize more than the children they endeavor to teach.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.p12" pid="xLBQ7jv0s0uCyQ7TWmenww" hash="Sc6KsA">President James E. Faust suggested that integrity is the mother of many virtues. He noted that integrity can be defined “as a firm adherence to a code of moral values.” He also suggested that “integrity is the light that shines from a disciplined conscience. It is the strength of duty within us” (“Integrity, the Mother of Many Virtues,” in <span class="emphasis">Speaking Out on Moral Issues</span> [1998], 61, 62). It is difficult for a person to display virtuous traits if he or she lacks integrity. Without integrity, honesty is often forgotten. If integrity is absent, civility is impaired. If integrity is not important, spirituality is difficult to maintain. In Old Testament times, Moses counseled the children of Israel that “if a man vow a vow unto the Lord, or swear an oath to bind his soul with a bond; he shall not break his word, he shall do according to all that proceedeth out of his mouth” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/num/30.2" class="scriptureRef">Numbers 30:2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.p13" pid="RpubZWb61USMJxOHSLXp_Q" hash="B4K3Ng">President Thomas S. Monson reminded us a few years ago that “most people will not commit desperate acts if they have been taught that dignity, honesty and integrity are more important than revenge or rage; if they understand that respect and kindness ultimately give one a better chance at success” (“Family Values in a Violent Society,” <span class="emphasis">Deseret News,</span> Jan. 16, 1994, A12, as quoted in “Finding Peace,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona </span>and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Mar. 2004, 4).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.p14" pid="DNGNL4RKAU2ynSTdo6aD5Q" hash="8H-Qvg">You may have heard about the <span class="emphasis">Lost </span>Battalion of World War I, the ten <span class="emphasis">lost </span>tribes of Israel, or perhaps the <span class="emphasis">“lost </span>boys” in J. M. Barrie’s play <span class="emphasis">Peter Pan.</span> You may also be acquainted with the album by Michael McLean entitled <span class="emphasis">The Forgotten Carols.</span> Virtuous traits, especially the “ity” virtues, must never be forgotten or set aside. If forgotten or set aside, they will inevitably become the “lost virtues.” If virtues are lost, families will be measurably weakened, individual faith in the Lord Jesus Christ will soften, and important eternal relationships may be jeopardized.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.p15" pid="_PD0S8PIS0CQQfVsVnfRPg" hash="j5U-Gg">Traits of virtue broadly practiced can loosen Satan’s firm grip on society and derail his insidious plan to capture the hearts, minds, and spirits of mortal men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.p16" pid="3cV7dFhbzEq2hgNoPD9zEg" hash="48GxjQ">Now is the time for us to join in rescuing and preserving that which is “virtuous, lovely, or of good report or praiseworthy.” As we allow virtue to garnish our thoughts unceasingly and we cultivate virtuous traits in our personal lives, our communities and institutions will be improved, our children and families will be strengthened, and faith and integrity will bless individual lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts.p17" pid="xLpA2WTYKUObdWRZhC_oXw" hash="r5L3jg">I testify and declare that our Heavenly Father expects His children to exercise integrity, civility, fidelity, charity, generosity, morality, and all the “ity” virtues. May we have the <span class="emphasis">humility</span> to take the <span class="emphasis">opportunity</span> to act upon our <span class="emphasis">responsibility</span> to demonstrate our <span class="emphasis">ability</span> to do so, I pray in the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2009/10/let-virtue-garnish-your-thoughts</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2009-general-conference/2009-10-4030-bishop-h-david-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5795520" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2009 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sanctifying Work of Welfare</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The work of caring for one another and being “kind to the poor” is a sanctifying work, commanded of the Father.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50028768_000_4030" doc-version="2" hash="BYT6qw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.head1">
    <h1 class="title" pid="zQJvk7bmqU6ZTgdlpSRNZw" hash="4p-wZA">The Sanctifying Work of Welfare</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="_aFfbrur8Euo4VPSaqRBFw" hash="XulAoA">H. David Burton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="fhbi28QGe0ymqByTuMQCtQ" hash="oPveuw">The work of caring for one another and being “kind to the poor” is a sanctifying work, commanded of the Father.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p1" pid="E3zJqJmZ90KgqqZ7tM_BlA" hash="_TjKGA">Good morning, brothers and sisters. In 1897 a young David O. McKay stood at a door with a tract in his hand. As a missionary in Stirling, Scotland, he had done this many times before. But on that day a very haggard woman opened the door and stood before him. She was poorly dressed and had sunken cheeks and unkempt hair.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p2" pid="PILRtCWoB0WOyAkUGnOFwQ" hash="QLxfeg">She took the tract Elder McKay offered to her and spoke six words that he subsequently would never forget: “Will this buy me any bread?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p3" pid="ncoBXoyTHUSfFY4MuQ-jwg" hash="V2FQbQ">This encounter left a lasting impression on the young missionary. He later wrote: “From that moment I had a deeper realization that the Church of Christ should be and is interested in the temporal salvation of man. I walked away from the door feeling that that [woman], with … bitterness in [her heart] toward man and God, [was] in no position to receive the message of the gospel. [She was] in need of temporal help, and there was no organization, so far as I could learn, in Stirling that could give it to [her].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p4" pid="tFSJg0RWmkCyoGx__XQfsw" hash="7f0gIA">A few decades later the world groaned under the burden of the Great Depression. It was during that time, on April 6, 1936, that President Heber J. Grant and his counselors, J. Reuben Clark and David O. McKay, announced what would later become known as the welfare program of the Church. Interestingly, two weeks later Elder Melvin J. Ballard was appointed as its first chairman and Harold B. Lee its first managing director.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p5" pid="1qZ-bWJC0U2j9CqfsQ45qg" hash="flpvGw">This was no ordinary endeavor. Although the Lord had raised up remarkable souls to administer it, President J. Reuben Clark made it clear that “the setting up of the [welfare] machinery is the result of a revelation by the Holy Ghost to President Grant, that it has been carried on since that time by equivalent revelations which have come to the brethren who have had it in charge.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p6" pid="sguGGu9XoE20_bqUy4rrBw" hash="85tRGQ">The commitment of Church leaders to relieve human suffering was as certain as it was irrevocable. President Grant wanted “a system that would … reach out and take care of the people no matter what the cost.” He said he would even go so far as to “close the seminaries, shut down missionary work for a period of time, or even close the temples, but they would not let the people go hungry.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p7" pid="CwDts-2OdEqLGY10JqHndw" hash="bF0KGg">I was at President Gordon B. Hinckley’s side in Managua, Nicaragua, when he spoke to 1,300 members of the Church who had survived a devastating hurricane that claimed more than 11,000 lives. “As long as the Church has resources,” he said to them, “we will not let you go hungry or without clothing or without shelter. We shall do all that we can to assist in the way that the Lord has designated that it should be done.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p8" pid="A6haR4F_uUicCNZtixLg-w" hash="wPpKrg">One of the distinguishing characteristics of this inspired gospel-centered endeavor is its emphasis on personal responsibility and self-reliance. President Marion G. Romney explained: “Many programs have been set up by well-meaning individuals to aid those who are in need. However, many of these programs are designed with the shortsighted objective of ‘helping people,’ as opposed to ‘helping people help themselves.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p9" pid="odjDlBsYs0ir7fiuwOesRQ" hash="i8wG2Q">Self-reliance is a product of provident living and exercising economic self-discipline. From the beginning the Church has taught that families—to the extent they can—need to assume responsibility for their own temporal welfare. Each generation is required to learn anew the foundational principles of self-reliance: avoid debt, implement principles of thrift, prepare for times of distress, listen to and follow the words of the living oracles, develop the discipline to distinguish between needs and wants and then live accordingly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p10" pid="YCUXq3VeOUOjBQIRgBnQvA" hash="seOPOQ">The purpose, promises, and principles that reinforce our work of caring for the poor and needy extend far beyond the bounds of mortality. This sacred work is not only to benefit and bless those who suffer or are in need. As sons and daughters of God, we cannot inherit the full measure of eternal life without being fully invested in caring for each other while we are here on earth. It is in the benevolent practice of sacrifice and giving of ourselves to others that we learn the celestial principles of sacrifice and consecration.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p11" pid="rPPzOXax1EW35F3RfBqvaA" hash="6pLMXg">The great King Benjamin taught that one of the reasons we impart of our substance to the poor and administer to their relief is so that we may retain a remission of our sins from day to day and walk guiltless before God.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p12" pid="NBmvPzafzEyS5kSfROvJ5Q" hash="Tg-VYA">Since the foundation of the world, the cloth of righteous societies has ever been woven from the golden threads of charity. We yearn for a peaceful world and for prosperous communities. We pray for kind and virtuous societies where wickedness is forsaken and goodness and right prevail. No matter how many temples we build, no matter how large our membership grows, no matter how positively we are perceived in the eyes of the world—should we fail in this great core commandment to “succor the weak, lift up the hands which hang down, and strengthen the feeble knees,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> or turn our hearts from those who suffer and mourn, we are under condemnation and cannot please the Lord<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> and the jubilant hope of our hearts will ever be distant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p13" pid="Q1KXg1eJXkysc7xCXHp16w" hash="czjzjA">Throughout the world, nearly 28,000 bishops search after the poor to administer to their needs. Each bishop is assisted by a ward council consisting of priesthood and auxiliary leaders, including a devoted Relief Society president. They can “fly to the relief of the stranger; … pour in oil and wine to the wounded heart of the distressed; … [and] dry up the tears of the orphan and make the widow’s heart to rejoice.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p14" pid="oSY_MepWC0u_yTxbUQi0kA" hash="sFqjqQ">The hearts of Church members and leaders throughout the world are being positively influenced and guided by the doctrines and divine spirit of loving and caring for their neighbors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p15" pid="aDKK0l7Qb0Smpi-ycWk4-g" hash="AhadTw">One priesthood leader in South America was burdened by the hunger and deprivation of the members of his little stake. Unwilling to allow the children to suffer in hunger, he found an empty plot of land and organized the priesthood to cultivate and plant it. They found an old horse and hooked up a primitive plow and began working the ground. But before they could finish, tragedy struck and the old horse died.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p16" pid="h5UESi64LEqL6Mt3QD2oqw" hash="QCRS3A">Rather than allow their brothers and sisters to suffer hunger, the brethren of the priesthood strapped the old plow to their own backs and pulled it through the unforgiving ground. They literally took upon themselves the yoke of the suffering and burdens of their brothers and sisters.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p17" pid="g1sVlpNchkWaUTzvgZHk3Q" hash="DFivmg">A moment in time from my own family history exemplifies a commitment to care for those in need. Many have heard of the Willie and Martin handcart companies and how these faithful pioneers suffered and died as they endured winter cold and debilitating conditions during their trek west. Robert Taylor Burton, one of my great-great-grandfathers, was one of those whom Brigham Young asked to ride out and rescue those dear, desperate Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p18" pid="yEqOb407E0-FghUrYyI2Kw" hash="4irT2A">Of this time Grandfather wrote in his journal: “Snow deep [and] very cold. … So cold that [we] could not move. … Thermometer 11 degrees below zero [-24°C] … ; so cold the people could not travel.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p19" pid="m7ViUoo0lk20KfIiENYNwA" hash="yvskSg">Life-saving supplies were distributed to the stranded Saints, but “in spite of all [the rescuers] could do many were laid to rest by the wayside.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p20" pid="VCeb4ssTYEi4RzCWZ9cinw" hash="vCOoNw">As the rescued Saints were traversing a portion of the trail through Echo Canyon, several wagons pulled off to assist in the arrival of a baby girl. Robert noticed the young mother did not have enough clothing to keep her newborn infant warm. In spite of the freezing temperatures, he “took off his own homespun shirt and gave it to the mother to [wrap] the baby.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> The child was given the name Echo—Echo Squires—as a remembrance of the place and circumstances of her birth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p21" pid="a5RRS0xBKEOqvjGaEEE9yQ" hash="pv22-A">In later years Robert was called to the Presiding Bishopric of the Church, where he served for more than three decades. At age 86 Robert Taylor Burton fell ill. He gathered his family to his bedside to give them his final blessing. Among his last words was this simple but very profound counsel: “Be kind to the poor.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p22" pid="-NzxCLQeck6cWHlck_Wsbw" hash="lO_NxA">Brothers and sisters, we honor those innovative giants whom the Lord raised up to organize and administer the institutional outreach to needy members of His Church. We honor those who in our day reach out in countless and often silent ways to “be kind to the poor,” feed the hungry, clothe the naked, minister to the sick, and visit the captive.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p23" pid="VRr0fR1vi0Ggp6iAiefkaA" hash="jxe6Aw">This is the sacred work the Savior expects from His disciples. It is the work He loved when He walked the earth. It is the work I know we would find Him doing were He here among us today.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p24" pid="1_BqpBQCCUyI9XlFhVQXWQ" hash="v1ZUAg">Seventy-five years ago a system devoted to the spiritual and temporal salvation of mankind rose from humble beginnings. Since that time it has ennobled and blessed the lives of tens of millions of people throughout the world. The prophetic welfare plan is not merely an interesting footnote in the history of the Church. The principles upon which it is based define who we are as a people. It is the essence of who we are as individual disciples of our Savior and Exemplar, Jesus the Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare.p25" pid="B2oBiEQHp0WTP_5nVSd4Yw" hash="IKV5nA">The work of caring for one another and being “kind to the poor” is a sanctifying work, commanded of the Father and divinely designed to bless, refine, and exalt His children. May we follow the Savior’s counsel to the certain lawyer in the parable of the good Samaritan: “Go, and do thou likewise.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> Of this I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/04/the-sanctifying-work-of-welfare</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2011-general-conference/2011-04-4030-bishop-h-david-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="6961603" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
