<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Harold G. Hillam</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Harold G. Hillam.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Harold%20G.%20Hillam.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Harold G. Hillam.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Apr 1980 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 1980 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>An Example of What Welfare Services Can Do</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I have made it a habit of running three miles every day, and I would have to admit that this walk up here leaves me a little more out of breath than the end of three miles. It is a humbling experience to occupy this pulpit, which has been occupied by</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03122_000_037" doc-version="2" hash="0vZ3VA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="VqWoYsukEkeFickcNXzmvQ" hash="15Sgag">An Example of What Welfare Services Can Do</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="HWJyVBjlWUKV7MiyrHp9og" hash="1w7f3g">Harold G. Hillam</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do.p1" pid="64W_AuGDyEK46ZLJLqZtrw" hash="LEhNdw">I have made it a habit of running three miles every day, and I would have to admit that this walk up here leaves me a little more out of breath than the end of three miles. It is a humbling experience to occupy this pulpit, which has been occupied by such great, great men in welfare services.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do.p2" pid="6F85PvjsbEGdm5I-FoB3Ew" hash="PtDKng">Sometime after the collapse of the Teton Dam and the ensuing flooding disaster which affected several counties in eastern Idaho, while serving as the area welfare leader, I was asked to speak on behalf of the Church to a group of people who were responsible for civil defense and disaster relief. They included representatives from city, county, state, and federal organizations as well as a number of religious, volunteer, and service groups. The requested topic was how the LDS Church is prepared to respond to emergency crises.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do.p3" pid="eIfAFFobUEaZvdGWOxQukg" hash="-gjPGw">I realized that they had already observed the response of the Church to the flood. They saw firsthand how the bishops’ storehouse system was almost immediately prepared to ship in truckloads of supplies and then stood by to fill the requests of the local priesthood leaders. They saw the Deseret Industries help bring order out of chaos. Large mountains of clothing were donated from many parts of the country and placed in large, unsorted piles. There were party dresses with work shoes, small sizes with large, men’s with women’s, and clean with soiled. In a very short time the Deseret Industries had these much-needed articles of clothing cleaned, pressed, sized, and placed on racks from which those in need could choose for their particular needs.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do.p4" pid="IXGQ0epS8UesNdLLrkWhgw" hash="Jqjchg">They saw how the LDS Social Services was available to help the people in their social and emotional needs as emotional tolerances were pressed to the limit. Many jobs were lost due to the flood, and many new ones were created. LDS employment program was busy as employees and employers were matched together. They saw, as did people from all over the world, the many thousands of volunteers who came, at their own expense, to help in the cleanup effort.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do.p5" pid="1z9AXmkGJk2xJVJerXNkRA" hash="KGe2Qw">There was a need in the early days of the flood cleanup for heavy equipment. A request was made for tractors and front-end loaders from stakes both near and far. We thought in terms of 5 or 6 outfits. Soon after the request was made, the area welfare leader from Soda Springs, approximately 165 miles away, called and said, “President, I understand that you need some tractors and front-end loaders. We are ready and prepared to bring 150.” I told him that 20 would be marvelous.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do.p6" pid="HNBVnVYs8UGCB1h4Oqp9lw" hash="G8EtQQ">There was a need for electricians to restore power to the homes that lost it because of the flood. We estimated that 150 would be a great response. The call went out. We didn’t get just 150. More than 450 licensed electricians and helpers responded to that call. This same type of devotion and dedication was shown many, many times over as a variety of needs was fulfilled.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do.p7" pid="0YOjxd0bikaMqq-Z6j7bwA" hash="tY1ILg">It was evident to this group to whom I would speak, as well as to others, what had happened in this major crisis, but were they aware of those who are helped every day on an individual basis—for example, the young girl who found love, understanding, and kind assistance from LDS Social Services when she was confronted with a major crisis in her life? Because of wise counsel, she did not compound an already serious problem with a graver tragedy when she found that there is an alternative to the accepted worldly philosophy of abortion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do.p8" pid="M08n9cb8L0uqFqebJMAwFg" hash="fxw_1w">They did not know of the many other services of LDS Social Services, the childless marriages with loving homes who are blessed with the opportunity to adopt a little infant, the Lamanite program, professional counseling, foster homes, and others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do.p9" pid="W8SWQopu4ESLOrdTSHg1XQ" hash="84R3RA">I was sure that most of them did not totally understand the Deseret Industries; and most certainly did not understand that it is a living example of the principle of consecration, wherein each of us has the opportunity to give freely of our surpluses, and then those great people who are not willing to be spectators in the arena of life are given the opportunity to maintain their dignity by enjoying the blessing of work. Perhaps they were not even aware that Deseret Industries is open for all to make purchases which are so helpful in meeting the pressures of an inflated economy. Shopping at Deseret Industries is like shopping at an exclusive store. There are many items that are one of a kind, and with shipments arriving daily we have an opportunity to make new choices every day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do.p10" pid="m-nGA8Cl7kiMS--vadj9pg" hash="MSKkKQ">On one occasion when I had arrived early at Deseret Industries prior to our monthly meeting of the local operating committee, I made a tour of the well-organized displays and racks of commodities. My eyes were drawn to the area of overcoats. One particularly appealed to me. It was a fine, all-wool, English-tailored coat. I thought, “If it fits, I’ll buy it.” I looked at the price: four dollars and seventy-five cents! At that price, I knew it fit. I bought it and I paid cash for it. I took it home and, when I modeled it for my wife, I put my hands in the pockets, and there were a number of rare, one-cent postage stamps. I guess the stamps themselves were worth probably about as much as I had paid for the coat. And I suspect that I was probably the only person who made a purchase at Deseret Industries who not only made an excellent buy but also received stamps!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do.p11" pid="frNmb9BQD0-96dm8EjWlAg" hash="KryC1g">This group of people to whom I would speak certainly had no way of knowing about the father who found himself with his loving bishop exclaiming, “Bishop, tragedy has struck our family. I have lost my job. I need welfare.” That knowledgeable bishop replied, “Brother, you don’t need welfare. What you need is a job, and you have come to the right place.” That wise bishop had just taught the great principle of work. The bishop’s comment was not an idle remark, because he had available to him, as a part of the great storehouse system, a ward employment specialist, who has access not only to the employers within the ward and stake but also, through the employment center, to those throughout the entire area. If a job could not be found in the open market, that same employment specialist would become a resource to the bishop to help find meaningful work opportunities for the needy brother within the Lord’s plan, thus allowing that father the joy of maintaining his dignity by working for the commodities received. This same employment system serves the needs of all members as they seek employment and seek to upgrade their opportunities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do.p12" pid="-seGXC27C0mJD9wtu3Alsw" hash="kfHLew">This group of interested people that I would speak to wanted to know what we as the Church can do in a major disaster, but that is not all. There are heartaches, hurts, problems—yes, even disasters—which occur in every life at some time. And, in the individual’s life, those personal disasters are just as real and just as deserving of our help as the disaster of those involved in the flood in eastern Idaho, or the earthquake in Guatemala, or the flooding in California.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do.p13" pid="hyJ2DvNPYkSGM3ZIqwDnkw" hash="oeFL4w">I wanted this group to know that in the Church not only are we prepared to deal with major disasters which involve many, but the Lord’s plan provides for the loving care of each of his children on an individual, one-on-one basis.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do.p14" pid="JnnzC-D03EyOrUUcWMnMhQ" hash="jp74Ig">Those of us who are here today have at our disposal the principles of the welfare plan, which assist us in helping to bless those who are in need.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do.p15" pid="juosSoU6c0OUaQs8f_GROg" hash="9oSbAQ">I give you my solemn witness that we are engaged in the Lord’s work. May each one of us strive to carry out our stewardships, so the work may be done in His own way. The work and labor which we perform in welfare services will lead us steadily forward to that time when we will be blessed to live the great law of consecration in a Zion society.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do.p16" pid="kNrOQYK7hkuqXFYzfueUFg" hash="jmg9TQ">May each of us be found doing our duty, I pray in the name of him whose plan it is, even Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1980/04/an-example-of-what-welfare-services-can-do</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1980-general-conference/1980-04-6020-president-harold-g-hillam-64k-eng.mp3" length="5500001" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 1980 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No More Strangers and Foreigners</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Some years ago, while I was serving as the mission president in Portugal, several of our missionaries introduced me to their shoeshine man. Their shoes looked so good that I was anxious to meet the man that could put such a shine on missionaries’ sho</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_90911_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="UNEmxQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="B6RZXPTq30aM6-xxBZ7DrA" hash="qRrfIQ">No More Strangers and Foreigners</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ifz7jmiPI0mFcGAePIHKTA" hash="1w7f3g">Harold G. Hillam</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1ef0.jpg" alt="Elder Harold G. Hillam" pid="k3Y1eIlDVEOXEAyblUrOdA" hash="esLRGA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.p1" pid="mg_kYWQ6VEOj-oKkOw8ABQ" hash="2BMIvQ">Some years ago, while I was serving as the mission president in Portugal, several of our missionaries introduced me to their shoeshine man. Their shoes looked so good that I was anxious to meet the man that could put such a shine on missionaries’ shoes. Even though he had not chosen to listen to the missionaries’ message, I considered the shoeshine man my friend, and we visited while he was busy shining my shoes. He indicated that his wife had died, that he had no family, and that about the only pleasure he had in life was seeing people walk away happy with the shoes he had just shined.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.p2" pid="lcER1WWn8Um_v9FwL92BBg" hash="AZdQQQ">His place of business was on the curbside of a small square on a busy street in downtown Lisbon. His stand seemed to have all that was necessary. It consisted of a short, rusty, three-legged stool, upon which my frail friend would sit as he shined the shoes that were placed on a stained and well-used shoeshine box that was full of his polishes and brushes, and there was an ornate lamppost (which was kindly furnished by the city of Lisbon), upon which the customer would lean while he was having his shoes shined.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.p3" pid="IolMIR0L_ECyj9nrr-1fWg" hash="QflJ0w">He would carefully apply two coats of polish, using a brush to polish between each coat. Last, he applied a special product that would give the shoes that extra special shine. With a final snap of the cloth, he would stand up, take off his little Portuguese cap, make a deep bow, and say, <span class="emphasis">“Pronto. Seus sapatos foram engrashados pelo o melhor engraxate do mundo.”</span> “There. Your shoes were shined by the very best shoeshine man in the world.” I was convinced that I had had my shoes shined by the very best.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.p4" pid="Odczgu_7q0GzQHKfD_7dZg" hash="IaZUkw">A few months after our mission, I was called to serve as the Regional Representative to Portugal and had the opportunity to return to Lisbon a number of times. As occasion permitted, I would have my shoes shined by the “best shoeshine man in the world.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.p5" pid="jdl3XOtSQk6KeLX2xdUi5Q" hash="aLeFnw">The last few times that I went, I was unable to find him at his usual place of business. I finally inquired at the prestigious stores that surrounded the square. The response was the same, “We don’t know what happened to him. It seems that we had heard that he had died.” I remember thinking, Could it be that the best shoeshine man in the world had died, and no one really knew or even seemed to care? I wondered: Had there been someone there with him, or did he slip away unnoticed?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.p6" pid="j_7120_u-EaB8d5jyifHOw" hash="NBxrzg">May we contrast that for a moment with Brother and Sister Joaquim Aires, a marvelous man and his wife who came to Portugal following the 1974 revolution of Portugal’s colonies in Angola and Mozambique. They had returned to Portugal unknown and with very few possessions. A great blessing occurred in their lives. They opened their door to two young missionaries, who taught them of the restoration of Christ’s church. They received the missionaries, accepted their message, and were baptized.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.p7" pid="X7NH-K9P2Eq3k56I6lXYdA" hash="Rky7BQ">As is the opportunity for all worthy men in the Church, he received the priesthood—authority to act in the name of our Father in Heaven—and to become a leader in the Church. Brother Aires became President Aires, president of one of the mission districts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.p8" pid="B6CbIjjoOkmkQbJ4O_Gqsw" hash="uLno5w">One day I received a telephone call. President Aires was in the hospital in Coimbra, several hours’ travel away. He had suffered a very serious cerebral hemorrhage and was in very critical condition. Another priesthood holder and I made the trip as quickly as possible. As we walked quietly into the hospital room, we found him asleep. My first inclination was not to awaken him. And then I thought he would want to know that we had come. So I reached over and carefully touched his hand. He slowly opened his eyes and then looked at me for a moment, and then the tears came to both of our eyes. He then said in a very weak and soft voice, “I knew you would come. I knew you would come. Would you please give me a blessing.” In his dear, sweet faith, he was asking for a priesthood blessing, the same that is taught of and recorded in the Bible. We read in <a href="/scriptures/nt/james/5.14-15" class="scriptureRef">James 5:14–15</a>: “Is any sick among you? let him call for the elders of the church; and let them pray over him, anointing him with oil in the name of the Lord:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.p9" pid="RlrZB_uGn0GTADQWE4XTmQ" hash="7nwCqg">“And the prayer of faith shall save the sick, and the Lord shall raise him up.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.p10" pid="ATrcufp_tkGliAHTqIcGOQ" hash="c2h24g">As men of the priesthood, it was our privilege to pronounce a blessing on him with power and authority of our Father in Heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.p11" pid="Wo3WEwJ65Eu_nRW0HTVsgw" hash="-rIz1w">As I would meet with the members of the Church from one end of Portugal to the other, the brothers and sisters would ask, “How is Brother Aires? Will you please tell him we love him and we’re praying for him?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.p12" pid="IUa4UfWVWE-jx8oPa3jksw" hash="l3mHxA">This good man and his wife, who had returned to Portugal almost unknown, now, because of their membership in the Church, had literally thousands who loved them and were concerned about them and remembered him in their prayers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.p13" pid="5qYJ7y6WsU-Dfzsj7PTKDA" hash="dv8chA">The prayers of faith were answered. He recovered completely, and he and Sister Aires went on to fulfill a full-time mission together.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.p14" pid="MnK-61zJW06TtBDu9ql-FQ" hash="XW2zvQ">I have thought often of the contrast between the two—my little shoeshine man on one hand, who, like so many of life’s unknown wanderers, had slipped away without any understanding of life’s purpose; and Brother Aires on the other, who was not only taught of life’s real purpose, but had now become a part of a great body of people who showed their love and appreciation for him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.p15" pid="qJxnWHNORUyh0pLcJb1RSQ" hash="5D-M2A">As the Apostle Paul wrote to the members of the Church, or Saints as they were called and are called today, he reminded the newly baptized members of the Church of the blessings of belonging when he told them, “Ye are no more strangers and foreigners, but fellowcitizens with the saints, and of the household of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/2.19" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 2:19</a>.) What a blessing it is to belong and to be wanted and needed! It becomes even more apparent during life’s tender moments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.p16" pid="6l8q6jy_Y0KpgmiF1NA2Mg" hash="VI6YfA">To all who find themselves outside the household of faith and away from the Saints, would you please accept this invitation to come unto Christ that we might all, as Alma said, “bear one another’s burdens.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.8" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:8</a>.) Join with the Saints, that you might not be any longer strangers alone in this world, but truly cared for, loved, and appreciated.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.p17" pid="C-xMrYNwwkqGyXV-UsksYw" hash="f0y9eQ">And to all of us—those of us who are members of the Church, could I just counsel with you for a moment? Do you have anyone that you know who might be as our little shoeshine man, who is alone—alone in this great crowd of people—that could use your special love and caring and concern? Could you take a moment and let such people know how much you love them?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners.p18" pid="4xF7tVPPtEWaBjUvqGW_zQ" hash="PfOkyg">And may we also, as members of the Church, truly do our part to make His church a welcome refuge for all of our Father in Heaven’s children, I pray humbly in the name of the Lord and Savior Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1990/10/no-more-strangers-and-foreigners</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1990-general-conference/1990-10-2040-elder-harold-g-hillam-64k-eng.mp3" length="4852834" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1990 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sacrifice in the Service</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As I look at you this evening, I can see many young men with their valiant fathers and loyal priesthood leaders seated side by side. These fathers and leaders are ready to pay the price, yes, even sacrifice, for the success of you young men.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95911_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="cLqp0g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="uO_ypu_AUUG27a4sDjmM-w" hash="LSaGuw">Sacrifice in the Service</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="u7xi_74oHUqUxsQDkfU0HA" hash="1w7f3g">Harold G. Hillam</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1ef0.jpg" alt="Elder Harold G. Hillam" pid="Mc-g-_vk6kq12FN8avbkUg" hash="esLRGA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p1" pid="X69UAUVUrka-XI34xzwtmg" hash="sOuhag">As I look at you this evening, I can see many young men with their valiant fathers and loyal priesthood leaders seated side by side. These fathers and leaders are ready to pay the price, yes, even sacrifice, for the success of you young men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p2" pid="vEJ7VebVSU26FUy48r9hPw" hash="-s1UcA">In the spirit of sacrifice, I recall a conversation I had some years ago with my stake president in Idaho. We were discussing the forthcoming Aaronic Priesthood/Scout campout. I explained to him that it would be necessary for each person to bring his own sleeping bag, to which the president replied, “I have never slept in a sleeping bag.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p3" pid="tusBW47Iuk-HR_G79TiW7Q" hash="T9TAGg">I quickly responded, “President, you can’t be serious. You have lived in beautiful Idaho all these years and you have never slept in a sleeping bag?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p4" pid="6Sl1LL09G0mWlZXExTrx6w" hash="G2VuAw">“Nope!” he said, “I never have. But I have sure lain in a lot of ‘em.” And then he went on to say, “And I’ll lie in a whole bunch more of them if it will help to save boys.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p5" pid="L7yJn1JvXECMZK7qm9y2QQ" hash="jWpDyw">The sacrifice I would like to speak to you about is the sacrifice that accompanies missionary service. Since the beginning of time our Heavenly Father has called worthy servants to go into the world to proclaim the gospel and to testify of the Messiah, Jesus Christ. Many of those who have fulfilled their callings have done so with considerable sacrifice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p6" pid="STr5bhD2mkqUR9MUWDn6xQ" hash="eDSK9Q">Let me tell you of four who served their missions long ago. They were Ammon, Aaron, Omner, and Himni, sons of Mosiah, the king. They had become so powerfully converted they wanted everyone to hear the gospel message. From the Book of Mormon we read:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p7" pid="7kUjNq5TbEG_s5igvapXMg" hash="5aQShg">“They were desirous that salvation should be declared to every creature, for they could not bear that any human soul should perish; yea, even the very thoughts that any soul should endure endless torment did cause them to quake and tremble” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/28.3" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 28:3</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p8" pid="W3StAgYykkqP3yBK3KJlDg" hash="g9dy-g">They pled with their father that they might go and do missionary work among the Lamanites. Now father Mosiah feared for his sons’ safety in the land of their enemy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p9" pid="1El_wUlTR0WsH1DN7gZTGg" hash="oBqVSA">“And king Mosiah went and inquired of the Lord if he should let his sons go up among the Lamanites to preach the word” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/28.6" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 28:6</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p10" pid="2zI045_TfUGRfbhEiM5mDQ" hash="U3YlDQ">The first part of the Lord’s answer might not have been exactly what Mosiah wanted to hear:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p11" pid="r_fWwcy0aU6ALHucI0L2tQ" hash="WuIIXA">“The Lord said unto Mosiah: Let them go up” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/28.7" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 28:7</a>). But then follow three marvelous promises: the first, “For many shall believe on their words,” and the second, “I will deliver thy sons out of the hands of the Lamanites,” and then the third, “They shall have eternal life” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/28.7" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 28:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p12" pid="P53Kl3S79UmT6wzxXo7uJQ" hash="tvr93A">Now, he did not promise them great wealth, but he did promise the greatest of all the gifts of God, <span class="emphasis">eternal life!</span> Can you imagine a more marvelous promise for faithful missionaries?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p13" pid="ZLC65Q8jG0GOT7wrfyv-cQ" hash="VQkrGQ">The four missionary sons of Mosiah did not choose the easy course. Their choice was neither convenient, nor popular: They gave up the kingship. “Mosiah had no one to confer the kingdom upon” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/28.10" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 28:10</a>)—they were all on missions. Serving a mission wasn’t necessarily accepted. They were ridiculed even by other members of the Church. Ammon recalls the experience: “Now do ye remember, my brethren, that we said unto our brethren in the land of Zarahemla, we go up to the land of Nephi, to preach unto our brethren, the Lamanites, and they <span class="emphasis">laughed us to scorn?</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/26.23" class="scriptureRef">Alma 26:23</a>; emphasis added.) Their choice to serve a mission was not one of convenience. Ammon spoke of the challenges they encountered: “We have been cast out, and mocked, and spit upon, and smote upon our cheeks; … and taken and bound with strong cords, and cast into prison.” However, Ammon continues, “Through the power and wisdom of God we have been delivered again” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/26.29" class="scriptureRef">Alma 26:29</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p14" pid="nPVdF0J39kaPM-o3m-8yRQ" hash="xpnF2g">They were not easy missions, but thousands were converted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p15" pid="ESqkI3X8Lk2CxNQYI2uKNA" hash="uL-wsA">Now let’s look to another set of missionaries closer to our time, the time of the Restoration. There was considerable persecution from enemies in and outside the Church. At a time when it appeared that the Prophet needed them at home, two of the Apostles, Brigham Young and Heber C. Kimball, were called on foreign missions. The following is Elder Heber C. Kimball’s historic account of the pathetic setting at his departure:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p16" pid="5AR_JO04dEikZ0FflYRwrQ" hash="rRSBog">“I went to the bed and shook hands with my wife, who was shaking with the ague, having two children lying sick by her side; I embraced her and my children, and bid them farewell; the only child well was little Heber Parley, and it was with difficulty he could carry a two-quart pail full of water from a spring at the bottom of a small hill to assist in quenching their thirst. It was with difficulty we got into the wagon and started down the hill about ten rods; it appeared to me as though my very inmost parts would melt within me; leaving my family in such a condition, as it were, almost in the arms of death; it seemed to me as though I could not endure it. I said to the teamster, ‘Hold up.’ Said I to Brother Brigham, ‘This is pretty tough, ain’t it? Let’s rise up and give them a cheer.’ We arose and swinging our hats three times over our heads, we cried ‘Hurrah! Hurrah! Hurrah for Israel!’ Vilate [Kimball] hearing the noise arose from her bed and came to the door; she had a smile on her face and she and Mary Ann Young cried out to us, ‘Good bye, God bless you.’ We returned the compliment and then told the driver to go ahead. After this I felt a spirit of joy and gratitude at having the satisfaction of seeing my wife standing upon her feet, instead of leaving her in bed, knowing as I did that I should not see them again for two or more years” (quoted in Helen Mar Whitney, “Life Incidents,” <span class="emphasis">Woman’s Exponent,</span> 15 July 1880, p. 25). This was one of four missions that these two Apostle missionaries served.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p17" pid="YnOlPlninUe4hsVl5lfv8g" hash="6xuIfQ">Now to the present for an interview I had with a handsome zone leader in the Brazil São Paulo Interlagos Mission. I said to the missionary, “Tell me about your family.” He then relayed the following. He was born into a wealthy family. His father had a responsible position in a multinational corporation. They moved from Brazil to Venezuela. He was one of seven children, all members of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p18" pid="N3YLBCYpXUmRZDfvMOahgQ" hash="_S6F4A">When the missionary was fifteen years old, his father was shot and killed by a fleeing thief. In a family council it was decided to return to Brazil and invest their savings in the purchase of a small home. A year and a half later, the mother informed the children that she had been diagnosed with cancer. The family used valuable savings to help pay the medical expenses—but to no avail. Six months later the mother passed away, leaving the young family alone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p19" pid="fLyNijhJjE-69q_RTrSwwQ" hash="XbBlug">Our young missionary, Elder Bugs (pronounced Boogs), now sixteen years old, went to work, first selling clothing, then later computer supplies. He used his hard-earned money to support the young family. He said, “We were always blessed to have enough to eat. I would work during the day, then help the children with their studies at night. I especially miss my little sister. I taught her to read.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p20" pid="aHVECWMiFkmPUw4YEYMNKA" hash="C9iflg">Elder Bugs continued, “Then the bishop invited me to come in for an interview. He called me on a mission. I told him I would need to speak with my family first. In our family council, they reminded me that Dad had always taught us that we should be prepared to serve the Lord as full-time missionaries. I accepted the call. When I received my letter from the prophet, I withdrew all my savings. I bought a new suit, a pair of pants, white shirts and ties, and a new pair of shoes. I gave the rest of the money to the bishop (enough for about four months of support for the family). I hugged my little family and left for my mission.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p21" pid="ZV8ontzpMUmBDfVv27e2cw" hash="xuGFQw">I looked at that brave young man and I said, “But Elder, with you away, who is taking care of your family?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p22" pid="kDCbdMXRoEWOYGf-MuiTjA" hash="kk1NwA">“Oh,” he said, “my brother is sixteen. He is the same age I was when our mother died. He is taking care of the family now.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p23" pid="Itv8WTpa50u42mctmnfJdg" hash="4SIKjA">I had an opportunity recently to talk by telephone with Elder Bugs. He has been home from his mission for six months now. When I asked him how he was doing, he said, “I have a good job again and I am caring for the family, but oh, how I miss my mission. It was the greatest thing I have ever done. I am now helping my younger brother prepare for his mission.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p24" pid="d3qDoFaiIEO9gnCfTYR2Jw" hash="iwxZZg">Why have these great missionaries and others like them been willing to sacrifice the comforts of home, family, loved ones, and sweethearts to answer the call to serve? It’s because they have a testimony of Jesus Christ. And when they know Him there is no bed too short or too hard, no climate too hot or too cold, no food too different or language so strange that they are unwilling to serve Him. No sacrifice is too great to serve the Master, who sacrificed His all to provide the way for His brothers and sisters to return home to their Heavenly Father. And because they are faithful to their callings, thousands will revere their names throughout the eternities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service.p25" pid="lRGaJ5-GukKF-gAMtkWzoQ" hash="r_d4bg">I testify there is no more majestic call than to be in the full-time service of our Redeemer, to help to bring our Heavenly Father’s children to the knowledge of Him who has made eternal life possible. I pray that every able young man and every able couple will join those who have paid the price to serve a full-time mission. And this I pray in the name of the Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/10/sacrifice-in-the-service</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1995-general-conference/1995-10-3020-elder-harold-g-hillam-64k-eng.mp3" length="6039885" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1995 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teachers, the Timeless Key</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Regardless of life’s circumstances or the nature of one’s calling, all members of the Church have the opportunity to teach and to testify.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_97911_000_025" doc-version="2" hash="j6GpGA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="na7SK7MTAUOmgGo2k_1kEA" hash="YP_GYw">Teachers, the Timeless Key</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="80q4K94_ikOG8di24YQEUA" hash="1w7f3g">Harold G. Hillam</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="SC4lYx6cDUe8wrgrm7eFwg" hash="x0Hprw">Regardless of life’s circumstances or the nature of one’s calling, all members of the Church have the opportunity to teach and to testify.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1ef0.jpg" alt="Elder Harold G. Hillam" pid="ZvFd1wA4UUKyv28wJxjndA" hash="esLRGA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p1" pid="9bfCALxUfUGErCrvIdhfog" hash="8iEDqg">This historic letter that I hold in my hand was typed 98 years ago. Each sheet is placed in a plastic, sealed envelope to protect it. Though written nearly a century ago, the words contained on these pages have a great deal of significance for us today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p2" pid="BdFM22SHMEiYPanSsV3pHw" hash="FX2HfQ">The year 1899 marked a jubilee celebration—the 50-year anniversary of the organization of the first Sunday School of the Church. As a culmination of that jubilee year, a time capsule in the form of a beautiful hand-carved box was filled with items considered to have meaning for those who would be present at its opening 50 years in the future.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p3" pid="-dJOiNXh-0KfJ9gICJ6zhQ" hash="pJ8c1g">Accordingly, in 1949 the time capsule was opened, and among other historical items was this letter addressed to the “General Sunday School Authorities of <small>A.D.</small> 1949.” The letter includes the following:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p4" pid="IAEs0Wl760ainKip0FR-2w" hash="4xqmSA">“The establishment of the first Sunday Schools in the Rocky Mountains was attended with hardships and discouragements. The people were in a dry and barren land and were subjected to many privations. It required all their time and strength to secure the necessaries of life; yet in the midst of it all, with the limited facilities at hand, they began the education of their children.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p5" pid="Aqstm_LzcUGjJxtzVlYRYQ" hash="3IDmuQ">The letter continues: “Now brethren, we can but dimly see what the next fifty years will do for the youth of Zion. The methods of today may be entirely abandoned for new ones to be discovered in the future.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p6" pid="7eoagWasB0mDacCTlphA3A" hash="oYno-Q">“It is probable that when you receive this Jubilee box, many of us, whose names are signed to this greeting, will have passed to the other side with the great army of Sunday School workers, and the greeting therefore of those of us who have gone to the great beyond, will be to you as a voice from the dead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p7" pid="MVLnh7cXbkiEgnCbcvX9ww" hash="DdilGg">“This Sunday School work has been to us a labor of love and our interest does not merely exist for today, but extends into the future.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p8" pid="cL_6PX29eEWJK4ul-8t3Og" hash="ksXdCQ">“… We beseech you that whatever may be the methods employed, whatever may be the changes wrought in the fifty years to come, that you never forget for an instant the object of the great Sunday School work, viz: To teach the children the principles of the Gospel of Jesus Christ; to make Latter-day Saints of them.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p9" pid="Gu4_n1Q5fU2UAzXwzbNihw" hash="t5SbMQ">The letter was signed by the general Sunday School presidency, as well as 21 other board members, including Joseph F. Smith and Heber J. Grant, both of whom later served as President of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p10" pid="C3ohQTusrke_htB4bi1etg" hash="tkwnIg">The letter was prophetic. Indeed, the signers may have seen only dimly what the next 50 years would bring for the youth of Zion. During that time the communication methods of the late 19th century were totally replaced by tremendous advances in the dissemination of information. Even the typewriter used to prepare this 1899 document was at the time a recent novelty and was the cutting edge in communication! The first broadcast of the human voice was still two years away. The first radio network broadcast was 21 years in the future, and general conference would not be transmitted over radio for another 25 years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p11" pid="qUpBoocCV0a5j-umsbCu3A" hash="CBSOeA">Could the writers of this 1899 letter have imagined, even dimly, the technological advances—the radio, color television, computers, the Internet, or the programming—that are present today, they would have been astounded to learn that just one small computer disk would contain large collections of the greatest of books and talks known to mankind. They would have seen that with just a few keystrokes of the computer, one could open the scriptures and with ease cross-reference them with other great talks and writings of the prophets, and with the attending light and knowledge which comes from God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p12" pid="NZD15ny_EUWw-piCC8diCw" hash="Dr3ykg">Sadly, they also would have seen that the very same tools that teach light and truth can, with the same ease but with different strokes of the keys, bring to view some of the most vile, sordid, wicked, and immoral material.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p13" pid="MW9r1NY890-OFvHndUYL5Q" hash="Q7jTLw">Indeed, we have been blessed with magnificent tools and methods which can be used to assist in teaching, but as with all tools, they are to be used with wisdom and discretion if they are to bless and simplify our lives. Just as fire under control brings so many comforts and benefits, a fire improperly used or out of control wreaks havoc and destruction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p14" pid="qNM3F_NUmkWWZ2aiCP8jIw" hash="NZyjdA">As we prepare for another 50 or 100 years, we might also see but dimly what lies ahead. We must learn to make wise use of the tools and technology that we have.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p15" pid="dgQuSddoRE-V3KUfkHu1wg" hash="hN0OnQ">Wise use of our technology would include care in that which we invite into our homes by the way of television, videos, computers, including the Internet. There is much that is good and edifying in the media, but there is also much that is gross, immoral, and time-consuming, enticing us to be “ever learning, and never able to come to the knowledge of the truth” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/3.7" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 3:7</a>). During the Second World War when gasoline was in short supply and rationed, I remember signs saying, “Is this trip necessary?” Today, with ever-increasing demands on everyone and time in short supply, might we ask ourselves before we turn on the video game, the television, the computer, or access the many programs available, “Is this trip necessary?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p16" pid="oTcLCKI7pES-6R7fRKBgtA" hash="e4jZxw">Perhaps every person who is listening might also ask these questions of himself or herself and expect an honest reply: “Is the information I am receiving from this tool of learning edifying, and adding truth into my life? Are the hours I am investing an effective use of my valuable time? Does this computer game assist me in fulfilling my responsibilities and goals?” If the answer is not a resounding yes, then we should have the courage and determination to click the off button and direct our lives to more important tasks.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p17" pid="UmK1qqE8SEqDP-pNtm_rJw" hash="gzdYWg">Despite the staggering technological advances of the past century, one of the elements of this 1899 letter still remains constant: that is, the importance of well-trained, humble, dedicated, and loving teachers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p18" pid="KZZ-l6bnN0KGBX8RCTJT_A" hash="5YWj4Q">Everyone can remember a special teacher that has made a profound difference in their life. I will ever be thankful to Miss Hamilton, my second-grade teacher. She was also my Sunday School teacher. I can still recall her saying, “Now remember, always be a good boy!” and “I am so proud of you.” She always made me feel very important. I grew to love her, and I’m sure she loved me. That school year was a glorious one. I hated to see it come to a close. The news traveled fast in the small town of Sugar City, Idaho, and one summer day my mother called me in the house to inform me of the disastrous news: my dear Miss Hamilton had gone and gotten married! And she didn’t even check with me to see if it was all right.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p19" pid="pFJm_aI77E2j3fGf_PB0UA" hash="tLbwgQ">Our daughter-in-law, also a teacher, received a note at the end of a school year from one of her third-grade students. He wrote, “Miss Scoresby, I will miss you more than my pet gerbil that died.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p20" pid="HA11_XH520O-c6e2SSCGtg" hash="TL753g">We are in essence a church of teachers. Regardless of life’s circumstances or the nature of one’s calling, all members of the Church have the opportunity to teach and to testify. The very nature of our lives bears witness of what we believe and teaches all who come within our sphere of influence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p21" pid="uQejpGzrwU-F2UdwesFfZg" hash="zm97tw">Many, perhaps most, adult members of the Church, however, find themselves in a position to teach in a more direct manner. Leaders, parents, and called teachers have the specific responsibility to constantly improve their teaching abilities so they can prepare, train, and edify those who fall within their stewardship. President David O. McKay reminded us that “the proper training of childhood is man’s most important and sacred duty” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Ideals</span> [1953], 220). The Lord has made it clear that parents shall “teach their children to pray, and to walk uprightly before the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:28</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p22" pid="B2AISlTdLUWwbocjA8xs_g" hash="viHZiw">There is power in the doctrines of the Church—hence the need for us all to be ever learning and constantly fortifying ourselves spiritually. President Hinckley has said: “The forces against which we labor are tremendous. We need more than our own strength to cope with them. To all who hold positions of leadership, to the vast corps of teachers and missionaries, to heads of families, I should like to make a plea: In all you do, feed the Spirit—nourish the soul. … I am satisfied that the world is starved for spiritual food” (“Feed the Spirit—Nourish the Soul,” <span class="emphasis">Improvement Era,</span> Dec. 1967, 85–86).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p23" pid="RmHqdusaO0CDVb4yV9wZDA" hash="BN0Y7A">President Hinckley made that statement nearly 30 years ago at a general conference. Then, how much more need have we to be spiritually fortified today! Indeed, inspired gospel teaching among all members of the Church is a lifeline to the spiritual stability and growth of members of all ages.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key.p24" pid="gZOyt5QEKEGqi-2UBtFo7w" hash="a9O39Q">Technology will surely advance and methods will certainly change, but the personal touch by a dedicated, loving teacher who radiates the Spirit is the key to filling the desire of the writers of this 1899 document, which was to teach the children, and others, the “principles of the Gospel of Jesus Christ; to make Latter-day Saints of them.” In the name of the greatest teacher of all, even Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1997/10/teachers-the-timeless-key</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1997-general-conference/1997-10-4030-elder-harold-g-hillam-64k-eng.mp3" length="6270317" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 1997 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Future Leaders</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I pray that you young people will develop a reverence for sacred things, a respect for your elders, and a willingness to keep the commandments. I pray that you will learn to know of the Savior.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10033256_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="nI4kPw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="tA_jv7DNlkKnoYqUl25gJw" hash="1L9DPw">Future Leaders</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="y2ELkdjvTUCrEV1lVgERRA" hash="1w7f3g">Harold G. Hillam</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="weowacdBqk2URaJiUAikVQ" hash="rJAp7Q">I pray that you young people will develop a reverence for sacred things, a respect for your elders, and a willingness to keep the commandments. I pray that you will learn to know of the Savior.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-d3.jpg" alt="Elder Harold G. Hillam" pid="utWLcmwkNEiGNntqCgGpQg" hash="G3wzNA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders.p1" pid="MtzVNb2lhU-TeGBciEVuUw" hash="zgiZTA">During the last general conference, a relatively insignificant thing caught my attention. It was a necktie! As a choir of young boys and girls was singing, one of the TV cameras happened upon a young boy in the choir. He thought he saw himself on the television monitor but perhaps wasn’t completely sure. So this is what he did: by wiggling his tie almost unnoticeably, he knew—yes—it was really him!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders.p2" pid="qt3TjMRBT063LAHWCranyg" hash="N-JImg">This modest act triggered a flood of thoughts in my mind. Turning to look at those young boys and girls, I thought, <span class="emphasis">These children represent millions of similar other boys and girls throughout the world. What will this great Church be like when they reach the ages of the leaders here, and what part will they play in its remarkable future? Which children will hold ward or stake positions? Might a future member of the Twelve be listening to the conference or even seated here today? Which young boy will someday preside as President of the Church when it has many more millions of members?</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders.p3" pid="RHCCAL6TmU6eStHVO81c1A" hash="Nr1-0w">As these thoughts continued in my mind, I realized that you young people will need to learn so many lessons. You will have to prepare for your awesome responsibilities in a time when the adversary seems to go unchecked by the world in his opposition to all that is good and decent. You will need to learn many lessons, but let me share three lessons that I believe are essential.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders.p4" pid="2ILcL0aozU65Gic8lipHKQ" hash="CDWunw">The first essential lesson is to develop a sense of respect for things that are sacred and a respect for other people, especially your elders.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders.p5" pid="L8uyufzLq0-pRlunrG18Rw" hash="puMY6Q">The Lord taught Moses about sacred things and places. When Moses approached the burning bush that was not consumed by fire, the Lord commanded, “Draw not nigh hither: put off thy shoes from off thy feet, for the place whereon thou standest is holy ground” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/3.5" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 3:5</a>). We, too, have the opportunity to stand in holy places. Temples, church buildings, and your home should command your respect because they are sacred.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders.p6" pid="X4tnoB3k9kCCHZHSIwRRLQ" hash="1YLI7w">You will need to recognize and value all that the Lord has revealed as being sacred. One of the most significant is the sacred nature of your own body. The Apostle Paul spoke of our bodies as temples given to us from God (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/6.19" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 6:19</a>). What a tragedy if you deprived yourself of life’s opportunities by willfully disfiguring your body or numbing your mind with drugs. Don’t use your body for immoral acts. Clothe it modestly, and leave the sloppy dress craze behind. When you have the courage to dress modestly and avoid fads in clothing, you will find that self-respect is a companion of obedience and that the Lord will help you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders.p7" pid="f5tQLa99QE2qUAOp-4RTmA" hash="BWxVsA">How we act and dress reflects how we regard where we are and who we are. Let me demonstrate. One of the natural occurrences in missionary work is the change in new converts, especially little boys, young men, and fathers. When they go to Church meetings, they want to look like the missionaries. Now, that tells us a lot about the importance of looking like a member of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders.p8" pid="8QFBuYqACU2eEhZ_YC3d3g" hash="HIW99Q">The words of the prophets as found in ancient scripture and in modern-day revelation are sacred also. They are the words of the Lord to us. Treat them with respect by listening carefully and then conforming your lives to them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders.p9" pid="mgv6B2NWjkqsokU5C8OBew" hash="vPWLNA">I urge you young people to develop the habit of always showing respect, courtesy, and deference to your parents and others, especially those who are older than you. My father taught me that every person in and out of the Church has a title, such as Mr., Mrs., Brother, Sister, Bishop, Elder, or President, and that they should be addressed with respect. When I was six years old, my father reinforced this principle when I made the horrid mistake of calling our local grocer by his first name. Upon leaving the grocery store, my father taught me with firmness that I had shown a lack of respect by being so casual to an older person. I have never forgotten that experience, nor have I after 60 years forgotten the name of the grocer. I even remember his first name.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders.p10" pid="KsBMeLQwY0OsoK4Tus9JUg" hash="p9DEDA">The second essential lesson is to learn the commandments and obey them because you choose to. Before you can obey the commandments, you must know what they are. You <span class="emphasis">learn</span> the commandments by being instructed. That is why family home evening, Sunday classes, and seminary are so important. You <span class="emphasis">know</span> the commandments by the Spirit through prayer, your own personal study, and by your own personal revelation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders.p11" pid="XJQqHxi92UWWEGCWNcg2Bg" hash="n-sbQg">You need to keep your minds clean so you can recognize and respond to the quiet whisperings of the Spirit. Select with care the information you allow to enter your mind. Avoid the cluttered clamor of the world. Television, movies, and especially the Internet can provide an open window through which you can peer into the far reaches of the world. They can bring to you information that is uplifting, good, and inspiring. But if used improperly, these media technologies can fill your mind with such unwholesome thoughts that you will be unable to hear the gentle prompting of the Spirit. Live each day so that you are able to be in tune with the Spirit like the boy prophet Samuel and you are able to respond to the Lord and say, “Speak [Lord]; for thy servant heareth” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-sam/3.10" class="scriptureRef">1 Sam. 3:10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders.p12" pid="yugRw7938ke6Hwyz7A0Wfg" hash="o3Ag3Q">A third essential lesson is to develop a love for the Savior. <span class="emphasis">Knowing about</span> the Savior is a natural part of our religious education. <span class="emphasis">Knowing</span> the Savior requires personal obedience, prayer, a closeness to the Spirit, and revelation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders.p13" pid="4KuA0-pfakym7mkhfgPbAw" hash="AMyz4A">I want to speak to you teachers for a moment: you parents, priesthood leaders, bishops, stake presidents, and teachers in Primary, Young Women, Young Men, and Sunday School. The Lord has reminded everyone that “the worth of souls is great in the sight of God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:10</a>). We are all responsible to teach and lead these wonderful young men and young women and touch their lives by our example. As the song says, “How will they know unless we [tell] them?” And maybe we could add, “How will they know unless we show them?” (<span class="emphasis">Children’s Songbook, </span>182–85).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders.p14" pid="mBIKF0__SUewqn8xJ2QT3w" hash="GDn8zw">Every leader and every teacher in every part of the world has a responsibility to teach the gospel by the Spirit. The boys and girls you teach have the potential to become outstanding fathers and mothers as well as revered Church leaders of the future. May you visualize each one of them in their important future callings. Some teacher somewhere is indeed teaching a young boy who will someday sit in these seats as he serves as the Lord’s prophet. What a marvelous opportunity is yours.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders.p15" pid="Qrlv7Zi4rEuIlBa2sEoWBw" hash="p8lI2Q">And now to you, my young friend with the tie, yes, it <span class="emphasis">is</span> you. You and the millions like you, if you prepare well, will be the faithful mothers and fathers in the Church and the Lord’s future leaders. You will be the teachers and leaders that will continue to establish the Church throughout the world. You will probably want to look in the mirror periodically and remind yourselves of the great mission that lies before you, and perhaps you might even want to wiggle your tie just to remind yourself of your important mission ahead. May you stand straight and noble in your callings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders.p16" pid="xLok9Tvrak-PFOnll1yKuQ" hash="p_Neog">I pray that you young people will develop a reverence for sacred things, a respect for your elders, and a willingness to keep the commandments. I pray that you will learn to know of the Savior and have an ever-growing understanding of His Atonement. I ask the Lord to help you throughout your life to join your testimony with those of today’s living prophets and apostles, who have declared: “We bear testimony, as His duly ordained Apostles—that Jesus is the Living Christ, the immortal Son of God. He is the great King Immanuel, who stands today on the right hand of His Father. He is the light, the life, and the hope of the world. His way is the path that leads to happiness in this life and eternal life in the world to come. God be thanked for the matchless gift of His divine Son” (“The Living Christ: The Testimony of the Apostles”). To this I also testify and witness in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2000/04/future-leaders</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2000-general-conference/2000-04-1030-elder-harold-g-hillam-64k-eng.mp3" length="5612798" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Worth of Souls</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls?lang=eng</link>
      <description>When we see the effect one person can have … , it perhaps is no wonder that the Lord reminded us, “Remember the worth of souls.”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10032029_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="A1aEUg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="LdizV2R940-8HcdBbX76nA" hash="5YUyeQ">The Worth of Souls</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="eQcFC23YLEqyChhjzyaYig" hash="1w7f3g">Harold G. Hillam</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="SU8N1LDs1kSDPj0aqdH_YQ" hash="9pBLow">When we see the effect one person can have … , it perhaps is no wonder that the Lord reminded us, “Remember the worth of souls.”</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-d3.jpg" alt="Elder Harold G. Hillam" pid="M4W-d0-Tu0Syk2j6LYd1-g" hash="G3wzNA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.p1" pid="JZ341bLTyE-GrWxtWEkdag" hash="W45evg">One of the talks that has had an everlasting impression on me is one given in a Saturday evening session of a stake conference years ago. The talk was given by a young mother. Here’s what she said: “I have been doing the genealogy of my great-grandfather. He and his large family of sons and daughters were members of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.p2" pid="jK8WJyLTZEeCs_lZcNU3IQ" hash="D1bxeA">“My great-grandfather,” she said, “left church one Sunday with his family, and they never returned—no indication why.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.p3" pid="X3ioylSRVUKvDgGVxRhsig" hash="2hPEow">She then said, “In my research, I have found that my great-grandfather has over 1,000 descendants.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.p4" pid="fEloO2TtL0SUOGcdgvD_jQ" hash="PfWLfw">And then she said, and this is the part I have not been able to forget, “Of those 1,000 descendants, I am the only one active in the Church today.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.p5" pid="H0ByhYvIOUuWvAfiraNmtw" hash="ccIyVA">As she said these words, I found myself thinking, “Is it only 1,000, or could it be more?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.p6" pid="HUSYC0iSDU-XdW9ygy3aXg" hash="9TLKoQ">The answer is apparent. The spiritual influence that family might have had on their neighbors and friends did not happen. None of his sons nor any of his daughters served as missionaries, and those they would have touched with their testimonies were not baptized, and those who were not baptized did not go on missions. Yes, there are probably many thousands who are not in the Church today, and not in this very meeting, because of that great-grandfather’s decision.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.p7" pid="SagY7FJXXUmhFBM81kh7jw" hash="8NXFoA">As I heard her talk I found myself thinking, “What a tragedy! Perhaps if I had been there at that time, I could have said something to the father, to the family, to the priesthood leaders that might have helped to prevent such a calamity to their family and to so many in the future generations that would follow.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.p8" pid="TpCSySyrKUaqFXfsjPSFxg" hash="6mG_BA">Well, that opportunity of the past is lost. But we can now look to the present and to the future. I would say to those who find themselves in the same position as that great-grandfather: Would you consider what you might be doing to your family and to all those who come after you? Would you ponder the effects of your thoughts and your actions?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.p9" pid="i9f5MgM7YkaPhpjV_a_qsg" hash="qWAe2Q">If there are any concerns about Church doctrine, consider the counsel given by President Gordon B. Hinckley to a large meeting of over 2,000 members in Paris, France, last year. He said: “I plead with you, my brothers and sisters, that if you have any doubt concerning any doctrine of this Church, that you put it to the test. Try it. Live the principle. Get on your knees and pray about it, and God will bless you with a knowledge of the truth of this work.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.p10" pid="zMURSGEFTEGAYylxsZ2YFg" hash="_sWL2w">If you feel you have been wronged, be ready to forgive. If there is, for some reason, an unpleasant memory, let it go. Where necessary, talk to your bishop; talk to your stake president.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.p11" pid="cuaFtS91l0GV1j_-KRavmw" hash="_JhnKg">To all, but especially to those who some day will be great-grandfathers and great-grandmothers, your eternal blessings and those of your posterity are far more important than any prideful reason which would deny you and so many others of such important blessings. In the Book of Mormon, King Benjamin reminds us: “And moreover, I would desire that ye should consider on the blessed and happy state of those that keep the commandments of God. For behold, they are blessed in all things, both temporal and spiritual; and if they hold out faithful to the end they are received into heaven, that thereby they may dwell with God in a state of never-ending happiness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.41" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2:41</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.p12" pid="t8eZdzooFE29KEVlKJrApg" hash="1cbyEQ">To those who are children in the homes of future errant great-grandfathers, you can continue to stand faithful; you can be a good example in the home and to those around you. You can do your part to bring peace and harmony in the home and with your associates. You can be the solution, and not the cause, of problems. Remember in the Book of Mormon when Father Lehi began to murmur, it was his righteous son Nephi who gave encouragement and found solutions to problems. So many times it is the righteous children who are able to steady the boat while sailing in turbulent waters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.p13" pid="jpzEftzRbU-oiZPnA9VusA" hash="nGRX9w">To you who are bishops and stake presidents, how I wish you could have been part of the meeting I attended with a handful of regional representatives. We heard Elder L. Tom Perry as he compared those who are prospective elders and those who are not active—the future great-grandfathers—to a thermometer. We were reminded that there are many of those individuals who are more than just warm. They would come back if someone would just encourage and show the way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.p14" pid="fC33H7NhqEq6MbyPr9OGEA" hash="FLwB4A">I would like to tell you of a stake conference I was assigned to attend. It was a reorganization; the stake president and his counselors would be released, and a new presidency would be called. The stake president was young and had served wonderfully for almost 10 years. He was a spiritual giant, but he was also an administrative giant. In my personal interview with him, he told me how he had delegated much of the responsibility for the stake functions to his counselors and to the high council and had thus freed himself to interview those who needed encouragement. Individuals and couples were invited to come to his office. There he got to know them, counseled with them, and invited them to do better, to put their lives in order, and to receive the blessings available to those who follow the Lord. He helped them by putting them in the care of a capable leader, a teacher who helped them to understand the beauties of the doctrine. Then he told me that in these interviews he would often ask if they would like a blessing. “I have placed my hands on the heads of many members of the stake,” he said.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.p15" pid="XFKksRXUxUmkYAXAZLfgDA" hash="pqRSFg">The next day in the general session of the stake conference, I doubt I have ever seen so many tears—not because they felt the president should not be released, but for the deep love of a young stake president who had blessed their lives. I felt prompted to ask, “How many of you have had the hands of the president on your heads?” I was amazed at the number of people who raised their hands. I thought to myself at the time, “How many of these people will bless the name of this great man, not only now but throughout the eternities?” Yes, these will be the great-grandfathers who will, because of this loving leader, leave a legacy of generations of thousands who will call him blessed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.p16" pid="HuMxvk6kiEC0c5kQoT3l5g" hash="jZ7hXg">When we see the effect one person can have on the lives of so many, it perhaps is no wonder that the Lord reminded us, “Remember the worth of souls is great in the sight of God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls.p17" pid="VVQMNkgu10KOxe80LtfFog" hash="tu1zcQ">I pray we all might consider what we can do individually to assist those who will be the future great-grandparents, whether a little child, a teenager, or an adult, so that each will leave a righteous legacy of those who know and love the Lord. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2005/04/the-worth-of-souls</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2005-general-conference/2005-04-2060-elder-harold-g-hillam-64k-eng.mp3" length="4660672" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2005 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
