<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Helvécio Martins</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Helvécio Martins.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Helv%C3%A9cio%20Martins.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Helvécio Martins.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1990 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Value of a Testimony</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Brothers and sisters, it all began one beautiful night during April of 1972 when Elders Thomas McIntire and Steve Richards knocked on my door. At that time, I was searching for answers to many questions that confused and troubled my spirit. The princ</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_90911_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="iDAnmQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="7gAI_kaQsUGgXNDAHDWkxg" hash="mbwxqw">The Value of a Testimony</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="V3zjdXnN4E-eI_dWzX9o8g" hash="Ut8VIg">Helvécio Martins</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-20fe.jpg" alt="Elder Helvécio Martins" pid="kymtWYuxlEGSZIc-xTDh_A" hash="ZkDbMQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p1" pid="lPqV2DJIvUm5m6Nn3vQX0Q" hash="Rxwaow">Brothers and sisters, it all began one beautiful night during April of 1972 when Elders Thomas McIntire and Steve Richards knocked on my door. At that time, I was searching for answers to many questions that confused and troubled my spirit. The principles taught that night contained the answers my wife and I had searched for so anxiously.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p2" pid="f0T9O5x9DkShg-LsQgxigw" hash="rf25kA">Our hearts rejoiced upon hearing the message of the restored gospel. But one special thing deeply affected our souls: the power of the testimonies of two representatives of the Lord. A marvelous feeling that we never before had experienced filled our hearts, certifying the truthfulness of the message. Our first visit to church was an edifying experience because of the Spirit there and the love those people showed us. The spirit of the messages and testimonies was confirmatory evidence that we had found the true church. The support of the missionaries, the successful fellowshipping efforts by the members, and our combined prayers and fasting gradually changed our worldly habits.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p3" pid="2ZeeJpjL7Ee5xX4es9pktA" hash="AoCDkw">With respect and reverence, we attended the meetings and activities, but we postponed baptism because of the fear of negative reactions from our extended families.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p4" pid="xvQpMSHkD02-KS0G3P5PpA" hash="yNCYVA">The events following showed us our complete lack of wisdom, and of this we repented. The district of Rio de Janeiro met in the Tijuca chapel for its quarterly conference. A strong spirit filled the hall from the first chords of the organ prelude.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p5" pid="RpfcL3zXi0Sxv9Sk2ilg3w" hash="An4J6g">The inspired messages from the pulpit prepared our hearts for an unforgettable moment. President George A. Oakes of the Brazil North Mission, who presided in the conference, introduced Brother Val Carter, his mission counselor.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p6" pid="ilvr-P-Fc0iUopLmYwZCOw" hash="MCJcMA">After quoting selected scriptures, President Carter invited the men to stand and sing “I Need Thee Every Hour.” After sharing his testimony of the mission of our Lord, Jesus Christ, President Carter declared his complete dependence on Christ for salvation and exaltation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p7" pid="xotrbhicd0KIBdipmS7deQ" hash="0KEFOA">That experience deeply touched my heart and all my being. It was not possible to control my emotions. I could not imagine myself in tears, but the tears were indeed real. In that moment, the Holy Ghost reconfirmed the truthfulness of the things we already knew: The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints was the Lord’s kingdom on earth, the road back to the celestial mansion of our Eternal Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p8" pid="1ymnEKuF-UO99xSr0p2sJA" hash="I7-YUw">A miracle occurred in that moment, and our fears about baptism vanished. On July 2, 1972, my wife and I and our eldest son, Marcus, entered the fold through the gates of baptism.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p9" pid="xin8H6gS6EGcJ85WhuWRig" hash="-v7ctQ">Through obedience to the laws of the gospel, fasting, and service, our Heavenly Father blessed us with power to overcome fear, challenges, and eventual adversities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p10" pid="ylFU-3ZlVkC45T6VYm73vg" hash="R0LLCg">From our extended families, only one of my sisters, Ivette, has accepted the restored gospel and been baptized. Nevertheless, the remainder of the family highly respects the Church. The same miracle happened in our social and professional circles—prejudice and misunderstanding eventually subsided, and some of our best friends have accepted baptism.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p11" pid="vIOG7ArdNUG2y4btraaM2g" hash="We1_1Q">To what must we attribute such miracles? To the strength and power of the testimonies of faithful Saints upon which I was temporarily dependent. This influence aroused me intellectually and spiritually, preparing my mind and heart to receive in fulness a personal confirmation of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p12" pid="0weWUFH3bEK9-DfvuptdDQ" hash="6gRLuA">But a testimony is not a work that is merely completed and concluded. Indeed, it is a process in continuous development. Nourishing and strengthening our testimonies is essential to our spiritual survival.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p13" pid="KT8lCGB-mEatpboP7tR9pg" hash="4nOfBg">John Taylor, still a newly called elder of the Church, arrived in Kirtland while the fierce winds of apostasy were raging. Parley P. Pratt reported to him the rumors murmured against Joseph Smith. John Taylor answered:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p14" pid="mIQKN2hbnE2lWMMx6fd-TQ" hash="09GETQ">“The principles you taught me led to [Joseph], and I now have the same testimony that you then rejoiced in. If the work was true six months ago, it is true today; if Joseph Smith was then a prophet, he is now a prophet.” (In B. H. Roberts, <span class="emphasis">The Life</span><span class="emphasis">of John Taylor,</span> Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1963, pp. 39–40.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p15" pid="cEDdOVgtIkaTKyymfNW7ow" hash="YAkr0w">In the same way, Ammon and his brothers “had waxed strong in the knowledge of the truth; for they were men of a sound understanding and they had searched the scriptures diligently, that they might know the word of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p16" pid="0y14t0jE_UiQczRR2xtaDg" hash="2JcXKg">“But this is not all; they had given themselves to much prayer, and fasting.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/17.2-3" class="scriptureRef">Alma 17:2–3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p17" pid="M5XK3-bX3UmExq_eIr54xA" hash="coaSgQ">A testimony should not be hidden. It must be shared. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/62.3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 62:3</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.61" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:61</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p18" pid="M4n9ZS2xikCAmJBlhR72lQ" hash="m2jqDQ">In a remarkable address during the April session of general conference in 1973, President Harold B. Lee said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p19" pid="GY-U52_SrU-w9wSMVTDNWA" hash="5CKGoA">“For the strength of the Church is not in the numbers, nor in the amount of tithes and offerings paid by faithful members, nor in the magnitude of chapels and temple buildings, but because in the hearts of faithful members of the Church is the conviction that this is indeed the Church and kingdom of God on the earth.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> July 1973, p. 6.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p20" pid="qfFAyUkOXUSv0FeLwtKl6w" hash="HV74sg">Brothers and sisters, I am absolutely sure that you can imagine how long my journey was to arrive here. But I ask if you know what brings me here? And I hasten to answer: my testimony.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p21" pid="AdGY-AcXWEmZKRF3epD1KA" hash="ZjU0VA">It is a special gift of our Heavenly Father given through the Holy Ghost to all people who search for truth. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.4-5" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:4–5</a>.) It is wise to gain and improve a testimony of the truth because it not only helps us face our daily challenges, but it also opens our eyes, minds, and hearts to the great and marvelous things created by our Heavenly Father for our improvement and eternal happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p22" pid="xZp_VS3OLkKSq7vm2KBpJw" hash="kMSkXw">I know that God lives. Jesus Christ, our Savior and Redeemer, also lives, and we are dependent on Him for our salvation and exaltation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p23" pid="mDul45JX2EuoZ5Wu19ZuGQ" hash="qdbDeg">Joseph Smith was indeed the key prophet of the Restoration in this dispensation. The Lord speaks today through our living prophet, President Ezra Taft Benson, whom we love and follow. The Book of Mormon contains the fulness of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony.p24" pid="EMgAjnEx4ECG8AOyJXOu2A" hash="at5sIg">This testimony I witness unto you with all my heart, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1990/10/the-value-of-a-testimony</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1990-general-conference/1990-10-2050-elder-helvecio-martins-64k-eng.mp3" length="4422189" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1990 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Watchmen on the Tower”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower?lang=eng</link>
      <description>June 8, 1978, is no doubt an unforgettable day. On this day, priesthood and temple blessings were extended to all worthy male members of the Church. Memorable indeed, its impact affected the lives of uncountable multitudes—of millions who had full kn</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95905_000_021" doc-version="2" hash="sqpiQw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="jqItJweeCUOqqE3Syr3JlQ" hash="2e0-NA">“Watchmen on the Tower”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="6Dy4sJIg_USpCTjDWobtLg" hash="Ut8VIg">Helvécio Martins</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-20fe.jpg" alt="Elder Helvécio Martins" pid="Ac0Hyh9RvkSgcIsXeU8guA" hash="ZkDbMQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p1" pid="EcGDNavqlkqOct5xjy7kyg" hash="K2PMig">June 8, 1978, is no doubt an unforgettable day. On this day, priesthood and temple blessings were extended to all worthy male members of the Church. Memorable indeed, its impact affected the lives of uncountable multitudes—of millions who had full knowledge of its meaning and of many others who have not yet arrived, perhaps, to the knowledge of the full extension of its effects.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p2" pid="-odvy4IGuUmZqHLu-cthpA" hash="OgwJPg">On that date, the First Presidency announced to the whole world a new and special revelation of the Lord, which revelation was preceded by many prayers and much supplication for his divine direction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p3" pid="huMYDvU70U-ZnDdZulMrvw" hash="WpBP5A">What great changes that revelation promoted in the lives of so many children of our Father in Heaven, and among them, my humble family in the city of Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p4" pid="4cLGIoixNU6PkRRNiCB14g" hash="zqKDlA">It seemed unbelievable. It was an unexpected event, never before dreamed of by those whom the Father in his perfect wisdom preserved until this day when they would be best prepared to respond to the serious requirements of this truly honorable stewardship, which is the priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p5" pid="sNhi1MCnyUaTEmqO-yiq0A" hash="SMJttg">In spite of the relative knowledge acquired throughout the six years of membership in the true Church, my first calling as a priesthood holder was not to serve as a General Authority, or a mission president, or a bishop, or as a member of two stake presidencies. It was not to serve as an executive secretary in the stake and in the ward. My first assignment and calling was that of serving as a home teacher. This calling preceded all the others. It is interestingly significant to think of it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p6" pid="mlEeWirXrkSi6w7d1rmbdQ" hash="vBZy-A">Since then, I have considered this to be a most important and wonderful calling. In previous callings I have always been released, but this first stewardship has been kept untouched.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p7" pid="RAMbWs5iekKtwi5ZLUkneg" hash="yswZBw">“There is no greater Church calling than that of a home teacher,” taught President Ezra Taft Benson. “There is no greater Church service rendered to our Father in Heaven’s children than the service rendered by a humble, dedicated, committed home teacher” (Ezra Taft Benson, <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1987, p. 50).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p8" pid="Yhu9Cfgoh02QMLcfyp9g_w" hash="L334_w">After his resurrection, and before ascending to heaven, Jesus asked Simon Peter, “Simon, son of Jonas, lovest thou me more than these? He saith unto him, Yea, Lord; thou knowest that I love thee. He saith unto him, Feed my [sheep]” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/21.15" class="scriptureRef">John 21:15</a>). The question was repeated two more times, and Peter answered in the same manner; and the Lord replied, “Feed my sheep” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/21.16,17" class="scriptureRef">John 21:16, 17</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p9" pid="h-BdAbqOOU6VOBYD9KAIGA" hash="9jn4cg">This is the work or the stewardship of the home teacher: to feed, to nourish and quench the thirst of the sheep who are assigned to him as a shepherd.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p10" pid="NYr_IcqzD0q_CL_mUTLfrw" hash="vFqNqA">Nothing has been represented to have higher priority or more urgency in my ecclesiastical life, followed by the lives of my children, than the dedicated, loyal, and devoted fulfillment of this stewardship.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p11" pid="-pABP7U5UUWz2LTb5Wwygw" hash="EJE3bg">It is worth noting the way the Lord prepares our spirit and mind, without our realizing it, to obtain this high level of understanding.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p12" pid="pHCMmzKH8E6CK8AEmbsSkg" hash="Z0vwAg">When we were still visiting the Church as investigators, in the second week we received a phone call from the branch president, Brother Antonio Landelino Barros, who asked if it were possible for him to come visit us the following night. At the assigned hour, President Barros arrived, accompanied by two men, all formally dressed. Before the family gathered in the living room, President Barros asked permission to offer a prayer. His words were a simple, but an inspiring supplication to the Lord asking for the guidance of his Spirit and special blessings upon the family, for us to understand the purpose of that visit and to benefit from it thereafter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p13" pid="9KH4m3CV4UChLE8X4Sc18A" hash="g5HGSg">Briefly, President Barros presented a discussion on the home teaching program and introduced his companions, Brothers Nelson Bezerra dos Santos and Alfredo Orlando Torres Lima, as our home teachers and from then on our first and most direct contact with the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p14" pid="WM-8tM6bXE-hj_CK0Q3W7g" hash="Hmla3w">What a great experience! What a great opportunity and privilege to serve! Those brothers were around our family during the whole time we lived in the branch area.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p15" pid="vpDVIg0vIE-z98hvDWtS8w" hash="HdCzhQ">President Marion G. Romney taught that the home teachers “carry the heavy and glorious responsibility of representing the Lord Jesus Christ in looking after the welfare of each member” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Mar. 1973, pp. 12–13).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p16" pid="AhmccLRsNEmyt4lLS-imgA" hash="brPfZw">Every Sunday, those brothers received our family when we arrived at the chapel. They sat next to us during meetings. They taught us the hymns. They taught us about the standards of the kingdom. They called us to inform about the passing away of President Joseph Fielding Smith, and later about the calling of the new prophet, President Harold B. Lee.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p17" pid="q7n3191UekiHcBW6yid6tw" hash="Mq1_Ug">They were interested in the well-being and the progress of our family and our eventual needs. After our baptism, postponed for two months, and even after we had moved to the Tijuca Ward, these dedicated home teachers and President Barros took turns during the following three months, approximately, in regular phone calls to know if our family was well adjusted in the new ward, if everything was all right, if any help was needed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p18" pid="oEN6vapOqUChPBFMVnQ76g" hash="Bdyp6A">In spite of the change of residence, the home teachers did not feel totally released of their duties of taking care and giving attention to our family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p19" pid="NJiBdQ55p0yCAvacy5IJfQ" hash="JEoXZA">Even being sure we had new shepherds, they continued as our brothers in Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p20" pid="uloeMgvYAkyNHVYVHU0hgw" hash="gOUZQw">What a magnificent attitude! They no longer had the assignment, but they kept the Christian interest. What an extraordinary bond was established. Almost twenty-three years have passed since then. Many other home teacher companions have succeeded those first ones. Their names, with few exceptions, are vaguely remembered, but the names and images of those first servants are forever in our memories since they served as true shepherds.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p21" pid="i4traXPfsECrDOwNEBc0HA" hash="N5XkDQ">“The most worthy calling in life … is that in which man can serve best his fellow man,” taught President David O. McKay (<span class="emphasis">Instructor,</span> Mar. 1961, pp. 73–74).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p22" pid="wnw6YbLM5kKuMeqaCulThQ" hash="XJ9EeQ">Those brothers were, in fact, guardians, keepers, and very supportive. It is also worth mentioning that they fulfilled their stewardship with happy countenances, which reflected a happy state of spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p23" pid="_3_uU0bGRky2N2ZxYPOE_Q" hash="WJkUWw">It seemed as if it were an honor and a privilege for them to serve so. They seemed to understand the duties of the eldest and youngest alike, as it was taught by the Apostle Peter:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p24" pid="WabgKnXHVkS31ANiwwt6kg" hash="A0tj2w">“Feed the flock of God which is among you, taking the oversight thereof, not by constraint, but willingly; not for filthy lucre, but of a ready mind” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-pet/5.2" class="scriptureRef">1 Pet. 5:2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p25" pid="iKpf3q5ZFUmWTWtN3mabxg" hash="EgtU9w">The example of those dedicated brothers served as the foundation for the future conduct of a new priesthood holder. As I recall these experiences, myself being a home teacher now, I have a pattern very close to the model of Jesus Christ to follow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p26" pid="Cv-tFfKqZ0awGxKllpxyFw" hash="TwTWzw">Ever since then I have devoted myself with all my might, with my best efforts, to the care of assigned families, and some of my most significant experiences as a priesthood holder were lived as a home teacher.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p27" pid="jLPwOk36YEW3_i7rjplG0g" hash="-4jRqw">During the regional representatives’ seminar held on 3 April 1969, President Harold B. Lee taught that “priesthood visitors are to be watchmen on the tower.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p28" pid="v8LqCg5hEkOzIJz6jSFKfg" hash="yx8Vgg">The Lord desires to gather “his people even as a hen gathereth her chickens under her wings” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/29.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 29:2</a>), and the home teachers, and by extension the visiting teachers, have a role of high relevance for the fulfilling of the desire of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p29" pid="bd3yK4howkKFP_fZNu7HXQ" hash="jy220A">As President Ezra Taft Benson taught, “[Home teaching is] a program so vital that, if faithfully followed, it will help to spiritually renew the Church and exalt its individual members and families” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1987, p. 48).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p30" pid="Rwa9o2fpn0qV3W5ZV9i8EA" hash="sfzuWw">I pray that, as priesthood holders, we may develop a more perfect understanding of this sacred stewardship.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p31" pid="D1zkYld9ykyBn-hB-BboYg" hash="h3kXcg">God lives, as does his Son, Jesus Christ, our Savior and Redeemer. The Lord speaks today through his prophet, President Gordon B. Hinckley, whom we love and follow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower.p32" pid="0yyIdf3CekCPYx5jMVaFgw" hash="vLexDg">I bear this testimony in the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/04/watchmen-on-the-tower</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1995-general-conference/1995-04-3030-elder-helvecio-martins-64k-eng.mp3" length="5070991" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 1995 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
