<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Henry D. Taylor</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Henry D. Taylor.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Henry%20D.%20Taylor.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Henry D. Taylor.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Man Cannot Endure on Borrowed Light</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As visits are made to the stakes throughout the Church and one observes the faithful, devoted service of you brothers and sisters, he is impressed by your earnest willingness to serve the Lord and to help your fellowmen.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03006_000_7060" doc-version="2" hash="zhppqQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="UrL2HBpWVkKO8gSYglMBCA" hash="_xxkAA">Man Cannot Endure on Borrowed Light</h1><p class="authorName" guid="38abc49d-7d9c-457c-994c-70a88fe01f3d" pid="iBr76Bk6Kk2Cv39b-iYJbg" hash="xJD0UA">Henry D. Taylor</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="ce31f265-33ee-46eb-984c-276d135bfc77">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27ea.jpg" alt="Elder Henry D. Taylor" guid="8a364f6e-c686-4deb-93b6-f53b445d55da" pid="79RF8ovLNUKPhmfZRpn2zQ" hash="GdqGVA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light.p1" guid="cd30dfe2-00f3-43c4-869d-6c747e0b0e34" pid="rA6iXBcG50WSCD07th_aog" hash="E9IDNA">As visits are made to the stakes throughout the Church and one observes the faithful, devoted service of you brothers and sisters, he is impressed by your earnest willingness to serve the Lord and to help your fellowmen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light.p2" guid="fe1269f8-5f26-4e9e-8e78-c521faccf251" pid="VPHTlGMuS06Ssxs-bKKJ1g" hash="xGc6qQ">This desire to serve is based upon a strong conviction that this is truly the Lord’s work in which you are engaged. That conviction is called a testimony, an impelling, driving force that results in righteous deeds and positive actions. As one observes this dedicated service, he concludes that the underlying strength of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is in the testimonies of its individual members.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light.p3" guid="f9ea6d07-9999-4d09-a791-a72ad29ff8a5" pid="yVbRKsojsUeCfxkjZvtCnA" hash="K97sDw">Every member of the Church is entitled to know that God our Heavenly Father lives; that he is not dead. He is also entitled to know that our elder brother, Jesus Christ, is the Savior and Redeemer of the world, and that he has opened the door for us, that we, through our individual acts, may receive salvation and exaltation and dwell once again in the presence of our Heavenly Father. This assurance and witness must be earnestly sought. Heber C. Kimball, a counselor to President Brigham Young, warned the Saints in 1856 that many trials would come to test their faith; that the time would come that no man or woman would be able to endure on borrowed light. Each must gain a personal knowledge of the truth and be guided by the light within himself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light.p4" guid="0068aea1-0326-4bfa-bb2b-c8cb7aa7eaa7" pid="p7b8JSqP8keLSZKOmJoTrQ" hash="0BZaHA">President McKay assured a group of young people that a knowledge of the truth and a testimony of the gospel could come to them if even in their youth they would learn one great lesson: “That purity of heart, and a sincere heart seeking after the Savior’s guidance daily, will lead to a testimony of the truth of Christ’s gospel. …” This counsel indicates that testimonies may be gained through clean living and prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light.p5" guid="999fc787-4b10-4561-83bf-97fb338d33b8" pid="oEFWbhM1GkmEW8TUcLetRw" hash="xfr2BA">Joseph Smith, although only a youth, had faith and prayed to our Heavenly Father for an answer to a problem which was of sincere concern to him. He was blessed with a personal visitation from our Father in heaven and the Lord Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light.p6" guid="e725224e-d088-4583-a76e-20fb166d1384" pid="iRwVuttDE0GjKFXUEUqeaQ" hash="gKCD7w">Saul of Tarsus, who was a persecutor of the followers of Jesus, became Paul the apostle, defender of the Christ, following a dramatic experience while on the road to Damascus. A light was seen in the heavens, and he heard a voice saying, “Saul, Saul, why persecutest thou me?” And he answered and said, “Who art thou, Lord?” And the Lord replied: “I am Jesus whom thou persecutest: it is hard for thee to kick against the pricks.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/9.3-5" class="scriptureRef">Acts 9:3–5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light.p7" guid="2d68497c-879d-458b-a88f-570bd42690a4" pid="wP1d9ZA0ckCR-3GiaJwkcg" hash="Uw3mYg">These two incidents were rare manifestations, but the impressions made by the Holy Ghost can be equally deep and lasting. President Joseph Fielding Smith has said, “Therefore, the seeing, even the Savior, does not leave as deep an impression in the mind as does the testimony of the Holy Ghost to the spirit. … the impressions on the soul that come from the Holy Ghost are far more significant than a vision. It is where spirit speaks to spirit, and the imprint upon the soul is far more difficult to erase.” (<span class="emphasis">Seek Ye Earnestly </span>[Deseret Book Co., 1970], pp. 213–14.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light.p8" guid="850aa438-ac5d-47bd-8e2f-00fce1fb46fc" pid="MeoxakCjLkauWFEygsbF_A" hash="t5ufCQ">This truth is further illustrated by the experiences of the three witnesses to the Book of Mormon. Each of the three—Oliver Cowdery, David Whitmer, and Martin Harris—saw the angel, saw and handled the gold plates from which the Book of Mormon was translated, and heard the voice of the Lord declare that the record was true. Yet later, all three, becoming disaffected and out of harmony with the leaders, dwindled in unbelief and apostasy. But the imprint of the Spirit had been so indelible that not a single one of them ever denied his testimony, which is still printed in each copy of the Book of Mormon. The testimony of the still small voice whispering to our innermost beings is of more worth than outward signs or manifestations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light.p9" guid="1625b7a4-eee6-4062-86b3-77c7095511d7" pid="M3FkG-UCnkGkc_BL67V5oA" hash="qqGSmA">As a young man living in Kirtland, Ohio, Lorenzo Snow, fifth president of the Church, was converted and baptized in 1836. He had studiously and conscientiously compared the teachings of the missionaries with the teachings of the Savior. Becoming convinced of the truths of the gospel, he had sought baptism by immersion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light.p10" guid="e87a988c-d7d3-4069-8f9c-7192c4795e88" pid="5ef9dq-WRUyD9JupDtjC7g" hash="Eda0ag">Following confirmation, he constantly anticipated an assurance that he had received the Holy Ghost. Two or three weeks following his baptism, he reflected that he had not yet received a testimony of the truth. Being uneasy, and laying aside his books, he left the house and wandered through the fields. A gloomy spirit and indescribable cloud of darkness seemed to envelop him. It was his custom, near the close of day, to retire to a nearby secluded grove and engage in secret prayer. This night he had no inclination to do so. The spirit of prayer had departed, and the heavens seemed like brass over his head. But, determined not to forgo his evening practice, he sought his accustomed place and knelt in solemn prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light.p11" guid="64d0aafc-1242-4974-819c-e974e2ccec1e" pid="8HZvZTTvLUey9oKorbOxSQ" hash="ZI4Ndg">“I had no sooner opened my lips in an effort to pray,” recalled President Snow, “than I heard a sound, just above my head, like the rustling of silken robes, and immediately the Spirit of God descended upon me, completely enveloping my whole person, filling me, from the crown of my head to the soles of my feet, and O, the joy and happiness I felt! No language can describe the almost instantaneous transition from a dense cloud of mental and spiritual darkness into a refulgence of light and knowledge. … I then received a perfect knowledge that God lives, that Jesus Christ is the Son of God, and of the restoration of the holy Priesthood, and the fulness of the Gospel. It was a complete baptism—a tangible immersion in the heavenly principle or element, the Holy Ghost; and even more real and physical in its effects upon every part of my system than the immersion by water.” (Eliza R. Snow, <span class="emphasis">Biography and Family Record of Lorenzo Snow, </span>p. 8.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light.p12" guid="71428cef-2e85-4e79-8ea9-3184b6add3d0" pid="j6ATnaYM80CMWvzJ6jtILw" hash="ptbBRg">In this manner Brother Snow received comforting assurance as the Spirit of the Lord came upon him, and the Holy Ghost blessed him with a testimony that remained with him to the close of his earthly existence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light.p13" guid="aa56117c-ab52-4771-973b-a76ccb840332" pid="rbklMSFN2UmZ8-_5qxKFBw" hash="4rGdEA">A testimony is a priceless gift from God. But even though a person may receive a witness through the Holy Ghost, there is no guarantee that this testimony will remain steadfast unless the person exerts constant effort to keep that testimony alive. Testimonies gained may be lost through carelessness, indifference, and/or neglect.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light.p14" guid="5d2a35bb-d5ea-4417-a07e-941fa3b5a4ed" pid="15rDnb-xsEKIqyptxJdEtA" hash="c98fWA">Testimonies need to be nourished and fed. President Lee wisely counseled: “If we are not reading the scriptures daily, our testimonies are growing thinner, our spirituality isn’t increasing in depth.” (Seminar for Regional Representatives of the Twelve, December 12, 1970.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light.p15" guid="66ce7835-a568-4e52-be26-d310a9e6d8f6" pid="Lqr5rVtSpEu9VMaaMiPcjA" hash="Yik_wg">The Savior, while teaching at the temple, was questioned by the Jewish teachers as to the source of his doctrine, which was astounding to them. Whence came his wisdom? they asked. Jesus answered their troubled inquiries, saying: “… my doctrine is not mine, but his that sent me. If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it be of God, or whether I speak of myself.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/7.16-17" class="scriptureRef">John 7:16–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light.p16" guid="6e13f5cc-2178-47aa-9f25-593ddc95587a" pid="0BrbOyVT-0aBtGWYxRsyDA" hash="9rOULg">The Lord’s answer was direct and applies to us today, just as it did to the people to whom he was speaking. If we will do our Father’s will and keep his commandments, the Holy Ghost will manifest the truth unto us—it’s as simple as that. May this be our lot, I pray in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/04/man-cannot-endure-on-borrowed-light</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1971-general-conference/1971-04-7060-elder-henry-d-taylor-64k-eng.mp3" length="5264567" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Time of Testing</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The prophet Abraham found favor in the sight of the Lord. He was given the assurance that he was a great and noble intelligence before coming to this earth. He learned that the earth was created as a place for the intelligences to dwell after their b</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03012_000_1030" doc-version="2" hash="5OOtSQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="u7kqmUfiB0aO-CWrZDtoNQ" hash="A-PD0g">A Time of Testing</h1><p class="authorName" guid="38abc49d-7d9c-457c-994c-70a88fe01f3d" pid="BGC-PSiEDUO_xl0OREsbbg" hash="xJD0UA">Henry D. Taylor</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="74a1bf3a-2966-4d8f-8130-fb8d06b16add">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27ea.jpg" alt="Conference photo" guid="1c672c08-cdbf-40ec-adf0-0f20f8995b5e" pid="-pNoFri3HkSjaGFDkS9aAA" hash="GdqGVA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p1" guid="612ab38e-9544-4469-b6db-c2f41f2368e9" pid="eLoqavEjkUCzIM9jt17Ssg" hash="85ms5g">The prophet Abraham found favor in the sight of the Lord. He was given the assurance that he was a great and noble intelligence before coming to this earth. He learned that the earth was created as a place for the intelligences to dwell after their birth as mortal beings. Here they would be tested and tried to see if they would do all things that the Lord God would command them to do. Earth life would thus become a testing ground.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p2" guid="e6e6f339-5637-4330-80d9-9e730af6b843" pid="ZQwYkBV17U-am_BJNc6VrA" hash="I6BFyA">It was not intended that the earthly road would be smooth, nor would the path be easy. Satan, the father of lies and deceit, and his evil followers would be permitted to use their wiles and influence to blind men to the truth and try to lead them astray. But man was to be allowed his free agency, the right to choose. It was contemplated that God, through his prophets, would provide guidelines known as commandments, which, if followed, would bring joy and happiness. However, it would be man’s privilege and responsibility to make a choice between good and evil. He himself must make the decisions. This was all part of the gospel plan. Joseph Smith, the Prophet, has given assurance that we were present as spiritual beings at a council when the plan was presented, and we gave it our approval.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p3" guid="d2f9dba7-bd83-4f2b-9d73-ed5663cd0087" pid="XwtZ8pEma0yDKv5PwF8hwQ" hash="yByGsQ">This is a glorious time in which to live here upon the earth. The gospel and priesthood have been restored. The Church has been reestablished. While Jesus the Christ is head of the church that bears his name, men whom we sustain as prophets, seers, and revelators are giving guidance to us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p4" guid="e514f40d-5f07-412f-bef6-fb0776459b51" pid="JcEO6Dd7i069SiDK6T42HQ" hash="5FH8Ew">As we travel through life upon this earth, there come times when we must stand up and be counted. These are times of testing. Are we on the Lord’s side, keeping his commandments? Do we sustain our leaders and uphold them? Do we stand steadfast and unwavering?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p5" guid="16ff89c2-bf75-4de2-a88f-a3d423d0bb6b" pid="M2vbLBLUH0u-IDeeV--xsQ" hash="8kRIJA">Lyman Wight, known as “The Wild Ram of the Mountains,” was one of the early apostles in this dispensation. He was strong-willed, determined, and a man whom few could influence. However, he loved and respected the Prophet Joseph and was obedient to him. After the martyrdom of the Prophet, he said on one occasion, “The only man in the world that can control me is now gone.” He disassociated himself from Brigham Young and the other members of the Twelve and led a group to Texas, where he finally fell into obscurity and oblivion, while Brigham Young and the faithful went west and gained in stature and prominence. Lyman Wight was tested and found wanting.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p6" guid="f0144acf-de82-438a-83ff-05874548c884" pid="Vs8Umd_cF0i3ND9V9_E1NA" hash="mCRuxg">Simon, a fisherman, who was to be known later as Simon Peter, or Peter, was introduced to Jesus by his brother Andrew, who already had a testimony that Jesus was the Messiah.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p7" guid="ba0c15ce-2aaf-401c-b0e5-788cce6c17c2" pid="VlHJYYtNh0maE1uKmS9WiA" hash="r0_NPg">When Jesus first beheld Simon he said: ”‘Thou art Simon the son of Jona: thou shalt be called Cephas [or Peter], which is by interpretation, A stone,’ (or the Rock). … So from that time, Simon was known as Simon Peter or ‘Simon the Rock.’” (David O. McKay, <span class="emphasis">Ancient Apostles, </span>Sunday School Course of Study, 1952, p. 6.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p8" guid="40fea1be-a0bd-4958-a4c6-acc0de0243aa" pid="X-2Wds7rEkyoSBG9NSRL4A" hash="bP0wRA">The rocklike characteristics that Jesus saw in Peter were not formed all at once. Near the time when Judas was betraying the Savior, Peter three times denied knowing Jesus. But in the deep grief that followed the crucifixion of the Savior and out of the deep silence of his suffering, there finally came that strength which Christ had urged upon him ever since he called him Peter. Simon was severely tested and tried before he finally qualified as Peter the Rock.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p9" guid="fff3b965-c5d6-4a30-aca9-fa6caa5b27c0" pid="ZgJvuShP1kyaBWxbgBk-kw" hash="xe8dng">Joseph Smith, the Prophet, was tried as few other men have been tried. From that day when he testified to the world that he had been blessed by a personal visitation from God, our Heavenly Father, and his Son, our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ, all the evil forces of the adversary seem to have been turned loose upon him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p10" guid="14117e84-463c-4045-83b2-f42549e457d1" pid="sna58OYAg0eTUIHqYtyIiQ" hash="p5He3A">Slandered, maligned, tarred and feathered, unjustly cast into prisons, subjected to inhuman treatment and humiliation, his soul was deeply tried.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p11" guid="8e83c3d5-b779-413c-a0e9-d90ae957f7cc" pid="CdfKGyeUE0SD3HRBEuiHmQ" hash="dYkACg">There were times when Joseph wondered if the Lord as well as his friends had deserted him. From the very depths of his anguished soul he cried out: “O God, where art thou? And where is the pavilion that covereth thy hiding place?” He then pointed out the wrongs and unlawful oppressions inflicted upon the Saints. Then came this comforting assurance from the Lord: “My son, peace be unto thy soul; thine adversity and thine afflictions shall be but a small moment;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p12" guid="a6a2efc1-0ac0-4189-a81c-1904428d277f" pid="HiRiOT6WvkKBLLx2Am2yWA" hash="QygCLg">“And then, if thou endure it well, God shall exalt thee on high; thou shalt triumph over all thy foes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p13" guid="75096716-6443-4f12-a305-7e2bbd91bb35" pid="34gMroBPXkGs5F-NAxrk5A" hash="HXr5Ug">“Thy friends do stand by thee, and they shall hail thee again with warm hearts and friendly hands.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.1,7-9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:1, 7–9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p14" guid="6ff3c314-6966-4fbe-b808-b7c1e330721e" pid="piEWAH1pykiKR5nX2N2kNg" hash="QhOe5Q">Joseph Smith was true, faithful, and unwavering to the trust placed in him. His associates were proud to declare to the world: “Joseph Smith, the Prophet and Seer of the Lord, has done more, save Jesus only, for the salvation of men in this world, than any other man that ever lived in it. … He lived great, and he died great in the eyes of God and his people; and like most of the Lord’s anointed in ancient times, has sealed his mission and his works with his own blood. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/135.3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 135:3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p15" guid="38b60894-9e6e-405a-8ca6-90472d1500b2" pid="phh19giU0kWOWLy7ZwkC3Q" hash="BsIibA">Joseph Smith truly was tested, tried, and not found wanting. He measured up to every requirement expected of him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p16" guid="bc315374-491a-44a8-b12d-96f65d14150a" pid="D23q7SIIe0W5NBwEOp0RyA" hash="D2MCUA">Every generation since the world began has had its peculiar temptations, with Satan as their author. Today we have ours in abundance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p17" guid="69c52bd7-b23f-4c1f-b5d5-c2a1ee5c3906" pid="RO9eNOmuTkayVz57FIkQcg" hash="DQmjQg">There are those who scoff at the idea that there is a Supreme Being. They declare and teach that God is dead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p18" guid="a55f41b6-80ba-4c04-b47a-f0a4acd7078e" pid="AwcYdV08MEGiHQnFrxORwQ" hash="Tk_L2g">Others ridicule the belief that there is a life after this. They contend that death is the end, that there will be no time of judgment, no accounting for our actions here in mortality, so why not live and be merry, for tomorrow we die?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p19" guid="b266c79d-42e8-4ca9-9a34-ff6bf2f8a22f" pid="zU9VDOykpUCH_OkpH1cACg" hash="bUvmOQ">There are those who would have us believe that the use of liquor, tobacco, and drugs is not harmful or injurious to the body; that illicit sex is acceptable, and dishonesty is justified if it helps to achieve an end.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p20" guid="e5a420f9-c35a-4889-9bde-b97af8fd348d" pid="sOhDAsZCGUGiZaZn6_FulQ" hash="go1GEA">It is a temptation to become so involved in the things of the world that we lose sight of more important values, the things of the spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p21" guid="1a7bc21d-c9ca-4157-a02d-de53b6bfcea3" pid="PHb6fGWdt02Pcl3btkBNCw" hash="ETPYAg">Not only the young people of the Church have trials and temptations, but each of us does. Like the Savior, we will all have our Gethsemane. And although the road may be rough at times, if we will hold fast to the rod of iron, spoken of by Lehi, it will lead us through the mist of darkness. If we will not be dissuaded by the mocking voices of the world or lose our way and fall into the river or wander in strange roads, we will pass the challenging test of life that Abraham foresaw.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing.p22" guid="f255722d-6de2-4f4b-8967-9b21d0c90cc6" pid="TfA3n1c3lEObpl19jocGzA" hash="TJGcsw">All the effort and struggle and sorrow will be well worth it, for we will earn the greatest of all gifts, the gift of eternal life. May this be our happy lot, I humbly pray in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/10/a-time-of-testing</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1971-general-conference/1971-10-1030-elder-henry-d-taylor-64k-eng.mp3" length="4658227" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 1971 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Am I My Brother’s Keeper?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper?lang=eng</link>
      <description>After Adam had been created by the Lord in his image and after his own likeness, the Lord pointed out that it was not good for man to be alone. So Eve was created and given to Adam to be his wife, his companion and helpmeet.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03020_000_4020" doc-version="2" hash="mMO0Og"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="XzH6nAnWbky11fmG-_UljA" hash="4uWjTA">Am I My Brother’s Keeper?</h1><p class="authorName" guid="38abc49d-7d9c-457c-994c-70a88fe01f3d" pid="PHz76tiNxkCSZTo76Bg6PA" hash="xJD0UA">Henry D. Taylor</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="6da9d672-1fe1-4f0d-89fd-19d6426f668f">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27ea.jpg" alt="Elder Henry D. Taylor" guid="186e019e-b6d9-425c-ad04-8fa79995f895" pid="o_U5xaauoEKk-UMA_BDSZQ" hash="GdqGVA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p1" guid="ddc1335a-d5eb-4c43-bc4c-d303ffc6ef57" pid="HncHYhHrskGkoNXJhw0nWQ" hash="7JRqyw">After Adam had been created by the Lord in his image and after his own likeness, the Lord pointed out that it was not good for man to be alone. So Eve was created and given to Adam to be his wife, his companion and helpmeet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p2" guid="b3e68871-b7b1-4395-b362-bf3401b670fa" pid="ZcxBI7CT-UqZLEYJf7FG0A" hash="U8bIbg">Adam and Eve received many instructions from the Lord. Among them was the mandate to multiply and replenish the earth, or in other words, to bring children into the world. Without hesitation they followed that injunction, and in due time a son was born to them. How proud, how thrilled and delighted they must have been with their new child. Undoubtedly, they had wonderful dreams and high hopes for him. They gave him the name of Cain. Later they were blessed with another son, who was called Abel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p3" guid="5f3845b1-bac4-4c26-ba39-d59527a5f24a" pid="wkXRX5VhGEyQFt2f__y60A" hash="4PNSbA">The boys differed noticeably in temperament and disposition. As they matured and reached manhood, Cain became a tiller of the soil and Abel chose to become a keeper of sheep. The scriptures reveal that Abel loved the Lord. He was obedient and hearkened unto his voice. Cain was rebellious and loved Satan more than God. Out of selfishness and in a fit of jealousy, Cain rose up and slew his brother, Abel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p4" guid="1ff5a9fb-5a23-425c-a1bc-1b78c2f21e3e" pid="4LRBAnpk5UuKK4-CcQ0znw" hash="00AqRQ">When the Lord inquired of Cain, “Where is Abel, thy brother?” Cain arrogantly replied with the question, “Am I my brother’s keeper?” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/5.34" class="scriptureRef">Moses 5:34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p5" guid="92611a19-09ed-4955-87bc-5a3afef7db88" pid="-EulxN-FEE6J82BeNT0U7A" hash="BkzOFA">Over the years that question has been asked numerous times. To that question, many today would respond with firm conviction, “Yes, Cain, you are your brother’s keeper, and not only you, but each one of us is our brother’s keeper.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p6" guid="5e8ae93b-1dff-48d3-8739-814820472852" pid="h9yDQXxXwUmNEmydijImFg" hash="mctSJw">Those who labor so diligently and unselfishly with aching backs and blistered hands on welfare projects are doing so because they love their brothers and sisters and do not want them to suffer from cold nor hunger.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p7" guid="c08f06e4-57de-4098-be4b-97d6a6210409" pid="j_kRNVstuECkT6pqrKGl_A" hash="S0wc1Q">The home teachers and visiting teachers who faithfully visit their assigned families regularly to determine if all is well and in order surely believe, Cain, that they are their brother’s keeper.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p8" guid="67b5427c-a408-4ce0-acf3-a55e4cd71617" pid="Gxm9dHDXcE6nf3ZadqfTMg" hash="svcM7Q">When one visits the houses of the Lord, the temples, he is impressed by the dedicated members of the Church who have sought out their deceased loved ones through research. They attend the temples often to perform vicarious ordinances for them that will make exaltation and eternal life possible. Truly they believe that they are their brother’s keeper.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p9" guid="87e09cc8-e3bc-4516-927c-79d9dbfcec32" pid="sYTVda5crkWSPWCMk4xLGw" hash="xFLxGA">As we observe the sincere and enthusiastic labors of the thousands of missionaries throughout the world declaring the restored truth, not for their individual benefit, but to teach the glorious principles of the gospel to the peoples of the earth for their blessing, we are again impressed, Cain, that they have a conviction that they are their brother’s keeper.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p10" guid="93b994b0-0c28-44a4-a090-ad6101e8de7d" pid="C2EzBNUUokGn_9QL0Q2zxA" hash="UPN-ow">There are over 5,000 American Indian children, coming from fifty tribal backgrounds, living with Latter-day Saint families during the school year. They receive the same love and attention given to their foster brothers and sisters—a true act of love and brotherhood on the part of these families, with no reward other than the knowledge that they are helping a choice son or daughter of our Heavenly Father take his or her rightful place in the world. They too are their brother’s keeper.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p11" guid="a22aecea-ef8d-4bc5-adfe-3b1968416ff5" pid="gCjvg3xJlEKLYKTU1hgFig" hash="etMgdA">In teaching his followers, Jesus often used the scriptural terminology of <span class="emphasis">neighbor </span>in designating his brother.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p12" guid="f24cd167-1472-4a32-af7d-efce93936bbb" pid="fz31G1FBLkOLQt700IkhaA" hash="YLhziw">At one time a certain lawyer asked the Savior what he must do to inherit eternal life. The Master asked him what he read in the law. The lawyer pondered a moment and then replied: “Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy strength, and with all thy mind; and thy neighbour as thyself.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.27" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p13" guid="44b7fa5a-1780-4e9d-96c5-9e66e624cda3" pid="CXqX0aoaCEyO1VjKQGbySQ" hash="EKOMZQ">He was assured his answer was correct. In order to justify himself, he then posed the question: “And who is my neighbour?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p14" guid="c8268a79-91d8-4f35-ad5b-0ea6ac6fa53b" pid="Fcz8qwgVXkePvNdUqsCcpg" hash="QJ8jWQ">Jesus, the Master Teacher, then told of a certain man who was traveling from Jerusalem to Jericho. Thieves fell upon him, stripping him of his clothing, beating him brutally, and leaving him half dead. By chance a priest came along and, observing the wounded man, turned his head, crossed the road, and passed by on the other side. Soon a Levite came along, and when he saw the injured person, he also passed by on the opposite side of the road.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p15" guid="bc00443d-6c6e-4d69-ba87-acea0f7ee443" pid="kJ3JDNDI3E6G-gC8_-VhnQ" hash="fLNY0A">But a Samaritan riding along was filled with compassion when he viewed the unfortunate man. Stopping his animal, he bound up the victim’s wounds and poured oil and wine into the afflicted parts. Placing the suffering man upon his beast, he took him to a nearby inn, where he further ministered unto him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p16" guid="9e61e1d8-977f-4bb2-8427-ddb0feab732d" pid="-8jmLl-nzEK_YVcxfPkszw" hash="IqckIg">On the morrow when he departed, he took some money from his purse and handed it to the innkeeper, requesting him to care for the injured man and promising that he would compensate him for any additional expense incurred when he returned from his journey.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p17" guid="2e29ae7f-c819-44c6-845b-f24817a3335a" pid="_gYae4M5tUyqA-FoYB2ROQ" hash="bIHUAg">The Savior then posed the question: “Which now of these three, thinkest thou, was neighbour unto him that fell among the thieves?” To this the lawyer readily answered: “He that shewed mercy on him.” The Savior said unto him: “Go, and do thou likewise.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.36-37" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:36–37</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p18" guid="89c5064b-a46e-4cf9-8f2c-95120a9cd6f9" pid="sex3UODRWEOaHvAoLjd8HQ" hash="0BiEHg">One of the most beautiful and tender accounts of brotherly love, concern, and devotion took place in Carthage Jail on the afternoon of the martyrdom. “The afternoon was sultry and hot. The four brethren [Joseph and Hyrum Smith, John Taylor, and Willard Richards] sat listlessly about the room with their coats off; and the windows of the prison were open to receive such air as might be stirring. Late in the afternoon Mr. Stigall, the jailor, came in and suggested that [in view of threats made by the radical and bloodthirsty mob] they would be safer in the cells. Joseph told him that they would go in after supper. Turning to Elder Richards the Prophet said: ‘If we go into the cell will you go with us?’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p19" guid="85ff258d-0095-4c30-bbd5-9c5edcb3dbf1" pid="_jUMvAHlDUSHistXk5O_6Q" hash="OosShg">Elder Richards answered, “Brother Joseph, you did not ask me to cross the river with you [referring to the time when they crossed the Mississippi, en route for the Rocky Mountains]—you did not ask me to come to Carthage—you did not ask me to come to jail with you—and do you think I would forsake you now? But I will tell you what I will do; if you are condemned to be hung for ’treason,’ I will be hung in your stead, and you shall go free.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p20" guid="ea8df6f1-1fb1-4bb8-a31e-e393af7062f1" pid="Quj-JlSfNUWMw_2x5w0R1Q" hash="gDNQNg">With considerable emotion and feeling Joseph replied, “But you cannot,” to which Brother Richards firmly replied, “I will.” (B. H. Roberts, <span class="emphasis">A Comprehensive History of the Church, </span>vol. 2, p. 283.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p21" guid="bede1f70-2c04-4e81-862b-4ea41ef497fc" pid="R1VQncWFck22LuIWF1Jh8A" hash="t50Gug">In these words Brother Richards displayed his concern for Joseph, who was his beloved brother and neighbor. The Savior taught: “Greater love hath no man than this, that a man lay down his life for his friends.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/15.13" class="scriptureRef">John 15:13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p22" guid="eccf4422-2012-41d8-97eb-fdd67fae397c" pid="jDP6MXdBTkuzh5jRElqSPg" hash="PWlHzg">As Latter-day Saints, we firmly believe that we are brothers and sisters, spiritual offspring of heavenly parents, members of a royal family who once dwelt and associated together. There is a beautiful song that our children sing called “I Am a Child of God,” which teaches that our Heavenly Father has sent us here and has given us a home on earth with kind and dear parents. The song contains the prayer that our Father in heaven will direct us, inspire us, and teach us what we must do to again live with him some day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p23" guid="cb8ed3f6-89f0-4cbf-8a79-11ac1a76e907" pid="-2C6DbDiFkuAXbsIu3C6nw" hash="6UdQHA">With the dawning of each new day, there will be opportunities for all of us to help our neighbors, who are our brothers, in their hour of need.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p24" guid="d12fb10f-00bc-4214-941e-3fc26e113cd1" pid="utcwnONXVk2gyT-U1NTJyA" hash="avuj3w">How will we respond? Will we be like the priest and like the Levite described by the Savior, and turn our heads, walk across the road, and proceed in an unconcerned and selfish way?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p25" guid="2e624cae-0ffd-4c66-bbe8-2a775304b6ee" pid="IVYWhKUkyk6ZrouOxetlWg" hash="h9fsnw">Or will we follow the example of the Good Samaritan and thoughtfully and sympathetically assist our neighbors and brothers in their time of trial, and thus receive approbation and the blessings of our Heavenly Father?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper.p26" guid="5561ce9e-d843-48b5-b829-7c84af41d2e8" pid="IgrQLQbiaUGTxByRg8U9qw" hash="qVHWIA">The choice is ours to make. May the Lord bless us that our decisions will be correct and righteous ones, for which I humbly pray, in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/04/am-i-my-brothers-keeper</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1972-general-conference/1972-04-4020-elder-henry-d-taylor-64k-eng.mp3" length="5419496" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“And Always Remember Him”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him?lang=eng</link>
      <description>On the evening of his betrayal, Jesus met with his Twelve Apostles in an upper room guest chamber in Jerusalem to observe the annual Feast of the Passover.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03033_000_3040" doc-version="2" hash="huGDAw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="OYCPHikquku98O7klL6qYw" hash="GXHvpA">“And Always Remember Him”</h1><p class="authorName" guid="38abc49d-7d9c-457c-994c-70a88fe01f3d" pid="RyRS4bd5cECtG8hTybo8oA" hash="xJD0UA">Henry D. Taylor</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="84dbd296-248f-414b-ad3f-2a4484bfec28">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p1" guid="4c758a19-1dc2-40b9-88f0-fab68ae38a09" pid="artdfHSd60qw0TU_3jNSwA" hash="nySWyQ">On the evening of his betrayal, Jesus met with his Twelve Apostles in an upper room guest chamber in Jerusalem to observe the annual Feast of the Passover.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p2" guid="c7270a05-2931-4a82-a17a-09c0173a80e8" pid="Kx4BaiKGV0qmnms_n19-0g" hash="bWmp2Q">Previously, Judas Iscariot, one of the Twelve, had bargained with the chief priests and had agreed to betray the Lord for a price of 30 pieces of silver. Jesus, being aware of this treachery, sat at the table with the Twelve. He said sorrowfully: “Verily, I say unto you, that one of you shall betray me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/26.21" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 26:21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p3" guid="4d2db392-8e02-4dc4-95f3-e7c23ef59e58" pid="HnZE8SP1PUCSRhybaCCJ1g" hash="wn-VdQ">After they had eaten, Jesus blessed the bread and wine and in a simple but impressive manner instituted the sacrament of the Lord’s Supper.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p4" guid="faa2be3e-3876-4419-9841-4940e4b63d8c" pid="MEJZOMkGYU6s0jCpXcFsuQ" hash="ha9umg">A beautiful, inspirational discourse was then delivered by the Savior, who concluded the sermon with a prayer. Before they left the guest chamber in the building, a hymn or psalm was sung. Then Jesus and the 11 apostles departed. Judas had previously left the group to meet the enemies of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p5" guid="b0af5d50-c1bb-4132-b568-0aa16642204f" pid="fligD5aw20qIbNPWS8U3ig" hash="SP4urQ">Jesus and his associates passed through one of the several gates in the wall of Jerusalem, crossed over the brook called Cedron, and entered an olive orchard, known as Gethsemane, on the slope of Mount Olivet. This was a favorite meeting place for the Lord and his apostles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p6" guid="79f57d2e-1470-43e3-ba96-97f433f242b1" pid="-V-w8E3LqUmseGhIj79nFw" hash="3jxcuw">Entering the garden, Jesus asked eight of the apostles to remain behind; then with Peter, James, and John, he went a short distance, where he requested them to wait and watch. Going on alone a little ways, he knelt and prayed to his Father, saying: “O my Father, if it be possible, let this cup pass from me [but then came this beautiful lesson]; nevertheless, not as I will, but as thou wilt.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/26.39" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 26:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p7" guid="6f671141-e21d-419b-b923-1bded313a0b6" pid="xN6tW3nomEGFbMLA9KRYRA" hash="BJIMUw">Three times he prayed, and we read: “And being in agony he prayed more earnestly: and his sweat was as it were great drops of blood falling to the ground.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/22.44" class="scriptureRef">Luke 22:44</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p8" guid="ea47fd93-0c88-451c-890e-b4704db66cb0" pid="Akv3L4_bOEKWUUh-FgMSnw" hash="cYd9DA">Elder James E. Talmage, a member of the Twelve in our dispensation, made this observation: “Christ’s agony in the garden is unfathomable to the finite mind, both as to intensity and cause. The thought that He suffered through fear of death is untenable. Death to Him was preliminary to resurrection and triumphal return to the Father from whom He had come, and to a state of glory even beyond what He had before possessed; and, moreover, it was within His power to lay down His life voluntarily.” Then Elder Talmage testifies: “In some manner, actual and terribly real, though to man incomprehensible, the Savior took upon Himself the burden of the sins of mankind from Adam to the end of the world.” (<span class="emphasis">Jesus the Christ, </span>p. 613.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p9" guid="cbabf6b3-ead4-417e-ad99-2bee2287afea" pid="zxFzMhAbJ0SwqFgrqiO7-Q" hash="jjBwIg">Following the Savior’s crucifixion and resurrection came the long dark night of the apostasy. Finally the heavens were reopened and the voice of the Lord was heard again on the earth. The gospel and priesthood were restored, and the church of Jesus Christ was reestablished in these latter days. Then from the Lord came this admonition to the members of the Church: “And that thou mayest more fully keep thyself unspotted from the world, thou shalt go to the house of prayer and offer up thy sacraments upon my holy day.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p10" guid="4d7cab71-7eb4-4866-ad35-5736880b1e68" pid="qEiABkXA7EO6E8BpDJkXaA" hash="85f0og">And then the Lord further instructed: “It is expedient that the Church meet together often to partake of bread and wine in the remembrance of the Lord Jesus.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.75" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:75</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p11" guid="a9f18d3a-e2c1-4c56-9693-5e3f040b49b3" pid="QgBEdDq8w0-YOUWVm0-Tdw" hash="OsbIDg">In these words was the sacrament of the Lord’s Supper authorized in our day, the dispensation of the fulness of times. The bread and water, duly consecrated by prayer, become emblems of the Lord’s body and blood, to be partaken of reverently and in remembrance of him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p12" guid="73ab4d30-360a-43b3-a57f-ea6d1c50bb26" pid="FHYq6XfF1EOp442p1bKwyw" hash="O2Ccgg">The sacrament is a sacred and solemn service. As we partake of the sacrament, we make covenants with the Lord. This is not unusual, because Latter-day Saints are a covenant-making people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p13" guid="dff830cc-6421-47f2-a40e-585dbe331dd5" pid="pi-L2MuAjUOoyUxk_VKidg" hash="y82WQg">There are few set prayers in the Church, and the sacramental prayers, which came from the Lord by revelation, are two of them. We should listen attentively as the prayers are given and realize—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p14" guid="1e5564f3-abcd-40e5-8c37-b8255adb9bb4" pid="iQG4MNEvI0-wySbLF3_D0A" hash="PZRK_g">First, that the bread and water are in remembrance of the body and blood which the Savior shed for us;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p15" guid="e6dce436-13c4-40f2-bbcd-70b98d1c4fdb" pid="U6bGXi6PfUuOzUK9Dx-2Jg" hash="hHwZQw">Secondly, that we pledge to take upon ourselves the name of the Lord Jesus;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p16" guid="1e4ae77b-7357-4c1e-9c55-ab4f897a1a7f" pid="3oinL1lkq0Shc7zPDNN6UQ" hash="lSpuug">Thirdly, that we will keep the commandments that he has given us; and,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p17" guid="42a84555-9d6d-4ffc-934c-a9f08f19a3fb" pid="jlLk5onqL02jbgRz5NF8cA" hash="dThyjg">Fourthly, that we promise we will always remember him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p18" guid="ac99da1a-5195-42e2-80e2-31b5418ad5fc" pid="c2iYfBg4Ek2-NvzIz3fdzQ" hash="GSrWaQ">There is one part of the prayer that I should like to emphasize. It is this: “that we will always remember him.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p19" guid="040f4153-39ea-4bf5-ba46-e566e35e120e" pid="OcWUFv5NSkuJI8o7CvZO4w" hash="kYiLCA">Of what do we think when we remember Jesus Christ, the Savior?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p20" guid="a9e9bba9-b6bb-45f2-a8c8-66e68ef66de5" pid="hRaY_JCvsEmXzCqs7xhtJA" hash="N6FSLQ">Do we think or remember that he is a member of the Godhead or Trinity, together with God our Eternal Father and the Holy Ghost, the three personages comprising the great presiding council of the universe?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p21" guid="56767ad1-9cc4-435e-8480-5127c8df4dfb" pid="rhB4x4m9U02yOl6sAhTB3w" hash="PZIIRA">Do we recall that Jesus was the Creator of this world and the chief executive in carrying out the wishes of the Father? John the Beloved, who referred to the Savior as “the Word,” gives this testimony: “In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p22" guid="50b6045e-8477-4f85-bf71-3ebc32571fda" pid="l_m9e-DuQk22pmFnqiRgPA" hash="4MAl9A">“The same was in the beginning with God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p23" guid="ecb06c7f-5d2b-4605-879c-6d4f0c5df5b3" pid="UgrB5e1wqkuN5ODYlYH7sQ" hash="i2KYcw">“All things were made by him; and without him was not anything made that was made.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/1.1-3" class="scriptureRef">John 1:1–3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p24" guid="20f82eea-8252-4895-bd45-3d12b025a6a3" pid="B4odhNuECEyN9ciXY-PSDw" hash="RALrkw">Do we remember that at the great council in the heavens in which we participated as preexistent spiritual beings, he presented a plan in which he offered his life, and that he was willing to suffer death to atone for the sins that would come into the world? In doing this he would assure us of a resurrection from the dead, and he would make salvation possible for us, his brothers and sisters, and thus become our Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p25" guid="a5c0bdb2-d053-4d50-b9ea-f05b9169e627" pid="hpsk1CJCdkCdgE-BDAgilQ" hash="CPYyRw">Do we remember his intense agony and suffering in the Garden of Gethsemane, as he took upon himself the sins of mankind?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p26" guid="9a329881-8f2d-4635-80da-483d1590aef8" pid="8xpbsRwD-0WfsF9Sy_MoiA" hash="7F269Q">As we partake of the sacrament, do we remember that we enjoy membership in the restored church which bears his name; do we resolve that we will strive to demonstrate our appreciation by responding to calls and assignments made by our leaders; and do we commit ourselves to do everything within our power to help build up his church?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p27" guid="fdc04640-7cbd-4326-a8fe-224a2787a9c4" pid="TywtRewslEahUV6wigH7Mg" hash="UWmLDQ">And, finally, do we remember the promises and assurances given to us by the Savior, that he will return once again, in what is referred to as his second coming? Do we remember that those who are faithful and keep his commandments may again have the privilege of entering his presence and that of our Father in heaven?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p28" guid="02af0001-077f-4176-a673-5a7e215cec26" pid="wIDcKet9dUKdJKo-FCKh3Q" hash="cXT1mQ">We learn, then, from the beautiful sacramental prayers that, first, the bread and water are taken in remembrance of the body and of the blood that the Savior shed for us; secondly, that we pledge to take upon us the name of the Lord Jesus Christ; and thirdly, we promise that we will always remember him, and that we will keep the commandments which he has given us. And if we do these things, we are then in a position to realize the meaningful promise: “that we may always have his Spirit to be with us.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p29" guid="87d5459a-3bac-4018-ad2b-94328ef62229" pid="TuqL3b04OkS033szibgZAA" hash="GRaZDw">What a wonderful blessing it would be if we could always have the Spirit of the Savior in our lives to guide and direct us!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p30" guid="27fa76ea-d699-4299-a0f4-71358b512ffa" pid="oqzpOuGrx0Cu0Q0lJZfkVQ" hash="IWa8ag">While Wilford Woodruff was crossing the ocean on his final mission to Great Britain, he testified that the martyred Prophet, Joseph Smith, and his brother Hyrum appeared to him in his cabin aboard the ship. The vessel had been caught in a terrible storm, which had abated as a result of the prayers of the brethren. Hear Brother Woodruff’s own words of what happened: “The night following [the storm] Joseph and Hyrum visited me, and the Prophet laid before me a great many things. Among other things, he told me to get the Spirit of God, as we all needed it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p31" guid="8bd5c5c1-f752-4bd3-a7f3-5d5c56f4d0ef" pid="_omNwhLvgUiKKenLTY_Qrw" hash="ZhjiPA">Many years later Brigham Young, after his death, also appeared to Brother Woodruff and said virtually the same thing—the importance of gaining and keeping the Spirit of the Lord in our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p32" guid="bb9c1888-7329-43e1-9e0a-296a5f7c378c" pid="G3xrY-zfa0OjM1K-lQEFMg" hash="PGgV0g">One of the surest ways to obtain and retain the Spirit of the Lord is to so live and keep ourselves unspotted from the sins of the world that we can partake worthily of the Lord’s Supper each week as we attend our sacrament meetings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him.p33" guid="53d446f4-b6ea-406a-93ee-e0205a66ba7e" pid="0vCsxT-LC0y-Q7IOXK8ovw" hash="oZUeYw">That we may do this and thus obtain the blessings predicated upon this law, is my humble prayer, which I ask in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1973/04/and-always-remember-him</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1973-general-conference/1973-04-3040-elder-henry-d-taylor-64k-eng.mp3" length="5399391" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 1973 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thou Shalt Love Thy Wife with All Thy Heart</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart?lang=eng</link>
      <description>After the Lord had created Adam, he made it crystal clear that he did not intend that Adam should go through life without a companion, when he said: “It is not good that the man should be alone; I will make him an help meet for him.” (.) So Eve was c</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03040_000_2040" doc-version="2" hash="JU8qSw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="v2Z7KR7aa0mwT8Ol7LeGqg" hash="pAENww">Thou Shalt Love Thy Wife with All Thy Heart</h1><p class="authorName" guid="38abc49d-7d9c-457c-994c-70a88fe01f3d" pid="kAC4N_05ckO_ygq2UfZwbQ" hash="xJD0UA">Henry D. Taylor</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="1f11617f-5288-485e-ab29-9005835e6ac0">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p1" guid="dd2b7eb0-3a9f-48d4-bb26-99af67789535" pid="YnKWMWx8oUGeBdi6L-XBgA" hash="nKBUrQ">After the Lord had created Adam, he made it crystal clear that he did not intend that Adam should go through life without a companion, when he said: “It is not good that the man should be alone; I will make him an help meet for him.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/2.18" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 2:18</a>.) So Eve was created and given to Adam to be his wife and companion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p2" guid="6dc1012b-9573-4940-8ab8-7c3406002064" pid="DTLVxsi2dka93OPiNh7LYw" hash="9nKCfg">Many of you young people in the Church have reached an age where you are old enough to look for a companion and mate. As you commence dating on a steady basis, you will enter a period known as courtship. This will be a thrilling and important time in your lives. President McKay referred to it in these words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p3" guid="5dbbc794-69e4-4dd2-81ed-c6f8ac549f04" pid="840AVTeqqEKmNJ9gsH6gZg" hash="fRdSJA">“Courtship is a wonderful period. It should be a sacred one. That is the time in which you choose your mate. Young men, your success in life depends upon that choice. Choose prayerfully the one who inspires you to your best and always remember that no man injures the thing he loves. … The seeds of a happy marriage are sown in youth. Happiness does not begin at the altar; it begins during the period of youth and courtship. …”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p4" guid="9663368f-a5af-44c2-b472-c21f4a38601c" pid="RNjmTNUbl0mxInmxF50ScA" hash="G9NAhg">Young people, choose prayerfully and carefully. Don’t rush hastily into marriage. Determine that you have common goals and interests. Especially be certain that you possess the same religious convictions and beliefs.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p5" guid="6d2cf050-ed8e-4a30-8b59-7bf8c7707071" pid="el6szA2KiEOOOJBVzRfr4w" hash="iof-Pw">A wise man once counseled: “Before marriage keep thine eyes wide open, then after marriage keep them half closed.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p6" guid="9a90aa45-0889-4f80-8049-233da41f7aee" pid="9JfO8nFkmU-PBmL9q-HV4g" hash="VV8c8g">Marriage brings adjustments, because each has his or her own personality. Reared in homes with varying backgrounds, marriage naturally will require the making of adjustments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p7" guid="c3992d11-181d-4d0d-9b44-3fa782130c32" pid="VgsMAPZJdUSGeW-V1ISclA" hash="B3TnLw">Marriage, my beloved young brothers and sisters, should not be just taken for granted. It must be worked at, but realize that you can have the kind of marriage that you earnestly desire and for which you are willing to work. Marriage will require giving and taking; it will mean sharing, because life was meant to be shared. A happy and successful marriage means forgetting oneself and thinking of ways in which to make one’s companion happy. It might be well each day for the husband to think, “What can I do today to make Mary happy?” And Mary should say to herself, “What can I do today to make John happy?” A happy Home is where the wife is treated like a queen and the husband is treated like a king. And so, it is not only marrying the right partner, it is <span class="emphasis">being </span>the right partner.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p8" guid="6f862153-a49d-40ed-a626-0d1bc0daa903" pid="uUOtVHSgL0We3Ighvo5Ivw" hash="mb4w8g">A happy and successful marriage will be one that is built on the important principle of love; a love recognizing not only a fleeting physical attraction, but more importantly a deeply spiritual love that will continue forever. At the dedication of the beautiful Oakland Temple, the prophet of the Lord, David O. McKay, emphasized the fact that love is eternal in these words: “One great purpose carried out by those who come into the temple is the sealing of man and wife in the sacred bonds of matrimony. That purpose is based upon the fact that man and woman truly love each other. That means that a couple coming to the altar should be sure that there is love in each heart. It would be a terrible thing to be bound for eternity to one whom you do not love, but it is a glorious thing to be sealed for time and eternity to one whom you do love.” President McKay then continued, saying: “Let us ever remember that love is the divinest attribute of the human soul. … love must be fed; … Love must be nourished; love can be starved to death just as literally as the body can be starved without daily sustenance. … If that love is fed daily and monthly and yearly throughout a lifetime, the husband’s attention will not be drawn to somebody else. …” He then concluded with these words: “If your spirit lives after death, as it does, then that attribute of love will persist. …” (David O. McKay, “Responsibilities of Those Who Enter the Temple,” <span class="emphasis">Improvement Era, </span>vol. 68 [1965], p. 92.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p9" guid="45b8becd-9a99-4064-953f-49f7d9d2b721" pid="8Qnsaa4Qjkek4Tk3MtsUQQ" hash="u7t6vQ">Honeymoons should not end right after the marriage ceremony, but should never cease. President and Sister McKay set a wonderful example to the Church and to the world. On their 65th wedding anniversary President McKay referred to their married life as 65 years of “wedded courtship.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p10" guid="496cb25c-7b9f-433e-98bb-b070e6ddba93" pid="TXEXufTKREKU5bPwtux47g" hash="S9c2fg">There are many kinds of marriages, but Latter-day Saints should realize that there is only one place on earth where one can obtain a first-class marriage, and that is in a House of the Lord, and it is one of the purposes for which temples are built. What a worthwhile and splendid tradition it is for those who are married and sealed in the temple to return each year on or near their wedding anniversary and recall the promises they have made to each other and to the Lord. Of course, this will be in addition to the many other times that they will attend the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p11" guid="8db09d30-9477-48d2-ac6b-6b1202ed0d43" pid="nN9ES0IUr0SJnmL8GZTJjA" hash="3OBl9Q">We are mindful that the Church has constantly stressed the importance of the home. Many valuable and worthwhile suggestions and programs have been introduced to point to ways in which a happy home may be realized.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p12" guid="9388a82a-ce37-40fa-a5de-4c88427aa6df" pid="bwzBrB6H8E6g6Ihj_BPSXA" hash="sRuOzA">I am convinced that a happy home is the result of a happy marriage: that is why it is so important to select a suitable companion and mate.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p13" guid="5851de5b-4972-445d-882a-73b6fd6d2e4f" pid="7HVCRrdkCUybt6ogx4l7-A" hash="DaqzxA">In our world today there is an apparent disregard for the marriage vows made, and we view with concern and alarm the noticeable increase in divorces throughout the land. This would indicate that homes are not happy and, as a result, marriages are failing. Too many men and women become discontented and develop a “roving eye” as their attention is attracted to someone else. Hence, too many divorces are a result of unfaithfulness on the part of the wife, the husband, or both. There would be fewer divorces if the counsel and guidance given by the Lord were followed. In a revelation to the Prophet Joseph he said: “Thou shalt love thy wife with all thy heart, and shalt cleave unto her and none else.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:22</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p14" guid="6b686518-5a7b-4904-884d-b57daa1bccbd" pid="vug7-Y1hMUylqheyAJ8LUQ" hash="1qJgTw">I am persuaded that many divorces today could be avoided and are not justifiable. President Stephen L Richards, a former counselor in the First Presidency, once aptly remarked: “In the case of marital disagreement, which may lead to separation, the proper remedy is not divorce, but <span class="emphasis">repentance—repentance </span>usually on the part of both husband and wife, repentance for both acts committed and harsh words which have made a ‘hell’ instead of a ‘heaven’ out of the home.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p15" guid="715960aa-1ad8-4aeb-b1de-b3f8688d7efa" pid="Us-xllhE0keXTFtvDFXGdQ" hash="kM2mHA">In order for a married couple to make a “heaven” out of their home, they must realize that repentance, love, faithfulness, humility, and forgiveness are basic essentials in achieving this noble and lofty goal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p16" guid="29cc303a-f697-4c8a-a579-fbe9ac1df629" pid="EWjIda1nukOf_lsfA2DVZg" hash="-nToNg">A serene home must also be a place where the Spirit of the Lord will dwell and abide. The Spirit of the Lord will not dwell nor abide in a home where there is constant bickering, quarreling, arguing, discord, or disharmony.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p17" guid="d66e214f-243d-45c1-93ba-7f77c62d3402" pid="RY2nXeh4kUSdSQ1Otpoowg" hash="RA4ksw">The Prophet Joseph had to learn many of these valuable lessons, as we will likewise have to do. David Whitmer, a close associate of the Prophet and one of the Three Witnesses for the Book of Mormon, related an enlightening experience which occurred while the prophet was translating the gold plates. These are Brother Whitmer’s words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p18" guid="46d98756-2a2d-4bad-a168-ed37f0bdb105" pid="e1t-X7bXUUiOp3Fyd8yZuw" hash="S9PwAg">“He [Joseph] was a religious and straightforward man. He had to be; for he was illiterate and could do nothing himself. He had to trust in God. He could not translate unless he was humble and possessed the right feelings towards everyone. To illustrate so you can see: One morning when he was getting ready to continue the translation, something went wrong about the house and he was put out about it. Something that Emma, his wife, had done. Oliver and I went upstairs and Joseph came up soon after to continue the translation but he could not do anything. He could not translate a single syllable. He went downstairs, out into the orchard, and made supplication to the Lord; was gone about an hour—came back to the house, and asked Emma’s forgiveness and then came upstairs where we were and then the translation went on all right. He could do nothing save he was humble and faithful.” (Brigham H. Roberts, <span class="emphasis">A Comprehensive History of the Church, </span>vol. 1, p. 131.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart.p19" guid="3e0d867c-21f7-44c4-9038-1d323b2ffea3" pid="llWPNjS_E0C4bbib8FUxxA" hash="U4n3Fg">It is my sincere and humble prayer that we may all live in such a way that we will have happy and serene homes where love abounds and the Spirit of the Lord is ever present, for which I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, our Lord and Savior. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1973/10/thou-shalt-love-thy-wife-with-all-thy-heart</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1973-general-conference/1973-10-2040-elder-henry-d-taylor-64k-eng.mp3" length="5550847" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 1973 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“I Will … Pour You Out a Blessing”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing?lang=eng</link>
      <description>With the rising cost of goods and services, inflation marches steadily onward. These increases result in hardships for many but especially upon individuals and families with fixed incomes. There are so many demands on each available dollar that const</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03044_000_040" doc-version="2" hash="P0LlRA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="IguWdjZ_MEq71RIcrBwvOg" hash="bX_34g">“I Will … Pour You Out a Blessing”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="m_uB4kJkOkKZ4hsc7Su2WQ" hash="xJD0UA">Henry D. Taylor</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p1" pid="sLbD-MZ590OIfV0HPHvjaA" hash="Xyj6yQ">With the rising cost of goods and services, inflation marches steadily onward. These increases result in hardships for many but especially upon individuals and families with fixed incomes. There are so many demands on each available dollar that constant adjustments are necessary to make ends meet. One frustrated person remarked: “I just get my affairs to the point where I think that I can make ends meet when something breaks loose in the middle.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p2" pid="FDxg0_UR_ESi3RDdqNE_BQ" hash="dLEOpg">Centuries ago the Lord through a prophet gave a formula that gives a solution for these problems, when he said to Malachi: “Bring ye all the tithes into the storehouse, that there may be meat in mine house, and prove me now herewith, saith the Lord of hosts, if I will not open you the windows of heaven, and pour you out a blessing, that there shall not be room enough to receive it.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/3.10" class="scriptureRef">Mal. 3:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p3" pid="q6g_wbLAtUm5gIc0WuA24A" hash="10wqIQ">Frequently we hear the expression “I can’t afford to pay tithing.” Persons who make such statements have not yet learned that they can’t afford <span class="emphasis">not</span> to pay tithing. There are many members who from experience can and do testify that nine-tenths carefully planned, budgeted, and spent wisely, with the blessings of the Lord, will go much farther than ten-tenths spent haphazardly without planning and without the Lord’s blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p4" pid="IaU5_OOXh0uElk3hwbRNoQ" hash="IiDfwA">The payment of tithing is a test of our faithfulness and loyalty. President Joseph F. Smith, many years ago, counseled: “By this principle (tithing) the loyalty of the people of this Church shall be put to the test. By this principle it shall be known who is for the kingdom of God and who is against it.” (Joseph F. Smith, <span class="emphasis">Gospel Doctrine,</span> Deseret Book Co., 1939, p. 225.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p5" pid="Ylltoepob0acncBM_0Y3XQ" hash="w2ffmw">Often the question is asked, “What is a tithe?” Joseph L. Wirthlin, a former Presiding Bishop of the Church, gave a clear definition when he explained: “The very word itself denotes one-tenth. A tithe is one-tenth of the wage earner’s <span class="emphasis">full income.</span> A tithe is one-tenth of the professional man’s <span class="emphasis">net income.</span> A tithe is one-tenth of the farmer’s <span class="emphasis">net income,</span> and also one-tenth of the produce used by the farmer to sustain his family which is a just and equitable requirement, as others purchase out of their income such food as is needed to provide for their families. A tithe is one-tenth of the dividends derived from investments. A tithe is one-tenth of net insurance income less premiums if tithing has been paid on the premiums.” (<span class="emphasis">Conference Report,</span> April 1953, p. 98. Italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p6" pid="2auDVHftO0CUupnjhX6vhA" hash="s_bRlA">Several presidents of the Church have explained that the payment of tithing is an individual and a personal matter and that it is a voluntary contribution. Brigham Young in the early days of the Church taught the Saints, saying: “We do not ask anybody to pay tithing unless they are disposed to do so; but if you pretend to pay tithing, pay it like honest men.” (“Brigham Young on Tithing,” <span class="emphasis">Improvement Era,</span> May 1941, p. 282.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p7" pid="oTvEFrVrP0aj5kp3oC-ydg" hash="5ZIJyA">Years later President Grant advised the people in these words: “The Lord, you know, does not send collectors around once a month to collect bills; He does not send us our account once a month; we are trusted by the Lord; we are agents; we have our free will. …” (Heber J. Grant, “Settlement,” <span class="emphasis">Improvement Era,</span> Jan. 1941, p. 9.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p8" pid="ljmDeWKAR0-8j0I6GL6F8Q" hash="6nVylg">There is merit in paying tithing when one receives the income or increase, although farmers and others operating their own businesses usually find it necessary to calculate their increase on an annual basis. Again, President Grant, speaking from years of experience and observation, suggested: “The payment of our tithing in the season thereof—when we get our income—makes it come easy. I find that those who pay tithing every month have very much less difficulty in paying it than those who postpone payment to the end of the year. …” (Heber J. Grant, <span class="emphasis">Gospel Doctrine,</span> p. 9.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p9" pid="y1BYtl1fJU2k07W3fBSNDQ" hash="2vn9dg">The law of tithing has come from the Lord as a commandment, and when we keep that law and commandment we are entitled to the blessings that are promised, for the Lord has said: “I, the Lord, am bound when ye do what I say; but when <span class="emphasis">ye do not</span> what I say, ye have no promise.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/82.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 82:10</a>. Italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p10" pid="d5Qm-mqsAkiM_O-lDCanrw" hash="LdoXgw">In the early days of the Church there was a good and faithful woman, Mary Smith, widow of the martyred patriarch Hyrum Smith. She firmly believed in the promises of the Lord. Her son, Joseph F., and her grandson, Joseph Fielding, lived to become presidents of the Church. President Joseph F. Smith related an incident that occurred when he was a 10-year-old boy:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p11" pid="3gQlhJdIrUCIkeUfj9MSBw" hash="Rz_VYA">“I recollect most vividly,” he said, “a circumstance that occurred in the days of my childhood. My mother was a widow with a large family to provide for. One spring when we opened our potato pits she had her boys get a load of the best potatoes, and she took them to the tithing office; potatoes were scarce that season. I was a little boy at the time, and drove the team. When we drove up to the steps of the tithing office, ready to unload the potatoes, one of the clerks came out and said to my mother, ‘Widow Smith, it’s a shame that you should have to pay tithing’. … he chided my mother for paying her tithing, called her anything but wise or prudent; and said there were others who were strong and able to work that were supported from the tithing office. My mother turned upon him and said: ‘… you ought to be ashamed of yourself. Would you deny me a blessing? If I did not pay my tithing, I should expect the Lord to withhold His blessings from me. I pay my tithing, not only because it is a law of God, but because I expect a blessing by doing it. By keeping this and other laws, I expect to prosper and to be able to provide for my family.’” (<span class="emphasis">CR,</span> April 1900, p. 48.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p12" pid="s3e0Izx0XEaYuyh3v6ESXQ" hash="Nooi_Q">I recall sitting in this historical Tabernacle back on October 1948 when the semi-annual conference of the Church was in session. Elder Matthew Cowley of the Council of the Twelve was speaking. He related an incident that made a deep and lasting impression on me. While serving as president of the New Zealand Mission he visited a good Maori sister who sincerely believed and observed the principle of tithing. Brother Cowley told of this experience in these words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p13" pid="oXk1bnGHHUif9H3tEZRwzA" hash="iEUslA">“Now, on one occasion I called in as I always did when I visited that vicinity, to see this grand little woman, then in her eighties, and blind. She did not live in an organized branch, had no contact with the priesthood except as the missionaries visited there. We had no missionaries in those days. They were away at war.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p14" pid="4VY1hBOVlEmYejAM4m7_Hg" hash="aLRY9g">“I went in and greeted her in the Maori fashion. She was out in the back yard by her little fire. I reached forth my hand to shake hands with her, and I was going to rub noses with her and she said: ‘Do not shake hands with me. …’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p15" pid="zDuIcifeP0G-PIDu1AR23g" hash="qXpk0g">“I said: “Oh, that is clean dirt on your hands. I am willing to shake hands with you. I am glad to. I want to.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p16" pid="frMviNs7EESK5htYH5pgzQ" hash="wh9WYA">“She said: ‘Not yet.’ Then she got on her hands and knees and crawled over to her little house. At the corner of the house there was a spade. She lifted up that spade and crawled off in another direction, measuring the distance she went. She finally arrived at a spot and started digging down into the soil with that spade. It finally struck something hard. She took out the soil with her hands and lifted out a fruit jar. She opened that fruit jar and reached down in it, took something out and handed it to me, and it turned out to be New Zealand money. In American money it would have been equivalent to [about] one hundred dollars.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p17" pid="zCfs0hglsE22WTkmYDSDdw" hash="7OlMug">“She said: ‘There is my tithing. Now I can shake hands with the priesthood of God.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p18" pid="9_NbwEMyTk63nSsiWL_q1Q" hash="dD53lw">“I said: ‘You do not owe that much tithing.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p19" pid="B9Fbl3Q7fUOfKS212l7a9w" hash="TuAOpg">“She said: ‘I know it. I do not owe it now, but I am paying some in advance, for I do not know when the priesthood of God will get around this way again.’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p20" pid="pgBNmXN6a0ilwRfg66gK0w" hash="1EP43w">Then after a brief pause and with considerable emotion Brother Cowley continued: “And then I leaned over and pressed my nose and forehead against hers, and the tears from my eyes ran down her cheeks. …” (<span class="emphasis">CR,</span> Oct. 1948, pp. 159–60.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p21" pid="p7fh5De6802N69wf15I9PA" hash="6jRqLg">My beloved brothers and sisters, the Lord does keep his promises. He truly opens the windows of heaven and pours out his blessings upon those who are faithful and who obey his commandments but it will be done in his own way. These blessings may come in a financial or temporal way or may be realized by a spiritual outpouring, bringing strength, peace, and comfort. His blessings may come in unusual and unexpected ways so that at the time we may not even recognize them as blessings; but the promises of the Lord will be kept.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing.p22" pid="27YwEN4TP0OrLMj60pyWzQ" hash="M8h_IA">And to this I testify in the name of our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/04/i-will-pour-you-out-a-blessing</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1974-general-conference/1974-04-7020-elder-henry-d-taylor-64k-eng.mp3" length="5498251" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 1974 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Law of the Fast</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In a recent meeting, President Marion G. Romney gave a message which impressed me greatly. First he said, “It has been, and now is, the desire and the objective of the Church to obtain from fast offerings the necessary funds to meet the cash needs of</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03050_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="3whpMQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="woyYcI5CRkemUoRaGkRxoQ" hash="DyBR0g">The Law of the Fast</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ZPbZkIom5kqHqFibdjukxQ" hash="xJD0UA">Henry D. Taylor</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27ea.jpg" alt="Elder Henry D. Taylor" pid="B772NFr9HEuHiq2L3rSwVA" hash="GdqGVA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p1" pid="3WuanqLDQUyk9bngInn_pQ" hash="6bGTvg">In a recent meeting, President Marion G. Romney gave a message which impressed me greatly. First he said, “It has been, and now is, the desire and the objective of the Church to obtain from fast offerings the necessary funds to meet the cash needs of the welfare program.” And he said, “We can, we ought, and we must do better.” Then from Brother Romney came this comforting assurance: “<span class="emphasis">If we will double our fast offerings we shall increase our prosperity, both spiritually and temporally.</span> This the Lord has promised, this has been the record.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p2" pid="SeAe8HnQ4UWkX8ELo7fu5Q" hash="qYe2WQ">Many years ago a day was chosen and designated upon which to observe the law of the fast. A very important feature in this observance was, and now is, a liberal contribution to the fast offering fund. The policy of the Church today has been stated as follows:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p3" pid="19TMdUojk0CSu2oDvkGrgw" hash="V2G7cA">“The first Sunday of each month is usually designated as a day of fasting and prayer on which a special testimony meeting is held. Adequate time should be allowed for testimony bearing. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p4" pid="lWwyoiqOm0q6O40cywBYgg" hash="NnCmPg">“A proper fast day observance consists of abstaining from food and drink for two consecutive meals, attending the fast and testimony meeting, and making a generous offering to the bishop for the care of those in need. A <span class="emphasis">minimum</span> fast offering is defined as the equivalent of the value of two meals.” (<span class="emphasis">General Handbook of Instructions</span> [1968], p. 40.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p5" pid="EFhmhBCpf0SWI9aNvxuHgw" hash="n8yUrw">Sunday, however, has not always been the day when fasting and testimony bearing has been observed in the Church. President Joseph Fielding Smith has furnished us with a very interesting account of the development of this law and principle. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p6" pid="HiaLLeRiZUigl3RX6WHbbA" hash="VW79TA">“Fasting and prayer in the present dispensation have been carried over from primitive times. From the organization of the Church the principle of fasting in the spirit of prayer has been a commandment of the Lord. [See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.8-13" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:8–13</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.76,119" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:76, 119</a>.] In regard to the choosing of a set day of the month, we have this testimony coming from President Brigham Young in a discourse [which was delivered] in the old tabernacle, [in] Salt Lake City, [on] December 8, 1867.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p7" pid="waG8OSJpTkq7F7fiqa6unQ" hash="tEdr5g">“President Young said, ‘… You know that the first Thursday in each month we hold … fast day. How many here know the origin of this day? Before tithing was paid, the poor were supported by donations. They came to [the Prophet] Joseph … and wanted help, in Kirtland, and he said there should be a fast day, which was decided upon. It was to be held once a month, as it is now, and all that would have been eaten that day, of flour, or meat, or butter, or fruit, or anything else, was to be carried to the fast meeting and put in the hands of a person selected for the purpose of taking care of the poor. If we were to do this now faithfully, [said President Young] do you think the poor would lack for flour, or butter, or cheese, or meat, or sugar, or anything they needed to eat? No! there would be more than could be used by all the poor among us. …’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p8" pid="Ek1pGoGmiEyK03LQ7crvhg" hash="TeN67Q">President Smith then explained:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p9" pid="h1loeAkENUCtqxs7qJkDmA" hash="mXqedA">“This custom of holding fast meetings on Thursday was continued in Nauvoo and also after the coming of the members of the Church to the Rocky Mountains. I can remember the time when certain business houses closed their doors each fast day and placed on the doors, ‘Closed for fast meeting.’ …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p10" pid="-lzOIVYsL0yZ3Qlaqdwmtw" hash="S_F_Jw">“The change from the first Thursday to the first Sunday of the month came about in this manner. Hyrum M. Smith, who later became a member of the Council of the Twelve, was a missionary in Newcastle, England, in the year 1896. On the Thursday of the fast meeting, members of the Church in that land had to get excused from their employment with a loss of pay. Some of them were workers in the coal mines. When these came from the pits, they had to go home, bathe, and change their clothes. This was a loss both of time and compensation. Hyrum wrote to his father, President Joseph F. Smith, and asked why, under such circumstances, the fast day had to be a Thursday and not a Sunday. President Smith took the letter to the meeting of the First Presidency and the apostles and presented it there. The following is an excerpt from the minutes of the meeting held November 5, 1896:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p11" pid="ft0_B9frtkeHCJr6seEA3Q" hash="78AA-g">“‘President Joseph F. Smith introduced the subject of fast meetings, suggesting that a change of the time from the first Thursday to the first Sunday in each month would probably be beneficial. This was endorsed by President George Q. Cannon, and after other brethren had spoken on the subject, it was decided that the Tabernacle services would be dispensed with on the first Sunday of each month, and that the saints in this city as well as in the country wards, should have the privilege of meeting in their meeting houses at 2 o’clock <small>P.M.</small> to observe fast day.’” (<span class="emphasis">Improvement Era,</span> Dec. 1956, p. 895.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p12" pid="fyznN2zmaE-wXAhpqCdFsA" hash="XihJQg">In addition to there being a change in the day of holding fast meeting and observing the law of the fast, one other development should be noted. When the Prophet Joseph set up the program in Kirtland in the early days of the Church, the Saints were counseled to bring to the fast meeting the items of food from which they had abstained. Subsequently this method has been modified so that currently the deacons of the Church call monthly on their assigned homes and the fast offering contribution is made in cash.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p13" pid="dLv4eB5TjkKZpBdIOdyWtg" hash="U5J_6A">Miracles are brought about through fasting and sincere prayer. In 1850 Lorenzo Snow, who later became president of the Church, labored in Italy as a missionary, trying to open that country to the gospel of the Lord Jesus Christ. He was somewhat shy and self-conscious, but spiritually, he was a giant. One family who had befriended him had a critically ill child. In fact, Elder Snow realized that only through sincere fasting, mighty prayer, unswerving faith, and through the power of the priesthood could that three-year-old child be saved. He knew how much the healing of this boy would mean to the people in this small Italian village.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p14" pid="gPuxFbucekuWoUekTnOrhQ" hash="YRNVSw">Climbing with his companion to a place of seclusion on the foothills of the Alps just above the village, in the spirit of fasting and prayer, he earnestly petitioned and pleaded with the Lord for six long, anxious hours for the privilege of using divine power to heal that little boy. Finally, the answer came; the reply was yes, he would be granted the privilege.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p15" pid="E5amZmEzPE6Fkz3gbcugEQ" hash="hl9PbQ">As a humble servant of the Lord, he walked down the mountainside with perfect faith that the dying child’s life would be spared. The boy was then given a blessing and a promise that he would live. A few hours later when Elder Snow and his companion returned to the home, they found that the child was greatly improved and was well on the way to recovery. Elder Snow realized that his fasting and prayer had reached the throne of a benevolent Heavenly Father. He remarked to the grateful parents: “The God of heaven has done this for you.” (See Eliza R. Snow, <span class="emphasis">Biography of Lorenzo Snow,</span> pp. 128–29.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p16" pid="T_NF0oTO9UWlTiL2gwmSRw" hash="ELI5UA">Surely the law of the fast is an inspired program and its observance has many virtues. President David O. McKay summed them up in these words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p17" pid="N9JY6wfGFkGRqL7MIlZ-hg" hash="bP_NHA">“The word <span class="emphasis">fast</span> is used to signify a self-imposed restraint with respect to the eating of food. Historians tell us that the custom of fasting dates back to the early history of the human race. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p18" pid="cMyA7CEtOUCBcX1XFVgb4w" hash="VUZ1yQ">“Whatever its origin, it is significant to note that several virtues are attached to the observance of the custom. … All the principles associated with fasting seem to point to the fact that it produces, first, physical well-being; [then, self-mastery; next, an opportunity to help others, and finally,] spiritual strength.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p19" pid="R3Pz-yLR60qceHlmc5ygAg" hash="zR3MHQ">“But the greatest of all [the] benefits [from fasting is] the spiritual strength derived by the subjection of physical appetite to the will of the individual.” (See David O. McKay, <span class="emphasis">Gospel Ideals,</span> Improvement Era, 1953, pp. 208–213.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p20" pid="_c6EEK9CDUGsvk8pY4zLSA" hash="FDTYDQ">An extremely important factor of the fast day observance is attending the fast and testimony meeting and acknowledging and expressing gratitude to our Heavenly Father for his many blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p21" pid="LnDaD_DHa0mnNtPVDslmrw" hash="lhH0Zg">It seems to me that there are four factors involved in a proper observance of the fast day, namely: first, abstaining; then, praying; next, testifying; and finally, contributing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p22" pid="5vtr2_VC3k6aLfuENwmgCw" hash="a9xe_g">I am confident that each of us has a continual need for additional blessings. A devoted servant of the Lord, a member of the First Presidency, has given us the formula, which, if followed, will increase our blessings. Again may I repeat his inspired promise: “If we will <span class="emphasis">double</span> our fast offerings we shall increase our prosperity, both spiritually and temporally.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast.p23" pid="1RYAO2KeBk-2uDz0y5twtw" hash="E68yZg">I firmly believe that the paying of fast offerings does result in rich blessings. And to this I testify in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/10/the-law-of-the-fast</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1974-general-conference/1974-10-1040-elder-henry-d-taylor-64k-eng.mp3" length="5741419" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 1974 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immanuel: God With Us</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As in all ages of history, youth today are faced with making many important and far-reaching decisions. President Spencer W. Kimball has announced that the Church has need of more missionaries. He declared that the time has come now when we should “l</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03063_000_028" doc-version="3" hash="wTNlZQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="Oc4wlkGeuk2lvmMhdD5j-A" hash="WKl5fg">Immanuel:</h1><p class="subtitle" pid="2PaDqRJjskqg34sqb8OO_Q" hash="yCnj4Q">God With Us</p><p class="authorName" pid="1snHK3O1ZkmW4Rk1ZNFLNA" hash="xJD0UA">Henry D. Taylor</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27ea.jpg" alt="Elder Henry D. Taylor" pid="cV1fAnKFsUSEfawIWiHO5w" hash="GdqGVA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p1" pid="DheF-lYig0e-W3pNsT5EBg" hash="l8_HoA">As in all ages of history, youth today are faced with making many important and far-reaching decisions. President Spencer W. Kimball has announced that the Church has need of more missionaries. He declared that the time has come now when we should “lengthen our stride, … change our sights and raise our goals.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p2" pid="1-1SOsBxY0OPUtt_T0KmOQ" hash="8B1lXg">As President Kimball issued this challenge in April 1974, he said, “Today we have 18,600 missionaries.” (The members accepted this challenge and today we have in excess of 21,000.) He then said: “We can send more. Many more! … When I ask for more missionaries, I am not asking for more testimony-barren or unworthy missionaries. … the young people will understand that it is a great privilege to go on a mission and that they must be physically well, mentally well, spiritually well, and that ‘the Lord cannot look upon sin with the least degree of allowance.’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p3" pid="TxRMIQ32VEmYKUmYARrb7w" hash="7nrCKw">As the President continued, he said, “The question is frequently asked: Should every young man fill a mission? And the answer has been given by the Lord. It is ‘Yes. Every young man should fill a mission.’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p4" pid="E-TYQvphcEqmqIlGINXS5g" hash="HvX9Tw">In addition to filling a mission, President Kimball pointed out, “Every man should also pay his tithing. Every man should observe the Sabbath. Every man should attend his meetings. Every man should marry in the temple and properly train his children, and do many other mighty works. Of course he should. He does not always do it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p5" pid="Wmsw7m4vI0-eyDv26Cgi0A" hash="ch3mJQ">As the President continued, he said, “We realize that while all men definitely should, all men are not prepared to teach the gospel abroad. Far too many men arrive at the missionary age quite unprepared to go on a mission, and of course they should not be sent. But they should all be prepared. There are a few physically unfit to do missionary service. … There are far too many unfit emotionally and mentally and morally, because they have not kept their lives clean and in harmony with the spirit of missionary work. They should have been prepared. Should! But since they have broken the laws, they may have to be deprived, and thereon hangs one of our greatest challenges: to keep these young boys worthy.” (Regional Representatives of the Twelve seminar held April 4, 1974; see also “When the World Will Be Converted,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Oct. 1974, pp. 2–14.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p6" pid="qIaHsKnbPUOFJmK494W2jw" hash="0n1dOw">While the major responsibility for preaching the gospel has been placed upon the shoulders of the priesthood, there are many young women who will be also granted the privilege of serving as missionaries. They should likewise prepare themselves for the time that they may be called.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p7" pid="Rg_EG8dfOEiquC8OmWI3Ig" hash="Vwe3ow">Parents can play an important part in instilling within their sons and daughters a desire to live worthy so that they can qualify to fill missions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p8" pid="f27l-iov8ky9SB8KQP9URg" hash="-J34_Q">I shall always be grateful for being born of goodly parents who taught their children that this was a part of their responsibility. In our home it was never a question of whether or not we would fill a mission; that was assumed and just taken for granted. It was a matter of when. As a result of this encouragement and hope, all of the six sons in the family filled missions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p9" pid="Dijg0x1IiEufiT-lIm9lhw" hash="uOKqVw">Now it’s a natural thing for prospective missionaries to have a preference for a certain area in which to labor. That was true in my case. Three of my grandparents were born in England. Here they heard the gospel. Here they were converted, then joined the Church. Later my father filled a mission there.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p10" pid="CZV6w6sVJESOu9jyWr4GCQ" hash="STjsNA">So later when my call came from President Heber J. Grant, it was to the eastern states and not to England. Momentarily I was disappointed. However, I had been taught that missionaries are called by inspiration to labor where the Lord wants them. The words of a favorite hymn came to mind: “I’ll go where you want me to go, dear Lord.” (See “It May Not Be on a Mountain Height,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 75.) I was reconciled and satisfied with my mission call.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p11" pid="GBnQqUOFtUG3PhgnbCPC7w" hash="inyqpQ">What a tremendous blessing my call to the Eastern States Mission has been in my life. The mission was then presided over by one of the General Authorities of the Church, Elder B. H. Roberts. At that time he was senior president of the First Council of the Seventy and a most effective missionary. The Lord blessed me with the privilege of a close association with this great leader and missionary. I gained a deep respect, admiration, and love for him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p12" pid="32ErzzOmFUWOV6bhThEWOA" hash="JbY0ng">President Roberts was an earnest scholar, a gifted writer, and an author of many inspirational books explaining the beautiful principles of the gospel. He was a courageous and stalwart defender of the faith. As a dedicated historian, he researched and related in a comprehensive manner the interesting and important events in the history of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p13" pid="BH3TXksJ6kWt2g7r0wGDPg" hash="aZUkXQ">President Roberts was a dynamic and popular speaker, and his services were in constant demand. He was a most forceful and influential speaker. Numerous times he stood at this pulpit and thrilled and inspired the members of the Church. I shall always recall with gratitude my opportunity of serving under this inspired leader.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p14" pid="d8Z29rdngUmPz4tgRmY74w" hash="LtduXg">President Roberts firmly believed and taught his missionaries that in order for them to be successful and effective, they must seek for and obtain the Spirit of the Lord to direct and lead them in their teaching efforts. He emphasized the words of the Lord, who said, “And the Spirit shall be given unto you by the prayer of faith; and if ye receive not the Spirit ye shall not teach.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p15" pid="AZYBDNQgl0myM3_fkShusg" hash="5fVDeA">President Roberts set his missionaries an excellent example by constantly and earnestly seeking for the Spirit of the Lord to guide and direct them. He did that himself. Now we held a daily devotional exercise in the mission home. When it was President Roberts’s turn to lead in prayer, he would pour out his soul in gratitude and supplication. As he prayed the veil would become thin, and we could feel through the Spirit the nearness of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p16" pid="OqjDFF9uH02IzCBlC_JYJg" hash="h3fl0g">From his knowledge of the scriptures President Roberts had selected and adopted a slogan for the mission. That slogan was just one word, “Immanuel.” Isaiah, in foretelling the birth of the Savior, foretold, “Therefore the Lord himself shall give you a sign; Behold, a virgin shall conceive, and bear a son, and shall call his name Immanuel.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/7.14" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 7:14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p17" pid="e4kWx8NQ_kK56NtgHV4VxQ" hash="zRUJuA">Centuries later, Matthew, an apostle of the Christ, explained the meaning of the name Immanuel when he recorded, “Behold, a virgin shall be with child, and shall bring forth a son, and they shall call his name Emmanuel, which being interpreted is, God with us.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/1.23" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 1:23</a>.) President Roberts used this slogan, “Immanuel,” constantly in his discourses, in his correspondence, when autographing books or photos, and on numerous other occasions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p18" pid="LGA8oneSskGzE0Bxx2T0Hg" hash="RkHJEA">To have “God with us” through his Holy Spirit should be the aim of every missionary, and it should likewise be the aim of every individual. To have the companionship of the Holy Spirit requires a person to keep his mind and his body clean, as the Holy Spirit is sensitive and will not dwell in an unclean tabernacle.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p19" pid="2aSanoPOp0uOSSgx1yxzjw" hash="fGHdSg">The young man who had gained a reputation for speaking (he had gained a great ability) had allowed this praise to go to his head; he became slightly arrogant. He had been invited to speak in his ward sacrament meeting. As the meeting proceeded, it was announced that he would be the next speaker. As he walked to the pulpit, overly self-confident and with no evidence of humility, the bishop leaned over and whispered to his counselor, “What a pathetic and lonely figure he is, standing out there all alone.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p20" pid="xNnyyMyEHkuiKJ8MyAGS_g" hash="f8mFZA">As the resurrected Savior met on a mountain near Galilee with his apostles for the last time before ascending into heaven, he assured them that although he would return, through his Spirit he would never leave them. He said, “Lo, I am with you alway; even unto the end of the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/28.20" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 28:20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p21" pid="9HVl80ODEUa8BMn1z8sYDQ" hash="VAEr5w">Yes, every young man should fill a mission. That should be his aim, his goal, his sincere desire. Whether to go on a mission or not will be one of the most important and far-reaching decisions that he will make in this life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us.p22" pid="jViHopmBjUKT0dUrN5QNng" hash="kuaPmQ">It is my prayer that every young man may prepare himself to accept a mission call, for which I pray in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/10/immanuel-god-with-us</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1975-general-conference/1975-10-4070-elder-henry-d-taylor-64k-eng.mp3" length="5468152" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Right to Choose</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose?lang=eng</link>
      <description>One of our greatest responsibilities, and yet privileges, is the right to make choices. Latter-day Saints firmly believe in the principle of free agency.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03070_000_033" doc-version="2" hash="EyoNaA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="9t3eLqnk2UmM7hHMqPOl-w" hash="0Cz0pw">The Right to Choose</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="lQm4YE9Uy0G7x-T4jPMuhA" hash="xJD0UA">Henry D. Taylor</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27ea.jpg" alt="Elder Henry D. Taylor" pid="hUQAdg22p0uIZ5FhaipKQA" hash="GdqGVA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p1" pid="pYGK1w6ukk2wWK2nQnxXwg" hash="TYqkAw">One of our greatest responsibilities, and yet privileges, is the right to make choices. Latter-day Saints firmly believe in the principle of free agency.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p2" pid="N1fkoD9HkUyJzTrmqsKQVQ" hash="q-l95Q">We are here upon this earth and possess wonderful mortal bodies because we chose wisely when vital matters were discussed and presented to us for our decision.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p3" pid="2zVnOC_UEE20jkxfb-44kg" hash="92k14A">Before the earth was created we existed as spiritual beings. When it was made known that an earth was to be organized, we were apparently very pleased with the announcement. This is evidenced by some very interesting and searching questions that were asked of Job by the Lord when he said: “Gird up now thy loins like a man; for I will demand of thee, and answer thou me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p4" pid="zaBvaVd2S02fnBUEQpYH7w" hash="DGs_3A">“Where wast thou when I laid the foundations of the earth? declare, if thou hast understanding.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p5" pid="wx0ObJBGnU6owEOtp7JlOQ" hash="-UW0dA">“Who laid the measures thereof, if thou knowest? or who hath stretched the line upon it?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p6" pid="xvxvqfK8LUKW2WyCerw9_g" hash="8z0Zow">“Whereupon are the foundations thereof fastened? or who laid the corner stone thereof;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p7" pid="ygxlveaku0SQxYFxvIQULw" hash="NWwupQ">“When the morning stars sang together, and all the sons of God shouted for joy?” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/job/38.3-7" class="scriptureRef">Job 38:3–7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p8" pid="A46AQYcc7k-R6JTAlXeuig" hash="F1SnHQ">We believe that a grand council was held to select one who would come to the earth to represent us, and who would atone for the sins of mankind. Joseph Smith has given us the assurance that: “At the first organization in heaven we were all present, and saw the Savior chosen and appointed, and the plan of salvation made, and we sanctioned it.” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith,</span> p. 181.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p9" pid="-yrbnj-VaE6rbTA1A1y0Wg" hash="bBHtFA">The Lord revealed to Moses some of the details of that grand council when he explained: “Satan … came before me, saying—Behold, here am I, send me, [and] I will by thy son, and I will redeem all mankind, that one soul shall not be lost, and surely I will do it; wherefore give me thine honor.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p10" pid="EFWJbhjdcUqzBHULDixBPA" hash="9eE65Q">Then the Lord continued: “But, behold, my Beloved Son … said unto me—Father, thy will be done, and the glory be <span class="emphasis">thine</span> forever.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/4.1-2" class="scriptureRef">Moses 4:1–2</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p11" pid="eNn7RTrTwE-WMXzwSnQkTA" hash="6kQaDw">Abraham quotes the words of the Lord when he said: “Whom shall I send? And one answered like unto the Son of Man: Here am I, send me. And another answered and said: Here am I, send me. And the Lord said: I will send the first.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p12" pid="v7d8DMe5Gkqv6_H9SwaLUg" hash="99E02g">“And the second was angry, and kept not his first estate; and, at that day, many followed after him.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.27-28" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:27–28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p13" pid="FU9om7m14k2pvj4uMxQv6g" hash="Xie-8g">John explains in the book of Revelation that as a result of Satan’s anger: “And there was war in heaven: Michael [who came to earth and was named Adam] and his angels fought against the dragon [who was Satan]; and the dragon fought and his angels,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p14" pid="hRLzjzCEokuOvvEsrhcnSw" hash="nFdfNg">“And prevailed not; neither was their place found any more in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p15" pid="KEcbWM9PD0ONd7hBvoC0yg" hash="8Thrvg">“And the great dragon was cast out, that old serpent, called the Devil, and Satan, … was cast out into the earth, and his angels were cast out with him.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rev/12.7-9" class="scriptureRef">Rev. 12:7–9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p16" pid="7jFB77MJNkC4IW0xcky27Q" hash="IBXfzA">We understand that Satan exerted such a powerful influence upon his associates that one-third of the hosts of heaven followed after him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p17" pid="nBaL7C0V4kKPUBifhgnsKw" hash="2AhhKQ">Here we observe two different personalities and two different motives of operation. Satan would have removed a person’s free agency and he proposed to redeem all mankind by force, for which he wanted the recognition, honor, and glory. The plan of Jesus would allow individuals to make a choice between what they considered to be right and what they felt would be wrong, and recommended that all honor and glory would be attributed to the Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p18" pid="eGCLjmRv6Ee0zLvuxQKvww" hash="11wfeQ">One has aptly said: “There is no end to the good that can be accomplished when we are not concerned as to the one who will receive the credit.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p19" pid="wYczw-rhW0ORzbLZ5bWLQA" hash="-NdWBA">As we journey through this earth life, we have many important and far-reaching decisions to make as individuals. We especially realize that young people must decide whom they will choose to be their friends and with whom they will associate. They must also determine what they will do to earn a livelihood. Young men and young women will hopefully fall in love, and they will have the privilege of choosing the ones whom they wish to marry. They will also determine if their marriage will be in the temple. That is the only place where they can be sealed for time and all eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p20" pid="MXfGWQWWGk-HPnWsp3wSVA" hash="rrRYOQ">Many more decisions must also be made, but a person is not alone in making these important decisions. Following his baptism, preparatory for entrance into the Church, hands are laid upon his head, and one bearing the holy priesthood confirms him a member of the Church and bestows upon him the gift of the Holy Ghost, often properly referred to as the Holy Spirit. If we live righteously, the Holy Spirit will be our companion and guide in making these important decisions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p21" pid="XYGuSfaNeU-NOb1YquplCg" hash="O9BH-w">Through the medium of prayer we can receive a solution to our problems and know what decisions to make. Ofttimes as we pray we receive a strong impression that the answer to the matter we are considering is “no.” Then again, we can have the feeling that our answer is right and should be a positive “yes.” On the other hand, we may not obtain a clear “yes” or “no” answer. In such instances the Lord has given us a formula that should be employed. One should ponder and study the problem out in his mind, make a decision, then ask the Lord if his decision is right. If it is right, he can receive a burning in his bosom and he will know and have the assurance that his decision is right; but if it is not right, there will be a stupor of thought that will cause one to forget the thing which is wrong. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/9.8-9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 9:8–9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p22" pid="dAkEgTVD4kCMO_jbjD7tLQ" hash="f45r_g">The words of one of our meaningful hymns have great significance for us. It carries this message:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="THDPMUQW-Uy85rUQy6RwTQ" hash="PoVCOg">Know this, that every soul is free</p>
          <p class="line" pid="8TMzi6RE5kuLwyj2BSMozw" hash="UGe9_g">To choose his life and what he’ll be,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="zJwMQCCrz0y2HQ5dlX-2kg" hash="-1Bkvg">For this eternal truth is given</p>
          <p class="line" pid="0Ta1MYw790ihqYFt1B31Fg" hash="X-qKNw">That God will force no man to heaven.</p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="KHWFjRUA_EuhFyR4HNGsTQ" hash="1rZbbQ">He’ll call, persuade, direct aright</p>
          <p class="line" pid="muxTJpZRekmRwcvr_pG34Q" hash="wVAJxg">And bless with wisdom, love, and light,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="qa-abGnxuUCXN9hZ2TWnOg" hash="De4ZKA">In nameless ways be good and kind,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="FZsr7H4JvEGhzV9C0YCAMQ" hash="AranKg">But never force the human mind.</p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="AnoLE2DCYkihSkD_qA-50w" hash="1SOfRA">Freedom and reason make us men;</p>
          <p class="line" pid="IZsJPYwANUKHh_bt52IXBg" hash="u_s2aw">Take these away, what are we then?</p>
          <p class="line" pid="uFhAdimaQUCtZAXD4CIt-Q" hash="ExGFnw">Mere animals, and just as well</p>
          <p class="line" pid="-C9D8kDF20Cn6T2JAl2pPQ" hash="unAcYQ">The beasts may think of heaven or hell.</p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p23" pid="7FpSWsODqkaPqfLlJKSlQw" hash="JF3ZLw">Yes, we do have the privilege of making decisions. Will they be good and be pleasing to our Heavenly Father? Or will they be self-centered and selfish?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p24" pid="DZn7ZgUGUkqUiyHKLwNHRQ" hash="GPqzyQ">Joshua, an ancient prophet, determined that he would try to live righteously, and after making this decision he proclaimed: “choose you this day whom ye will serve; … but as for me and my house, we will serve the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/24.15" class="scriptureRef">Josh. 24:15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose.p25" pid="Z18KeLhH70qPrDmKlMKKrA" hash="25_wWA">May we be inspired to make wise decisions that will meet with the approval of the Lord and be for our best good and the blessing of our fellowmen. For this I pray, in the name of our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/04/the-right-to-choose</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1976-general-conference/1976-04-5050-elder-henry-d-taylor-64k-eng.mp3" length="9053822" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1976 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Search the Scriptures</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures?lang=eng</link>
      <description>During His ministry here on earth, as the Savior taught the people, He counseled them: “Search the scriptures; for in them ye think ye have eternal life: and they are they which testify of me.” (.)</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03076_000_028" doc-version="3" hash="5sgetg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="z0XFNT3M8kyImFl2XM93dg" hash="ULU1tg">Search the Scriptures</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="5Joy15rYt0mz10f4HJrBNQ" hash="xJD0UA">Henry D. Taylor</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-27ea.jpg" alt="Elder Henry D. Taylor" pid="px1pLy0TqkyCEX2rUxg4KQ" hash="GdqGVA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p1" pid="I6J8Mcp_pE2VVQbukrsb3Q" hash="NPW2rg">During His ministry here on earth, as the Savior taught the people, He counseled them: “Search the scriptures; for in them ye think ye have eternal life: and they are they which testify of me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.39" class="scriptureRef">John 5:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p2" pid="AQ5vNOsfFUS5bbz5qxIJ5Q" hash="82C8fg">What do we consider to be the scriptures? One dedicated student has explained: “Any message, whether written or spoken, that comes from God to man by the power of the Holy Ghost is <span class="emphasis">scripture.</span> If it is written and accepted by the Church, it becomes part of the <span class="emphasis">scriptures or standard works</span> and ever thereafter may be read and studied with profit.” (Bruce R. McConkie, <span class="emphasis">Mormon Doctrine,</span> Bookcraft, 1966, p. 682.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p3" pid="IDa5M2aSlEaDE80Im539-w" hash="lJtFAQ">President Kimball has urged us to study the scriptures when he suggested: “Let us this year seek to read and understand and apply the principles and inspired counsel found within the [scriptures]. If we do so, we shall discover that our personal <span class="emphasis">acts</span> of righteousness will also bring <span class="emphasis">personal revelation</span> or <span class="emphasis">inspiration</span> when needed into our own lives.” (“Always a Convert Church,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Sept. 1975, p. 4.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p4" pid="v4BTnYvj90mDywPZWkZvgA" hash="d6iZfQ">President Lee recommended a daily reading of the scriptures. He taught us that our testimonies need to be nourished and fed. “If we’re not reading the scriptures daily, our testimonies are growing thinner, our spirituality isn’t increasing in depth.” (Harold B. Lee, Seminar for Regional Representatives of the Council of the Twelve, Dec. 12, 1970.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p5" pid="Zzu2Dx8J8UCIQlYA-lTngQ" hash="9XtHfA">Joseph Smith, although but a youth, was an earnest student of the scriptures. In one of the offices in the Church Office Building is a painting showing Joseph seated in a chair in his bedroom with a Bible in his hands. On such an occasion, he undoubtedly read the passage of scripture located in James. This passage gave him the guideline he needed to answer some very grave questions that concerned him. We all know that passage. The passage read: “If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask of God, that giveth to all men liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given him.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.5" class="scriptureRef">James 1:5</a>.) Joseph Smith accepted this invitation, as he had a most important decision to make. Retiring to a secluded spot in a grove of trees on his father’s farm, he knelt and prayed earnestly for an answer to his problem. Unexpectedly he was visited by our Heavenly Father and His Son, the resurrected Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ. This dramatic visitation was his first revelation in this dispensation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p6" pid="gp7gLfZDPE-PHlzTLFBpBw" hash="ApV_6Q">The knowledge and use of the scriptures are important in our lives. A prominent Church educator, many years ago, taught: “The scriptures are sign boards leading to eternal life.” (George H. Brimhall, <span class="emphasis">Long and Short Range Arrows,</span> Provo: Brigham Young University Press, 1934, p. 189.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p7" pid="27rDYC-bIkWZTpmZrPtgsg" hash="WALAfw">As Latter-day Saints we accept the following scriptures as the standard works of the Church: the Bible (consisting of the Old Testament and the New Testament), the Book of Mormon, the Doctrine and Covenants, the Pearl of Great Price, and official statements made by our leaders.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p8" pid="L3-svFnmVEqOUUa1iL0-0Q" hash="Ta4XCw">Regarding the Bible: There is a misconception that the Bible is one book instead of a collection of sixty-six books, thirty-nine of which comprise the Old Testament and twenty-seven of which constitute the New Testament. Since the books are so numerous and the period covered so great—about 2,500 years from Moses to John—and since the books are composed by so many writers, there is a vast variety in the materials presented. The first five books of the Old Testament contain an early record of the Hebrew race, and are ascribed to Moses by Josephus and other authorities. These books are called “The Pentateuch.” (See B. H. Roberts, <span class="emphasis">The Seventy’s Course in Theology,</span> Deseret News, 1907, 1:23ff.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p9" pid="xZNSt4Km5EG_hQEbEao-XA" hash="LiY2ZQ">The Book of Mormon, as we know, was translated by Joseph Smith from the golden plates in the custody of the angel Moroni. This book contains the record of the Lord’s dealings temporally and spiritually with the ancient peoples who dwelt in the lands of America. It also gives the beautiful account of the appearance of the resurrected Lord and Savior Jesus Christ to the people, which is most inspiring.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p10" pid="RP0L3RHa1UOMvwAwjviNwQ" hash="1svK1A">The Doctrine and Covenants contains revelations given to Joseph Smith, the Prophet, with some additions by his successors in the presidency of the Church. One edition I examined recently pointed out that certain lessons entitled “Lectures on Faith,” which were bound in with the Doctrine and Covenants in some of its former issues, are not included in this edition. These lessons were prepared for use in the School of the Elders, which was conducted in Kirtland, Ohio, during the winter of 1834–35; but they were never presented to nor accepted by the Church as being otherwise than theological lectures or lessons.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p11" pid="ibUeyA_tRUaZEfU8Fs3IEA" hash="G9V3pg">The Pearl of Great Price presently contains “a selection from the revelations, translations, and narrations of Joseph Smith” (Title Page), which includes: First, eight chapters known as the book of Moses. The material contained in the first chapter was revealed in June 1830. The materials in the next seven chapters were revealed in December 1830. Second is the book of Abraham, which consists of five chapters. These were the writings of Abraham and also of Joseph of Egypt. They were translated by Joseph Smith from two rolls of papyrus that were found in coffins with four mummies and were discovered in the catacombs of Egypt by Antonio Sebolo, a celebrated French traveler, in 1831. (See <span class="emphasis">History of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints,</span> 2:348.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p12" pid="v__Tstd1wESwoJCp0JWomA" hash="LNLocQ">Third, in the Pearl of Great Price are the writings of Joseph Smith, taken mainly from his history. Then fourth, the Articles of Faith, taken from the letter the Prophet wrote to John Wentworth, who wished to furnish the information to a friend who was writing a history of the state of New Hampshire. (See <span class="emphasis">History of The Church,</span> 4:535.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p13" pid="7wfIN_ZFN0q_YunS-gscNw" hash="Rtp_5g">New scriptures have recently been added to the Pearl of Great Price. At the last general conference, held in April 1976, President Tanner made this announcement:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p14" pid="h5LbjGIxsE61QeK1XYA7eg" hash="BTKt9Q">“President Kimball has asked me to read a very important resolution for your sustaining vote. At a meeting of the Council of the First Presidency and Quorum of the Twelve held in the Salt Lake Temple on March 25, 1976, approval was given to add to the Pearl of Great Price the following two revelations:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p15" pid="-_RgpIlUIUCUni8v11TzKw" hash="uQLBSA">“First, a vision of the celestial kingdom given to Joseph Smith, the Prophet, in the Kirtland Temple, on January 21, 1836, which deals with the salvation of those who die without a knowledge of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p16" pid="YZM-FT9A1ES8AQ973zE7uA" hash="faB_pA">“And second, a vision given to President Joseph F. Smith in Salt Lake City, Utah, on October 3, 1918, showing the visit of the Lord Jesus Christ in the spirit world [between His crucifixion and resurrection] and setting forth the doctrine of the redemption of the dead.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1976, p. 19.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p17" pid="HjBPF10ZskOBN2vA2ZUnAw" hash="0_frpA">Yesterday as we sustained the General Authorities we sustained designated ones as prophets, seers, and revelators. We firmly believe that they receive revelations from the Lord. President Lee has said: “In this day the scriptures are the purest at their source, just as the waters were purest at the mountain source; the purest word of God, and that least apt to be polluted, is that which comes from the lips of the living prophets who are set up to guide Israel in our own day and time.” (Harold B. Lee, <span class="emphasis">Ye Are the Light of the World,</span> Deseret Book, 1974, pp. 55–56.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p18" pid="wED54fJRUEKr0KAtFa8J3w" hash="Yp3Unw">We should search the scriptures and ponder over the truths contained in them, for they are the words leading to eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures.p19" pid="5dJ8XmUZQk6rPDA-zHej6w" hash="lEmuVQ">I bear solemn testimony that inspired men are leading the Church today. Let us hearken to their voices and obey their teachings, for which I pray, in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/10/search-the-scriptures</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1976-general-conference/1976-10-4060-elder-henry-d-taylor-64k-eng.mp3" length="5065923" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 1976 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
