<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Hilarie Cole</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Hilarie Cole.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Hilarie%20Cole.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Hilarie Cole.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 1995 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>He Will Be There to Help</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/04/he-will-be-there-to-help?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We are all different. Each of us has been given talents as well as challenges. Some of us may have physical or mental limitations; others may be lonely or come from homes that do not teach gospel principles. Because Heavenly Father loves each of us, </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/he-will-be-there-to-help" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95905_000_042" doc-version="2" hash="IFFOEA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/he-will-be-there-to-help.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="zhsWs2jJZU2-_NU0kkFUBA" hash="I3KwjA">He Will Be There to Help</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="llDJiCUKlUmSszCUIIQ8nA" hash="eBs1xA">Hilarie Cole</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/he-will-be-there-to-help.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/he-will-be-there-to-help.p1" pid="B__h33e80Eaj-IoegdIxeQ" hash="d7wjUw">We are all different. Each of us has been given talents as well as challenges. Some of us may have physical or mental limitations; others may be lonely or come from homes that do not teach gospel principles. Because Heavenly Father loves each of us, he has provided us with a source of comfort and strength—the scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/he-will-be-there-to-help.p2" pid="Rs5LSvek00GiE7VT2HIw5g" hash="j8jFRQ">My dear friends, I am thankful for this opportunity to share with you my experience with the scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/he-will-be-there-to-help.p3" pid="sV4w1dZCBkirpdgoOG5xjA" hash="gOjEJw">While growing up, I was blessed to come from a home where scriptures were an important part of our lives. I had gone to many Church activities and heard friends and family bear testimony of the power of the scriptures. I had a desire to gain a personal testimony of the power and truthfulness of the scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/he-will-be-there-to-help.p4" pid="uVxH2IqM4U-YIgbcB0NGTg" hash="nJF7IQ">But that did not happen easily. Because of my learning disability, it was hard to read the words and even more difficult to understand them. I often felt embarrassed and frustrated. I didn’t like to go to Young Women because I felt inadequate. I was afraid I might be called on to read. I felt more comfortable with my family, but I continued to feel frustrated.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/he-will-be-there-to-help.p5" pid="ppwuN2wZgkOXaBQNICWW6g" hash="7kcPVw">I prayed for help and I found this scripture. Please turn with me to Moroni 7:33 [<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.33" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:33</a>], and I will share with you my answer: “And Christ hath said: If ye will have faith in me ye shall have power to do whatsoever thing is expedient in me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/he-will-be-there-to-help.p6" pid="mWq-mnlYBU2KNC-7OMmoNQ" hash="mdXH1w">What a wonderful promise! If I would put my faith in the Lord, he would help me. He would help me to understand the scriptures. This was the key for me. One verse at a time, one day at a time, I began to understand. Even my schoolwork improved. The Book of Mormon got me through high school. I still have my learning disability and face challenges every day, but daily scripture study reminds me to have faith in my Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/he-will-be-there-to-help.p7" pid="dJeMrAc-BUqIfGiMF49jhg" hash="jfGRVg">No matter where you live or what kind of family you come from, Heavenly Father loves you and will be there to help and strengthen you whenever you need him. I know this because he has been there for me. I love my family, who understand the challenges I have. I’m grateful for leaders who have worked with me. I know the Church is true. I know the scriptures are there for each of us to learn from. I know that Christ lives. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/04/he-will-be-there-to-help</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/1995-general-young-women-meeting/1995-03-0060-hilarie-cole-64k-eng.mp3" length="1421956" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 1995 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
