<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By J. Devn Cornish</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by J. Devn Cornish.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/J.%20Devn%20Cornish.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by J. Devn Cornish.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2011 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2011 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Privilege of Prayer</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Prayer is one of the most precious gifts of God to man.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50029123_000_5060" doc-version="2" hash="lhKa_g"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="v2UYYOxn2UWrS75isTKNDQ" hash="IA4lDA">The Privilege of Prayer</h1><p class="authorName" guid="469415b2-cdc6-4d48-8fc5-66f56f0cf741" pid="97cgf_FiUUKFuRQlYQqAeg" hash="a0n7uA">J. Devn Cornish</p><p class="kicker" pid="k6DykyfpY0SrrzuuHVsyNg" hash="DlJgyQ">Prayer is one of the most precious gifts of God to man.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="b12387b8-ef5b-4ecd-b72b-0fa7ca1c404a">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p1" guid="eed639a6-8f2e-4974-9689-ab2325d8888d" pid="e7S4cRGjO0uq5I17UuSXNg" hash="8y4YWQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="101"></span>My beloved sisters and brothers, God our Father is not a feeling or an idea or a force. He is a holy person who, as the scriptures teach, has a face and hands and a glorious immortal body. He is real, He knows each of us individually, and He loves us, every one. He wants to bless us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p2" guid="c2a7ec13-67dc-4420-84d4-9c0b98b9eed7" pid="cvv_LRdeO0qDxoYCosb2FQ" hash="rcpG_w">Jesus said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p3" guid="a876e315-8de4-4c17-a6f6-2f48f95627a7" pid="_RMf271RBUCZVzfjxEK6gw" hash="etfzag">“Or what man is there of you, whom if his son ask bread, will he give him a stone?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p4" guid="e36bb8ca-d12f-4395-b600-f0b23c6385f3" pid="DUxUCGC_lEqHGyZB3UpilQ" hash="gE1LTA">“Or if he ask a fish, will he give him a serpent?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p5" guid="dcc829e7-36c5-4492-9559-504f8213834a" pid="dsen31CbckG15XGu0Svkxg" hash="jeeaDA">“If ye then, being evil, know how to give good gifts unto your children, how much more shall your Father which is in heaven give good things to them that ask him?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.9-11" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 7:9–11</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p6" guid="2b5d99e9-4909-4768-bad6-687566f41b0a" pid="YlTm9U9ZdkSsQ0UinXTUGQ" hash="EebkOA">Perhaps a personal experience will help to illustrate the point. When I was a young resident physician at Boston Children’s Hospital, I worked long hours and traveled between the hospital and our home in Watertown, Massachusetts, mostly by bicycle since my wife and young family needed our car. One evening I was riding home after a long period in the hospital, feeling tired and hungry and at least a bit discouraged. I knew I needed to give my wife and four small children not only my time and energy when I got home but also a cheery attitude. I was, frankly, finding it hard to just keep pedaling.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p7" guid="5ab3bb8a-f2f8-46c8-9fdc-29fb4d6cc047" pid="23Dbwdw6yU2yjY2yx0PoKg" hash="UvwleA">My route would take me past a fried chicken shop, and I felt like I would be a lot less hungry and tired if I could pause for a piece of chicken on my way home. I knew they were running a sale on thighs or drumsticks for 29 cents each, but when I checked my wallet, all I had was one nickel. As I rode along, I told the Lord my situation and asked if, in His mercy, He could let me find a quarter on the side of the road. I told Him that I didn’t need this as a sign but that I would be really grateful if He felt to grant me this kind blessing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p8" guid="e57a0811-2779-42af-9d6f-6dd8e1f60bce" pid="yNcbwroB_E2sToRYHZdRGA" hash="IHzQZg">I began watching the ground more intently but saw nothing. Trying to maintain a faith-filled but submissive attitude as I rode, I approached the store. Then, almost exactly across the street from the chicken place, I saw a quarter on the ground. With gratitude and relief, I picked it up, bought the chicken, savored every morsel, and rode happily home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p9" guid="93928914-33e1-4fbb-83aa-6e386b9348bc" pid="TZ8PK_-WFkiUZ5ab1AcGzA" hash="4z2Fkg">In His mercy, the God of heaven, the Creator and Ruler of all things everywhere, had heard a prayer about a very minor thing. One might well ask why He would concern Himself with something so small. I am led to believe that our Heavenly Father loves us so much that the things that are important to us become important to Him, just because He loves us. How much more would He want to help us with the big things that we ask, which are right (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.20" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 18:20</a>)?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p10" guid="b210dd5a-456e-46b1-8a27-0b9412b0ef55" pid="HyuVyScnEkq4V1Ff5wlXTw" hash="caNfmw">Little children, young people, and adults alike, please believe how very much your loving Heavenly Father wants to bless <span class="emphasis">you.</span> But because He will not infringe upon our agency, we must ask for His help. This is generally done through prayer. Prayer is one of the most precious gifts of God to man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p11" guid="b173a4ab-b8c0-4dca-83f0-43393471b614" pid="plgqijAOuEaODI3O364hsw" hash="y9glLA">On one occasion Jesus’s disciples asked, “Lord, teach us to pray” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/11.1" class="scriptureRef">Luke 11:1</a>). In response, Jesus gave us an example that might serve as a guide to key principles of prayer (see Russell M. Nelson, “Lessons from the Lord’s Prayers,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 2009, 46–49; see also <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.9-13" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 6:9–13</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/11.1-4" class="scriptureRef">Luke 11:1–4</a>). According to Jesus’s example:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p12" guid="bd6ddf75-32b9-4d2a-b4b4-0180b6afa771" pid="MkCNUO4cW0Wuf24AGV5O2w" hash="dmikWw">We start by speaking to our Heavenly Father: “Our Father which art in heaven” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.9" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 6:9</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/11.2" class="scriptureRef">Luke 11:2</a>). It is our privilege to approach our Father directly. We do not pray to any other being. Remember that we have been counseled to avoid repetitions, including using the name of the Father too often as we pray.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p13" guid="aed729d7-b4c0-4776-93dd-cecd4ecfb0d7" pid="-CzmGRF0jkeWt4on2HeSxw" hash="80oYOA">“Hallowed be thy name” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.9" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 6:9</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/11.2" class="scriptureRef">Luke 11:2</a>). Jesus addressed His Father in an attitude of worship, recognizing His greatness and giving Him praise and thanks. Surely this matter of reverencing God and giving heartfelt and specific thanks is one of the keys to effective prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p14" guid="d9ff9f78-fe2a-4664-b127-311411293ad0" pid="Ia-Oj3Tk1EWGssc3bF8GJg" hash="0klhXQ">“Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.10" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 6:10</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/11.2" class="scriptureRef">Luke 11:2</a>). We freely acknowledge our dependence on the Lord and express our desire to do His will, even if it is not the same as our will. Our Bible Dictionary explains: “Prayer is the act by which the will of the Father and the will of <span class="pageBreak" page-number="102"></span>the child are brought into correspondence with each other. The object of prayer is not to change the will of God, but to secure for ourselves and for others blessings that God is already willing to grant, but that are made conditional on our asking for them” (Bible Dictionary, “Prayer”).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p15" guid="ed948b4b-a7d6-4acc-9467-33b8eba2225e" pid="BUTLXl0oxEWZgo_2R2hBFw" hash="U_sTUw">“Give us this day our daily bread” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.11" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 6:11</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/11.3" class="scriptureRef">Luke 11:3</a>). We ask for those things we want from the Lord. Honesty is essential in requesting things from God. It would not be fully honest, for example, to ask the Lord for help on a test in school if I have not paid attention in class, done the homework assigned, or studied for the test. Often as I pray, the Spirit nudges me to admit that there is more I should do to receive the help I am asking from the Lord. Then I must commit and do my part. It is contrary to the economy of heaven for the Lord to do for us that which we can do for ourselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p16" guid="da397d2f-4780-4807-b6c9-bf134599a18d" pid="a3eUQMo9BkOwgQSUdPGpfQ" hash="AmgKBg">“And forgive us our debts” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.12" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 6:12</a>), or in another version, “Forgive us our sins” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/11.4" class="scriptureRef">Luke 11:4</a>). An essential and sometimes forgotten part of personal prayer is repentance. For repentance to work, it must be specific, profound, and lasting.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p17" guid="3a60337e-5b25-4045-813e-116024f33f1f" pid="w4ST7fsyI0mOOXMG_ECt4w" hash="O3MDmQ">“As we forgive our debtors” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.12" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 6:12</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/11.4" class="scriptureRef">Luke 11:4</a>). The Savior made a clear connection between being forgiven of our sins and forgiving others who have wronged us. Sometimes the wrongs others have done to us are very, very painful and very hard to either forgive or forget. I am so grateful for the comfort and healing I have found in the Lord’s invitation to let go of our hurts and turn them over to Him. In Doctrine and Covenants, section 64, He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p18" guid="8f0ca3dd-9603-4a60-8e47-d6784a3d6fa5" pid="BURTGY27-ke9eGWZ-gWBAQ" hash="VE30Hg">“I, the Lord, will forgive whom I will forgive, but of you it is required to forgive all men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p19" guid="de9842f1-eca6-4695-9511-74c30e932cce" pid="ghI1wRqL5UWdmrbj3g_mzA" hash="pKlnhg">“And ye ought to say in your hearts—let God judge between me and thee, and reward thee according to thy deeds” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.10-11" class="scriptureRef">verses 10–11</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p20" guid="7b83b711-1594-41ba-8082-e113f0c9a2f1" pid="epN2M7LJA0K6WPQlrA_LNQ" hash="vJufxg">Then we must drop the matter completely, letting the Lord take it from there, if we desire to be healed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p21" guid="29703d29-8ccb-4baf-8dad-3753f61abfae" pid="XEvRLKLWWE6dT6-mHIC7xg" hash="n0s1gg">“And suffer us not to be led into temptation, but deliver us from evil” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.13a" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 6:13, footnote a</a>; from Joseph Smith Translation, Matthew 6:14; see also <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/11.4c" class="scriptureRef">Luke 11:4, footnote c</a>; from Joseph Smith Translation). Thus, in our prayers we may begin the protective process of putting on the whole armor of God (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/6.11" class="scriptureRef">Ephesians 6:11</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/27.15" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 27:15</a>) by looking forward to the day ahead and asking for help with the sometimes frightening things we may face. Please, my friends, do not forget to ask the Lord to protect and be with you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p22" guid="39889275-567b-4b2b-8c0d-b4318baab0fa" pid="k7TR6xGhuEStDX5KmPEl7Q" hash="7QLMAQ">“For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.13" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 6:13</a>). How instructive it is that Jesus concluded this prayer by praising God again and expressing His reverence for and submission to the Father. When we truly believe that God rules His kingdom and that <span class="pageBreak" page-number="103"></span>He has all power and all glory, we are recognizing that He really is in charge, that He loves us with a perfect love, and that He wants us to be happy. I have found that one of the secrets to a joyful life is to recognize that doing things the Lord’s way will make me happier than doing things my way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p23" guid="8f7934f8-79f3-44cc-8e08-169d83e2ae28" pid="ZyxN8t0HkEeuX2WO8y596g" hash="gEmKyg">There is a risk that a person may not feel good enough to pray. This idea comes from that evil spirit who is the one who teaches us not to pray (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/32.8" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 32:8</a>). It is as tragic to think we are too sinful to pray as it is for a very sick person to believe he is too sick to go to the doctor!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p24" guid="316ab558-a82a-40a6-b5ab-74993b8ab198" pid="rgsAWHKa-0Wkv4xy-JOqSw" hash="c-BykA">We must not imagine that any kind of prayer, no matter how sincere, will be very effective if all we do is to say the prayer. We must not only say our prayers; we must also live them. The Lord is much more pleased with the person who prays and then goes to work than with the person who only prays. Much like medicine, prayer works only when we use it as directed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p25" guid="60a33aa6-c8aa-415a-ae03-b6264f19c006" pid="ib5YEEVC20m2R82tMDopcA" hash="cuZdlw">When I say that prayer is a sweet privilege, it is not just because I am grateful to be able to talk to Heavenly Father and to feel His Spirit when I pray. It is also because He actually answers and speaks to us. Of course, the way He speaks to us is usually not with a voice we hear. President Boyd K. Packer explained: “That sweet, quiet voice of inspiration comes more as a feeling than it does as a sound. Pure intelligence can be spoken into the mind. … This guidance comes as thoughts, as feelings through promptings and impressions” (“Prayer and Promptings,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 2009, 44).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p26" guid="e552883e-7221-47f3-96e0-66d304a78acb" pid="rSbIWD9pjkuQW6Kj_BHsTg" hash="oeouIg">Sometimes we seem to get no answer to our sincere and striving prayers. It takes faith to remember that the Lord answers in His time and in His way so as to best bless us. Or, on further reflection, we will often realize that we already know full well what we should do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p27" guid="48a7cfb7-4363-4766-a944-d6002e05d3e4" pid="P15v3T_IQ0qJzHCWe33fnA" hash="cPln6A">Please do not be discouraged if this does not work for you all at once. Like learning a foreign language, it takes practice and effort. Please know, though, that you can learn the language of the Spirit, and when you do, it will give you great faith and power in righteousness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p28" guid="8d40708b-4fad-4ece-b5a5-63abacf1268a" pid="4FhhpYnuKkmefCgQaeVVQg" hash="hKrWbQ">I cherish the counsel of our beloved prophet, President Thomas S. Monson, who said: “To those within the sound of my voice who are struggling with challenges and difficulties large and small, prayer is the provider of spiritual strength; it is the passport to peace. Prayer is the means by which we approach our Father in Heaven, who loves us. Speak to Him in prayer and then listen for the answer. Miracles are wrought through prayer” (“Be Your Best Self,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 2009, 68).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer.p29" guid="6a9a5015-c64e-453b-9e85-016d30925819" pid="LIm-wjmO1kqQb8oSD1ojBg" hash="1ZHBpw">I am deeply grateful for the privilege of going to my holy Heavenly Father in prayer. I am thankful for the countless times He has heard and answered me. Because He answers me, including sometimes in predictive and miraculous ways, I know He lives. I also humbly testify that Jesus, His holy Son, is our living Savior. This is His Church and kingdom on the earth; this work is true. Thomas S. Monson, for whom we fervently pray, is His prophet. Of which things I testify with full certainty in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/10/the-privilege-of-prayer</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2011-general-conference/2011-10-5060-elder-j-devn-cornish-64k-eng.mp3" length="4848437" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2011 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Am I Good Enough? Will I Make It?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Cornish explains that as long as we keep trying to live the commandments, repent, and rely on Christ, we will be worthy to return to live with God.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60001311_000_26cornish" doc-version="1" hash="363Siw">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="YF0r2Wn8-kyQbXGcjZWijQ" hash="2z3gRQ">Am I Good Enough? Will I Make It?</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p2" pid="eagTb6SFVEuxza6wPL10NA" hash="isUy_A1">By Elder J. Devn Cornish</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p3" pid="LiX83o0aPEmvJetbJBNrMg" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="pU2dZtBtE0yiLhlE6uWSXw" hash="D6Uk3w">If you will really try and will not rationalize or rebel—repenting often and pleading for grace—you positively are going to be “good enough.”</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="rTnxHzFOVE283uLc9GCzSQ" hash="isUy_A">By Elder J. Devn Cornish</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p5" pid="5kcuv3PGQEalj3P36CtBuA" hash="Ex8_Pg">Dear sisters and brothers, what a blessing it is for us to gather to be taught by the Lord’s servants. Isn’t it wonderful how many ways our loving Heavenly Father guides and blesses us? He really wants us to come home.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p6" pid="ReBEb6-ZKkuSpRfbTsQClw" hash="eM6lgQ">Through a series of tender mercies as a young doctor coming out of medical school, I was accepted for pediatric residency training in a high-powered, competitive program. When I met the other interns, I felt like the least intelligent and least prepared of all. I thought there was no way I could measure up to the rest of the group.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p7" pid="CDxlRrkJiEu5q4dh8Pw_JA" hash="okXPLQ">Early in our third month, I was sitting in the nurse’s station in the hospital late one night, alternately sobbing to myself and falling asleep as I tried to write the admission orders for a small boy with pneumonia. I had never felt so discouraged in my life. I didn’t have any idea how to treat pneumonia in a 10-year-old. I began to wonder what I was doing there.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p8" pid="dWyDyz4aOkugj8QXJI-2WQ" hash="_9Eguw">Just at that moment, one of the senior residents put his hand on my shoulder. He asked me how I was doing, and I poured out my frustrations and fears. His response changed my life. He told me how proud he and all of the other senior residents were of me and how they felt like I was going to be an excellent doctor. In short, he believed in me at a time when I didn’t even believe in myself.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p9" pid="fm3Lqz8Zt0WurD95PW-eTg" hash="V7Y1hg">As with my own experience, our members often ask, “Am I good enough as a person?” or “Will I really make it to the celestial kingdom?” Of course, there is no such thing as “being good enough.” None of us could ever “earn” or “deserve” our salvation, but it is normal to wonder if we are acceptable before the Lord, which is how I understand these questions.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p10" pid="Hhz4Pl4qpUuXS61Ysf56ag" hash="jIprKg">Sometimes when we attend church, we become discouraged even by sincere invitations to improve ourselves. We think silently, “I can’t do all these things” or “I will never be as good as all these people.” Perhaps we feel much the same as I did in the hospital that night.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p11" pid="ropCycqn7EGb5r2sgPhexQ" hash="KAYOIA">Please, my beloved brothers and sisters, we must stop comparing ourselves to others. We torture ourselves needlessly by competing and comparing. We falsely judge our self-worth by the <span class="emphasis">things</span> we do or don’t have and by the <span class="emphasis">opinions of others.</span> If we must compare, let us compare how we were in the past to how we are today—and even to how we want to be in the future. The only opinion of us that matters is what our Heavenly Father thinks of us. Please sincerely ask Him what He thinks of you. He will love and correct but never discourage us; that is Satan’s trick.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p12" pid="2jagb0hSPUmtLPeY7soIcQ" hash="lXFuew">Let me be direct and clear. The answers to the questions “Am I good enough?” and “Will I make it?” are “Yes! You are going to be good enough” and “Yes, you are going to make it as long as you keep repenting and do not rationalize or rebel.” The God of heaven is not a heartless referee looking for any excuse to throw us out of the game. He is our perfectly loving Father, who yearns more than anything else to have all of His children come back home and live with Him as families forever. He truly gave His Only Begotten Son that we might not perish but have everlasting life!<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Please believe, and please take hope and comfort from, this eternal truth. Our Heavenly Father intends for us to make it! That is His work and His glory.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p13" pid="HvKECcBJc0CTl-8FPHv02A" hash="T6CFPQ">I love the way President Gordon B. Hinckley used to teach this principle. I heard him say on several occasions, “Brothers and sisters, all the Lord expects of us is to try, but you have to <span class="emphasis">really</span> try!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p14" pid="C9J8cjbujUeuyBwN-cvk4A" hash="Epe-lw">“Really trying” means doing the best we can, recognizing where we need to improve, and then trying again. By repeatedly doing this, we come closer and closer to the Lord, we feel His Spirit more and more,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> and we receive more of His grace, or help.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p15" pid="xW-OROPzMk25SpdoU0TOkA" hash="PizAPw">I sometimes think we don’t recognize how very much the Lord wants to help us. I love the words of Elder David A. Bednar, who said:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p16" pid="TES1hJ_D8U2UidXl60pJFw" hash="TXeALA">“Most of us clearly understand that the Atonement is for sinners. I am not so sure, however, that we know and understand that the Atonement is also for saints. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p17" pid="W9VM-yUGMUyJY-IHZh-aeQ" hash="pM8vEQ">“… The Atonement provides help for us to overcome and avoid bad and to do and become good. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p18" pid="O8H1fCRZQ0-ABlmwFW8A8w" hash="pdZICw">“‘<span class="emphasis">… It is … through the grace of the Lord that individuals … receive strength and assistance to do good works that they otherwise would not be able to [do]. … This grace is an enabling power …</span>’ [Bible Dictionary, “Grace”; emphasis added] … or heavenly help each of us desperately needs to qualify for the celestial kingdom.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p19" pid="3E_2fTUCBEaJ9Crbr0viUw" hash="zWtpRg">All we have to do to receive this heavenly help is to ask for it and then to act on the righteous promptings we receive.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p20" pid="t3XZJysFvEWKBgUsuXrb3A" hash="wFxcEw">The great news is that if we have sincerely repented, our former sins will not keep us from being exalted. Moroni tells us of the transgressors in his day: “But as oft as they repented and sought forgiveness, with real intent, they were forgiven.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p21" pid="EdCUvbLDjUyvzPtFC7zJ7A" hash="YjWkEw">And the Lord Himself said of the sinner:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p22" pid="KMFTBvSbcEGEYt2j6RO-zQ" hash="ueAhnw">“If he confess his sins before thee and me, and repenteth in the sincerity of his heart, him shall ye forgive, and I will forgive him also.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p23" pid="nUUaM5McAkyPYme7PkynlA" hash="vVd97w">“Yea, and as often as my people repent will I forgive them their trespasses against me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p24" pid="yX-EUiGdFk6CaQLxR5dcHw" hash="bz99_Q">If we will sincerely repent, God really will forgive us, even when we have committed the same sin over and over again. As Elder Jeffrey R. Holland said: “However many chances you think you have missed, however many mistakes you feel you have made … , I testify that you have <span class="emphasis">not</span> traveled beyond the reach of divine love. It is not possible for you to sink lower than the infinite light of Christ’s Atonement shines.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p25" pid="rzcplafs00-3tzZSLDeN0A" hash="hqpyHQ">This does not mean in any way that sin is OK. Sin always has consequences. Sin always harms and hurts both the sinner and those affected by his or her sins. And true repentance is never easy.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Moreover, please understand that even though God takes away the guilt and stain of our sins when we sincerely repent, He may not immediately take away all of the consequences of our sins. Sometimes they remain with us for the rest of our lives. And the worst kind of sin is premeditated sin, where one says, “I can sin now and repent later.” I believe that this is a solemn mockery of the sacrifice and sufferings of Jesus Christ.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p26" pid="hbPv51Pj4keA_a5PKhmLNw" hash="1QISOA">The Lord Himself declared, “For I the Lord cannot look upon sin with the least degree of allowance.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p27" pid="Tk2kTcM5AEaa9a4aHzwLNA" hash="SjACOQ">And Alma proclaimed, “Behold, I say unto you, wickedness never was happiness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p28" pid="Ug8sfbgU10Gb8lrRVFRy0w" hash="URo65A">One of the reasons that Alma’s statement is particularly true is that with repeated sinning, we distance ourselves from the Spirit, become discouraged, and then stop repenting. But I repeat, because of the Savior’s Atonement, we can repent and be fully forgiven, as soon as our repentance is sincere.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p29" pid="UbBzvdVKKUeVtR1SkYrqbQ" hash="dl3dIA">What we cannot do is rationalize rather than repent. It will not work to justify ourselves in our sins by saying, “God knows it’s just too hard for me, so He accepts me like I am.” “Really trying” means we keep at it as we fully come up to the Lord’s standard, which is clearly defined in the questions we are asked in order to get a temple recommend.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p30" pid="o-qfQqiYG0Gm4Ghhk5rgcg" hash="63HVww">The other thing that will surely keep us out of heaven and separate us from the help we need now is rebellion. From the book of Moses, we learn that Satan was cast out of heaven for rebellion.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> We are in rebellion any time we say in our hearts, “I don’t need God, and I don’t have to repent.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p31" pid="9CcLgmZdfE6uD04eH8VUfA" hash="Fmo6wQ">As an intensive care pediatrician, I know that if one inappropriately rejects lifesaving treatment, it can lead needlessly to physical death. Similarly, when we rebel against God, we reject our only help and hope, who is Jesus Christ, which leads to spiritual death. None of us can do this on our own power. None of us will ever be “good enough,” save through the merits and mercy of Jesus Christ,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> but because God respects our agency, we also cannot be saved without our trying. That is how the balance between grace and works works. We can have hope in Christ because He wants to help and change us. In fact, He is already helping you. Just pause and reflect and recognize His help in your life.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it.p32" pid="c5So3NZheEKP3bocHojC2g" hash="CyAs8g">I witness to you that if you will really try and will not rationalize or rebel—repenting often and pleading for the grace, or help, of Christ—you positively are going to be “good enough,” that is, acceptable before the Lord; you are going to make it to the celestial kingdom, being perfect in Christ; and you are going to receive the blessings and glory and joy that God desires for each of His precious children—including specifically you and me. I testify that God lives and wants us to come home. I testify that Jesus lives. In the holy name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/10/am-i-good-enough-will-i-make-it</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2016-general-conference/2016-10-1060-j-devn-cornish-64k-eng.mp3" length="4787205" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
