<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By J. Richard Clarke</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by J. Richard Clarke.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/J.%20Richard%20Clarke.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by J. Richard Clarke.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 1976 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>“I Will Never Be the Same Again”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/10/i-will-never-be-the-same-again?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My brothers and sisters, it is impossible to describe the feelings of my heart at this time—and during this past week. Someone tried to describe, I guess, some of the feelings that had been going through his mind; he said, “I’m not sure that I was ne</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-will-never-be-the-same-again" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03076_000_046" doc-version="3" hash="dw_XbA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-will-never-be-the-same-again.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ZUNQAf3_WUG6pN4QsaTzjA" hash="49H_WQ">“I Will Never Be the Same Again”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="fE9ALzXo7k-FklHz_QJf5A" hash="72aVTw">J. Richard Clarke</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-will-never-be-the-same-again.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a6e.jpg" alt="Bishop J. Richard Clarke" pid="qC4Ig6FsukiBdK424gcP2w" hash="S4JOpA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-will-never-be-the-same-again.p1" pid="H3-RYR2OS0iHPS6Lmhk4tg" hash="SU7p3A">My brothers and sisters, it is impossible to describe the feelings of my heart at this time—and during this past week. Someone tried to describe, I guess, some of the feelings that had been going through his mind; he said, “I’m not sure that I was nervous but I was incredibly alert.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-will-never-be-the-same-again.p2" pid="kHMcHA3owkyRz9bjZKLMyQ" hash="Vu2bFw">The one thing I do know for sure is that I will never be the same. To be called by a prophet of God, and to receive a commission under his hand with the Brethren of the Council of the Twelve, is a unique experience which will last me for a lifetime.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-will-never-be-the-same-again.p3" pid="IZuliLuzqkSvu0ImyHcfPw" hash="fltdNQ">And may I join Elder Wells in paying homage to those who have made so many contributions to my life to make this experience possible. In front of a television set in Rexburg there sits an elderly couple in their nineties who feel, I am sure, that part of the reason for their longevity was to see a fulfillment of this hour.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-will-never-be-the-same-again.p4" pid="8d8h29C_G0WVEJA47E_zJQ" hash="hx-8Ug">I pay my respects to my wife and companion, who has always sustained me in whatever calling has come to me, as I have tried to sustain her in those things which she has been called to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-will-never-be-the-same-again.p5" pid="4cY2USNIMUujq-CTehttGg" hash="C-FaMA">When President Kimball asked me in my numb silence if I wanted to go home and think over the proposition, I was pleased to say that was a decision which my wife and I had made at the time of our marriage, and so I could immediately answer in the affirmative.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-will-never-be-the-same-again.p6" pid="xAvKbU4AeEiVcLFuNW-ZYw" hash="wis3ng">Let me say to my family that this, as other callings which we have received, is a family calling. We recognize that we have a responsibility to each other—that families of Church leaders live in glass houses, as it were—and that we will do our best to live worthy of the blessings which have come to us and to try to live as closely as we can to the principles of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-will-never-be-the-same-again.p7" pid="4aGzWYXYDUWasdvp6DEJJg" hash="7TwOUA">Now may I add my testimony that God has borne witness to my soul that sitting behind me is a choice and holy prophet of God; that we are the recipients of one of the greatest blessings in the history of the world—to be living at this time when the Lord has called for all who would hear His voice to come and be partakers of His Spirit and righteousness and enjoy the peace and prosperity within His kingdom, here and in the eternal life hereafter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-will-never-be-the-same-again.p8" pid="0eImTEVzEUaTcwPeR0E42g" hash="ddmImg">May I bear witness that I know that Jesus is the Christ, the Son of the Living God, and our eternal Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-will-never-be-the-same-again.p9" pid="b-7iO_6uN0-6TzCNAt2gjg" hash="iJayRw">And may I express my love and appreciation to the Prophet Joseph Smith and all those who have given their lives or so much else that we might enjoy this hour in peaceful assembly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/i-will-never-be-the-same-again.p10" pid="STIxh6zOMkSNqyvokO1RDw" hash="uv460w">Now I pray for the Lord’s blessings upon all of us, that we may fulfill the righteous desires of our hearts and do His work as He would have it, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/10/i-will-never-be-the-same-again</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1976-general-conference/1976-10-7080-bishop-j-richard-clarke-64k-eng.mp3" length="1864296" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 1976 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ministering to Needs through LDS Social Services</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My brothers and sisters, I am sure each of you has been touched by the stories of the Church’s great relief efforts to members stricken by floods or earthquakes. Our hearts go out to these people in need. There are, however, other needs—social-emotio</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services" dup-mag="false" dup-conf="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03083_000_039" doc-version="3" hash="beVIvg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="xiKnAd8_tk-soEKbl3phuA" hash="OwJ2aQ">Ministering to Needs through LDS Social Services</h1><p class="authorName" pid="iZNm4F_Vj0WGDKUK0z1bNw" hash="72aVTw">J. Richard Clarke</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a6e.jpg" alt="Bishop J. Richard Clarke" pid="IMXEDYTZUE-jmNtUDliWaA" hash="S4JOpA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p1" pid="I2-7CSz2a0y6SwngBaSVhA" hash="D8yPgA">My brothers and sisters, I am sure each of you has been touched by the stories of the Church’s great relief efforts to members stricken by floods or earthquakes. Our hearts go out to these people in need. There are, however, other needs—social-emotional needs—that can be just as devastating as any natural disaster. And these needs cannot be met with truckloads of food or clothing. I would like to illustrate several of them in my talk to you today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p2" pid="yC31Zq3P4U2x_iuYrtZSnA" hash="OIC0Ng">Let me begin by reading a letter which relates the tragic story of a young man who became entangled in a way of life which led him to violate the most sacred of God’s commandments:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p3" pid="nBmya5o6TkyzHZdXu7iwdQ" hash="yWJwiQ">“I know not why I write this letter. Perhaps I grasp at last straws before it’s over or whatever. I seek help, without hope of receiving it. Not because I doubt that the Church is true, but because of my sins. Let me say here, <span class="emphasis">I love my parents</span> and do what I am able to help them, but my strength is going, and what flicker of spiritual life there is left in me spends itself on writing this letter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p4" pid="pxf37gHWskiNMasLXxeFNw" hash="SQpRSA">“At a very young age,” this young man continues, “I became convinced that my father didn’t love me. It stemmed from an encounter when one evening I went to kiss him good night and he brushed me away. I’m sure he doesn’t remember, and it had no significance to him, but I was devastated: my entire sense of security and my world crumbled into ashes as I stood there.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p5" pid="rtUEvbJ2v0aQhdfsa7EKkg" hash="fdX12g">“Not knowing what else to do, I ran from this new stranger in a panic to my mother and whispered tones to her of my calamity, which she denied, but did not convince me. That night I watched my father as I stood in the shadows of my darkened bedroom. I swore to myself that I would close the door until he sought to open it. I would ignore him until he sought after me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p6" pid="avtxYOcNL0eRZUBZQYuirA" hash="Vuwzow">“He didn’t notice. If he did, he never asked me what was wrong. Well, needless to say, through the next years I went through the motions and rebelled to get his attention, which I got in the form of anger. At any rate, I developed into a homosexual, a vitiating disease, and was soon entrenched in my prison. I didn’t know myself. And I have felt for more years than I can remember that the Lord didn’t love me either. From age seventeen to about twenty-three I began using drugs. …”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p7" pid="7B-8elV6jE25sJcSp4dFvQ" hash="7KlGTA">Well, you can imagine where his life went from there. This young man closes his letter with these words: “Thank you for your time. Can you help me? Is there reason for me to help myself? Can you convince me? Can you spare the time? I’ve not much left.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p8" pid="zpZgMR5qDU-Q9-fqxFhErQ" hash="QqDmFg">Yes, young man, there is help available to you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p9" pid="HZgQ4mliNEmwXJzGo8-9Fw" hash="I3rFDg">We know that the Lord does love this young man, as he loves all of us. This individual has since been referred through the priesthood to an LDS Social Services agency. Hand in hand, his priesthood leader and his LDS Social Services caseworker will help this brother learn what he didn’t learn at his father’s knee—that the Lord loves him and that the gospel’s plan of repentance and forgiveness is available to all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p10" pid="x_PWUVCFPEGetHS3C6VQBA" hash="5fBIgg">In this next situation, Janet, as I will call her, was involved in serious transgression. After discovering that she was expecting a child out of wedlock, her bishop referred her to LDS Social Services. Instead of being condemned by staff personnel as she had feared, she found love and understanding—the love and understanding that she needed to help her repent. With the help of her bishop and the agency, she began to seek the Lord’s forgiveness. She was introduced to foster parents who lovingly accepted her into their home. She attended church regularly and studied the gospel. An unwed parents group sponsored by the Church helped her to realize the magnitude of her transgression and to resolve to start a new life. She began to more fully understand herself and her relationship to her Father in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p11" pid="cbXOYURIHEGqmEO41xm8bA" hash="9tNCgA">“I went through an awful lot,” she recalled. “But I felt like such a load was lifted by being able to share the burden with those who understood. I’m so grateful for all the help I received from my Heavenly Father.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p12" pid="qeKbGPhio0mxcw4f3pHGLw" hash="X0dSRQ">In the final story, Verinda, a vibrant young Apache girl, was accepted into the Indian Student Placement Service. She later gave this testimony:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p13" pid="l02Deu1osUa-P_RBhPV2CQ" hash="B9GAUw">“When I first participated in this program eight years ago, I got off the bus with only the clothes on my back and a few small possessions in a shoebox. I came from a humble home. My people are humble. But you have opened your hearts unto me. For that I am thankful. Now I can go home with a brand new suitcase of clothes. But that is not my wealth. I am wealthy because that which is inside of me is as precious as all of the wealth in this world. <span class="emphasis">I have a testimony of the gospel.</span> I know that Jesus is the Christ and that God lives and answers prayers. I now have a goal—something I can strive for.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p14" pid="gxzJWSBAGk2Lu-47QBhnfA" hash="etKLTQ">Brothers and sisters, these three stories are in sharp contrast to the world around us. Today, we suffer not only from physical pollution, but from mental pollution as well. Perversions of our basic values are offered as the “new morality.” Cheating and violence are often accepted as a means of achieving individual and group desires. Working mothers and weekend fathers abdicate their parental responsibilities. Husbands and wives separate at the smallest argument. Natural affection is waning. I remember as a bishop an incident of a couple who lost custody of their two young children—one in diapers, the other too young for school. Each day the mother and father went to work and left their children locked in the house to fend for themselves. When questioned by the judge, the mother was quite surprised. She said that they had always left sufficient food for the children to last until suppertime! Can you imagine such an attitude?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p15" pid="Q5KSnQ5gIE-WUZvFrkKJpA" hash="UaIWVQ">This “age of alienation” was foreseen by that great American prophet Moroni. He spoke of our day as “a day when there shall be great pollutions upon the face of the earth; [when] there shall be murders, and robbing, and lying, and deceivings, and whoredoms, and all manner of abominations.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/morm/8.31" class="scriptureRef">Morm. 8:31</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p16" pid="jBnVWycSTk-cwKo6Nbfkyw" hash="iQHnLQ">In almost every instance, such tragic conditions in society can be traced back to the failure of men to live the eternal principles of the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p17" pid="T6dXYOU9l0WGyxsfSHn7HA" hash="Yp-LLg">These currents in society affect us, too. In many of our stakes there are unwed parents, youth on probation or in detention homes, cases of child abuse or neglect, drug and alcohol problems, serious marital problems, sexual deviancy, and members in mental hospitals and prisons. These problems are staggering, and while we would all prefer that they did not exist, we cannot avoid life as it really is.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p18" pid="YSABdNISxEeU2IN963MDtA" hash="j4EZqA">As priesthood and Relief Society leaders, we are charged with the responsibility of helping members who suffer from these social and emotional problems. Indeed, the Lord has said that we are to “succor the weak, lift up the hands which hang down, and strengthen the feeble knees.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/81.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 81:5</a>.) The Brethren recognize the magnitude of this charge and have provided us with a valuable resource so that we might minister “in the Lord’s own way.” This resource, of course, is our own LDS Social Services division of Welfare Services.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p19" pid="k0xyOlo2u0eOrUWvttQEhA" hash="5d_vJg">Of their vital work President Harold B. Lee instructed the Regional Representatives in 1970:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p20" pid="9PoTGfps50yXbAqErYo1mw" hash="EOICXg">“Our social services program has already been a great blessing to our Church members. This program seeks to respond to many problems that beset our members in an affluent society, and it will no doubt increase in its importance, because so many of the problems which this cluster of agencies deals with are symptomatic of our time. Members may need counseling more than clothing, and members who, through bishops, are referred to an agency in our social services program should feel no more hesitancy in asking for help of this kind than we should in requesting help through the priesthood welfare program.” (Seminar for Regional Representatives of the Twelve, Oct. 1, 1970.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p21" pid="V9Da6olswESwF6aFCAJGMw" hash="B-KGAQ">The purpose or mission of LDS Social Services is to assist priesthood leaders by providing quality <span class="emphasis">licensed</span> and <span class="emphasis">clinical</span> services to members of the Church. This is accomplished by using highly qualified staff members and volunteers whose values, knowledge, and professional skills are in harmony with the gospel and the order of the Church. We should remember that LDS Social Services exists not because anyone doubts that a bishop or quorum doesn’t receive inspiration; rather, it exists because our prophets were inspired to give local priesthood leaders a <span class="emphasis">resource</span> to meet social-emotional needs. However, it is important to underscore this caution found on page 25 of the <span class="emphasis">Welfare Services Handbook:</span> “The bishop and Melchizedek Priesthood quorum and group leaders are the Lord’s ecclesiastical leaders. They cannot and must not abdicate their responsibility to any agency. Social services agencies are established to be a <span class="emphasis">resource</span> to the ecclesiastical leaders. There is no substitute for the inspired counsel and priesthood blessing by the bishop or quorum or group leader.” (<span class="emphasis">Welfare Services Handbook,</span> 1974, p. 25; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p22" pid="ynJxMUCloU-UMKAOs7ta8Q" hash="3rJ_eA">We should also remember that the aim of the Church is to help people to help themselves. To care for people on any other basis, President Romney has said, is to do them more harm than good. A spiritual or emotional dole, Elder Boyd K. Packer has noted, can be just as damaging as a material one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p23" pid="2CzeeqR1z0uEVZy--fwxcg" hash="bwv7Nw">The <span class="emphasis">General Handbook of Instructions</span> indicates that LDS Social Services is the official arm of the Church to handle <span class="emphasis">licensed services</span>—which include services to unwed parents, adoptions, foster care, and Indian student placement.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p24" pid="bhsQsrDVsUSK1LsISghO1A" hash="cw-NeQ">May I emphasize some of our concerns regarding these services. Independent child placements are often illegal and are made without the care and protection exercised by our licensed agencies. Resulting problems have caused untold grief to children involved and their natural parents, as well as to foster and adoptive parents. When Church members and officers in any country are involved in such independent child placements, government officials and others often view these placements as being sanctioned by the Church. As a result, missionary work and other Church programs may be jeopardized. May we encourage all priesthood officers who may be involved in these independent child placements to study the handbook and gauge the propriety of your personal involvement in light of this directive from the First Presidency: “All matters pertaining to the adoption and foster care of children in which the Church is or should be involved have been assigned to LDS Social Services.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p25" pid="--wTccKANEmsqa0npHiH3g" hash="XHhiEA">Licensed, professional adoption services are available to many qualified Latter-day Saint families through LDS Social Services in compliance with all state and federal laws. Families interested in adoption will be made aware of all resources available to them. The goal is to find the right home for a particular child and to ensure the full protection of all parties concerned.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p26" pid="d5rg7evtQEasC3x-d-N1_Q" hash="5HBkIA">The Unwed Parent Services has been designed to assist single persons in coping with out-of-wedlock pregnancy. This service operates under the direction of the local priesthood leader, except in licensed matters, and includes counseling, foster home placement, educational assistance, medical care, and above all, friendship and understanding. When the natural parents determine that releasing their children for adoption is the best alternative, the agency will ensure that the children are placed in homes of worthy LDS couples. In all instances, services to unwed parents are strictly confidential. Referrals to this program are accepted from any source.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p27" pid="qaHtmbQkrUmCkgDrjPQgUg" hash="BWP8Uw">Through the Indian Student Placement Services Program, LDS Social Services, upon referral from the local priesthood leader, assists Indian parents in providing educational, spiritual, cultural, and social experiences for their children from ages eight to eighteen. Children who qualify are placed with carefully screened, active Latter-day Saint foster families for the school year.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p28" pid="tG7mV5gGlk6kBr0rCqu4ig" hash="W8GW4Q">Licensed, supervised foster home care provides help and guidance to children who, because of necessity, have been temporarily separated from their parents. This experience, along with spiritual and professional counseling, helps both children and parents prepare for the reuniting of the family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p29" pid="SJmnaqKYA0298hPAmCCLCw" hash="KMwBQw">Clinical services provided by the agency include consultation, evaluation, and treatment of social-emotional problems. At the request of priesthood leaders, professional therapists assist members in exploring causes and solutions to their problems.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p30" pid="2b_SCyR3TUuu_9E1iaQjnQ" hash="QIy1Nw">Presently there are twenty-one LDS Social Services agencies. In areas where agencies have not been established, priesthood leaders may evaluate the need for this service. Additional agencies will be established when sufficient need has been identified and when regional and area welfare leaders so determine.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p31" pid="A4PBI-7ZdEymrxlpzml_GQ" hash="PxMCCg">When a new agency is established, a small core of professionals is employed. Trained volunteers are added to this basic group of people. Stake presidents work with agencies to the fullest extent possible in identifying and inviting volunteers to serve.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p32" pid="YanQhGNM5ka9h2A0t4VTYg" hash="zwGNyw">In areas where LDS Social Services agencies are not established, priesthood leaders should maintain a listing of LDS and non-LDS resources that provide similar services. Individuals and agencies being considered should be screened to ensure that their values are compatible with Church standards and values. Local laws should always be observed when adoption, unwed parent, or foster care services are used.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p33" pid="BytQPgRFjk2EugdZOQ54jQ" hash="obFw-w">It should go without saying that many of these problems would be alleviated if parents would spend more time teaching and rearing their children. Related to the story that I gave at the beginning of my talk is evidence of a clinical researcher who, after studying 850 individual cases, stated: “Homosexuality would not occur where there is a normal, loving father-and-son relationship.” Any of our people living in righteousness would normally avoid being involved in these problems.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p34" pid="wCnmf8cmf0a4Ltk2HEu8xw" hash="fhDtNA">Each of the stories I have told illustrates, I believe, the value of LDS Social Services when directed by the priesthood. In 1973, President Lee said: “The greatest miracles I see today are not necessarily the healing of sick bodies, but the … healing of sick souls, those who are sick in soul and spirit and are downhearted and distraught, on the verge of nervous breakdowns. We are reaching out to all such, because they are precious in the sight of the Lord, and we want no one to feel that they are forgotten.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> July 1973, p. 123.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p35" pid="jGKtjDEF3ESIGnkgV9BYNw" hash="I77-Yw">They are not forgotten. Think of the young man who was estranged from his father, the seventeen-year-old girl expecting a baby, the bright-eyed Indian student—these are not statistics, brothers and sisters; these are real people with real needs.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p36" pid="8ZMOY8PjYUmPcA2tNdCCmA" hash="5-tWbw">As priesthood and Relief Society leaders, we are charged to reach out to these people. But we have been given help. Just as a physician may attend to physical illness, so may LDS Social Services assist in meeting social-emotional needs under the spiritual direction of the priesthood leader.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services.p37" pid="fdl0KV5dh0qEu7FSI3vTVw" hash="OOIOEg">As we contemplate how we can use this resource, think of the young boy staring out of his darkened bedroom at his father. How many more are there like him? How can we walk down the hallway and open the door? I pray that we priesthood leaders may magnify our callings and let the Spirit guide us in using this resource of LDS Social Services, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1977/04/ministering-to-needs-through-lds-social-services</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1977-general-conference/1977-04-6030-elder-j-richard-clarke-64k-eng.mp3" length="7928955" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 1977 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Storehouse Resource System</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Each bishop knows that ministering to the temporal needs of stricken members awakens in him a spark of the divine nature. The Savior taught us that all things are spiritual unto him. Elder B. H. Roberts declared that the highest development of the sp</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03096_000_040" doc-version="2" hash="puhcSg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="dhQNGBeFiUCIyN4em0pvqg" hash="QBJ00Q">The Storehouse Resource System</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="NcfU3vMiLEG6UpSkH4zrmQ" hash="72aVTw">J. Richard Clarke</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a6e.jpg" alt="Bishop J. Richard Clarke" pid="DHuCCgL4RUWrNRFff9gZhA" hash="S4JOpA" />
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.f2">
	<p pid="TkV-njafzEqwa6eUCGfaYQ" hash="eY0SOQ">A bishop’s ministry is blessed with joy-filled opportunity to “succor the weak, lift up the hands which hang down, and strengthen the feeble knees.” (D&amp;C 81:5.) As the father of the ward, he is looked to for answers to a whole range of human problems:</p>
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="rcKbeyvq90y4hqfyWqtcng" hash="qTupUQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="Ntgk86qIuUS4lyNusoc-eQ" hash="fXbLBg">To an unemployed father—a job</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="NxRAub9EWEKyrroHcFvmOQ" hash="aRHi4Q">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="Jt3yhbA5vEuA-CxBbTamvw" hash="qI3F1g">To a family home gutted by fire—furniture and clothing</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="3G5dYyabfkatrq8fVZIiDg" hash="FwDhcg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="XiQsgmfiVUiCv1GF6QvsjQ" hash="wOWOdA">To a grateful recipient harvesting the corn crop—meaningful work</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="E9HJrOfZ5U-9_JDieh2kxQ" hash="FSLFDg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="DHzzDjxwbkOsrzL58ZDgjQ" hash="GxAUyQ">To an unwed mother—a new home and loving parents</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="SiE2pr32L0ue2We4EsQHOw" hash="bO3pzQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="J8wKfj0anEKg0i6V0PUipA" hash="HVhF6Q">To an emotionally disturbed couple—a trained therapist</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="4AO-CAqVd0qsSovxj36NAA" hash="9RDy3Q">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="A9Uvj5SM1kmh9ExgTjof1Q" hash="7QuIOQ">To a willing but unemployable member—dignity through labor</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p1" pid="GO902v8pA0KPV5jhYv1Wgw" hash="MGLtUQ">Each bishop knows that ministering to the temporal needs of stricken members awakens in him a spark of the divine nature. The Savior taught us that all things are spiritual unto him. Elder B. H. Roberts declared that the highest development of the spiritual is in its connection with the physical. (See B. H. Roberts, <span class="emphasis">The Mormon Doctrine of Deity,</span> Salt Lake City: The Deseret News, 1903.) In our temporal world, the problems of the flesh are real and constant and demanding. The Church has been commissioned of the Lord to provide the means by which its members may solve these problems. President McKay was once challenged by a man who said, <span class="emphasis">“If yours is the only true church, then it must have the answer to every problem of the human soul, spiritually, temporally, and socially.”</span> Brothers and sisters, we <span class="emphasis">do</span> have the answers!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p2" pid="UUU1rMtyrU-m7nNpI6l5fw" hash="4z5_Iw">It has always been the disposition of the true disciples of Christ, as they reached higher degrees of spirituality, to look after the needy. During Alma’s day,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p3" pid="FZQuHmXuu0eOjFzeXPVhHA" hash="ORUKBw">“They did impart of their substance, every man according to that which he had, to the poor, and the needy, and the sick, and the afflicted; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p4" pid="6Xc8EMuGPkWz2ds4tF6e9Q" hash="7mZT8A">“And thus, in their prosperous circumstances, they did not send away any who were naked, or that were hungry, or that were athirst, or that were sick, or that had not been nourished.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/1.27,30" class="scriptureRef">Alma 1:27, 30</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p5" pid="hPmdB6R240GWcSXw2z_Flg" hash="74vX0Q">In this dispensation, the Lord has declared, “I give unto the church in these parts a commandment, that certain men among them shall be appointed. … And they shall look to the poor and the needy, and administer to their relief that they shall not suffer.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.34-35" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:34–35</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p6" pid="XhZgTwQlhkm28DkO4PnRGw" hash="12u9tw">From then until now, the Lord has patiently allowed us to learn the principles that govern temporal salvation. It took the terrible economic depression of the 1930s to restimulate the Church to apply revealed principles and develop a formal plan under which the priesthood could minister to our needy. The fundamentals of the Welfare Plan were articulated in 1933. Stake presidents and bishops were asked to survey their needs. Because of its great complexity, the matter was taken under advisement for three years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p7" pid="NLmx6-w-W0GYxFhoEcSdYA" hash="ITlV-A">In October 1936, the First Presidency officially put into operation the Welfare Plan of the Church. You are acquainted with their published statement. And I quote, in part:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p8" pid="aqrh1LIeSkOyA3XQsJOC7A" hash="wM2B7g">“Our primary purpose was to set up, in so far as it might be possible, a <span class="emphasis">system</span> under which the curse of idleness would be done away with, the evils of a dole abolished, and independence, industry, thrift and self respect be once more established amongst our people.” (In <span class="emphasis">Conference Report,</span> Oct. 1936, p. 3, italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p9" pid="LqZRnItZ8k-mId64HyJfIw" hash="v9mwLw">Perhaps, like me, you have heard this declaration of principle many times and yet not fully considered that our individual efforts are to be united through a <span class="emphasis">system</span>—a system that is balanced and integrated, not merely that men shall be clothed and fed, but, to continue to quote from the Presidency, “The eternal man should be built up by self-reliance, by creative activity, by honorable labor, by service. From the beginning the long-range objective of the Welfare Plan was to build character in the members of the Church, both givers and receivers alike.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p10" pid="Xo9paC-6qkmrtUqdKbwdoA" hash="jJ4Oxg">The welfare system has expanded and matured and is now referred to as the <span class="emphasis">Storehouse Resource System.</span> The system is established on the six foundational principles of Welfare Services, which are love, work, self-reliance, service, stewardship, and consecration. While the bishop authorizes assistance <span class="emphasis">from</span> the system, each of us contributes resources to the system.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.f3">
	<p pid="7GRq7M7b3kSJyCNw-RW5uA" hash="ykYw4w">No bishop stands alone in his ministry. Thanks to the consecrations of the Saints, he has a full range of services and aids available through this great resource system. Many in the Church perceive a storehouse to be just a general store where food and clothing may be obtained on a bishop’s order. However, as members’ needs have expanded, the Storehouse Resource System has broadened to include:</p>
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="CfW6HS8f50eHb18fMfHg4w" hash="CWf5TQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="fNVdotAAOESf4DYP-THQBA" hash="2toCQw">Employment services</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="DaHzF0he9U68lH5A_DTWcg" hash="sFbDbQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="Vie_84ZBzUK99NubY67Wag" hash="q0vQ8g">Bishops storehouses</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="7MPfF-fhlEiMxyueUJc_qA" hash="j_tOzw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="M8471IIWHUi53N5TWjNtYg" hash="Gl38wg">Production projects</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="lzm_-uWCvU-771h-TJG69w" hash="PtS9dQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="vDU7v70C8EiSK3hJPdeqCQ" hash="idxk4w">LDS Social Service</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="CJcuXdZ1UUGkOx8aDTzlng" hash="O8UZfw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="4XEyU4BsHkCvhmcyidwj1w" hash="lr7oDg">Deseret Industries</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="GGrYfKBadEaJg6dQXONgog" hash="-eEzcg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="_RIaFCIptkWHrWhZlK-ejw" hash="jQmzFg">Fast offerings and other welfare resources</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p11" pid="Idbn8063Xk22dlPmwmCoEA" hash="dTS4ww">Bishops may now provide clothing, shelter, food, medical assistance, employment, adoption and foster care services, and professional therapy for the emotionally afflicted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p12" pid="JhbFjU9cBEimdTS0NffZ8g" hash="nAuTrg">Surely the “founding fathers” of the Welfare Plan must be thrilled to see the magnificent evolution of the system they envisioned. Let us thank the Lord for those who in darkness see, and from doubtings lead! Let us thank the Lord for prophets who can see, in finished form, the visions of the mind. It was this capability that President Romney referred to in his quotation of Brigham Young when he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p13" pid="33JNOAVPn0CcgCEhaGm79Q" hash="Xzr--A">“If any of you had a vision of Zion, it was shown to you in its beauty and glory after Satan was bound. … You did not see a vision of driving cattle across the plains and where you would be mired in this or that mudhole. You did not see the stampedes among the cattle, and those of a worse character among the people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p14" pid="_Rjq_jfWXkiLXX8Jyd3tYQ" hash="cMyJTg">“But you saw the beauty and glory of Zion that you might be encouraged and prepared to meet the afflictions, sorrows and disappointments of this mortal life and overcome them and be made ready to enjoy the glory of the Lord as it was revealed to you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p15" pid="DOiYDlPhukylF_VCUv1zIg" hash="R_n9qQ">President Romney then concludes: “We have … visions of the welfare program. We have great visions of the redemption of Zion and the building of the new Jerusalem, the inauguration of the United Order, the coming of the Millennium. But before these visions materialize, we must travel some rough roads.” (Addresses delivered at the special Welfare Meeting, 5 Apr. 1949, p. 13.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p16" pid="sLcJNoGbMEK8H3d1Aiu9LA" hash="pqySqw">Could this have been the day envisioned by President J. Reuben Clark, who said in 1942: “We have all said that the Welfare Plan is not the United Order and was not intended to be. However, I should like to suggest to you that perhaps, after all, when the Welfare Plan gets thoroughly into operation—it is not so yet—we shall not be so very far from carrying out the great <span class="emphasis">fundamentals</span> of the United Order.” (In <span class="emphasis">Conference Report,</span> Oct. 1942, p. 57; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p17" pid="gcASlzjZbE-WVgA85LRJBg" hash="W_pf1A">I am persuaded that in the ensuing thirty-six years since President Clark made this statement the Welfare Plan has more <span class="emphasis">thoroughly been put into operation.</span> Last October Conference President Kimball stirred our imaginations with this challenge:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p18" pid="cP_ggSYYI06APgru8WE_1g" hash="wHa72A">“As I considered my remarks for this Welfare session, I was struck by the thought that … a generation has passed since the reestablishment of this great welfare work. … In my mind’s eye the great leaders of this effort passed in review. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p19" pid="1dJn81VDLEK9Zpt_QUBFxg" hash="fhKZUQ">“As I recounted their contributions and the Church’s splendid growth in Welfare Services, I encountered this question: Do our people today and more particularly do our regional, stake, and ward leaders today <span class="emphasis">have the same grasp of welfare principles and the same commitment to Welfare Services work</span> as did those of this previous generation?” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign, </span>Nov. 1977, p. 76.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p20" pid="zOmJ_ksiWUiMBPTjJPYrww" hash="Nsi7dg">It is my conviction, President Kimball, that this generation accepts the challenge and has indeed “lengthened its stride” in its present implementation! We have entered a new era in Welfare Services, one characterized by improvement in five areas of activity:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p21" pid="RxkyAH8gdEyP3ZHRGSkkZw" hash="oQCDjA">First—<span class="emphasis">better coordination and cooperation within the system</span> so that production, processing, and distribution now flow more effectively. This means that priesthood employment leaders need to integrate better their efforts with the local Welfare Services Employment Center. It means better utilization of the great volunteer efforts of the Saints, whether on our project farms, or in LDS Social Services offices, or in Deseret Industries, or whatever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p22" pid="rVrTKLQJNE-GUDbuS2KW7g" hash="xRETDw">Next, <span class="emphasis">improved planning</span> so that the Storehouse Resource System operates as an integrated whole, thereby allowing us to control and balance its growth. Superior planning and good judgment will reduce the possibility of compromise in establishing and maintaining all elements of the system.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p23" pid="k_SxQ1gcfUS4fRTt4LgyBQ" hash="fL1KPg">Third, <span class="emphasis">increased managerial effectiveness</span> in all aspects of our welfare operations. The last four decades of welfare work have served as a powerful schoolmaster to teach us basic principles and disciplines. With new technologies and management skills, we can far exceed our previous productivity and efficiency.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p24" pid="RcLHW00DYkeNQxmVPNDvYQ" hash="smpSkg">Next, <span class="emphasis">higher levels of commitment and consecration to the kingdom.</span> Our quorum representatives and visiting teachers, as agents of the bishop, must get more involved in searching out the distressed and the needy. In our time of abundance, we must be generous with our surplus, which may be consecrated through the medium of the fast offering into the resource system. We are not restricted to paying the equivalent value of two meals only. Our prophet has entreated us to give even ten times more than two meals where possible. (See <span class="emphasis">Conference Report,</span> Oct. 1974, p. 184.) The prosperous should think beyond their ward and stake boundaries. Through the fast offering, we are distributing our expressions of love through the bishop to the one in need. This is the Lord’s way, wherein both giver and receiver are blessed to the ultimate salvation of both.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p25" pid="LCkUAW7tEUy5xZNd9erpTQ" hash="CZtiSw">Finally, <span class="emphasis">increased spirituality,</span> which implies a closer communion with the Savior and more sensitivity to the Spirit in our daily lives. Our prophet has counseled us to “emulate the Savior in your life by serving and consecrating, by overcoming temporally so that you might more fully achieve spiritually.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1977, p. 79.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p26" pid="IkPHLt2OV0CsXgYkxjBrtw" hash="BfU33w">My brothers and sisters, it is my sincere belief that this new era of Welfare Services implementation by our generation is proceeding as the Lord has ordained it. It goes forth to meet a perceived but not a completely defined need. President Harold B. Lee, in his last public reference to Welfare Services, stated:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p27" pid="WL3Ar7aZHkWb6YvRDY3L3A" hash="K0oGMg">“There is no person who knows the purpose for which this Welfare Program is being instituted, but hardly before sufficient preparation has been made the real purpose will be revealed, and when that time comes, it will challenge every resource of the Church to meet it.” (Church Employees Christmas Program, 1973.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p28" pid="BgPFIA7UT068qv3ZsTUpsA" hash="POmDPQ">Perilous times await us. Judgments will be poured out upon the wicked. Saints must live in obedience to righteous principles to be safe from the calamities declared by holy prophets. There is much work to be done before the return of our Lord and Savior. It is true that we do not know precisely the <span class="emphasis">day</span> of the Lord’s second coming. As Elder Bruce R. McConkie says, “Deliberately and advisedly the actual time of his coming has been left uncertain and unspecified, so that men of each succeeding age shall be led to prepare for it as though it would be in their mortal lives.” (<span class="emphasis">Doctrinal New Testament Commentary,</span> vol. I, Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1973, p. 675.) Now there is always some risk in speaking of prophetic events in connection with welfare planning because there are those who jump to speculative conclusions. But the Lord gives us prophecy that we might prepare ourselves: for he said, “If ye are prepared ye shall not fear.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.30" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:30</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system.p29" pid="ojDOUlQmVkKR3o1Jq_Oxiw" hash="6lVr_A">The Storehouse Resource System enables us to apply the principles of preparation, love, service, sacrifice, and consecration. It is only upon these principles and these works that Zion is ever established. I bear witness that while we now face and will always face difficult challenges, this is God’s kingdom; this is his work; we are his people; and our ultimate triumph through the Lord is assured, to which I testify in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1978/04/the-storehouse-resource-system</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1978-general-conference/1978-04-6020-bishop-j-richard-clarke-64k-eng.mp3" length="6164706" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 1978 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Successful Welfare Stewardship</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Brothers and sisters, I am so thankful to be involved in the great welfare plan of the Church. I testify from the depths of my soul that this great movement was revealed by Almighty God to his latter-day prophets.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03102_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="G_d2ww">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="iezaA9L8AkaWB-npgK03cQ" hash="z6T50Q">Successful Welfare Stewardship</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="TkbqrAC69ECfMQdA6JKD2g" hash="72aVTw">J. Richard Clarke</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a6e.jpg" alt="Bishop J. Richard Clarke" pid="bwAyP9p-xUC4_MXGzLoQiw" hash="S4JOpA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p1" pid="77UaFZFgFkWDi6tCBMaGhQ" hash="YMqV_A">Brothers and sisters, I am so thankful to be involved in the great welfare plan of the Church. I testify from the depths of my soul that this great movement was revealed by Almighty God to his latter-day prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p2" pid="5xDSr81HgUankFDYJkK3LA" hash="6DFYAQ">We have come a long way since the early days of welfare, but we have an enormous distance yet to travel. With the great expansion of missionary work throughout the earth, the ministering to temporal needs will likewise expand. To meet this magnificent challenge successfully, we must be wise and faithful stewards.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p3" pid="GTHETHey6kyvgZE1aTYvOQ" hash="Aj-8dA">Modern scripture reminds us that all things belong to the Lord. He declared, “I, the Lord, stretched out the heavens, and built the earth, my very handiwork; and all things therein are mine, … all these properties. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p4" pid="Hzeha2E8R0yQONN5gQ7Gwg" hash="oILbtw">“And if the properties are mine, then ye are stewards.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/104.14,55-56" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 104:14, 55–56</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p5" pid="V5TyuRIhtkKyM0h54xmrXA" hash="Ak6-ew">The lessons of stewardship are vividly taught in the parable of the talents (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.14-30" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:14–30</a>). To be profitable servants, we must improve that which the Lord has entrusted to us. Stewards are managers, and sound management reduces waste and ensures an appropriate return on invested resources. How happy were the servants who could report to their lord that they had done all that was expected of them and were told, “Well done, thou good and faithful servant: thou hast been faithful over a few things, I will make thee ruler over many things” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.21" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p6" pid="W5K1QKCKQkqGshNnTvOVfg" hash="l_6IhA">I believe there are three elements which characterize successful stewardship—agency, diligence, and accountability. We are free to accept or reject the invitation to serve, but once we accept, we assume full responsibility for the results. In section 4 of the Doctrine and Covenants, we read, “O ye that embark in the service of God [I see this as the invitation], see that ye serve him with all your heart, might, mind and strength” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/4.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 4:2</a>). And then, in section 72: “It is required of the Lord, at the hand of every steward, to render an account of his stewardship, both in time and in eternity” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/72.3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 72:3</a>). While we are ultimately accountable to the Lord, we are also accountable to his mortal priesthood administrators.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p7" pid="KmCYlAvpakmn6xUrDGrUkQ" hash="3ogoKg">Let us now focus more specifically on how we may fulfill our stewardship responsibilities within the Storehouse Resource System:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p8" pid="9kB0RYaYXUSZweK3ZMR5fQ" hash="8rzGng">First is the process of planning. Planning makes it possible to control and maximize our resources. Lack of proper planning results in frustration. Most of us have learned that trial-and-error management is wasteful and discouraging. So that eventually each area or zone will be self-sustaining, we are selectively introducing master planning throughout the Church. Welfare master planning is the process of identifying needs and programming resources to meet those needs. When the master plan is fully implemented, our bishops will be able to assist the needy more adequately under changing economic conditions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p9" pid="MWkWimFHXUK3YfjR433KDg" hash="_7YwTg">Second, a good steward operates efficiently. Two years ago, President Kimball said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p10" pid="4-dcn3gdBEu9N88d1iGBFw" hash="Bl-N3Q">“Let us become efficient in our production operations, so that we don’t merely go through the motions of having welfare farms. The time will come when we will need all the products and more from our projects—even more than we do now.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p11" pid="m5Yd97KMQ06DhZ3_Jo6wFQ" hash="nnLzug">“Do what you can to make our projects economically viable, so that we don’t rationalize that the welfare project is good simply … for the priesthood to labor side by side; we can have the brotherhood of labor and the economic efficiency too.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign, </span>May 1976, pp. 125–26.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p12" pid="UrQyJJGXtUaXlsII0MLedw" hash="RZOWzg">Addressing a welfare conference in 1960, President J. Reuben Clark, Jr., counseled:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p13" pid="NwcPCsR2iUOcM7Hms4RL0w" hash="zX_VBg">“It is my humble judgment today that it would be better for us never to have acquired a welfare project than to fail to take care of it now that we have it. The Lord will not hold us blameless, those of us who lead in the wards and the stakes, … if we take of the funds of the people, those sacred trust funds, and purchase projects and then do not utilize those projects as the Lord would have us.” (Welfare agricultural meeting, 4 Apr. 1960.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p14" pid="QZoc7kOSkE-InnccXXo5Sg" hash="15Uuag">It is a sobering responsibility to administer these sacred funds at Church headquarters. When we receive an application for a loan or Church participation, we review financial statements and projections very carefully. We critically assess the organizational structure, the management, and the local priesthood involvement with each project. The application forms tell us much about the quality of the stewards operating the project.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p15" pid="amvcjhWRXUaY2VX_e3JTIA" hash="6OM-BA">Third, let us improve our quality control. Good quality is never an accident; it is always the result of high intention and sincere effort. We commend you who are following the prescribed standards and procedures to assure that our storehouse commodities are pure and nutritional. President Kimball put quality control in perspective recently at the groundbreaking of a new cannery. He said, “[We should] be pleased to serve a meal of our products to the Lord, were it … our privilege to have him visit any one of our storehouses.” The phrase “good enough for welfare” must take on new meaning. Nothing less than our very best is acceptable to the Lord. The <span class="emphasis">Deseret</span> label should stand for highest quality because behind that label are the labors of love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p16" pid="n4lgUnOA3EitUiI9LQfGYg" hash="__SS-g">Whether in services or produced goods, by management or volunteer workers, quality control applies to every aspect of welfare services. The quality of commodities received into the storehouse is the final measurement of our production efficiency.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p17" pid="oW2oM7l2WE-4_mikCIa4GQ" hash="NKseqg">Fourth, closely associated with quality control is safety. I am glad to say that our safety record is improving, but there are still too many accidents occurring in some of our units. The cost in human terms is tragic. In dollars, in labor losses, and fire losses it totals several hundred thousand dollars each year.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p18" pid="FGnN3iCh90q6Y6zhK6wVvQ" hash="9ZU5SA">We would like to remind you that the Church is primarily self-insuring. This means that when carelessness results in replaceable loss, we are forced to draw upon the sacred funds of the Church to restore that which has been damaged or lost. A handbook has been prepared to outline the safety procedures for all that is done in the Storehouse Resource System. Will you study its contents carefully and apply them consistently? Remember, most accidents are preventable.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p19" pid="9PH023gxsUue1-wf1ew_qA" hash="QScTDA">Fifth, a good steward will follow preventive maintenance. He will see that every building is well constructed and annually inspected and that all equipment is regularly inspected and serviced. He will extend the life of every capital asset through wise management. I have a sign in my office which reads: “Why is there always enough time to do things over, but never enough time to do it right?” Preventive maintenance allows us to do it right the first time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p20" pid="ac4Rt6AK7EmrQjAIFA5Liw" hash="CSQfJQ">Sixth, a wise steward maintains good accounting records and follows sound financial practices. We are upgrading our accounting data system to provide you and us with better information. We appreciate your patience and assistance in implementing this new system. As you know, sound judgment depends upon effective data. We thank you who are accurately submitting your reports as requested.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p21" pid="-H6x32mFgUaUabxwHL2Nxw" hash="yDt25A">With general Church participation in acquiring capital assets, it is incumbent that you manage prudently. We exhort you to seek participation only for equipment and other capital assets that are justifiably needed for successful production. The Lord’s trust in these matters should never be violated.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p22" pid="a8kk0PaKrkiy1TVu8ihgvQ" hash="SFigMA">The business reputation of the Church must be held impeccable. All accounts payable should be remitted as agreed. Very often nonprofit organizations expect discounts on their purchases and then they’re dilatory in payment. Let it not be so with us. This applies to your promissory notes with the Church and your production commitments. These are sacred obligations and should be honored accordingly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p23" pid="P3CwyUHQCk2BmtgUtc49Pg" hash="lZ3i1w">Now, brothers and sisters, so much remains to be done. May we follow the counsel and example of our leader, President Kimball. At the October welfare conference last year, he said: “May I urge you to go forward in this great work. So much depends upon our willingness to make up our minds collectively and individually, that present levels of performance are not acceptable, either to ourselves or the Lord.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1977, p. 79.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p24" pid="MFQZT61mQ0yEButsep9uHg" hash="0uPMjw">To all who diligently labor, the Lord gives this promise: “And whoso is found a faithful, a just, and a wise steward shall enter into the joy of his Lord, and shall inherit eternal life” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/51.19" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 51:19</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship.p25" pid="Zcqv_wkOIEWaClvLc4jokA" hash="LrEjbg">My brothers and sisters, the Lord loves you for your devotion and untiring efforts. May he bless you as you continue to meet the great challenges before us today and tomorrow, I humbly pray in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1978/10/successful-welfare-stewardship</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1978-general-conference/1978-10-6040-bishop-j-richard-clarke-64k-eng.mp3" length="10238332" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 1978 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Household of Faith</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, the greatest test for any generation is how it responds to the voice of the prophets. Our prophets have admonished us to—</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03128_000_036" doc-version="2" hash="zxgjlg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="ShmWTOuOoUKLXWiGIVKMrA" hash="8Q6yWA">The Household of Faith</h1><p class="authorName" pid="ybpN3T3gnkKLJv0YabjgSQ" hash="72aVTw">J. Richard Clarke</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a6e.jpg" alt="Bishop J. Richard Clarke" pid="pIiHTeNF7UeRydJksDVGjQ" hash="S4JOpA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p1" pid="v585HoDp-kKSoavMGmpu1Q" hash="AomQpw">My dear brothers and sisters, the greatest test for any generation is how it responds to the voice of the prophets. Our prophets have admonished us to—</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.f2"><ol class="number"><li pid="5s49pPArxU66vzks2_Kw4Q" hash="RRNoyw">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="Rp0Ny-rXKkKC1xnfCAMjMw" hash="m8A1aw">Increase our personal righteousness.</p>
        </li><li pid="vqehXy56u0Cv5GYXTDrGhw" hash="-x8NFQ">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="rx7K7FimNUq-CVyMW8VYSg" hash="v2ikig">Live within our means and get out of debt.</p>
        </li><li pid="-35FJlYO7U-lAOeZmdlQpQ" hash="L1mFqQ">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="xeafgr7GskGu_aJZ1KF51g" hash="yEfOxA">Produce, can, and store enough food, clothing, and, where possible, fuel for one year.</p>
        </li></ol></div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p2" pid="R6zvS4oVlk2jL7aF8F-mjg" hash="EUFbdg">This straightforward counsel has not been followed by all of you. Some have believed and complied; others have waited until they could be sure the storm clouds were really gathering; and still others have rejected the counsel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p3" pid="ampddWUcxk-iXaI5cv6dbQ" hash="3DJnGQ">There was once a group of villagers who instructed their young shepherd, “When you see a wolf, cry ‘Wolf! Wolf!’ and we’ll come with guns and pitchforks.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p4" pid="h-MyBLF27EO8PnRc3hCEYw" hash="T13s5Q">The next day the boy was tending his sheep when he saw a mountain lion in the distance. He cried out, “Lion! Lion!” But no one came. The lion killed several sheep. The boy was distressed: “Why didn’t you come when I yelled?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p5" pid="elKVCZKl0UGKTdUvH4jdoA" hash="6K4kZw">“There are no lions in this part of the country,” they replied. “It is wolves that we are afraid of.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p6" pid="LkNEfOSfCkSNsrJqxRzS7w" hash="7jB3Rg">The young shepherd learned a very valuable lesson:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p7" pid="X6HKJbBX40acQYuhkT_o2g" hash="Hcdz5w">
        <span class="emphasis">People respond only to what they are prepared to believe.</span> The Brethren hesitate sometimes to talk in bold terms regarding the realities of the economy and the need for individual and family preparedness. Such talk is interpreted by the black-cloud watchers as a time of general calamity, and many stampede to the grocery stores to get ahead of the hoarders.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p8" pid="mrtxhGo0YEaQ057Zjm0EZQ" hash="m5RiPw">In April 1976 Bishop Featherstone suggested a one-year goal for members to store a year’s supply of food. Some of those who had not yet begun a home storage program rushed out and plunged deeply into debt to buy hundreds of dollars of groceries. They then sat back, as did the Prophet Jonah, to see what was going to happen to Nineveh: It was as if Brother Featherstone had officially set doomsday as April 1, 1977. This was not his intention. The Lord’s way has always been an orderly preparation, not one of second-guessing, confusion, and panic.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p9" pid="5U871MpTcUK0JmkiZJED9g" hash="PVxVlg">Let us be wise stewards. Let us ponder the lessons of history and profit from the experiences of those who have not heeded the prophets. Gibbons, Toynbee, Durant, and other noted historians have analyzed the reasons for the fall of the mighty civilizations. The repetition is monotonous. In summarizing cause and effect, an American educator lists six common reasons why each civilization fell:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p10" pid="9CYSvZdP6kWRke2r0pkCSA" hash="dY73JQ">“1. They lost their religious convictions and flouted basic morality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p11" pid="uh8hvPJxyUyQhvlTtv6vgQ" hash="IJQQMA">“2. They became obsessed with sex.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p12" pid="nQaahutt1UWzKmBhwQ_04g" hash="YpL0aQ">“3. They debased their money of its intrinsic value and let inflation run rampant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p13" pid="KOe16Sz7pk2Yr8BBbGR4ag" hash="0VM22A">“4. Honest work ceased to be a virtue.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p14" pid="60qVBahn2Ee1vLAX12uP6Q" hash="jzB9nA">“5. Respect for law disintegrated and violence became an accepted method of achieving individual and group desires.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p15" pid="HVxaDRQugES4-ofXHROUNA" hash="4htSqQ">“6. Finally, citizens were no longer willing to be soldiers and fight for the defense of their nation and their heritage.” (Dr. Kenneth McFarland speech, “Bicentennial America’s Opportunity,” given at Fairmont Hotel, San Francisco, at the National Convention of the Independent Petroleum Association of America.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p16" pid="9Y4tsXUtbkC467cGyef6oQ" hash="MGBu_w">Brothers and sisters, will our modern nations be wise enough to escape similar destruction? Are we prepared to reverse the course of history? Through the exercise of our political rights and responsibilities, through community service, and through personal righteousness, we must free our nations from tyranny and from fiscal and moral bankruptcy to the extent of our ability. But we must never forget that permanent security is possible only on the condition that we follow the prophets of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p17" pid="L1T7EAUO3UaD9cKpmoVMBA" hash="pR47Og">In section 101 of the Doctrine and Covenants, the Lord reminds us that when the Saints are slow to hearken to his words, he is “slow to hearken unto their prayers, to answer them in the day of their trouble.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p18" pid="pCMuUQ_8HE2DaXC0Y-97Lw" hash="iu6rtw">“In the day of their peace,” he explains, “they esteemed lightly my counsel; but, in the day of their trouble, of necessity they feel after me.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/101.7-8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 101:7–8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p19" pid="ePnvFG1cuUaZJ-SDtitHjw" hash="Rh2b6w">Later in this same revelation a very powerful lesson is taught in the parable of the husbandmen. You will recall that husbandmen were hired to plant twelve olive trees in the vineyard, to build a hedge around it, to build a tower, and to set a watchman thereon. As they counseled together, however, they couldn’t understand why the Lord would have need for a tower, “seeing this is a time of peace” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/101.48" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 101:48</a>). While they held a committee meeting, contending, “at variance one with another they became very slothful. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p20" pid="WTsIl95uS0GOpaU43pSwxg" hash="9ASa_Q">“And the enemy came by night, and broke down the hedge,” scattered the frightened servants, and “destroyed their works, and broke down the olive trees.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/101.50-51" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 101:50–51</a>.) It was a terrible way to learn the consequences of disobedience. How much better just to follow the simple instruction of the Master.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p21" pid="OHccjjIse0Cohu11JOWNTA" hash="k5iqdg">Each gospel dispensation produces a number of valiant, faithful Saints—the truly elect and noble of God. They may be one individual or an entire family. They are honored and remembered not by worldly standards but for their simple majestic faith. They have placed obedience to God as their sacred obligation. They love him. They trust him. They are committed to serve him. They are the bone, muscle, and sinew of the church of God in every age. They form the household of faith. Here are some classic statements from their ranks:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p22" pid="knJ_XTao10evNKSO-otyGQ" hash="ZBO_dQ">“I know not, save the Lord commanded me” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/5.6" class="scriptureRef">Moses 5:6</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p23" pid="XDrlJ45gg0KhaFDuEZ8CVg" hash="uKSWjw">“As for me and my house, we will serve the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/24.15" class="scriptureRef">Josh. 24:15</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p24" pid="fEFKXfasEEOOnbbEaen_bQ" hash="_pC1pA">“I will go and do the things which the Lord hath commanded” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 3:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p25" pid="uE8TfZtx9kyZtyqRhlGjLg" hash="K1RpSA">“Behold the handmaid of the Lord; be it unto me according to thy word” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/1.38" class="scriptureRef">Luke 1:38</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p26" pid="qk6qXTaVuk28Q6PRGtjkLw" hash="aocRRA">“I … feel to say to the Lord, humbly, ‘Give me this mountain’ (<a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/14.12" class="scriptureRef">Josh. 14:12</a>), give me these challenges. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p27" pid="Q3bKWXdat0aCfXNJiuPqkQ" hash="oD8NFg">“I will ‘wholly follow the Lord my God’ (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/14.8" class="scriptureRef">Josh. 14:8</a>) to the fullest extent of my energy and ability.” (Spencer W. Kimball, in Conference Report, Oct. 1979, p. 115.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p28" pid="QLnituHDgkWH27BL0u18hA" hash="F8lkwg">Brothers and sisters, we do not always know why the Lord commands us to do certain things. His ways are not man’s ways. But this much we do know—his paths are straight. They are not the crooked paths of men. We accept faith as the first principle of the gospel; but do we trust the Lord enough to act first and receive confirmation later? Some may call this blind obedience. An Idaho bishop used to say, “Any kind of obedience is better than any kind of disobedience.” Faith is not blind. However, we will often receive no witness until <span class="emphasis">after</span> a trial of our faith. If we have been disobedient in the past, let us commit today to repent and to put our house in order.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p29" pid="esNZijpvgU68Q9EphhD94w" hash="0168WQ">I believe we can best accomplish this by applying the counsel of the prophets in three critical temporal problems confronting the Saints: (1) the management of personal income and expenditures; (2) the dwindling of work quality and productivity; and (3) the insufficiency of reserves, in the form of both cash and commodities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p30" pid="sWZ4YnrbwEO6zr-1qPG1Bg" hash="hcwHwA">Regarding the need for financial management, let me refer you to President Tanner’s classic talk, “Constancy and Change,” given during October 1979 general conference and suggest that you study it carefully. Proper budgeting is essential to sound management. There is no question that we all need the discipline of a budget.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p31" pid="URuAzyY7WkqpK-ZrSPu8MQ" hash="H8Nirg">We have been counseled to get out of debt. This directive has been confusing to many of us over the years. How is it possible to be out of debt and to buy a home, finance education, or start a business? When President Clark advised us to avoid debt as we would the plague, I believe he was teaching us a vital principle of temporal harmony. Debt is always a burden, but some debt is necessary. Sound business debt, home mortgages, and other forms of “secured” debt are unavoidable for most of us. However, extravagant use of credit, which comes from yielding to our emotions rather than reason, creates burden.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p32" pid="VkEjhjuaCkWOlXRi2Yqhqg" hash="3BOw7w">For most of us, consumer debt is dangerous and difficult to contain because it is so readily available. It can appease an immediate want—as well as a bona fide need. Enticing advertisements convince us that luxuries are our right and our need. Isn’t it interesting how a luxury once enjoyed soon becomes a necessity?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p33" pid="NyhC1EIDhkqJcONDXkCB5Q" hash="MsEDiQ">Our guide for credit management should be: borrow only what we must, at the lowest rate available, for the shortest time possible. This requires restraint of appetites and practice of the time-honored virtue of frugality. There is an insidious philosophy that advocates plunging into debt and letting inflation pay it off. I reject this philosophy. If we all operated on that premise, we would completely subvert our economic system. As long as we secure our debt with equity, we can manage it; but to amass debt by pledging future earnings submerges us in financial quicksand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p34" pid="MDFdmUxBkEimHD92uIeUTQ" hash="wuLqHQ">In order to balance our personal income and expenditures, we obviously reduce expenses or increase our earnings. Too often, however, people find it easier to adjust to a tighter budget than to find ways to generate additional income. Is it possible that our members are becoming part of a “conspiracy for mediocrity” by being content with their present knowledge and skills? Pride of workmanship has always been the heart of a competitive free-enterprise system. There are too many tradesmen who will not pay the price to become craftsmen, teachers who do not teach, repairmen who do not repair, farmers who do not farm, leaders who do not lead, and problem solvers in every field who do not solve problems.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p35" pid="IBMNK9iVdUiaTt4GKwEkDw" hash="H5qN6g">Our labor should be honest labor and quality labor. The only honorable way for each of us to share in the world’s wealth is to exchange our own goods and services for those produced by someone else. The Saints would be in demand everywhere and could command premium compensation if we would accept the challenge to set a Mormon standard of quality, unique because of its excellence. This is part of our religion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p36" pid="vrXfFCD8J0K1U0JHyAwuxQ" hash="ccvr7g">Let me repeat what has been taught from the beginning. Adam learned, as part of his first lesson by the Lord on economics, that the earth was to be subdued and dominion gained by sweat, by brain and brawn. The divine law of work shall never be repealed—for God established it. He has cursed idleness and commanded parents in Zion to teach their children to work. There is a high price for excellence, but the compensation and soul satisfaction are truly worth it. To work below our capabilities creates a deep hunger in ourselves and enormous waste in society. Our doctrine of eternal progression certainly encompasses our occupational progress. Each of us should be on a career path which will require us to stretch to our full potential.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p37" pid="Nm4o1iIf0EKk8J10HRnskw" hash="PrhHlg">Finally, concerning the insufficiency of reserves, God gave a natural instinct to the animals he created to preserve their surplus against a time of need. But man has developed the tendency to squander all that he harvests and to leave to chance or to others his satisfaction of future needs. This is contrary to divine law. Frugality is a principle of righteousness. Consumption should never exceed our production. Economic freedom comes from the surpluses we create.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p38" pid="FvGuwd0kpEWwaJUjxBPJ_w" hash="fdrNtQ">In addition to our reserve of food, we should build a cash reserve. We should form habits of thrift and teach our children that part of everything we earn should be ours to keep. It is true that inflation reduces the purchasing power of savings, but how much purchasing power do no savings have?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p39" pid="Se-a7AhZ6kizc-M-7zJy4g" hash="Cx9mfg">Another major reserve is home equity. Our major concern is that too many families have overextended themselves so that the debt burden overshadows the benefit of home ownership. Again, let us be sure we do not confuse wants with needs.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p40" pid="W2LoQjvwnk6CRQOAZQDsiw" hash="OyndsA">One final concern of reserve deficiency is the need to insure against our greatest potential loss. I think we all would agree that our ability to earn is our greatest asset. When the provider insures his life, he is insuring his future income for his family. As husbands, let us not force our wives into the marketplace to be both the provider and homemaker should our lives be cut short by premature death. We can increase their options by proper insurance planning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p41" pid="fHmuxb7DOka6td3-CA4CKQ" hash="FqrjCA">We would also urge each family to carry adequate health insurance. Medical costs are soaring, and trying to self-insure from personal savings is very risky. During inflation, medical costs increase faster than our savings accumulate.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p42" pid="H6wkHmaIhE-_fWv3pALklg" hash="W0K6MA">Since its inception, there have been critics of the welfare program—but some people have a problem for every solution. I am sure there were Israelites in Egypt who did not want to leave their homes until Moses could explain how they were going to get across the Red Sea. It was not until they followed Moses to the shores of the Red Sea that the Lord opened up the way to them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p43" pid="T3SdsgsKUECGIpGOEaJ9kQ" hash="aj5CfQ">Brothers and sisters, we do not know by what means or when a crisis will occur in our family. Residents of Michigan did not need a nationwide, full-scale depression to tax their economic resources and cause many to lose their jobs. If I have a crippling disability for a prolonged period, my income stops just as surely as if it were caused by a national catastrophe. We tend to view distasteful circumstances in a rather detached way; but, as one of the American presidential candidates recently said, “If my neighbor loses his job, it is a recession; but if I lose my job, that’s a depression.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p44" pid="smXw2x5JXkaGyu_MiMYxKg" hash="J7gtHQ">There are some who feel that they are secure as long as they have funds to purchase food. Money is not food. If there is no food in the stores or in the warehouses, you cannot sustain life with money. Both President Romney and President Clark have warned us that we will yet live on what we produce.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p45" pid="--nhGDQzckWwZRdEiqAVxA" hash="_Vallw">I would like to make one point very clear. The welfare services program of the Church is essentially you and I being self-sufficient within our own families. The Church storehouse system is a backup system for the small number of members who are poor or physically handicapped, or for emergencies or disasters. There is <span class="emphasis">no way</span> the Church, as an institution, intends to assume the responsibility that rightfully belongs to the individual. The welfare program was never designed to do so. Personal and family preparedness is the Lord’s way. Then, by uniting together to pay generous fast offerings and by providing commodities from our projects and canneries, we can help our neighbor who cannot help himself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p46" pid="mTAPFPLeIEWEGbpj-S9DFw" hash="oDMmLA">Most important of all, brothers and sisters, with all our storing, let us store righteousness that we may stand approved of the Lord. In 1833 the Lord said,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p47" pid="mpynSm_d5E6uG29muCaJtA" hash="kXtjoQ">“Therefore, let your hearts be comforted, for all things shall work together for good to them that walk uprightly, and to the sanctification of the church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p48" pid="xfsKjHxB_EGk-IFwFLVCbw" hash="i51bbQ">“For I will raise up unto myself a pure people, that will serve me in righteousness;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p49" pid="itAgjVXlxEGgJVBZMht-5Q" hash="76a0XA">“And all that call upon the name of the Lord, and keep his commandments, shall be saved.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/100.15-17" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 100:15–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith.p50" pid="5FiK2qrJN061Gyl0Xe1AyA" hash="t-2yoA">Such a people will be known as the “household of faith” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.45" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:45</a>). That we may be found in their midst is my prayer, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1980/10/the-household-of-faith</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1980-general-conference/1980-10-6030-bishop-j-richard-clarke-64k-eng.mp3" length="15856999" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 1980 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Love Extends beyond Convenience</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Brothers and sisters: Rikki Pace, the fifteen-year-old daughter of Glenn Pace, our new managing director of the Welfare Department, was overheard in a conversation with a school friend. It went something like this:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03141_000_032" doc-version="2" hash="OWZ6qA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="6qGFgWC5r0OdBEcZTDoFcw" hash="Zqt6Qw">Love Extends beyond Convenience</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ABP8E87-_EabQRkesRP0ew" hash="72aVTw">J. Richard Clarke</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a6e.jpg" alt="Bishop J. Richard Clarke" pid="3y9N2fgFOEmLXGWlyW872A" hash="S4JOpA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p1" pid="fC81nzRQMUqyxYqajMr2Ig" hash="iBQf1w">Brothers and sisters: Rikki Pace, the fifteen-year-old daughter of Glenn Pace, our new managing director of the Welfare Department, was overheard in a conversation with a school friend. It went something like this:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p2" pid="XXRAuO9QGk24qQZ5j4Z2KA" hash="BFXRSg">“Where does your dad work?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p3" pid="agzuGlVxkUuiyCEcSsxE-Q" hash="o7WM_w">“At the Church Office Building.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p4" pid="-3GYSnztYkirchSE1LsODg" hash="FmtjoA">“Where’s the Church Office Building?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p5" pid="noFwzvFDMkGCDIBZwvwfAA" hash="TE-gWQ">“You know, that tall building by the Temple.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p6" pid="VBUHX5G1V0y4USoclm1z3A" hash="4uQv6A">“What does he do?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p7" pid="SL2NNp8Pl0OtWUzVBqDqTw" hash="CRAq2A">“He’s in charge of the Welfare Department.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p8" pid="DNrsEnwBDkihCDZsLv7XGA" hash="GZLoSQ">“What’s the Welfare Department?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p9" pid="nHCdrKePfUmP0gibEKjLhg" hash="5AfEEQ">Well, after several attempts to explain, it didn’t appear as if any big impressions had been made. So, with one final attempt to put the subject to rest, Rikki said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p10" pid="YA5vosjsOE-qkvijkE6OyQ" hash="XSaQ4w">“Let me put it this way: between now and the Millennium if a member of the Church starves to death, it’s all my dad’s fault.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p11" pid="2EVHj02gZEiCWM8M39gTDw" hash="qj-Y4w">There are many perceptions of Welfare Services. I suppose most people perceive of welfare as farms, canneries, bishops’ storehouses, and Deseret Industries. Welfare Services is essential to that part of the central mission of the Church, which is: to perfect the Saints. Welfare Services is the gospel in action for individual members. It is not just for group or institutional involvement. Salvation comes to us on an individual basis—each must climb the ladder independently to ascend to the level of the Master. If we are to achieve perfection, we must emulate the works of Jesus as well as his words. The Apostle Peter instructed those who would be disciples of Christ to be “partakers of the divine nature.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-pet/1.4-7" class="scriptureRef">2 Pet. 1:4–7</a>.) He told them, “For even hereunto were ye called: … that ye should follow his steps.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-pet/2.21" class="scriptureRef">1 Pet. 2:21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p12" pid="sfmfcUvi8EC6iUXwKQQ32w" hash="y-1rcw">In 1897 Dr. Charles Sheldon, a young minister in Topeka, Kansas, wrote a book which he titled <span class="emphasis">In His Steps.</span> It was a novel based upon an experiment he tried. He disguised himself as an unemployed printer and tramped the streets of Topeka. He was shocked at his treatment by this “Christian” community. In his novel, a Christian minister presents his congregation with this interesting challenge:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p13" pid="OYTId8mLoEyUUsHw6hvVTw" hash="Mighhw">“I want volunteers … who will pledge themselves, earnestly and honestly for an entire year, not to do anything without first asking the question, ‘What would Jesus do?’ … Our aim will be to act just as He would if He [were] in our places, regardless of immediate results. In other words, we propose to follow Jesus’ steps as closely and as literally as we believe He taught His disciples to do.” (Charles M. Sheldon, <span class="emphasis">In His Steps,</span> New York: Grosset &amp; Dunlap, 1935, pp. 15–16.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p14" pid="NcvugpfxgE6OtPbO_qI8fw" hash="nzz4UA">The book describes the fascinating experience of those who accepted the challenge. I have been intrigued by the experiment and wonder, if it were conducted today among the Latter-day Saints, how we would measure up. As latter-day Christians, we know that the “royal law” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/2.8" class="scriptureRef">James 2:8</a>) of love in action is to “succor the weak, lift up the hands which hang down, and strengthen the feeble knees.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/81.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 81:5</a>.) Do we catch the significance of this thought? We demonstrate the depth of our love for the Savior when we care enough to seek out the suffering among us and attend to their needs.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p15" pid="rU3WYCYQbkCoq6ZhWlu3lQ" hash="SG3mbA">The philosopher William George Jordan has identified “four great hungers of life—body-hunger, mind-hunger, heart-hunger, and soul-hunger. They are all real; all need recognition, all need feeding.” (William George Jordan, <span class="emphasis">The Crown of Individuality,</span> New York: Fleming H. Revell Company, 1909, p. 63.)</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.f2">
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="SMuX7oisF0Gwn3yi_DMw-g" hash="60mFjg">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="-wO2a6koe0CTudYkRIb33A" hash="UBXHjQ">Body-hunger is our most conscious biological need. It is difficult to be spiritually strong when temporally deficient.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="w_YxdnP_UEaTcEpjBCNHGA" hash="BrWxtQ">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="1QnxgqQssEiC1C6a_Z2D6w" hash="7nd7Ng">Mind-hunger is a craving for intellectual food, for education, and for personal development.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="O7xdr3H_z0uegv3f44q6QA" hash="IJC8tw">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="KL6bt1KW-0GNRoAM8D8c_Q" hash="8n2nlQ">Heart-hunger is to be lonely, to have low self-esteem, to be misunderstood, to crave companionship, sympathy, and appreciation. However, we find that as we seek to satisfy the heart-hunger of our neighbor, we reduce our own.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="DnX4xWr-zkqFXbpo_oztUA" hash="FB3aOg">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="l3I0SvetiU2ajTybuAhnIQ" hash="gT4vUA">Soul-hunger is the burning desire to know eternal truth. It is the yearning of the spirit to commune with God. (See Jordan, pp. 63–75.)</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p16" pid="fPhsweunj0iMhA1qG53_hQ" hash="70q5Hg">The restored gospel of Jesus Christ provides the solution to all the hungers of life. Jesus said: “I am the bread of life: he that cometh to me shall never hunger; and he that believeth on me shall never thirst.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/6.35" class="scriptureRef">John 6:35</a>.) We would all like to have the Savior’s capacity to assuage the hungers of the world; but let us not forget that there are many simple ways by which we can walk in His steps. Let us remember that in giving of ourselves, it is less a question of giving a lot than of giving at the right moment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p17" pid="zQXgnPMyOky1Xt2Hfmq2KA" hash="Yv_pxg">A noted columnist, Erma Bombeck, described an experience which reminds us that little things can mean a lot. She recounted a frustrating morning of numerous phone calls and interrupting conversations before leaving for the airport.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p18" pid="7RQ_0N0LZ0yWLZ8tvitUCg" hash="Bf7auw">And then she said, “[At last] there were thirty whole beautiful minutes before my plane took off—time for me to be alone with my own thoughts, to open a book and let my mind wander. A voice next to me belonging to an elderly woman said, ‘I’ll bet it’s cold in Chicago.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p19" pid="DbB3vLadGkeFAjgvf50ffA" hash="eBdwTg">“Stone-faced, I answered, ‘It’s likely.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p20" pid="w7FkPFajZEaJcTaUa_SY7Q" hash="mqRi-Q">“‘I haven’t been to Chicago in nearly three years,’ she persisted. ‘My son lives there.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p21" pid="ljtc4aguRUK-RNVqx4WQQA" hash="eY96zQ">“‘That’s nice,’ I said, my eyes intent on the printed page of the book.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p22" pid="dCkx_uqWdUWPlJ_9N5-_iw" hash="lc-imw">“‘My husband’s body is on this plane. We’ve been married for fifty-three years. I don’t drive, you know, and when he died a nun drove me from the hospital. We aren’t even Catholic. The funeral director let me come to the airport with him.’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p23" pid="Peq7A1q5nUensh53b8_6zA" hash="phsMcQ">Erma said, “I don’t think I have ever detested myself more than I did at that moment. Another human being was screaming to be heard and in desperation had turned to a cold stranger who was more interested in a novel than in the real-life drama at her elbow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p24" pid="UoSG8szPG0SLdAcutJiFKA" hash="VlG6xA">“All she needed was a listener—no advice, wisdom, experience, money, assistance, expertise or even compassion—but just a minute or two to listen. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p25" pid="ykpBTkrZVEa4V5HCgah_Fg" hash="d906zg">“She talked numbly and steadily until we boarded the plane, [and] then found her seat in another section. As I hung up my coat, I heard her plaintive voice say to her seat companion, ‘I’ll bet it’s cold in Chicago.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p26" pid="ZT2MxS9XtkWnv3gG7uEz0Q" hash="mJpP6Q">“I prayed, ‘Please, God, let her listen.’” (Erma Bombeck, “Are You Listening?” <span class="emphasis">If Life Is a Bowl of Cherries—What Am I Doing in the Pits?,</span> New York: McGraw-Hill Book Co., 1978, pp. 197–98.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p27" pid="HuSsA1ExG0uuOj3rq1FOqg" hash="0NwDAw">How many times have we observed a benevolent act performed by someone and asked ourselves, “Why didn’t I think of that?” Those who do the deeds we would have liked to do seem to have mastered the art of awareness. They have formed the habit of being sensitive to the needs of others before they think of themselves. How swiftly opportunity slips away, and we are left with another unfulfilled good intention. If only our acts of kindness could equal the righteous desires of our hearts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p28" pid="xRLqcsg_VEWShD8Z4nS2jg" hash="5RJ_Zw">Striking a blow at our propensity to delay our acting as we know we should, the poet John Drinkwater penned his poem, “A Prayer,” which I quote in part:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.f3">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="TYXd--Dgyk2VoYQe1krRJg" hash="fa_PvQ">
            <span class="emphasis">We know the paths wherein our feet should press,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="-PoM3Yg3bUiGMRgVhUgweg" hash="-044Ow">
            <span class="emphasis">Across our hearts are written Thy decrees.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Pb0JoVtDpE2_YvWiygm7sg" hash="Cece5w">
            <span class="emphasis">Yet now, O Lord, be merciful to bless</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="gzt3F-X0tEWBlXfKR1X7Qw" hash="ssOC6w">
            <span class="emphasis">With more than these.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="Ogxav-E4CU6u4hppZ_LzXQ" hash="ffexYw">
            <span class="emphasis">Grant us the will to fashion as we feel,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="L_Z14DMZ_EKJ-DT6FwEq8g" hash="2URyyw">
            <span class="emphasis">Grant us the strength to labour as we know,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="NeDvrDUVBEm1SIS6kD_JRg" hash="3xrDRQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Grant us the purpose, ribbed and edged with steel,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="P0uIGXsd3UuFA60MFtv3NA" hash="wJ-bfw">
            <span class="emphasis">To strike the blow.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="kdxvoRXOgUudINv_9teqSw" hash="j3GEBw">
            <span class="emphasis">Knowledge we ask not—knowledge Thou hast lent;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="NsPsUN62R0qswUiEj8D_iQ" hash="5mALOw">
            <span class="emphasis">But Lord, the will—there lies our bitter need.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="l1ITFKg9SUioQd0zx0S-0w" hash="OIoWgA">
            <span class="emphasis">Give us to build above the deep intent</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="-We8ZaEycUGQC86BGpChPg" hash="BLjf4A">
            <span class="emphasis">The deed, the deed.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p29" pid="pc06x4aKGkKFrBZyPjFTLw" hash="iLayMg">When I think of performing deeds of kindness, I immediately think of bishops and Relief Society presidents. Relatively few people know of the many hours they selflessly spend in serving members of their wards. They truly translate principles into deeds.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p30" pid="xBFusbs8BUyrZpALZEZf4Q" hash="15Tf0Q">To illustrate, I quote this heartwarming pioneer account:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p31" pid="G0LgywJSDUW44P73RYECcQ" hash="bkSOCA">“Many years ago in a small town in the southern part of the state of Utah, my great grandmother was called to be the president of the Relief Society. During this period of our Church’s history there existed a very bitter and antagonistic spirit between the Mormons and the Gentiles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p32" pid="-D3DkC7NbUyESwOfoT7IHA" hash="82844w">“In my great grandmother’s ward one of the young sisters married a gentile boy. This of course did not please either the Mormons or the Gentiles very much. In the course of time this young couple gave birth to a child. Unfortunately the mother became so ill in the process of childbirth that she was unable to care for her baby. Upon learning of this woman’s condition, great grandmother immediately went to the homes of the sisters in the ward and asked them if they would take a turn going into the home of this young couple to care for the baby. One by one these women refused and so the responsibility fell completely upon her.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p33" pid="lhhPrhK600O569tGpxUsdg" hash="mOwhLw">“She would arise early in the morning, walk what was a considerable distance to the home of this young couple where she would bathe and feed the baby, gather all that needed to be laundered and take it with her to her home. … One morning she felt too weak and sick to go. … However, as she lay in bed she realized that if she didn’t go the child would not be provided for. [With the help of the Lord,] she mustered all her strength and went. [When she returned home, exhausted, she] collapsed into a large chair and immediately fell into a deep sleep. She said that as she slept she felt as if she were consumed by a fire that would melt the very marrow of her bones. She … dreamed that she was bathing the Christ child and glorying in what a great privilege it would have been to have bathed the Son of God. Then the voice of the Lord spoke to her saying, ‘Inasmuch as ye have done it unto the least of these, ye have done it unto me.’” (<span class="emphasis">My Errand from the Lord,</span> A Personal Study Guide for Melchizedek Priesthood Quorums 1976–77, pp. 154–55.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p34" pid="ZBHQYnHxPUSu4NWWV0NWAA" hash="ozrhmQ">Perhaps the most heroic acts are done quietly and with no recognition except from a loving Heavenly Father who rewards us with the sweet peace that passeth understanding (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/philip/4.7" class="scriptureRef">Philip. 4:7</a>) and by His Spirit whispers, “Well done, [my] good and faithful servant.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.21" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p35" pid="2Ur3AfQ_xECeoElaRkUPog" hash="Thg2cg">I was touched by an experience that was recently related to me. A dear sister had been incapacitated for the past eight years—she could not walk or talk and was confined to bed. About six years ago, she and her husband were assigned a faithful home teacher. He asked if his wife could come over to their house every Sunday morning and stay with the invalid woman while her husband attended priesthood meeting. For six years, every Sunday this home teacher would bring his wife over to stay with the invalid sister while her husband went to his meeting. And every Sunday the home teacher’s wife would bring with her some baked goods or something special that she had made for this older couple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p36" pid="vuKeOiFDL0SP9dj_yTxbug" hash="Tj025Q">Finally, this sister who had been ill passed away. When her daughter tried to express her deep love and appreciation to this loving home teacher and his wife for what they had done over the years, the wife said, “Oh, don’t thank us. It was our <span class="emphasis">privilege</span> to visit with your sweet mother. What am I going to do now? The hour and a half on Sunday morning will now be, for me, the loneliest hour and a half in the week.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p37" pid="Nq1fyj40B02xIlR5vhV8KA" hash="6ByF3g">I am impressed that in the last moments of the Savior’s life, He had an abiding concern for His mother and for her welfare, thus again setting the example for us. Walking in His steps are the devoted sons and daughters who honor aging parents who are no longer able to help themselves. About two years ago I read this column in the newspaper:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p38" pid="-WO2fFBX20SATm8QSEucIA" hash="fsSJYA">“Dear Abby:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p39" pid="wrTlVNzB0Ue5bCxQD8KzwA" hash="IrRsCw">“I’m sitting here on the plane reading the letter in your column about the son who didn’t want to put his father up temporarily because he felt his father’s visit would be an invasion of his privacy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p40" pid="kyEHlZ4kOES0MZAUO2yMZg" hash="J1dXdA">“That item caught my eye because I am on my way to visit my son in Omaha for two weeks—at his insistence. I was reluctant to do so initially because I felt I might be interfering with his personal activities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p41" pid="JQ73ArOh8UeW9mWNzfPUPw" hash="Tu_AEw">“I wonder if the son who wrote that letter ever gave a thought to the privacy his father might have forfeited during his son’s time at home?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p42" pid="aFv0RvvtxUmbcOK7VH2Ctg" hash="Uc34Ag">“There were times during my children’s lives when, given my druthers, I’d have preferred some alternative activity, but now I don’t regret one minute of the time I spent with them. I’m only sorry it couldn’t have been more. Their time at home seems to have been so brief.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p43" pid="yGExegG8xkuDp9iAuspiTA" hash="QGY52w">“I won’t mail this, of course, since I realize you will receive thousands of more articulate letters on the above. This is just my way of …”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p44" pid="3Pww0WH4WU2JTPqexw4f_Q" hash="L-HPag">“Dear Abby: My father died suddenly of a heart attack, and this unfinished letter was in his pocket. My wife and I will miss him very much. Sign this—‘A son who really wanted his dad to come.’ William Smzyk, Omaha, Nebr.” (Abigail Van Buren, <span class="emphasis">Deseret News</span> 13 Dec. 1979, p. C7.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p45" pid="c0EvCeDI2UOIO3JBkrNSuw" hash="VhMn9w">Brothers and sisters, what I have tried to illustrate this morning is that if we are to walk in the steps of the Savior, we cannot do it without personal sacrifice and sincere involvement. It is rarely convenient; but love extends beyond convenience for those who have conditioned themselves to look for opportunities to serve. I believe that the Savior was equipped to accomplish His mission not only through His parentage, but because of His thirty years of preparation in developing an awareness of and a sensitivity to the needs of His fellowmen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p46" pid="yaUAsnW5m060lu0dlFWNLw" hash="W35dMA">In Alma, chapter seven, we read:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p47" pid="4CQcDhO9NkSqjQmeBKZYyQ" hash="zjvGiw">“And he shall go forth, suffering pains and afflictions and temptations of every kind; … that the word might be fulfilled which saith he will take upon him the pains and the sicknesses of his people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p48" pid="ujJxiSQ3x0isYt1WthA_oQ" hash="cAcsBQ">“… And he will take upon him their infirmities, that his bowels may be filled with mercy, according to the flesh, that he may know according to the flesh how to succor his people.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/7.11-12" class="scriptureRef">Alma 7:11–12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p49" pid="etrhDaEUrUCYLpLc9DC94g" hash="FzQyRw">After a recent stake conference meeting where I had discussed the role of the family in the Church, I was approached by a sweet woman who said: “Bishop, I’m a widow and I really appreciated everything you said today. I have a lovely family, but I have many problems and I do need help. My priesthood leaders have families of their own and they have lots of problems and I don’t want to bother them and add to their problems. So what should I do?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p50" pid="KrEbwSRSKUid88A3iBtzow" hash="v4QmEA">I asked her, “Do you have a good home teacher who really cares about you?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p51" pid="80RvUiZTy0ifwxTyF9gy4Q" hash="JQiXSA">She said, “Yes, I have a home teacher and he comes by every month or so; but he isn’t very involved with our family.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p52" pid="QypOcvab8Emj8set_a8EQA" hash="IV47jw">Then I asked, “Well, do you have a visiting teacher who visits you and understands you?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p53" pid="JLziqUalb0yEzMDZ5ViODA" hash="Jje_mw">She said, “Yes, the Relief Society sometimes comes.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p54" pid="qHdwXqFkEEy04BTdOwElPg" hash="AT-4KQ">At this point, I was praying for a right answer, when a lovely sister, who was standing nearby and heard our conversation, said, “Excuse me, but I was a widow; and even though I have just remarried, I know how you feel and I understand your problems. Please let me drop by. I’d like to visit with you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p55" pid="3HY0O1llIUSBmK1xX-RwPA" hash="6P5zuA">Dr. Tom Dooley offers some interesting insights regarding those who have known difficulties and can now share the burden of another. I quote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p56" pid="b8Xy8_G4h0iAPNrVNDG5HQ" hash="bg4ZOA">“One of Dr. (Albert) Schweitzer’s most important concepts is that of the Fellowship of Those who Bear the Mark of Pain. … Who are its members? Those who have learned by experience what physical pain and bodily anguish mean. These people, all over the world, are united by a secret bond. He who has been delivered from pain must not think he is now … at liberty to continue his life and forget his sickness. He is a man whose eyes are opened. He now has a duty to help others in their battles with pain and anguish. He must help to bring to others the deliverance which he himself knows.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p57" pid="DD0OYxF7F0uP2LomGGr_NQ" hash="kOsp6w">“Under this Fellowship come not only those who were formerly sick, but those who are related to sufferers, and whom does this not include?” (Thomas Dooley, “A Worldwide Fellowship,” <span class="emphasis">Words of Wisdom,</span> ed. Thomas C. Jones, Chicago: J. B. Ferguson, 1966, p. 150.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p58" pid="4v1l8RJYw0uPF5UWCt6tcA" hash="Bo-QSw">Again I refer to Dr. Sheldon’s book:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p59" pid="QcEpF0JhSkOsB1pMup6a8A" hash="gVW_5w">“It is the personal element that Christian discipleship needs to emphasize. ‘The gift without the giver is bare.’ The Christianity that attempts to suffer by proxy [<span class="emphasis">alone</span>] is not the Christianity of Christ. Each individual Christian … needs to follow <span class="emphasis">in His steps</span> along the path of personal sacrifice to Him. There is not a different path to-day from that of Jesus’ own times. It is the same path.” (Sheldon, <span class="emphasis">In His Steps,</span> p. 239; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p60" pid="bD3jzwOMzUyqmkeaBdiF8g" hash="-BLRKA">This has been a difficult assignment for me. As I have pondered how practicing welfare principles brings us to Christ, I have searched my own soul and realized that I am far short of my ideal—the Savior. As a result, I have recommitted myself to achieve the “divine nature” of Christ (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/2-pet/1.4" class="scriptureRef">2 Pet. 1:4</a>) by becoming more aware of ways in which to bless those in need.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p61" pid="4ran0mZQNUyBG6mDSQ9VPw" hash="al49aQ">I bear my testimony to you that there is a special Spirit of the Savior which accompanies welfare services. I know He loves this work and the thousands of Saints who are engaged in it. And as He counseled His covenant people in the Book of Mormon, so He entreats us today:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p62" pid="wxnE46jTeUiwCPANeU5RWg" hash="Jt-Vcw">“Verily, verily, I say unto you, this is my gospel; and ye know the things that ye must do in my church; for the works which ye have seen me do that shall ye also do; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p63" pid="51vCGc8n3k2Hhf1Nr-evmw" hash="i3mA0Q">“Therefore, if ye do these things blessed are ye, for ye shall be lifted up at the last day. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p64" pid="ohNJQDCHiEev2VWxQU_1UA" hash="xEydQQ">“Therefore, what manner of men ought ye to be? Verily I say unto you, even as I am.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.21-22,27" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 27:21–22, 27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience.p65" pid="RVWNey3F-kO3w3nMxTNByw" hash="_DyrcA">That we may walk in his steps and become even as he is I pray, in the sacred name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1981/10/love-extends-beyond-convenience</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1981-general-conference/1981-10-6010-bishop-j-richard-clarke-64k-eng.mp3" length="9517059" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 1981 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Value of Work</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Few writers in our generation have produced the number and quality of best-selling books that James A. Michener has. I am amazed at the range of his interests and his commitment to excellence. His success is not accidental. It does not come solely fr</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03148_000_035" doc-version="2" hash="Z1yVjw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="YAjGg9oloEGtZxcz9Jyt_w" hash="uJY2Bg">The Value of Work</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="2bd3_soJ2Uqys3gYOif2ew" hash="72aVTw">J. Richard Clarke</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a6e.jpg" alt="Bishop J. Richard Clarke" pid="R2f92_DMFEumY-YySXw1_Q" hash="S4JOpA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p1" pid="0_xhQjz6bEei8tGZdhXCTw" hash="ROjUwg">Few writers in our generation have produced the number and quality of best-selling books that James A. Michener has. I am amazed at the range of his interests and his commitment to excellence. His success is not accidental. It does not come solely from the endowment of a natural talent. His success comes from developing the habit of hard work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p2" pid="b-EX2uEDREqrRDDUGNnuAw" hash="OoP3Vw">He was raised in poverty by a widowed mother. From age eleven, James worked six days a week every summer and delivered papers during the winter. At age fourteen he apprenticed as a plumber and worked fourteen hours a day in the summer and four hours a day in the winter. In looking back he says, “Instead of turning me against work, this ingrained in me the attitude that sensible people work hard to attain sensible goals—a philosophy I still adhere to.” (“An Authentic Work Ethic: I. The Path to Achievement,” <span class="emphasis">Reader’s Digest,</span> Jan. 1977, p. 149.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p3" pid="Qlkdw4kFEkad5A-2W2z5Fw" hash="HeW8kA">Work is a blessing from God. It is a fundamental principle of salvation, both spiritual and temporal. When Adam was driven from his garden home, he was told that his bread must be produced by his physical toil, by the sweat of his brow. Note carefully the words: “Cursed shall be the ground <span class="emphasis">for thy sake</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/4.23" class="scriptureRef">Moses 4:23</a>; italics added), that is, for his good or benefit. It would not be easy to master the earth; but that was his challenge and his blessing, as it is ours.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p4" pid="KNlvTTDqn0OIgRgh8u__TA" hash="HKSyXA">We are cocreators with God. He gave us the capacity to do the work he left undone, to harness the energy, mine the ore, transform the treasures of the earth for our good. But most important, the Lord knew that from the crucible of work emerges the hard core of character.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p5" pid="dM4lGOWK70ugmIN4xurK5A" hash="cFLOZQ">Work has become a Mormon trademark. We are known throughout the world as a highly motivated, industrious people. Eric Hoffer once cautioned, “Put a Mormon in a hopper and out comes a tycoon.” (Quoted by C. Brooklyn Derr in <span class="emphasis">Ensign, </span>Feb. 1978, p. 3.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p6" pid="1emoYySNsUqqyxB_j70ceQ" hash="HTLt0w">This intense commitment to the work ethic is our tradition. Mormon industry has left its mark upon every piece of land we have occupied. Missouri, Nauvoo, the Salt Lake Basin, and all the valleys of the mountains where the Saints have settled are famous monuments to Mormon toil.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p7" pid="g82m45fkOEG8bMKsrQAEmQ" hash="gqHW_g">Of this period, President J. Reuben Clark observed: “We moved under our own power, without subsidy, without loan, wished on our way only by the maledictions of those who drove us out from our own homes and then appropriated, without paying for it, the property they forced us to leave behind. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p8" pid="2ou0TOKGUEm2Wg7xqJHN_g" hash="0VBlew">“So we struggled on against want and misery; toil and hardship were with us daily. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p9" pid="LYMAjTbQBUmCBpvMx0Xeag" hash="n6yJbA">“But the Church survived; the people prospered. <span class="emphasis">Character endured intact.</span> We took care of our own poor. In times of scarcity neighbors helped one another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p10" pid="p-5jn8kCPUWKOmIidzx5Lg" hash="8aZs3A">“Time and again, we passed through the fiery furnace; we came out of it each time, refined, with the dross burned away, re-inspirited, sanctified.” (<span class="emphasis">Church Welfare Plan,</span> pamphlet, 1939, pp. 8–9; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p11" pid="5eJkIaG060Wg1cMB6uhNiA" hash="hPMhRA">In this commitment, our prophets have led by example. It is said that President Wilford Woodruff loved work. “To him it was a blessing, a privilege. … His toil in the canyons, his sweat in the harvest field, … were all important parts in divine economy. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p12" pid="YYkEYaYf4Uas5fUTrs28WQ" hash="165v0A">“To sweat, was a divine command as much so as to pray.” (Matthias F. Cowley, <span class="emphasis">Wilford Woodruff: History of His Life and Labors,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret News, 1909, pp. 644–45.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p13" pid="hmBTAytjA0SsDnTDpn916Q" hash="NIiqNw">In our day, I know of no better example of obedience to the divine law of work than President Kimball. Personifying his “Do it!” philosophy, President Kimball has committed himself not only to the pursuit of happiness, but to the happiness of pursuit. On one occasion, when Dr. Wilkinson showed concern for President Kimball’s health and the increasing demands he was making on his body, President Kimball responded in a kindly way, “Your job, Brother Wilkinson, is to keep me going at the pace I am going to go.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p14" pid="A6prNrfNEEGWwWqNNMg85Q" hash="im5ISw">This reminds me of the farmer who was feeling a little sluggish and went to see his doctor. After examination, the doctor told him that his problem was that he was burning his candle at both ends. The farmer replied, “I knew that before I came. What I want from you is some more wax.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p15" pid="v7XsoSN2eUGzsAksP9By2A" hash="5jSU1Q">President Kimball’s complete dedication to his work sets a high standard for all of us. We have a moral obligation to exercise our personal capabilities of mind, muscle, and spirit in a way that will return to the Lord, our families, and our society the fruits of our best efforts. To do less is to live our lives unfulfilled. It is to deny ourselves and those dependent upon us opportunity and advantage. We work to earn a living, it is true; but as we toil, let us also remember that we are building a life. Our work determines what that life will be.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p16" pid="a8dzhYzoDkqhKopGIp-n-w" hash="YkiV2w">Work is honorable. It is good therapy for most problems. It is the antidote for worry. It is the equalizer for deficiency of native endowment. Work makes it possible for the average to approach genius. What we may lack in aptitude, we can make up for in performance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p17" pid="pocGhpUHUUmoZo2PFK2I7Q" hash="vcqCgA">As recommended by Korsaren: “If you are poor, work. … If you are happy, work. Idleness gives room for doubts and fears. If disappointments come, keep right on working. If sorrow overwhelms you, … work. … When faith falters and reason fails, just work. When dreams are shattered and hope seems dead, work. Work as if your life were in peril. It really is. No matter what ails you, work. Work faithfully. … Work is the greatest remedy available for both mental and physical afflictions.” (<span class="emphasis">The Forbes Scrapbook of Thoughts on the Business of Life,</span> New York: Forbes Inc., 1968, p. 427.)</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.f2">
	<p pid="_VErkbJ6h0-7f2ji8idDcw" hash="ndDKpg">Let me suggest some other elements of the work ethic which are important:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="xztmsAN6yE6ofZNhT90BMg" hash="0cM1cw">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="UwNrc-k_CEKVWgJE9c1Vog" hash="04KOpw">As Latter-day Saints, if we would be true to our religion, we must perform high-quality work. It is a matter of integrity. Every piece of work we do is a portrait of the one who produced it. We are increasingly concerned with the diminishing quality of work in our society. On every hand we see shoddy workmanship for which full compensation is expected, whether the product meets acceptable standards or not. We must be motivated by a higher ideal than simply meeting the artificial standard of a society which has allowed inferior performance to be acceptable. That is not the Mormon ethic. In times of unemployment, Latter-day Saints who practice the work principles of our religion should be in great demand.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="_KsbCzIWfke6YOkRkfTuQg" hash="Pex1Dg">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="M3Ivy4kfxkKp-O1ztzjstw" hash="IKbPAg">Let us give full, honest effort to our jobs as though we owned the enterprise. In a very real sense, each of us is in business for ourselves, no matter who pays us. Be honest with your employer. Make sure that “the laborer is worthy of his hire.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.79" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:79</a>.) Our employers should get the best we have in us, not just enough to get by or to meet common standards. Each of us should set a personal standard based upon our ability. Let us exemplify the old pioneer motto: A Full Day’s Work for a Full Day’s Pay.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Ry9zN4A_N0qqAXEZMFKCOQ" hash="t492Iw">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="YxwqbA-TjUuLclJFQSgtPw" hash="srpZTg">Continue to invest in your personal development. Expand your occupational horizons by constant study. Use your spare time wisely. If we waste thirteen minutes each day, it is the equivalent of two weeks a year without pay. Look to your present job as a stepping-stone along your career path. Take time to think. The dimensions of most jobs are constrained only by the mind of the uncreative worker. I like what one businessman counseled: “If at first you <span class="emphasis">do</span> succeed, try something harder!”</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="zHcxg2F8ykKYwZu1iEjj1w" hash="ThNi9A">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="YkYQ3nacd0e3ZxbzhGmKLw" hash="RbMRFg">To teach our children to work is a primary duty of parenthood. Our children have experienced unprecedented prosperity created by parents who have worked hard to provide what they themselves did not have as youngsters. If we are to save our children temporally and spiritually, we must train them to work. They must learn by example that work is not drudgery, but a blessing.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p18" pid="ah7nQNv6oUeHJFBARtmGEQ" hash="00TMdA">Fortunate is the young man or woman who has learned how to work. Wise is the parent who requires children to learn responsibility and to meet acceptable performance standards.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p19" pid="Pib4Zs65qEu_neDt1LFU0g" hash="k61GdA">In a Mother’s Day tribute, a lovely Latter-day Saint mother, Beverly Graham, expressed appreciation for her home training. She said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p20" pid="XKp6a0jAoEuxE_6qsk_4fQ" hash="27j77g">“Mother’s love included strict discipline, definite rules, and regulations that were firmly enforced. We used these rules as the starch for our backbone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p21" pid="4XO1WZx9fUy6QnQpQoXDjQ" hash="pQzd-g">“Mother loved being a mother and a lady and enjoyed the arts of homemaking. She has passed this on to my sister and me. It was with great patience that she taught us to sew, cook, clean house, iron, etc. Can reironing one of Daddy’s white shirts until it was perfect be a blessing? Or getting up to do the washing and ironing before school—a blessing? Or peeling beets, shelling peas by the hour, husking bushels and bushels of corn for canning, picking berries at the crack of dawn before the sun got too hot—blessings? You couldn’t convince me then, but you can now. They taught me great lessons in the value of thrift, work, and responsibility.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p22" pid="Qf5zfXyBbkqjjxiI3ZQBCQ" hash="wamItQ">As we teach our children these values, let us emphasize the principle of shared responsibility. Do not be confused by attempts to label some jobs as strictly male or strictly female. Generally speaking, each child should know how to do simple cooking, wash dishes, clean the house, mow the lawn, tend the baby, and wash the car. These skills will do much to make their adult lives happier and more productive.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p23" pid="D7fcD6DshEChSJG8391b4A" hash="Errjew">Now, what about our leisure time? How we use our leisure is equally as important to our joy as our occupational pursuits. Proper use of leisure requires discriminating judgment. Our leisure provides opportunity for renewal of spirit, mind, and body. It is a time for worship, for family, for service, for study, for wholesome recreation. It brings harmony into our life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p24" pid="OfX-kCN_PkO_mEgfeaV60w" hash="fRDOfg">Leisure is not idleness. The Lord condemns idleness. He said, “Thou shalt not idle away thy time, neither shalt thou bury thy talent” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/60.13" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 60:13</a>.) Idleness in any form produces boredom, conflict, and unhappiness. It creates a vacancy of worth, a seedbed for mischief and evil. It is the enemy of progress and salvation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p25" pid="dPlRCz2XakmQ94wW_fh15g" hash="HqFCAg">Work is an essential element in the Lord’s welfare plan; but it is a special kind of work. Work of the members, sanctified by love, produces the commodities which solve the temporal needs of our worthy poor. The laborer is blessed and sanctified in his unselfish service. The needy member accepts assistance in the spirit of love and gratitude. He knows it was provided by the toil and sacrifice of the Church members. To the extent of his ability, the needy member works for what he receives, as assigned by the bishop, thereby preserving his dignity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p26" pid="3RVDybsqEEitbLHcJaO9SQ" hash="H33xTA">The individual is all-important in the Lord’s plan. Any system which does not require initiative, self-reliance, and the necessity of work for what we receive, if able, will not preserve its integrity. The design of the welfare plan of the Church is to abolish the dole. The dole is a blight in any welfare system and should be feared as cancer in the human body.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p27" pid="Be0tLvLZXUySXpR70tM5yg" hash="5wvH_Q">Brigham Young declared, “It is never any benefit to give out … to man or woman, money, food, clothing, or anything else, if they are able-bodied, and can work and earn what they need.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p28" pid="NItQb-ZGqUyuJRD3J-5yUQ" hash="vpJ3wA">“To give to the idler is as wicked as anything else. Never give anything to the idler.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p29" pid="fSTDmtxxvEmtroyRL-RoVg" hash="e_hcsA">“Set the poor to work.” (<span class="emphasis">Discourses of Brigham Young,</span> sel. John A. Widtsoe, Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1954, pp. 274–75.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p30" pid="PdV0wH0XmUCwXvjXp0U77Q" hash="gmvfmA">President Clark added, “Brethren, … do your best to see that those … who consume, shall be among those who produce. It is a principle … that destroys character [and] initiative, to get into the frame of mind where our sustenance comes as a gift.” (Transcript of talk given in welfare meeting, Apr. 1960, p. 3.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p31" pid="gimTvJNKWEW7hFFmlNhKUg" hash="RIOdzw">In the broader sense, work is the means to achieve happiness, prosperity, and salvation. When work and duty and joy are comingled, then man is at his best. Tagore wrote,</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.f3">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="Xa5wghbCbk216nD4qUVWHg" hash="FLw0uw">
            <span class="emphasis">I slept and dreamt</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="X6Nbx3JmckCOIAE1bUsJWA" hash="mBjEag">
            <span class="emphasis">That life was joy</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="VMWfqm8XvEakgmNHZRuveg" hash="zK_zMA">
            <span class="emphasis">I woke and saw</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="kfMvsBcKG0ixCLH1IZLudw" hash="iDCkyA">
            <span class="emphasis">That life was duty</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="uLbQMHlC30ms_LljzjHUyw" hash="io_p0g">
            <span class="emphasis">I acted, And behold!</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="azZFNsTDa0-1uwGRVI2YpQ" hash="nTS4aQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Duty was joy!</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p32" pid="_AhF2n3uBEqXdocTTrsb4g" hash="cJK2ew">Work was instituted from the beginning as the means by which the children of God were to fulfill their earthly stewardship. Work is our divine heritage. Elder Stephen L Richards taught: “Work with faith is a cardinal point of our theological doctrine and our future state—our heaven, is envisioned in terms of eternal progression through constant labor.” (In Conference Report, Oct. 1939, pp. 65, 68.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p33" pid="H-v_zgootkGjrEPF_otyYw" hash="MYVyAQ">The voice of the Lord to this generation is:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p34" pid="cV7ANJSq6kGLnhMDN-a4xA" hash="w7ZmUg">“Behold, I say unto you that it is my will that you should go forth and not tarry, neither be idle but labor with your might. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p35" pid="tPRKVGzXgkmMDKKhkZhJzA" hash="g0y8sw">“And thus, if ye are faithful ye shall be laden with many sheaves, and crowned with honor, and glory, and immortality, and eternal life.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/75.3,5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 75:3, 5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work.p36" pid="dNFqzmhGRki-DRdbp2Pgkg" hash="ebH5SA">To this I testify, in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1982/04/the-value-of-work</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1982-general-conference/1982-04-6010-bishop-j-richard-clarke-64k-eng.mp3" length="7399142" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1982 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“My Soul Delighteth in the Scriptures”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures?lang=eng</link>
      <description>One of the most beautiful and inspiring passages in the Book of Mormon is often referred to as “The Psalm of Nephi.” It begins with these stirring words: “My soul delighteth in the scriptures, and my heart pondereth them, and writeth them for the lea</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03154_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="n9zedQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="jQr4Wl9_w02ZeO_mO4vM-g" hash="Duyxyg">“My Soul Delighteth in the Scriptures”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="zs4fK__SP0KXFir4_shMpQ" hash="72aVTw">J. Richard Clarke</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a6e.jpg" alt="Bishop J. Richard Clarke" pid="DX4A34y6jUqUs7Iy39rGzg" hash="S4JOpA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p1" pid="EhQtHXBkp0W86oRzMIjvNw" hash="T2LEfw">One of the most beautiful and inspiring passages in the Book of Mormon is often referred to as “The Psalm of Nephi.” It begins with these stirring words: “My soul delighteth in the scriptures, and my heart pondereth them, and writeth them for the learning and the profit of my children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p2" pid="wmbr6p8l_0CqrIwAcuxeZg" hash="m4FGoQ">“Behold, my soul delighteth in the things of the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/4.15-16" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 4:15–16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p3" pid="BU_wiyRDXUy7e5wwkZlxUA" hash="CazG4A">These words have special meaning to me. I grew up in a small Mormon community. I was raised in a fine Latter-day Saint home. I was taught to love the Lord, to reverence His name, and to communicate with Him in prayer. I was very young when I learned that the Father and the Son had appeared to Joseph Smith. I believed as a boy and I have never doubted as a man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p4" pid="RNm-M6GgnEyz7aSatcLm6w" hash="4KlzGg">However, until I enlisted in the navy, I had not experienced the shock of meeting so many people who had never seen a Mormon or who had never heard of Mormonism. I soon realized how limited was my knowledge of the gospel. I was asked some pretty tough questions about the Church that I had difficulty answering. I was the only Mormon in our outfit and so there was no one with whom I could counsel. The only scripture I had was a small military copy of the Book of Mormon. I am ashamed to confess that I left Lehi and his family somewhere in the wilderness on a number of occasions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p5" pid="pKpzEEFH70OweAURnH1Whg" hash="6OTUKQ">While I had grown up as an active member of the Church, I had felt no special need or urgency to study the scriptures and the writings of the prophets. When asked a question or when strong ridicule was directed at me and the Church, I could only state the personal beliefs I had learned from my family and teachers. I tried to compensate for my knowledge deficiency by being a good example of the principles I professed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p6" pid="lQsqMsb09UKnMzjsqan1NQ" hash="8NMo8Q">After leaving the navy, I received a mission call. I still had not developed a real appetite for gospel knowledge. I had not equated understanding the holy scriptures with being a good Latter-day Saint. Following some brief training in the old mission home in Salt Lake, my companions and I were exposed to a few weeks of tracting in Texas while waiting for the ship that would take us to South Africa. That exposure expanded my vision of what I was going to be doing for the next two years. I gained a lot of humility in a hurry.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p7" pid="13XUWvDFhUKi0Tqlts2tUw" hash="9dM58w">An unusual quirk of fate changed my whole life as we sailed toward Cape Town. It was to be a twenty-eight-day voyage, but our ship developed boiler problems crossing the equator. Limping into the port of Recife, Brazil, we hit the rocks, gashing the ship’s hull. A tugboat rescued us; but before we finally arrived in Cape Town, we had spent eighty-four days on board ship. I was fortunate enough to share quarters with a fine companion, Roy Stevens, who was a dedicated student of the gospel. His father had also been a missionary and had sent a large box of Church books with his son. It was during this confinement that a whole new world of gospel knowledge opened up to me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p8" pid="xJMCt5xsO0SQ6e5Da1uTFw" hash="aqglGA">It was a time to study, to ponder, to pray. I read all the standard works from cover to cover, as well as <span class="emphasis">Jesus the Christ</span> and several other Church books. On this voyage I received my witness from the Lord that the Book of Mormon is the word of God. It was here that I came to know that Jesus is the Christ. It was here I developed an insatiable appetite to know the eternal truths. What a pity I had waited so long. I had wasted so much time during military service. What a priceless treasure I had ignored! I am persuaded that we will be held accountable for how we use our discretionary time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p9" pid="Kmc5SlpMbkW6d73iLsf_Ig" hash="wehQUA">There is so much we can learn from the example of the young Prophet Joseph Smith, whose persistent, prayerful study of the Holy Bible compelled him to seek the God of Heaven for divine guidance. This brought him to the threshold of the greatest revelation ever given to man since the mortal ministry of the Savior Himself. Throughout the Prophet’s life, he continued to probe and ponder until he gained a mastery of the scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p10" pid="zQK3_56U60GBQe6byUDd8g" hash="G6Xu0A">Another young man, Spencer W. Kimball, was about fourteen when Susa Gates spoke at their stake conference. He recalls: “She gave a rousing talk on the reading of the scriptures; … then she stopped … to ask … us, ‘How many of you have read the Bible through?’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p11" pid="OYZ9NYAxGkisx4UojL5WvQ" hash="ygfU2w">“… My accusing heart said to me, ‘You, Spencer Kimball, you have never read that holy book. Why?’ I looked around me … to see if I was alone in my failure to read the sacred book. Of the thousand people, there were perhaps a half dozen who proudly raised their hands. … When the meeting closed, I … rushed home … gritting my teeth and saying to myself, ‘I will. I will.’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p12" pid="eemnZilMzk-YzsENGusoyg" hash="kINPCA">He went home, got a coal-oil lamp, and climbed the stairs to his attic room. “There,” he said, “I opened my Bible and began [with] Genesis … and I read well into the night with Adam and Eve … and through the flood even to Abraham.” (<span class="emphasis">President Kimball Speaks Out,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1981, pp. 92–93.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p13" pid="D6lV2eUj3keHecm5aIU5wA" hash="FPXMJQ">He continued to read a little each night. Although he didn’t always understand what he was reading, he had made a commitment to himself. At the end of a year, he had finished. This achievement set a pattern for his life. The sermons and the writings of President Kimball convince us that he has labored long hours to gain his profound insights into the holy scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p14" pid="ArWOmFp6LESBhqrcTF8Jow" hash="5flBvA">I am convinced that families, even young children, can learn to love the scriptures. A few years ago when I was in Colorado Springs for a conference, I called on Mark McConkie, son of Elder and Sister Bruce R. McConkie, to address the question: “How did you develop a love for the scriptures?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p15" pid="xE7su6f1GEmnEGQO7RQ9dw" hash="dwp7IA">As I recall, he said: “I first developed a love for the scriptures from my mother. I remember she would teach me while she did her ironing. I felt how she loved the scriptures by the way she would speak about the prophets. How much she loved them! As I grew older, I would listen to the recordings of the scriptures. I wanted to know the scriptures like my father. Sometimes he would enter the room while I was listening and it would take him just a moment to identify the exact scripture I was listening to. I wanted to be able to do that.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p16" pid="orKVlQ-ixUa5zhkM_1kIwg" hash="0bjv3w">You may remember the sweet experience shared by President Romney, who had been reading the Book of Mormon with his son. He related: “I remember reading it with one of my lads when he was very young. … We were each reading aloud alternate paragraphs of those last three marvelous chapters of Second Nephi. I heard his voice breaking and thought he had a cold, but we went on to the end of the three chapters. As we finished he said to me, ‘Daddy, do you ever cry when you read the Book of Mormon?’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p17" pid="83Lz-ldkkU-ePAZOOg3dLw" hash="yD28TQ">“‘Yes, son,’ I answered. ‘Sometimes the spirit of the Lord so witnesses to my soul that the Book of Mormon is true that I do cry.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p18" pid="SyLxuAiYm0G5P20y3bPR5Q" hash="yI6LJQ">“‘Well,’ he said, ‘that is what happened to me tonight.’” (In Conference Report, Apr. 1949, p. 41.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p19" pid="XEJYd120oEunNC0lCcRp1g" hash="lN_KEA">Some time later, I was reading a Jack London book with our youngest son Brandon, before going to bed. I recalled President Romney’s story and thought, What an experience we’re missing by not reading the standard works together. Before he leaves on his mission, I want him to become intimately acquainted with the great heroes of sacred literature and to pattern his life after them. We began to read just fifteen minutes or one chapter each day. What a choice experience! I commend it to you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p20" pid="GcZyVxxeLUKz7bp-dqlihw" hash="dJZBdA">All of our sacred records have come to us at high cost. When we consider the fiery furnace of conquest and persecution through which the Bible has passed, the great wonder is not whether it is complete or translated correctly, but a miracle that it has survived at all! Surely the Lord has preserved it for the salvation of his children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p21" pid="enDY7Dd0WUa5NTbkNVorUQ" hash="3hiabA">Laban’s life was taken by divine command that the Nephite nation not “dwindle … in unbelief.” (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/4.13" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 4:13</a>.) Think of the travail of the Nephite prophets who kept the records of their people so future generations might profit from their experiences. Think of the millions of people who have lived at a time when there was no printing or translating capability or who, because of political oppression or illiteracy, have been denied access to the scriptures. Think about the blessings of living in this dispensation, when the holy scriptures are available to us. In 1981, the United Bible Societies distributed 444,000,000 complete copies or portions of the Bible throughout the world. By the end of 1982, the Book of Mormon or selected portions will be available in fifty-seven languages.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p22" pid="YQx8DxTSQEeGBf7peHG4yA" hash="UcmJXg">We are the beneficiaries of great sacrifice. What excuse do we have for not taking advantage of this? Brothers and sisters, you don’t have to be a natural student to read the scriptures; you just need to love the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p23" pid="0bwhRZa9S0inb75pnzwbwQ" hash="38iT2Q">The value of sacred records was indelibly taught by the Savior as he ministered among the Nephites. He declared: “A commandment I give unto you that ye search these things diligently; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p24" pid="kr5dSvFYzUeRXxTfuj6zqA" hash="qiBMvQ">“Give heed to my words; write the things which I have told you; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p25" pid="9YRJIml4Gk2cwrMt_zECOQ" hash="zQsqsg">“Search the prophets, for many there be that testify of these things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p26" pid="og1moz6SL0icpHhMIClinQ" hash="n6CWLQ">“And now … after [Jesus] had expounded all the scriptures unto them which they had received, he said unto them: Behold, other scriptures I would that ye should write, that ye have not. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p27" pid="sx9NJLVHN0KLfbDkB4UekA" hash="xATEuA">“How be it that ye have not written this thing, that many saints did arise and appear unto many and did minister unto them?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p28" pid="Vd6X5KdyBEKfvx-m1_bmuw" hash="PDvQKQ">“And … Nephi remembered that this thing had not been written.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p29" pid="eECuPR6uZkmhW-dMVIsAiw" hash="-2sCDg">“And … Jesus commanded that it should be written; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p30" pid="lCe7Myda5UaDTomN_xqlWA" hash="84jz0Q">“Now … when Jesus had expounded all the scriptures in one, which they had written, he commanded them that they should teach the things which he had expounded unto them.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/23.1,4-6,11-14" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 23:1, 4–6, 11–14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p31" pid="fKcnSauoVkW_W4DgjmaRsw" hash="itK2IQ">I concur with the strong counsel of President Romney, given to a group of seminary and institute coordinators in 1973. He told them, and I quote: “I don’t know much about the gospel other than what I’ve learned from the standard works. When I drink from a spring I like to get the water where it comes out of the ground, not down the stream after the cattle have waded in it. … I appreciate other people’s interpretation, but when it comes to the gospel we ought to be acquainted with what the Lord says. … You ought to read the Book of Mormon and the Doctrine and Covenants; and … all the scriptures with the idea of finding out what’s in them and what the meaning is and not to prove some idea of your own. Just read them and plead with the Lord to let you understand what he had in mind when he wrote them.” (Address delivered at Coordinators’ Convention, Seminaries and Institutes of Religion, 13 Apr. 1973.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p32" pid="yYv4RS9sZEKhZvQ4fcgN1w" hash="H-otVg">I fear there are far too many Latter-day Saints who do not have a testimony of the gospel from their own diligent efforts. Is it possible that you are living on the reflected light of others who have prayed and pondered the revelations of God? A testimony comes from personal endeavor. The Lord has provided us the means of salvation, but our success is dependent upon individual effort.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p33" pid="m-IQos-YP0-iODdq_7yOWg" hash="5I6nAQ">I conclude with this admonition of the Prophet Joseph Smith, given in 1832:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p34" pid="QYRnpqVdQE2FFQG2j35_LA" hash="iT5iCQ">“Search the scriptures—search the revelations which we publish and ask your Heavenly Father, in the name of His Son Jesus Christ, to manifest the truth unto you, and if you do it with an eye single to His glory nothing doubting, He will answer you by the power of His Holy Spirit. You will then know for yourselves and not for another. You will not then be dependent on man for the knowledge of God; nor will there be any room for speculation. … For when men receive their instruction from Him that made them, they know how He will save them. … Again we say: Search the Scriptures, search the Prophets and learn what portion of them belongs to you.” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith,</span> comp. Joseph Fielding Smith, Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1938, pp. 11–12.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p35" pid="cx4SYE_nrEur1dY2dQn74w" hash="lz3Whg">To this I add my witness. The holy scriptures are the word of God. If we are to know God, we must read His words, for therein He stands revealed to the honest in heart. I so testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2c86.jpg" alt="Members of the Quorum of the Twelve, ca. 1870" pid="KMMLsHivBUeYLLJSSflbmA" hash="s2_kpA" />
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1982/10/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1982-general-conference/1982-10-1040-bishop-j-richard-clarke-64k-eng.mp3" length="6022408" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 1982 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Practice of Truth</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In the book of John, we read the famous dialogue between Pontius Pilate and Jesus of Nazareth. The Savior was an enigma to the Roman. He asked, “Art thou a king …” Jesus answered, “To this end was I born, and for this cause came I into the world, tha</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03174_000_028" doc-version="2" hash="BGEvQA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Ybh98ESoGEGTJ94Ua4Sx7w" hash="wOdLeA">The Practice of Truth</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Z4CDUBQvzUG6M5r5-o1jzA" hash="72aVTw">J. Richard Clarke</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a6e.jpg" alt="Bishop J. Richard Clarke" pid="XdcsIrid4Umyf1UGz8_uUQ" hash="S4JOpA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p1" pid="iwW8FSuq3E24H6uIFnsgKw" hash="KDrMGQ">In the book of John, we read the famous dialogue between Pontius Pilate and Jesus of Nazareth. The Savior was an enigma to the Roman. He asked, “Art thou a king …” Jesus answered, “To this end was I born, and for this cause came I into the world, that I should bear witness unto the truth.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/18.37" class="scriptureRef">John 18:37</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p2" pid="HqCJNVKEZk-w6nnu1ijrvg" hash="SCw--g">Pilate turned away, asking the question of the ages, “What is truth?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/18.38" class="scriptureRef">John 18:38</a>.) He did not wait for an answer. I doubt he expected one. Pilate was aware that “truth” had been a favorite subject for debate by Roman and Greek philosophers for centuries, and remained the quest of philosophy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p3" pid="YwDhnUucTkOo943a9-iOsA" hash="wqH4Kg">It is not my purpose today to discuss truth in the abstract. I would speak of the practice of truth. It is both principle and application.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p4" pid="w6bDwVSz0ECNDnzo3T2k2Q" hash="kU7bFA">As William George Jordan taught:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p5" pid="JZYxMg7laUu1cfBEECiy3w" hash="f1evCQ">“Truth … as loyalty to the right as we see it; it is courageous living of our lives in harmony with our ideals; it is always—power.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p6" pid="XmZ_Qzsv50yegNype-v0lw" hash="EwLqGQ">“Truth … defies full definition. Like electricity it can only be explained by noting its manifestation. It is the compass of the soul, the guardian of conscience, the final touchstone of right. Truth is the revelation of the ideal; but it is also an inspiration to realize that ideal, a constant impulse to live it.” (<span class="emphasis">Power of Truth,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1935, p. 3.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p7" pid="oUibiRh-AESyjjbF0mMg9A" hash="uskaCg">As Latter-day Saints, we are committed to the principles of truth. We seek the truth; we believe the truth; and we know the “truth will make us free.” (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.32" class="scriptureRef">John 8:32</a>.) To be genuine disciples, we must have harmony between the principles that we profess and the truths we practice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p8" pid="oX6kI6dMmU2j1ixVMV9EPw" hash="b1_scw">We must be like the people of Ammon, who were “distinguished for their zeal towards God, and also towards men; for they were perfectly honest and upright in all things; and they were firm in the faith of Christ, even unto the end.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/27.27" class="scriptureRef">Alma 27:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p9" pid="dpkooszElUusEyPyKuxKeg" hash="SGrMdA">Our souls must be more than “whited sepulchres,” which appear praiseworthy but inside are hollow chambers bereft of goodness. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/23.27" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 23:27</a>.) We must not only <span class="emphasis">seem</span> but also <span class="emphasis">be</span> what God would expect of His sons and daughters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p10" pid="tGp9__J0Mkmy_9A9fdzS2Q" hash="W3y1Eg">The practice of truth, the acid test of our commitment, is known by many terms—for example, <span class="emphasis">honesty, integrity, uprightness,</span> and <span class="emphasis">probity.</span> I especially like <span class="emphasis">probity.</span> It is taken from the Latin <span class="emphasis">probus,</span> meaning good, and <span class="emphasis">probare</span>—to prove, signifying tried and confirmed integrity. A person who has mastered probity by discipline, until it has become part of his very nature, is like a moral compass which automatically points “true north” under all circumstances. This individual strives for instinctive honesty, acting on impulse toward the right, without having to weigh the merits of advantage or disadvantage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p11" pid="2VP0L8_oNECUcAV7gb7WVw" hash="4MpbKg">“[One] who makes Truth his watchword,” wrote Jordan, “is careful in his words, he seeks to be accurate, neither understating nor over-coloring. … What he says has the ring of sincerity, the hallmark of pure gold. … His promise counts for something, you accept it as being as good as his bond, you know that no matter how much it may cost him to verify and fulfil his word by his deed, he will do it.” (<span class="emphasis">Power of Truth,</span> p. 5.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p12" pid="muEOY6BhUEWeCF5uxEpWtA" hash="4jXeNg">Perhaps you remember the story told by President N. Eldon Tanner. A young fellow came to him and said, “I made an agreement with a man that requires me to make certain payments each year. I am in arrears, and I can’t make those payments, for if I do, it is going to cause me to lose my home. What shall I do?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p13" pid="_3TvS9W_m02oEQLGsChV0w" hash="Mik8gg">President Tanner looked at him and said, “Keep your agreement.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p14" pid="iWwfTBLChUW03Od-fQ6E0w" hash="PnjHWw">“Even if it costs me my home?” the man asked.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p15" pid="b_2d7u5UoUu4qYEjJGobhg" hash="fyHFgw">President Tanner replied, “I am not talking about your home. I am talking about your agreement; and I think your wife would rather have a husband who would keep his word, meet his obligations, keep his pledges or his covenants, and have to rent a home, than to have a home with a husband who will not keep his covenants and his pledges.” (In Conference Report, Oct. 1966, p. 99.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p16" pid="-jSRQKShFEyqQEvRAViP6w" hash="D25NuQ">I had an interesting experience a few years ago while attending general conference. I went to purchase some merchandise at ZCMI and to cash a check. Being from out of state, I was sent to the cashier. She asked for some identification. I reached into my wallet and took out some credit cards. Inadvertently, my temple recommend came out. The cashier said, “I’ll accept that.” I said, “You’ll accept what?” She said, “Your temple recommend. It’s current, isn’t it?” I said, “Yes, it’s current.” She said, “That will do.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p17" pid="Oqo3D3jx8EWYsiMurdK_7g" hash="BxOAVA">Well, I pondered that all the way home. I thought, Wouldn’t it be a great idea if we had a Mormon credit card? A card-carrying Mormon could be depended on to keep his word, to be honest with his employers, and to pay his bills as agreed. Then our professionals, tradesmen, and business people would perform without compromising their ethics for profit, each putting his signature on his work with pride; all of us striving for excellence in every way. Wouldn’t it be wonderful to be a “peculiar” people known for our honesty and the quality of our services? The Mormon standard of integrity should be the highest standard in all the world, for we are the covenant people of God. The Lord makes no special concessions for culture, race, or nationality; He expects all His Saints to live according to gospel standards.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p18" pid="zxvXIX8TVUawBq_JSjusDg" hash="H7ATRQ">I believe for every law of truth we keep, there is a compounding effect. Our character is a complex of coordinated support systems, just like a well-engineered bridge. Each truss, column, or girder contributes to the strength or weakness of the whole structure.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p19" pid="UO8Z5yH1okqlEcNdJgfchA" hash="GIn7ag">The individual of probity has integrated his virtues into a pattern of consonance, whereas one who practices selective honesty, to fit time and circumstance, is never quite balanced.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p20" pid="OnQ34LrXtkK19xYXAJmGPQ" hash="w5s8UQ">General David Shoup, former Commandant of the United States Marine Corps, felt very strongly about consistency in practicing moral values. Commenting upon marines who were untrue to their wives, he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p21" pid="i1ByezC-eECzTpET2wzoyQ" hash="wr8WCA">“It is not the actual act of adultery that is of so great a concern to me; that’s merely the by-product, so to speak. The vital thing is this: A man who can somehow rationalize breaking the oath he gave before God and man when he repeated the marriage vows, is also a man who could, if he so desired, or when subjected to sufficient pressure, rationalize breaking the oath he took when he became a Commissioned Officer in the United States Marine Corps. A man who can betray his wife and children for lustful purposes is a man who could betray his country for his own ends.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p22" pid="buDq0hi8RUyHJmKXW0CLRg" hash="y-UxSw">Brothers and sisters, we often perform below our ideals, but our aim must exceed our grasp if we would rise to a higher standard of integrity. We all have old habits to break and new ones to form. Surely it takes a long time to perfect character, and we probably won’t achieve it totally in this life. But success must be measured by effort and small improvements until we eventually reach our goals. Norman Cousins described integrity as “no luxury for the pious: it is the bread of life for the truly human … for the man who seeks not length of days, but quality of spirit.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p23" pid="_6f2RciH8kub0t0IRqdsTQ" hash="e4GPWw">The love for truth and the practice of truth are best learned in the home. The Lord has laid the responsibility with parents to “teach their children to … walk uprightly before the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:28</a>.) And again, “I have commanded you to bring up your children in light and truth” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.40" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:40</a>), for “light and truth forsake that evil one.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.37" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:37</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p24" pid="MI70S3x5J06jJbr_lValyA" hash="lnjr1Q">Children gain a love for truth by watching parents practice truth; they learn to emulate noble character. They need models of consistency, not just sermons alone. I believe one of the most important lessons a parent can teach a child is that integrity and honor are not practiced without price. They usually require sacrifice, almost always inconvenience, and often embarrassment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p25" pid="woyfe07QuEiNlj0Ji7cw-Q" hash="8g6K8Q">With the permission of President Jeffrey Holland and his lovely daughter, Mary, I’d like to share their story of several years ago. It is an example of what I have tried to say today—not truth in theory, but truth in action.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p26" pid="08POKGFH0UaGEgGh_xctcg" hash="KxBFag">Brother Holland begins:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p27" pid="6BDSGo_yu0yqD41N69CPrQ" hash="DA00ow">“One night I came home quite late from work. My nine-year-old daughter Mary seemed visibly distressed. … I asked if she felt all right; she nodded that she did; but I guessed otherwise. I waited as she got ready for bed. Sure enough, she walked softly into the living room and said, ‘Daddy, I have to talk to you.’ I held her hand and, as we walked into her bedroom, she started to cry.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p28" pid="VYKmbhSlAEeLwmROZK5tHQ" hash="QxiCKA">“‘I was at Grand Central this morning and saw a ladies’ compact I knew Mother would love. I was sure it was quite expensive, but I picked it up just to admire it.’ More tears and struggle to get it all said: ‘It fell out of my hands onto the floor. I quickly picked it up, but Daddy, the mirror was cracked. I didn’t know what to do! I didn’t have enough money to pay for it, and I was all alone. … I put the compact back on the shelf and left the store. Oh, Daddy, I think I’ve been dishonest.’ And then she wept and wept.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p29" pid="pe-SJAiUPkeaGhp_KKKoBA" hash="QbwqQg">“I held her in my arms as that little nine-year-old body shook with the pain of sin being expelled. She said, ‘I can’t sleep and I can’t eat and I can’t say my prayers. What will I do? I won’t ever get it out of my mind.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p30" pid="uTxK-D0aT0GcwLXtebYzhA" hash="tzdi6g">“Well, Mother joined us and we talked quite a while that night. We told her that we were very, very proud of her honesty … and we would have been disappointed if she had been able to eat or sleep very well. I told her … the compact probably wouldn’t cost <span class="emphasis">too</span> much, and that we would go back to the store manager, tell him of the problem, and, between the two of us, cover the cost. If the compact was still there, [perhaps we could] buy it for Mom. That little cracked mirror could be a reminder for as long as she owned it that her little girl was unfailingly honest and spiritually sensitive. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p31" pid="PrRejwBQSUqzHGHwmLXGQw" hash="O8i5_w">“The tears gradually stopped, her little body began to relax, and Mary said, ‘I think now I can say my prayers.’” (“The Excellence of the Actors,” unpublished ms., BYU faculty assembly, 1978.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p32" pid="wxwxAIs180ecMgJiLZrJKw" hash="w-qRNw">We have tried to teach our children that the practice of truth is the premier virtue. If they master that great principle, all else will fall into place.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p33" pid="UzsTuNqtkUCcbeZ0zYoiwA" hash="ZIzjmA">As Jesus of Nazareth was the embodiment of truth, so should we bear witness. We may talk about our religion, we may discuss marvelous manifestations and revealed gifts and powers, we may profess high ideals and noble values; but the proof of our commitment lies in our performance in the daily transaction of our life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p34" pid="Mu3291DgfEGGVWO6DX6WjQ" hash="Q4r1Sg">Let us covenant as did Job, even in his extremity: “Till I die I will not remove mine integrity from me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p35" pid="cKFJKCTBnEqHNZP3-7uR5w" hash="A_BmTA">“My righteousness I hold fast, and will not let it go: my heart shall not reproach me so long as I live.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/job/27.5-6" class="scriptureRef">Job 27:5–6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p36" pid="SnsgZfRrHkq6DsAmjsT65g" hash="fA9V5w">The Psalmist posed the question: “Lord, who shall abide in thy tabernacle? who shall dwell in thy holy hill?” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/15.1" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 15:1</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p37" pid="3OiG63tLYkSXQoL2RmLFzA" hash="QHnJig">The answer: “He that walketh uprightly, and worketh righteousness, and speaketh the truth in his heart.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/15.2" class="scriptureRef">Ps 15:2</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth.p38" pid="Kf-MLYiyqUuC7-0UwfoM5Q" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1984/04/the-practice-of-truth</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1984-general-conference/1984-04-4050-bishop-j-richard-clarke-64k-eng.mp3" length="6303178" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 1984 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Hold Up Your Light”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Brothers and sisters, this has been a wonderful week. We have been so spiritually fed, and I pray now that I might be able to share something that will be appropriate.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03187_000_030" doc-version="2" hash="X4tQ-Q">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="rCOYzUsgdkKvtr9gIscdAA" hash="O_QXCg">“Hold Up Your Light”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="gFt4gRH84kivEmMjvACXgQ" hash="72aVTw">J. Richard Clarke</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-225e.jpg" alt="Elder J. Richard Clarke" pid="UksDqYucwUy5CztAed9zHA" hash="vwyPfA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p1" pid="neElrZ_uRE-UIhjS53c28Q" hash="RGddXg">Brothers and sisters, this has been a wonderful week. We have been so spiritually fed, and I pray now that I might be able to share something that will be appropriate.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p2" pid="X60eImW1J028XHpT25CdFw" hash="TjNYtw">Before doing so, I would like to express my love and appreciation to Bishop Brown and to Bishop Peterson for eight and a half wonderful years of association in the Presiding Bishopric. And to the Seventy and the Twelve and the First Presidency who have been so supportive and encouraging, I express my love and continued support for them. I also would like to acknowledge those wonderful brothers and sisters who work behind the scenes here at headquarters and throughout the world to provide so many services and resources to help move the work along.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p3" pid="laszjkum8kOLCg9egKYZMw" hash="SvTwhA">It’s marvelous to be in the service of the Lord and now to be called as a witness for our Lord and Savior and to return to a land that I love more than I can express. It’s just about as much emotion as I can handle at one time. So I pray that I might be able to fulfill the expectations of that wonderful call.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p4" pid="oBxrlI_KLEW7_CZbfSp1gw" hash="FkCMtg">In the Pearl of Great Price we read that the Lord delivered Abraham from idolatrous sacrifice. He introduced Himself as Jehovah and declared, “[Abraham], I will lead thee by my hand, and I will … put upon thee my name, even the Priesthood of thy father, and my power shall be over thee. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p5" pid="zOC4B8C9l0yPK6g2C6ez4A" hash="SBalbg">[And] through thy ministry my name shall be known in the earth forever, for I am thy God.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/1.18-19" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 1:18–19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p6" pid="PlhXE-l1gEq5F1MOTfPhWQ" hash="0PjMRA">This blessing was extended to Abraham’s posterity, who would “bear this ministry and Priesthood unto all nations.” (See <a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/2.9" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 2:9</a>.) The covenant children of Abraham were to be distinguished by their sacred obligation to declare to the world the true and living God. Not only were they to be believers and worshipers, but His witnesses, boldly testifying of Him among the unbelievers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p7" pid="L65vaQkYIkOhUzms9yKw2w" hash="DmZW7w">God has once again spoken from the heavens and restored the fulness of the gospel through His chosen prophet. We have become the covenant children of Abraham, a new generation of witnesses to bear testimony that God lives and Jesus is the Christ. We are to be a pure people, a holy people, fully committed and zealous in our proclamation of the gospel in word and deed. This is an awesome responsibility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p8" pid="to-OI3yRNUKLQZlAuaTNEw" hash="M1F9Ug">In the Book of Mormon we are told that “to be called His people” we must be willing “to stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things, and in all places, … even until death.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.8-9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:8–9</a>.) As individual members of the Church it is in the everyday context of our lives that this witness we exemplify comes under constant scrutiny.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p9" pid="23-XAJbMREOk6Pdt1empvQ" hash="9mj0eQ">May I share with you a personal experience to illustrate how humbling this can be? I was employed by a major corporation for almost twenty-five years. During those years I developed a personal friendship with a fine business associate from Texas. Our careers paralleled each other very closely. A few years ago, he presented me with a most unusual gift, which I shall always cherish. It was a large, molded bronze, personalized coat of arms. He said, “I have been observing you for many years and have created an original coat of arms using symbols which I believe represent the four most important values to which you have committed your life, namely, your church, your family, your profession, and your quest for personal development.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p10" pid="t_jS7RSj80eu46s1Yq_wfg" hash="_7Uq-A">Naturally, I was surprised, deeply impressed, and flattered. As the significance of this gift settled upon my mind, the thought of someone quietly taking mental notes of my actions, attitudes, and values fired my imagination. I realized the weighty responsibility each of us has to demonstrate accurately the principles and priorities to which we are committed. It was like a mini-foretaste of Judgment Day!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p11" pid="_NGTXesOaUaWsppDmgDDhw" hash="w84a-w">I thought of the scripture in Revelation in which John saw the books opened, “and the dead were judged out of those things which were written in the books, according to their works.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rev/20.12" class="scriptureRef">Rev. 20:12</a>.) It was a most sobering experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p12" pid="AL1i88nk4Ei-pY7HRkogIA" hash="vtlWug">All of us give our lives daily for what we believe is important. Those with whom we associate are silently assessing us, our values and character traits. Is there anything about our daily conduct we would change if we knew someone was doing a written appraisal for publication?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p13" pid="FG0mQtzHoEm9J_se9ebxjw" hash="pYlgeg">Suppose you received, as the head of a family, a telephone call from your stake president, who said, “The local newspaper is doing a series of articles on the Church. They have asked permission for a reporter to move into one of our homes for a week to observe firsthand what a Mormon family is really like. We have selected you to represent the Church in our stake.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p14" pid="nJYLeFzliUCE7toTctFqlw" hash="lmQ1mA">You say, “Yes, President, we will be happy to do it.” You have seven children ranging from age two months to a nineteen-year-old son awaiting his mission call. Little time is allowed for “sprucing” things up—just a typical week with life as you live it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p15" pid="uU-tZAeHrkCe6igf0kxfiA" hash="zgfqmQ">This actually happened to Max and Nettie Ann Nelson of Boise, Idaho, in 1983. How proud I was of this fine family as I read the reporter’s account. What a positive impression was made upon him. The question going through your mind is possibly the same one that I had: “If our family were selected, would we be ready?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p16" pid="xGp9TUbdsEKpjVoamvhgew" hash="M8GpWw">To the Nephites Jesus said, “Hold up your light that it may shine unto the world. Behold I am the light which ye shall hold up.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.24" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p17" pid="UQ7BUfuqbkCHpGrAOQG8Rw" hash="ouBnsg">In a related admonition, Peter counseled “that ye should shew forth the praises of him who hath called you out of darkness into his marvellous light. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p18" pid="7FNNJmWBDEKK0xgbbReloQ" hash="00PjtA">“Abstain from fleshly lusts, which war against the soul;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p19" pid="6V_Nn_urDEeLvrhu0l3LPQ" hash="I_lqeQ">“Having your conversation honest among the Gentiles: that … they may by your good works, which they shall behold, glorify God in the day of visitation.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-pet/2.9,11-12" class="scriptureRef">1 Pet. 2:9, 11–12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p20" pid="R8WjNnv4FkesstWBay0odQ" hash="jvBXwQ">To the Israelites and again to the Nephites the Lord commanded: “Thou shalt not bear false witness.” (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.16" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:16</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/13.23" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 13:23</a>.) Are we not false witnesses if we are untrue to gospel principles we profess but do not practice?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p21" pid="S603vOLVpEmUJ1fbewDr9Q" hash="Pu6aSg">Most damage to the collective reputation of the Church is done by those members who want to straddle the line, with one foot in the kingdom and the other foot in spiritual Babylon. Those who so compromise their principles want to play for both teams at once—the Lord’s and Satan’s—as if to say, “I want to wait and see which side is winning before I declare myself.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p22" pid="KSm4NLc3l0G9cCmBskNBFA" hash="7d0X-A">There are some members who are not concerned about their outward appearances and actions, rationalizing that they know what they really are on the inside. These individuals inevitably are judged “guilty by association.” To be judged fairly, we must avoid the very appearance of evil. We would do well to remember the words quoted by President McKay: “Whate’er thou art, act well thy part.” (See <span class="emphasis">Cherished Experiences,</span> comp. Claire Middlemiss, Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1955, pp. 174–75.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p23" pid="Gs6yMOZ5G0uo7Ip7FLS8Kw" hash="uL70kA">Character is revealed under pressure. Let me illustrate. A few years ago, Elder Gordon B. Hinckley related this inspiring story:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p24" pid="rOfHG1OukkKxZo7n9XkaJg" hash="aW6AMQ">“I talked with a young man recently returned from the war. He too had walked the jungle patrols, his heart pounding with fear. But reluctantly he admitted that the greatest fear he had was the fear of ridicule.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p25" pid="cXxTBJsoukykFtM-xeSpxg" hash="opTLug">“The men of his company laughed at him, taunted him, plastered him with a nickname that troubled him. They told him the things they reveled in. Then on one occasion when the going was rough, he faced them and quietly said, ‘Look, I know you think I’m a square. I don’t consider myself any better than any of the rest of you. … But I grew up in a different way. I grew up in a religious home and a religious town. I went to church on Sundays. We prayed together as a family. I was taught to stay away from these things. It’s just that I believe differently. With me it’s a matter of religion, and it’s kind of a way of respecting my mother and my dad. All of you together might force me toward a compromising situation, but that wouldn’t change me, and you wouldn’t feel right after you’d done it.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p26" pid="NxUrOX8ToUmi-LJmA2Dvwg" hash="WpW9Og">“One by one they turned silently away. But during the next few days each came to ask his pardon, and from his example others gained the strength and the will to change their own lives. He taught the gospel to two of them and brought them into the church.” (<span class="emphasis">Church News,</span> 29 Apr. 1972, p. 14.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p27" pid="VP05knlKj0OwCASa6HFjgg" hash="PBFCIQ">As Church members, we all benefit when one of us is honorable and righteous. Some years ago I made a speech at a business convention. When I concluded, a distinguished gentleman came up to me and asked, “Are you a Mormon?” I responded, “Yes.” He said, “I am associated with John Russon, a member of your church. He is the finest practicing Christian I have had the pleasure to know.” To him, and I’m sure to countless others, Brother Russon, now the president of the St. George Temple, is a reliable witness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p28" pid="kFHfpqdqXUO22d8JE9bVDw" hash="ldmU9A">One of our greatest needs is for true witnesses among our youth. Young people need models from their own generation. Thankfully we have a tremendous army of latter-day sons and daughters of Helaman, stripling “Saturday’s warriors,” who are not ashamed of the gospel of Jesus Christ. Rather, they have turned this commitment to the Lord into an advantage. Let me tell you of one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p29" pid="qXS8Ko3ajUa7YI5TW-pxHA" hash="H-gBgg">Steve Hawes is the student body president at New Canaan High School in Connecticut. Of its twenty-three hundred students, only twenty-four are Latter-day Saints. Steve ran unopposed in a landslide election. This is impressive. But even more impressive is Steve’s moral courage—his commitment to living the principles of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p30" pid="_daBbpN2skWcKQ_6nZV2tQ" hash="Jo2VZA">The Hawes family lived for a time in Tampa, Florida. Steve played junior high football and basketball. When his family was preparing to move to Connecticut, the coach told Steve’s father how much he appreciated and admired Steve, not just because he is a fine athlete, but because of his deep religious convictions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p31" pid="eDVWd0JjOUqgbr-xg9WV6w" hash="FMxZnA">“He doesn’t preach sermons; he just quietly lives his religion each day. I remember,” said the coach, “a group of us were in the squad room, and one of the boys pulled out a copy of <span class="emphasis">Playboy</span> magazine. They opened to the centerfold and began to make some vulgar comments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p32" pid="ExUepD_lb0m7zYNqRlZI2w" hash="3xd3hA">“I noticed Steve walk away, so I followed him and asked if anything was wrong. He said, ‘I’m okay, Coach, but that just isn’t my kind of thing.’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p33" pid="lP36vzwRMU2IBIJQAYQkRA" hash="MuOpEQ">The coach said, “Steve made us all better people. When he joined us, most of the guys were swearing. Then they stopped swearing around Steve, and after a while, they pretty well stopped swearing altogether.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p34" pid="RNYMtzEmg0aHr6QapyvuMA" hash="ONpPzQ">When I heard this tribute, I thought of Paul’s counsel to Timothy: “Be thou an example of the believers, in word, in conversation, in charity, in spirit, in faith, in purity.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-tim/4.12" class="scriptureRef">1 Tim. 4:12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p35" pid="4hvoPV7dtESn9YmwZ-Y4Wg" hash="Is4AkQ">“Ye are my witnesses,” said the Lord through Isaiah. (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/43.10" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 43:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light.p36" pid="qcQz4Txj40eYrrJ7ExVG-A" hash="Z-VX8Q">Let us stand tall, brothers and sisters, and be not ashamed to take upon us the name of Christ. May God bless us as a church and as individuals that the testimony we bear as His witnesses will be true and clear and fully reliable, I humbly pray in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1985/04/hold-up-your-light</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1985-general-conference/1985-04-5020-elder-j-richard-clarke-64k-eng.mp3" length="12297765" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 1985 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Kindred Family—Expression of Eternal Love</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My brothers and sisters, since last October it has been my blessing to be associated with the Family History Department of the Church. It enables each of us to experience the joy of the covenants and the ordinances of the temple as we make them avail</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03239_000_024" doc-version="2" hash="5NsRRw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="0szUl2nmH0qcJuyk35wv_g" hash="UTOnpA">Our Kindred Family—</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="ksP1YCrnP0O1LCpRTppcJA" hash="LBY_qA">Expression of Eternal Love</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="8frum-EblU2kxH9dgsP5ig" hash="72aVTw">J. Richard Clarke</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-225e.jpg" alt="Elder J. Richard Clarke" pid="zvggVeBJfEyr9iXEN9Wg-A" hash="vwyPfA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p1" pid="Ixqpip3lH0K0aU187Me4wA" hash="NyiU5g">My brothers and sisters, since last October it has been my blessing to be associated with the Family History Department of the Church. It enables each of us to experience the joy of the covenants and the ordinances of the temple as we make them available to our loved ones.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p2" pid="gjaTG2nXuEWZbyD_77phXg" hash="oiUuVA">Famous <span class="emphasis">Roots</span> author, Alex Haley, once said: “In all of us there is a hunger, marrow-deep, to know our heritage—to know who we are and where we have come from. Without this enriching knowledge, there is a hollow yearning. No matter what our attainments in life, there is still … an emptiness, and the most disquieting loneliness.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p3" pid="4q0ycIkURUG7SBWMLJkr6w" hash="X-vmqw">Through family history we discover the most beautiful tree in the forest of creation—our family tree. Its numerous roots reach back through history, and its branches extend throughout eternity. Family history is the expansive expression of eternal love. It is born of selflessness. It provides opportunity to secure the family unit forever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p4" pid="gl69yTLuOE6fpydGNIXGdw" hash="sezYeQ">Moroni told young Joseph Smith that Elijah the prophet would come and reveal anew the purposes, powers, and blessings of the holy priesthood which had been lost to the world. Through the keys he would restore, promises made earlier to the fathers would be planted in the hearts of their latter-day children. Our hearts would then turn to our fathers, and, through this impelling promise, the sacred relationships of mortality could be extended forever. Families of the earth could become families of heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p5" pid="YBTzouy2V02Lm5ykIlIJvw" hash="1qH7rw">Dr. Krister Stendahl, bishop of the Lutheran Church in Stockholm, expressed this profound sentiment about our temple in Sweden: “Isn’t it wonderful!” he said. “Only the Mormons are extending the blessings of the atonement of Jesus Christ to those beyond the grave.” He is right. The blessings of the Atonement do extend beyond the grave. Jesus suffered and died to preserve and unify our Father’s family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p6" pid="nMG6a6DrQka7NVFWtFD-DA" hash="Ne48Rg">In earliest biblical culture, the family was more than a parent and child unit. It included all who were related by blood and marriage. This kindred family, as I prefer to call it, was strongly linked by natural affection and the patriarchal priesthood. The elderly were venerated for their experience and wisdom. There were strength and safety in numbers, and, through love and support, members established solidarity and continuity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p7" pid="Lz-vAlQivk2couVYkBkkgA" hash="7-4tsA">Many social and economic conditions in today’s world militate against such a kindred family. Throughout the ages, evil forces have attacked the family. Why do you suppose Satan is so obsessed with its dissolution? Because it stands for everything he wants and cannot have. He cannot be a husband, a father, or a grandfather. He cannot have posterity now or ever. Satan cannot even keep those he has led away from God. He has no eternal kingdom or inheritance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p8" pid="Nbf3u--SzE-G1BY_EcnDIw" hash="hv6SzA">Nevertheless, the family is society’s strongest and most important institution. Where it has survived, it has done so as a matter of highest priority. Individual interests have been subordinated to the interests of the group. Sacrifice has exceeded selfishness. Loyalty, respect for the family name, pride in one another’s achievements, and shared quality time have been pre-eminent.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p9" pid="17IohlnzUUiXmh1EMxWJ0g" hash="7QVGyA">I had the good fortune of marrying into such a family. I have marveled as relatives have traveled great distances to support a family activity, a missionary farewell, or a wedding. An elderly aunt still invites cousins of four generations, who are attending Brigham Young University, into her home for family home evenings. Through this association, the cousins strengthen each other in keeping the covenants of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p10" pid="QJsQXm6d40ql0MwFnremBw" hash="PxrS7Q">If the kindred family system were working as it could, our hearts would encompass each family member in time of need. Shared resources would make the family self-reliant. Children would consider it a blessing, not a burden, to care for aged parents.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p11" pid="mzuOzVPfXk2o4Pd9kjxkrQ" hash="c2Kypw">I know of a widowed father who was reluctant to live with his daughter who resided in another state. She thanked him for the privilege of taking him into her home, insisting that she now would be able to demonstrate her love for all she had received from her parents. She felt selfish in finally having him to herself. Upon his death, she told me how blessed she was to have had those last precious years with her father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p12" pid="DOka2FFBOUSlfo1CiMJsVw" hash="3J3FZA">The priesthood is the vital power which solidifies the kindred family. One of the most sacred privileges of fatherhood is the blessing of one’s children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p13" pid="_8afZc6w6Eyu-iPW5fzBBQ" hash="XLbdmg">Many years ago, in this Tabernacle, I heard Elder Sterling Sill recognize the men who had performed the essential priesthood ordinances listed on his membership record. I suddenly realized that my father’s name did not appear on my record. He had not been active in the Church while I was growing up but had since become a faithful high priest.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p14" pid="6yXm74x7p0KS9tTdxjG0qQ" hash="2FILOg">Returning home from conference, I brooded about this, feeling deprived. I telephoned my father and said, “Dad, I’d like to ask you a favor. You can do something for me that no other living person can do. I would like a father’s blessing.” He hesitated and said, “Well, we’ll see, the next time you come to Rexburg.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p15" pid="Vkxdw8RpxEa8uIJM2YEVPA" hash="GCH02w">I persisted. To my knowledge, he had never given a father’s blessing before, and he was nervous. At the age of eighty-four, he placed his quivering hands upon my head. And this son will never forget the supreme joy of hearing a proud father pour out his heart in a blessing—a blessing which will be held sacred and cherished not because of its eloquence but because it came from my father. I hope, brethren, that you will not deny your children this choice experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p16" pid="TwIegJNyZUibCPtm64mb7A" hash="okGTPw">Now, I realize there are numerous single-parent families in the Church who do not have a priesthood bearer to preside in the home and bless them. They are reluctant to impose on others and are frequently offended by insensitive remarks regarding their family status. This is also true of single adults who have yet to marry. They often feel cut off from the mainstream of Mormon family life. They especially need to be part of a gospel kindred family, where blessings can be obtained from worthy priesthood bearers and role models can be found in quorum brotherhood and Relief Society sisterhood. Families in the ward can reach out and share loving concern. Within the Lord’s design, no one should be ignored. We are all members of the body of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p17" pid="ueCLmIr7qUWlPjtk60gtQw" hash="7RN4MQ">As we learn to be loving, caring families in mortality, our hearts will naturally turn to members of our kindred family in the spirit world. As they continue to live beyond the veil, they wait—they wait for us, their family, to share the blessings of the ordinances of the priesthood. They yearn to belong to the eternal family circle. They are anxious for us to make this possible. Are we not compelled to do so?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p18" pid="gDRsv8rE_kam1su5XrV-ww" hash="dpEqPQ">I was impressed by the testimony of a single adult in Washington, D.C., who, as a recent convert, found herself suddenly immersed in the pursuit of her family history. After her first sacred experience of participating in the temple ordinance work for several of her kindred family, she expressed her feelings with tears of joy. “Now,” she exclaimed, “I am no longer the only member of the Church in my family!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p19" pid="nn2dWwmxR0yryCEmXba8Bg" hash="ybxvyA">Our family research and temple ordinances make it possible for us to be forever families. The process of compiling family history records need not be expensive or complicated. We may not be able to do everything; but we can do something.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p20" pid="2qBZBuS97k-zVWgQC2uXnw" hash="Y4HLTQ">With her permission, I would like to share part of a sweet letter I received from Sister Linda Seamon of the Flagstaff Arizona Stake.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p21" pid="xUtZl846EkCzOYHziQpgow" hash="MmN5dQ">“We are a young family. My husband and I are 33. We have three small children. This is a busy ‘family time’ for us in our lives. For months, Diana, our ward genealogy person, would call us on a regular basis to ask if there was anything she could do to help us get started on our family history.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p22" pid="EXXoZyVT-UCOlD0-ZaEf9A" hash="aj8-cA">“We of course thanked her for the call, but firmly replied that ‘Aunt Leona, Cousin Nellie, and Aunt Bertha have done all there is to do on our families.’ Then, intrigued by an article in the <span class="emphasis">Ensign</span> about the new 8.5 x 11 forms for family history, I mentioned this to Diana and a week later she was at my door with the forms! I took a look and thought how neat it would be to fill in the forms with our own names in the blanks. This simple experience of a loving, persistent family history representative was what got us started.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p23" pid="FIoX0DhdxkmHory8Fe7bxg" hash="bTM3cQ">“We both come from Mormon families several generations back. We thought the ordinance work for our ancestors had been completed. We were wrong! In the short months we have been collecting copies of family group records, we have had so many experiences that confirmed to us the Lord’s hand in this work: 44 baptisms, 45 endowments, 29 children sealed to parents, 16 marriage sealings. All of these from records that were supposedly ‘all done.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p24" pid="YF91kr9wfEm1wTytVPAV7A" hash="Vqy3-Q">“Words cannot express the joy we have felt in the temple performing ordinances for our ancestors. Family relationships, some estranged since childhood, have been healed. Our extended families have also become involved. We have sent names to five different temples so that we could be united in helping to complete the temple work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p25" pid="jcwCSvVgqEqgdMs3KcGJlg" hash="olpLlQ">“We believe that it takes just one temple experience for one’s ancestors to convince a person of the importance of this work. It is possible to become involved in this exciting work at any age. We’re committed to it!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p26" pid="yRF903aU6EOTHF5Jh2zP8Q" hash="rc6-UA">The Prophet Joseph Smith gave us this sober warning: “The earth will be smitten with a curse unless there is a welding link … between the fathers and the children. … For we without them cannot be made perfect; neither can they without us be made perfect.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/128.18" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 128:18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p27" pid="gZzuQ58G30m6i_l0pvtrSg" hash="iBDILw">In the councils of heaven before the world began, we made a solemn agreement with the Lord to assist in bringing to pass the eternal life of man. Elder John A. Widtsoe reminds us that the least of us, the humblest, is in partnership with the Almighty in achieving the purpose of the eternal plan of salvation. It is man’s duty, his pleasure and joy, his labor and ultimately his glory. By that doctrine, with the Lord at the head, we become saviors on Mount Zion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love.p28" pid="4jeTEDqnYU2gBVTLgkM6cw" hash="GqAMaw">I bear witness that this work is true. I testify that we may anticipate a glorious reunion with our kindred family through the covenant blessings of the priesthood. I pray that we will heed the prophets and inherit the supreme joy which comes from performing this marvelous work of salvation, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1989/04/our-kindred-family-expression-of-eternal-love</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1989-general-conference/1989-04-4030-elder-j-richard-clarke-64k-eng.mp3" length="6174010" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 1989 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“To Honor the Priesthood”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood?lang=eng</link>
      <description>When Bob Barfuss was on his mission, his mother, Mary, prayed each day, reminding the Lord, in detail, of Bob’s needs. One day she concluded that maybe she shouldn’t take so much of the Lord’s time with her long list of concerns. She said, “I just co</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_91905_000_020" doc-version="2" hash="L3nY1w">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="HUl17Y3Cf0y2eZPEjivypw" hash="N_MrpA">“To Honor the Priesthood”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="g90P-XYqH0-NRoiiluCcAQ" hash="72aVTw">J. Richard Clarke</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-225e.jpg" alt="Elder J. Richard Clarke" pid="Wv_W3sBUT0KJocHqbWenpA" hash="vwyPfA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p1" pid="Fv7oVzNwfUaXhujW0xeKWQ" hash="8RPxkw">When Bob Barfuss was on his mission, his mother, Mary, prayed each day, reminding the Lord, in detail, of Bob’s needs. One day she concluded that maybe she shouldn’t take so much of the Lord’s time with her long list of concerns. She said, “I just condensed it to: Heavenly Father, please bless Bob to honor his priesthood.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p2" pid="MeLWqh2-90KhFsmkW5UTyA" hash="b2QWcw">Brethren, if that simple plea were fully realized in our lives, it would satisfy most needs and prevent most problems. “Bless me, Father, to honor the priesthood.” This should be our daily petition.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p3" pid="Gr3cmKvkiU2VA35cQ0YbiA" hash="vCG16A">At a recent stake priesthood meeting, a young man was sustained to receive the Melchizedek Priesthood. When congratulated, the boy’s response was surprising: “Why? That’s no big deal, is it?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p4" pid="dldPxdwnrU2EMHWKkq5Feg" hash="UUsQ_w">No big deal? If he only knew how big! I wondered how he reached such a conclusion. If I were his father, his bishop, his quorum adviser, how would I feel to hear that response?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p5" pid="bRyE8-a1yUWGpYoK9yLaIQ" hash="ir5czQ">We often say impulsive things as youth that we probably would not say with more maturity. I hope this young man is now serving a mission and getting a better idea of what it really means to bear the Melchizedek Priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p6" pid="yWINwOkqO02qRYoA9aZ5qQ" hash="20Bcew">President Benson has said, “The greatest power in this world is the power of the priesthood. … No greater honor or blessing can come to man than the authority to act in the name of God.” (<span class="emphasis">The Teachings of Ezra Taft Benson,</span> Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1988, p. 219.) What a privilege! What a trust!</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.f2">
	<p pid="1MuN46hzv0K6LS3tc5-0Ww" hash="6VdMxA">May I offer two suggestions to help us better honor the priesthood:</p>
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="1CpXXVFfBkil-ySUSQYWKQ" hash="45a8ag">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="_YJTXI1xz06i3SHof_qGiA" hash="Ew2cZg">Live righteously to merit the power of the priesthood.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Pg3JluNiqkiQexAMerq9BQ" hash="YFFOpg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="iVLhV1zufEiAhF6t2lHxMQ" hash="yd7_Cg">Aggressively search out opportunities for quorum service.</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p7" pid="sRTUIVw-9EuEl8t2L46fkw" hash="TTGnkQ">To have the priesthood conferred upon us does not automatically bless us with power any more than receiving a driver’s license makes us a responsible driver. The Lord declared, “The powers of heaven [can] be controlled … only upon … principles of righteousness.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:36</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p8" pid="hlYfH3fl8EOGX3qoPS8VhA" hash="tthDdw">The power of the priesthood comes gradually. Even our Savior had to master the flesh and grow “grace for grace” until He received a fulness. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.12-13" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:12–13</a>.) We may also, if we are true and faithful to our covenants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p9" pid="g0hWMkpjH0mo--IsHhy_lA" hash="DDa43Q">However, we may forfeit priesthood power when we commit transgression. Spiritual powers are sensitive and withdraw from evil influences. As Peter warned, we must escape “the corruption that is in the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-pet/1.4" class="scriptureRef">2 Pet. 1:4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p10" pid="W9mahnQclEqSFF6vliC26g" hash="8jBjtQ">I was proud of a young priest, Rick Dove of Tucker, Georgia, who reported his experience at a rock concert. He observed the drinking, dress, profanity, and general crudeness of the young people there. He said, “I suddenly remembered who I am and felt that I was out of place; so I left.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p11" pid="8OAl6_ICpE6DTfEa8v1FrQ" hash="RnMIsw">Sometimes we forget who we are. The other day, I stopped at a magazine shop to buy a newspaper. I was shocked to see a man whom I knew well, a high priest, viewing a magazine in the “adults only” section. He was unaware that I saw him. I was quite disappointed. The thought occurred to me: What if I had been his son, who looked to his dad as a hero?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p12" pid="AvkQwzqcB0GHvlmXwMHU0Q" hash="9X3etA">I remembered a conversation between a father and son in Arthur Miller’s play <span class="emphasis">All My Sons.</span> The son discovers that his father has compromised ethical principles in business. Knowing that losing his son’s esteem is one of the greatest losses he could have, the father says, in effect, “Son, I know; I’m sorry. But really, I’m no worse than anyone else.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p13" pid="59WWM2hFXEqt2xqHnP3j-A" hash="OLGlvQ">The son replies, “Dad, I know; but I thought you were better.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p14" pid="jC7cDi-Xc0C-FIrqdZlL2w" hash="nuwmfA">For those who bear the priesthood, young men or adults, there is only one standard of moral decency. Any film, television show, music, or printed material unfit for youth is also unfit for parents.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p15" pid="8JyeTlhLV0-jFAJgaqMmhw" hash="n_LHBg">Those who rationalize acceptance of immoral material on grounds of maturity or sophistication are deceived. Those who excuse transgression by saying “Well, I’m not perfect” may be reminded that conscious sin is a long way from perfection. We would do best to consider this counsel of President Brigham Young: “‘Be … as perfect as [you] can,’ for that is all we can do. … The sin … is [not doing] as well as [you know] how.” (In <span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses,</span> 2:129–30.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p16" pid="YNnWasjwAEO1gwq66EL3sw" hash="k3UxaA">The prophet Alma, who suffered “nigh unto death” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/27.28" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 27:28</a>) repenting of his rebellion and transgressions, pleads: “Come ye out from the wicked, and be ye separate, and touch not [the] unclean things.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.57" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:57</a>.) To us, who bear His holy vessels, the Lord commands, “Be ye clean.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:42</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p17" pid="kY0fnW4GpUG6UFZYZz4G-g" hash="7GvsJA">The priesthood quorum was designed by the Lord to be the finest service fraternity in all the world. If we had the wisdom and faith to utilize the quorum as the Lord envisions it, we would be magnified before Him, and every member of the Church would be blessed. Isn’t that a primary purpose of the priesthood—to bless, to encourage, to exalt? The quorum maximizes the good which comes from a synergy of brotherhood and service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p18" pid="PEc7o6f5F0mi9b5iA5wv7w" hash="asef9A">Let me share some examples of the priesthood in action.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p19" pid="kb-z-hm1ckucR_ZOIu_RRg" hash="2v6Icw">An inspiring funeral was held for eighteen-year-old John Anderson. John was a remarkable young man who courageously battled muscular dystrophy and lost. He was confined to a wheelchair during his Aaronic Priesthood years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p20" pid="uGRYhF4ksUCDDxtfzt5DMQ" hash="3kIQCA">Conspicuous at the funeral were devoted members of his priests quorum. John’s influence upon his quorum was profound, and yet he never played a football game, nor went camping with them, nor danced, nor did any of the usual teenage activities. It was his faith and commitment to the Church that touched his quorum members. And something else—John provided his quorum with an opportunity to serve with love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p21" pid="lztT98OIzk2MLxjKRbVocg" hash="uX8v8g">When John was a deacon, he wanted to pass the sacrament. One boy was assigned to push his wheelchair while John held the tray on his lap. It seemed awkward at first, but soon others were anxious to help him perform his priesthood duty.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p22" pid="O5RiA9bY7k2uroYLsAJmXg" hash="q0RSdA">By the time John was ordained a priest, he was very weak and could not kneel to bless the sacrament. His quorum found a solution. They placed his wheelchair next to the sacrament table. One would break the bread, then kneel for him, by the wheelchair, and hold a microphone while John pronounced those sacred words. To do this for their brother soon became an honor for each one in the quorum.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p23" pid="i3MAjB4KoECfjQGFLqW-wA" hash="6i8XXQ">They enthusiastically followed his leadership as first assistant in the priests quorum. Because John was unable to realize his dream of becoming an Eagle Scout, the priests raised money to buy a special achievement plaque which was given to him in sacrament meeting. It read: “Presented to John Anderson for outstanding service to your quorum and for being a great example to us all.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p24" pid="llkExrTbGkG5tWl1niQVKA" hash="di4jDA">Over the years, the young men in John’s quorum enjoyed many fun activities, but none had greater impact or taught them more about magnifying their priesthood callings and loving each other than this choice experience they shared with their friend John.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p25" pid="b571HNKoV0KI06i2JLomrg" hash="A7Clng">We expect a lot from our Aaronic Priesthood brethren, and, properly trained, they seldom disappoint us. I remember when Dr. Harold Hulme served as bishopric adviser to a deacons quorum. They were invited to tour a hospital. As he introduced his quorum to the nurses, one of them said, “How unusual. The deacons in our church are older men.” Dr. Hulme replied, “Well, our deacons are outstanding young men. They can handle it when they are twelve years old!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p26" pid="jnYlkPxI0EaIetvsBcS7Tw" hash="VZQsZQ">Remember a few years ago when devastating fires burned out of control in Southern California? As fierce winds blew, the public was restricted from the area by police. A few families were allowed to remain and try to save their homes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p27" pid="uQuAshI5hEi7ipp3LeAcRA" hash="9GMP6Q">Soon a van arrived at one house, filled with brethren from the quorum, carrying their shovels. They were asked: “How did you get past the police barricade?” Response: “It was easy. We just told them our brother lives here.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p28" pid="DAHzBdPXkE-aeFbl6Ey6Rw" hash="XoBL1Q">The count was soon up to thirty-nine brethren who were helping dig a trench for fire protection. A curious police officer appeared and said: “I just want to meet the man who has thirty-nine brothers!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p29" pid="uaw6OdH0FUux9yt2fKxNVg" hash="-N1erQ">Elder Matthew Cowley once asked an elders quorum president how his elders were getting along as a quorum. “Do you do anything to help one another?” “Oh, yes,” was the response. “We’ve got a member of our quorum in the hospital in New Mexico. He was a vigorous young man, buying a farm, a hard worker with a lovely family. All of a sudden he was stricken.” That could have meant the end of his farm and family security.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p30" pid="j0mJPbCyDk27rIDVN76_Ig" hash="5q6WUQ">The elders quorum president said, “That was our loss as much as for his wife and children. So we took over, and we’ve operated that farm. All he has to worry about is getting well.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p31" pid="fqoqYWXAvk6ctlEFnOm_Ig" hash="8-sTXQ">Many times we magnify our callings individually, quietly, without fanfare. I’m thinking of an elders quorum president, Kirk Barnett of Las Vegas. Visiting a hospital early one morning, he was impressed to ask if any other LDS were there. He was told of an elderly grandmother awaiting her first surgery for a brain hemorrhage. She had no family or friends present, no one to encourage her. She was terrified! President Barnett sat with her for two hours. His hand was white from her strong grip. She said she loved him at least twenty times.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p32" pid="mxf6-Q5q80u8FHRBQwolxA" hash="PQRWuw">Brethren, we are the sons of God. We have been commissioned of Jesus Christ to bear His holy priesthood and to build up His church. We must expand our awareness as quorums and as individuals, and increase our caring capacity. Let us live righteously and extend the healing power of the priesthood, through loving quorum service, to “succor the weak, lift up the hands which hang down, and strengthen the feeble knees.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/81.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 81:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood.p33" pid="5XXxsJqAyU2zX4pybYfjQg" hash="k1KVqQ">In his last tender letter to Moroni, Mormon concluded: “My son, be faithful in Christ.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/9.25" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 9:25</a>.) I believe that would be the loving counsel of every father or mother to a son: Be faithful in Christ. So may we be, and honor His priesthood. In the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1991/04/to-honor-the-priesthood</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1991-general-conference/1991-04-3020-elder-j-richard-clarke-64k-eng.mp3" length="5847055" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 1991 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lord of Life</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life?lang=eng</link>
      <description>First, may I thank my grandchildren who have been praying the last couple of weeks that their grandfather would have the Spirit of the Lord with him on this occasion.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_93905_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="twIt1A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="t0OQUmF1IECDTra897tpuA" hash="Q4SoPg">The Lord of Life</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="AEyhmsbPV06djT_f7qUdag" hash="72aVTw">J. Richard Clarke</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-225e.jpg" alt="Elder J. Richard Clarke" pid="dfl3kzB8d0moOWNVqWOuvg" hash="vwyPfA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p1" pid="gHMy5RBNDkW2UJ2HbOYF4g" hash="eCL9eA">First, may I thank my grandchildren who have been praying the last couple of weeks that their grandfather would have the Spirit of the Lord with him on this occasion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p2" pid="7P8KmH8g2UO3AdsqrOdvNQ" hash="wLzPVg">Springtime in Utah brings the anticipated renewal of life. Easter approaches, and once again we ponder the Resurrection and our Father’s plan of salvation. The miracles of nature and the gospel combine to remind us that the Lord of Life is a God of miracles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p3" pid="OJNaCut2h0--A6kcVC0iKg" hash="CGd_zg">For many, perhaps the most spectacular miracle would be the raising of someone from the dead. The scriptures describe the supreme joy of the widows of Zarephath and Nain whose dead sons were restored to life (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/1-kgs/17.17-24" class="scriptureRef">1 Kgs. 17:17–24</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/7.11-15" class="scriptureRef">Luke 7:11–15</a>.) The most dramatic episode tells how the Savior went to the sepulcher of His beloved friend Lazarus, who had lain dead for four days. Asking them to take away the stone, “he cried with a loud voice, Lazarus, come forth. And he that was dead came forth, bound hand and foot with graveclothes.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/11.43-44" class="scriptureRef">John 11:43–44</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p4" pid="wjXIh7YDck6OMu9UREJpVw" hash="J8I_sQ">The Prophet Joseph Smith shared a profound insight which I’ll rephrase in the form of a question: <span class="emphasis">Is it any more incredible that one could be raised from the dead than to be spiritually reborn?</span> (See <span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith,</span> p. 191.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p5" pid="lf1nfgi4zEerUZ4su09fag" hash="7X-IBw">John the Apostle taught that the highest manifestation of our Heavenly Father’s love was to send “his only begotten Son into the world, that we might live through him.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-jn/4.9" class="scriptureRef">1 Jn. 4:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p6" pid="P9K_8ACKr0yAtzosSNvWNw" hash="RlRyRg">Few understood this during His ministry. The intellectual Nicodemus was impressed with the miracles of Jesus; but even with extensive knowledge of the scriptures, he could not grasp the doctrine of spiritual rebirth, the transformation of the human soul, what it means to be born again. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.1-10" class="scriptureRef">John 3:1–10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p7" pid="aDQeFoRwJk6vfYMsCODOEg" hash="0gLzxw">Nature provides some striking parallels. The late film producer Cecil B. DeMille shared this experience:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p8" pid="vRfAei5QV0yyyjPSjPVAWg" hash="Wc0AYg">“One day as I was lying in a canoe, a big black beetle … climbed up to the canoe. I watched it idly for some time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p9" pid="hALyygYe5EyGRvaxCkowCQ" hash="TS6beg">“Under the heat of the sun, the beetle proceeded to die. Then a strange thing happened. His glistening black shell cracked all the way down the back. Out of it came a shapeless mass, quickly transformed into beautifully, brilliantly-colored life. … There gradually unfolded iridescent wings from which the sunlight flashed a thousand colors. … The blue-green body took shape.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p10" pid="LwpIRIqsUEywy2atAq8M6w" hash="k_J6jw">“Before my eyes had occurred a metamorphosis—the transformation of a hideous beetle into a gorgeous dragonfly. … I had witnessed … a miracle. Out of the mud had come a beautiful new life. And the thought came to me that if the Creator works such wonders with the lowliest of creatures, what may not be in store for the human spirit!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p11" pid="lzS0b26dVkmDK9ujC0SMYA" hash="GK9Cyw">My testimony today is that through Jesus Christ we can be born again. We can change. We can change completely. And we can stay changed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p12" pid="6SimYvWYD0eezx72Fy0_Pw" hash="XQ8WxA">Such complete changes require the power of God. He gives this promise to His covenant people:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p13" pid="_hlhIiUyeUKH_SuCg4KElQ" hash="ZetWsA">“A new heart also will I give you, and a new spirit will I put within you: … and cause you to walk in my statute.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ezek/36.26-27" class="scriptureRef">Ezek. 36:26–27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p14" pid="J-G7SrC8u0ST1HH9HQNa1w" hash="CSzJtw">The king of the Lamanites was stirred by the power of the Spirit when taught the gospel. He asked Aaron: “What shall I do that I may have this eternal life of which thou hast spoken? … that I may be born of God, having this wicked spirit rooted out of my breast, and receive his Spirit … ? … I will give up all that I possess … that I may receive this great joy.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/22.15" class="scriptureRef">Alma 22:15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p15" pid="CA8J3sABTkKpcbYtHEawww" hash="vbnvAw">Note Aaron’s prescription: “If thou desirest this thing, if thou wilt bow down before God, yea, if thou wilt repent of all thy sins … and call on his name in faith, believing that ye shall receive, then shalt thou receive the hope which thou desirest.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/22.16" class="scriptureRef">Alma 22:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p16" pid="ZMoB5cfjBEGF2srw4Pgi4w" hash="s639WA">Prostrating himself before the Lord, the king pled, “If thou art God, wilt thou make thyself known unto me, and I will give away all my sins to know thee.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/22.18" class="scriptureRef">Alma 22:18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p17" pid="EvMj482ypkGK1-oKxKfKEg" hash="du8bjw">From the pages of our missionary journal comes an event repeated often throughout the missions of the Church. John and Shirley Withers were successful advertising executives. They were on the fast track, indulging themselves in worldly pleasures. When contacted by our missionaries, they were impressed by their clean, sparkling countenances so unlike other young men they had known.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p18" pid="IawN0EVl3k20SyRB2LG-cg" hash="sxqIFA">As the Spirit touched their hearts, the conversion miracle began. Their previous behavior became incompatible with gospel principles. A new set of priorities and values replaced worldly interests. Alcohol and tobacco habits became expendable, although with great effort. Modesty became the dress standard. Prayer, scripture study, Relief Society and priesthood service became the focus. They were baptized and received the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p19" pid="SEHLuH1mY0O7obnSoIuIXQ" hash="f8Wv-A">As Sister Clarke and I, with some of our missionaries, assembled in the Salt Lake Temple, John and Shirley Withers, with their children, were sealed together as an eternal family. Their countenances reflected the resplendent beauty of the emancipation of the soul. We witnessed a spiritual rebirth as if from the grave.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p20" pid="FmgDiT_BMkOAhmd5SX2w9Q" hash="hzYVaw">I recently participated in a religious service in a state prison. As the inmates shared their testimonies, I was moved by their remorse for the behavior that necessitated their incarceration. But more impressive were their expressions of love for the Savior and hope for His mercy and forgiveness as they prayed that their repentance would be acceptable to Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p21" pid="9qyAkD5gQUSGFSGSWhEt4A" hash="o7wEiQ">May I share these words from one in that meeting. In reading the Book of Mormon, he has discovered the healing balm and the compassion of a loving Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p22" pid="Jiahw4wABECdH5aoDX5aAw" hash="bdpCzA">I quote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p23" pid="0cgfjDoh_Eq_7KMa0ZlZ2g" hash="-__HkQ">“Over the past month the Lord has given me so many blessings. He’s changed my heart. He’s taken away the anger, hatred, and fear. He’s replaced these with love and hope. He’s also taken away my foul mouth and my desire for tobacco. He’s helping me to overcome many fleshly weaknesses.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p24" pid="tbIUnThr_EubREgvHodIGQ" hash="9grpYg">“I always believed I had a relationship with the Lord. I see now how self-serving that relationship was. When I read about Korihor it really hit me hard. I used a lot of the same justifications and rationalizations to create a ‘malleable god’ that I could shape to meet my wicked needs.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p25" pid="vX6pmATlEkOsoleZqVNaMA" hash="LP753A">“I truly want to be baptized … a member of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. I believe it is His Church and know my lifelong search is over.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p26" pid="DgOXujlkWE2HNjc8KfoiNQ" hash="pF-b8A">Spiritual conversion is preceded by an intense desire for change and an admission that we need divine help. Only those who humbly open their hearts have the courage to admit error and place their trust in the Lord for forgiveness and redemption.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.f2">
	<p pid="gr1BnA1Gr0KAa6FlOfAMqw" hash="sqkSIA">I do not know how our Savior actually performs the sanctifying miracle of the Atonement, how He takes upon Himself our anguish of mind and body and assumes our pain and guilt; but I know He does. This leads me to these conclusions:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="bBc2TAGiXU6iZMrPy3LYgg" hash="dbtprw">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="VjHJsYQyVEeQtBg6-HV-aA" hash="m7oGGA">The incomprehensible severity of His suffering should convince us that we are loved and very important to our Heavenly Father. Otherwise, why would such suffering be permitted?</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="O5kQqVz9XUCs-tYjsd4eew" hash="v9qHnA">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="gg-3FdjZC0uVlekozUPB0A" hash="btA4yw">Our Savior’s sacrifice had to be a voluntary act of mercy, the shedding of innocent blood, the just for the unjust, the perfect for the imperfect.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="ODTLWV2aLU6UsSSP1a4YsQ" hash="lIV_5Q">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="S97-1hM5IU-c4kM4-7i7wg" hash="KIcfSQ">The Atonement must be infinite and eternal, available to all mankind.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="UrGkw6I2IEiNDaodvYjDZQ" hash="V-xetw">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="F_Qe_xy_xkuVqgMj438iUQ" hash="pmlDyg">I believe, to use an insurance phrase, we must pay the deductible. We must experience sorrow enough, suffering enough, guilt enough so we are conscious and appreciative of the heavier burden borne by the Savior.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="7mLYTKQqj0ydx8DCMJ_dgA" hash="hsHPAg">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p pid="bvg2XfxTKUCRW9vUcM3ZmQ" hash="Okk28w">Finally, we must acknowledge the gift and comply with the conditions so that redemption might be complete. Love motivates our obedience to God. To express our love and gratitude for the Atonement, we covenant with our Heavenly Father to take upon us the name of His Son and to bear witness of Him at all times and in all places, observing His commandments. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.8-10" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:8–10</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life.p27" pid="1Olq8ioZpk6mqmM3vawR_g" hash="5JSsnA">I bear my solemn witness that full acceptance of the Atonement, with the saving ordinances of the gospel, changes lives. Through Jesus Christ, the Lord of Life, we can be raised from a death of error and sin to a spiritual rebirth of hope and eternal joy. He lives. He loves us. He pleads with us to come unto Him and find peace. That we may do so is my prayer in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1993/04/the-lord-of-life</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1993-general-conference/1993-04-1030-elder-j-richard-clarke-64k-eng.mp3" length="5681557" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1993 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
