<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Jack H Goaslind</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Jack H Goaslind.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Jack%20H%20Goaslind.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Jack H Goaslind.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 1991 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 1991 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>“Yagottawanna”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I am deeply grateful for my calling to serve as Young Men General President. This assignment seemed overwhelming when I received it. It has become ever more challenging as I daily gain a greater appreciation of both the marvelous future you young men</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_91905_000_022" doc-version="2" hash="_vt_zw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="nfD70pIFmE6470Pze3fR7Q" hash="9-Fmow">“Yagottawanna”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="-SS-74Eo_EeoXjF7J69gGg" hash="ahBN5w">Jack H Goaslind</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e4e.jpg" alt="Elder Jack H Goaslind" pid="LCadEKjjxESsRhhcIHl2Ng" hash="JdHhKA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p1" pid="08cZdtuhzkGwPTawzZiclA" hash="GHwv5A">I am deeply grateful for my calling to serve as Young Men General President. This assignment seemed overwhelming when I received it. It has become ever more challenging as I daily gain a greater appreciation of both the marvelous future you young men can have and the obstacles you must surmount to achieve your goals.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p2" pid="OLdlvDcu7kSA4EuZgdYG-g" hash="yYjltg">Your potential, young men, is described in a Book of Mormon phrase: “the man of Christ.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/3.29" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 3:29</a>.) What is the man of Christ like? Can you deacons, teachers, or priests become such a man, or is that something reserved for an older generation? While my formal title is Young Men General President, I hope that I am actually presiding over a brotherhood of young men of Christ. I’d like to refer to you young men as “<span class="emphasis">men</span> of Christ.” Even though you are <span class="emphasis">young</span> men, you are <span class="emphasis">men.</span> I pray that each of us may come to understand the word of God, which will lead us in a strait and narrow course and help us to avoid a lot of suffering and misery in our lives. I wish to discuss one distinguishing quality of the young man of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p3" pid="oePflIHUmkWEx-rjMGw7mw" hash="-V-lZw">This quality was expressed in a word that I recently saw printed on a young man’s worn T-shirt from a bygone youth conference. It read, “Yagottawanna.” I jokingly guessed it might be an ancient Indian word, but I asked him to explain it to me. He gave me that “you gotta be kiddin’” look, but condescended to answer anyway. “‘Yagottawanna,’” he said, “means that you have to <span class="emphasis">want</span> to do something before you will do it.” Of course I knew that all along, but it was good to hear him say it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p4" pid="9l4bzrk6hEG196xqU5naIg" hash="iUXE6w">Whoever planned that youth conference had the right idea. “Yagottawanna” captures several important gospel principles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p5" pid="4NpUTmGUTkeY_69RIDJpLQ" hash="dN9zbw">It reminds me of one of the qualities of godhood. “And there is nothing that the Lord thy God shall take in his heart to do but what he will do it.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.17" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:17</a>.) Isn’t it wonderful that we can trust our Father in Heaven to do what he says he will do?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p6" pid="334JhuyCGUCQFjqv5RPfpQ" hash="igjBmQ">There are two elements to this principle. First, God takes something into his heart. When we take something into our hearts, it usually means that we <span class="emphasis">feel</span> something. This is the spirit of revelation. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/8.2-3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 8:2–3</a>.) It gives an intense feeling of peacefulness or well-being. President Marion G. Romney said that it “comes into our minds and feelings and induces us to do what is right” (“Ye Are a Peculiar People,” <span class="emphasis">Brigham Young University Speeches of the Year,</span> Provo, 10 Apr. 1956, p. 8); it leads us to do good (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/11.12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 11:12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p7" pid="-jBR7o6xlkmQY_1egTqgFQ" hash="SHu_3Q">How many of you have heard an inspiring thought, hymn, or story, and then had a desire to go do something good? This is not unusual; it is a healthy, spiritual feeling that is essential to our progress. But how often have you <span class="emphasis">followed through</span> on those feelings? This brings us to the second part of the equation. When God takes it into his heart to do something, whatever it is, he <span class="emphasis">does</span> it. He simply <span class="emphasis">does</span> it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p8" pid="zpdtFPZJtkCb-Cv1mjzjTA" hash="HKoECA">It has been said, “Our feelings were given us to excite to action, and when they end in themselves, they are cherished to no good purpose.” (Daniel Keyte Sandford, in <span class="emphasis">The International Dictionary of Thoughts,</span> comp. John P. Bradley, Leo F. Daniels, Thomas C. Jones, Chicago: J. G. Ferguson Publishing Co., 1969, p. 291.) This means that once we have <span class="emphasis">felt</span> something, we must <span class="emphasis">act</span> in order to hold on to those feelings we experience. Elder Joseph B. Wirthlin noted that “individuals who do right and ‘hunger and thirst after righteousness’ (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.6" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:6</a>) get and keep alive through their actions the feeling to do right.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1976, p. 56.) In contrast, those who do not act out their righteous desires place themselves in a dangerous position. As C. S. Lewis said, “The more often [a person] feels without acting, the less he will be able ever to act, and, in the long run, the less he will be able to feel.” (<span class="emphasis">The Screwtape Letters,</span> New York: Macmillan Publishing Co., 1982, p. 61.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p9" pid="xyP_9J6-2kis6aT07v5E_Q" hash="nNfb9Q">“Yagottawanna” also helps us understand the principle of agency. Youth with sincere desires take initiative. They do good things without waiting to be told. They “do many things of their own free will, and bring to pass much righteousness.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.27" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:27</a>.) They <span class="emphasis">act</span> rather than wait to be <span class="emphasis">acted upon.</span> They are in control of themselves. Such control is a wonderful feeling. It is a feeling we get when we exercise one of our most precious gifts—that of free agency.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p10" pid="7foFDxHTvEGVfDBquBKiiA" hash="Qe25SA">“Yagottawanna” also shows an attitude of faith. <span class="emphasis">Desire</span> is the beginning of faith. The Lord will bless you “even if ye can no more than desire to believe.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.27" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:27</a>.) If we let it, this desire will grow into a mature faith that can make things happen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p11" pid="Jxt6Kg3VxkOiqXk66E6Xbg" hash="zgcZFA">What we desire will ultimately help determine our eternal judgment. Alma said that God “granteth unto men according to their desire, whether it be unto death or unto life.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/29.4" class="scriptureRef">Alma 29:4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p12" pid="W_POcyvTAUmllK8FuGlNpA" hash="UYiHmA">Desires change during our lives, sometimes dramatically and quickly, and sometimes gradually. Elder Boyd K. Packer once quoted Lady Astor: “I always dreaded growing old, because then you can’t do all of the things you want to. But it isn’t so bad—you don’t want to!” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1974, p. 89.) Be aware that things that seem all-important to you now will not matter in years to come. But you can choose now to want things that are in harmony with eternity. For example, you can choose to be righteous rather than waste your time on perishable things; you can choose to serve willingly rather than selfishly. Elder Marion D. Hanks has often quoted the wise saying that “the things that matter most must not be at the mercy of the things that matter least.” The choices we make in this life have a very important influence on our eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p13" pid="8OVGlYvkIUaJybfT00_Usw" hash="d9qyIw">Proper worship illustrates how “Yagottawanna” works. For example, how many of you have assumed the “bored position” during sacrament meeting? You know the position: bent forward at the waist, chin resting on hands, elbows on knees, staring vacantly at the floor. Has it occurred to you that it is your <span class="emphasis">choice</span> whether the meeting is interesting or not?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p14" pid="IcG_LlGrME6E7KafxcBwKQ" hash="64k0SA">Several years ago I heard about a good brother who described his attitude as President David O. McKay gave the concluding talk of general conference. It was a sultry afternoon, and this was the fifth session he had attended. He was sitting in the balcony, and his mind had a serious wandering problem. He noticed a man sitting in the middle section who had fallen asleep with his head tilted back and his mouth open. It occurred to him that if he were in the roof of the Tabernacle, he could drop a spit wad through one of the vent holes right into the mouth of that sleeping man. What a glorious thought! Following the meeting, he overheard two men talking about their feelings during President McKay’s talk. They were visibly moved by what they had heard. He thought to himself, These two brethren were having a marvelous spiritual experience, and what was I doing? Thinking about dropping spit wads from the ceiling!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p15" pid="WZlk3A__d0KTM_KYfRwT-Q" hash="9eYJIg">President Spencer W. Kimball said that worship “is an individual responsibility, and regardless of what is said from the pulpit, if one wishes to worship the Lord in spirit and in truth, he may do so. … If the service is a failure to you, you have failed. No one can worship for you; you must do your own waiting upon the Lord.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Jan. 1978, p. 5.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p16" pid="Mr-ny04h2kaia6-p3B3S1Q" hash="DJaA2Q">One youth described how he first experienced the spirit of worship. He had been marginally active through his Aaronic Priesthood years. When he attended sacrament meeting, he usually sat in the back with a group of his friends, and he was less than a model of reverence. One day, however, he came in a little late, and there were no seats by his friends. He sat alone, and for the first time in his life, he closed his eyes during the prayers, he sang the hymns, he listened to the sacrament prayers, and he paid attention to the speakers. About midway through the first speaker, he found tears welling up in his eyes. With some embarrassment, he carefully glanced around; no one else seemed emotional. He didn’t know for sure what was happening to him, but the experience changed his life. It was during that meeting that he really started his spiritual preparation for his mission. He <span class="emphasis">felt</span> something, and fortunately, he acted and thus sustained those feelings. I want to especially emphasize one important desire you should cultivate. “Yagottawanna” keep yourself pure, and free from immoral conduct. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/38.12" class="scriptureRef">Alma 38:12</a>.) You can control your passions. I hope you will cultivate the desire to honor young women. Elder M. Russell Ballard told us during last October general conference that young women want to be treated with courtesy. (See <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1990, p. 37.) The standards outlined in the pamphlet <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth</span> are of great value. These Church standards will become <span class="emphasis">your</span> standards when you really cherish them, when you feel something about their value, and when you act in accordance with them. Yes, “Yagottawanna” live these standards.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p17" pid="LGwtxK2cVkClTzWcQ0oreA" hash="MhhlLQ">When you are pure in your heart, when you desire that which is good, true, and beautiful, then you can avoid the pitfalls of life. If you build your foundation upon the “rock of our Redeemer, who is Christ,” then the devil “shall have no power over you.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/5.12" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 5:12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p18" pid="qR3FmMZbv0ODJNPtyv3Lug" hash="uA_zmg">You can also be an influence for good, so that the gospel message will shine through your countenance. I recently heard of a young woman who invited a group of her friends to bring their dates to her home after a dance. One couple stopped on the way to pick up a videotape to watch. As they played it, the group realized it was an R-rated movie. This young woman became disturbed and excused herself to talk to her parents. They reminded her that R-rated movies are not shown in their home and suggested that someone should turn it off. The young woman said she would do it, and she did. Everyone seemed relieved. This is a simple incident, but it illustrates a point. A young woman who <span class="emphasis">wanted</span> to be good acted on her desires, and a whole group of youth were spared a little bit of evil. Repeated many times over, until it becomes a pattern, such actions can be an influence that will spread through the Church and through society.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p19" pid="AfjDUkG-X0mEwTMWHixHIw" hash="LZCqfw">I ask you men of Christ to cultivate, to cherish, and to maintain righteous desires. “Yagottawanna.” That’s the key to action; it’s the key to happiness. It’s the key to worshipping the Lord, to developing faith, and to maintaining standards of purity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna.p20" pid="atQPSpjbjk6pY6Fa8s8tqA" hash="jZuN0A">I promise you that the Lord will bless you with right attitudes and desires as you pray to him, attend to your duties, keep the commandments, and serve him. Then you young men will truly be men of Christ. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1991/04/yagottawanna</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1991-general-conference/1991-04-3040-elder-jack-h-goaslind-64k-eng.mp3" length="6520821" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 1991 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spiritual Mountaintops</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Recently I had the opportunity to attend meetings at Jackson Lake in the majestic Teton Mountains of Wyoming in the western part of the United States. The rugged mountain peaks and the breathtakingly beautiful scenery and the cool, crisp autumn air c</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95911_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="ltrwWQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="LMAq1CpcaEGer782Adtdng" hash="CmS5cQ">Spiritual Mountaintops</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="XuX2yo1_7063CiPIASXMEA" hash="ahBN5w">Jack H Goaslind</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e4e.jpg" alt="Elder Jack H Goaslind" pid="iPqxBrDgq0uMvFytMOPofA" hash="JdHhKA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p1" pid="gURUNjU0pECe7sCxta4wHg" hash="aQiKvw">Recently I had the opportunity to attend meetings at Jackson Lake in the majestic Teton Mountains of Wyoming in the western part of the United States. The rugged mountain peaks and the breathtakingly beautiful scenery and the cool, crisp autumn air combined to lift and restore the spirits of almost every visitor. I must admit that the work I’d been sent there to do seemed a lot less like work than what most of us experience every day. The peaceful mountain setting had a restorative effect on me and others in attendance. The world’s problems seemed less insurmountable. The challenges I faced seemed much less threatening. I came away with a heightened outlook and a spirit brightened by new hope and enthusiasm.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p2" pid="pmnidW_GK0eaGgCZWwwf6w" hash="6fr5SQ">Those mountain heights also stirred in me other reflections. I’d like to share some of those with you this morning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p3" pid="JC6EeOK9KEaBPJT6uMKggg" hash="TOFL8A">The Lord has often used mountaintops as sanctuaries. In Old Testament times, when temples were not available the Lord used mountaintops as sacred places in which to reveal truths to his prophets. Likewise, the New Testament and the Book of Mormon describe sacred mountaintops where God revealed truths to his servants. Joseph Smith, kneeling in the Sacred Grove, was figuratively kneeling at the top of a great spiritual mountain.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p4" pid="ekiaqDwEPEqLiHZ8_V7Wjw" hash="MZXvBg">Today the Lord provides us with ample space which, in a personal way, becomes our own spiritual mountaintop where we receive truth and inspiration. Searching the scriptures, for example, can answer many of the questions of our day by lifting our spirits to clarifying heights. Further, the world is dotted with holy temples which we may enter to receive instruction and inspiration and to perform sacred ordinances. Conferences such as this one, reports of the prophetic utterances of our beloved leaders, our own sacrament meetings and stake conferences—all provide rich, fulfilling opportunities to hear the truth and allow it to sink deep into our souls.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p5" pid="zmL6Gs1PqUy75ZnHKUku7w" hash="DxKjPw">In our own lives, in our daily workaday world, we can create our own “mountaintop experience” so unique and personal that I wonder why more of us do not readily do so. The spiritual mountaintop of which I speak is the development and refining of a testimony of our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ. Just as we can stand on the top of any great mountain and experience an awe-inspiring panorama, I believe we can stand in our own places and experience overwhelming awe in knowing that the Savior, in an act of love which defies mortal understanding, gave his life in taking upon himself our pain and suffering.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p6" pid="bTXcjL_hiUC-z8cKNCg2aQ" hash="DVWCEw">It seems to me that the power of a testimony of Jesus Christ is one of the great, untapped sources of direction in our lives today. I am convinced that each of us, however good, loyal, or dedicated we try to be in the gospel and in the Church, could do so much more if we did it with the power and influence of an unwavering faith in the Lord. Let me give you an example.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p7" pid="Udafy3GcXky10U7KUd01bg" hash="jFMTxA">I believe most parents within the sound of my voice try to teach their children right from wrong, to be honest, to respect others and their property, to live morally clean lives, and to love their families. They work hard to teach them the importance of the saving ordinances, such as baptism for the remission of sins. At the appropriate age, they want their sons to be ordained to the priesthood. They teach their children to know that to be married in the right place to the right person at the right time by the right authority is critical to exaltation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p8" pid="yRTy2WXAZES7W_kp7BDr0w" hash="nYAHjg">These important lessons, and others like them so crucial to every Latter-day Saint, are the hallmarks of everything we believe and hold dear. If these lessons are learned through the Spirit, taught under the strong influence of a strong testimony of the atonement of the Savior, they are taught and learned in an atmosphere of love and trust that goes a long way in ensuring they will be retained. As the scripture teaches, “Train up a child in the way he should go: and when he is old, he will not depart from it” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/22.6" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 22:6</a>). The belief, and finally conviction, that Jesus of Nazareth, the carpenter’s son, the Redeemer of Israel—even our Lord and Savior, Jesus the Christ—gave his life in a selfless sacrifice so that we may have immortality and eternal life bring into focus every other teaching that we impart to our children and others for whom we have a stewardship.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p9" pid="aCt9n_mzdUKgiE75_efmvg" hash="Irbcag">Sometimes I think that we fear too much to link all of our teaching to the foundation of gospel truths. Too often, perhaps, we teach children to obey a law or a principle because our family expects that obedience. They might observe another truth in order to please a neighbor or a bishop, and another for yet some other reason. When we teach an eternal truth to our children and don’t explain it in the context of a firm testimony of the Savior, we miss the power of the example of the greatest teacher the world has ever known.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p10" pid="7g_kRwdbB0OCVOdu6FM9Rg" hash="NvHGSg">Likewise, many of us have attained a level of obedience in which we consistently keep the letter of the law; we commit no grievous sins. As we look about us, we see that we do no worse than the next family, and we feel satisfied, comfortable. We are compatible with others on our plateau partway up the mountain. We like this scenic ledge where we have all the “do’s and don’ts” under control. We need to learn—and then teach—that we are obedient to the laws and principles of the gospel because of our belief, our knowledge, our testimony, and our faith in Jesus Christ. Nephi, who reports in the scriptures that his “soul delighteth in plainness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/25.4" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 25:4</a>), reminds us in the twenty-fifth chapter of 2 Nephi, “We talk of Christ, we rejoice in Christ, we preach of Christ, we prophesy of Christ, and we write according to our prophecies, that our children may know to what source they may look for a remission of their sins” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/25.26" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 25:26</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p11" pid="yWV4fJTlYEeZXKcwRiod8g" hash="wi8eSA">Perhaps knowing that it would be difficult at times for us to place our faith so fully in our testimonies of the Savior, President Harold B. Lee admonished us, “Walk to the edge of the light, and perhaps a few steps into the darkness, and you will find that the light will appear and move ahead of you” (as quoted by Boyd K. Packer, regional representatives’ seminar, 1 Apr. 1977).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p12" pid="8PKSOMjONEG7kxJeF45_6g" hash="A5DaCQ">It is in the development of our testimonies, in the moving even partway up the mountain and out of our comfort zones, that I think we begin to approach our own personal, spiritual mountaintop where we can receive inspiration and truth as never before. It is there, just as I experienced in the tops of the Tetons, that we can think more clearly, see things more as they really are, and understand truth in a light that is pure and fresh. There, with the Holy Ghost to guide and influence us, we begin to understand, know how to teach, or bless the lives of others with new meaning and increased perception.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p13" pid="SVAme27UHki88yVklioZkA" hash="EtiaTQ">If I could have but just one wish fulfilled this morning, I would plant deep in your hearts the unwavering remembrance of Jesus Christ. In our day, President Howard W. Hunter inspired all of us by saying, “We must know Christ better than we know him; we must remember him more often than we remember him; we must serve him more valiantly than we serve him” (in Conference Report, Apr. 1994, p. 84).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p14" pid="hZC3ak7lEk2bMTdXmADL9Q" hash="5dP17w">Perhaps what President Hunter asked us to do in those challenging words was the same thing that the prophet Alma taught us about finding a mighty change in our hearts. Alma taught the members of the Church in Zarahemla that they needed to lift their hearts to a higher spiritual plane. He spoke of the need to trust God, and he told them how important it was to exercise faith. And then he asked this critical question which we need to ask ourselves today: “And now behold, I say unto you, my brethren, if ye have experienced a change of heart, and if ye have felt to sing the song of redeeming love, I would ask, can ye feel so now?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.26" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:26</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p15" pid="S0C-HIprNUKDHMoMs0JTpA" hash="hOuYww">Brothers and sisters, our goodness—our every righteous endeavor—our good works, our obedience, and our efforts to bless others must be anchored in and driven by our faith in Christ, our testimonies of his mission and sacrifice, and our willingness to move off our comfortable plateaus. Until we find ways to strengthen, increase, and magnify our testimonies of Jesus Christ and the effect of the Atonement in our lives, we will be unable to answer Alma’s question in the affirmative.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p16" pid="d2wSfH8qL0GSwSE6kaKFeg" hash="QSiFYw">Satan wants us to fail to reach that mountaintop that will allow us to develop a testimony so powerful that he will be unable to influence us. His work is to thwart our efforts, but the Lord has counseled us, “Fear not, little flock; do good; let earth and hell combine against you, for if ye are built upon my rock, they cannot prevail” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.34" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:34</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p17" pid="oJt12u5tLk-EnYIZvJ9LmQ" hash="Nfwm8g">We have every confidence that earth and hell will not overtake you, but it will require that you move from your current plateaus and climb to higher ground.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p18" pid="FyjVg26OKUi-pgu8tAAVqw" hash="eI1hkw">May I close with the powerful words of our beloved prophet, Gordon B. Hinckley, and I quote: “Go forward with your lives. The best lies ahead. Bring into the lives of our young people something more of spirituality; cultivate in the heart of every boy [and girl] a sense of [their] relationship to the Lord—as [they] become acquainted with the Savior of the world by knowing some elements of the atonement of the Redeemer through which eternal life is made possible for each of us” (West High seminary graduation, Salt Lake City, 14 May 1995; priesthood leadership meeting, Heber City/Springville, Utah, regional conference, 13 May 1995).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops.p19" pid="b81YSoPx5kKgH9HEfjttkg" hash="zvEF1g">God bless you, parents. We love you. We know it is not easy to do what you are doing. We know that every new day brings challenges and trials that often seem insurmountable. May you find through increased faith and reliance upon the Lord renewed strength, vigor, and resilience in teaching and blessing the lives of those in your parental stewardship. May you find in the counsel given us by President Howard W. Hunter, President Gordon B. Hinckley, and all who have stood to bear unfailing testimony of Jesus Christ that only through love and devotion to the teachings of him of whom we testify, and through the blessings of his atonement in our behalf, may we teach with the power to bless and save our families in the kingdom of God. Of this I testify in the holy name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/10/spiritual-mountaintops</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1995-general-conference/1995-10-1030-elder-jack-h-goaslind-64k-eng.mp3" length="6310517" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1995 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“In His Strength I Can Do All Things”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Ordinary men, blessed with the privilege of holding the priesthood of God, may be called upon to do extraordinary tasks and accomplish mighty feats through faith in that sacred power!</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_97905_000_020" doc-version="2" hash="GOmH6g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="jfvXOrTH70GGFfsf-IrZUw" hash="f866fA">“In His Strength I Can Do All Things”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="iYLVD0RrsE6MYL0VkB3B-g" hash="ahBN5w">Jack H Goaslind</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="I4cqlcFMO0O-4p_icvaxUw" hash="Zx8N9A">Ordinary men, blessed with the privilege of holding the priesthood of God, may be called upon to do extraordinary tasks and accomplish mighty feats through faith in that sacred power!</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e4e.jpg" alt="Elder Jack H Goaslind" pid="xvPrCiNeNE-t_Jm0QaMe0Q" hash="JdHhKA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p1" pid="Vyb88VAI4kqipru-vjPGHw" hash="2NEdCg">This evening, brethren, I have a strong desire to relate to you an aspect of a well-documented story, but it’s little-known in the Church. It involves the courage, the strength, of a few young men from the pioneer era; some were priest or teacher age, like many of you assembled here tonight. These young men willingly made significant sacrifices when they received a call.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p2" pid="1Ssh9tmxAkm_4W1IXv0zPA" hash="vI4XhQ">As I tell their story, please keep in mind what power it is that unifies us and also connects us to them. The royal priesthood we bear is more than coincidental to this account. Theirs was the same priesthood which today empowers <span class="emphasis">you</span> to perform great and small acts of service to your fellowmen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p3" pid="TC3kwL4pE0O-7VIPq1e_fQ" hash="JK7B0g">Ordinary men—including, and perhaps <span class="emphasis">especially,</span> young men—blessed with the privilege of holding the priesthood of God may be called upon to do extraordinary tasks. Holders of the holy priesthood can accomplish mighty feats of heroism, bravery, and service through faith in that sacred power.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p4" pid="fqboIw_-iky6l7rYSC2n3A" hash="7amAvQ">The pioneers did not doubt it. They bore frequent witness that the Spirit of the Lord guided and directed them. In confirmation of their testimony, I declare unto you His Spirit is with each of us. He desires to bless and strengthen us. He will make us equal to every righteous task we undertake in His name. He will magnify many times over our own natural ability. You can succeed beyond your own strength <span class="emphasis">if you learn to rely on the Spirit of the Lord.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p5" pid="BjdKwxeBK0a2FKL2yqav1Q" hash="eYu_ag">Now, the story I promised to tell you began before the October 1856 general conference, but that is where we will begin. President Brigham Young stood at the Old Tabernacle pulpit on this square and issued a call to go rescue the Willie and Martin Handcart Companies. Two days later, about 30 faithful brethren with good mule teams were dispatched to go bring in the handcarters stranded several hundred miles east. Dan W. Jones, a convert of less than five years, volunteered.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p6" pid="pLR_Y4mt2UewZt0VWx1ZQw" hash="HrV7Ew">After arduous effort, the Willie Company finally was found. Caught in the storms of early winter, the Saints were freezing and starving to death. The relief party did all they could to improve conditions, but for some it was simply too late. The morning after the rescuers’ arrival, nine of the company were buried in a common grave.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p7" pid="pR7W2RD2gkSsY_dOfq8TqA" hash="RhBIxA">Some of the rescuers were assigned to escort the handcarters to the Salt Lake Valley, but others pushed further eastward in an effort to find the Martin Company. Finally they were found, along with the Hodgett and Hunt Wagon Companies, bogged down and helpless in the snow east of Devil’s Gate, Wyoming.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p8" pid="41IXNzyKY0arAM1mJkrQYw" hash="CLTJRA">Members of the Martin Company were in dire straits. Their food rations had been cut to a few ounces of flour per day. Only a third of them could walk, and deaths were recorded daily.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p9" pid="2QXQ2DJT3UOdKduhMdDYNA" hash="z-nLZA">The leaders of the rescue party wisely decided to spare no effort in getting the suffering survivors to safety in the Salt Lake Valley. Because of the shortage of space in the wagons, it was necessary to leave most of the handcarters’ possessions in storage at Devil’s Gate till spring.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p10" pid="JqtFprfMlkSKCcNY2Y4-kQ" hash="UA31Pw">Brother Dan W. Jones and two others from the relief party, along with 17 young men from the wagon companies, were called to stay behind to guard the property. They were left to face five winter months in Wyoming, hundreds of miles from help, with scarcely anything to eat, and under conditions of extreme privation. Imagine the sacrifice! Offers were made to each man to join the wagons bound for the valley, but every one of them chose to stay behind, obedient to the call to serve.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p11" pid="ULtPPaLUi06SnANaNrsyRg" hash="3eQtcQ">That winter was recorded as one of the most severe ever. The intrepid watchmen struggled to repair the cabins at Devil’s Gate; killed the remaining cattle; stored the tough, stringy beef for food; and reconditioned and stacked the goods they were left to protect.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p12" pid="Y1v1vS98tU-RdbLfiGjoYw" hash="1RbgoQ">They killed a few buffalo, but the hunting became bad. Soon they were reduced to living on animal hides, from which they scraped off the hair, then boiled the leather. They ate the leather wrappings off the wagon tongues, old moccasin soles, and a well-worn buffalo hide that had been used as a foot mat for two months. At one point Dan Jones was literally preparing to eat his own saddle!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p13" pid="D6E8dYqGj0OFzM1FZrMV_Q" hash="wLIugQ">In February of that extreme winter, a member of the Snake Indian tribe visited and helped them. That first night he and two scouts came to camp loaded with good buffalo meat.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p14" pid="jxg48voXS0a5JHAEBI8oPg" hash="J3PIpA">The winter passed, and finally, early in May, the relief wagons began to roll in. Of the various communications Brother Jones received, one critical letter from Brigham Young had not arrived. Loading and shipping of the stored goods could not commence without it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p15" pid="9fIK61XknUmaFajGP8t7_Q" hash="MoV5Eg">For days they waited, becoming increasingly anxious. Finally Brother Jones sought the Lord in prayer to know how to proceed. He recorded the following testimony: “Next morning without saying anything about the lack of instructions we commenced business. Soon some one asked whose teams were to be loaded first, [and] I dictated to my clerk. Thus we continued. As fast as the clerk put them down, orders would be given, and we passed on to the next. We continued this [way] for four days. … All the teams were loaded up, companies organized and started back [to the valley]” (Daniel W. Jones, <span class="emphasis">Forty Years among the Indians</span> [1960], 107).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p16" pid="1PNQgZBaTk2P0GhhxSIlRA" hash="xN1DBg">The 17 young men were loaded on the last wagons departing to the Salt Lake Valley, where they would be reunited with their families and loved ones.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p17" pid="vfJGzpaM90miGClyvzkpVA" hash="UNdWFQ">Brother Jones arrived later to report to President Young, feeling not a little uncertain how he would be received. Should he have waited for the President’s written orders? As everything unfolded, it was learned that President Young had indeed dictated a letter of instructions, which was never received. Dan carefully presented his detailed report. It was a testimony to him to find that the inspiration he’d received in Wyoming was <span class="emphasis">exactly</span> the same as in the prophet’s letter.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.f2">
	<p pid="ikliShhwGEC933EaHPFhqg" hash="Oybysw">Dan Jones’s young men had done more than they ever would have imagined they could:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="R_JxI3hQH0CSpzSJ6XdX5g" hash="bIlm9Q">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="LcdjLEtMo0CCzhqkekbhCw" hash="h3XUUA">They had crossed the plains in wagons and by handcart, mostly on foot.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="S6hjYtvfB0GWkJ9p1G47vg" hash="mFHkSg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="9SxJJfAV0kmL1qOrlIGASg" hash="MtLROQ">They had seen many of their friends and relatives die along the way.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="uSrLssmGFUCsB_UTCYvX-g" hash="HiXsgg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="6ATcnf_Fx0GgJWRvlYImlg" hash="mAlClw">They had volunteered to spend the winter 300 miles from their destination.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="zZSSjLcTsUmfreXZx5Jk5g" hash="xmEvGA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="1_v1jWJsZkSPlStgz6N7cg" hash="sEm2Tg">They had survived a harsh winter with little food and few, if any, comforts.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="p4qHNxJcq0qhfQOQJ1jMOg" hash="Js20Sg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="h3V-hqE1IkKNPPyOInwnlg" hash="CGPCWA">They had heeded the call of the prophet to serve their fellow Saints.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="4xkkaEHvqUe83gb9oyTtuA" hash="HVCkbQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="MyNcQ05-uECLhEN_jPiH5w" hash="EGX3RA">They had endured to the end nobly and were blessed for their efforts.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p18" pid="_pWQ1Vk_M0O-IMWUpT5FfA" hash="242N_A">I repeat, brethren: Ordinary men, blessed with the privilege of holding the priesthood of God, may be called upon to do extraordinary tasks and accomplish mighty feats through faith in that sacred power!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p19" pid="0CuiYGztvkGmphBOy4tFuQ" hash="YJvVRg">One of my Book of Mormon heroes, Ammon, the great son of Mosiah, explains how much two people can accomplish when one of them is the Lord: “Yea, I know that I am nothing; as to my strength I am weak; therefore I will not boast of myself, but I will boast of my God, for in his strength I can do all things; yea, behold, many mighty miracles we have wrought in this land, for which we will praise his name forever” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/26.12" class="scriptureRef">Alma 26:12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p20" pid="lJC3mPWnjEKwkfl5IpKF-Q" hash="OByYKw">To you young men of the Aaronic Priesthood and to you brethren of the Melchizedek Priesthood, I witness that we <span class="emphasis">can</span> perform “many mighty miracles,” as testified by Ammon and by Dan Jones! They took the Lord as their guide, listened to and obeyed the Holy Spirit, and learned that they could indeed perform mighty miracles, which thing they never had supposed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p21" pid="jd3SIYc-DkObwr6SD_YhKQ" hash="0q3gFA">Our own challenges in this day will be great. Our needs will be significant. Our loyalty to great gospel truths must be no less valiant than that of those young men over 140 years ago.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p22" pid="WtJoWp8cvkayLFv80h4osQ" hash="EHu_-w">It is my prayer, brethren, that each of us will make the Lord—and His revealed word through His servants, the prophets—the guiding influence in our lives. Each of us has a miracle to perform, a journey to complete, and a marvelous mission to fulfill.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things.p23" pid="cFM37QTAw0Kcuj7tVcR-eQ" hash="FCb9Dg">May Heavenly Father bless you to know that you are one of His chosen sons in a blessed and royal generation, and that He has mighty miracles for <span class="emphasis">you</span> to perform. With His strength and the guidance of the Spirit, you too can do all things! To which I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1997/04/in-his-strength-i-can-do-all-things</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1997-general-conference/1997-04-3020-elder-jack-h-goaslind-64k-eng.mp3" length="5334849" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 1997 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
