<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By James A. Cullimore</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by James A. Cullimore.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/James%20A.%20Cullimore.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by James A. Cullimore.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1971 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1971 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Marriage Is Intended to Be Forever</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My beloved brethren and sisters, as I stand before you here today I seek an interest in your faith and prayers as I deliver the things that I have in my heart.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03006_000_6040" doc-version="2" hash="u7uxOw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="vdKumrq9MUKR0Z0omwtu7g" hash="99KUog">Marriage Is Intended to Be Forever</h1><p class="authorName" guid="d78a7914-5ab5-4be1-8fcd-fb376723c734" pid="-jy6bOKnpEWWeYeNfkx8uQ" hash="vveEig">James A. Cullimore</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="8020de35-3188-4b0d-8e15-17d5c67f77da">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-28aa.jpg" alt="Elder James A. Cullimore" guid="83c46848-c8cf-43a8-a32e-ca1376c4365f" pid="cAr1i1MHaEie8EgJT-jG5A" hash="u_okMA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p1" guid="75c87059-2666-408a-bde5-092eb6dff663" pid="P-lJ2T8lzECBbuOIK6-eow" hash="oSS8mg">My beloved brethren and sisters, as I stand before you here today I seek an interest in your faith and prayers as I deliver the things that I have in my heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p2" guid="09317c0d-fd09-49ff-8141-a0e44c8365b1" pid="jati_DD_L0W4asRTeCDtow" hash="BNMqMA">Marriage in the temple for time and eternity should be the goal of every member of the Church, for marriage is ordained of God. Marriage is a commandment. Marriage was instituted by divine edict.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p3" guid="ce151d95-a4fa-411a-94f4-26f474e5370a" pid="3zyJyJQwP0G_R_k1dUgphA" hash="-8gfbQ">The Lord said: “And again, verily I say unto you, that whoso forbiddeth to marry is not ordained of God, for marriage is ordained of God unto man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p4" guid="232729b3-7ea7-4656-b168-c4baca83dc6a" pid="24DNJvKq0kSVQIpEMmuHHA" hash="7YKhsA">“Wherefore, it is lawful that he should have one wife, and they twain shall be one flesh, and all this that the earth might answer the end of its creation;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p5" guid="606a0d7b-f1a7-43e1-8749-b56aa6b21747" pid="yxsbnF7SwEa5FDb-dr6Q8A" hash="jK0WGw">“And that it might be filled with the measure of man, according to his creation before the world was made.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/49.15-17" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 49:15–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p6" guid="c93a63b9-478d-4590-9dc2-8e121c2d6e5b" pid="TuK3UpWa9kqX7KGCc9KPgQ" hash="hvWzLA">Marriage is a sacred relationship entered into primarily for the rearing of a family, in fulfillment of the commandments of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p7" guid="173b638a-79a0-4ea4-9b23-910cb8215a9a" pid="YKjUuqf-y0q9aIAgTXiDcg" hash="utPEPA">Marriage with children, and the beautiful family relationship which can come of it, is the fulfillment of life. If things were as they should be, we would see a mother and father in a home having been married in the temple for time and eternity. The father honoring his priesthood, presiding in his home in righteousness. Father and mother loving each other and their children. Children loving and respecting each other and mother and father. All actively engaged in their church responsibilities. The Lord intended that marriage performed for eternity in the temple should endure forever. This was his plan. President Joseph Fielding Smith has said: “Marriage, as understood by Latter-day Saints, is a covenant ordained to be everlasting. <span class="emphasis">It is the foundation for eternal exaltation, for without it there could be no eternal progress in the kingdom of God.</span>” (<span class="emphasis">Doctrines of Salvation </span>[Bookcraft, 1967], vol. 2, p. 58.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p8" guid="ba11816a-1fa5-4697-b7c7-71767ce5fcb8" pid="jr6mBMd5wUGXwXll5Q-_kg" hash="NdoLhg">“What therefore God hath joined together, let not man put asunder.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/10.9" class="scriptureRef">Mark 10:9</a>.) It is evident from the scriptures that marriage performed in the Lord’s way should not be dissolved.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p9" guid="ada240dd-703f-4d69-aea8-8208ae9e4470" pid="_3sjitXr6kaLcp0M8k9yng" hash="3ONLZQ">It is sad, indeed, to see how lightly some take their marriage vows. There is great concern among the Brethren as to the increasing number of divorces in the Church today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p10" guid="63cec129-540f-477e-ad7a-f7ac3eddd89f" pid="vEQYKQm8c0aCKdVYlRVPRw" hash="jXYEhA">Even though the divorce rate among members of the Church is considerably less than the national rate, and the rate of divorce among those married in the temple is less than with those married civilly, yet the rate is alarmingly high.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p11" guid="c7468d85-85de-4d9f-b5f2-da71fda5cc64" pid="jEcXMBPm3ki2I7sWnvjfTw" hash="TvdFCw">Divorce is usually the result of one or both not living the gospel. I suppose this is the same reason divorce was finally permitted in the time of Moses, as referred to by the Savior as he answered the Pharisees, when he said: “Moses because of the hardness of your hearts suffered you to put away your wives: but from the beginning it was not so.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/19.8" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 19:8</a>.) And so in our day members do not abide by the law of the gospel in its fullness, and, as in the day of Moses, divorce is permitted, when deemed necessary, although it was never intended to be.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p12" guid="f6fb1384-70d3-4811-aff1-857983effa07" pid="EF2of00Po0mtMPaF0XzEPA" hash="qcKkGA">If, in marriage, both parties would make gospel standards and principles the basis of their marriage, few problems would arise they could not handle. When one or the other or both begin to compromise gospel standards, problems follow. Marriage is a sacred relationship, and good members of the Church would know that it is entered into primarily for the rearing of a family. Other important desires and plans in marriage should be well understood by both parties as well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p13" guid="0a1dfdaf-82ec-48e6-b0ed-f74890bdfe11" pid="yNFTMjwdSUOYR3FVkGQCRA" hash="w1-itA">President McKay said, in reference to the seriousness with which we enter the marriage contract: “… to look upon marriage as a mere contract that may be entered into at pleasure in response to a romantic whim, or for selfish purposes, and severed at the first difficulty or misunderstanding that may arise, is an evil meriting severe condemnation, especially in cases wherein children are made to suffer because of such separation.” (Quoted in Blaine R. Porter, <span class="emphasis">The Latter-day Saint Family </span>[Deseret Book Co., 1966], pp. 402–403.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p14" guid="e51c1198-67af-4866-80b4-1203e75ca09f" pid="Ww2Xq7zL8keZx7CDdb0C8A" hash="lKIFVA">Possibly to list some of the most common causes for which civil divorces are sought might be helpful in avoiding these problems: incompatibility, adultery, money matters, physical abuse, dishonesty, not living the gospel, infidelity, not honoring priesthood, desertion, constant bickering, apathy, drunkenness, uncontrolled temper.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p15" guid="4cfe906a-7a5b-4c29-94be-9eeaa45a1d38" pid="bt4eCOM8NkGy3lLKKioK-A" hash="RYRksg">Incompatibility has come to be such a common word, it seems to be the justification for many problems. I’m sure there are occasions where this is justified, but what is incompatibility? Doesn’t this indicate selfishness? Are we truly unselfish, do we love our neighbor as ourself when we are not compatible? Have we made every effort to compromise our likes and dislikes with those of our spouse? If we were truly living the gospel, there would be much less incompatibility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p16" guid="c97fd2dd-88e0-4bdd-ac69-47bd63b8adeb" pid="nsm95CryFUWQ62y38NtOLQ" hash="Hwb48w">President McKay said of incompatibility, “For a couple who have basked in the sunshine of each other’s love to stand by daily and see the clouds of misunderstanding and discord obscure the lovelight of their lives is tragedy indeed. In the darkness that follows, the love sparkle in each other’s eyes is obscured. To restore it, fruitless attempts are made to say the right word and to do the right thing; but the word and act are misinterpreted, and angry retort reopens the wound, and hearts once united become torn wider and wider asunder. When this heartbreaking state is reached, a separation is sought.” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Ideals </span>[Improvement Era, 1953], p. 469.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p17" guid="f2c1ea25-20cf-4d32-8977-5f3434859ccf" pid="TwVl24PnuU-cvvZdlFJ-SQ" hash="vbpLmQ">I have been shocked in learning the extent to which men are physically abusive to women. In the October conference of 1951 President McKay said, “I cannot imagine a man’s being cruel to a woman. I cannot imagine her so conducting herself as to merit such treatment. Perhaps there are women in the world who exasperate their husbands, but no man is justified in resorting to physical force or in exploding his feelings in profanity. There are men, undoubtedly, in the world who are thus beastly, but no man who holds the priesthood of God should so debase himself.” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Ideals, </span>p. 476.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p18" guid="4f096687-4a97-417b-b75a-36a914bedee3" pid="da_Q01cjPEmDBH2VAwFcgQ" hash="APYMAQ">The matter of disinterest, lack of voluntary expression, lack of affection are common causes for breakdown of marriage. President Harold B. Lee recently said this to a group of priesthood leaders: “I say to you brethren the most dangerous thing that can happen between you and your wife or between me and my wife is apathy, … for them to feel that we are not interested in their affairs, that we are not expressing our love and showing our affection in countless ways. Women to be happy have to be loved and so do men.” (Seminar for Regional Representatives of the Twelve, December 12, 1970, p. 6.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p19" guid="8b643e8f-2976-47e4-aee4-3eaa1a381bc2" pid="JIdRY9UVP0W9pHstO9RXWw" hash="sw98Xg">To take lightly the law of chastity or to violate the moral teachings of the Savior is a sober matter. It seems incredible that priesthood holders and women who have been considered worthy to hold a recommend to the temple and be married therein are so often guilty of adultery, infidelity, and other sex sins.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p20" guid="5f58aa9a-541e-47d0-9676-d70c0b0d933b" pid="oGa3xcN3tkO3xMok9RrvPg" hash="B65Ksw">In this day when so many women are working out of the home, as men and women work together, many homes are broken up by what at first starts to be an innocent association.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p21" guid="a1926758-bcb3-4eee-949c-6f9a2aebdfc8" pid="8gSSOt6AFUKgLY4mQux3sg" hash="g2SUng">President McKay gave some sober direction to the men when he said, “A man who has entered into a sacred covenant in the house of the Lord to remain true to the marriage vow is a traitor to the covenant if he separates himself from his wife and family just because he has permitted himself to become infatuated with the pretty face and comely form of some young girl who flattered him with a smile. Even though a loose interpretation of the law of the land would grant such a man a bill of divorcement, I think he is unworthy of a recommend to have his second marriage performed in the temple.” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Ideals, </span>p. 473.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p22" guid="552dddf6-1c6b-4976-b41c-56327e1db6a0" pid="-JSHCxGBW0a3m74Z-haNNw" hash="lsDi2g">No matter what the reason for divorce, those usually hurt most are the children. Too often the children are robbed of the basic needs to prepare them for life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p23" guid="5ee55147-477b-43f5-92f2-e48a8d1cb005" pid="6lilBDH--kOYMatYP6nvGg" hash="y0vZ2Q">President McKay said there are three fundamental things to which every child is entitled: (1) a respected name, (2) a sense of security, (3) opportunities for development. (<span class="emphasis">The LDS Family, </span>p. 406.) The possibility of any of these is lessened in divorce.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p24" guid="1344c9f0-6f83-4e32-9e6c-0476eca49b62" pid="xduic-qb2EmlSIJlWcXZgA" hash="dvn08w">As Sister Cullimore and I went to the temple to be married, President George H. Brimhall [of Brigham Young University] called us into his office. He gave us some direction we have appreciated through the years. He said: “The four fountains that will keep your ‘Garden of Eden’ from becoming a desert are constant confidence, constant counsel, constant compromise, constant courtship.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p25" guid="9ce2f458-8d35-4782-b6cc-9eb5d5e790dc" pid="-Q1aJcnbckmS1SlJKdfIhw" hash="oFrMNw">Important to any marriage is complete confidence—trust in all things. The confidence born of true love, never doubting, never questioning the integrity of each other. Someone has said: “Society is built upon trust, and trust upon confidence in one another’s integrity.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p26" guid="b2ee3fb5-54ed-411c-973c-74341e3a522f" pid="l1skSN1syU-ekvXIXybcGA" hash="Xu0qyg">To counsel with each other and make decisions together is so important to a happy marriage. Counsel which includes the whole family might build good family relationships.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p27" guid="2b6c7e13-e6c9-49b7-b1e9-33be1ff79441" pid="mtV6JLqhgUKm5w6BJkQp0A" hash="cC6O5Q">Counseling with each other in all that is done will strengthen the bonds of marriage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p28" guid="6a83a41a-bc60-426e-bdc8-efc92ad91fd1" pid="P7bkdyyve0SfopObkpPlIA" hash="uj9oEA">I suppose there is no surer need in marriage than <span class="emphasis">constant compromise. </span>It is through compromise that we grow closer to each other. As we acknowledge our own faults and recognize the virtues in the other and make the adjustments, we strengthen our marriage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p29" guid="1b13d006-5274-4a6d-91a2-d42ec92cba3a" pid="IYHXEz5uykGF5PQySdzTAw" hash="1M9REw">Henry Watterson has said: “I would compromise war. I would compromise glory. I would compromise everything at that point where hate comes in, where misery comes in, where love ceases to be love, and life begins its descent into the valley of the shadow of death. But I would not compromise Truth. I would not compromise the right.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p30" guid="cccb11f4-7226-4970-b98d-f86416a96cfa" pid="PNu2QsuoJ0GdX_ACZTL6fA" hash="VQKIPw">
        <span class="emphasis">Constant courtship. </span>President McKay has said: “The seeds of a happy married life are sown in youth. Happiness does not begin at the altar: it begins during the period of youth and courtship.” (Pathways to Happiness [Bookcraft, 1957], p. 49.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p31" guid="e462d621-d873-4df1-bbf7-13a9d856fdce" pid="ickz8JpC0UyafOEbO_UgVg" hash="7zaRyQ">Neither should courtship end at the altar. How important it is to constantly be conscious of our marriage and work at it every day we live, keeping alive our courtship by kind acts, thoughtfulness, and consideration always. Archibald F. Bennett, in his writings on family exaltation, expresses this beautifully: “Too many couples have come to the altar of marriage looking upon the marriage ceremony as the end of courtship instead of the beginning of an eternal courtship. Let us not forget that during the burdens of home life … that tender words of appreciation, courteous acts are even more appreciated than during those sweet days and months of courtship. It is after the ceremony and during the trials that daily arise in the home, that a word of ‘thank you,’ or ‘pardon me,’ ‘if you please,’ … will contribute to that love which brought you to the altar. … The wedding ring gives no man the right to be cruel or inconsiderate, and no woman the right to be slovenly, cross or disagreeable.” (<span class="emphasis">The LDS Family, </span>p. 236.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever.p32" guid="275c0b6e-c2a9-4b92-9afc-7562c23a24ac" pid="UvYNfy8YWkS_QCG4SZNPQg" hash="o9rtDA">May we keep sacred our marriage vows and live so that we might enjoy its eternal blessings, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/04/marriage-is-intended-to-be-forever</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1971-general-conference/1971-04-6070-elder-james-a-cullimore-64k-eng.mp3" length="6444038" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1971 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confession and Forsaking: Elements of Genuine Repentance</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As I look out over this vast audience, I am conscious that the greatest number on the main floor are priesthood leaders and of that group likely the largest number are bishops.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03012_000_4020" doc-version="2" hash="jp1vCw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="oCb4OwlRW0SyZ5UWJ0gwSw" hash="5jzgbg">Confession and Forsaking:</h1><p class="subtitle" pid="lGZFv_Y7nE6mgkDmW3Ecgg" hash="ucPpIw">Elements of Genuine Repentance</p><p class="authorName" guid="d78a7914-5ab5-4be1-8fcd-fb376723c734" pid="APlKDTYTUEybvcKe4C3V6w" hash="vveEig">James A. Cullimore</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="b977fdf9-367a-4574-9143-2b95c65c059f">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-28aa.jpg" alt="Conference photo" guid="dc870259-d4fe-4153-a6cd-d462f9432ce5" pid="8EyqA6DsDkuCptIi-vEbWw" hash="u_okMA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p1" guid="b5590d0d-98ec-46f0-91db-0877be870053" pid="9QtQz8hYQkaIi7rj2NP7Mg" hash="qUunYw">As I look out over this vast audience, I am conscious that the greatest number on the main floor are priesthood leaders and of that group likely the largest number are bishops.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p2" guid="cdcf7763-7c00-4a67-8c1e-8c1490d10f75" pid="Fgxg1M26E0uJF8Rsb8MAwg" hash="BOq50g">I have great respect for the bishops of the Church and for their many responsibilities. A bishop is the father of the ward, the presiding high priest of the ward, and a common judge in Israel. One of the areas in which he sits in judgment is when he must determine one’s worthiness to hold office in the Church, to officiate in Church ordinances, to hold temple recommends, etc.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p3" guid="d22354cc-9105-49e5-8608-bb95e4240cda" pid="ybRUyxe8SUCZkb1hQPJbsQ" hash="9vdjJg">It is the bishop’s duty to counsel the members of his ward, assist them in their problems, listen to the confessions of the transgressors and assist them in their repentance. Unfortunately, many in the last category, because of their transgressions, are quite inactive and need much attention. Because of their sins, they feel they are lost—that there is no use trying. It is to these members throughout the Church that I would particularly like to direct my remarks today. These are all wonderful sons and daughters of our Father who, in a weak moment or because of circumstances possibly not of their own liking, have slipped. Now in their despair and guilt of conscience, they feel lost. An attitude prevails of “What’s the use? There’s no hope for me now; I can never be forgiven.” Through the devotion of a wonderful bishop who never gives up in working with these individuals, they can be helped. When they learn that there is hope, that God is merciful, that there is forgiveness for sin, a beam of light can begin to shine through the heaviness and depression of transgression.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p4" guid="075cdff4-7166-42ae-b34a-03dbb5cd93df" pid="aW7-66-kcUW1h-K_KqdcqQ" hash="rAHy2Q">Listen to a letter received by a bishop from one in such a circumstance. There had been a beautiful interview in which the young lady poured out her heart to the bishop. He had given her the assurance that all was not lost and that there is forgiveness for sin, providing there is complete repentance. After a few days she wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p5" guid="a05032f3-1619-4f60-b608-863ce01922d6" pid="1jIHqf2Kh0CVtSQGPTGkNg" hash="vR7yQA">“Somehow you don’t realize how bad it has been until the weight begins to be lifted. I know it takes time to make up for wrong done, and maybe the best way I can express my thanks to you and my Father in heaven is to become the person you think I am and the person God knows I can become. In kind of a funny way, I’m scared inside—not scared exactly, just a feeling of how important what we do in this life is. Life has always had so much to offer me, like being able to see and touch and taste and enjoy; like seeing a sunset, hearing a baby’s laugh, watching two children playing, or seeing someone overcome an obstacle in his life. But there is always the baby’s cry, the children arguing, and someone not quite making it. I don’t know where I got this thought, but it seems to be just right.</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.f1" guid="3114fed1-0fae-4366-a664-2bd00760d00a">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="GrkBPSUoG0SeRl1am6nKjg" hash="r_Wxzw">“‘I ask no dream, no prophet’s ecstasies,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="7jXGMl4GC0SB-vd2TM4b8g" hash="ryn8fw">No sudden rending of the veil of clay,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="wApT8QE37UOwrCWQxt1DIw" hash="sDZwzA">No angel visitant—no opening skies,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="YxAy40k-tUSZ8xxkoBcAqA" hash="q1QG3A">But take the dimness of my soul away.’”</p>
        </div>
        <p class="citationInfo" pid="RPQLVrUPJEedPy6LjfhgDQ" hash="s2v3Zg">(Author unknown)</p>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p6" guid="1fe03b4b-4910-4e02-8b9a-31c979cea6db" pid="uF-1BdPRkk6E0Jj3GqqSpg" hash="KpS4VA">President Spencer W. Kimball has described just such a situation as I have referred to:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p7" guid="bd45afff-d1d1-4032-a627-8bf974d10c9b" pid="IHVp_RPybECzpvlcxnAQow" hash="nP03YA">“Sometimes a guilt consciousness overpowers a person with such a heaviness that when a repentant one looks back and sees the ugliness, the loathsomeness of the transgression, he is almost overwhelmed and wonders, ‘Can the Lord ever forgive me? Can I ever forgive myself?’ But when one reaches the depths of despondency and feels the hopelessness of his position, and when he cries out to God for mercy in helplessness but in faith, there comes a still, small, but penetrating voice whispering to his soul, ‘Thy sins are forgiven thee.’” (<span class="emphasis">Miracle of Forgiveness </span>[Bookcraft, 1969], p. 344.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p8" guid="6c83e918-c1f0-4d56-9983-45fc2b319334" pid="XC7xJo6AyE6exnWWRgFHRw" hash="gnIRig">The scriptures give us great comfort. In First John we read: “If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins, and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-jn/1.9" class="scriptureRef">1 Jn. 1:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p9" guid="b48a5a61-cc44-4d72-9473-0a3f953df28e" pid="Q1a0RaCQikKq82x-e9kwfQ" hash="CjXnGQ">And again we read: “For I the Lord cannot look upon sin with the least degree of allowance;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p10" guid="b9d7cb03-17f5-4996-8b26-60df10b3e7c6" pid="UoGAw4sG4keCaMK2sbdeuA" hash="I0JWRQ">“Nevertheless, he that repents and does the commandments of the Lord shall be forgiven.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.31-32" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:31–32</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p11" guid="158959e3-04eb-4dd4-97db-b7be140bf9d7" pid="e6Aev6bYt0yB8Kz6ebP3RA" hash="VrS__w">Possibly one of the most soul-satisfying scriptures to the transgressor is this: “Behold, he who has repented of his sins, the same is forgiven, and I, the Lord, remember them no more.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:42</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p12" guid="9c319cbb-2cf2-49ac-a091-19a85602e169" pid="617uq2OXiU6D_iF_dqP3yA" hash="6bTymQ">President Kimball has used some sound logic as he explains this matter. He said: “… the call to repentance from sin is to all men … the call promises forgiveness of sin to those who respond. What a farce it would be to call people to repentance if there were no forgiveness, and what a waste of the life of Christ if it failed to bring the opportunity for salvation and exaltation!” (<span class="emphasis">The Miracle of Forgiveness, </span>p. 344.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p13" guid="4b577323-2991-4910-83b3-4be19d7f7aed" pid="KZ9-dDhUdUuT1zK5ZitrZw" hash="RcInLw">One of the most beautiful scriptures comes from Isaiah, in which is given the promise of forgiveness to all who repent:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p14" guid="444d664c-57bf-4714-b796-64edd7be44e9" pid="dp0eQZ5KSEqrWmajaOzByA" hash="PeaT7g">“Seek ye the Lord while he may be found, call ye upon him while he is near:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p15" guid="68ebb866-2348-4579-8f6d-57021bfbcbbf" pid="TQOKKu4jsEy94_01EV4oCg" hash="KAUIAA">“Let the wicked forsake his way, and the unrighteous man his thoughts: and let him return unto the Lord, and he will have mercy upon him; and to our God, for he will abundantly pardon.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/55.6-7" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 55:6–7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p16" guid="54bba524-6fe3-4014-8fb7-197d007fcf6a" pid="PEFolAPf0kOzoL3JmIBshA" hash="ylmSLA">Repentance isn’t always easy. It takes great humility. It often requires superhuman courage, especially in major transgression. But the Lord has told us plainly how we can tell if a man or woman has repented of his sins. He said: “By this ye may know if a man repenteth of his sins—behold, he will confess them and forsake them.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.43" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:43</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p17" guid="87a5fc57-0d66-4048-ad43-229ecb189322" pid="trxVIj4Af0iZqHrBP1_FpQ" hash="eeJMMg">Confession and forsaking, then, are the two important elements of repentance. After one has been brought to realize his transgression and made his determination to turn from it, he must humble himself to make his confession. It would be much easier to simply cease doing the wrong, in the case of serious sin, and say nothing to anyone. But to humble himself to confess it to the ones offended and to the bishop is a more sobering matter and takes real humility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p18" guid="58c3cf11-b228-4a17-ac86-68b47017bcdb" pid="e6j6-KOpiUKeByP16VATmQ" hash="jT4k4g">Following confession, the transgressor should demonstrate with good works his repentance, keeping faithfully the commandments of the Lord. Restitution is also an important part of repentance. Restitution, to the degree possible, should be made to restore that which has been taken or to repair the damage that has been done, demonstrating to those offended by his actions his remorse and determination to make amends.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p19" guid="d26cca76-7f11-42dd-9367-e5d3bebb1de2" pid="Ni1Z98F9Mk-7YziVY3UqHA" hash="chxFLg">President Harold B. Lee has expressed this so beautifully:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p20" guid="edbf5f34-27d7-461b-954a-60c8382f239c" pid="kBgCV1xIykqgtH4UwzvRzg" hash="VIMFSg">“That confession must be made first to him or her who has been most wronged by your acts. A sincere confession is not merely admitting guilt after the proof is already in evidence. If you have ‘offended many persons openly,’ your acknowledgment is to be made openly and before those whom you have offended that you might show your shame and humility and willingness to receive a merited rebuke. If your act is secret and has resulted in injury to no one but yourself, your confession should be in secret, and your Heavenly Father who hears in secret may reward you openly. Acts that may affect your standing in the Church, or your right to privileges or advancement in the Church, are to be promptly confessed to the bishop whom the Lord has appointed as a shepherd over every flock and commissioned to be a common judge in Israel. He may hear such confessions in secret and deal justly and mercifully, as each case warrants. … Following confession, one in sin must show forth the fruits of his repentance by good deeds that are weighed against the bad. He must make proper restitution to the limit of his power to restore that which he has taken away or to repair the damage he has done.” (<span class="emphasis">Youth and the Church </span>[Deseret Book Co., 1970], p. 99.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p21" guid="b44472cb-b290-4d58-8bce-d6e261364cd6" pid="_8gCqvSXv0mdUzjGRmatJg" hash="AKDkXA">After one has confessed his transgression and started in motion the processes of repentance, by demonstrating with good works his sincere desire to be completely forgiven, how do we know when to forgive? When do we know he has truly repented?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p22" guid="2c0263c5-8625-473c-90f8-11fe9cd3a9ac" pid="9wBBpmPuDkaLLiQi_NYvBg" hash="uo3w_A">In a revelation to the Church in Kirtland, Ohio, in 1831, the Lord said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p23" guid="a4799990-9155-4892-8ca4-efdb27634c9a" pid="AWNPdUx_H0KVXVC27N5UBg" hash="sbRtKQ">“… verily I say unto you, I, the Lord, forgive sins unto those who confess their sins before me and ask forgiveness, who have not sinned unto death.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p24" guid="0f3900a3-a624-4502-aee3-9de5a1fe5439" pid="JTA6SEhPH0Cv0b2y5LrbTA" hash="Bleqrw">“Wherefore, I say unto you, that ye ought to forgive one another; for he that forgiveth not his brother his trespasses standeth condemned before the Lord; for there remaineth in him the greater sin.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p25" guid="f0ffb371-208d-4552-b120-d8602ea6be5b" pid="ew0_EFheLUasX7Mbaw_RFg" hash="3V7Q0A">“I, the Lord, will forgive whom I will forgive, but of you it is required to forgive all men.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.7,9-10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:7, 9–10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p26" guid="73cf9ffd-cc05-467e-9318-5be7e73b6112" pid="GnZYM9Kp9UKARzHQHVheJw" hash="FgkZbw">In these explicit instructions to the Church—that we are to forgive all men their trespasses—it doesn’t mean that after the bishop hears the confessions of one of his members, he immediately absolves them of all responsibility for their transgressions by his forgiveness. Surely he is forgiving. He puts his arm around them, is kind and understanding, and does everything possible to help them back to complete activity. But in spite of his love and understanding, he may have to impose a penalty, a “time of forsaking” in which the individual is denied certain church privileges for a period of time, depending on the seriousness of the transgression.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p27" guid="e4a9a52d-79b6-4c12-9c9d-6495d863b589" pid="Az4xfMU9uUahHGuDaQHtMg" hash="lM1C4A">Someone is reputed to have asked one of the Brethren, “When is one forgiven of his transgressions?” and he replied, “When he has repented.” He was then asked, “How do you know when he has repented?” His answer was, “If you could look into the heart of the individual you could tell. Possibly repentance was at the time of confession, but since we don’t know, there must be a time in which the person can demonstrate his repentance through faithfulness to the gospel.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p28" guid="3056388b-3dd2-4dc8-8542-9892e49376bb" pid="FWNdnkGb7EaekiRah_ucxg" hash="hMSvXA">The time of forsaking will likely be determined by the seriousness of the transgression and the repentant attitude of the transgressor. A letter from the First Presidency to a stake president, who was assisting one of the members of his stake to receive forgiveness for a serious moral transgression, included the following enlightening paragraph:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p29" guid="5c2c6ad7-d481-4d93-88bd-2d51046f14bc" pid="UohYTc4ieEWD3VAWPRu7GQ" hash="2ADpVg">“Confession and forsaking are elements of genuine repentance and must be coupled with restitution, so far as possible, for whatever wrong has been done, and the living of all the commandments of the Lord. There is a question as to whether or not sufficient time has elapsed to determine compliance with the forsaking element. We feel more time should be required to prove this person can live righteously in the future.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p30" guid="124070a0-9994-417b-9f44-e47b83bff5e2" pid="pscexg1f00Wk0Ro4FTM1Cg" hash="yqXpyA">The <span class="emphasis">General Handbook of Instructions of the Church </span>indicates a certain time of waiting, after serious transgression, before individuals can be given full Church or priesthood privileges.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p31" guid="8d33e897-3e2b-486b-afc9-0650cb4dbf16" pid="O9U7KgUswUuJ6B47J0Mchg" hash="kqcGSg">But whatever the penalties, however long or arduous the process, even humbling in sackcloth and ashes, repentance is the only course.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p32" guid="ddb85080-307a-4797-8d45-91e09ebe8281" pid="lvF6_VvCgke1e8GRtK_quA" hash="FLA1SA">Through the atoning blood of Jesus Christ our sins can be washed clear. In the words of Amulek: “… he said unto him that the Lord surely should come to redeem his people, but that he should not come to redeem them in their sins, but to redeem them from their sins.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p33" guid="ae2f2359-d4e5-4649-a470-32c7fa119b38" pid="YrTlccj51kGB7Ir7ed05JA" hash="zdA5aw">“And he hath power given unto him from the Father to redeem them from their sins because of repentance.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/5.10-11" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 5:10–11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p34" guid="12005846-ee95-46a1-9d1f-0aebd687f2bb" pid="HrLTs0HVTUGkqqsPTKNjvg" hash="I0uYKw">Now one final bit of assurance that the repentant one may be forgiven: “Verily, thus saith the Lord: It shall come to pass that every soul who forsaketh his sins and cometh unto me, and calleth on my name, and obeyeth my voice, and keepeth my commandments, shall see my face and know that I am.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.1" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:1</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance.p35" guid="bef311e7-e1d5-449a-a386-534f24609599" pid="WwhHdua-qEKuxWIbNOog2A" hash="qKRSgg">It may not be easy—the road may be long, but I leave you my witness it is the way the Lord has provided in his mercy to us. In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/10/confession-and-forsaking-elements-of-genuine-repentance</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1971-general-conference/1971-10-4030-elder-james-a-cullimore-64k-eng.mp3" length="13396808" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of a Personal Testimony</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I have been greatly impressed, my brethren and sisters, at the strength of the testimonies that have been borne this afternoon and this morning in these conference sessions. I thought the testimony of President Smith was so firm, so strong, so certai</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03020_000_2050" doc-version="2" hash="_3BoxQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="femq_l5oFECXim9GAUxHiQ" hash="xDNUog">The Importance of a Personal Testimony</h1><p class="authorName" guid="d78a7914-5ab5-4be1-8fcd-fb376723c734" pid="y8QtKhZxG0SimvEzwFV1jQ" hash="vveEig">James A. Cullimore</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="52853869-e984-444f-bab3-49cb8151882e">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-28aa.jpg" alt="Elder James A. Cullimore" guid="da4f754f-ca06-4b15-b003-bfe0000b70be" pid="0Mf7-TOrkU-CxjU6hOgaLA" hash="u_okMA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p1" guid="a7d224bf-7fcb-4b5d-971a-bf170d5c6e1b" pid="5LFnLsPexU6whO0__WEjbg" hash="UWXrEA">I have been greatly impressed, my brethren and sisters, at the strength of the testimonies that have been borne this afternoon and this morning in these conference sessions. I thought the testimony of President Smith was so firm, so strong, so certain. How can anyone doubt! And then to have it followed by Brother [Mark E.] Petersen in his masterful way, and so sincere. The testimonies of the other brethren, Bishop Featherstone and Bishop Peterson, so humble and so certain, a testimony in their lives, and the testimony of others that have been given. Brother Kimball, always so sweet and so sincere. These are the things that are important to us in our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p2" guid="4a08e9d6-bc8c-46ca-b3b3-46bdd8420e4e" pid="BbYr5IUy7UasginNtXqBHQ" hash="G-2YWQ">A testimony of the gospel is one of the most valued possessions of a member of the Church. The strength and unity of the Church depend upon each member so living that he comes to know for himself that the gospel is true.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p3" guid="19a9ffbb-7450-40f0-8802-07e21cde7e47" pid="Opp2-UvvukSiKirZp3Pa3Q" hash="0YIuPQ">The spiritual condition of the membership of the Church is determined by the degree to which the members live the gospel and are worthy of the companionship of the Holy Spirit in giving witness of the truth of this great work. It would follow that the prosperity of the Church is also measured to a great extent by the strength of testimonies of its members as demonstrated by their worthiness and righteous living.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p4" guid="5b51509b-b5dd-4fc4-a12a-d4b3ff20c2b2" pid="GGaP6fAlvUm0dWJ2p0EamA" hash="NCgpnw">One of the great testimonies of the scriptures is that given by Peter as he was brought before the judges after having healed the lame man at the temple gate.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p5" guid="98254155-b663-45d8-8489-e85447ddb6fd" pid="-a4S-tl3vk6Cp-dj7modog" hash="5cKb-Q">“Then Peter, filled with the Holy Ghost, said unto them, Ye rulers of the people, and elders of Israel,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p6" guid="b75d6f2d-9451-4cc1-95f5-32a3ddc4ec10" pid="-YM3U_BZ2EGG-rtDe0FGZA" hash="3TvTPA">“If we this day be examined of the good deed done to the impotent man, by what means he is made whole;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p7" guid="ae5ee0b1-01d3-40c1-9ef7-84c9d190caab" pid="PezBUJL38k-Vdf4P4kSH6g" hash="F1GFlQ">“Be it known unto you all, and to all the people of Israel, that by the name of Jesus Christ of Nazareth, whom ye crucified, whom God raised from the dead, even by him doth this man stand here before you whole.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p8" guid="04892acc-e9e8-4c5c-a48e-3dc53d86cc4f" pid="qC8V04jsmEuRJB0SEEI-Ng" hash="O5wLNA">“This is the stone which was set at nought of you builders, which is become the head of the corner.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p9" guid="2085b95c-fa5d-415d-969b-1f2e898dfaaa" pid="BgsUkTdSvUW8YhSM2c_Wtg" hash="BttBAg">“Neither is there salvation in any other: for there is none other name under heaven given among men, whereby we must be saved.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/4.8-12" class="scriptureRef">Acts 4:8–12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p10" guid="9fdaff1e-5452-4620-9fd9-0d2e726a64e1" pid="uJOzd42ohUqYP9k5eaOFjw" hash="yxxl9w">A second great testimony was given by Peter of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p11" guid="b8f784fb-e245-4506-8e04-7e2b1ced8c0d" pid="3ZkKXSlcW0CcpJbtJ16SHg" hash="nVP8_A">“When Jesus came into the coasts of Cæsarea Philippi, he asked his disciples, saying, Whom do men say that I the Son of man am?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p12" guid="12cb1f8b-b597-48ba-a60c-7e0e44de5aeb" pid="sFvoboB6o0qatUQyu2A5FQ" hash="j7ecPg">“And they said, Some say that thou art John the Baptist: some, Elias; and others, Jeremias, or one of the prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p13" guid="c14db39d-5389-4095-9406-691da2888b9e" pid="pu32JfcLS0yilr8byRKq7g" hash="zYTRdg">“He saith unto them, But whom say ye that I am?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p14" guid="26a3a098-e427-4d58-a3a8-c20af65bd170" pid="54BIrBozJku7qHX8p8QBtg" hash="3d-4RA">“And Simon Peter answered and said, Thou art the Christ, the Son of the living God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p15" guid="c7e9e23b-f920-46b4-84d6-327a2a20f479" pid="ADzYj4OhF06gNdgd8HPzKQ" hash="P5l7fQ">“And Jesus answered and said unto him, Blessed art thou, Simon Barjona: for flesh and blood hath not revealed it unto thee, but my father which is in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p16" guid="b2271ea4-0d8a-4eb4-b453-cc649111bb81" pid="krT0WfrzwkegjVRZIMhyZw" hash="g6ldwg">“And I say also unto thee, That thou art Peter, and upon this rock I will build my church; and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p17" guid="81122728-4318-4f31-b630-afeced175669" pid="8iMEApxOnUOGXKNDBhmvhQ" hash="5pfYSw">“And I will give unto thee the keys of the kingdom of heaven: and whatsoever thou shalt bind on earth shall be bound in heaven: and whatsoever thou shalt loose on earth shall be loosed in heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/16.13-19" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 16:13–19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p18" guid="87214910-698f-4351-a520-0e1c45ee5ad2" pid="BOmxeWLo70Cs_Eehx4bFRw" hash="Rh6mLw">In a day when churches are generally losing members and declining in popularity, many wonder what the secret is in the growth and stability of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p19" guid="d651afea-7526-4ca6-b0eb-ad6b3cf3950a" pid="BGGiMT_QJk25lKvXZ6XHhg" hash="IueYew">President McKay answered it: “The secret lies in the testimony, possessed by each individual who is faithful in the Church, that the Gospel consists of correct principles. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p20" guid="616c1867-564b-4550-8e1f-0f27ab3f6922" pid="zJ7WB5At5UabAnco5W3K_g" hash="TpCW6g">“This testimony has been revealed to every sincere man and woman who has conformed to the principles of the Gospel of Jesus Christ, who has obeyed the ordinances, and has become entitled to and has received the Spirit of God, the Holy Ghost, to guide him.” (<span class="emphasis">Pathways to Happiness </span>[Bookcraft, 1957], pp. 314–15.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p21" guid="b9523e29-d9f3-4cc2-9b00-c0380d2eedb2" pid="BOnTKoNYAESOtTLtyB7Qzg" hash="sUVbhQ">In an editorial in the <span class="emphasis">Impact </span>magazine, Brother William E. Barrett expressed well the great influence of the Holy Spirit in guiding and uniting the Church today:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p22" guid="7ffcd0ba-50f7-440d-b0ef-b6b6bd249000" pid="XO6mhZUbDU2P2cL2hbVtlw" hash="r4FV2g">“The great miracle of our day is that Spirit which unites the members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints with those multitudinous authorities appointed to lead them. For those appointed thus to lead speak a diversity of tongues, belong to a variety of races and cultures, and live in many different lands. Yet there is a unity which manifests itself in the obedience to Church calls, in the acceptance of basic doctrines, and in the belief that we are led by a living prophet of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p23" guid="8911d357-4072-4157-9039-09ef7e773b2b" pid="l64fKAIYvkCOTFfnPjsTZQ" hash="V6PeOQ">“This unity is baffling to the world generally and is not understood by many whose names grace the Church rolls. The unifying influence is none other than the Holy Ghost, bestowed upon men by the authority of God, through his holy priesthood. Through the work of the Holy Ghost, men may come to know the truth, as it springs forth from the printed pages of scripture or from the lips of our living prophets. In the words of Brigham Young, ‘the eloquence of angels never can convince any person that God lives, and makes truth the habitation of his throne, independent of that eloquence being clothed with the power of the Holy Ghost; in the absence of this, it would be a combination of useless sounds. What is it that convinces man? It is the influence of the Almighty, enlightening his mind, giving instruction to the understanding.’” (<span class="emphasis">Impact, </span>Spring 1970, p. 2.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p24" guid="f208ede2-f1bf-4a1e-a981-d9ab7a9ce607" pid="D8ySWWNEDEijLXys388DnQ" hash="pUApTQ">Every member of the Church is entitled to the companionship of the Holy Ghost. At the time of baptism, hands were placed upon our heads and it was said, “Receive the Holy Ghost.” Based upon our worthiness, this gives us the right to the constant companionship of the Holy Ghost in which we can receive its revelations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p25" guid="bcd04fa0-af4d-434b-a0e4-50928b842b89" pid="ryBiTSPyE0qzEgvGr_H2yA" hash="fmzh4Q">The blessings to those who have lived worthy of the companionship of the Holy Ghost were revealed to the Prophet Joseph Smith and Sidney Rigdon:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p26" guid="637d34f8-1975-4674-a3f1-36384d813687" pid="Xi3PFvbPLEWOL5C17aNbVA" hash="WTbJRg">“For thus saith the Lord—I, the Lord, am merciful and gracious unto those who fear me, and delight to honor those who serve me in righteousness and in truth unto the end.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p27" guid="8506f75f-a7b4-4184-8d8a-f1195f5467dc" pid="nAjMii80PESKxkc3P2lLgQ" hash="K_QM-w">“Great shall be their reward and eternal shall be their glory.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p28" guid="ac341c94-8bee-4cf1-b38c-ac99a6d04db9" pid="d720u1Xb4EG6rIGLXz5eEg" hash="qw3AJg">“And to them will I reveal all mysteries, yea, all the hidden mysteries of my kingdom from days of old, and for ages to come, will I make known unto them the good pleasure of my will concerning all things pertaining to my kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p29" guid="98e99def-4bd8-47fa-aa0b-54b61374d9bc" pid="qJWcLxMPkkqjXkooRH2-Cw" hash="n_sbPA">“Yea, even the wonders of eternity shall they know, and things to come will I show them, even the things of many generations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p30" guid="f21035ac-44d3-490d-8e3d-e8b768abdafb" pid="P-MtPAxzqE6bUvfcf3p6Qg" hash="qjxSwQ">“And their wisdom shall be great, and their understanding reach to heaven; and before them the wisdom of the wise shall perish, and the understanding of the prudent shall come to naught.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p31" guid="06aca393-502a-409a-88d0-406a0aee156e" pid="RoV2sn8u8E-WKCKDn_voyA" hash="MBs8uQ">“For by my Spirit will I enlighten them, and by my power will I make known unto them the secrets of my will—yea, even those things which eye has not seen, nor ear heard, nor yet entered into the heart of man.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.5-10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:5–10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p32" guid="ebb8961f-4ab9-4666-a34c-ffe33061fd44" pid="k1Hk0_9f9E-vYH3yZoKkvw" hash="eoL2Vw">And again the Lord told the Prophet:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p33" guid="8c495988-a312-49d0-83f0-af6877a7c057" pid="QSwFKvIg-kyIl7HuP87f7A" hash="DrIsug">“And the Spirit giveth light to every man that cometh into the world; and the Spirit enlighteneth every man through the world, that hearkeneth to the voice of the Spirit.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.46" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:46</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p34" guid="4f4d3804-0f20-466e-8e28-e779bb9389f6" pid="s-k1rrvR-ECiY9V5EquX0g" hash="xPIdUg">The Twelve Apostles are special witnesses of the Savior. I don’t know how many of them have actually seen a personage. They don’t talk about it. But they don’t have to, to receive their special witness that can come by the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p35" guid="3ca2d857-46bc-4d20-b629-a38d7fea489e" pid="ORwxltz6FEqBYzQL5fNPGw" hash="601WLA">President Harold B. Lee said to a group of young people, “Not many have seen the Savior face to face here in mortality, but there is no one of you who has been blessed to receive the gift of the Holy Ghost after baptism but that may have a perfect assurance of his existence as though you had seen.” (<span class="emphasis">Youth and the Church </span>[Deseret Book, 1970], p. 51.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p36" guid="cbaeaff6-710c-4087-a25b-b7ace04dc618" pid="mWgHvJdh4EqgLDm-bv-IbQ" hash="j5Jddw">The impact of the witness of the Spirit in our lives has been made clear by President Joseph Fielding Smith when he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p37" guid="6642e71f-bde5-4b3c-aa95-c6f00feae9ea" pid="I1RCaqGRSE2I9FnzstclkA" hash="Rb2VDQ">“… the Lord has taught that there is a stronger witness than seeing a personage, even of the Son of God, in a vision. … The Savior said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p38" guid="3105f01f-c449-4849-af0a-aa627482e47b" pid="3czhFHXUi0yUwRM0hLv2UA" hash="VAdZPA">“‘Wherefore I say unto you, All manner of sin and blasphemy shall be forgiven unto men: but the blasphemy against the Holy Ghost shall not be forgiven unto men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p39" guid="4e01b411-5d66-4b86-b0dc-25fcf2f0d459" pid="KJ1rn3vIO0yuY2pfcsqd_A" hash="BdWwzg">“‘And whosoever speaketh a word against the Son of Man, it shall be forgiven him: but whosoever speaketh against the Holy Ghost, it shall not be forgiven him. … neither in the world to come.’ [<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/12.31-32" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 12:31–32</a>.]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p40" guid="646a6643-53be-4a89-8c65-ccb1f8ad11ff" pid="GTPf7AYiRkevPfKivk9e_A" hash="XldXqA">“Therefore the seeing, even the Savior, does not leave as deep an impression in the mind as does the testimony of the Holy Ghost to the spirit. Both Peter and Paul understood this. Here are the words of Paul:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p41" guid="19b8788d-3501-4346-8291-62d5b9eff4df" pid="hT2QM0tUeEufg9HJJHmHyQ" hash="GGpZRQ">“‘For it is impossible for those who were once enlightened, and have tasted of the heavenly gift, and were made partakers of the Holy Ghost,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p42" guid="a6f18234-c0ee-4b2f-968e-4d6903162ce8" pid="CRZUQyxnVEyZ3hN1km4-yQ" hash="RPEQUQ">“‘And have tasted the good word of God, and the powers of the world to come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p43" guid="584b422e-8289-4a89-a8eb-0cab6e8e6314" pid="x-AuhUg3FESDegGunXvDhQ" hash="Pu5DGw">“‘If they shall fall away, to renew them again unto repentance; seeing they crucify to themselves the Son of God afresh, and put him to an open shame.’ [<a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/6.4-6" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 6:4–6</a>.]”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p44" guid="65d39607-4566-43fa-a801-5305097d6567" pid="JGnMsj9YzUiSuAJ_Df026Q" hash="N82i-g">President Smith concludes: “… the impressions on the soul that come from the Holy Ghost are far more significant than a vision. It is where Spirit speaks to spirit, and the imprint upon the soul is far more difficult to erase. Every member of the Church should have the impressions on his soul made by the Holy Ghost that Jesus is the Son of God indelibly pictured so that they cannot be forgotten.” (<span class="emphasis">Seek Ye Earnestly </span>[Deseret Book, 1970], pp. 213–14.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p45" guid="21a0b549-b10a-4cf8-9906-7ce243fa555f" pid="yf76mo8QFUWRZdpEvWdt5A" hash="mSlX3g">In our search for truth and in our pursuit of eternal life, the Lord has not left us without guidance. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p46" guid="3ed90696-7556-4eea-81ee-09141a80a2e7" pid="HaoovMD0k0eI_lEUhkZHYg" hash="zas3dw">“Oliver Cowdery, verily, verily, I say unto you, that assuredly as the Lord liveth, who is your God and your Redeemer, even so surely shall you receive a knowledge of whatsoever things you shall ask in faith, with an honest heart, believing that you shall receive. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p47" guid="8da4ea69-63b0-463b-bab2-e76b5e61eeb2" pid="pL5CTf9L-EirMelSACTsRw" hash="RQ9x-w">“Yea, behold, I will tell you in your mind and in your heart, by the Holy Ghost, which shall come upon you and which shall dwell in your heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p48" guid="b50fb9e5-3b0d-49e7-8a3e-03fbffb91b67" pid="S2B-Mme06kq1nSROpxVzbA" hash="6wBWow">“Now, behold, this is the spirit of revelation.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/8.1-3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 8:1–3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p49" guid="b644d37a-b169-4719-873a-7fc6e5104659" pid="FcgVnR-yXUSmyUNxkYtx2A" hash="Wjq0xQ">We need the companionship of the Spirit in our lives to continually confirm to us the divinity of the gospel plan. Two things are vital to the assurance of the companionship of the Spirit:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p50" guid="abd5ca46-0fb0-45a1-9391-7868c31928cf" pid="uV1nYY6bLk203kbJQhwUPg" hash="l65ZBw">1. Our lives must be in conformity to the gospel standards. “… the Spirit of the Lord doth not dwell in unholy temples.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/4.24" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 4:24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p51" guid="72227a76-e95c-4bf5-8b65-2d9f5d4e326c" pid="q0oAYdawa0KJ29LEiDNRXg" hash="DvHSUQ">2. We must be engaged in the work. As the Pharisees listened to the bold teachings of the Savior, they said: “How knoweth this man letters, having never learned?” He answered them: “If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it be of God, or whether I speak of myself.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/7.15,17" class="scriptureRef">John 7:15, 17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p52" guid="097fd4fa-2878-421b-a38a-b375d71fe13d" pid="t59ivC4-gEulm2t0Wmorvw" hash="vEvisA">The Lord plainly told the Prophet Joseph Smith how one might obtain a witness of him:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p53" guid="82b3a6ae-ae44-4a1e-bb7f-37353bd1c487" pid="023c1pscO029fh34F-wfLg" hash="fK7TJw">“Verily, thus saith the Lord: It shall come to pass that every soul who forsaketh his sins and cometh unto me, and calleth on my name, and obeyeth my voice, and keepeth my commandments, shall see my face and know that I am;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p54" guid="4b720409-a5a7-4f7d-a524-e3cd2dd55ac7" pid="vhhpp4XC6kKUfpX_pn1YOA" hash="GfkrEQ">“And that I am the true light that lighteth every man that cometh into the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.1-2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:1–2</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p55" guid="4b6a1d0b-2c4f-4219-a777-d9ce0b3cb39e" pid="InDXQshVCEaUMLGZH5RzsA" hash="72QUvw">Too often we ask the Lord for the direction of his Spirit before we’ve done all we can. The Lord gave Oliver Cowdery the key here when he attempted to translate and failed. He said: “But, behold, I say unto you, that you must study it out in your mind; then you must ask me if it be right, and if it is right I will cause that your bosom shall burn within you; therefore, you shall feel that it is right.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/9.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 9:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p56" guid="86916026-8d08-4e1b-8352-06e683997a7e" pid="wYQVf38PmUeiB8uBokdXNw" hash="1hj_xw">After we have done all we can, having studied it out and determined how best to solve our problems, then we take our decisions to the Lord; and if they are right, our bosoms will burn within us and we will have spiritual confirmation as to what to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p57" guid="ffc45645-7eae-47ed-a1d3-3ea88583e6a0" pid="3EpfAr4naE-GqsRUsSTQpw" hash="DvIj6A">The prophet Alma spoke regarding his testimony of certain gospel teachings. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p58" guid="262f32fc-5e07-400c-8ff9-78cf7a69df8d" pid="tK3TTb9A_E-S6w7dYwEzyg" hash="3cAGWQ">“And this is not all. Do ye not suppose that I know of these things myself? Behold, I testify unto you that I do know that these things whereof I have spoken are true. And how do ye suppose that I know of their surety?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p59" guid="2d5f4868-4a86-4d0f-87da-66fd13d36911" pid="zkKxB_bGUESD1VvuMdWhjg" hash="vMCMGw">“Behold, I say unto you they are made known unto me by the Holy Spirit of God. Behold, I have fasted and prayed many days that I might know these things of myself. And now I do know of myself that they are true; for the Lord God hath made them manifest unto me by his Holy Spirit; and this is the spirit of revelation which is in me.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.45-46" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:45–46</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p60" guid="673f5bb4-bf69-4d1b-8d07-a72ca67349ae" pid="59cK98Glj02Uzkl0LjEp3Q" hash="h4UJoA">Yes, “the Spirit enlighteneth every man that hearkeneth to the voice of the Spirit.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony.p61" guid="2fee06aa-cc2e-4d53-872f-1a679d2652e0" pid="IUPMtf-Gg0OlUivg7vAGIg" hash="Pn0fJg">I bear testimony that by the witness of the Spirit one can come to know of the divinity of this great work, that God lives, that Jesus is the Christ, that Joseph Smith was divinely called, that President Joseph Fielding Smith is a prophet of God, and that this gospel is the great plan of life and salvation as instituted of the Lord. This is my personal testimony to you, my brethren and sisters, and I leave it in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/04/the-importance-of-a-personal-testimony</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1972-general-conference/1972-04-2050-elder-james-a-cullimore-64k-eng.mp3" length="7531833" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home Teachers—Watchmen over the Church</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church?lang=eng</link>
      <description>What I have prepared to say today, my brethren and sisters, is directed primarily to the home teachers of the Church and those directing their work.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03027_000_7030" doc-version="2" hash="-JJbFg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="qtMJnmSycEGOaRtHojoExA" hash="NKAugQ">Home Teachers—</h1><p class="subtitle" pid="RYGZsCJH00Cg8zEdBLoS8w" hash="EpUd2A">Watchmen over the Church</p><p class="authorName" guid="d78a7914-5ab5-4be1-8fcd-fb376723c734" pid="1J0HB-5_R0KkiO_eq_TGjQ" hash="vveEig">James A. Cullimore</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="a3851e02-53f4-41cc-bb1a-bc4b24117fff">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p1" guid="cbfd6091-90a8-4eb3-b581-1e6a42db5711" pid="THqwM_7p1Eq8jOMv3YG-ZA" hash="wqhQHw">What I have prepared to say today, my brethren and sisters, is directed primarily to the home teachers of the Church and those directing their work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p2" guid="a09e5726-3cb9-40cf-9184-0f888135a8aa" pid="AiUBt3dn3UG-ZwCqNRtxzA" hash="VOv49g">Much has been given during these conference sessions about the family and the home and the importance of them by those who have spoken. It has been indicated, “The very essence of divine government is fatherhood and the recognition of the family relationship. The Church itself exists to exalt the family.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p3" guid="302392b6-1429-4c03-a31f-f778e99cce19" pid="qjvHiAEfBUu3sn4BeGIR4A" hash="n8r5AQ">President Joseph F. Smith told us, “The very foundation of the kingdom of God, of righteousness, of progress, of development, of eternal life, and eternal increase in the kingdom of God is laid in the divinely ordained home.” (Hugh B. Brown, in <span class="emphasis">Conference Report,</span> October 2, 1966, pp. 103–104.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p4" guid="7bb295ab-b50e-44cc-97cc-dbd95df5a58c" pid="GG-PVRjoM0qOgYsQAnx68Q" hash="K8MEgQ">President Harold B. Lee said recently, “The most important of the Lord’s work will be that which we do within our own homes.” (Regional Representatives Seminar, April 7, 1972, p. 2.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p5" guid="eb90a97d-d1ee-4f5c-8967-f42bc5e74ee8" pid="kzp9t1yLuEukzzSM2QqEeQ" hash="sBW3Ig">We are told that each family in the Church is really a kingdom or government within itself. The father, by virtue of the priesthood of God that has been bestowed upon him, is the head of that government. This is what constitutes patriarchal office in the family. Originally it was the only government on the earth and was passed down from Adam to his descendants. Eventually, as society became more complex, the manner of governing the people of the earth had to change, but as far as the Church is concerned, the same order exists within the families as God set it up originally with Father Adam. And this same order will extend into the eternities. (See <span class="emphasis">Millennial Star,</span> vol. 14, p. 290.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p6" guid="545eb32b-e40c-449e-91ef-0464905f3d2a" pid="fTpERWrJz0-x6d3rxIeBYA" hash="mJd7aw">The importance of the family was emphasized to the Prophet Joseph Smith even before the Church was organized. The Lord revealed to him a plan by which the priesthood was to watch over the Church. The Saints were instructed “to visit the house of each member, and exhort them to pray vocally and in secret and attend to all family duties.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.47" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:47</a>.) He told the teachers to “watch over the church always, and be with and strengthen them;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p7" guid="9197ffcd-c46c-45f3-83f9-ac0f0cd12090" pid="L3gpj5OYwkCegwFfSpvGaQ" hash="WD4W-w">“And see that there is no iniquity in the church, neither hardness with each other, neither lying, backbiting, nor evil speaking;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p8" guid="e3e558c6-b697-4a78-81c3-0bba979ee20d" pid="ZacptfE37k2cs4sf-Yn5ng" hash="oVWZ7Q">“And see that the church meet together often, and also see that all the members do their duty.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.53-55" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:53–55</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p9" guid="367f2e4b-659c-4d71-a53a-804766232f3c" pid="HliRJAltwkmc5tAybNFcow" hash="D2y7kQ">From that time forward, to a degree, all homes in the Church have been visited monthly. This was known as ward teaching.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p10" guid="62b1da93-db1a-40a0-a571-cd84e4896326" pid="p8DKRTDGG0KlhyGg7VtCAw" hash="_yevEw">In September 1963 home teaching was introduced to the Church. This differs from ward teaching in that greater emphasis is placed on watching over the family, rather than just making a monthly visit. Instructions have been given that the duty of the home teacher is to keep in touch with the families, to watch over them, to contact them in whatever manner necessary, in order to watch over them. We are told that home teaching is not just the one visit a month, but that home teaching is never done. We are to have concern for these families every day as long as they are assigned to us. The one visit a month to a family is important, but it is only one means of contact as we watch over our families.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p11" guid="60e93c94-7148-443e-aba8-cd9063d3ccdf" pid="c42446NP0UC48Rqmopg8Jg" hash="9DXLJA">On the occasion of the official introduction of the home teaching program, President Marion G. Romney suggested some of the challenges and opportunities of home teaching, in these words: “Through the program of priesthood correlation, we bearers of the priesthood must increase our efforts to encourage, teach, and inspire the Saints to become ‘partakers of the divine nature,’ … through obedience to the sanctifying principles of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p12" guid="aba79638-b035-4c89-b688-7770d5c1dcb4" pid="bjWL3o3roEGnT8SeMhWQSQ" hash="r2hz-A">“We are performing far below our potential in this matter. … Now, priesthood correlation, as we are using the term here, contemplates all that is now being done in ward teaching and much more. It unites under one undertaking many activities. It requires that attention be given to every member of every family, particularly to those who need special encouragement to live the gospel. It means much more than a perfunctory visit once a month. It includes:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p13" guid="0de5c3d8-e095-41ec-b030-b0da0c538016" pid="KBD4l1-xB0Cl4wfxwTr1_w" hash="hkRSDA">“1. Periodic visits to every family by two priesthood bearers:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p14" guid="503ad0c6-d5f0-41f0-8452-ac917f4c2b9f" pid="far7V-wcEUulXgYY18EwQQ" hash="b9nlcQ">“2. Laboring with Melchizedek Priesthood bearers [the fathers] to build spiritual and temporal ‘strength’;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p15" guid="fa8d8cd5-e4d3-492f-83a4-7b443301827a" pid="TmSzp1T01UeWCntmEytM_A" hash="vUZyXw">“3. Laboring with inactive and overage members of the Aaronic Priesthood under 21;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p16" guid="7708c67c-3c0d-42c5-9dea-b17a1202db77" pid="VxI14y0TQU61L11r3t8BXw" hash="7la1_w">“4. Activating and bringing into full church participation senior members of the Aaronic Priesthood and their families [now known as prospective elders]:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p17" guid="eae6e6e1-000e-426d-9780-b2b2baa3ea85" pid="SmtXfM0WSke1tVFa74L_Xg" hash="oxrxyQ">“5. Fellowshipping and bringing into full activity recent converts, new arrivals, and all inactive church members;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p18" guid="49691bce-c333-4fa1-887c-5d7f05cd64cb" pid="mKs6Nm7nAUGX5qLNcBjlxA" hash="qQVPJQ">“6. Encouraging all parents and other family heads to maintain genuine Latter-day Saint homes in which are practiced and taught the sanctifying principles of the gospel. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p19" guid="d76c5b9c-c181-42d6-9547-0652467c68d0" pid="u0MbZDHU-UuVUNg8LoRIQw" hash="7aOTyw">“It will be their [the home teachers’] responsibility,” President Romney continues, “to make sure that infants are blessed; that children are baptized at eight years of age; and that boys are worthy and qualified to be ordained to the priesthood at 12 years of age and that they are so ordained; that they move through the grades of the priesthood in proper order; that candidates for marriage are properly taught the importance and sanctity of temple marriage and the church standards which will qualify them for it, to the end that they will be married in the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p20" guid="3fcbfaf1-dfa9-4e02-9b12-f4f662784c18" pid="FZ5irFD2gUSdUeQGg_-liQ" hash="aDZ70g">“It will be the responsibility of the two visiting brethren to know the available church activities for each family member and encourage him to avail himself of them—such activities, for example, as Sacrament meetings, stake conferences, and other activities; activities provided by priesthood quorums, auxiliary organizations, … genealogical and temple work, and so forth.” (<span class="emphasis">Improvement Era, </span>December 1962, pp. 938–39.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p21" guid="43deab9f-4920-4d81-815c-47eac02d9b19" pid="NWTr1TLNq0qxlmXXxVQUHQ" hash="YKZZGw">This is really watching over the Church. After nine years of home teaching, however, I am afraid we are really still doing mostly ward teaching. We are still prodding the priesthood home teachers to “hurry and get your home teaching done—the month is nearly over.” Even now the home teacher is heard to say, “If I really had a message to take to my families, I could do my teaching.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p22" guid="68e0ea35-bcea-467b-a206-a2a71700af52" pid="e5ZZFNY9YE6C0ZxhTeg8CQ" hash="0cnhbQ">These things indicate we really don’t have the vision of “watching over the Church.” We might have a great record of percentage of homes visited each month, but the real test is: Are we affecting the lives of the individual members of the family for good through our contacts? Are we respecting the sacred nature of the family unit by working with and through the father? Do we sit down with the father as often as needed? Do we listen to him? Do we encourage and praise and otherwise uplift him?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p23" guid="02b8545d-8a21-4f8b-9128-cb59ac22f6bb" pid="dA17n2jsxk2wkqRpV731Aw" hash="VzTvVg">Our calling and opportunity as home teachers is to watch over and strengthen fathers of families; the Lord expects fathers and mothers first to teach the gospel to their families in regular family home evenings and daily as teaching opportunities arise. Home teachers may be asked to assist on special occasions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p24" guid="03ff34f5-e392-4783-87e8-3fdbd1628c46" pid="7fW9qtuOh0uleHSfKspXAQ" hash="_tcu5A">We have been counseled that the family, presided over by the priesthood holder, is the basic church unit. We know, as home teachers, that the order of the priesthood requires us to work with a family through the presiding authority in the family, the father. The father should be recognized in his position. The Lord holds him responsible for the righteous functions of his family in relation to other church units and for the conducting of his family into eternal life. The home teacher working with and through the father strengthens his role and responsibility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p25" guid="c887faa8-15a7-4ef5-8358-76d32c302c68" pid="sAIE4a9VVkqJrgJj7d-Rww" hash="Rz5aAA">Our thought as home teachers should always be: How can I help the fathers under my care magnify their priesthood by fully accepting their responsibilities as patriarchs of their families?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p26" guid="e97f1d1f-7a2d-4027-9755-d3ef2e2d826a" pid="6Vspwjtwg0iUbd3onsAyUQ" hash="GB8Kvw">We might put much effort into working with individuals in a family and eventually reach a child, but our real challenge is to work with the father in strengthening him that he might lead the entire family to celestial glory.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p27" guid="2ebb9749-f1f6-4092-a048-63eed64b94bd" pid="2AYa80LsEkeI6WeRGF0WIw" hash="2HBxAg">President Joseph F. Smith said, regarding the right of the father: “There is no higher authority in matters relating to the family organization, and especially when that organization is presided over by one holding the higher Priesthood, than that of the father. … The patriarchal order is of divine origin and will continue throughout time and eternity. There is then a particular reason why men, women, and children should understand this order and this authority in the household of the people of God, and seek to make it what God intended it to be, a qualification and preparation for the highest exaltation of His children. In the home the presiding authority is always vested in the father, and in all home affairs and family matters there is no other authority paramount.” (<span class="emphasis">The Juvenile Instructor,</span> March 1902, p. 146.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p28" guid="5dd906e1-8b10-4203-9c6f-11d3ea83dc93" pid="ulJfrG5ebU6kAkIS6Uo_iw" hash="ypH3XQ">There is great need for a fresh new look at ourselves as home teachers. How can we more nearly accomplish that which was intended by the Lord in the revelation to the Prophet Joseph Smith?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p29" guid="1945497a-3b51-4816-b3e2-20edaa6d5812" pid="7rC1VMPCGkyv5O3jqFdBww" hash="NTB5yA">I think President Lee sounded the note to the Regional Representatives of the Twelve last April when he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p30" guid="72fa83c4-8429-4a9f-ad62-3f5679f9d039" pid="4UQ5y6PWF0iJjydQnkTzIQ" hash="umVbBQ">“Maybe the home teacher should be charged more clearly to describe his mission to watch over and to strengthen to see that members do their duty. … They think themselves as teachers of the Gospel message only. Maybe we ought to be calling them home guardians or sentinels and to report their stewardship to the fathers of the ward. We must do something to change the emphasis from teaching to guardians, ‘watching over the church kind of concept.’ Until we get that into our minds, we are not going to do the kind of home teaching that is going to get results.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p31" guid="892fb2f6-42b6-44f8-b673-92b499581964" pid="jb32bvnzrUeXvCg1CApj-A" hash="vk-yLA">We need, at once, to catch the spirit of what President Lee has said and become priesthood guardians, priesthood watchmen, rather than teachers of the gospel only. We need to make sure home teachers are not guilty, after having made the one visit a month to each family, of relaxing, feeling good about it, and declaring our home teaching done for the month. Remember, home teaching is never done.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p32" guid="7abf5fef-4b03-41fa-98eb-d8b7ed34c031" pid="Lzt6RCUx9U6gFlafRbTEqA" hash="xNnCDQ">Brother Rex Reeve, one of the Regional Representatives of the Twelve, gave us some wonderful direction when he said: “Priesthood home teachers must think in terms of needs of the family, not just taking a message. When the priesthood home teacher can see souls—not just another home to visit—and when he can feel the needs of individuals and, in his heart, when he can love them and has a yearning to help, he can give courage to struggling souls as they try to climb homeward in these perilous times.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p33" guid="79a1afda-b2e1-4035-8e6c-850277efa8a6" pid="VeCl9YzqPEig5jIvdvuHsQ" hash="gGKpBw">“Priesthood home teaching is not just another program of the Church, something to get done so you can send the report in. It is a principle of action the vehicle by which all of the programs of the Church are taken to the family and the individual, and, in addition, it has the power to bless and guide and strengthen souls.” (Regional Representatives Seminar, December 12, 1970.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p34" guid="8f9a049e-8f98-4a97-ae75-f276119075da" pid="02aG87FfC0OHC6GKmwr3EQ" hash="1XahbA">When stake presidents, bishops, and priesthood leaders generally get the real concept and feeling of home teaching and let it be the vehicle by which all Church programs are taken to the family and the individuals, when families and individuals come to properly recognize and work with the home teachers, we will be able to give a much better account of ourselves in watching over the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p35" guid="cfa45b11-329d-41f1-8fa3-6544f801bc88" pid="T9Q4cG4ktUutwV91Hbj7KQ" hash="zM9q_A">The First Presidency many years ago stated, “The home [is] the basis of a righteous life and no other instrumentality can take its place or fulfill its essential functions.” (Cited by Elder Harold B. Lee, in CR, September 30, 1961, p. 79.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church.p36" guid="71cfdf52-bb38-4374-9f4b-98fc1d8ba95e" pid="P0c6utWmVkCRUrb06l_bhQ" hash="IWgtBA">May we better fulfill our assignment as home teachers by becoming guardians and watchmen over the families of the Church and thus strengthen them, I pray, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/10/home-teachers-watchmen-over-the-church</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1972-general-conference/1972-10-7030-elder-james-a-cullimore-64k-eng.mp3" length="6680150" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Be in the World but Not of the World</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In one of the most beautiful prayers ever offered, the Savior invoked the blessings of the Father upon his apostles. He sensed his time was near when he must leave them. He prayed:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03040_000_7040" doc-version="2" hash="z8zmYQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="wKKYlbe50EaSDdj2bTtfhg" hash="ZLbL8g">To Be in the World but Not of the World</h1><p class="authorName" guid="d78a7914-5ab5-4be1-8fcd-fb376723c734" pid="I7BdH0GQGkyzFZKVwOHXfg" hash="vveEig">James A. Cullimore</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="e54e1e1d-19f0-445a-be17-89db4d94efd2">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p1" guid="ea01791f-b214-4734-ab5e-2f1ffdf567cd" pid="JWq0pxh0B0-AtNDRuWkyGw" hash="2PWfZg">In one of the most beautiful prayers ever offered, the Savior invoked the blessings of the Father upon his apostles. He sensed his time was near when he must leave them. He prayed:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p2" guid="4aa68ca3-7ff7-4673-9241-f3f8ac17930e" pid="0cm-73cCTkyLB0Lf8YEIlg" hash="3FGW2A">“And now I am no more in the world, but these are in the world, and I come to thee. Holy Father, keep through thine own name those whom thou hast given me, that they may be one, as we are.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p3" guid="cef5c3c9-a971-4e77-b48a-a29b6eac0f92" pid="cqj5Ncu0cU-qhuibnueg_g" hash="1FXkQg">“I have given them thy word; and the world hath hated them, because they are not of the world, even as I am not of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p4" guid="6acb736b-f86f-42c3-bb32-11c4647c1641" pid="zlwdaIRODkqMIfkhVnm1IQ" hash="xuVTrg">“I pray not that thou shouldest take them out of the world, but that thou shouldest keep them from the evil.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.11,14-15" class="scriptureRef">John 17:11, 14–15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p5" guid="81f2ffa5-a332-41f1-80f0-9be4f46ea4db" pid="K2aE7rmWqE-TBT5hR805rg" hash="jrMQuA">The members of the Church are constantly being reminded that even though they are “<span class="emphasis">in</span> the world, they should not be <span class="emphasis">of</span> the world.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p6" guid="3c8ed5da-ba6b-453b-a8b5-5c6fa47a547a" pid="77xx95JzOECmUskNzio3GA" hash="flQjrQ">What do we mean by the “world”? President McKay refers to it as those “… alienated from the Saints of God. They are aliens to the Church, and it is the spirit of this alienation that we should keep ourselves free from.” (<span class="emphasis">Conference Report, </span>October 1911, p. 58.) Elder Bruce R. McConkie defines the “world” as “the social conditions created by such of the inhabitants of the earth as live carnal, sensuous, lustful lives, and who have not put off the natural man by obedience to the laws and ordinances of the gospel.” (Bruce R. McConkie, <span class="emphasis">Mormon Doctrine, </span>[Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1966], p. 847.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p7" guid="6978e0a8-548e-4d67-944d-5a1cab7c50f7" pid="uXJmLsGpo06dD2vl3GDhzA" hash="n5rqMw">John, in his epistle, describes the “world” as “the lust of the flesh, and the lust of the eyes, and the pride of life.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-jn/2.16" class="scriptureRef">1 Jn. 2:16</a>.) He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p8" guid="c6b25c90-1af9-4fa4-9792-889e95bfc180" pid="F8V3KQxg3UOQjgqksB_RAA" hash="W-evdA">“Love not the world, neither the things that are in the world. If any man love the world, the love of the Father is not in him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p9" guid="622b4ec9-d63f-4bbc-8276-431232d7a86b" pid="J0roTufQJE2rMx3iyFVsYw" hash="bB9cXw">“For all that is in the world, the lust of the flesh, and the lust of the eyes, and the pride of life, is not of the Father, but is of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p10" guid="f92798e2-54a1-475d-bb27-f6b1a27f5a87" pid="Gu3KDZ71uES1BEq1X8YqcA" hash="KE1oqQ">“And the world passeth away, and the lust thereof: but he that doeth the will of God abideth for ever.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-jn/2.15-17" class="scriptureRef">1 Jn. 2:15–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p11" guid="39136eb3-4966-4ba2-a309-c224fea0123c" pid="gxOoLi9JGUmf5mUodFD6Gw" hash="Qza7Vg">It is obvious the “world,” as referred to by the Savior, does not mean the sphere on which we live, but an environment created by individuals who live contrary to his teachings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p12" guid="30727588-9a1e-4fcc-8ba6-1ba897bb9a6d" pid="St0bC9yDSEi-IJAhWKPEBA" hash="LeDMag">Just as the Savior prayed that his apostles not be taken out of the world, but kept from the evil of the world, so are members of the Church everywhere praying that by the power of the Holy Ghost and the priesthood they may be strengthened to withstand the “world.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p13" guid="968309f8-8003-4e24-8c72-6d8bf87671cc" pid="Vk44YNzH0US4ABRObIgHjw" hash="jfzN3g">We would not want to be free of our responsibility of being in the world by being taken out of the world, for this life is a probationary state. The “world” is our opportunity to prove ourselves. This is a part of the great plan of the Lord, to be confronted with the things of the “world,” that we might overcome them and be strengthened.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p14" guid="63e7c75a-2c5f-4774-8c15-d0c8b0daeca8" pid="xLDJIYt_LkG4XjSOEqQ69Q" hash="_XVAig">As the Lord showed Abraham the creation of the earth, he said: “… We will go down, for there is space there, and we will take of these materials, and we will make an earth whereon these may dwell;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p15" guid="f08fe3ae-919b-473e-9502-72cc787ff406" pid="1vW5qx1gtkeCS-U8ZJnPaw" hash="Wrj8uA">“And we will prove them herewith, to see if they will do all things whatsoever the Lord their God shall command them.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.24-25" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:24–25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p16" guid="13a62a74-abcf-419f-8d41-b5df6c47201c" pid="tK18uvYat0elmgR3OsnO-Q" hash="9f6iVw">It is important that each of us overcome the “world.” “That every man may act in doctrine and principle pertaining to futurity, according to the moral agency which I have given unto him, that every man may be accountable for his own sins in the day of judgment,” says the Lord. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/101.78" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 101:78</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p17" guid="ac4d89cf-a8be-4b91-ad41-b691e65b7e73" pid="rT1EN1o6e0ujNG7EXPVLpA" hash="pd9ncg">Lehi taught, “For it must needs be, that there is an opposition in all things. If not so, … righteousness could not be brought to pass, neither wickedness, neither holiness nor misery, neither good nor bad. …” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.11" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p18" guid="2d6570f3-c51c-4438-9b7b-0b2c8fa75138" pid="9DHFF4GOrUmapWdtxeD2NA" hash="TczWUQ">It matters not what our nationality, our race, our culture, our academic degree, or our political or social standing. We build security and strength in our lives by living the gospel. President Joseph Fielding Smith said: “And there is no cure for the ills of the world except the gospel of the Lord Jesus Christ. Our hope for peace, for temporal and spiritual prosperity, and for an eventual inheritance in the kingdom of God is found only in and through the restored gospel.” (“Counsel to the Saints and to the World,” Joseph Fielding Smith, <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> July 1972, p. 27.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p19" guid="14c61b74-36e9-4777-bff5-88c732812791" pid="5lu6j8cq5EaJThEhs-J-WQ" hash="HncFpg">May I say to members of the Church everywhere, this is how we establish Zion where we live, by living the gospel, by being pure in heart, by being worthy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p20" guid="a4e3a5a0-6024-484e-8223-a9dea78afe83" pid="Mw-I4jCUjUaJaABF54yq-w" hash="MNLdtw">Zion is defined by the Lord as the “pure in heart.” The Lord said, “… let Zion rejoice, for this is Zion—<small>THE PURE IN HEART</small>; therefore, let Zion rejoice, while all the wicked shall mourn.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/97.21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 97:21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p21" guid="c5e6c825-dd3f-4092-a867-aa04b3625db4" pid="2BM2a9zez0mRzDw0O3Xzmw" hash="UfLmLA">Since Zion is defined as the “pure in heart,” those who make up Zion must be free from worldly practices and indulgences.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p22" guid="b81b7227-eaa7-4f85-9c63-854c3911f688" pid="SK_w2TLn_kGcQa0-70Tf8w" hash="WfQw-w">President Lee said to us in last April conference that “The rule by which the people of God must live in order to be worthy of acceptance in the sight of God” is indicated in this scripture: “For Zion must increase in beauty, and in holiness; her borders must be enlarged; her stakes must be strengthened; yea, verily I say unto you, Zion must arise and put on her beautiful garments.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/82.14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 82:14</a>.) (“Strengthen the Stakes of Zion,” Harold B. Lee, <span class="emphasis">Ensign, </span>July 1973, p. 3.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p23" guid="18b17f02-87d3-4f17-bf14-ff629b5c5fd9" pid="Y9jbCnb720erDtR__GeSJw" hash="xcLDCA">President McKay referred to Zion as the pure in heart and said: “… the strength of this Church lies in the purity of the thoughts and lives of its members, then the testimony of Jesus abides in the soul, and strength comes to each individual to withstand the evils of the world.” (<span class="emphasis">Conference Report, </span>October 1911, p. 58.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p24" guid="7dc5157b-816a-4bed-9ea8-d943f454a279" pid="swBCGZMyqUqi8OJqrkUs6g" hash="oSFKvA">The righteous lives of members of the Church throughout the world is a great leaven to the gospel loaf. There are many wonderful, honest men and women in the world whose lives are influenced by the teachings of the gospel, as seen in the virtuous lives of good members of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p25" guid="b91307fd-2668-45a3-959f-8ebdd99dbb96" pid="BB-Ljihjk0idBLAm5eFBBA" hash="-lrB3Q">Everything in the world is not evil. There are many things of virtue, many great men and women working for the finer things of life, who have high standards and live righteously. ‘Possibly a good definition of the world would be: “Exposure to things about us, whether good or bad—right or wrong.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p26" guid="bc139d2f-1e02-4d2d-aae5-cfbdbdef39de" pid="GVRjetPvJk6JVbE0eDznhw" hash="K20uKg">President Lee said on one occasion to the youth of the Church: “We don’t pray that you may be withdrawn into a ‘Shangri-la’ away from the evils of the world, because you are to be a leaven wherever you are, to bring about righteousness, but we are pleading with the Lord with all our might that while you are in the world, you may be kept from evil.” (Harold B. Lee, <span class="emphasis">Decisions for Successful Living </span>[Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1973], p. 223.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p27" guid="fd348380-fba9-47ed-bcc7-927c609a790c" pid="_33v2BvylUub-EsWvLHRBw" hash="CZ7nnA">There is a great challenge in living in the “world.” The concern is not where we live—but how we live. Obedience to the laws of the Lord will bring happiness and peace. We never need apologize for living the standards of the Church. Listen to two stalwart members of the Church who have proven this in their lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p28" guid="51fb2e72-97cf-4230-a8d9-58dce27cc419" pid="bt-t5mGM2UOtjBg2mlVH8Q" hash="sk421g">John K. Edmunds, now president of the Salt Lake Temple, was an outstanding attorney in Chicago for over a quarter of a century. He said, “During all my years in Chicago, I have never felt the necessity for indulging in alcohol, tobacco, tea, or coffee, nor have I ever served or kept these things in our home. And I have never felt the need to apologize for the observance of our church standards. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p29" guid="5b12d33d-fb0b-4111-8309-39f11850aeb5" pid="TdOX5jwqtU2FCb2rYUisHA" hash="Ht6hgQ">“I have found no magic formula for keeping the standards of the Church. To me the observance of these standards is a matter of the will. … God gives to every man and woman, to every boy and girl who sincerely desire it the power to keep his commandments. …” (“Living in the World without Being a Part of the World,” John K. Edmunds, <span class="emphasis">Improvement Era, </span>November 1965, p. 1053.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p30" guid="4dbbde5f-7eb0-451b-8248-0daa2881d87c" pid="smBUebc5kUed3edoXs-v_g" hash="IVyvIw">De Witt J. Paul, who is now serving as a mission president in California and who was an executive of one of the nation’s largest financial institutions, states:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p31" guid="eaf91923-1463-4a0e-8c7f-099d86d75109" pid="C5_LsbQKxUKTjG4rJ2NTWA" hash="sn9IzQ">“… Adhering to gospel standards has never stood in my way. Quite to the contrary, doing so has been an asset rather than a liability. Moreover, it has not been difficult or embarrassing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p32" guid="dedfccf7-5e48-4c44-b31b-5546969b22e3" pid="tp78o0Yk9UeY252jE0gJfQ" hash="1p0W6Q">“In a world of rather wishy-washy convictions, one who believes in something and lives in accordance with his beliefs is usually admired and respected. I never appreciated this so much as when the chairman of the board of directors of my company one day said to the board members: ‘I am retiring, and I propose Mr. Paul as my successor. As you know, Mr. Paul is a Mormon. Mormons have rather high standards to live by, and among other things they do not smoke or drink. I have kept an eye on this fellow for many years now, and never once have I seen him make a slip. I recommend him to you as a man of integrity. …’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p33" guid="5848a65b-a38c-40b4-89c9-854cddd3d990" pid="6kWW6bwh6kmLihAHgSqLeg" hash="NIw4Ww">“It is my experience that there are a lot of very fine people in the world. Just because they do not have my outlook on life has never given me reason to alienate them through prudish self-righteousness. Perhaps herein lies the secret of ‘living in the world without being a part of the world.’” (“Living in the World without Being a Part of the World,” De Witt J. Paul, <span class="emphasis">Improvement Era, </span>September 1965, p. 838.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p34" guid="43270d95-ef36-479a-960f-36a3415a488c" pid="hEXkMaxLIkyK4_1kdNjT4A" hash="hMThkg">We are living in the most glorious time since the creation of the world. Never before has man been able to do so many remarkable things, see and know so much of the world, have so many conveniences, enjoy so many luxuries.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p35" guid="c3e2bb90-a045-447f-88ed-33c350ae5042" pid="bRi65tCiw0yv_09XPMjc9w" hash="cQj3Dw">We are living in the Dispensation of the Fulness of Times, in which the Lord has said: “… in the which I will gather together in one all things, both which are in heaven, and which are on earth.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/27.13" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 27:13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p36" guid="2208c1aa-a9aa-4b31-adc6-029b6a770775" pid="Zo7R6SkCMUKvurLW_fNl8g" hash="fT52iA">He said further, “For I deign to reveal unto my church things which have been kept hid from before the foundation of the world, things that pertain to the dispensation of the fulness of times.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/124.41" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 124:41</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p37" guid="b378fa21-db93-43e1-88c4-613e0fd71dcb" pid="idGQoaypE0OX0bdBtZRz1Q" hash="wxzFfg">The prophet Joel prophesied of the times in which we live when he said, “And it shall come to pass afterward, that I will pour out my spirit upon all flesh; and your sons and your daughters shall prophesy, your old men shall dream dreams, your young men shall see visions:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p38" guid="2e589962-757f-4d47-9386-f5863132038b" pid="hJyOpPgFh0Sp_RjT3xYDqA" hash="vdUF4Q">“And also upon the servants and upon the handmaids in those days will I pour out my spirit. And I will shew wonders in the heavens and in the earth. …” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/joel/2.28-30" class="scriptureRef">Joel 2:28–30</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p39" guid="cfee0cad-b6ef-4727-ac16-c026b5f80037" pid="bq1Xj8ZUgkayeDV9S55uiA" hash="8RxmGg">The Lord has already commenced to pour out his spirit upon all flesh. Since the restoration of the gospel, the Spirit of the Lord has inspired men in the world to accomplish things almost unbelievable to those who behold them. We are able to travel all over the world at incredible speed. Inventions too numerous to mention bless the lives of the inhabitants of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p40" guid="f588ad20-8dcc-44e5-a7fb-4d4ed4567a42" pid="oQZe5xoPt02A_Sosw2uLIw" hash="BlOhxQ">President Wilford Woodruff described this day when he said, “The day has already dawned when the light of heaven is to fill the earth; the day in which the Lord has said that nothing should be kept hidden, … the day in which everything that has been kept from the knowledge of man ever since the foundation of the earth, must be revealed; … It is a day in which the gospel is to be preached to every nation, tongue and people for a witness of what shall follow. …” (<span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses, </span>vol. 24, p. 51.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p41" guid="c27cb5fb-6626-46e9-9c0b-13e264d2c65e" pid="cxmDuyVwHE6q7U_p5WJ2Dg" hash="_EYaIg">The Prophet Joseph wrote an editorial in the <span class="emphasis">Times and Seasons </span>in May 1842 regarding the purpose of the Church in which he indicated the great joy of living in this day:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p42" guid="08d8c351-1551-44dd-967e-b138f4a01aa7" pid="kKH4005USUqWQBGxCjL4fA" hash="R8FzuQ">“The building up of Zion is a cause that has interested the people of God in every age; it is a theme upon which prophets, priests, and kings have dwelt with peculiar delight; they have looked forward with joyful anticipation to the day in which we lived; and fired with heavenly and joyful anticipations, they have sung, and wrote, and prophesied of this our day;—but they died without the sight. …” (<span class="emphasis">Times and Seasons, </span>vol. 3, p. 776.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world.p43" guid="20cb364a-383f-439b-b888-e9b703e65200" pid="n3SHl_Aucki-dT69L5yT-g" hash="CLVYhA">May we appreciate the privilege that is ours in living in this time, in the beautiful, wonderful world in which we live. May we let the gospel light guide us that we may be in the world and yet not partake of the evil of the world. I so ask in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1973/10/to-be-in-the-world-but-not-of-the-world</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1973-general-conference/1973-10-7040-elder-james-a-cullimore-64k-eng.mp3" length="6352858" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 1973 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justice and Mercy</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I would like to direct your attention, my brethren and sisters, to the principles of mercy and justice. I have taken my text today from the Proverbs of Solomon: “My son, despise not the chastening of the Lord; neither be weary of his correction:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03044_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="V6uwsQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="U3Or5QdF20qRh047dgcxWw" hash="S5ZE3w">Justice and Mercy</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="rOr5cBsuXEq1BiN7K2WDYw" hash="vveEig">James A. Cullimore</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p1" pid="HPHC53LZ4EueEv2duOywVA" hash="z9h_4A">I would like to direct your attention, my brethren and sisters, to the principles of mercy and justice. I have taken my text today from the Proverbs of Solomon: “My son, despise not the chastening of the Lord; neither be weary of his correction:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p2" pid="62Tz7t4jUUO9nFU5uB12vQ" hash="qtGoPQ">“For whom the Lord loveth he correcteth; even as a father the son in whom he delighteth.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/3.11-12" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 3:11–12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p3" pid="1jAfitiT7USCu21Xivd0tg" hash="y9SBog">The Lord found it necessary to call to the attention of some of the brethren in the early days of the Church their negligence in doing all that they should. To the Prophet Joseph, he said: “… I have commanded you to bring up your children in light and truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p4" pid="wTkV3DHLgUKzfm5xq77Xqw" hash="7H8TgQ">“But verily I say unto you, my servant Frederick G. Williams, … You have not taught your children light and truth, according to the commandments; and that wicked one hath power … over you. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p5" pid="nBREMI64ekSf0G7mu1BjnA" hash="jlvGpg">“Verily, I say unto my servant Sidney Rigdon, that in some things he hath not kept the commandments concerning his children; therefore, first set in order thy house. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p6" pid="JEvEc7LAvEu9zagNOavq1A" hash="awlPDA">“My servant Newel K. Whitney also … hath need to be chastened, and set in order his family, and see that they are more diligent and concerned at home, and pray always, or they shall be removed out of their place.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.40-42,44,50" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:40–42, 44, 50</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p7" pid="tr4rT09JU0SmRC-iczW5hw" hash="KrsNkA">When the Prophet Joseph reluctantly permitted Martin Harris to take part of the manuscript of the Book of Mormon, and they were lost, the Lord reproved the Prophet for his disobedience. He said, “The works, and the designs, and the purposes of God cannot be frustrated, neither can they come to naught.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p8" pid="YXrkOusHn0KVudxDEUcXwg" hash="QRosQA">“For God doth not walk in crooked paths, neither doth he turn to the right hand nor to the left, neither doth he vary from that which he hath said, therefore his paths are straight, and his course is one eternal round.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p9" pid="VDdL46HPn0ONB-YWfKs3Vg" hash="rJ1Lig">“Remember, remember that it is not the work of God that is frustrated, but the work of men;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p10" pid="nh0lim-KukORyuA49jaing" hash="i5cmlg">“For although a man may have many revelations, and have power to do many mighty works, yet if he boasts in his own strength, and sets at naught the counsels of God, and follows after the dictates of his own will and carnal desires, he must fall and incur the vengeance of a just God upon him. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p11" pid="R6YnF3_psEmTfP-d4i_4zQ" hash="9wEQrA">“For, behold, you should not have feared man more than God. Although men set at naught the counsels of God, and despise his words—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p12" pid="_ak__95Jd0S42pnd79F55Q" hash="_MqnSg">“Yet you should have been faithful; and he would have extended his arm and supported you against all the fiery darts of the adversary; and he would have been with you in every time of trouble. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p13" pid="6i93xmY_dEiHtbr-TMBKpw" hash="1hSXKA">“But remember, God is merciful; therefore, repent of that which thou hast done which is contrary to the commandment which I gave you, and thou art still chosen, and art again called to the work.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/3.1-4,7-8,10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 3:1–4, 7–8, 10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p14" pid="sfEl46UPXEmxIW3M-hm1XQ" hash="h3zo5g">One of the basic concepts of forgiveness is that one must be truly repentant, having satisfied justice before forgiveness can take place. The Prophet Joseph said: “There should be no license for sin, but mercy should go hand in hand with reproof.” (<span class="emphasis">Documentary History of the Church,</span> vol. 5, p. 24.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p15" pid="zJ9hq5THAEmG4OwCV3xK4w" hash="1Pplcg">President Kimball has said: “There are many people who seem to rely solely on the Lord’s mercy rather than on accomplishing their own repentance. … The Lord may temper justice with mercy, but he will never supplant it. Mercy can never replace justice. God is <span class="emphasis">merciful,</span> but he is also <span class="emphasis">just.</span>” (Spencer W. Kimball, <span class="emphasis">The Miracle of Forgiveness,</span> Bookcraft, 1969, p. 358.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p16" pid="8rp6EtowOUibhFscKuv0jA" hash="WrRfzw">An eternal aspect of justice has been decreed by divine law, that “… God is not mocked: for whatsoever a man soweth, that shall he also reap.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/gal/6.7" class="scriptureRef">Gal. 6:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p17" pid="I8yM2sqQIUWmhdsubb7N6A" hash="7McWXw">The gospel of Jesus Christ is founded on law for the salvation and blessing of its people. For every law the Lord gives us, there is also a penalty for its violation. The prophet Alma explained this very plainly: “Now,” he said, “how could a man repent except he should sin? How could he sin if there was no law? How could there be a law save there was a punishment?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/42.17" class="scriptureRef">Alma 42:17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p18" pid="xIiHXZNQMkicq0iwIyv7fA" hash="6ijIbw">President Stephen L Richards said: “The Savior himself declared that he came to fulfill the law, not to do away with it, but with the law he brought the principle of mercy to temper its enforcement, and to bring hope and encouragement to [the] offenders for forgiveness through repentance.” (<span class="emphasis">CR,</span> April 1954, p. 11.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p19" pid="IA4GCYvFGkyDvKK8ZdolXQ" hash="0KJETA">God’s laws, as given for the government of the Church, must be supported and endorsed to win salvation and respect of those within the Church and without. The bishops of the Church have been designated as common judges and, together with their counselors, are authorized to deal with cases of serious transgression coming under their jurisdiction. Other cases go before the high council court under the direction of the stake president. These judges are expected to deal with all cases of infraction against the laws of the Church mercifully and justly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p20" pid="3kHPQH1mFkWfbaR9FoaJAA" hash="mrlhtw">I’m sure the most difficult problem for the priesthood leaders to determine and for the transgressor to understand is: When does repentance become effective? When are the demands of justice satisfied? When does the principle of mercy take over? I suppose there is no answer as clear as that given by Alma:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p21" pid="160O82etz0SjgNItP5i48Q" hash="JI4pzQ">“For behold, justice exerciseth all his demands, and also mercy claimeth all which is her own; and thus, none but the truly penitent are saved.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p22" pid="wBNLBE4-BEyC4vs5LcUKDw" hash="sB2kjA">“What, do ye suppose that mercy can rob justice? I say unto you, Nay; not one whit. If so, God would cease to be God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/42.24-25" class="scriptureRef">Alma 42:24–25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p23" pid="xl_3vhKn_ECbQ9aRoNAAGw" hash="H3hHuw">How plain, then, is the logic as to the necessity of taking appropriate action in case of serious transgression. The need is to cleanse the Church and to help to bring about full repentance to the individual.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p24" pid="lyKsYxC17UyZpAOdpMomcw" hash="8ArN3A">President Lee said as he spoke to the Brethren in 1972: “Now, this doesn’t mean when we have to take action that we turn our backs on him who has sinned, … we don’t do [that]—we should try not to do it. But we have to be like fathers—sometimes we have to discipline … , we have to spank them, then we have to love them. It is the doctrine of the Lord, and we should do that in kindness. It seems to me, that there comes a time in the lives of those who have sinned so seriously that, short of disciplinary action, I think some men can’t repent until they are turned over to the buffetings of Satan by the loss of the Spirit of the Lord.” (Priesthood Board Meeting, March 1, 1972, p. 12.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p25" pid="3QYITaQl1UC3Q0GTqZjvlg" hash="EQX_Tg">President Stephen L Richards has said: “What good to the Church, what real benefit to erring members, can come from ignoring this obligation, and as we sometimes say, winking at and ‘white-washing’ the offenders? Can the judges thus help in setting people on the way to repentance and forgiveness?” (<span class="emphasis">CR,</span> April 1954, p. 11.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p26" pid="XYsgn77aQUin0M0HwJsNKg" hash="DHdsyA">Many who have violated the laws of the Lord feel unjustly dealt with if they are called before proper Church courts and appropriate action is taken in reference to their transgressions. Many priesthood leaders, whose responsibility it is to watch over the Church and take action in cases of serious transgression, are remiss in convening courts and taking action that one might be put in a position where he can be forgiven. What might be thought to be a kindness in not taking proper action may really be the most unkind thing that could have been done.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p27" pid="cfOT9R2jDEabLX8Nx_HALQ" hash="cfgFQg">President Lee has said: “Never must we allow supposed mercy to the unrepentant sinner to rob the justice by which the true repentance from sinful practices is predicated.” (<span class="emphasis">Strengthening the Home,</span> 1973, p. 5.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p28" pid="trwxq2HoGEW1QPE-MmgEDA" hash="OOcSAg">How then, does forgiveness become operative? When is repentance recognized?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p29" pid="JzlfxthKAE2u5mB8uJV8Ig" hash="rdiOZg">True godly sorrow, which the scriptures tell us “worketh repentance to salvation … ,” is the first step in repentance. (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-cor/7.10" class="scriptureRef">2 Cor. 7:10</a>.) Confession of sins logically follows godly sorrow, prompted by an earnest desire for relief from the suffering brought about by positive realization of wrongdoing. Confession should be made to demonstrate one’s humility and his determination to make restitution for the transgressions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p30" pid="gkXd0DC_8kK_kt_AtG41Fg" hash="2M80GA">To whom should confession be made? To quote President Richards, “To the Lord, of course, whose law has been violated. To the aggrieved person or persons, as an essential in making due retribution if that is necessary. And then certainly to the Lord’s representative, his appointed judge in Israel, under whose ecclesiastical jurisdiction the offender lives and holds membership in the Kingdom.” (<span class="emphasis">CR,</span> April 1954, pp. 11–12.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p31" pid="k_eZqVl3QkW8Gg-y_hqUxQ" hash="EWkjaQ">Closely associated with confession is the matter of probation—of demonstration. The Lord said: “By this may ye know if a man repenteth of his sins—behold, he will confess them and forsake them.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.43" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:43</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p32" pid="oF_cOGAluE2WxhN1e3vT3w" hash="Fn6eEg">How may the judge know when repentance is adequate? The individual might become impatient as he demonstrates his repentance. But it has been said that “sufficient time [should] elapse to permit a period of probation for the one seeking forgiveness. This probation serves a double purpose: First, … it enables the offender to determine for himself whether he has been able to so master himself as to trust himself in the face of ever-recurring temptation; and secondly, to enable the judges to make a more reliable appraisement of the genuineness of repentance and worthiness for restored confidence.” (<span class="emphasis">CR,</span> April 1954, p. 12.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p33" pid="jEbRe8lL5UqmqqSfe5OQVw" hash="A2dhZw">Yes, “for whom the Lord loveth he correcteth; even as a father the son in whom he delighteth.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/3.12" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 3:12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p34" pid="216JRQxGkUqTm0KT8iPP6Q" hash="FdXCcQ">“For God so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son, that whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.16" class="scriptureRef">John 3:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p35" pid="vqtX2uZBwU-w2dZynXUJEw" hash="Ii0qBQ">Were it not for the atonement of Jesus Christ, in which he assumed our sins on condition of our repentance, man could not be forgiven. Even though we were offered mercy, yet justice must be satisfied for he cannot save us in our sins.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p36" pid="ihlxZgBhc0e3aKjtYvEmgA" hash="UUJ8Xg">Alma explained to his son Corianton God’s role in the principle of mercy and justice:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p37" pid="S2Mnu-DbrUWEqcw645T1tQ" hash="Ut7HNw">“But there is a law given,” he said, “and a punishment affixed, and a repentance granted; which repentance mercy claimeth; otherwise, justice claimeth the creature and executeth the law, and the law inflicteth the punishment; and if not so, the works of justice would be destroyed, and God would cease to be God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p38" pid="ZNyCuxYHZU6F-Vs07HfozA" hash="aSw6xA">“But God ceaseth not to be God, and mercy claimeth the penitent, and mercy cometh because of the atonement; and the atonement bringeth to pass the resurrection of the dead; and the resurrection of the dead bringeth back men into the presence of God; and thus they are restored into his presence, to be judged according to their works, according to the law and justice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p39" pid="C1m8MhEKn0ep3zpPhh5j5Q" hash="JI4pzQ1">“For behold, justice exerciseth all his demands, and also mercy claimeth all which is her own; and thus, none but the truly penitent are saved.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p40" pid="gkURNyHmNUuNFkzAaO31RA" hash="VWIqDQ">“What, do ye suppose that mercy can rob justice? I say unto you, Nay; not one whit. If so, God would cease to be God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/42.22-25" class="scriptureRef">Alma 42:22–25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p41" pid="-Bgd_odcVEabA4WYltFHWQ" hash="UdwF9w">The prophet Alma said, in recounting the words of Amulek, “… If ye will repent, and harden not your hearts, then will I have mercy upon you, through mine Only Begotten Son;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p42" pid="esgbRNk01EynT5P0u98fDQ" hash="-dZXmQ">“Therefore, whosoever repenteth, and hardeneth not his heart, he shall have claim on mercy through mine Only Begotten Son, unto a remission of his sins; and these shall enter into my rest.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/12.33-34" class="scriptureRef">Alma 12:33–34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy.p43" pid="eot83eVTRUGneiMJrSl_-w" hash="q5i2jA">May we so enjoy the blessings of the gospel. I leave you my testimony of the divinity of this great work in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/04/justice-and-mercy</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1974-general-conference/1974-04-2060-elder-james-a-cullimore-64k-eng.mp3" length="11488563" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 1974 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gifts of the Spirit</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Among the sure signs of the true church of Christ are the accompanying spiritual gifts. This has always been from the beginning. When the authority of the priesthood has been found on the earth, it is accompanied by the manifestations of spiritual gi</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03050_000_011" doc-version="2" hash="HMmbUw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="-d34gX_XfEi0Bt6mZKJxAg" hash="aYFZiw">Gifts of the Spirit</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="LmB0ht9-UUKeApaofaHz4Q" hash="vveEig">James A. Cullimore</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-28aa.jpg" alt="Elder James A. Cullimore" pid="RfxMu5C7tk-jndKeqLL9rg" hash="u_okMA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p1" pid="HPZw_nqPHEaUw61NhqTxTQ" hash="HnIxww">Among the sure signs of the true church of Christ are the accompanying spiritual gifts. This has always been from the beginning. When the authority of the priesthood has been found on the earth, it is accompanied by the manifestations of spiritual gifts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p2" pid="ucm-DgnRtEaTMPu1bAKpLQ" hash="5901yQ">During the earthly ministry of the Savior, it is recorded that he “went about all Galilee, … healing all manner of sickness and all manner of disease among the people.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/4.23" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 4:23</a>.) “And great multitudes followed him, and he healed them all.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/12.15" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 12:15</a>.) Before the Savior departed from his apostles after his resurrection, “he said unto them, Go ye into all the world, and preach the gospel to every creature.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p3" pid="Fff3bMOdhUaiWq19bU0KyQ" hash="Edq0dQ">“He that believeth and is baptized shall be saved; but he that believeth not shall be damned.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p4" pid="xqRTodNLN02OGBBE4r3vyQ" hash="yeyLRQ">“And these signs shall follow them that believe; In my name shall they cast out devils; they shall speak with new tongues;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p5" pid="xQj86GlJO0q7Is26ix3flw" hash="_kxUGQ">“They shall take up serpents; and if they drink any deadly thing, it shall not hurt them; they shall lay hands on the sick, and they shall recover.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/16.15-18" class="scriptureRef">Mark 16:15–18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p6" pid="N6m4GiWMhUKUek0GQzo33A" hash="0awaCQ">“And by the hands of the apostles were many signs and wonders wrought among the people. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p7" pid="z7PR7iOaA0iqQZtZk36P2A" hash="3Y1kEA">“Insomuch that they brought forth the sick into the streets, …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p8" pid="WyK1PRcWhk-KR2PwICYZrg" hash="Dw0Rdw">“… and them which were vexed with unclean spirits: and they were healed every one.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/5.12,15-16" class="scriptureRef">Acts 5:12, 15–16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p9" pid="lUo5B2v2EkqqjZZpginGHQ" hash="Ucvp4g">The apostle Paul said to the Corinthian saints:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p10" pid="1CZ3UaqGhEqGM-l-aeCQCA" hash="gPLg7Q">“Now concerning spiritual gifts, brethren, I would not have you ignorant. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p11" pid="81Ob97oviUuJPrbsgN4byw" hash="9SqN_w">“Wherefore I give you to understand, that no man speaking by the Spirit of God calleth Jesus accursed: and that no man can say that Jesus is the Lord, but by the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p12" pid="k29lN01rukGCdWBTteELSg" hash="qlsKzw">“Now there are diversities of gifts, but the same Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p13" pid="MGM2LGdljkyQbyPYcood8g" hash="TEFEdg">“And there are differences of administrations, but the same Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p14" pid="eyqEMUr6_06SB8awkw2Xlg" hash="eRUVWQ">“And there are diversities of operations, but it is the same God which worketh all in all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p15" pid="mbgc3LCg4k66WuhWc0FN9Q" hash="N-bkQQ">“But the manifestation of the Spirit is given to every man to profit withal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p16" pid="VbmKlu_37UarvwAhkOWwtw" hash="L3p2Jw">“For to one is given by the Spirit the word of wisdom; to another the word of knowledge by the same Spirit.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/12.1,3-8" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 12:1, 3–8</a>.) And he stated the many gifts of the Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p17" pid="wy5NTMQCkUCn4V9VsftUrA" hash="CQ7nqA">And unto his church in this dispensation the Savior promised these same gifts. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p18" pid="bu2xPwm18k-k41rkuFB39Q" hash="N4XlEA">“Therefore, as I said unto mine apostles I say unto you again, that every soul who believeth on your words; and is baptized by water for the remission of sins, shall receive the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p19" pid="xVFSooiKjkmjnjwWglu9cQ" hash="WbF8wA">“And these signs shall follow them that believe—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p20" pid="L5td5u_0wECnjm1sTVh2OQ" hash="2kXWoQ">“In my name they shall do many wonderful works;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p21" pid="83s2cHwns02hHWhKYXMURA" hash="3Rtuzg">“In my name they shall cast out devils;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p22" pid="8FjxQNUD4ki2mSR-h4Ouww" hash="Df2nUw">“In my name they shall heal the sick;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p23" pid="Q6hlHd2tcEmauQ7iu7pU6Q" hash="AgM7PA">“In my name they shall open the eyes of the blind, and unstop the ears of the deaf;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p24" pid="c5ZZyNfyB0-uR0q71bCVUA" hash="iHM55Q">“And the tongue of the dumb shall speak.” And so on. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.64-70" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:64–70</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p25" pid="dKv0C5wmSUu6443riTlUDw" hash="2KdLXA">I bear my solemn witness that these gifts are with the Church today. The sick are healed, the eyes of the blind are opened, the ears of the deaf are unstopped, the lame are made to walk. The gift of tongues blesses our missionaries and others the world over. The gifts of wisdom and knowledge are evidenced by the leadership of our people everywhere. Devils are cast out, spirits are discerned, the gift of faith is demonstrated on every side. Many mighty miracles give evidence that this is indeed his church, the church of Jesus Christ. All the gifts and powers and blessings that have always identified Christ’s church are with the Church today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p26" pid="-90T_z3qxEe_3XdThJvnsw" hash="HNSPGA">As members of the Church, is our faith sufficiently strong? Are we in tune with the Spirit that we might be blessed by these great gifts? Do we believe a miracle can be performed or a blessing given? Do we call upon the priesthood as often as we should to administer to the sick? Do we believe we can be healed? Do we have faith to heal? Is the priesthood always prepared to give a blessing? How strong is your faith?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p27" pid="sVHkvCSO7EarH5J8_bdv6w" hash="R43w6w">President George Q. Cannon said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p28" pid="NwM87_Bq30SjHgXXX0IgSA" hash="h-aMJg">“I have felt deeply impressed … that the members of our Church do not value as they should the means which God has placed within their reach for the relief and healing of the sick.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p29" pid="raNyRUTE4UecA7kxaFxghg" hash="y70Ufw">“There is too great a disposition, when sickness enters a household, to send for a doctor. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p30" pid="670FaQyUOEuvYeUrVoOjoQ" hash="IZC0Nw">“Instances are very common among the faithful Saints of the gift of healing being manifested in a very wonderful manner. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p31" pid="6xlF8qC95EGNLZHFxDjiHw" hash="QGPtpQ">“God has not forgotten His promises, and He has not withdrawn Himself from His people. But the Latter-day Saints should make use of these means more frequently than they do, and put more trust in God and less in man’s skill.” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Truths,</span> comp. Jerrald L. Newquist, Deseret Book, 1974, 2:186–87.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p32" pid="rw15iyPXaUmmlJiJ1OWlWw" hash="rPTSuw">We have been instructed as to the administration of the sick:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p33" pid="H0sHcFAC00KXYO0-v7cdRQ" hash="XPBreA">“Is any sick among you? let him call for the elders of the church; and let them pray over him, anointing him with oil in the name of the Lord:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p34" pid="xAba-mG5502daGvYybgyYQ" hash="0tsOAw">“And the prayer of faith shall save the sick, and the Lord shall raise him up; and if he have committed sins, they shall be forgiven him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p35" pid="G_yTuuyk7067y0Bn9KLwoA" hash="4Afz0A">“Confess your faults one to another, and pray one for another, that ye may be healed.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/5.14-16" class="scriptureRef">James 5:14–16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p36" pid="PtHukHtf40i7GS8QRdSJ1g" hash="kTIedQ">“And the elders of the church, two or more, shall be called, and shall pray for and lay their hands upon them in my name; and if they die they shall die unto me, and if they live they shall live unto me.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.44" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:44</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p37" pid="CzVsxKOoP0SmLEApGTrdwA" hash="D2-sog">The accounts of miraculous healings in the Church are numerous. They warm one’s soul and give great strength of testimony as to the divinity of this great work. But the Lord has instructed us that we are not to boast of these great blessings. He said, “But a commandment I give unto them, that they shall not boast themselves of these things, neither speak them before the world; for these things are given unto you for your profit and for salvation.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.73" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:73</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p38" pid="yFmhWO3c70qoB8MOiRDaoQ" hash="axQc1g">It was not intended that we make merchandise out of the gifts of God and shout to the world the result of these most wonderful gifts. They are given to us for our salvation, to strengthen our testimony and the testimonies of others as we bear humble witness of them in our meetings, quietly, by the Spirit but not before the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p39" pid="bHdyX_jZPUysh2XKfizaDA" hash="0aT2UA">“Behold, faith cometh not by signs, but signs follow those that believe.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p40" pid="HNq4_iVrZEamMkRxHJW3Tg" hash="zFdUIw">“Yea, signs come by faith, not by the will of men, nor as they please, but by the will of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/63.9-10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 63:9–10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p41" pid="UQ6vNDuSwkCy9kx-FNJMHA" hash="kj-rxg">Faith to heal the sick is one of the most desirable gifts of the gospel and should be sought after by all Melchizedek Priesthood holders. They should always be ready to exercise this power in behalf of those who need a blessing. They should seek to have and develop the gift of faith, faith to heal and faith to be healed. “And whoso shall ask it in my name in faith,” the Lord has said, “they shall cast out devils; they shall heal the sick; they shall cause the blind to receive their sight, and the deaf to hear, and the dumb to speak, and the lame to walk.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/35.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 35:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p42" pid="dt-5UT6REEqGYTr_fkJvSA" hash="x9klJg">Administration to the sick should be done at the request of the sick persons or someone close to them who is concerned about them, that it might be done through their faith. The Lord said, “And these things ye shall not do, except it be required of you by them who desire it, that the scriptures might be fulfilled; for ye shall do according to that which is written.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/24.14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 24:14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p43" pid="RFtvTTsTw0-H40WCQhO9wA" hash="Wr0EUQ">Both the one receiving the blessing and the one giving it should be in tune with the Spirit through their worthy lives, and then the Lord has promised, “Whatsoever thing ye shall ask the Father in my name, which is good, in faith believing that ye shall receive, behold, it shall be done unto you.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.26" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:26</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p44" pid="Gm18g0XHx0WArLsyDJxjnQ" hash="yckomQ">After one has demonstrated his worthiness through good works and manifested his faith through prayer or proper administration to the sick, it must be left in the hands of the Lord those who will be healed and those who will not. We may not always understand why someone is healed and why another for whom we have also exercised great faith is not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p45" pid="kmZ-4p0alkiHKYzZ1v-PUg" hash="z7-yxA">The Lord said that when the elders administer to the sick, if they die, they die unto him, and if they live, they live unto him. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p46" pid="Q_bc_UEqUEeY5nr3wRfmHA" hash="wkgooA">“Thou shalt weep for the loss of them that die, and more especially for those that have not hope of a glorious resurrection.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p47" pid="VPZMDuI8cUSRpX_XCPVqMA" hash="IKi5hg">“And it shall come to pass that those that die in me shall not taste of death, for it shall be sweet unto them. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p48" pid="bEY__2wsrUa4rILOswgnQw" hash="4i477g">“And again, it shall come to pass that he that hath faith in me to be healed, and is not appointed unto death, shall be healed.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.45-46,48" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:45–46, 48</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p49" pid="WHwVEKrOREyfO_KDCId6PQ" hash="d2Tufg">President Kimball has said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p50" pid="3sbe6MC53Ei1WCm6yPJnFQ" hash="ilgAag">“If all the sick for whom we pray were healed, if all the righteous were protected and the wicked destroyed, the whole program of the Father would be annulled and the basic principle of the gospel, free agency, would be ended. No man would have to live by faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p51" pid="z62QdXFvzE6YN4E-Hh3YZg" hash="Nq-q1w">“Should all prayers be immediately answered according to our selfish desires and our limited understanding, then there would be little or no suffering, sorrow, disappointment, or even death, and if these were not, there would also be no joy, success, resurrection, nor eternal life and godhood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p52" pid="A1lJ7FQNMUWHdlukliv49g" hash="8-1CUg">“Being human, we would expel from our lives physical pain and mental anguish and assure ourselves of continual ease and comfort, but if we were to close the doors upon sorrow and distress, we might be excluding our greatest friends and benefactors. Suffering can make saints of people as they learn patience, long-suffering, and self-mastery.” (<span class="emphasis">Faith Precedes the Miracle,</span> Deseret Book Co., 1973, pp. 97–98.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p53" pid="IZsA6k5V2UWzdamw4HnBng" hash="xJIYDw">Even though the Lord has prescribed proper procedures in administration to the sick, this does not mean that humble prayers by faithful individuals would not be answered. James has said, “The effectual fervent prayer of a righteous man availeth much.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/5.16" class="scriptureRef">James 5:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p54" pid="zW3epSQmdEy8VPkCASyzOg" hash="CtKTxQ">The Savior said during his administration on earth that in the last days, men not authorized of God would, in Christ’s name, perform wondrous works. This is evidenced by his words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p55" pid="Y9RhDoEMbkqnJ74P-FEi2A" hash="pU5iWg">“Many will say to me in that day, Lord, Lord, have we not prophesied in thy name? and in thy name have cast out devils? and in thy name done many wonderful works?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p56" pid="WPlV52TKb0awtchyTLRG-A" hash="V4sHGg">“And then will I profess unto them, I never knew you: depart from me, ye that work iniquity.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.22-23" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 7:22–23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p57" pid="CcjruYVKRUeetv8Xi2Qmbw" hash="lUOKig">He gave the same warning to the Prophet Joseph Smith:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p58" pid="v_-mbzCwu0S3FzWs_2zqUg" hash="VkWZEA">“[Walk] uprightly before me, … that ye may not be seduced by evil spirits, or doctrines of devils, or the commandments of men; … and that ye may not be deceived seek ye earnestly the best gifts, always remembering for what they are given;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p59" pid="W5hbiWbROkWfXMvV78oo1g" hash="w7lZlw">“… they are given for the benefit of those who love me and keep all my commandments, and him that seeketh so to do.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/46.7-9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 46:7–9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit.p60" pid="GeHYo-EwhEKeBHtaPkCAZg" hash="c6rdrw">May we so live that we may always have the companionship of the Holy Spirit and be blessed by these beautiful spiritual gifts that are a part of the gospel, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/10/gifts-of-the-spirit</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1974-general-conference/1974-10-2040-elder-james-a-cullimore-64k-eng.mp3" length="6054170" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 1974 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Family Home Evening</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brethren and sisters, I would like to say something about family home evening this afternoon. As President Kimball addressed the Stockholm Area Conference he pointed out the great need of home teaching and family home evenings to help neutral</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03063_000_012" doc-version="3" hash="8orHag"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="RXaQN0t9Ok66IG7ze4Wrzg" hash="t5KMQQ">Family Home Evening</h1><p class="authorName" pid="Z_FmP_8N_0m3czUhgjzHXQ" hash="vveEig">James A. Cullimore</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-28aa.jpg" alt="Elder James A. Cullimore" pid="HaytSUz3y0qqTgx8jEKkLQ" hash="u_okMA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p1" pid="HkwEUXsCXECGspB3-c95SQ" hash="EUTLaQ">My dear brethren and sisters, I would like to say something about family home evening this afternoon. As President Kimball addressed the Stockholm Area Conference he pointed out the great need of home teaching and family home evenings to help neutralize the ills of the world. He said: “The spirit of the times is worldliness. Hoodlumism is common. Supposedly good youth from recognized good families express their revolt in destructive acts. Many defy and resist the law-enforcing officers. Respect for authority, secular, religious, and political, seems to be at a low ebb. Immorality, drug addiction, and general moral and spiritual deterioration seem to be increasing, and the world is in turmoil. But in our time the Lord has offered his ageless program in new dress and it gives promise to return the world to sane living, to true family life, family interdependence. It is to return the father to his rightful place at the head of the family, to bring mother home from social life and employment, the children away from unlimited fun and frolic. The home teaching program with its crowning activity, the family home evening will neutralize the ill effects only if people will apply the remedy.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Jan. 1975, pp. 3–4.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p2" pid="pZ1er31LwUuWzJmefs_5sQ" hash="DD9JSw">In the October conference of 1964 President David O. McKay reintroduced a family home evening program designed to assist parents in teaching the gospel in the home. Since that time this important program has been emphasized by the Church. Monday evening has been set aside by the entire Church for holding family home evening. A beautiful manual is prepared each year by an expert staff of writers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p3" pid="bIxc6neIq0yS1jCRWHX26Q" hash="MXM2hg">Over 907,000 copies of the Family Home Evening Manual are now printed each year—about 830,000 in English and 77,000 in seventeen other languages. They are distributed to forty-eight countries.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p4" pid="LwMzSbPo80CIuk6YLXSwSw" hash="kVMgqg">In the Family Home Evening Manual of 1973–74 the First Presidency said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p5" pid="U5U4qj4U50S8OI6QBfHTpA" hash="Y3RSgg">“May we remind you of just how important the family unit is in the overall plan of our Father in heaven. In fact, the Church organization exists to assist the family and its members in reaching exaltation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p6" pid="6HbMp3XiVEmyoBHrLpA2aw" hash="F3XMgg">“The primary function of a Latter-day Saint home is to ensure that every family member works to create the climate and condition in which all can grow toward perfection. For the parents, this requires a dedication of time and energy far beyond the mere providing of their children’s physical needs. For the children, this means controlling the natural tendency toward selfishness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p7" pid="SXPhpboZi0OUdqi_D-eddQ" hash="EQAIPA">“Parents and children must be willing to put family responsibilities first in order to achieve family exaltation.” (p. 4.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p8" pid="Ymz4clbeNkGDgjJNBkamfQ" hash="tUBxhA">Our family home evening program has received national attention. Many individuals and groups and organizations out of the Church have written for information on the program and requested the manual. To quote just a few:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p9" pid="wt7c6Qr2RkqFGPIWK1jHyQ" hash="6-fCtg">
        <span class="emphasis">Immanuel Lutheran Church of Lincoln, Nebraska:</span> “I recently saw a copy of your Family Home Evening Manual. I was deeply impressed with the quality and approach of your program.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p10" pid="86DWM2hQP0-R9dalQUjASA" hash="r_vLVQ">
        <span class="emphasis">Trinity Evangelical Divinity School, Deerfield, Illinois:</span> “I have recently seen materials on your family home evening. I would be very interested in obtaining copies of any available materials, especially the Family Home Evening Manuals.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p11" pid="Y9YqupdYlEWAi61cierERA" hash="m35mkg">
        <span class="emphasis">Oklahoma State Department of Health:</span> “It has been brought to our attention that your Church has initiated a new program emphasizing family interaction called ‘Family Home Evening.’ We think that the major source of health development arises out of positive family life. We would be pleased if you could share with us information about your program.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p12" pid="u_C0N6hrtU6Xkav9Y690Iw" hash="Doa-TA">Many articles have been written by the national and local press praising our efforts. The late Mr. Louis Cassels of the United Press International wrote the following after visiting a family home evening:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p13" pid="oZZK6xUHNkqNFK7jBHYVKw" hash="_7uNRg">“A child gets his most important religious instruction at home. It is very difficult for Sunday School or any other agency of the church to communicate Christian faith to boys and girls who haven’t been exposed to it through family life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p14" pid="vrjwoBSu8kyIwbDTr5zY0w" hash="g-wSJg">“All denominations agree on this. One denomination—The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints—is doing something effective to help families fulfill their key role in the religious nurture of children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p15" pid="Nrerqe4Bj06DSY31B7Ojag" hash="TJvk2g">“Every Monday, in some 350,000 Mormon homes around the world, parents and children join in observing ‘Family Home Evening’ …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p16" pid="3VscY3eavki76wTfAuUwUw" hash="zX8IYA">“The most impressive aspect of a Mormon Family Home Evening, to this outside observer, is the apparently natural, unself-conscious and willing way in which older teen-agers participate …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p17" pid="RGyrbWvIT0GC_PcegsgPUQ" hash="gZhIxQ">“LDS President Harold B. Lee is a strong proponent of the home evening concept. He told a group of Mormon leaders recently that ‘the most important of the Lord’s work will be that which we do within our own homes.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p18" pid="ocbzJDqiWkmvdLxV6LWcsw" hash="by4l3w">“President Lee says family home evenings not only are an invaluable opportunity for religious instruction. They also serve to unite families, to bridge generation gaps, and to maintain communication between parents and children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p19" pid="S1w-6vCiJUOy1wzUqRvm9Q" hash="tVw-pg">“‘When the home functions properly, much has been done to prevent problems from happening,’ the Mormon president told UPI. ‘So much that we do, both in the world and the church, is done to compensate for failures in the home. We have found the Family Home Evening to be a great assistance to parents in fostering meaningful and close family relationships which help the home serve as a sanctuary from evil influences and as a source of strength to each family member.’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p20" pid="oC1ESiPAiU2mBgWTW29CSg" hash="Ka_i5w">Numerous mayors of cities and governors of states have recognized the virtue in family solidarity and know of the soundness the family home evening program is bringing about. Many have issued a proclamation declaring a “family unity” week or month. For example:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p21" pid="72BIkbhW0kaL_qGWutUMSA" hash="R9C1JA">“WHEREAS, public officials throughout the United States are gravely concerned about the erosion of the family unit and its effect upon society as a whole; and</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p22" pid="YKbaRpBuR0SWgkQXBoDaZg" hash="R5YKBw">“WHEREAS, the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints has originated a Family Home Evening program which has received worldwide recognition, the primary purpose of which is to bring the family back together through a weekly family get-together of fun, relaxation and learning; and</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p23" pid="EprxtzChfECKGAhEytfVgw" hash="oxdQSQ">“WHEREAS, good family relationships constitute the primary source of strength in our community:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p24" pid="ZeSDW6AdR0WPjpS_Lv0DzQ" hash="qe8yAQ">“NOW, THEREFORE, I, Fred Hofheinz, Mayor of the City of Houston, do hereby proclaim the month of December, as FAMILY UNITY MONTH.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p25" pid="bVuUDTfdxUm0e87eyeLrPg" hash="Gbw8Pw">A copy of another excellent proclamation was received from the governor of Arizona, who recognized the practice of the Church in teaching their children through family home evenings. He commended them in this and recommended such a practice to all inhabitants of his state through this proclamation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p26" pid="hJveQsDtX0eymVxEuhaOqQ" hash="iJeCew">“WHEREAS, the family is the basic and indispensable institution of our society … and</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p27" pid="PiUFJ6k7zEaRaUkP8ps_Hw" hash="kwTegg">“WHEREAS, we are observing in our nation a breaking up of family life at a rate unprecedented in history, with serious effects and repercussions in many segments of our society, particularly the welfare of children and the weakening of the single greatest strength of America; and</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p28" pid="77vZjMkRcUSCAG-EQv3R1A" hash="oV2ebw">“WHEREAS, there is increasing concern among all thinking Americans over the dissolution of Family Life and the effects such destruction portends for our nation;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p29" pid="m3RqeUs570GQYhLIzMz4og" hash="aZdOYQ">“WHEREAS, prominent religious leaders have said; ‘No Success Can Compensate For Failure In the Home’ and ‘The Most Important Work You Will Ever Do Is Within The Walls of Your Own Home;’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p30" pid="Uc3J42kVdEmUDhBbG9nvFA" hash="khPgTQ">“NOW, THEREFORE, I, Jack Williams, Governor of Arizona, do hereby proclaim the week beginning Sunday, June 2, 1974, as FAMILY WEEK and do call upon all serious and right-thinking Americans to reflect upon the meaning of Family Life to themselves, to their children, to their children’s children, and to our great nation. …”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p31" pid="I_dQZa_2wU-7MoJP8YAz9w" hash="s0m5Rw">The Church has also received from the Senate of the United States a proclamation from the 93rd Congress, “commending the members … for their spirit of pioneering, for their wholesome living, for their concern for their fellowmen, and for their many achievements.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p32" pid="dxkA35QDdkegCE99891LwQ" hash="PToGBw">President Kimball stated, “These recognitions from government, state, and city leaders who were not members of the Church are most gratifying. They know what creates nations and governments. They know what destroys cities and states and governments. They know that the breaking up of the family is the beginning of the fall of the empire. They know well that the dishonesty, immorality, homes broken through divorce and infidelity, limited family size, and adult preoccupation with entertainment and sex presages a collapse of the government.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Jan. 1975, p. 9.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening.p33" pid="ptJ9yPcM9ECCXdhI3f4R2w" hash="ffBnXg">I bear you my solemn witness, my brothers and sisters, that this is the work of the Lord, that these Brethren who instituted the family home evening program were greatly inspired. I see as well the great inspiration given to those who prepare the Family Home Evening Manual. I leave this testimony with you in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/10/family-home-evening</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1975-general-conference/1975-10-2050-elder-james-a-cullimore-64k-eng.mp3" length="10597513" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Book of Mormon</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brethren and sisters, I’d like to talk to you today about the Book of Mormon. I often wonder if we take as seriously as we should this great record. Early in the Church the members seemed to be taking the Book of Mormon too lightly. The Lord </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03070_000_038" doc-version="2" hash="dhHuJg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="iCH2pUrEjUWj_HDS_uiEZw" hash="WUV6sw">The Book of Mormon</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="EdbjktIKKUe5_f_WHv2r2A" hash="vveEig">James A. Cullimore</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-28aa.jpg" alt="Elder James A. Cullimore" pid="9hex5Nwoi0-tfvDVnp6urw" hash="u_okMA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p1" pid="ThpXCoN7pUalW6OFXEhiqQ" hash="e3fKvw">My dear brethren and sisters, I’d like to talk to you today about the Book of Mormon. I often wonder if we take as seriously as we should this great record. Early in the Church the members seemed to be taking the Book of Mormon too lightly. The Lord gave the following warning and condemnation. This might be as applicable today as it was then.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p2" pid="FwMYh3qYSkOkHuVSRbpVQA" hash="jXR0zg">“And your minds in times past have been darkened because of unbelief, and because you have treated lightly the things you have received—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p3" pid="EsayF_777EOmzmb1nacR9A" hash="fyXKsw">“Which vanity and unbelief have brought the whole church under condemnation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p4" pid="Qvuo1wlo40u3xSn8D4qwQQ" hash="MQBwMQ">“And this condemnation resteth upon the children of Zion, even all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p5" pid="-652SlxqZU28rtaCkCXkaw" hash="25uqPQ">“And they shall remain under this condemnation until they repent and remember the new covenant, even the Book of Mormon and the former commandments which I have given them, not only to say, but to do according to that which I have written—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p6" pid="SiWesUBCBUu5AD_xh1fjCw" hash="LMcjsg">“That they may bring forth fruit meet for their Father’s kingdom; otherwise there remaineth a scourge and judgment to be poured out upon the children of Zion.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.54-58" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:54–58</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p7" pid="4Q2Ujf7l00mckf0Ky2Hm5w" hash="wXN5zQ">The Book of Mormon is no ordinary book.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p8" pid="uPjEBE4EhkisRnYJI518Mw" hash="0Cn49Q">It was translated from gold plates which were delivered to Joseph Smith by an angel of God. It was translated by the gift and power of God. Oliver Cowdery, who was the scribe, said, “I wrote, with my own pen, the entire Book of Mormon (save a few pages,) as it fell from the lips of the Prophet Joseph Smith as he translated it … by means of the Urim and Thummim.” (<span class="emphasis">Millennial Star</span> 21 [1859]:544.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p9" pid="wKHE-tVFRkSHq-bLWpXH4w" hash="B-C6bA">It gives an account of Christ’s visit to the people of this continent. It corroborates and complements the Bible. It establishes the truth of the Bible. The central theme of the Book of Mormon concerns Jesus Christ and his mission. It is for the convincing of the Jews and the gentiles that Jesus is the Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p10" pid="DQ8IQe4whUSRZcscS-Mj_Q" hash="uE_MmQ">The Book of Mormon is a prophetic book. Its coming forth fulfills many biblical prophecies.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p11" pid="VCzMIFrookqhZ7VOtWnk3Q" hash="SBdg7A">The Book of Mormon was given to the world with the admonition that man should test its authenticity by reading it and asking God if it is true. Before concluding the record of the Nephites, Moroni, the last surviving prophet of these people, wrote to those who would read the record in the latter days:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p12" pid="kk1YUkh2yUiYUklJazdP3A" hash="2WrDFA">“When ye shall receive these things, I would exhort you that ye would ask God, the Eternal Father, in the name of Christ, if these things are not true; and if ye shall ask with a sincere heart, with real intent, having faith in Christ, he will manifest the truth of it unto you, by the power of the Holy Ghost.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.4" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p13" pid="MGetVz9BkkyC3Awa-7EDuw" hash="yip0qQ">
        <span class="emphasis">What a powerful challenge!</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p14" pid="Brqj2nVvIU2fAHD0l4q2SA" hash="fMdv8Q">Brother William E. Berrett gives an account of an interesting gathering in New York City in 1938. It was the New York City Book Club. Their speaker was the Honorable Henry A. Wallace, then Secretary of Agriculture. His subject was “Good Books of the Nineteenth Century.” In the course of his remarks he said, “The greatest book published in the nineteenth century in the field of religion was the Book of Mormon. Although this book was read by less than one percent of Americans, it affected that one percent so powerfully as to change the history of the nation.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p15" pid="KVL_lY62lkme3yyhV9XP9A" hash="yeqDrw">Brother Berrett states further, “It is a book that has aroused a storm of protest. It has done what the Prophet Joseph said it would do. It has divided men into two camps—those who are for it and those who are against it. There have [possibly] been more books written against it than against any book ever published in America. … On the shelves of the Church Library in the Church Office Building there are more than 1,500 [anti-Mormon] books, each of which, in a portion of its pages, makes an attack on the Book of Mormon. Fifteen hundred volumes by fifteen hundred separate authors. Of those fifteen hundred probably only two ever reached a second edition. …” (William E. Berrett, “What Is the Book of Mormon?” in <span class="emphasis">Know Your Religion Series 1953–54,</span> 21 Oct. 1953, pp. 1–2.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p16" pid="YtbqbOjWEU6NnXXtG0Wgnw" hash="E3PxKQ">Critics of the Church today seldom claim the Book of Mormon to be a fraud. It has proven itself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p17" pid="Yjn3i3ZX_kOHWyEkj5qlQg" hash="jzF4mQ">Robert B. Downs wrote a book entitled <span class="emphasis">Books That Changed America.</span> He listed the Book of Mormon as one of twenty-five such books. In his comments he said, “Throughout the history of Mormonism, the Church’s most powerful and effective weapon has been the Book of Mormon.” (Robert B. Downs, <span class="emphasis">Books That Changed America,</span> New York: MacMillan Co., 1970, p. 35.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p18" pid="Ygg1pdpejkGNbA11AWni2w" hash="UKVKZw">
        <span class="emphasis">It is a powerful book!</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p19" pid="v5lHIHULVUynKQdwKa_Uog" hash="wlpy5w">Many individuals have read it. It has caused them to leave their churches in which they have been active members. It has caused them to give up their fathers, mothers, and families. Their faith in the book and the truths it teaches was so strong they still believed even though they were told they would be disowned if they joined the Church. They have given up their occupations, their countries. Many have spent all they had, in some cases, for passage on a boat, then walked across the plains to the Salt Lake Valley and lived under most trying circumstances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p20" pid="pZo5mQZ2JkG-klEp4TIiig" hash="XvL9Eg">The Prophet Joseph records in his diary, “I told the brethren that the Book of Mormon was the most correct of any book on earth, and the keystone of our religion, and a man would get nearer to God by abiding by its precepts, than by any other book.” (<span class="emphasis">History of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints,</span> 4:461.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p21" pid="ShRywuKXOUiEiCMHDvMb9w" hash="jczmhA">We believe the Bible to be the word of God, but I have often asked missionaries what they would do without the Book of Mormon and modern revelation. With just the Bible, what would be their approach? The Prophet Joseph answered it. “Take away the Book of Mormon and the revelations and where is our religion? We have none.” (<span class="emphasis">HC,</span> 2:52.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p22" pid="2xen7PtIjUqQhEynj4Juwg" hash="dGYong">If the Book of Mormon is not true, then Joseph Smith was not a prophet of God. I testify to you that the Book of Mormon is true and that the revelations contained in the Doctrine and Covenants and Pearl of Great Price and other places are true and of the Lord. Our message to the world is that God lives, that Jesus is the Christ, that God has revealed himself to man in this dispensation and restored his gospel with all its keys and power. Nothing will be more certain to build faith and testimonies of members and touch the hearts of honest seekers for the truth than this great book.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p23" pid="afIKz85oI0a4ziYJSlQ3_w" hash="kUGjMw">There is a special power about the Book of Mormon. It bears a strong, silent witness of its truth as one reads it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p24" pid="t2kgDjGEaE25EYYtfj8Q4w" hash="5osn1A">Parley P. Pratt stated, “The Spirit of the Lord came upon me, while I read [The Book of Mormon], and enlightened my mind, convinced my judgment, and rivetted the truth upon my understanding, so that I knew that the book was true, just as well as a man knows the daylight from the dark night.” (<span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses,</span> 5:194.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p25" pid="PCSdG0zD1UeXcjt6SJAWlg" hash="k1ufRQ">Brigham Young said as he read the book, “I knew it was true, as well as I knew that I could see with my eyes, or feel by the touch of my fingers, or be sensible of the demonstration of any sense.” (<span class="emphasis">JD,</span> 3:91.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p26" pid="ElvFWNwaRke0SXAqt6wUhw" hash="tHFoug">In the hands of nonmembers it works while one sleeps. Let me give you two personal experiences regarding this.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p27" pid="9K4Dw3jutkWGFH-LyawGtw" hash="5hFkTQ">The first is about James Monroe Hastings and his wife, Eddie. Mr. Hastings was a Baptist minister in New Mexico during the depression days in the early 1930s. After one of his revival meetings, someone gave him a Book of Mormon which he took home and placed on the shelf. About five years later he picked it up and started to read it. After he had read it through, he testified to his family it was true. The next weekend he went to Springerville, Arizona, to find a member of the Church who could teach him more. It was only a few weeks until he and his family were baptized.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p28" pid="OnrmaUx5JkeUCaKflni5UA" hash="Xx3tqg">Brother and Sister Hastings and their family appeared in our little branch in Oklahoma City in mid-1939. They had moved there to try to convert his brother and family who lived there. After they had brought them into the Church, they moved where others of the family lived so they could teach them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p29" pid="83aAsGnj1U-qRRsm5IIH5Q" hash="hpJ0vA">The other experience was related to me by a good friend. He gave a Book of Mormon to one of his associates in business. He soon retired from the company and heard nothing from this former associate for several years. When he saw him again, the friend said, “Possibly you’d like to know what happened to your Book of Mormon? I haven’t read it, but many of my family have, and there are now nineteen of my family members in your church as a result of reading it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p30" pid="2zYkHwZNHUOjHFxD01A3Zw" hash="3GCIKQ">“I took the book home and put it on the shelf. One night as my mother was babysitting for us, she saw the book and began to read it. When we came home, she asked us about it. She said, ‘This book is true.’ This started a chain of events that brought about these many baptisms.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p31" pid="yQatEJ2gAU2mtGp5IuWpGw" hash="ABAoEQ">The Lord said to Joseph Smith, “This generation shall have my word through you.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/5.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 5:10</a>.) The Book of Mormon and latter-day revelation to the Church came through Joseph Smith. It testifies of Christ. It is a new witness for Christ. Listen to the words of Nephi:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p32" pid="wUQg2egvnkKVqNUieTp4AQ" hash="AYoDVg">“The words which I have written in weakness will be made strong unto them; for it persuadeth them to do good … and it speaketh of Jesus, and persuadeth them to believe in him, and to endure to the end, which is life eternal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p33" pid="-n319r8L10KEcqW6kp5NGA" hash="jxrEYg">“And it speaketh harshly against sin, according to the plainness of the truth; wherefore, no man will be angry at the words which I have written save he shall be of the spirit of the devil.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p34" pid="fiXuaHS1g0658i7rhQ0DIQ" hash="S0LiLg">“… If ye shall believe in Christ ye will believe in these words, for they are the words of Christ, and he hath given them unto me; and they teach all men that they should do good.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/33.4-5,10" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 33:4–5, 10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p35" pid="4SRmih1UMk2aSKgjq2wjEQ" hash="tNnh-w">The Nephites were individual witnesses of the risen Lord. When he visited them, he invited them to see for themselves. He said, “Arise and come forth unto me, that ye may thrust your hands into my side, and also that ye may feel the prints of the nails in my hands and in my feet, that ye may know that I am the God of Israel, and the God of the whole earth, and have been slain for the sins of the world. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p36" pid="Ee5OyTKUI0qL1vlp0sLwWw" hash="auXpFQ">“And the multitude did see and hear and bear record; and … all of them did see and hear, every man for himself.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.14" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:14</a>, <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.25" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p37" pid="PCguOqRya0i1IHdqD0T0ng" hash="PCE-cQ">The Book of Mormon testifies of Joseph Smith. The prophet Lehi in his words to Joseph, his youngest son, referred to the covenant made by God to his ancestor, the great Joseph who was sold into Egypt. This unusual seer, Joseph of Egypt, received from the Lord the promise that from the fruit of his loins a righteous branch should be raised up and also the promise that the Messiah should be manifest to his descendants in the latter days. The Lord would raise up a choice seer, like unto Moses, to the remnants of Joseph:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p38" pid="Nlq9yNoRt0-S524w8RVKzQ" hash="XR0dLA">“For Joseph truly testified, saying: A seer shall the Lord my God raise up, who shall be a choice seer unto the fruits of my loins.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p39" pid="mkzC0BcVMEK2pvzqm8GY7g" hash="cwH2Bw">“And I will make him great in mine eyes; for he shall do my work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p40" pid="KLU8p2_Kyky_yHA19Of9jA" hash="J7VNiw">“And he shall be great like unto Moses.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p41" pid="epedGSW8dkiP8ydYoir35Q" hash="S95r_Q">“And his name shall be called after me; and it shall be after the name of his father. And he shall be like unto me; for the thing, which the Lord shall bring forth by his hand, by the power of the Lord shall bring my people unto salvation.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/3.6,8-9,15" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 3:6, 8–9, 15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p42" pid="I_sJTOr4wk6EiAJqYZ4z9A" hash="Xc8dVA">Joseph Smith, the Latter-day prophet, fulfilled this prophecy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p43" pid="ZdFBe1LiXkmFTseryi8vxQ" hash="NhJrvQ">The Book of Mormon is truly a witness for Jesus Christ and his plan of salvation for mankind. It is a witness that Jesus Christ, through Joseph Smith, has again established his work in our day. We invite all mankind to read it and learn for themselves its powerful message.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon.p44" pid="8N0fVJjn3kSoMTkHSbyPTQ" hash="ZgGXGw">I leave you my witness of the truth of this gospel and of the Book of Mormon, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/04/the-book-of-mormon</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1976-general-conference/1976-04-6030-elder-james-a-cullimore-64k-eng.mp3" length="12437439" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1976 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grieve Not the Holy Spirit, Lest We Lose It</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My brethren and sisters, I bring greetings to you from the Saints in Great Britain and South Africa. It’s exciting to see how the work is moving forward in this area. There are now twenty-seven stakes in Great Britain and one in South Africa. The lea</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03096_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="VWe4Wg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="6TKboH7m4EO8mkUeZsFXTQ" hash="oBjPVA">Grieve Not the Holy Spirit, Lest We Lose It</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="bVjLoHEahEuTG4DksLgeXA" hash="vveEig">James A. Cullimore</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-28aa.jpg" alt="Elder James A. Cullimore" pid="nA-VSlUhEEOv1H-jsoVxjg" hash="u_okMA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p1" pid="W2EQK8VdUEOkUFJrwpv2QA" hash="HTpsGA">My brethren and sisters, I bring greetings to you from the Saints in Great Britain and South Africa. It’s exciting to see how the work is moving forward in this area. There are now twenty-seven stakes in Great Britain and one in South Africa. The leadership is generally strong and the work is moving forward and blessing the people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p2" pid="m2GC4O-yeUyw4TQlOyah3Q" hash="c8cxiw">And now, to have a General Authority from this area! I’m sure the people will be excited. And Brother Cuthbert, I think I can safely assume to bring to you the congratulations and the blessings of the people in your native land. We congratulate you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p3" pid="4aNZtxEcQk2MKEC3qUAj-w" hash="NhwOLg">It’s a pleasure to serve in this area. As I visit the stakes each weekend, I often ask the stake president what his greatest concern is in the stake. So often he replies: “The lack of commitment by the individual members, the lack of determination to put the work of the Lord first in their lives.” I think of the words of Nephi:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p4" pid="StTpNWUjj0KCgt44UKwPKg" hash="BkVhLw">“And I heard a voice from the Father, saying: Yea, the words of my Beloved are true and faithful. He that endureth to the end, the same shall be saved.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p5" pid="q92QGy4XUEePfDJgf8BASw" hash="WG9Hew">“And now, my beloved brethren, after ye have gotten into this straight and narrow path, I would ask if all is done? Behold, I say unto you, Nay; for ye have not come thus far save it were by the word of Christ with unshaken faith in him, relying wholly upon the merits of him who is mighty to save.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p6" pid="jN236DEqDkeyodmwdpthtw" hash="xc-p9A">“Wherefore, ye must press forward with a steadfastness in Christ, having a perfect brightness of hope, and a love of God and of all men. Wherefore, if ye shall press forward, feasting upon the word of Christ, and endure to the end, behold, thus saith the Father: Ye shall have eternal life.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.15,19-20" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:15, 19–20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p7" pid="7GMxlqib0keHmYrps3gu5g" hash="rMHoUw">How very important it is to have the light of the Holy Ghost to give us direction. The Holy Ghost functioning through the priesthood can greatly enrich our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p8" pid="oPR9uJ1tcUunRS3PYnriPQ" hash="RVtFSQ">“And the light which shineth, which giveth you light, is through him who enlighteneth your eyes, which is the same light that quickeneth your understandings;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p9" pid="msl4CczO5UWTxOzEW6O3Jg" hash="YTo1yA">“Which light proceedeth forth from the presence of God to fill the immensity of space.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.11-12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:11–12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p10" pid="b4-36U43YUuHpHUY-fo8Yw" hash="JhogQQ">The Lord said to Frederick G. Williams:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p11" pid="LNW9QxaNa0a6EEWHe9ZVXg" hash="GWDdug">“Wherefore, be faithful; stand in the office which I have appointed unto you; succor the weak, lift up the hands which hang down, and strengthen the feeble knees.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p12" pid="76ETD9SCXUeflRFujfg8sg" hash="bepz0w">“And if thou art faithful unto the end thou shalt have a crown of immortality, and eternal life in the mansions which I have prepared in the house of my Father.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/81.5-6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 81:5–6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p13" pid="rCfBySVTWEGykNOFz-sWNQ" hash="dh2-qA">God gives to each of his children his Spirit to help them keep the commandments and fulfill the purpose of life. But as it is written:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p14" pid="EX9FM4VpvUaBkVmmH--KPw" hash="6ufZTQ">“Eye hath not seen, nor ear heard, neither have entered into the heart of man, the things which God hath prepared for them that love him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p15" pid="xMO-xLcfq0SKcOutjVXwhA" hash="jQubog">“But God hath revealed them unto us by his Spirit: for the Spirit searcheth all things, yea, the deep things of God. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p16" pid="0SMYGcseSkylZO5bLVpbrQ" hash="Aa6cGA">“Now we have received, not the spirit of the world, but the spirit which is of God; that we might know the things that are freely given to us of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p17" pid="jGgrRU1MxUm9hTMqwRY8dQ" hash="1BimLw">“Which things also we speak, not in the words which man’s wisdom teacheth, but which the Holy Ghost teacheth.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/2.9-10,12-13" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 2:9–10, 12–13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p18" pid="J5sZxgVEHE6el9lcVc-_tQ" hash="6FEogA">From President Lorenzo Snow we learn the benefits of seeking the Spirit:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p19" pid="mQODgNvGkk2GP84fBPXBKQ" hash="uwz-Mg">“There is a way by which persons can keep their consciences clear before God and man, and that is to preserve within them the spirit of God, which is the spirit of revelation to every man and woman. It will reveal to them, even in the simplest of matters, what they shall do, by making suggestions to them. We should try to learn the nature of this spirit, that we may understand its suggestions, and then we will always be able to do right. This is the grand privilege of every Latter-day Saint. We know that it is our right to have the manifestations of the spirit every day of our lives. … The spirit is in every man and every woman so that they need not walk in the darkness at all, and it is not always necessary for them to come to the President of the Church, or to the Twelve, or to the Elders of Israel, to get counsel; they have it within them. … From the time we receive the Gospel, go down into the waters of baptism and have hands laid upon us afterwards for the gift of the Holy Ghost, we have a friend, if we do not drive it from us by doing wrong. That friend is the Holy Spirit, the Holy Ghost, which partakes of the things of God and shows them unto us. This is a grand means that the Lord has provided for us, that we may know the light, and not be groveling continually in the dark.” (In <span class="emphasis">Conference Report,</span> Apr. 1899, p. 52.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p20" pid="VJOZLy7eH0yy54ltHMtQqg" hash="MYaapA">The apostle Paul admonished us about grieving the Holy Spirit lest we lose it. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p21" pid="MPEsirPLXUGhF_xbYsQxAg" hash="A1TGuw">“Grieve not the holy Spirit of God, whereby ye are sealed unto the day of redemption.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p22" pid="ctA4zHIJv0quGLjLwBtoyg" hash="YXXvrQ">“Let all bitterness, and wrath, and anger, and clamour, and evil speaking, be put away from you, with all malice:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p23" pid="O2PAIbHSDE-1UBrZTccckQ" hash="Qtk5eg">“And be ye kind one to another, tenderhearted, forgiving one another, even as God for Christ’s sake hath forgiven you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/4.30-32" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 4:30–32</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p24" pid="VL93zZd0hEWaINYYshOU6w" hash="Ajml8A">President Harold B. Lee has said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p25" pid="uAcKvPZfE0Gofvfr0oupTA" hash="LuW2Nw">“I have learned something of what the Spirit has taught, and I know now that the place of safety in this world is not in any given place; it doesn’t make so much difference where we live; but the all-important thing is how we live, and I have found that security can come to Israel only when they keep the commandments, when they live so that they can enjoy the companionship, the direction, the comfort and the guidance of the Holy Spirit of the Lord, when they are willing to listen to these men whom God has set here to preside as His mouthpieces, and when we obey the counsels of the Church.” (In <span class="emphasis">Conference Report,</span> Apr. 1943, p. 129.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p26" pid="4aLice8FTkugOgASeIJh9A" hash="-9GRHQ">The lifeblood of the Church is the Holy Ghost functioning through the holy priesthood. The Church is guided in every move by revelation. The Lord said to Oliver Cowdery:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p27" pid="SjISfdyBj0KKvTRuQRQSVA" hash="FxIeVA">“Verily, verily, I say unto you, that assuredly as the Lord liveth, who is your God and your Redeemer, even so surely shall you receive a knowledge of whatsoever thing you shall ask in faith, with an honest heart, believing that you shall receive.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p28" pid="xRXjsvjdPEanjKnnD2JyRg" hash="RQ9x-w">“Yea, behold, I will tell you in your mind and in your heart, by the Holy Ghost, which shall come upon you and which shall dwell in your heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p29" pid="y4NtdPeEhk-C45aQ5UyuNg" hash="6wBWow">“Now, behold, this is the spirit of revelation.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/8.1-3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 8:1–3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p30" pid="pL-cxPazLkqNAX4ZyxxGDg" hash="pWewug">This is the way direction comes to the President of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p31" pid="cp2MKDEFIkKoR50xyD-hqQ" hash="vouZ_w">This is the same spirit that gives direction to the stake president, to the bishop of the ward and the individual members of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p32" pid="_DeM-2ZNkU-DrM8tU5vd9w" hash="w3ENyA">I like the verse of one of our hymns:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="GmAq37Y0F06IThN9cH6e4w" hash="RKr4HQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Thy Spirit, Lord, has stirred our souls,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Bxwfldebm0OqgNI0_McdrQ" hash="B4kdiA">
            <span class="emphasis">And by its inward shining glow</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="r0_7fTPRjkC5LEUClwJ0fg" hash="1KM_wg">
            <span class="emphasis">We see anew our sacred goals</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="t8cLY-tf_kS4Jy-jlLhlxg" hash="4Ct93w">
            <span class="emphasis">And feel thy nearness here below.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="2mVPpYu7OEOD-BcoLxg-Kg" hash="9fVSyw">
            <span class="emphasis">No burning bush near Sinai</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="v8lxByBS5k6Y1GgRY5MIGA" hash="F_O4iw">
            <span class="emphasis">Could show thy presence, Lord, more nigh.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="5LTFxpDGIU2AlVNfWhz9LQ" hash="yUuLPQ">
            <span class="emphasis">“Did not our hearts within us burn?”</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="a8gginQKlUOLYmUvjm01CQ" hash="fyxxiw">
            <span class="emphasis">We know the Spirit’s fire is here.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="O7SSyfZi5kqZMmMeSouV2w" hash="wH_dnw">
            <span class="emphasis">It makes our souls for service yearn;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="EJAMD3DWVUSXtBFAk1Rbpw" hash="tdCe9g">
            <span class="emphasis">It makes the path of duty clear.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="gY-1eKAllUKZNomPcsJc7A" hash="A8dtkg">
            <span class="emphasis">Lord, may it prompt us, day by day,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="3JVetMPk3UGkwkQSTUnnww" hash="FrVIFA">
            <span class="emphasis">In all we do, in all we say.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it.p33" pid="Zqy7vFCbBU-4ahkR9Nlh7g" hash="Y6HXeA">May I leave with you my witness, my brothers and sisters, of the truth of this great work, which I have received in this same manner, through the Holy Ghost as it has witnessed unto me. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1978/04/grieve-not-the-holy-spirit-lest-we-lose-it</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1978-general-conference/1978-04-2060-elder-james-a-cullimore-64k-eng.mp3" length="4337817" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 1978 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
