<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By James B. Martino</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by James B. Martino.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/James%20B.%20Martino.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by James B. Martino.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>All Things Work Together for Good</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/04/all-things-work-together-for-good?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We may never know in this life why we face what we do, but we can feel confident that we can grow from the experience.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/all-things-work-together-for-good" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021388_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="MkjbNg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/all-things-work-together-for-good.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="5kSGOVFQXEqVDOCG4BJqEA" hash="daqw_g">All Things Work Together for Good</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="jwchKhz6OU2bpadc2fd9KA" hash="NXjE4g">James B. Martino</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="G2cWjEphlkyd5kdbIGrdLg" hash="WET1VA">We may never know in this life why we face what we do, but we can feel confident that we can grow from the experience.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/all-things-work-together-for-good.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/all-things-work-together-for-good.p1" pid="XjAxQ83VY0mpCwFF9Ovspg" hash="kPSqBA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="101"></span>When I was young I looked forward to the spring of the year. As the weather warmed, I was ready for baseball to begin. Like most young boys, I would wish that I could become a great baseball player. I am reminded of a story about a very young boy with similar dreams. With the desire to become the next mighty ballplayer, he decided to go outside and practice. He held the baseball in one hand and the bat in the other, and he threw the ball into the air. With a wish to hit the ball as far as he could, he took a great swing, but the ball fell to the ground without even touching the wood of the bat. Not to be denied, he went at it again. As he was about to throw the ball in the air, his determination grew as the thought of a powerful hit came into his mind. But alas, the results were the same. The ball lay on the ground. But as any good ballplayer knows, you have three strikes before you are out. He concentrated even more, threw the ball in the air, and gave the mightiest swing he had ever attempted. As the ball again fell to the ground, the tears began to swell in his eyes. Then all of a sudden a great smile appeared, and he said, “What a pitcher!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/all-things-work-together-for-good.p2" pid="JjQxL77Ad0m8ZjdCVb4_IQ" hash="W_utSw">Each of us will face trials and tests, and as in this simplistic example, it is how we react to those difficulties that will determine our success and happiness. Each of us will face adversity no matter where we are. We are taught in the scriptures that there “must needs be … an opposition in all things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> We will each face times of difficulty, and the question is not when we will face them but how we face them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/all-things-work-together-for-good.p3" pid="vQPVK0qhn0OyoJdLXQDQ4Q" hash="mFaZIg">The Apostle Paul taught an interesting lesson only a few years before the Saints in Rome were to face some of the most violent persecution of any Christian era. Paul reminded the Saints that “all things work together for good to them that love God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Our Heavenly Father, who loves us completely and perfectly, permits us to have experiences that will allow us to develop the traits and attributes we need to become more and more Christlike. Our trials come in many forms, but each will allow us to become more like the Savior as we learn to recognize the good that comes from each experience. As we understand this doctrine, we gain greater assurance of our Father’s love. We may never know in this life why we face what we do, but we can feel confident that we can grow from the experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/all-things-work-together-for-good.p4" pid="nJpzR_vBxUS8mGmiMVozoQ" hash="kcDGig">Now, I realize that it is much easier to look back when a trial is over and see what we have learned from our experience, but the challenge is to gain that eternal perspective while we are going through our tests. To some, our trials may not seem great, but to each of us who are passing through these experiences, the trials are real and require us to humble ourselves before God and learn from Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/all-things-work-together-for-good.p5" pid="m4jC1RjuRUKgxIyIMN4frw" hash="SADhJA">On this Easter Sunday, we remember the life of our Savior. It is He whom we desire to emulate in all of our actions. May I mention five things that we can learn from those last hours of the Savior’s life on earth that can help us to face our own trials.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/all-things-work-together-for-good.p6" pid="EIe6OpOUu0KQG35kLsBKbA" hash="usiSaQ">First, He sought not to do His will but only the will of His Father. He remained committed to His sacred mission even through the trial. As He fell to His face in the Garden of <span class="pageBreak" page-number="102"></span>Gethsemane, He asked, “Father, if thou be willing, remove this cup from me: nevertheless not my will, but thine, be done.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Sometimes we pass through pain and sorrow that we might grow and be prepared for potential trials in the future. I ask a question to you mothers: “Would you ever do something that would cause pain and bring tears to your children when they have done nothing wrong?” Of course you would! When mothers take young children to the doctor to receive immunizations, almost every child leaves the doctor’s office in tears. Why do you do that? Because you know that a small amount of pain now will protect them from possible pain and suffering in the future. Our Father in Heaven knows the end from the beginning. We need to follow the example of the Savior and trust in Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/all-things-work-together-for-good.p7" pid="-anSck_ab0ScEEHSJpXAUQ" hash="GHBjeA">Second, when we are faced with trials, we must learn to not complain or murmur. Nephi, after a great vision of the Savior’s atoning sacrifice, told us: “Wherefore they scourge him, and he suffereth it; and they smite him, and he suffereth it. Yea, they spit upon him, and he suffereth it, because of his loving kindness and his long-suffering towards the children of men.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> We must always attempt to correct the problem and overcome the trial, but instead of asking “Why me?” or “What did I do to deserve this?” maybe the question should be “What am I to do? What can I learn from this experience? What am I to change?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/all-things-work-together-for-good.p8" pid="nj2VBkkOFES1mESYbB2yew" hash="R3CjHw">Several years ago while my wife and I were serving in Venezuela, our youngest son left the comfort of his high school to join with us. He did not complain, but it was obvious that he struggled as he went to this country where everything was new to him; but in an amazing turn of events, the experience went from one of trial to a huge blessing in his life. He accomplished this by changing his own attitude and developing a determination to succeed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/all-things-work-together-for-good.p9" pid="N6Ktt-gGGEW9lvJfefB1MQ" hash="L13kPg">Third, when we face our challenges, we must seek greater help from God. Even the Savior of us all found a need to pray “more earnestly” as He was in the Garden of Gethsemane.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> We can learn to gain great faith if we do this. We must remember that often the answers from our Heavenly Father do not remove the trial from us, but instead He helps strengthen us as we pass through the experience. As He did for the followers of Alma, the Lord can “ease the burdens which are put upon your shoulders, that even you cannot feel them upon your backs.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> In our trials, let us not become bitter or uncommitted, but let us follow the Savior’s example of becoming more earnest, more sincere, and more faithful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/all-things-work-together-for-good.p10" pid="r4Dz-SHUPEi2NbqsypkRGg" hash="vdE1zQ">Fourth, learn to serve and think of others even in our times of trial. Christ was the epitome of service. His life was filled with examples of helping and serving others, and His greatest gift of all was what He did for us. As He said, “For behold, I, God, have suffered these things for all, that they might not suffer if they would repent.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> We must repent and then follow His example of service. When we serve others, we forget our own problems, and by working to relieve the pain or discomfort of others, we strengthen ourselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/all-things-work-together-for-good.p11" pid="UGGnt6l2lkeHT0YlQTrtWQ" hash="9sLfFw">In our last general conference, our beloved prophet, President Thomas S. <span class="pageBreak" page-number="103"></span>Monson, stated: “I believe the Savior is telling us that unless we lose ourselves in service to others, there is little purpose to our own lives. Those who live only for themselves eventually shrivel up and figuratively lose their lives, while those who lose themselves in service to others grow and flourish—and in effect save their lives.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/all-things-work-together-for-good.p12" pid="NiYDuDLS1kOnjxqtjsxGrw" hash="x8R1Zg">Fifth, forgive others and do not seek to pass the blame of our situation to them. Sometimes we like to say, “If they had not done this, then I would not have reacted the way I did.” There is a tendency for the natural man to pass blame to someone else so as not to be accountable for his or her own actions. The Savior looked at those who had nailed Him to the cross and pled with His Father in Heaven to “forgive them; for they know not what they do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Can we not be more forgiving?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/all-things-work-together-for-good.p13" pid="DqNa0nj3UUeUK5yxC6P8vQ" hash="1F7Hyg">As we pass through the trials of life, let us keep an eternal perspective, let us not complain, let us become even more prayerful, let us serve others, and let us forgive one another. As we do this, “all things [will] work together for good to [us] that love God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> I bear a solemn and certain witness that our Father loves us and He sent His Son to show and pave the way for us. He suffered, He died, and He was resurrected that we might live, and He desires that we “might have joy,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> even in our trials of life. I say this in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/04/all-things-work-together-for-good</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2010-general-conference/2010-04-5040-elder-james-b-martino-64k-eng.mp3" length="4960854" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turn to Him and Answers Will Come</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Martino teaches how obedience, scripture study, prayer, and fasting help us to feel the Spirit and find answers to our questions.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13768_000_37martino" doc-version="2" hash="sUL0IQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="0HbDzRGzEE2OEvkIHwmW4Q" hash="6Deoaw">Turn to Him and Answers Will Come</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p2" pid="UTIb46lvbkW79skyfXOjJA" hash="QiABWQ">By Elder James B. Martino</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p3" pid="hoZCgY1efUe0-8zinpDDJw" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=dDO_5s8fOkaQH4hSN3aooA"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" alt="Elder James B. Martino" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255551/e1fc3130a699469dbff0d0a2c0d37bad/100x135.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x67="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255551/e1fc3130a699469dbff0d0a2c0d37bad/50x67.jpg" data-src-100x135="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255551/e1fc3130a699469dbff0d0a2c0d37bad/100x135.jpg" data-src-200x270="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255551/e1fc3130a699469dbff0d0a2c0d37bad/200x270.jpg" data-src-320x432="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255551/e1fc3130a699469dbff0d0a2c0d37bad/320x432.jpg" data-src-460x621="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255551/e1fc3130a699469dbff0d0a2c0d37bad/460x621.jpg" data-src-640x864="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255551/e1fc3130a699469dbff0d0a2c0d37bad/640x864.jpg" data-src-1024x1383="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255551/e1fc3130a699469dbff0d0a2c0d37bad/1024x1383.jpg" data-src-2048x2766="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255551/e1fc3130a699469dbff0d0a2c0d37bad/2048x2766.jpg" data-src-4031x5446="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255551/e1fc3130a699469dbff0d0a2c0d37bad/4031x5446.jpg" pid="dDO_5s8fOkaQH4hSN3aooA" hash="KWColQ"></img></a></div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="ft_BAWJ1_EmrXVvtClITVA" hash="Vw0QlA">Be obedient, remember the times when you have felt the Spirit in the past, and ask in faith. Your answer will come.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="yvrzE_OIBU-203p2YM_RDA" hash="NXjE4g">James B. Martino</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p5" pid="cdduYSY-JkSYRNUS-Mci3g" hash="WVdTig">When I was a young man, my parents joined The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. We knew that the missionaries had been teaching them, but my parents had taken the missionary lessons alone.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p6" pid="2DGX2-GuGkerC6PBdwT4hA" hash="1xut1A">After this surprising announcement, my brothers and I began to listen to the missionaries as well, and they each received the message of the Restoration with gladness. Although I was curious, my heart was not into changing my life. I did, however, accept the challenge to pray about whether the Book of Mormon was the word of God, but I did not receive an answer.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p7" pid="b3pXcP9k0k-_mRZucZYPJg" hash="ZfHhPw">You might ask why Heavenly Father did not answer that prayer; I certainly wondered. I have learned since that the promise made by Moroni is accurate. God does answer our prayers about the truthfulness of the gospel, but He answers them when we have “a sincere heart” and “real intent.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> He does not answer just to respond to our curiosity.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p8" pid="4bncX6e-LkG8G5AKgrLATA" hash="5qYmVw">Perhaps there is something in your life that you have a question about. Perhaps there is a problem you do not know quite how to answer. Today I would like to share some thoughts that may help you obtain the answers or help you are seeking. The process begins with being converted to the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.t1">
				
					<h2 pid="zPYAGGidMUWu2H7S_eb_pA" hash="c31dHg">Receiving Revelation Depends on the Condition and Intent of Our Hearts</h2>
				
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p10" pid="2z569kW85kKMBFQY541ESg" hash="Fe2-NQ">I have thought about the accounts of several individuals in the scriptures. Take, for example, Laman and Lemuel. Like Nephi, they were “born of goodly parents” and taught “in all the learning of [their] father.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Yet they murmured because their father was a visionary man. From their point of view, his decisions defied logic, for they knew not the things of God, and therefore they would not believe.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p11" pid="clzRCQlrQUOYKBGjvquDPw" hash="eRK7mw">It is interesting to note that their choices allowed them access to potentially faith-building experiences. They left their home and their riches. They suffered through wanderings in the wilderness. They eventually helped build the boat, and they agreed to journey to an unknown land.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p12" pid="aK6ktBxy8kOd6JAriJPIZg" hash="LoKcdg">Nephi passed through these same experiences. But did these actions build their faith? Nephi’s faith was made strong, but Laman and Lemuel grew more cynical and angry. These brothers even saw and heard an angel, but alas, they continued to doubt.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p13" pid="m2gbX_lb9UujmoO2I6Cu8A" hash="yaMfkw">Mortal life is not easy for any of us. We are placed on earth to be tried and tested. Our response to life’s experiences will often greatly influence our testimonies. Consider some of the reactions of Laman and Lemuel: They murmured when their father asked them to do hard things.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> They attempted to obtain the brass plates, but when success did not come, they gave up. Their attitude was “We’ve tried; what more can we do?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p14" pid="wDWOmNm93UibjtGLoS8a7w" hash="G4QF7g">There was even a time when they were sorrowful for doing wrong and asked for forgiveness.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> They prayed and were forgiven. But the scriptures record that later they returned to complaining and they refused to pray. They came to Nephi and said they could not “understand the words which [their] father [had] spoken.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Nephi asked them if they had “inquired of the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Notice their response: “We have not; for the Lord maketh no such thing known unto us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.t2">
				
					<h2 pid="B9PfsvNZ60qjSxFfSNsSdg" hash="7MbuQw">Continuing Obedience Allows Us to Receive Answers</h2>
				
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p16" pid="ucQ1U85IoUCAcxsGd7xWeA" hash="MZFtXA">Nephi’s reply to his brothers is a key for us to receive continual answers to prayer:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p17" pid="NIPJstG3OESJ3DqJy-j18A" hash="RFuANg">“How is it that ye do not keep the commandments of the Lord? How is it that ye will perish, because of the hardness of your hearts?</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p18" pid="zyirERJDx0KDPWUMgDULVA" hash="bLuyGg">“Do ye not remember the things which the Lord hath said?—If ye will not harden your hearts, and ask me in faith, believing that ye shall receive, with diligence in keeping my commandments, surely these things [will] be made known unto you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p19" pid="1_tjOL6wFkWxJoOqalwkjQ" hash="2G0OqQ">I know some returned missionaries who have had undeniable spiritual experiences, but the lack of certain spiritual habits seems to have caused them to forget the times when God has spoken to them. To those returned missionaries and to all of us, if you “have felt to sing the song of redeeming love, I would ask, can ye feel so now?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> If you do not feel it now, you can feel it again, but consider Nephi’s counsel. Be obedient, remember the times when you have felt the Spirit in the past, and ask in faith. Your answer will come, and you will feel the love and peace of the Savior. It may not come as quickly or in the format you desire, but the answer will come. Do not give up! Never give up!</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p20" pid="qL19pqs8gEe6WgzUk1s5NA" hash="30yL-g">Let us compare Laman and Lemuel to the sons of Mosiah. Both groups of men were raised in righteous families, yet both strayed. Both were called to repentance by an angel, but what was different about the experience of the sons of Mosiah?</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.t3">
				
					<h2 pid="dyo8dOdBBEGxSvMm7IMy7Q" hash="ttjA0w">Trials Will Build Our Faith</h2>
				
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p22" pid="pRO5x0MsZ0OXKA4pjT0P8Q" hash="RrNNdA">Their missionary success is unforgettable. Thousands were converted to the ways of the Lord. However, we often forget that as they began their missions, their “hearts were depressed, and [they] were about to turn back, [but] the Lord comforted [them].” They were counseled by the Lord to “bear with patience [their] afflictions.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.t4">
				
					<h2 pid="Uo680Gz5Q0efBz3rISIOxQ" hash="Z1rD_g">The Study of the Scriptures Tells Us God’s Will</h2>
				
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p24" pid="4dK7-4uk9UmdtQejoWmHZQ" hash="6JIBLA">Why did the trials of these sons of Mosiah strengthen their faith and commitment rather than cause them to murmur or doubt? The key is that “they had waxed strong in the knowledge of the truth; for they were men of a sound understanding and they had searched the scriptures diligently, that they might know the word of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> We will all face trials and have questions, but remember that we must be “continually holding fast to the rod of iron.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> “The words of Christ will tell [us] all things what [we] should do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> We must make scripture study a daily part of our lives, as this will open doors of revelation.</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.t5">
				
					<h2 pid="xsc4LZh6b0WSy15UsZm0Bw" hash="hPLktA">Prayer, Combined with Fasting, Invites Revelation</h2>
				
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p26" pid="wE40lVGM_EmRuMRSm8gyxA" hash="N_gIxg">For the sons of Mosiah, “this is not all; they had given themselves to much prayer, and fasting; therefore they had the spirit of prophecy, and the spirit of revelation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> Prayer and fasting will allow us to be susceptible to spiritual promptings. Communicating with Heavenly Father while purposefully abstaining from food and drink allows us to “loose the bands of wickedness [and] to undo the heavy burdens.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> Prayer, combined with fasting, will provide so that when we “call, … the Lord shall answer; … [and when we] cry, … he shall say, Here I am.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.t6">
				
					<h2 pid="vKm9jhZO0USnPHdb93dD1g" hash="HTZjeg">Turn to Him</h2>
				
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p28" pid="QnTNRcny10W4qvwsQCZ2cQ" hash="tgM1hQ">These personal religious habits—obedience, scripture study, prayer, and fasting—strengthened the sons of Mosiah. The lack of these same personal religious habits was a major reason that Laman and Lemuel were left vulnerable to the temptation to murmur and doubt.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p29" pid="jxgDtQBeHEqOsfLsQVO_6w" hash="xNceUw">If you have been tempted to murmur, if you have had doubt that leads to unbelief, if trials seem more than you can bear, turn to Him. If you are one who has turned away or rationalized your behavior, turn to Him. Can you remember when He did “speak peace to your mind … ? What greater witness can you have than from God?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> Ask yourself, “Am I as close to living like Christ now as I was before?” Please, turn to Him.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p30" pid="C0JIcpTzc0u31z2j-_CJFA" hash="mFAvHQ">May I return to my personal story. Eventually I began to be sincere. I remember when the missionary who was teaching me asked if I was ready to be baptized. I replied that I still had some questions. This wise missionary told me that he could answer them but that I would have to answer his question first. He asked me if the Book of Mormon was true and if Joseph Smith was a prophet. I told him that I did not know, but I wanted to know.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p31" pid="66jqw5BcQkSAfhOmnc8r_A" hash="bm2PSg">My questions led to increased faith. For me, the answer came not as an event but as a process. I noticed that as I did “experiment upon [the] words” and began to “exercise a particle of faith,” the Book of Mormon became “delicious to me” and it did “enlighten my understanding” and truly did “enlarge my soul.” Eventually I had that experience the scriptures describe as a swelling within your breast.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> It was at this point that I desired to be baptized and to commit my life to Jesus Christ.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p32" pid="V4pdaVW6xEuuAiyK2S8jVQ" hash="GsVSLA">I truly know that the Book of Mormon is the word of God. I know that Joseph Smith was a prophet. Oh, I still have things I do not comprehend, but my testimony of truth draws me closer to the Savior and builds my faith.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p33" pid="Z5bkH5z7AE2ulD6O1bCKRg" hash="S3h-6w">Brothers and sisters, remember Nephi and the sons of Mosiah, who had spiritual experiences and then acted in faith so that answers came and their faithfulness grew. Contrast this with Laman and Lemuel, who doubted and murmured. Even though they sometimes acted in worthwhile ways, work without faith is dead. We must have faith with works to receive answers.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come.p34" pid="uj_noh0OPkGxrfNUMOJ_vA" hash="Y0Gp2A">I hope as you have listened this morning that the Spirit has impressed on your minds and hearts something that you might do to have your questions answered or to find an inspired solution to the problem you face. I bear a solemn witness that Jesus is the Christ. Turn to Him and your prayers will be answered. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div>
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/10/turn-to-him-and-answers-will-come</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2015-general-conference/2015-10-2070-elder-james-b-martino-64k-eng.mp3" length="5005859" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
