<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By James J. Hamula</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by James J. Hamula.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/James%20J.%20Hamula.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by James J. Hamula.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Winning the War against Evil</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil?lang=eng</link>
      <description>You were entrusted to come to the earth in these last days to do again what you did before—to once again choose good over evil.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00009501_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="9XnDhQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="bTm1zRWf6EqJIaBqK0jZOg" hash="gIimuw">Winning the War against Evil</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="bjEExlpcGUCw6msr-44mEg" hash="7RBD4A">Elder James J. Hamula</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="KfI_sEWr80yLFjtoFpMDIg" hash="1dNGfQ">You were entrusted to come to the earth in these last days to do again what you did before—to once again choose good over evil.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p1" pid="-_jiQvJpgke-rQycK4S6pg" hash="irg1kw">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="50"></span>I speak tonight to my brethren of the Aaronic Priesthood. It is my desire to help you more deeply appreciate who you are, what your purpose in life is, and how you may succeed in accomplishing that purpose.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p2" pid="xy8GAEEE60GTgPkAJspCug" hash="3YLydg">You have come into the world at a most significant time. We are entering the final stages of a great war. This war commenced before the foundations of the world and has been pursued with awful consequence throughout the world’s history. I speak of the war between the followers of Christ and all those who deny Him as their God.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p3" pid="x5LgTuRQqUebjqM2gGVcYg" hash="11-ALA">John the Revelator wrote concerning this war:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p4" pid="WiDBScmwT0ic-Ihs3klk7Q" hash="w3IhfA">“And there was war in heaven: Michael and his angels fought against the dragon; and the dragon fought and his angels,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p5" pid="3ImOJUYiIUKwu8lxz1gjbw" hash="nFdfNg">“And prevailed not; neither was their place found any more in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p6" pid="lWre8grIMEy6XTnpfqH_zw" hash="1jGyuQ">“And the great dragon was cast out, that old serpent, called the Devil, and Satan, which deceiveth the whole world: he was cast out into the earth, and his angels were cast out with him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p7" pid="0kM8hzTWKk2vVQMiOA-rKA" hash="oMAfRQ">It was Satan who instigated this premortal war. He did so by rebelling against our Father’s plan of salvation for His children and rejecting the Christ, who was designated to effectuate the plan. Tragically, a third of our Father’s children followed Satan.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Yet two-thirds did not. You, my young friends, were among these, and with them have come to earth to pursue the Father’s plan of happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p8" pid="5wgSn3k9Z0ytnW8aapr46A" hash="NG3dTQ">Unfortunately, Satan’s war did not end with his expulsion from heaven. As John observed, Satan and his followers were “cast out into the earth”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> and have come here with “great wrath.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> The evidence of their wrath can be seen in the blood and horror that has afflicted man from the beginning of time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p9" pid="v-iQtmVCEUGRFk06NNGvhQ" hash="Jkq6pw">So profound and extensive have been the wounds suffered among men that God Himself wept as He surveyed man’s condition.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p10" pid="BLuGHVZJ8EqDn0ACX4lJZA" hash="MSMhUg">We now find ourselves in the last days of this earth’s temporal history. In a coming day, our Father’s Son will return to the earth from which He was rejected and reclaim it as His own.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> In that day, He will subdue Satan and his legions and usher in a thousand years of peace and righteousness.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> In anticipation of that day, God has restored His kingdom to the earth one last time. That kingdom is The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p11" pid="f4wa0wYSukSxqgQ-_9M2RA" hash="2X7I-A">While God’s kingdom has been established on the earth in times past, the people to whom the kingdom was previously committed were unable to keep it. This time, however, is different. The prophetic promise is that this time God’s kingdom will not be lost but will overcome the world.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p12" pid="QS9C3TAPGkiGopkkMrQzHg" hash="sTAYJQ">To ensure its ultimate success, the final restoration of God’s kingdom has been commenced with unprecedented spiritual power<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> and is being sustained by that same spiritual power and something more. Reserved to come forth in these last days and labor for our Father and His Son are some of the most valiant and noble of our Father’s sons and daughters. Their valiance and nobility were demonstrated in the pre-earth struggle with Satan. There, “being left to choose good or evil,” they “[chose] good” and exhibited “exceedingly great faith” and “good works.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Such are the traits that are now needed to sustain the work of God in the earth and to save the souls of men from the intensifying wrath of the adversary.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p13" pid="JA8TFHCyZEy6q-M83yH5jg" hash="7FIuEg">Now, my young friends of the Aaronic Priesthood, you are these valiant and noble sons of our Father! You are the strength of the Lord’s house, His warriors!<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> You are those who chose good over evil and who exhibited “exceedingly great faith” and “good works.” And because of your personal history, you were <span class="pageBreak" page-number="51"></span>entrusted to come to the earth in these last days to do again what you did before—to once again choose good over evil, exercise exceedingly great faith, and perform good works—and to do so in behalf of the kingdom of God on the earth and your fellowman!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p14" pid="KpvHIOrZoUOtKuoMI0jLFQ" hash="vupOWw">With God’s kingdom restored to the earth and your entry into the world, Satan knows that “he hath but a short time.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> Therefore, Satan is marshalling every resource at his disposal to entice you into transgression. He knows that if he can draw you into transgression, he may prevent you from serving a full-time mission, marrying in the temple, and securing your future children in the faith, all of which weakens not only you but the Church. He knows that nothing can overthrow God’s kingdom “save it [be] the transgression of [his] people.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> Make no mistake about it—the focus of his war is now on you—you who seek to “keep the commandments of God, and have the testimony of Jesus Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p15" pid="UziEimkEN0u-lPZjT6Fhbg" hash="c9_H7g">Now, my young friends, you need to appreciate that our days now and the days that lie ahead are “perilous.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> In this regard, President Boyd K. Packer has observed:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p16" pid="INgwKtQ0oU208qmjMYElQw" hash="LAY9xA">“I know of nothing in the history of the Church or in the history of the world to compare with our present circumstances. Nothing happened in Sodom and Gomorrah which exceeds in wickedness and depravity that which surrounds us now.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p17" pid="A9wdR6pVHUGS9bdaqno4qA" hash="vkme5g">In referring to the perils of our day, I do not intend to inspire fear, but soberness. Being sober means being earnest and serious in assessing your circumstances and careful and circumspect in weighing the consequences of your actions. Soberness therefore yields good judgment, as well as measured conduct. No wonder then that prophets counsel young men to be sober.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> Remember Mormon’s observation that what made Helaman’s 2,000 stripling warriors so effective in battle was not just their courage, strength, and trustworthiness, but their “soberness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> Mormon valued such a trait because he was blessed to possess it himself. It was Mormon who was entrusted with the sacred records of the Nephite nation at only 10 years of age because he was a “sober child” and “quick to observe.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> And it was Mormon who, at age 15, was “visited of the Lord” and “knew of the goodness of Jesus” because he was of a “sober mind.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p18" pid="60Lxaapn_UqCbuPxcFo-kg" hash="i5XmNA">So, as we enter the final climactic stages of the war against Satan, be sober, my young friends. Understand that you cannot partake of drugs, alcohol, or tobacco. You cannot participate in pornography or other immoral activity. You cannot lie, cheat, or steal. You cannot use false, demeaning, or dirty language. You cannot deface your body with tattoos and other piercings. You cannot do these things and be victorious in the battle for your own soul, let alone be a valiant warrior in the great struggle for the souls of all the rest of our Father’s children.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p19" pid="Pr33GlGqOkuum-G1Pa7tkg" hash="4sD6zw">Understand, my young friends, that there is only one way to win the war against Satan, and that is to win it in the same way it was won in the beginning. When victory was finally achieved in the War in Heaven, a loud voice was heard to declare:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p20" pid="1D65IUj92EWBP3rkYaI_fQ" hash="J8ARcw">“Now is come salvation, and strength, and the kingdom of our God, and the power of his Christ. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p21" pid="G9m_V6XWaEysCAX5rl2yPQ" hash="O-7sJA">“For they [referring to Michael and <span class="pageBreak" page-number="52"></span>his angels] have overcome him [referring to the devil] by the blood of the Lamb, and by the word of their testimony; for they loved not their own lives, but kept the testimony even unto death.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> Do not miss the significance of this declaration. Satan was overcome in the beginning by (1) <span class="emphasis">faith</span> in the Lord Jesus Christ and His atoning sacrifice, (2) <span class="emphasis">testimony </span>of Him that was steadfastly kept to the very end, and (3) <span class="emphasis">consecration</span> of oneself to the Lord and His work. If this was the means for defeating him in the beginning, you can be sure that this is the one sure way to defeat him now.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p22" pid="p4Jgu-4N-kK6XCSZeJE3Ww" hash="TYKUyA">Now, you may wonder how to acquire the faith, testimony, and consecration of spirit necessary to overcome the adversary. Let me assure you that these qualities are already within you. You simply need to recover them. To that end, allow me to make three suggestions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p23" pid="Y8VOseF_nUaPK_cj5f9V6g" hash="0Wh_Dw">First, do as young Joseph Smith did. Find a quiet place and pray to your Father in Heaven.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26">26</span> Do so regularly and earnestly. Prayer is a precondition to revelation. The more regular and earnest the prayer, the more frequent the revelation. When received, revelation provides the evidence or assurance of things unseen, which is the foundation of faith.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_27">27</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p24" pid="7gdIwr2TXUymZmwgpwAT7w" hash="lPVHuQ">Second, learn to hear the voice of the Lord. His is a still, small, and whisper-like voice.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_28">28</span> It is one that is felt more than it is heard. It comes in the form of thoughts, feelings, and impressions. To hear such a voice, you must be still and quiet in your own soul, laying aside your excess laughter and light-mindedness.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_29">29</span> While it may not seem easy to so discipline your life, hearing the precious, loving voice of the Lord will sustain you in every circumstance and is therefore worth every effort.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p25" pid="I5j7n5AnA0qlhMN_NwuEFA" hash="Quiekw">Third, obey the word of the Lord as it is given to you. His word will not only love and comfort but invariably instruct and correct. Do as He bids you to do, no matter how hard it may seem to you, and do it now. It is in doing the will of the Lord that knowledge of Him and love for Him accrue to your soul, which leads you to be ever more willing to lay down your own life and follow Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_30">30</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil.p26" pid="dbcdt0ipMUWvTz7FZg-yxw" hash="IjdEmA">My dear brethren of the Aaronic Priesthood, these are your days! Do not squander them! Be sober! Take “the shield of faith, wherewith ye shall … quench all the fiery darts of the wicked.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_31">31</span> Then “fight the good fight of faith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_32">32</span> And when you have done all, “stand”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_33">33</span> still and “see the salvation of the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_34">34</span> I assure you that His salvation will come, delivering you and yours from every evil. I so testify in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2008/10/winning-the-war-against-evil</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2008-general-conference/2008-10-3030-elder-james-j-hamula-64k-eng.mp3" length="5626656" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sacrament and the Atonement</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder James J. Hamula testifies of the importance of the sacrament and encourages us to make it a more sacred part of our lives.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10991_000_45hamula" doc-version="6" hash="cL5nrw">
			
			<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.head1">
				<h1 class="title" pid="LweM-tk2LE-c3QZ0wjb_GA" hash="An2lOA">The Sacrament and the Atonement</h1>
				<div class="byline">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p2" pid="uaxByWtheUODTwWZr2V05A" hash="oWXmYg">By Elder James J. Hamula</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p3" pid="fgDjZWziPEy3dU35EuUBBA" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
					<a href="gl://image/?pid=Gxakp_DaXk-9dq38H173fg"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255540/40f118d02cb647deb85d7236ffc68c31/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255540/40f118d02cb647deb85d7236ffc68c31/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255540/40f118d02cb647deb85d7236ffc68c31/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x279="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255540/40f118d02cb647deb85d7236ffc68c31/200x279.jpg" data-src-320x447="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255540/40f118d02cb647deb85d7236ffc68c31/320x447.jpg" data-src-460x642="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255540/40f118d02cb647deb85d7236ffc68c31/460x642.jpg" data-src-640x894="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255540/40f118d02cb647deb85d7236ffc68c31/640x894.jpg" data-src-1024x1431="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255540/40f118d02cb647deb85d7236ffc68c31/1024x1431.jpg" data-src-2048x2862="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255540/40f118d02cb647deb85d7236ffc68c31/2048x2862.jpg" data-src-3837x5363="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255540/40f118d02cb647deb85d7236ffc68c31/3837x5363.jpg" altText="Elder James J. Hamula" pid="Gxakp_DaXk-9dq38H173fg" hash="VlPOVQ"></img></a>
				</div>
				<p class="kicker" pid="CZk0b6rFNUSztzCCwshORA" hash="NV67BQ">The ordinance of the sacrament needs to become more holy and sacred to each of us.</p>
			<p class="authorName" pid="SuN_xXZcbEi7PHvv-hBZUA" hash="oWXmYg1">By Elder James J. Hamula</p></div>
			<div class="bodyBlock">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p5" pid="2L6-bf74OUOcZ-L--_DSJQ" hash="3YB5_A">On the eve of Gethsemane and Calvary, Jesus gathered His Apostles together one last time to worship. The place was the upper room of a disciple’s home in Jerusalem, and the season was Passover.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p6" pid="WXLQALMC2keosZoKdVMidQ" hash="3yYi0g">Before them was the traditional Passover meal, consisting of the sacrificial lamb, wine, and unleavened bread, emblems of Israel’s past salvation from slavery and death<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> and of a future redemption yet to be realized.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> As the meal drew to a conclusion, Jesus took bread, blessed and broke it,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> and gave it to His Apostles, saying, “Take, eat.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> “This is my body which is given for you: this do in remembrance of me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> In a similar manner, He took the cup of wine, offered a blessing on it, and passed it to those around Him, saying: “This cup is the new testament in my blood,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> “which is shed … for the remission of sins.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> “This do in remembrance of me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p7" pid="f4YzDdv0lEur0nT6E7kcJg" hash="FfnAfg">In this simple yet profound manner, Jesus instituted a new ordinance for God’s covenant people. No longer would animal blood be spilled or animal flesh be consumed in anticipation of a redeeming sacrifice of a Christ who was yet to come.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Instead, emblems of the broken flesh and spilled blood of the Christ who had already come would be taken and eaten in remembrance of His redeeming sacrifice.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> Participation in this new ordinance would signify to all a solemn acceptance of Jesus as the promised Christ and wholehearted willingness to follow Him and keep His commandments. To those who would so signify and conduct their life, spiritual death would “pass over” them, and eternal life would be assured.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p8" pid="GKGIFLq6nkaztfca7_p7bA" hash="serKUg">In the hours and days that followed, Jesus entered into Gethsemane, was taken to Calvary, and triumphantly departed the Arimathean’s tomb. After His departure from them, Jesus’s faithful disciples in and about Jerusalem came together on the first day of the week to “break bread,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> and they did so “steadfastly.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> Surely, they did so not only to remember their departed Lord but also to express gratitude for and faith in His marvelous Redemption of them.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p9" pid="4x9yjdVWekiedrmMV1ZLzw" hash="3aeX3A">Significantly, when Jesus visited His disciples in the Americas, He also instituted the sacrament among them.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> In doing so, He said: “This shall ye always observe to do,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> and “it shall be a testimony unto the Father that ye do always remember me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> Again, at the outset of the Restoration, the Lord instituted the ordinance of the sacrament, giving instructions to us similar to those He gave His earlier disciples.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p10" pid="XiWDNYZSs0yfjLS73hsUGw" hash="wmkxhw">The ordinance of the sacrament has been called “one of the most holy and sacred ordinances in the Church.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> It needs to become more holy and sacred to each of us. Jesus Christ Himself instituted the ordinance to remind us what He did to redeem us and to teach us how we may avail ourselves of His Redemption and thereby live with God again.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p11" pid="HO2XDqSlt0i9PSVeyK0oMw" hash="iWkkhg">With torn and broken bread, we signify that we remember the physical body of Jesus Christ—a body that was buffeted with pains, afflictions, and temptations of every kind,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> a body that bore a burden of anguish sufficient to bleed at every pore,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> a body whose flesh was torn and whose heart was broken in crucifixion.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> We signify our belief that while that same body was laid to rest in death, it was raised again to life from the grave, never again to know disease, decay, or death.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> And in taking the bread to ourselves, we acknowledge that, like Christ’s mortal body, our bodies will be released from the bonds of death, rise triumphantly from the grave, and be restored to our eternal spirits.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p12" pid="obSvhvzHgUCFIOPyTjs6GQ" hash="hpcq2A">With a small cup of water, we signify that we remember the blood Jesus spilled and the spiritual suffering He endured for all mankind. We remember the agony that caused great drops of blood to fall in Gethsemane.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> We remember the bruising and scourging He endured at the hands of His captors.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span> We remember the blood He spilled from His hands, feet, and side while at Calvary.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26">26</span> And we remember His personal reflection on His suffering: “How sore you know not, how exquisite you know not, yea, how hard to bear you know not.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_27">27</span> In taking the water to ourselves, we acknowledge that His blood and suffering atoned for our sins and that He will remit our sins as we embrace and accept the principles and ordinances of His gospel.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p13" pid="jYaauPO0x0a9lxRpvfvb6g" hash="BJkcdA">Thus, with bread and water, we are reminded of Christ’s Redemption of us from death and sin. The sequence of bread first and water second is not inconsequential. In partaking of the bread, we are reminded of our own inevitable personal resurrection, which consists of more than just the restoration of body and spirit. By the power of the Resurrection, all of us will be restored to the presence of God.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_28">28</span> That reality presents to us the fundamental question of our lives. The fundamental question facing all of us is not whether we will live but with whom we will live after we die. While every one of us will return to the presence of God, not every one of us will remain with Him.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p14" pid="shtDyhc5t0qCU487nxc-EA" hash="bPJqLA">Through mortality, every one of us becomes soiled with sin and transgression.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_29">29</span> We will have had thoughts, words, and works that will have been less than virtuous.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_30">30</span> In short, we will be unclean. And the consequence of uncleanliness in the presence of God, Jesus made perfectly clear: “No unclean thing can dwell … in his presence.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_31">31</span> That reality was brought home to Alma the Younger, who, when confronted by a holy angel, was so racked, harrowed, and tormented by his uncleanliness that he desired to become “extinct both soul and body, that [he] might not be brought to stand in the presence of … God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_32">32</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p15" pid="MOKf3g4ZC0CcpDuCH7oMuw" hash="dlFhbQ">In partaking of the sacramental water, we are taught how we may be made clean from sin and transgression and thus stand in the presence of God. By the shedding of His innocent blood, Jesus Christ satisfied the demands of justice for every sin and transgression. He then offers to make us clean if we will have faith in Him sufficient to repent; accept all the ordinances and covenants of salvation, beginning with baptism; and receive the Holy Ghost. Upon our receipt of the Holy Ghost, we are cleansed and purified. Jesus made this doctrine very clear:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p16" pid="aD2wLRIi9E2418tqPsF3gA" hash="lMND7A">“No unclean thing can enter into [God’s] kingdom; … nothing entereth into his rest save it be those who have washed their garments in my blood. …</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p17" pid="9Ntod3ERP0Sxe3V0btHhwQ" hash="gmAoYA">“Now this is the commandment: Repent, all ye ends of the earth, and come unto me and be baptized in my name, that ye may be sanctified by the reception of the Holy Ghost, that ye may stand spotless before me at the last day.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_33">33</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p18" pid="2CtzWKi0Akync0wBV79kgA" hash="oOikXg">This is the doctrine of Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_34">34</span> When we receive this doctrine and conduct our lives accordingly, we are in effect washed in the blood of Christ and made clean.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_35">35</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p19" pid="gw_V4VmphkOUYUJrdzedOQ" hash="_MW1eg">Through the sacramental prayers, we express our acceptance of this doctrine of Christ and our commitment to live according to it. In our petition to God, our Eternal Father, we declare that we will “always remember” His precious Son. First, we witness our “willingness” to remember. Then we witness that we “do” remember. In so doing, we are making solemn commitments to exercise faith in Jesus Christ and in His Redemption of us from death and sin.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p20" pid="g_WQAXIJk0-4It8IKAjIEA" hash="Rk_iRg">We further declare that we will “keep his commandments.” That is a solemn commitment to repent. If our thoughts, words, or actions have been less than what they should have been in days past, we recommit ourselves to more closely align our lives with His in days to come.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p21" pid="hZ0hf8jJTEW_wCWaAekV7w" hash="6PZ_PQ">Next, we declare that we “are willing to take upon [us] the name of [the] Son.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_36">36</span> That is a solemn commitment to submit ourselves to His authority and to do His work, which includes receiving for ourselves every saving ordinance and covenant.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_37">37</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p22" pid="GifWuPTS_U-qpmv2EzkeSA" hash="XH52Sw">When we commit ourselves to these principles, we are promised in the sacramental prayers that we will “have his Spirit to be with [us].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_38">38</span> Receiving anew the Spirit is a consummate blessing because the Spirit is the agent who cleanses and purifies us from sin and transgression.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_39">39</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p23" pid="bn9PHaHQYkuxpFhtXKLjvw" hash="uIZuJg">Brothers and sisters, the most important event in time and eternity is the Atonement of Jesus Christ. He who accomplished the Atonement has given us the ordinance of the sacrament to help us not only remember but also claim the blessings of this supreme act of grace. Regular and earnest participation in this sacred ordinance helps us continue to embrace and live the doctrine of Christ after baptism and thereby pursue and complete the process of sanctification. Indeed, the ordinance of the sacrament helps us faithfully endure to the end and receive the fulness of the Father in the same way Jesus did, grace for grace.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_40">40</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement.p24" pid="3IbBAhFP_Emmo2eNYkvv2g" hash="_QIBjA">I bear witness of the power of Jesus Christ to redeem us all from death and sin and of the power of the ordinances of His priesthood, including the sacrament, to prepare us to “see the face of God, even the Father, and live.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_41">41</span> May we receive the sacrament next week, and each week thereafter, with deeper desire and more earnest purpose, I pray in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div>
			
		</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/10/the-sacrament-and-the-atonement</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2014-general-conference/2014-10-4050-elder-james-j-hamula-64k-eng.mp3" length="5817349" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
