<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Janette Hales Beckham</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Janette Hales Beckham.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Janette%20Hales%20Beckham.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Janette Hales Beckham.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1995 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Goodness</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness?lang=eng</link>
      <description>At one time a mother said, “I wish they would just lock all the youth in the temple until they turn twenty-one.” A father said, “I feel totally powerless in my own home. We are out of control.” What force or power could soften the human cry for great</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95911_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="HwW4kQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="rrv4QxS4uEKaqBVEJ-Lkfg" hash="ztG1EQ">The Power of Goodness</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="iyswg6R4UECfBIbf8u1SCA" hash="kcgPrQ">Janette Hales Beckham</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e58.jpg" alt="President Janette Hales Beckham" pid="uNElZJrXNUKujqhk5B-_MQ" hash="OwLG5A" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p1" pid="Z8i-Vq-bPkyoFwizQgj8qQ" hash="ppDevA">At one time a mother said, “I wish they would just lock all the youth in the temple until they turn twenty-one.” A father said, “I feel totally powerless in my own home. We are out of control.” What force or power could soften the human cry for greater security, orderliness, control, even peace?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p2" pid="ASLKyncNW0eb9ecQBTO11w" hash="TgGwKw">My first memories of a need for power came when my family moved the year I began third grade. I started figuring out more about friends and other people’s families. As my new friends talked to kids in the extended neighborhood, we sized up assets and numbers—who had shade trees you could sit in or chicken coops you could climb on. Besides whose dad was the strongest, I noticed many of the kids were older than I. Luckily, I had two big sisters with lots of friends. In fact, I once said I could call out the whole high school if needed. I felt I had the needed personal power for safety and self-preservation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p3" pid="GcfltuqSq0aipCK4HeH1NA" hash="NTF6kg">My eight-year-old world was enlarging. So was the need for the skills that help one cope in this civilized world. I started appreciating the safety one gets from size, numbers, resources. Our use of what I call personal or political power begins early. Most children learn about size first. “If you don’t stop that, I’ll call Mom.” “When Dad comes home, you’ll be in big trouble.” Resources can supplement our need for size. A toy becomes a stick. What begins as a snowman becomes a fortress. The world was at war in those days, but I was a third-grader. The physical danger I feared was the boy with a wooden gun that shot rubber rings taken from fruit jars. His target was girls’ legs. Friends told me you could give the boy bottle rings and he wouldn’t hit you, but adding to his arsenal seemed like a traitorous thing to do, and I doubted you could trust a commitment from a bully. I think a teacher eventually took his gun. In my world, I appreciated people who had power, like teachers and parents, especially if they had fair rules.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p4" pid="iY2uWSR1KU2kcSbHExF-zw" hash="vcCXWw">That same year the community seemed to rejoice with our family when my mother gave birth to her only son after four daughters. My dad was an only son and now he had someone to carry on his name. Within months it was obvious that Tommy was severely handicapped. A force that was just the opposite of my outside world started to be felt inside. There seemed to develop a new dimension of love, tenderness, compassion. I watched my mother and dad make adjustments in lifestyle to lovingly care for a child who in his five-and-one-half years never learned to sit or speak but who warmed an entire room with his smile. The whole town seemed more gentle, interested, concerned. My outside fears were diminished. I felt securely attached because my mother and brother were there. My parents were home at night. Our home seemed more warm, full. There was a different power. It seemed to grow from the inside. It felt more permanent, unlike the temporary power I felt with my friends. It was calm and peaceful—the power of goodness, the power of love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p5" pid="hk8pk7nUA0ySZDrKL2YVjg" hash="c5iqTQ">There <span class="emphasis">is</span> a power in goodness that is often learned in families. There is a void when it is lacking. I know one family that left what they described as “the good life” in a desire to <span class="emphasis">do good.</span> They agreed on a noble purpose that would take them to the Philippines for a year. The mother of this family reported, “We were flabbergasted it was so hard.” Without the normal routine and conveniences of home, she said, “We were just the same old ornery people.” Then they set a new routine—exercise at 5:30 <small>A.M.</small>, 6:30 scripture study, then breakfast and school. Each afternoon they visited orphanages to play with the children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p6" pid="yYnRqkLwzEe9i4kB-3gYEA" hash="AIEk6Q">Gradually the family started to notice a change—new levels of patience, gratitude, and respect. They started to talk to each other—to <span class="emphasis">really</span> talk and to <span class="emphasis">really</span> listen. The mother stated, “I will never forget the learning that took place for me and my family the day they brought a five-month-old baby into the orphanage whose tongue had been cut and an eye poked out.” When they learned the mother, a beggar, had injured her own child, it gave a new dimension to the social studies lesson they had discussed at home. A new level of compassion started to develop—greater reverence for the sanctity of life. This family put their “trust in that Spirit which leadeth to do good” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/11.12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 11:12</a>), and gradually they started to experience the power to become changed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p7" pid="6_hfjUJd7ECYkhCCjDSwhw" hash="wSbgrA">The powers of heaven are available to everyone through righteousness. Mormon teaches that “every thing which inviteth to do good, and to persuade to believe in Christ, is sent forth by the <span class="emphasis">power</span> and gift of Christ” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.16" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:16</a>; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p8" pid="x79oNZMHlEKzfgdaGtVx3Q" hash="3ShlbQ">Revelation concerning power was given to Joseph Smith when political power had turned against him and he was a prisoner in Liberty Jail. His first plea to the Lord was for help to avenge his enemies. His prayer: “Let thine anger be kindled against our enemies” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:5</a>). Our Father in Heaven responded with a greater blessing: “My son, peace be unto thy soul” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:7</a>). Then he made a promise if Joseph would endure and be faithful: “God shall exalt thee on high; thou shalt triumph over all thy foes” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p9" pid="euppcWmWD0qe8zJSI-4Vaw" hash="xbaJUA">It was in this prison setting that God taught Joseph Smith about priesthood power. “No power or influence can or ought to be maintained by virtue of the priesthood, only by persuasion, by long-suffering, by gentleness and meekness, and by love unfeigned” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.41" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:41</a>). Priesthood power is used to minister, to preach, to teach, to baptize, to ordain, to heal, to seal, to restore, to bless, to prophesy, to testify, to do good.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p10" pid="wuoq6zS8gEGBr6QZgmbvNg" hash="3C3iYA">Political power, on the other hand, can be used as a force for good or it may be a force for evil. It is always temporary. We all have political power. We each need it. We should <span class="emphasis">use</span> it for <span class="emphasis">good.</span> Without proper exercise of this power, we might lose our freedom. Churches might cease to exist. Of course we need rules. We need laws, but we must remember that the scriptures tell us “the powers of heaven cannot be controlled nor handled only upon the principles of righteousness” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:36</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p11" pid="tjtPQB3l_kaNWiM6EIkkUw" hash="izyw1Q">A faithful member shared her testimony of how the <span class="emphasis">power</span> of goodness influenced her life. She writes:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p12" pid="a46mHbiJKUGoQ0-68c2QJQ" hash="V36YEQ">“Until I was about eight years old, I was oblivious to the fact that my mother had serious health problems—later diagnosed as multiple sclerosis. When I was a first-year Beehive, I awoke one May morning to find that my mother was paralyzed from the neck down. She was already blind.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p13" pid="oWgWOvGyE02JrDUgdMlBZQ" hash="OKmnoQ">Confined to her bed, this courageous woman became the hub of the household. Her daughter wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p14" pid="k9eAqATJwk22Gh6iQHfZkg" hash="yPTdbg">“One day it fell upon me to clean the oven, a chore I approached with self-pity and much complaining. I went into her bedroom to whine a little and realized that Mom was crying. She said, ‘Do you know how much I would give to be able to get up and scrub that oven?’ I gained a different perspective on the nature of work. To this day, I think of that experience every time the oven needs cleaning.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p15" pid="KtPkmBl15Um4ruuzJAyMVA" hash="5OIKww">She continues: “An unusual blessing came to me in having my mother available. She listened patiently to my early-adolescent concerns and questions. She made me feel like the most important and interesting person in the world. She was <span class="emphasis">always</span> HOME—attentive, interested, and always available.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p16" pid="zayalWIAckylU3KFs80nhA" hash="Wu3gFw">Her mother died the spring of her senior year. She relates:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p17" pid="s69qhwLgJUKmz2DsQfxZ6A" hash="60iZXg">“One of the hardest moments in my young life was the day I returned home from school to an empty house and walked down that long hallway to her bedroom. My built-in counselor and confidante was no longer there, but she had given me those eternal, intangible gifts of love, wisdom, and acceptance. I will be forever grateful for her goodness.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p18" pid="jCrJeguniUuxQkPbQA_szQ" hash="hAl3Fw">This strong woman, though physically helpless, had the <span class="emphasis">power</span> to love, to motivate, to inspire, to perpetuate righteousness, to do good.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness.p19" pid="yNZTAENk502ykgMd3biXVg" hash="z4zpUQ">My plea for each of us is to recognize that God has given each of us power—the power to act, to choose, to serve, to love, and to accomplish <span class="emphasis">much good.</span> Perhaps it is time to take control of ourselves. Our prophet, Gordon B. Hinckley, has said, “Be faithful … do good.” He has told us: “we have nothing to fear. God is at the helm. … He will shower down blessings upon those who walk in obedience to His commandments” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1995, p. 71). It is my prayer that we will seek the power of righteousness in our lives by following the counsel of the living prophet, and by living the teachings of our Savior, Jesus Christ, in His name, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/10/the-power-of-goodness</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1995-general-conference/1995-10-1040-janette-hales-beckham-64k-eng.mp3" length="4973384" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1995 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustaining the Living Prophets</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets?lang=eng</link>
      <description>There is always a feeling of excitement for me as I know young women are gathering for our annual Young Women meeting. Tonight my excitement feels more like a whisper—the witness of the Holy Ghost whispering to me that a prophet of God has a message </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_96905_000_034" doc-version="2" hash="Qv7QUw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="76Cd_qzh_kib_bP1vKrU9A" hash="GQWAoA">Sustaining the Living Prophets</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="8Px3ywme50iYaSHXPf9ovw" hash="kcgPrQ">Janette Hales Beckham</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets.p1" pid="onXGTrjAqk-EM-rPi5nV5g" hash="y0yWdQ">There is always a feeling of excitement for me as I know young women are gathering for our annual Young Women meeting. Tonight my excitement feels more like a whisper—the witness of the Holy Ghost whispering to me that a prophet of God has a message just for young women.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets.p2" pid="9glUy7e3xUi4PEniquPm0Q" hash="GOCj2Q">Our theme for this meeting is “Stand As a Witness by Sustaining the Living Prophets.” As you think of the word <span class="emphasis">sustaining,</span> ask yourself this question: Is sustaining the living prophets different from having a testimony that we have prophets? When we sustain, it means we <span class="emphasis">do</span> something about our belief. Our testimony of the prophet turns into action when we sustain him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets.p3" pid="IIlxRoOcj0WADDI94aVg6Q" hash="efBUkg">My faith in a living prophet began in Primary and continued with me into my growing-up years. I had a testimony that we have prophets, but I hadn’t thought about what it meant to sustain the prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets.p4" pid="lalZrzhBHU-1hSDGyMIbbA" hash="61TK1w">In general conference in October 1994, Elder David B. Haight said: “When we sustain the President of the Church by our uplifted hand, it not only signifies that we acknowledge before God that he is the rightful possessor of all the priesthood keys; it means that we covenant with God that we will abide by the direction and the counsel that comes through His prophet. It is a solemn covenant” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1994, 14–15).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets.p5" pid="U3Qyp0ssxEuPUrqXN5yZfw" hash="JFhUoA">I pondered the words of Elder Haight. I considered the commitment I was making when I raised my hand and made a solemn covenant with God that I would sustain the prophet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets.p6" pid="mZCYagPWT0eHzHHrHwoS3Q" hash="7ZEv2A">The following April, the members of the Church sustained President Gordon B. Hinckley as prophet, seer, and revelator and President of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, with President Thomas S. Monson and President James E. Faust as his counselors. I watched the young women when, for the first time in history, you were asked to stand as a separate group; and I asked myself, “Do the young women know what it means to sustain?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets.p7" pid="kt-aovcd40Gdkks-RHPBIQ" hash="1JPukw">President Hinckley said at that conference: “The procedure of sustaining is much more than a ritualistic raising of the hand. It is a commitment to uphold, to support, to assist those who have been selected” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1995, 51). When we sustain, it affects our behavior. President Hinckley also quoted the Doctrine and Covenants, section 107, verse 22, where we are told that the First Presidency, or “three Presiding High Priests,” are “appointed and ordained to that office, and upheld by the confidence, faith, and prayer of the church.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets.p8" pid="aMR3qMCF6UeUU5VqBHsYUA" hash="LYkzqQ">I often discuss our theme with young women and ask what it means to them to “stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things, and in all places” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:9</a>; quoted in <span class="emphasis">Personal Progress</span> [booklet, 1990], 6). I believe it means that we show by our behavior what we believe. Surely we are standing as witnesses of God when we sustain his living prophets, especially when we know what it means to sustain. We will abide by the direction and counsel of the prophets. We indeed become witnesses when we make this solemn covenant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets.p9" pid="YA8_GOCG90OHTXf3q4z6_g" hash="Q8TXnA">As a young child, I believed we had a prophet and that he spoke the truth; but I’m not sure I understood that the prophet was speaking to me personally. When I was a young wife and mother, my husband spent two years in the air force. We lived in military housing on Long Island, New York. While tending our young children, I often visited with neighbors who had come from all over the country. One day as a neighbor and I were talking about our beliefs, she became curious about what was different about The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets.p10" pid="5g7oacMOnES6o-oVuG0VfA" hash="8Ob0Uw">I told her briefly about the Restoration, and I explained that the restored Church of Jesus Christ has a living prophet today. This really seemed to pique her interest, and she wanted to know what the prophet had said. As I started to tell her about the Doctrine and Covenants and modern revelation, she said, “But what has he said lately?” I told her about general conference and that the Church had a monthly publication with a message from the prophet. Then she got really interested. I was so embarrassed to admit that I hadn’t read the current message. She concluded our conversation by saying, “You mean you have a living prophet and you don’t know what he said?” In that situation I hadn’t shown what it meant to sustain.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets.p11" pid="IdCIVoquGU6-Uh1IF9KtuA" hash="pHEtCQ">I’ll suggest another way to think of the word <span class="emphasis">sustain.</span> When you play a violin, if it is in tune you can move the bow across one string and the other strings vibrate. The harmonious strings not only help sustain the sound, but they enlarge and carry the sound.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets.p12" pid="dTbImYcKJEmdBCRu-oVZLw" hash="kRa4ug">As each of us listens to the prophet and responds to his message, if we are in tune we can carry his message with us. Others will feel the prophet’s message because of the way we act. In this way the message doesn’t end tonight—it just begins. Isn’t that exciting to think about? We can make his message be a force for good in our own lives, but also in our homes, in our neighborhoods, and at school.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets.p13" pid="CIlueTNcy0Sx_TrEyf5TPw" hash="QObOig">When the prophets speak to us, it is as if our Heavenly Father is speaking to us. In the first section of the Doctrine and Covenants, verse 38, it states, “Whether by mine own voice or by the voice of my servants, it is the same.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets.p14" pid="4HGkfJG-zUmGJnst-PSSfQ" hash="xuJGmQ">Fortunately, in this day of satellites and modern technology we can see and hear the prophet. We can read and reread his messages. This blessing is not yet available to many young women in distant lands. This is a sacred night for those of us who have gathered to hear President Hinckley’s message for young women.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets.p15" pid="rqpnEas1UE6bf0ZiX4z9Ag" hash="AurBQA">Tonight, as President Gordon B. Hinckley has a message for each one of us, we as young women, mothers, and leaders want him to know that we have a message for him and his counselors, President Monson and President Faust. <span class="emphasis">We</span> sustain you. We know what it means to sustain: we will abide by the direction and counsel you give us. We will uphold you by our confidence, faith, and prayers. In general conference next week, as we young women and leaders raise our hands to sustain the living prophets, we understand that we are making a solemn covenant. We know as we follow the counsel and direction of the living prophets, we will be better prepared to “make and keep sacred covenants, receive the ordinances of the temple, and enjoy the blessings of exaltation” (<span class="emphasis">Personal Progress,</span> 6).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets.p16" pid="tnenwZJf60Odx6m_HuWCTg" hash="QvyhpA">It is my prayer that we will show by our behavior that we are a covenant people, that we sustain the living prophets. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1996/04/sustaining-the-living-prophets</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/1996-general-young-women-meeting/1996-03-0010-janette-hales-beckham-64k-eng.mp3" length="4150022" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 1996 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Pioneers</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We must have faith to walk away from those things that would tear us down or hold us back. … We must have faith in every footstep.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_97905_000_041" doc-version="2" hash="5s22bQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="feg79g2ONUGj75AFZSBhsw" hash="1ePD7w">Modern Pioneers</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="h5UCUfhvdUqv6IQYQ_XHvw" hash="kcgPrQ">Janette Hales Beckham</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="fI3t9GNp5kCDfR3BFjLTvQ" hash="nvyM7A">We must have faith to walk away from those things that would tear us down or hold us back. … We must have faith in every footstep.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e58.jpg" alt="President Janette Hales Beckham" pid="w3Tt9Hbo40uZIb5RzPOSnA" hash="OwLG5A" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p1" pid="ULYeNwxzH0CmX0haGNBR0Q" hash="iBdwLw">Tonight I pay tribute to these three young pioneers and to each of you—the pioneers of this generation. You pioneers must have the same faith in every footstep as the pioneers of the past. I am so proud of you as I see young women leading the way through acts of courage and righteousness. Your faith in the Lord helps to strengthen others who look to you as an example.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p2" pid="cwOmSwVOrUuaBsf4E55a_g" hash="eguF9A">The Apostle Paul counseled a youth in his time to be a pioneer. He said, “Let no man despise thy youth; but be thou an example of the believers, in word, in conversation, in charity, in spirit, in faith, in purity” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-tim/4.12" class="scriptureRef">1 Tim. 4:12</a>). That is the theme for my remarks to you tonight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p3" pid="9mGzfnL4IEWcacVnvUWpuA" hash="FRZjbA">Whether you are a Beehive, a Mia Maid, or a Laurel, you can be an example to others—an example of the believers. Gospel principles are the same yesterday, today, and tomorrow. The commitment to keep the commandments is the same in every generation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p4" pid="UbEIK-9FBkuWKpKJIO0qAQ" hash="ImHFAA">You young women often have struggles just as difficult to face as the pioneers who came before. One young woman wrote, “You always hear about people today saying they don’t know how the pioneers got through all their hardships, but I’m sure some that are in heaven are saying the same things about us today.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p5" pid="Pa622nEjwE-VO3MXM4VpUw" hash="k85JzQ">The courage to take a step of faith is needed today as never before. For many of you, the first step of faith was baptism. LeeAnn was 15 years old when she read the Book of Mormon, prayed about it, and gained a testimony of the gospel. She wanted to join the Church, but her mother said no. LeeAnn and the missionaries fasted and prayed. That same day her mother agreed she could join the Church, so LeeAnn was baptized. When her friends found out, they laughed at her and deserted her. Even the principal of the religious school she was attending called her in and told her that she had made a foolish mistake. But she stayed faithful to the Lord. She understood the eternal perspective, and eventually she had the wonderful blessing of marrying a righteous young man in the temple. Her mother eventually joined the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p6" pid="xjt2-Gqhd06e6UGeeABENQ" hash="OMLgyQ">Kara also became a pioneer in her family. She came from a family that never attended church meetings. Her eighth birthday came and went, and she was not baptized. But with the same courage of those faithful pioneers, she approached her father when she turned 12 and asked if she could be baptized. He said yes. Now she has been married in the temple, and she can instill her pioneering strength, her integrity, and her faith in her own children. What a wonderful pioneer heritage she has given to them!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p7" pid="HMbRcQLuBUeNBnnmsrj_vg" hash="kaG8Ww">Just as the early pioneers sacrificed to make their way to the Rocky Mountains, modern pioneers like LeeAnn, Kara, and all of you are also on the trail to a mountain—“the mountain of the Lord’s house” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/2.2" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 2:2</a>). That’s the way the prophet Isaiah referred to latter-day temples, where we make sacred covenants with our Heavenly Father. It is the most important destination we have here on earth. As we make sacred covenants with our Heavenly Father in the temple, He promises us that we will be able to live with Him again. As you plan and prepare for the temple, your example can make you a pioneer to your friends and also your family members.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p8" pid="Wn5ueJ0iK0qdj88KFmMxrQ" hash="61rPVg">One important step of faith for you as a pioneer is to resist going along with the crowd in ways that would lead you astray. A modern pioneer also encourages others to stay on course. When you lead out in righteousness, others will follow you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p9" pid="rU8uitZNk02H5_3DFt0YEQ" hash="fY5Prw">One young woman named Allison told us about a friend who is an example to her because her friend chose not to gossip. She encouraged other friends not to. They listened, and Allison and her friends quit gossiping.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p10" pid="4SSBm6wgEkCjS-zlZddecQ" hash="QCkI1Q">When Rachel became a teenager, her friends started swearing more and more. She knew that was wrong. Rachel had the courage to go against what others were doing. She chose not to swear. Through her example, she was a modern pioneer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p11" pid="ZIMbCnir6U-sr5OkhXOLBg" hash="FEEkTA">Danielle is a Beehive class president. She tries to be a good example for the other girls in her class by attending all of her meetings. She lives in an area where drugs and violence are a major problem. “I have chosen not to be involved with those kinds of people,” she wrote. “I do not want to ruin my life. I have chosen to keep the commandments and follow Heavenly Father by doing what is right and by following in His footsteps.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p12" pid="vNYZsvicPkCZ6QVtpIK2cA" hash="46ssnw">Another young woman, Melinda, was in junior high, and a couple of boys in a mall offered alcohol to her and her friend. Melinda didn’t know what to do, but her best friend told the boys she and Melinda didn’t drink. The boys made fun of them, but it didn’t matter. Melinda said, “[My friend] leads the way for others … just like a pioneer. … Latter-day pioneers keep me on the path to the celestial kingdom, and I’m so thankful for them.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p13" pid="jQa7fA6Iw02SgXAsRHqP3A" hash="aGHhVQ">So many of you young women are great examples. I know about a group of young women who make a point at lunchtime of sitting by someone eating alone and becoming a friend to that person. Some of you have family difficulties, yet you stay strong in the gospel. Some of you are the only active members in your families. One young woman in a large city has to transfer to three different buses just to get to sacrament meeting on her own.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p14" pid="0pdgH5RD1EGP_0m2z06TJA" hash="iaqfng">The Lord loves you for your strength and your courage. He is always there for you. You are not alone. He has promised us that when we are trying to live righteously and are serving Him, “I will be on your right hand and on your left, and my Spirit shall be in your hearts, and mine angels round about you, to bear you up” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.88" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:88</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p15" pid="C075-Ax88U2oZtjYOM1kgw" hash="llr5kw">We have asked some of you young women to tell us about the noble characteristics of the pioneers around you. It is not surprising that often you described members of your families—a mother or father, a grandmother or grandfather, an older sister or brother. You often see your leaders as pioneers, whether it is your adviser, your camp director, or your bishop.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p16" pid="4ptB8e5xn0eSiy7lrJbYwA" hash="yJUVXw">One young woman said, “I am so grateful for my modern pioneer mother. She broke the tradition of alcoholism in her family. She joined the Church at age 15 after spending a summer with Latter-day Saint relatives. She worked hard in school. She developed a commitment that has brought the blessings of gospel living to our family.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p17" pid="QLZUvU2-sEWy12KEUytAIQ" hash="PA7Vbg">Our priesthood leaders seated on the stand tonight are fathers and grandfathers. Their children and grandchildren surely see them as pioneers. A young woman named Tarynn told us that her grandpa was the pioneer in her life. His life was hard and he had many trials and tribulations, but no matter how hard it was, he always stayed faithful. A pioneer, she said, is someone who has touched another’s life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p18" pid="U4jSI2OvU0qQjtVLMLPTHg" hash="UCKMig">How grateful we are this night to be able to listen to a member of the First Presidency, President Thomas S. Monson. He is a great pioneer of this day who has touched many lives. When I was called to be the Young Women general president, President Monson said to me, “Tell the young women to keep the commandments so they can have all of the blessings Heavenly Father wants so badly to give them.” The words of our prophets can help us to be sure that our steps are secure.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p19" pid="JGzTMSQfOU6A-MF0hx_5iQ" hash="UKqJFA">One young woman said, “My brother decided to follow the counsel of the prophet [when he began dating] to date … no one exclusively.” He recognized that many youth live in an atmosphere where it seems that almost everyone is pairing off and dating. She added, “He was extremely creative and careful to maintain high standards and keep good company. This may seem a small thing, but it impressed me and helped me to do the same thing as I began dating. When you are promoting righteousness, you’re being a hero in someone else’s life.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p20" pid="P7YB9Jr-A0yFP2x8pg5Imw" hash="JTwBHw">There will be many occasions this year to remember the early pioneers, and each of us—the pioneers of today—must have the same character and determination. We must have faith to walk away from those things that would tear us down or hold us back from our destination. We must have faith in every footstep. We must listen to the words of our prophets, love the Lord, and keep His commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p21" pid="wxvzvvuEZEyWwdAJReH6Yg" hash="STkZtw">A young woman named Stephanie has the eternal perspective about being a pioneer. She said, “Like the pioneers who walked across the plains and eventually found Zion in the mountains, I will, if I live righteously, eventually arrive at my destination of living with Jesus Christ and Heavenly Father. It will not be easy, but I know I can and will make it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p22" pid="TeVRUVO320m3zeliDwGKNQ" hash="b_j8lw">Young sisters, you can make it. Heavenly Father wants you to. Your faith and courage and determination will bring you to “the mountain of the Lord’s house”—the holy temple—as you prepare to “make and keep sacred covenants, receive the ordinances of the temple, and enjoy the blessings of exaltation” (<span class="emphasis">Young Women Leadership Handbook</span> [1995], 4). Your steps of faith will bless future generations. Through you, your children and your grandchildren will receive the blessings the Lord has promised those who follow Him. If only you could see those whom you will influence—not just your friends, but your children and their children!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p23" pid="V6Iubo38k0i5FkFOcPIG-g" hash="oV2XVQ">I have tremendous faith in you young women. I see you struggle to overcome difficulties. I see so many of you living righteously—courageously “holding aloft our colors” (“Carry On,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 255), holding on to the Young Women Values, showing others the way to follow, helping one another when the going is rough. You are truly the pioneers of this generation. I love each one of you so much! And I know how much our Heavenly Father loves you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p24" pid="tgaJKX2_xkGHTOUG4YYT1A" hash="1LFq9A">Many years ago when I was attending a Young Women camp, I met with the young women and their leaders early one morning in a wooded area they called their sacred grove. As I looked into their faces, I realized I had been given a wonderful blessing that has remained with me. I can see divine nature. I look into your faces and see what Heavenly Father sees—your divine potential. Be an example of the believers. Stand as a witness of God as you move forward in faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers.p25" pid="WpnLrZJNbk2MZUDN2O_t9g" hash="nkKfjg">Listen again to the words of the Apostle Paul: “Let no man despise thy youth; but be thou an example of the believers, in word, in conversation, in charity, in spirit, in faith, in purity” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-tim/4.12" class="scriptureRef">1 Tim. 4:12</a>). As the pioneers of this generation, may our faith keep us on the path of eternal life, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1997/04/modern-pioneers</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/1997-general-young-women-meeting/1997-03-0060-janette-hales-beckham-64k-eng.mp3" length="6304062" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 1997 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Faith a Reality</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Fundamentals of daily living—scripture reading, prayer, family home evening, the conversation at dinner—these provide the experiences that make faith a reality.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_97911_000_030" doc-version="2" hash="rnHjpA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="74Lo1UlAy0yyY7rRZSkNaQ" hash="dtBp1Q">Making Faith a Reality</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ZcxayaXW2EurZO-wPG0d3g" hash="kcgPrQ">Janette Hales Beckham</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="3BDsNiYFc0eeOLbBKYJORA" hash="xauaEQ">Fundamentals of daily living—scripture reading, prayer, family home evening, the conversation at dinner—these provide the experiences that make faith a reality.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e58.jpg" alt="Janette Hales Beckham" pid="nHqz3-asvk6fDKJAPbXZLw" hash="OwLG5A" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p1" pid="gxy7-vSh80C6GINvhZC1Lw" hash="2w2YQA">It would be difficult to imagine a more pure and perfect example of innocence than a newborn baby. We just returned from welcoming a new grandson. As I held little Benjamin, I recalled a question asked of me by the editor of a national magazine. In an interview she inquired, “How do you prepare your young people to live in the real world?” Our visit reminded me that our perception of the real world to some extent is dependent on our experience. She and I could quickly relate to the challenges in the world, but for me preparation for the <span class="emphasis">real</span> world has a dimension of faith that hers did not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p2" pid="ttK5Rcpa0U-LjzWmGurlXg" hash="GXdAFw">Our discussion caused me to consider with renewed appreciation the experiences that help make faith a reality in a person’s life. In order to have faith, or know that we have faith, we need to have experience with faith. For little Benjamin that experience has begun already as his mother and father join in prayer with his older brother before he is tucked into bed. As an infant, he is a witness of faith in his family. He is gaining experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p3" pid="sk5HrODAak6_S3L72tVdAA" hash="lEETZA">After Primary a few weeks ago our four-year-old grandson, Michael, reported to his parents, “When I pray, my heart feels like a roasted marshmallow.” Already Michael is recognizing the feelings associated with faith. How fortunate that he is willing and able to identify and talk about his feelings with his parents.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p4" pid="y1c0BR4VX0Kx2v3g4sabQQ" hash="NS_rvw">The prophet Alma described these feelings when he said, “For ye know that the word hath swelled your souls, … that your understanding doth begin to be enlightened. … O then, is not this real? I say unto you, Yea, because it is light; and whatsoever is light, is good, because it is discernible” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.34-35" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:34–35</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p5" pid="ZPRhY1YzW0iPF_VUL-z7ng" hash="fwcntg">Learning to discern the teachings of the Spirit is an important part of helping faith become a reality. My daughter Karen shared her experience. She said, “When I was just a little girl, I started reading the Book of Mormon for the first time. After many days of reading, I came one night to 1 Nephi 3:7 [<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 3:7</a>]: ‘I will go and do the things which the Lord hath commanded, for I know that the Lord giveth no commandments unto the children of men, save he shall prepare a way for them that they may accomplish the thing which he commandeth them.’” Karen continued: “I didn’t know this was a famous verse, but as I read that verse, I felt strongly impressed. I was impressed that Heavenly Father would help us keep His commandments, but the deep impression was really more of a feeling. I had seen my parents mark verses in their scriptures with red pencils. So I got up and searched through the house until I found a red pencil, and with a great sense of solemnity and importance, I marked that verse in my own Book of Mormon.” Karen continued, “Over the years as I read the scriptures, that experience was repeated time and time again—reading a verse and feeling deeply impressed. In time I came to recognize that feeling as the Holy Ghost. As a missionary I saw others read verses and feel deeply impressed to the extent that they were willing and able to change their lives and accept the gospel.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p6" pid="mdiFVVsJWk-UOq3Ue3v-wg" hash="X1FNTA">As we are learning to discern the promptings of the Spirit, there are so many distractions. At one time President Ezra Taft Benson reminded us that “the world shouts louder than the whisperings of the Holy Ghost” (“Beware of Pride,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1989, 5). Each of us has to learn to be sensitive and to listen to the whisper.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p7" pid="DaD-Vf_-H0uPio-RYmiFYA" hash="nhPCww">Years ago a friend was feeling challenged as she saw the world shouting at her family. She said, “I wish we could lock our children in the temple until they turn 21.” That solution might have kept them innocent, but that is not the plan. Just as Adam and Eve had to leave the Garden of Eden, spiritual maturity requires that we have experience in this world. It is experience that helps us know good from evil. It is experience that helps us recognize the promptings of the Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p8" pid="bts12onisk6-o9XatnF01g" hash="TdG0Mw">Experience can also help us recognize when <span class="emphasis">good</span> feelings are lacking. In the booklet <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth,</span> it states: “You cannot do wrong and feel right. It is impossible!” (pamphlet, 1990, 4). A young woman said: “The past few weeks I have come back to the Church. I went to my bishop and repented and I’ve been trying to live the gospel.” She added, “I have learned something: when I do good, I feel good.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p9" pid="tzQ04CtZVkqsa9sWy6dYOg" hash="HHEoIg">Our Heavenly Father knew we would make mistakes as we learn to make choices. He provided a Savior for us. Elder Bruce C. Hafen said because of “the Atonement of Jesus Christ [we may] <span class="emphasis">learn</span> from our experience without being <span class="emphasis">condemned</span> by that experience” (“Eve Heard All These Things and Was Glad,” in <span class="emphasis">Women in the Covenant of Grace,</span> ed. Dawn Hall Fletcher and Susette Fletcher Green [1994], 32; emphasis added). We need to know how the Atonement works in our lives and how good feelings can be regained and retained when mistakes have been made.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p10" pid="lj1IDB3_VE2AQ-lmMmqozw" hash="Uyxjfw">As we gain experience in this demanding “real world,” we sometimes fail to see the sacred nature of our seemingly routine daily tasks. Fundamentals of daily living—scripture reading, prayer, family home evening, the conversation at dinner—these provide the experiences that make faith a reality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p11" pid="JpmqmvNyQ0-bECGAPR1mvg" hash="xBjvJA">Arthur Henry King, in discussing the importance of scripture reading, wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p12" pid="26x6G-RvY0K55hgds80y8g" hash="WzO3xg">“Some may think that the language of the scriptures is too difficult for children, but … [w]e need to remember that the Lord has given children faculties for learning language even greater than those of adults. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p13" pid="tPl52gAVp0iN8yJcudTbZA" hash="sbPdpg">“It is good for children to hear their favorite passages of scripture, and their other favorite stories, too, over and over. … We should <span class="emphasis">not</span> bring up our children to respond to the exciting, the thrilling. … They are a titillation of the nerves. To be <span class="emphasis">moved</span> is one thing; to be excited or titillated, a very different thing. If we bring up our children always to be wanting something new, … they will have to have a stronger [and stronger] stimulus each time until they finally [burst]. But if we inure our children to stability, to repetition, to normal life … , then they will live decent lives” (<span class="emphasis">The Abundance of the Heart</span> [1986], 222–23; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p14" pid="49zzZWJ0jUmz8aa2XKUy8Q" hash="ttV32w">The time we spend with children and youth in their growing years provides the experience that is preparation for the real world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p15" pid="bzJ9rCTN8UiAcS71lB7DKw" hash="9EApGw">A young man returning from his mission shared his experience with faith. He acknowledged it as a miracle in his life. He said, “I was the first of six children born to my parents. My mother and father taught me when I was young the principles of the gospel. Faith was taught through the example of both my mother and father. When I was only 10 years old, my father, this great example of trusting the Lord, was killed in an accident. I was young and had many feelings to deal with that were new to me.” This young man said he realized that he had two choices available to him, “I could have become bitter towards the Lord and lost all that I now have, or I could trust the Lord. Because of the example of my parents, trust was the path I chose. Choosing faith has made all of the difference.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p16" pid="H7UCjcB_X0y9Utl3OdqrsA" hash="HppdeQ">Being a witness of the faith of young people has increased my faith. One young mother wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p17" pid="-DwVtFNsjE634R75TuNCsQ" hash="zaPq7w">“When I was 13 I knew my life was not worth living. I was living in an abusive home where there never seemed to be lasting happiness. My two best friends told me they didn’t want to be friends with me anymore because I thought I was too good for them, which made no sense but left me feeling completely alone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p18" pid="xPfQUA-f7Ei9ddL6P-rdnw" hash="hyq6pw">“As the battles in my house continued to rage, I went to my bedroom. I was so scared. I knelt and called to the one person I still knew I had. I pleaded to my Father in Heaven to somehow take me home. I said, ‘Father, I need to be with you. I need to feel your arms around me.’ As I sat crying and quietly waiting in that desperate moment for Heavenly Father’s arms to reach down, I heard a voice, ‘Put your arms around yourself, and I will be with you.’ As I followed that prompting, I felt Heavenly Father’s love assure me that I could go on, and I would go on and I was not alone.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p19" pid="G8Zw2zjikEWdQnHcX7rAFw" hash="A5Etgg">At a difficult time, this young woman turned to Heavenly Father. Her experience made her faith stronger and more real. The reward of her faith is evident in her temple marriage and family life today (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.42-43" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:42–43</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p20" pid="xIms-qxIBkCGbtQkkSWLhA" hash="rNldxA">I am so thankful for leaders who encourage us to commit to experiences that help build faith. The auxiliaries of the Church are a resource to families in strengthening the faith of members. The Personal Progress program encourages each young woman to make commitments that will help make her faith a reality. Her choices invite her to make a commitment, carry it out, and report to someone. It is the process of progress. It is very much the same process we go through as we accept callings in the Church—make a commitment, carry it out, and report to someone. One of the miracles of the Restoration of the gospel and the organization of the Church in these latter days is that the plan allows growth and change to come to the members. We each have available to us the experience that will help us change—to become spiritually mature. Through our own repeated efforts, our faith can become a reality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality.p21" pid="Y7zzELWHMUas3F8vKd6DlA" hash="mI_OWw">May I, in concluding my service, express my love and appreciation to the many who have counseled and supported me—the First Presidency, priesthood leaders, and the other auxiliary leaders. My counselors, past and present, the Young Women general board, and the Young Women office staff are magnificent women, women of faith. Wherever they serve, their names will be known for good. I express gratitude to my Heavenly Father for my experience here, in the name of His Son, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1997/10/making-faith-a-reality</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1997-general-conference/1997-10-5030-janette-hales-beckham-64k-eng.mp3" length="5712714" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 1997 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
