<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Jayne B. Malan</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Jayne B. Malan.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Jayne%20B.%20Malan.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Jayne B. Malan.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 1989 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Summer of the Lambs</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The day school was out at the beginning of each summer, our family went to our ranch in Wyoming. It was there with my parents and brothers and sisters, and a few cousins mixed in, that I learned about family loyalty; love and concern; birth and death</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03245_000_030" doc-version="2" hash="LVDF9A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="McPGbSYbWECgAtHmngvgUg" hash="KoxjuA">The Summer of the Lambs</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="VmtCm7aSkkGwsvLkO6DHhg" hash="d_k62A">Jayne B. Malan</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-254a.jpg" alt="Jayne B. Malan" pid="5lSWUhqVm0-q5tju_Qbq7Q" hash="Eb-fXQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p1" pid="jJ9mBN5Q4U64pK9UcXM4WA" hash="ejWWsA">The day school was out at the beginning of each summer, our family went to our ranch in Wyoming. It was there with my parents and brothers and sisters, and a few cousins mixed in, that I learned about family loyalty; love and concern; birth and death; that one must finish a job once it is started; and, to quote my father, “There are only two things important—the family and the Church.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p2" pid="81-lq5aOJEycCyhHus1_1A" hash="GRWKPQ">One year my father was waiting for us as we arrived. He said he had a big job for my brother Clay and me to do that summer. I was about twelve at the time, and my brother was two years older. Pointing to the field by the side of the house, my father said, “Do you see all of these lambs in that field? I’ll share the money we get for the ones you raise when we sell them in the fall.” Well, we were excited. Not only did we have a significant job to do, but we were going to be rich! There were a lot of lambs in that field—about 350 of them. And all we had to do was feed them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p3" pid="Giogh2zxfEqWAgAcOLzgQQ" hash="zEMtaA">However, there was one thing that my father hadn’t mentioned. None of the lambs had mothers. Just after shearing, there was a violent storm that chilled the newly shorn sheep. Dad lost a thousand ewes that year. The mothers of our lambs were among them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p4" pid="NBlAQGTzEEmTQhy7qbEqDw" hash="zmWiSg">To feed one or two baby animals is one thing, but to feed 350 is something else! It was hard. There was plenty of grass, but the lambs couldn’t eat the grass. They didn’t have teeth. They needed milk. So we made some long, V-shaped feeding troughs out of some boards. Then we got a great big tin washtub, ground up some grain, and added milk to make a thin mash. While my brother poured the mash into the troughs, I rounded up the lambs, herded them to the troughs, and said, “Eat!” Well, they just stood there looking at me. Although they were hungry and there was food in front of them, they still wouldn’t eat. No one had taught them to drink milk out of a trough. So I tried <span class="emphasis">pushing</span> them toward the troughs. Do you know what happens when you try to push sheep? They run the other way. And when you lose one, you <span class="emphasis">could</span> lose them all because others will follow. That’s the way with sheep.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p5" pid="Km5Io6c3_EGQTamaHNm7CA" hash="FcIbNA">We tried lining up the lambs along the troughs and pushing their noses down in the milk, hoping they’d get a taste and want some more. We tried wiggling our fingers in the milk to get them to suck on our fingers. Some of them would drink, but most of them ran away.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p6" pid="DipSpgT5ck-qE3KAeLTAYQ" hash="ePgboQ">Many of the lambs were slowly starving to death. The only way we could be sure they were being fed was to pick them up in our arms, two at a time, and feed them like babies.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p7" pid="d6Xjj-l0JUy9cTKnng2Qmw" hash="f8ElQQ">And then there were the coyotes. At night the coyotes would sit up on the hill, and they’d howl. The next morning we would see the results of their night’s work, and we would have two or three more lambs to bury. The coyotes would sneak up on the lambs, scatter the herd, and then pick out the ones they wanted and go after them. The first were those that were weak or separated from the flock. Often in the night when the coyotes came and the lambs were restless, my dad would take out his rifle and shoot in the air to scare them away. We felt secure when my dad was home because we knew our lambs were safe when he was there to watch over them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p8" pid="3IjcEUlLxkeiXdJ-twLYaQ" hash="aLgNNQ">Clay and I soon forgot about being rich. All we wanted to do was save our lambs. The hardest part was seeing them die. Every morning we would find five, seven, ten lambs that had died during the night. Some the coyotes got, and others starved to death surrounded by food they couldn’t or wouldn’t eat.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p9" pid="SQKGqoZr40aI5HPxaB6mmA" hash="3AmEag">Part of our job was to gather up the dead lambs and help dispose of them. I got used to that, and it really wasn’t so bad until I named one of the lambs. It was an awkward little thing with a black spot on its nose. It was always under my feet, and it knew my voice. I loved my lamb. It was one I held in my arms and fed with a bottle like a baby.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p10" pid="JXWYucDeXESg6znNEB_ZbA" hash="fqT4GA">One morning my lamb didn’t come when I called. I found it later that day under the willows by the creek. It was dead. With tears streaming down my face, I picked up my lamb and went to find my father. Looking up at him, I said, “Dad, isn’t there someone who can help us feed our lambs?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p11" pid="pDXLLEco2ECSSp0xObyu5g" hash="phCFtQ">After a long moment he said, “Jayne, once a long, long time ago, someone else said almost those same words. He said, ‘Feed my lambs. … Feed my sheep. … Feed my sheep.’” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/21.15-17" class="scriptureRef">John 21:15–17</a>.) Dad put his arms around me and let me cry for a time, then went with me to bury my lamb.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p12" pid="yKK6fC8cikaqEwuE4fv2yA" hash="nwuTWA">It wasn’t until many years later that I fully realized the meaning of my father’s words. I was pondering the scripture in Moses that says, “For behold, this is my work and my glory—to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of [all mankind].” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>.) As I thought about the mission of the Savior, I remembered the summer of the lambs, and, for a few brief moments, I thought I could sense how the Savior must feel with so many lambs to feed, so many souls to save. And I knew in my heart that he needed my help.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p13" pid="KQX4-p9TQUqVoqUdVk5jwQ" hash="UJOnUA">You wonderful young people, from what we’ve observed, you’re not unlike our lambs. You, too, are hungry—hungry for things of the Spirit that will make you grow strong and keep you safe from the coyotes that are out to destroy you. You are capable and willing to do your part in building the kingdom when you are taught how. And we want to help you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p14" pid="0H14J2QTdEejghFslftj6w" hash="apPCBQ">We know that you need someone to love you, someone to listen and understand. You need to be needed. You need opportunities to come together in a safe environment, a safe fold so to speak, where you can share with one another and develop wholesome friendships based on brother-sister relationships rather than romantic involvement. You need opportunities to experience the joy of sacrifice and service, of caring for and loving one another as our Savior loves us. Within the gospel we have what you need, but you will need to reach out and accept it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p15" pid="P9ku3hn-m0ayrhFfVvbtTg" hash="JhEziQ">It would have been far easier to save our lambs if the mothers had been there to feed them. Young women, you are the mothers of tomorrow. Young men, you are the fathers. Together, you are the parents, the teachers, and the advisers who will help nurture and feed young lambs and lead them home. Prepare yourselves now for that sacred responsibility. Study the scriptures. Develop your God-given talents. Learn all you can about the world around you that is clean and good. Prepare yourselves to enter the temple of the Lord and be worthy to receive the ordinances and blessings by living, teaching, and sharing the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p16" pid="D6yxxYJw_0Kncq0kLEJ-sA" hash="beY_AQ">Your Heavenly Father knows you and cares about what you are doing. He wants you to fulfill your divine mission, then come home and bring your family and friends with you. He wants you to be happy. Be on your knees daily and talk to your Heavenly Father. Share the happy times. Talk about what’s hard for you. Like my father, your Heavenly Father will understand. He’ll be there to walk with you, and to comfort and protect you, for he has promised to those who seek him, “I will be on your right hand and on your left, and my Spirit shall be in your hearts, and mine angels round about you, to bear you up.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.88" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:88</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p17" pid="0C4hCs0iqk6kiiQnuLM8Ww" hash="L9xUiA">Our prophet, President Benson, has said, “The symbolism of the Good Shepherd is not without significant parallel in the Church today.” The sheep need to be led by watchful shepherds. “With a shepherd’s loving care, our young people, our young lambs, will not be as inclined to wander. And if they do, the crook of the shepherd’s staff, a loving arm, and an understanding heart will help to retrieve them.” (Regional Representatives’ Seminar, 3 Apr. 1987.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p18" pid="BguKAHj8kECh25zn11N55Q" hash="f6TfAQ">Parents, priesthood leaders, teachers, advisers, be “watchful shepherds”; and you, our noble youth, band together in the strength of the Lord and lead out in righteousness. Reach out with loving arms and understanding hearts to those who are weak or wandering. Help bring them back to the fold, where they can learn of the Good Shepherd and grow close to him. And please choose carefully the paths you walk, for others will follow. That’s the way with sheep.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p19" pid="dQt3Au4oyUCBeeanaDDkiA" hash="huINWA">Of our little flock, we saved only one-third. And what of the Savior’s flock? He has said, “Feed my lambs. … Feed my sheep.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs.p20" pid="EOReswcAnEq9zbvZ9y6H-Q" hash="9Jjc6g">This I know: He needs our help. With more people to help, more lambs will be saved. A simple fact, but true. Of this I can bear testimony in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1989/10/the-summer-of-the-lambs</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1989-general-conference/1989-10-5040-jayne-b-malan-64k-eng.mp3" length="4839086" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 1989 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>These Are Your Days</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days?lang=eng</link>
      <description>When I was released as a stake Young Women president, I was surprised to find that it was camp that I missed most of all. I missed the fun and excitement of young women learning to appreciate the world around them, and the tender testimonies of those</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_91911_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="s589DA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="cU-AM38xI0CSoivM9CW8eQ" hash="Yy1x2A">These Are Your Days</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="fP96dJdTeEaaHCniy3U8Gg" hash="d_k62A">Jayne B. Malan</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-254a.jpg" alt="Jayne B. Malan" pid="0V0SprGS0UipQ5NJrychzQ" hash="Eb-fXQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p1" pid="pePk1OuiRkuzyOOlW1wv0Q" hash="4tqCGg">When I was released as a stake Young Women president, I was surprised to find that it was camp that I missed most of all. I missed the fun and excitement of young women learning to appreciate the world around them, and the tender testimonies of those who had “never felt that way before.” I missed the young women I had grown to love. And I missed sleeping under the stars.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p2" pid="XKh1SK2I9UCDf8ha3I75Sw" hash="5lHqVA">There’s something magic about sleeping under the stars at a Young Women camp, especially on a dark night when there’s no moon and the stars are bright. It’s a perfect setting for quiet talks about things that matter most and for music. No matter how tired the girls may be, there’s music—little groups singing somewhere in the dark as they settle in for the night—and, at times, the faraway sound of a ukulele or guitar. I found that sleeping outside keeps one closer to the action when someone needs help or comfort or counsel in the middle of the night.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p3" pid="weJoFXG7fEG-EQydQze9tA" hash="zxEZMw">It had been a night such as this that last year I went to camp. About the time the last tearful campers were tucked into bed and the camp was finally quiet, I noticed the first hint of morning in the sky. We had been looking for a place to hold a sunrise service, and because I was still awake, this seemed to be the perfect time to find it. So I slipped out of my sleeping bag and headed up a little trail through the trees. Coming up over a small rise, I found a grassy meadow where you could look out over the valley and the mountains to the north. I stood there for a long time watching the sky grow lighter and the clouds turn from grey to pink and then white.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p4" pid="oq2t0IHdZka6NzOZ8N5pfA" hash="JO7LUw">As it grew light, the mountains across the valley seemed in some way to be familiar to me even though I had never been in this location before. I dismissed the thought at first, and then realized that I was looking at the back side of the same mountains that I knew so very well from a different viewpoint. These were the mountains that I could see from my bedroom window at the ranch when I was a child growing up. Many times I had watched them change color on stormy days as clouds would gather over them, and the rain came down the valley where our ranch was located.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p5" pid="WPVBCe4pbkm-XVExRPQfgQ" hash="6tCuQg">Memories flooded back of my mother and father and their love for me. I thought of my Heavenly Father and how he had blessed me. As I stood there watching the sunrise, I could feel the warmth of the Savior’s loving, guiding hand. I knew without being told that I was a literal daughter of God and, because of the sacrifice of his Son, I can be with my earthly parents again some day and live in the presence of our Heavenly Father. I had taught this truth many times to others, but this morning it seemed as if I had discovered it for the first time. Perhaps I really had. I had received a witness of the Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p6" pid="l21DM4ixJ0u8NQVoKPzghw" hash="2dhqNw">Standing on that hilltop, I thanked my Heavenly Father for what I knew. And I promised to dedicate my life to his service. I can’t express the joy of that moment. I wanted to hurry back to camp and wake everyone up. I wanted to tell them who they really are, daughters of God! I wanted to tell them to have faith, to talk to our Heavenly Father—to stop worrying about little things or things they can’t change. I wanted them to know that God lives and watches over us, and through his Son, Jesus Christ, all things are possible. All he asks is that we do the best we can with what we have and stay close to him. I wanted to tell them, “You’re a daughter of God and he loves you. He needs you—every one of you! Do you know that?!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p7" pid="qPtZKv0HykS5hcRaux19Rg" hash="u4WbAA">When I got back to camp, I didn’t wake them up. People don’t listen very well when they’re half asleep. I saved it for another time—for today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p8" pid="J92ZqbcCmEqx7i-z2-3DIQ" hash="ekrAIg">My young sisters, do <span class="emphasis">you</span> know that you are daughters of God? If each one of you could only have a sure knowledge of this for yourself, you would have a sweet peace in your heart and confidence to meet any challenges that life may bring. There would never be a question of what to do when temptations come your way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p9" pid="sD1-mHsev0W7DzMfubeldg" hash="bFMy9Q">Many of you know what I’m saying is true. You <span class="emphasis">know </span>who you are. You have felt the Savior’s loving, guiding hand as you have followed the promptings of the Holy Ghost and have found the peace I speak of in your hearts. People around you can tell who you are; they can see it in your eyes and feel the spirit you radiate as they associate with you. We have met many of you as we have traveled throughout the world. We have heard you make your commitment to stand “as [a witness] of God at all times and in all things, and in all places” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:9</a>) as you have repeated the Young Women theme in many different languages. We have hugged a lot of you and talked to many of you. How thrilled we are to see how prayer, scriptures, and living the gospel in preparation for temple blessings have become part of your lives!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p10" pid="bgvQF9fQ8ESacDJnOKaIlQ" hash="2cbmxw">Janalyn is one. Each year, for the Days of ’47 celebration in the state of Utah, three young women are selected to represent the descendants of the Mormon pioneers. Jana had received national recognition for her outstanding community service and was among the finalists. As she waited on stage for the final selection, she found herself repeating the Young Women theme in her mind. She could feel that peace in her heart. She thought, “I can stand as a witness of God—even here, at this time and in this place.” Her only desire was “to be at the right place at the right time to be the most help for the Lord to build his kingdom.” When it was announced that she had been selected, they asked her to say a few words. She took the microphone and, even though she knew that many in the audience were not Mormons, she bore her testimony. The audience became very quiet as she said, “I fasted. And last night I prayed and told the Lord I would represent him if I received this honor. I’m grateful for this <span class="emphasis">calling </span>to represent my pioneer heritage.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p11" pid="lA--7boCYkGV67qo-kudnQ" hash="kUdycQ">To you, like Janalyn, who know for yourselves you are daughters of God and are living your lives in harmony with that knowledge, we say, “Carry on. Continue on the paths you walk.” These are your days to lead out in righteousness so that others can safely follow and, along with you, prepare to “come unto Christ.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.30" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:30</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p12" pid="dGOzI5_UJk-_UIbNIBXfOg" hash="fqAQmQ">To you who may question your worth and wonder if God really loves you, these are your days to experiment upon the word of God by obeying his commandments and staying close to him. That feeling of love and acceptance cannot come without obedience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p13" pid="QBT-H5Ey3U-GLkEGBrW6HQ" hash="UcAfWA">As it says in this little booklet, <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth,</span> “You cannot do wrong and feel right! It is impossible.” (<span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth,</span> Salt Lake City: The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, 1990, p. 4.) In a spirit of love and concern for you, these standards were outlined by the First Presidency to help you know how to make wise choices and experience the Savior’s love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p14" pid="W_NZdDiXpES3EDVwU3RvwA" hash="ktn4mg">They’re summarized on this little card. Carry it with you all the time to remind you of the standards to live by.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p15" pid="Ry6xcmlN10WNNrmeNvHQUA" hash="ZUk3AQ">To any of you who know you’re doing wrong things, stop now. Repent. Come back. You can do it. There are those who can help you. Your Heavenly Father loves you and needs you, each one of you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p16" pid="_M0eOE8bS0ydZr6LKKkO0Q" hash="5iW-xg">Young women, let your days begin and end with prayer. Read from your scriptures every day. When you pray and talk with your Heavenly Father, when you let him communicate with you through the scriptures and through his Spirit, you will find answers to your prayers—just as Dawn did.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p17" pid="FchSZx4ea0qeRemIEy6_FQ" hash="zyy1jQ">When Dawn’s parents received a mission call to Japan, she was given the choice of going with them or staying behind. Going meant leaving her friends, missing her senior year in high school, and, in general, changing many of her future plans. The decision seemed too hard to make. She said, “I spent a lot of time crying and wondering why this should be happening to me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p18" pid="r8hAm8n08UyJ3f84MhL6lQ" hash="_HW8Wg">She fasted and prayed about the decision. It seemed coincidental that they were studying the Book of Mormon in seminary and were talking about Lehi’s family. In the past she had wondered why Laman and Lemuel had such a hard time choosing the right. It bothered her that they were the older brothers and didn’t set a good example. She began to liken herself to the scriptures. She was the oldest child in the family, and going to Japan was like going into the wilderness for her. She would have to leave a lot of important things behind. She said, “I didn’t want to be a Laman or Lemuel. I wanted to obey my Father in Heaven and do his will.” She knew her decision was right when she told her parents she would love to go to Japan with them and it felt so good.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p19" pid="yKcbzWpFgECwFOQzCjQpTg" hash="W4wfsA">At the farewell, Dawn told her friends how much she loved them and would miss them, then said, “I realize that the greatest friend I have is Jesus Christ. I feel of his love every day.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p20" pid="-5qXJgiBGkidgI6PyVgLdw" hash="DMJqfA">These are your days to look to the scriptures for guidance and to build a closer relationship with the Savior through prayer. He can become <span class="emphasis">your </span>best friend. Through him you can know for yourself that you are a daughter of God. He is the Son of God, the Savior of the world. And you are his sister. Think of that!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p21" pid="PpykU8R_nUmJzEx2zVrWFg" hash="_BGNJA">What an exciting time to live—at this great moment in history when the gospel has been restored in its fulness and borders of nations are opening in dramatic ways to allow the gospel message to spread forth!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p22" pid="q2vaREuPz0qpk5m5W61kgg" hash="IiY78w">Young women, these are your days to prepare to do your part—to take your place in the great forward movement that is rolling across the earth like a mighty wave. Prayer, scripture study, and obedience to the commandments will prepare you to lead out in righteousness for the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p23" pid="BE0DBAMOk0yn4HwFbd2H2w" hash="c5z_YQ">As the Young Women general presidency, we call on you to unite in your wards and branches, to love one another, to gain strength from one another. We call on you to stand together and lead out for morality, to speak against the evil forces of the world. Will you stand for truth and righteousness and lead others who will follow if you will show the way? Will you stand as a witness for our Heavenly Father and his Son Jesus Christ?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p24" pid="UeOBL5K3_E2_f_m8FfwtTA" hash="Rqzs8Q">Hear the words of President Ardeth G. Kapp.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p25" pid="86Zfku_z4UiWysAvb1LVqg" hash="TVtWww">“I can hear a growing chorus of young women’s voices reaching out across the land and across the water and heavenward, responding to the call for righteous young women. I see you standing strong and firm in your faith … filled with the joy of discovery and youth. Caught up in the excitement of doing good deeds and making wise choices. Learning, growing and feeling at home with the beauties of the world. Reaching out and gathering those who may be weaker. Rallying together, gathering strength as the Young Women Values become a part of your life … gathering strength as young women like yourself come together from the mountains, the valleys, the islands of the sea, from arid deserts, and tropical rain forests … wherever the seeds of the gospel have been sown.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p26" pid="SJeBPFkixU2Ev6X-kkVL7A" hash="XJ7rmg">“Reach out to others in a great bond of sisterhood. Unite in righteousness. Hold your banners high for all to see. Don’t be ashamed of the gospel of Christ, for you have a cause and the cause is glorious!” (Young Women fireside, 10 Nov. 1985.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p27" pid="V3AFfE1D8UaXM2LkZ81aqw" hash="WTqBQg">“Look to this day. Arise in all your splendor, and bear the standards of the world-to-be.” (Maude Osmond Cook, cited in <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1977, p. 32.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days.p28" pid="3YhPZ6dd8kODFQVHbzex1A" hash="Pu_Xvg">We honor you, we pray for you, we love you. May God bless you. I say this in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1991/10/these-are-your-days</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1991-general-womens-meeting/1991-09-0030-jayne-b-malan-64k-eng.mp3" length="6905674" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 1991 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
