<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Jean B. Bingham</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Jean B. Bingham.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Jean%20B.%20Bingham.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Jean B. Bingham.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>I Will Bring the Light of the Gospel into My Home</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sister Bingham teaches that we can share the light of the gospel by being kind and nonjudgmental and by developing the gift of charity.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60001311_000_11bingham" doc-version="1" hash="qOU-Vw">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="Egt5gJA6yUO61jx15ceXfQ" hash="FOfofA">I Will Bring the Light of the Gospel into My Home</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p2" pid="gbRLqdxXakaeXWgEinGopQ" hash="P7-0Mg1">By Jean B. Bingham</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p3" pid="EDPz5Q-Oj0KUDyYSQ24E_Q" hash="Iy-2ig">First Counselor in the Primary General Presidency</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="AOEZrufU7kmTWRXqewRh3g" hash="4McwLQ">We can bring the light of the gospel into our homes, schools, and workplaces if we look for and share positive things about others.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="APoVuOf8x0ihhHhKuzH5gA" hash="P7-0Mg">By Jean B. Bingham</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p5" pid="00CMzA62HkWKluyFMbPs8w" hash="86-odQ">In response to Sister Linda K. Burton’s invitation at April’s general conference,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> many of you have been involved in thoughtful and generous acts of charity focused on meeting the needs of refugees in your local area. From simple, one-on-one efforts to community-wide programs, those acts are the result of love. As you have shared your time, talents, and resources, your—and the refugees’—hearts have been lightened. The building of hope and faith and even greater love between receiver and giver are inevitable results of true charity.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p6" pid="ubcoX8bsGEy5kONhSOw6Qw" hash="g0F_lg">The prophet Moroni tells us that charity is an essential characteristic of those who will live with Heavenly Father in the celestial kingdom. He writes, “Except ye have charity ye can in nowise be saved in the kingdom of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p7" pid="Z3yXN5v2o0mgooqsqzrBAQ" hash="OiDh4w">Of course, Jesus Christ is the perfect embodiment of charity. His premortal offering to be our Savior, His interactions throughout His mortal life, His supernal gift of the Atonement, and His continual efforts to bring us back to our Heavenly Father are the ultimate expressions of charity. He operates with a singular focus: love for His Father expressed through His love for each of us. When asked about the greatest commandment, Jesus answered:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p8" pid="UvX9T88eKEG8Wsu6HLU5xg" hash="aZeI9w">“Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p9" pid="3_YYMlHv6keEPNZy-OdkqA" hash="pLnaTg">“This is the first and great commandment.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p10" pid="JayTnRNinE2RlGqXUvHU7g" hash="vC73tA">“And the second is like unto it, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p11" pid="-BXps2D-5kKLPRoixf4RqA" hash="At5fBA">One of the most significant ways we can develop and demonstrate love for our neighbor is through being generous in our thoughts and words. Some years ago a cherished friend noted, “The greatest form of charity may be to withhold judgment.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> That is still true today.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p12" pid="pKKJHLf1R0OAoVakTWXT-g" hash="KYdLVA">Recently, as three-year-old Alyssa watched a movie with her siblings, she remarked with a puzzled expression, “Mom, that chicken is weird!”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p13" pid="UfTfbSaZuUOzuc0PjpqSzw" hash="3YEY8w">Her mother looked at the screen and responded with a smile, “Honey, that is a peacock.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p14" pid="Gtn92HlKZUiv24GRyIsfAg" hash="u1X0gQ">Like that unknowing three-year-old, we sometimes look at others with an incomplete or inaccurate understanding. We may focus on the differences and perceived flaws in those around us whereas our Heavenly Father sees His children, created in His eternal image, with magnificent and glorious potential.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p15" pid="l5AopNY8O0y3eVg7JGejHA" hash="PmkLoQ">President James E. Faust is remembered to have said, “The older I get, the less judgmental I become.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> That reminds me of the Apostle Paul’s observation:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p16" pid="Yomu8eKlU0mhNPYIJfK69g" hash="mR_-bw">“When I was a child, I spake as a child, I understood as a child, I thought as a child: but when I became [older], I put away childish things.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p17" pid="VWf-dVr2EUSpPB5kFPJIbA" hash="owa0pQ">“For now we see through a glass, darkly; but then face to face: now I know in part; but then shall I know even as also I am known.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p18" pid="Ct0Pnxnf1EmqQh7gWXfWdw" hash="XE8XNg">When we see our own imperfections more clearly, we are less inclined to view others “through a glass, darkly.” We want to use the light of the gospel to see others as the Savior does—with compassion, hope, and charity. The day will come when we will have a complete understanding of others’ hearts and will be grateful to have mercy extended to us—just as we extend charitable thoughts and words to others during this life.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p19" pid="KpM8togW7kGoKDlEZP9tXg" hash="N9H_IQ">Some years ago, I went canoeing with a group of young women. The deep blue lakes surrounded by green, thickly forested hills and rocky cliffs were breathtakingly beautiful. The water sparkled on our paddles as we dipped them into the clear water, and the sun shone warmly while we moved smoothly across the lake.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p20" pid="DxPqMYDFekWJ-NOEw7bpNA" hash="MISgEA">However, clouds soon darkened the sky, and a stiff wind began to blow. To make any progress at all, we had to dig deeply into the water, paddling without pausing between strokes. After a few grueling hours of backbreaking work, we finally turned the corner on the large lake and discovered to our amazement and delight that the wind was blowing in the direction we wanted to go.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p21" pid="dIPzPMNSfkOL2p6HdoxZqA" hash="6w6i8A">Quickly, we took advantage of this gift. We pulled out a small tarp and tied two of its corners to paddle handles and the other corners to my husband’s feet, which he stretched out over the gunwales of the canoe. The wind billowed the improvised sail, and we were off!</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p22" pid="lPQElRuucU-EI6OWfYNFwg" hash="mAjM8A">When the young women in the other canoes saw how we moved along the water with ease, they quickly improvised sails of their own. Our hearts were light with laughter and relief, grateful for the respite from the challenges of the day.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p23" pid="ssUaISYV4keydBnth2lDAw" hash="MNYNIQ">How like that glorious wind can be the sincere compliment of a friend, the cheerful greeting of a parent, the approving nod of a sibling, or the helpful smile of a co-worker or classmate, all supplying fresh “wind in our sails” as we battle the challenges of life! President Thomas S. Monson put it this way: “We can’t direct the wind, but we can adjust the sails. For maximum happiness, peace, and contentment, may we <span class="emphasis">choose</span> a positive attitude.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p24" pid="fDwxbSOk5kKfVR_Zk0loMA" hash="RKgh0g">Words have surprising power, both to build up and to tear down. We can all probably remember negative words that brought us low and other words spoken with love that made our spirits soar. Choosing to say only that which is positive about—and to—others lifts and strengthens those around us and helps others follow in the Savior’s way.</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=26_mpahHw0S2vT26Xni16Q"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810459/869baa98e467489fbac3eee0e9774889/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810459/869baa98e467489fbac3eee0e9774889/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810459/869baa98e467489fbac3eee0e9774889/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810459/869baa98e467489fbac3eee0e9774889/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810459/869baa98e467489fbac3eee0e9774889/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810459/869baa98e467489fbac3eee0e9774889/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810459/869baa98e467489fbac3eee0e9774889/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810459/869baa98e467489fbac3eee0e9774889/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810459/869baa98e467489fbac3eee0e9774889/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1810459/869baa98e467489fbac3eee0e9774889/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Cross-stitch of “I will bring the light of the gospel into my home”" pid="26_mpahHw0S2vT26Xni16Q" hash="AAAAAA"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p25" pid="SUZoOyIFM0SsBNbY4bGiJA" hash="bEVLfA">As a young Primary girl, I worked diligently to cross-stitch a simple saying which read, “I will bring the light of the gospel into my home.” One weekday afternoon as we girls pulled our needles up and down through the fabric, our teacher told us the story of a girl who lived on a hill on one side of a valley. Each late afternoon she noticed on the hill on the opposite side of the valley a house that had shining, golden windows. Her own home was small and somewhat shabby, and the girl dreamed of living in that beautiful house with windows of gold.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p26" pid="uLDwLrgAWEy8A4HgiFmvhA" hash="SvgtqQ">One day the girl was given permission to ride her bike across the valley. She eagerly rode until she reached the house with the golden windows that she had admired for so long. But when she dismounted from her bike, she saw that the house was abandoned and dilapidated, with tall weeds in the yard and windows that were plain and dirty. Sadly, the girl turned her face toward home. To her surprise, she saw a house with shining, golden windows on the hill across the valley and soon realized it was her very own home!<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p27" pid="NGTNRMs4lkGip561wS2gYw" hash="r6QpRg">Sometimes, like this young girl, we look at what others might have or be and feel we are less in comparison. We become focused on the Pinterest or Instagram versions of life or caught up in our school’s or workplace’s preoccupation with competition. However, when we take a moment to “count [our] many blessings,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> we see with a truer perspective and recognize the goodness of God to <span class="emphasis">all</span> of His children.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p28" pid="C9GbQkVHmke_v5fHb_fdQQ" hash="smFggA">Whether we are 8 or 108, we can bring the light of the gospel into our own environment, be it a high-rise apartment in Manhattan, a stilt house in Malaysia, or a yurt in Mongolia. We can determine to look for the good in others and in the circumstances around us. Young and not-so-young women everywhere can demonstrate charity as they choose to use words that build confidence and faith in others.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p29" pid="eguP0FiHnk-SQO02n4hurg" hash="5svY_Q">Elder Jeffrey R. Holland told of a young man who was the brunt of his peers’ teasing during his school years. Some years later he moved away, joined the military, received an education, and became active in the Church. This period of his life was marked with wonderfully successful experiences.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p30" pid="cirMVx4tb0e91pDP7Uzsyg" hash="wUDTkA">After several years he returned to his hometown. However, the people refused to acknowledge his growth and improvement. To them, he was still just old “so-and-so,” and they treated him that way. Eventually, this good man faded away to a shadow of his former successful self without being able to use his marvelously developed talents to bless those who derided and rejected him once again.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> What a loss, both for him and the community!</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p31" pid="E88VOwoiN0WVudDiMGIadA" hash="uz38EA">The Apostle Peter taught, “Above all things have fervent charity among yourselves: for charity shall cover the multitude of sins.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span><span class="emphasis"> Fervent</span> charity, meaning “wholehearted,” is demonstrated by forgetting the mistakes and stumblings of another rather than harboring grudges or reminding ourselves and others of imperfections in the past.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p32" pid="NC-wg3BDTk6t0y6ZJEYppQ" hash="hpVazA">Our obligation and privilege is to embrace improvement in<span class="emphasis"> everyone </span>as we strive to become more like our Savior, Jesus Christ. What a thrill it is to see light in the eyes of someone who has come to understand the Atonement of Jesus Christ and is making real changes in his or her life! Missionaries who have experienced the joy of seeing a convert enter the waters of baptism and then enter the doors of the temple are witnesses of the blessing of allowing—and encouraging—others to change. Members who welcome converts who might have been considered unlikely candidates for the kingdom find great satisfaction in helping them feel the love of the Lord. The great beauty of the gospel of Jesus Christ is the reality of eternal progression—we are not only <span class="emphasis">allowed</span> to change for the better but also encouraged, and even <span class="emphasis">commanded,</span> to continue in the pursuit of improvement and, ultimately, perfection.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p33" pid="qFdYRkzRa0-6M1PbClubKA" hash="sFUeag">President Thomas S. Monson counseled: “In a hundred small ways, all of you wear the mantle of charity. … Rather than being judgmental [or] critical of [one] another, may we have the pure love of Christ for our fellow travelers in this journey through life. May we recognize that each one is doing her [or his] best to deal with the challenges which come [her or his] way, and may we strive to do <span class="emphasis">our</span> best to help out.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p34" pid="yM8U4YaR9kCIlQT_yb-FAg" hash="C4lt2g">Charity, in positive terms, is patient, kind, and content. Charity puts others first, is humble, exercises self-control, looks for good in others, and rejoices when someone does well.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p35" pid="pnkmx04Ox0WYtReMjFpvhw" hash="1ij2ug">As sisters (and brothers) in Zion, will we commit to “<span class="emphasis">all</span> work together … to do whatsoever is gentle and human, to cheer and to bless in [the Savior’s] name”?<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> Can we, with love and high hopes, look for and embrace the beauties in others, allowing and encouraging progress? Can we rejoice in the accomplishments of others while continuing to work toward our own improvement?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p36" pid="ODA_GrIprUWqvdsRthlVcQ" hash="IdOtlA">Yes, we <span class="emphasis">can</span> bring the light of the gospel into our homes, schools, and workplaces if we look for and share positive things about others and let the less-than-perfect fade away. What gratitude fills my heart when I think of the repentance that our Savior, Jesus Christ, has made possible for all of us who have inevitably sinned in this imperfect and sometimes difficult world!</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home.p37" pid="2jNitlS_Gku2iXy3_iXOIw" hash="C5X76g">I bear my witness that as we follow His perfect example, we can receive the gift of charity, which will bring us great joy in this life and the promised blessing of eternal life with our Father in Heaven. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/10/i-will-bring-the-light-of-the-gospel-into-my-home</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2016-general-conference/2016-09-0010-jean-b-bingham-64k-eng.mp3" length="5788915" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>That Your Joy Might Be Full</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sister Bingham teaches that, despite the difficulties of mortal life, we can turn to Jesus Christ as the source of all healing, peace, and eternal progress.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60003502_000_52bingham" doc-version="1" hash="AN6NkA">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="2irG36-6nUqim0sheHzV5A" hash="krqaTw">That Your Joy Might Be Full</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p2" pid="Cx8J0c_mnUyatGhk4DvAKg" hash="P7-0Mg1">By Jean B. Bingham</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p3" pid="_dyND9C8bUCHCZxzKpJmLw" hash="Wft9FQ">Relief Society General President</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="d8884RkMQkuXZyhfigSeVg" hash="yirxXA">Jesus Christ is the source of all healing, peace, and eternal progress.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="n9sQ7vcRlkOS7zPfMRi3Rg" hash="P7-0Mg">By Jean B. Bingham</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p5" pid="9BgNJDNAVUyIQ5HcEPdctw" hash="b3Rf6Q">Brothers and sisters, it is a joy to be with you. And that’s what I would like to talk with you about this morning—having a fulness of joy.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p6" pid="Q2oxA4adREK2KIOfAMsQUQ" hash="O7fxgA">A recent news headline reads, “Disasters rock the nation [and] world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> From hurricanes and floods to heat waves and droughts, from wildfires and earthquakes to wars and devastating diseases, it seems “the whole earth [is] in commotion.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p7" pid="ybfdFvOsMU2fOz9qYoaGVA" hash="IjhYqQ">Millions of people have been displaced, and countless lives have been disrupted by these challenges. Contention in families and communities as well as inner struggles with fear, doubt, and unfulfilled expectations also leave us in turmoil. It can be difficult to feel the joy that Lehi taught is the purpose of life.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> We have all asked at times: “Where can I turn for peace? Where is my solace … ?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> We wonder, how do I find joy despite the difficulties of mortal life?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p8" pid="gjnlmlKp5ESD73ObLWGWhg" hash="U7LZZA">The answer may seem too simple, but it has proven true from the days of Adam. Lasting joy is found in focusing on our Savior, Jesus Christ, and living the gospel as demonstrated and taught by Him. The more we <span class="emphasis">learn about, </span><span class="emphasis">have faith in,</span> and <span class="emphasis">emulate</span> Jesus Christ, the more we come to understand that He is the source of all healing, peace, and eternal progress. He invites each of us to come unto Him,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> an invitation that President Henry B. Eyring has characterized as “the most important invitation anyone could accept.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.t1">
				<h2 pid="2qUlj9I390KR6YNIgpiCDg" hash="aXbFeQ">Learn of Jesus Christ</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p10" pid="CmQBNLDmPECh6sloNx7IBw" hash="VZAHiQ">How do we come unto Him? Last April, President Russell M. Nelson and Elder M. Russell Ballard encouraged us to study “The Living Christ”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> as part of learning about the Savior. Many have accepted the challenge and been blessed. Not long ago a dear friend gave each of her adult children copies of the document with gospel pictures to illustrate each phrase. She encouraged her children to help her grandchildren understand and memorize it. Sometime later my friend shared a video of her six-year-old granddaughter, Laynie, reciting her memorized version with enthusiasm and poise. I realized that if a six-year-old could do it, so can I!</p>
				<a href="gl://image/?pid=kuI3DKGLVUa8YQl3qXO9Tw"><img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1974916/cba5d7b09ef640a1b000239090151f86/100x134.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x67="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1974916/cba5d7b09ef640a1b000239090151f86/50x67.jpg" data-src-100x134="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1974916/cba5d7b09ef640a1b000239090151f86/100x134.jpg" data-src-200x269="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1974916/cba5d7b09ef640a1b000239090151f86/200x269.jpg" data-src-320x431="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1974916/cba5d7b09ef640a1b000239090151f86/320x431.jpg" data-src-460x620="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1974916/cba5d7b09ef640a1b000239090151f86/460x620.jpg" data-src-640x862="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1974916/cba5d7b09ef640a1b000239090151f86/640x862.jpg" data-src-1024x1380="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1974916/cba5d7b09ef640a1b000239090151f86/1024x1380.jpg" data-src-1335x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1974916/cba5d7b09ef640a1b000239090151f86/1335x1800.jpg" altText="Laynie, who memorized “The Living Christ”" pid="kuI3DKGLVUa8YQl3qXO9Tw" hash="AAAAAA1"></img></a>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p11" pid="5e6RMu8U0EKBRgwL1yjEdw" hash="OdT7Zg">As I have studied the life and teachings of Jesus Christ with more focus and committed “The Living Christ” to memory, my gratitude and love for our Savior have increased. Each sentence of that inspired document contains a sermon and has enhanced my understanding of His divine roles and earthly mission. What I have learned and felt through this period of study and reflection confirms that Jesus truly “is the light, the life, and the hope of the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Ancient scripture and latter-day prophets’ words written or spoken in praise of Him bear witness that “His way is the path that leads to happiness in this life and eternal life in the world to come.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.t2">
				<h2 pid="EtBZrn6A2UuoLVeUjUjJjA" hash="iD5QNw">Have Faith in Jesus Christ</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p13" pid="7uO1T-zd5kyyVggWPdbhCA" hash="OvS_Dw">As you study Christ’s life and teachings in a myriad of ways, your faith in Him will increase. You will come to know that He loves you individually and understands you perfectly. In His 33 years of mortality, He suffered rejection; persecution; bodily hunger, thirst, and fatigue;<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> loneliness; verbal and physical abuse; and finally, an excruciating death at the hands of sinful men.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> In the Garden of Gethsemane and on the cross of Calvary, He felt all of <span class="emphasis">our </span>pains, afflictions, temptations, sicknesses, and infirmities.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p14" pid="C5PgQTK30ky_9prdfg2W0Q" hash="Tqa9oQ">No matter what we have suffered, He is the source of <span class="emphasis">healing</span>. Those who have experienced any manner of abuse, devastating loss, chronic illness or disabling affliction, untrue accusations, vicious persecution, or spiritual damage from sin or misunderstandings can all be made whole by the Redeemer of the world. However, He will not enter without invitation. We must come unto Him and allow Him to work His miracles.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p15" pid="8t3dK8FCSkGYoQOcG9luZA" hash="TfjrDw">One beautiful spring day I left the door open to enjoy the fresh air. A small bird flew in the open door and then realized this was not where it wanted to be. It flew desperately around the room, repeatedly flying into the window glass in an attempt to escape. I tried to gently guide it toward the open door, but it was frightened and kept darting away. It finally landed on top of the window drapes in bewildered exhaustion. I took a broom and slowly reached the bristle end up to where the bird nervously perched. As I held the head of the broom next to its feet, the bird tentatively stepped onto the bristles. Slowly, very slowly, I walked to the open door, holding the broom as steady as I could. As soon as we reached the open door, the bird swiftly flew to freedom.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p16" pid="uas51J-7jUmoEOo9FCaSEQ" hash="JA9ahw">Like that bird, sometimes we are afraid to trust because we don’t understand God’s absolute love and desire to help us. But when we study Heavenly Father’s plan and Jesus Christ’s mission, we understand that Their only objective is our eternal happiness and progress.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> They delight to help us when we ask, seek, and knock.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> When we exercise faith and humbly open ourselves to Their answers, we become free from the constraints of our misunderstandings and assumptions, and we can be shown the way forward.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p17" pid="nF8ua7lQbkavBHSiPBltpQ" hash="-vxr2Q">Jesus Christ is also the source of <span class="emphasis">peace.</span> He invites us to “lean on [His] ample arm”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> and promises the “peace … which passeth all understanding,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> a feeling that comes when His Spirit “speak[s] peace to our souls”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> no matter what challenges surround us. Whether they are personal struggles, family troubles, or community crises, peace will come as we trust that God’s Only Begotten Son has power to soothe our aching souls.</p>
				<a href="gl://image/?pid=_pfUY1uQI06nauf06w4bbw"><img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1974917/60fd410d92114ed8930f13131760dc7a/200x200.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x50="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1974917/60fd410d92114ed8930f13131760dc7a/50x50.jpg" data-src-100x100="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1974917/60fd410d92114ed8930f13131760dc7a/100x100.jpg" data-src-200x200="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1974917/60fd410d92114ed8930f13131760dc7a/200x200.jpg" data-src-320x320="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1974917/60fd410d92114ed8930f13131760dc7a/320x320.jpg" data-src-460x459="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1974917/60fd410d92114ed8930f13131760dc7a/460x459.jpg" data-src-640x640="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1974917/60fd410d92114ed8930f13131760dc7a/640x640.jpg" data-src-1024x1024="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1974917/60fd410d92114ed8930f13131760dc7a/1024x1024.jpg" data-src-1800x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1974917/60fd410d92114ed8930f13131760dc7a/1800x1800.jpg" altText="Snježana Podvinski, a member in Croatia" pid="_pfUY1uQI06nauf06w4bbw" hash="AAAAAA"></img></a>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p18" pid="xieqJIuHZkiYpM6Xtbv19g" hash="riRUqA">Snježana Podvinski, one of a small number of Saints in Karlovac, Croatia, leaned on the Savior when her husband and both of her parents died within a six-month period last year. Grief-stricken, but having a testimony that families are forever, she used all of her savings to travel to the temple, where she was sealed to her husband and parents. She shared that those days in the temple were a highlight in her life. Because of her firm testimony of Jesus Christ and His Atonement, she has felt peace and experienced healing that have also been a strength to those around her.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p19" pid="hYyKwXy9SEKJ1TdKd5_Rtw" hash="uS3X6A">Faith in Jesus Christ brings even more gifts than healing and peace. As President Henry B. Eyring shared: “I have been thankful for the many ways the Lord has visited me with the Comforter when I needed peace. Yet our Father in Heaven is concerned not just about our comfort but even more about our upward progress.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p20" pid="upxZDsnVIkuBA942YP7Yww" hash="W0Z7WQ">Because of Jesus Christ’s Atonement, which includes the gifts of redemption and resurrection, we are able to repent, change, and <span class="emphasis">progress eternally.</span> Because of the power He gives us as we are obedient, we are able to become more than we ever could on our own. We may not understand completely how, but each of us who has felt faith in Christ increase has also received a greater understanding of our divine identity and purpose, leading us to make choices that are consistent with that knowledge.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p21" pid="yeE1NzqmP0iErJvJ44LCxQ" hash="EbRb0w">Despite a world that will try to knock us down to the level of “mere animals,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> knowing that God is our Father assures us that we have divine potential and royal promise. Despite a world that tells us this life is a dead end, knowing that God’s Only Begotten Son has made it possible for us to be redeemed and resurrected gives us hope for eternal progress.</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.t3">
				<h2 pid="HTA6o3qjN0isnklbnuRnZg" hash="oXpJEg">Emulate Jesus Christ</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p23" pid="BsWZXjfFS06IssWtOHJdxA" hash="UQkmIA">As we learn more about Jesus Christ, we develop greater faith in Him and we naturally want to follow His example. Keeping His commandments becomes our greatest desire. Our hearts yearn to relieve others’ suffering, as He did, and we want them to experience the peace and happiness we have found.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p24" pid="IjMkPYpcHUifeTsI_rJlrw" hash="OTSayA">Why is trying to do as He did so powerful? Because when we put our faith into action, the Holy Ghost bears witness of eternal truth.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> Jesus instructs His disciples to keep His commandments because He knows that as we follow His example, we will begin to experience joy, and as we continue on His path, we will come to a fulness of joy. He explained, “These things have I spoken unto you, that my joy might remain in you, and that your joy might be full.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p25" pid="IiWS-LR4KUuycW6ULHQN-A" hash="YxZuzg">Are our testimonies built on the bedrock foundation of Jesus Christ and His gospel? When the storms of life press upon us, do we frantically look for a how-to book or an internet post for help? Taking the time to build and strengthen our knowledge and testimony of Jesus Christ will yield rich dividends in times of trial and adversity. Daily reading of scriptures and pondering the words of living prophets, engaging in meaningful personal prayer, mindfully partaking of the sacrament each week, giving service as the Savior would—each of these simple activities becomes a building block for a joyful life.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p26" pid="KZr0oUPhUkiF_gLLb7p-Zg" hash="QsuxIA">What brings you joy? The sight of your loved ones at the end of a long day? The satisfaction of a job done well? The light in someone’s eyes when you share their burden? The words of a hymn that reaches deep into your heart? The handclasp of a close friend? Take a private moment to reflect on your blessings, and then find ways to share them. As you reach out to serve and lift your brothers and sisters within your neighborhood or throughout this world that is in so much commotion, you will feel greater peace and healing and even progress.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full.p27" pid="gSYL-QG7wEGL8rjzhRs20g" hash="sEQgPg">Come unto Him. I testify that as you center your life on Jesus Christ, you will find joy in your circumstances, whatever they may be. Indeed, “He, only One,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> is the answer. Make time and take time to come to know Jesus Christ through studying diligently, developing greater faith in Him, and striving to become ever more like Him. As we do so, we too will be moved to say, with little Laynie, “God be thanked for the matchless gift of His divine Son.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> In the blessed and sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2017/10/that-your-joy-might-be-full</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2017-general-conference/2017-10-4010-jean-b-bingham-64k-eng.mp3" length="5496382" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
