<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Joanne B. Doxey</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Joanne B. Doxey.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Joanne%20B.%20Doxey.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Joanne B. Doxey.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 1987 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening the Family</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Near the shores of Galilee, as the resurrected Christ dined with his disciples on a fresh catch of fish, he asked of Simon Peter: “Simon, son of Jonas, lovest thou me more than these? He saith unto him, Yea, Lord; thou knowest that I love thee. He sa</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03219_000_033" doc-version="2" hash="6200rw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="81XbXXMvMEWPjMi7RhkcOg" hash="zCq2ig">Strengthening the Family</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="qxtP0aBohUOHAC2eRnyJFQ" hash="O5atlw">Joanne B. Doxey</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26e6.jpg" alt="Joanne B. Doxey" pid="R38OwJcCBESjSVAIhJcW-g" hash="PQv6Zw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p1" pid="bbiJ4VXiv0eyU2E82yGcfg" hash="umJNuA">Near the shores of Galilee, as the resurrected Christ dined with his disciples on a fresh catch of fish, he asked of Simon Peter: “Simon, son of Jonas, lovest thou me more than these? He saith unto him, Yea, Lord; thou knowest that I love thee. He saith unto him, Feed my lambs” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/21.15" class="scriptureRef">John 21:15</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p2" pid="zXqM6HemBkaWCYwEt2IN5w" hash="kS4DfQ">Do our worldly pursuits take precedence over our eternal objectives? Would we respond as Peter did when he was questioned about his priorities?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p3" pid="4rnBgNsl8E6UdXzxCsuH4A" hash="wUI8pg">My beloved sisters, my message to you this hour is one of love and encouragement, that we, as women, can demonstrate our love of the Lord through fulfilling our God-given responsibility to “feed his lambs” by bringing souls unto him and by strengthening the family both here and hereafter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p4" pid="ZKUKBVmvUU6QA80h1q1ZiA" hash="_3e7Ig">It is a glorious thing to be a woman in these latter days. We, together with the priesthood, are to prepare a righteous generation for the second coming of Christ. We are led by a living prophet who counsels us to feed the lambs, enrich and protect the home, and strengthen the family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p5" pid="_luUaLs4YkOYLYYB4TzNgw" hash="DTXOjw">Why do you think the prophets are reminding us of our sacred duty to feed the lambs and protect the home and family? Because it is against the home and family that Satan has aimed his greatest efforts to destroy, and far too many sheep are wandering or being enticed away out of the sheep fold, and wolves lie in wait to devour the flock.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p6" pid="oqu_Xvt4u0WLwRaoMJImzA" hash="3iVEGg">How can we help prepare children for their significant role if we, their mentors, are absent or uncaring? It is an awesome task, but one filled with hope and happiness, if we make it so.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p7" pid="JWJe78cCCkuCp0mqNTpPMQ" hash="-Wf4RQ">Let’s take an expanded look at the eternal family. We all lived with our Father in Heaven before this earth life. The scriptures say we received our “first lessons in the world of spirits and were prepared to come forth in the due time of the Lord to labor in his vineyard for the salvation of the souls of men” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/138.56" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 138:56</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p8" pid="CZ0gAEbxq0y_GWqIK1GqDg" hash="a2YYww">In the premortal existence, our heavenly family was a prototype for us to follow in guiding our families here on earth. We were prepared to come to an earthly family, where we could learn again sacred truths we had learned before.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p9" pid="PKDnFMIAekuwaUVo_oqHjQ" hash="rbWsiw">Parents are their children’s first and most influential teachers. The responsibility of teaching proper values and sacred truths cannot be successfully delegated to anyone else. We must remember the sanctity of these children; they do not belong to us; they are children of our Father—his spirit children come to earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p10" pid="nls_wjae_UKB4HL2GW7nSw" hash="wOh3Nw">There is a story of a group of Relief Society sisters making candy called “divinity” at the home of one of the sisters. Two little boys in the family were allowed to eat all of the divinity they could scrape from the spoons, pans, and bowls. It was the weekend of general conference and, as the family listened to the talks one of the speakers said, “There is a spark of divinity in each of us.” One of the little boys jumped up and said, “A spark of divinity? Wow, I’m full of it!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p11" pid="4U-hLYn86UeDdyO0WfF6lw" hash="3vdVyg">Yes, children are full of divinity. Surely the angels attend them. But the loving care and teachings they need in order to abide on the earth must be given by mothers and fathers and those who influence them. They need to be loved, and they need to be taught. The risen Lord reiterated the counsel of Isaiah when he said, “And all thy children shall be taught of the Lord; and great shall be the peace of thy children” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/22.13" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 22:13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p12" pid="gbZ3vX47oEWQsO4J1tOvpQ" hash="YFqiJw">If we love the Lord, we will “feed his lambs.” But how? He has given us resources that will guide us through this brief mortal existence back to our heavenly home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p13" pid="ttlG0nY890Cp982fIen12Q" hash="HlanjA">The principle is illustrated in an experience that some members of our family had when we were in a very large city. Because of differences in work and school schedules, we had to book separate flights from two different airlines. Some of the family left from one airport, but my son and I were scheduled to leave from an airport south of town, nearly two hours away. There were challenges ahead: motoring on the opposite side of the road from that to which we were accustomed, congested highways, road repairs, as well as a limited time to catch the plane. We felt a dependence on the Lord as we began our journey. With road map in hand, I tried to navigate (which is not my forte), and my son tried his hand at the wheel of a rented car. I earnestly hoped that the people who had made the maps had designed them to match the road signs. We were not in a position to make a mistake or backtrack, or our destination would not be realized.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p14" pid="SiPRcRn8a0SNPQLdTZdKJw" hash="diptew">How like life, I thought: If we rely on the Lord, follow the map, and watch the road signs, without making a lot of unnecessary detours, we can navigate through mortality and reach our destination safely, in the Lord’s due time. Decisions determine destiny.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.f2">
	<p pid="jGDNMj8zFUGlK_wLRHSR1A" hash="BsRktA">What are some of the road signs or guides that help us through this earthly life?</p>
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="dRtlRfMJS0iG1Tr3q571RA" hash="Z085-w">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="pPUCzt0xY0OD-EBpcmwavw" hash="hnOzEg">A living prophet, who speaks the mind and will of God;</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="r_WmWhC9ukaU-wCIkyQt3Q" hash="c2derg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="7i9fEMjVI06CSdzIAj3nmA" hash="FlCHgQ">Prayer, whereby we can speak to God and be directed by the Holy Spirit;</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="fANWuj8gMUWu54EIb8J5Lw" hash="k_CDzw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="N7ZB0UjSXUOyscLaCAScfw" hash="ruaxUA">The scriptures, wherein God speaks to us;</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="S7Pmh40Qj0ager8L84coOQ" hash="h8Sezg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="HG_QeRcTT02SyZxmc2EwEQ" hash="jXK3gw">The priesthood, with power to act for God; and</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="0CowL0Mq1UiVAmBu2--5bA" hash="ssYf0Q">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="2D7xSseTdUy0ZCXGg5P4Vw" hash="HQ-Tyg">Sacred covenants and ordinances, which offer us family life with our Heavenly Father forever.</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p15" pid="1ZwToiwdX02CfM-OH6LvhA" hash="Pqv0Sg">“The home is the basis of a righteous life,” said President David O. McKay (<span class="emphasis">Stepping Stones to an Abundant Life,</span> comp. Llewelyn R. McKay, Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1971, p. 276). It is the place to teach the vision of eternity to our families and to help them follow the road signs in order to reach their destiny. Women hold a key role in teaching these truths, so we need to be knowledgeable and full of faith. When we are firm in our own convictions, we can give our inner strength to those about us with confidence. We are responsible for our personal development that will give us this confidence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p16" pid="97jva1hTDUunfGoEkOWYqQ" hash="Nfa52w">True personal worth comes from a secure relationship with Heavenly Father. Individual worth is intrinsic, it is internal; it is eternal. It is something that cannot be taken from us when the blossom of youth fades, when economic conditions leave us desolate, when sickness or handicaps befall us, or when prominence and visibility are obscured.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p17" pid="ltwxMgxJi0OkPFLr3-RBnQ" hash="FqHNkA">Many are led astray by the false doctrines of the world that youthfulness, beauty, adornments, possessions, power, titles, or attainments are what make one worthwhile. As in Book of Mormon times, there are those who want to become popular in the eyes of the world rather than do what God expects. The Lord counseled Joseph Smith early in his ministry, “You should not have feared man more than God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/3.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 3:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p18" pid="abg3SWe3GUGqUgEJjPha4Q" hash="oDuwsQ">How can we build a secure relationship with Heavenly Father? Again, we can refer to the guides and road signs we have been given to direct us through life: fervent prayer, being directed by the Holy Spirit, and searching the scriptures daily, all of which help us live virtuous lives. “Then,” say the scriptures, “shall thy confidence wax strong in the presence of God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.45" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:45</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p19" pid="65BFJPz2gkqSkOj7f4nTYg" hash="07o0wg">A woman’s inner strength is important in the husband-and-wife relationship. As husbands and wives work together in righteousness, loving and appreciating each other, the family is fortified in countless ways.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p20" pid="43_B5dhfj02RDRFZDq4NbQ" hash="a--BMg">President Ezra Taft Benson spoke to the fathers and husbands at a fireside for parents and said, “We look to you to give righteous leadership in your home and families and, with your companions and the mothers of your children, to lead your families back to our Eternal Father” (<span class="emphasis">To the Mothers in Zion,</span> Salt Lake City: The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, 1987, p. 13).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p21" pid="F6r3LukptU-NT-CX_nz1kQ" hash="8hE2IA">This righteous leadership is enhanced by the priesthood power that was restored to earth to bless and direct us. How can we, as women, receive the full blessings and power of the priesthood in our lives? We can sustain and support those who bear it righteously. This is by divine design, not by plan of man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p22" pid="Y9Oetxy-HUG1g0RTrzIs0Q" hash="bUVhqg">I know a woman with several small children whose husband served in a time-consuming Church calling. He often came home late from work—just long enough to say hello—then off he went to perform his Church duties. The children sometimes had to be reassured, and sometimes the mother had to reassure herself, by saying, “Aren’t we glad that Daddy is worthy to serve Heavenly Father so we can receive so many blessings?” A support instead of a murmur brought results that had a lasting influence on that home and family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p23" pid="QaPzz8uLqEyI6OsolqCciA" hash="Q9g-Xw">An important part of the plan for continued family relationships is to receive ordinances and covenants in the holy temples for ourselves and our ancestors. These ordinances and covenants are an anchor to safety for the family, both here and hereafter. Each of us belongs to a family and has ancestors who really belong to us. Should we not be about seeking after these loved ones and performing temple work that will seal them to us in eternal families?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p24" pid="qongXsLfo0e_aWqZc_cALg" hash="GYQueg">Elder John A. Widtsoe spoke from his own experience when he said, “Whoever seeks to help those on the other side receives help in return in all the affairs of life” (<span class="emphasis">The Forefather Quest,</span> Salt Lake City: Genealogical Society of Utah, 1937, p. 22).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p25" pid="yVBpBSYRVEKs0CpdCDOxwA" hash="bxisYA">When I was a young girl, a group of us were invited to Elder Widtsoe’s home for a fireside, and afterward he showed us his pedigree chart, a result of devoted research. As he unrolled the chart, it stretched across three rooms of his house. This was so impressive to our young minds that it motivated us to begin searching for information about our own ancestors. What a wonderful beginning to a lifelong interest and participation in this sacred work! A spiritual dimension is truly added to our lives when we work on our family histories.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p26" pid="9RJTbB4nnE6T_Hcz0VyIPA" hash="gM8afA">Sisters in Zion, could there be a more rewarding calling than to labor in the Lord’s vineyard for the salvation of souls? We have the choice privilege of strengthening families and influencing those who have been placed in our care, as well as those who have preceded us beyond the veil. Lest we think the task is too hard, be reminded that angels will be round about us to bear us up if we are willing to do our part. The promised blessings are almost more than we can imagine.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p27" pid="-oRcmT1xR0WE7pFnfcg9eg" hash="0dPdRQ">We have been blessed by a prophet of God in our day as he said: “We pray for you. We sustain you. We honor you as you bear, nourish, train, teach, and love for eternity. I promise you the blessings of heaven and ‘all that [the] Father hath’ (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:38</a>) as you magnify the noblest calling of all” (Benson, <span class="emphasis">To the Mothers in Zion,</span> p. 13).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p28" pid="Lz3M7akWvE-VsdTIyGd1gA" hash="6g1M8Q">I love being a mother, a wife, a daughter, a sister, a woman in these latter days. The Lord knows us and loves each of us and desires to bless us in our important work. We must be willing to come unto him; to accept his will over our own wants; to bring souls unto him; to feed his lambs and his sheep, so that at that great day when we meet him face to face he will say, “Come unto me ye blessed, for behold, your works have been the works of righteousness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.16" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family.p29" pid="o5f234UcOkOIEdcxgawT0Q" hash="_eYe7g">I bear you my witness that the Lord lives, and I pray that we may eagerly fulfill our sacred responsibility to strengthen families both here and hereafter. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1987/10/strengthening-the-family</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1987-general-womens-meeting/1987-09-0010-joanne-b-doxey-64k-eng.mp3" length="6334131" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 1987 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Remember Him”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My beloved sisters—you who belong to the worldwide sisterhood of the Church and you who are yet to become members, you who are women and you girls who are yet to become women, you who are now mothers and you who are yet to become mothers—despite our </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03245_000_036" doc-version="2" hash="5ijwvA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="DIVWZq6-HkW45jnD1szu7g" hash="ujhdRg">“Remember Him”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Y0VIFJ4AkUmGNRr4yTfjkw" hash="O5atlw">Joanne B. Doxey</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26e6.jpg" alt="Joanne B. Doxey" pid="2d_w3l_6c0mlSFltxj_nxw" hash="PQv6Zw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p1" pid="UyJpESPpNUq1g131yH39nA" hash="0v87AQ">My beloved sisters—you who belong to the worldwide sisterhood of the Church and you who are yet to become members, you who are women and you girls who are yet to become women, you who are now mothers and you who are yet to become mothers—despite our varied backgrounds and our differences in status and standing, we all are alike in one important respect. We are all sisters, daughters of God, with a common purpose, which is to return to Him with honor after our earth life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p2" pid="S-RZcdUSmkuDojlVpdPQXA" hash="mbLmeg">In our premortal existence we were taught the plan of salvation. We accepted that divine plan, including the privilege and responsibility of becoming daughters, sisters, wives, mothers, and grandmothers. We knew as we came to earth that we would be tested and tried to see if we would do all things whatsoever the Lord would command us. (See <a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.25" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:25</a>.) Then a veil of forgetfulness was placed on us so we would be dependent on faith in a Savior to guide us back to our heavenly home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p3" pid="CwSUa_koPkSLFGf15tnL2A" hash="XBnB3Q">A living prophet, who speaks for the Savior today, has told us: “When our Heavenly Father placed Adam and Eve on this earth, He did so with the purpose in mind of teaching them how to regain His presence. Our Father promised a Savior to redeem them from their fallen condition. He gave to them the plan of salvation and told them to teach their children faith in Jesus Christ and repentance.” (Ezra Taft Benson, <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Aug. 1985, p. 8.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p4" pid="RAiluFjMm0aX5CcZahHA7w" hash="rmRWQw">We in the latter days of this world have a responsibility to teach these same truths to our children. It was ever thus. As someone said, “Into a woman’s keeping is committed the destiny of this generation and of generations to come.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p5" pid="mOwksno21kajmB3CALNqmw" hash="YDDnrQ">How important is our work, sisters! And how eternal is our influence on our homes and families! The Lord is depending on us to remember Him and to teach our children to remember Him, so that they are prepared to teach their children to remember Him, that we all may regain His presence in righteousness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p6" pid="EvyvujrpgEqcnJQ-2E-l1g" hash="u5DlcQ">The proper nurturing and teaching of our children must be our first priority. What mother would not want her children to experience joy and happiness in this life and in the eternities to come?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p7" pid="-s5J97JbKEetggHx1UQO8g" hash="12fxXA">There is always sacrifice required when working toward long-range goals like striving toward an Olympic gold medal, a mark of excellence in school, a flawless performance, or other extended efforts. Raising children is no different.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p8" pid="wEGauz6YmUe_iuIldtxdYw" hash="d7seug">The adversary, who is the enemy to all righteousness, seeks to thwart the efforts of the Lord’s people. His deadly forces are arrayed against our homes. He plans every move with accuracy and precision. There is nothing haphazard or careless about his plan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p9" pid="Zqr_p0QM5kCRLdvD6ZTecQ" hash="9OPjEA">Then, can there be anything haphazard about our plan and our efforts to teach this generation in righteousness? How can we be fortified in teaching the truths of the gospel to our children and in helping them remember they are a royal generation, chosen from the foundation of the world?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p10" pid="0zoMiIUpg0uvml2YY1CcLw" hash="NMVnOA">A loving Heavenly Father knew we would need help to learn again the basic things we had once been taught in the heavenly councils. So He gave us the gift of the Holy Ghost to bring all things to our remembrance, and living prophets to direct us. He also provided scriptures to teach us, commandments to help us become like the Savior, and covenants to remind us of our solemn responsibility to remember Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p11" pid="d5_ZtkOX50ask9tzTFmEXA" hash="nwIHCg">Let’s consider how the scriptures, commandments, and covenants can fortify us in our efforts to return to Him.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.f2">
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="_YOH97HIx0-wAJVbZG8s6w" hash="L0OhTg">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p12" pid="_JwUGyXZq0ezNibz2Nuiqg" hash="h-4IJw">We Can Remember the Lord through the Scriptures. The scriptures have been written and preserved at great cost so that we can “treasure up” the truths of the gospel. We have a responsibility to know what these scriptures contain.</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p13" pid="3ldAwtKcvkmzSWBWh-5YmA" hash="IQ-5Fw">I quote from the words of President Spencer W. Kimball:</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p14" pid="leO1MYnvQUu0IOvnVYELhg" hash="9LMx6Q">“I stress again the deep need each woman has to study the scriptures. …</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p15" pid="qFGr3UHD4kmxW6e31IRaZw" hash="0UNaCQ">“As you become more and more familiar with the truths of the scriptures, you will be more and more effective. … After all, who has any greater need to ‘treasure up’ the truths of the gospel (on which they may call in their moments of need) than do women and mothers who do so much nurturing and teaching.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1979, p. 102.)</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p16" pid="RJ1H4fbNNUakhMUlXNrKVw" hash="yBm_oA">If we treat the scriptures lightly, letting them gather dust on the shelves, unopened and unread, they are unable to bless our lives as planned. We will be denied the sweet whisperings of the Spirit in guiding our lives and the lives of our families unless we pay the price of studying, pondering, and praying about the scriptures.</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p17" pid="m28xVBFz9kCi3gbPpLnBew" hash="jxuDcQ">If we immerse ourselves daily in the scriptures, particularly the Book of Mormon, we will have increased discernment. We will have power to do good and to resist evil, and our ability to solve problems will be expanded. Messages to help us in our day were foreseen by the Lord and were divinely placed on the pages of the scriptures to assist us and our families.</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p18" pid="_5gN20yhdEintIq7k7zwKA" hash="0epRHw">King Benjamin in the Book of Mormon set a wonderful example of how parents should teach their children from the scriptures, as found in Mosiah 1, beginning with verse 3. Note how many times he uses the word <span class="emphasis">remember.</span></p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p19" pid="puLHNd8dH0qsdgUXGycpmQ" hash="3_emcg">“My sons, I would that ye should <span class="emphasis">remember</span> that were it not for these plates [meaning the scriptures], which contain these records and these commandments, we must have suffered in ignorance, even at this present time, not knowing the mysteries of God.</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p20" pid="LTYq1Qym70uGiWPlTa-GpQ" hash="4Ybp_Q">“For <span class="emphasis">it</span> were not possible that our father, Lehi, could have <span class="emphasis">remembered</span> all these things, to have taught them to his children, … that thereby they could teach them to their children, and so fulfilling the commandments of God, even down to this present time.</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p21" pid="k0M4C3YA9k-CLwwFfYVmAA" hash="Yk7uHQ">“I say unto you, my sons, were it not for these things, which have been kept and preserved by the hand of God, that we might read and understand of his mysteries, and have his commandments always before our eyes, … even our fathers would have dwindled in unbelief. …</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p22" pid="XVluOi-nE0K1Fz1UHf2o9A" hash="ggFTIQ">“O my sons, I would that ye should <span class="emphasis">remember</span> that these sayings are true, and also these records are true. …</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p23" pid="Z0QYlqSAf0yUwu6q8Fel9w" hash="Up95Cw">“And now, my sons, I would that ye should <span class="emphasis">remember</span> to search them diligently, that ye may profit thereby; and I would that ye should keep the commandments of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/1.3-7" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 1:3–7</a>; italics added.)</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p24" pid="TZcGuLqRNUiI749wVZjjqQ" hash="-roapA">I bear testimony that keeping the scriptures “always before our eyes” works! We have found the sweet influence of the Spirit in our home as we have learned from the scriptures daily with our children—beginning while the children were very young. Some mornings it meant putting “mind over mattress” as we got out of bed early to gather as a family for scripture study, but “sacrifice brings forth the blessings of heaven.” (“Praise to the Man,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> 1985, no. 27.)</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="jqsZDtqUl0OkB09BA21fvA" hash="lFQUFA">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p25" pid="oE9ZO8DnC0a-uus6CeaO8Q" hash="TNy2VQ">We Can Remember the Lord through Keeping the Commandments. We have been given commandments in order to help us draw near to the Lord and eventually to become like Him. “How gentle God’s commands! How kind his precepts are!” (Hymns, 1985, no. 125.) Is it any wonder that His love for us shows through His rules for us? Might we as parents use this as the manner in which we teach our children?</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p26" pid="r7HsNKI7PEem-DHzoAEJ9w" hash="K2z9kw">The Lord has told parents, “And thou shalt teach [the commandments of God] diligently unto thy children, and shalt talk of them when thou sittest in thine house, and when thou walkest by the way, and when thou liest down, and when thou risest up.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/deut/6.7" class="scriptureRef">Deut. 6:7</a>.) I might also add, when thou ironest thy clothes, when thou makest thy beds, and when thou plantest thy garden—that is to say, talk about the gospel in every teaching moment.</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p27" pid="rQIXft7RFEOCmN2RXbeLbQ" hash="d8S6gg">The gospel of Jesus Christ teaches us a way of life that, if followed, will help us avoid the stumbling blocks and the detours that draw us off course and beckon us to follow the ways of the world. Think of it! What a protection we have when we obey His laws such as the Word of Wisdom, the law of chastity, the law of tithing, and other commandments.</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p28" pid="bmldIdcVG06k-TWgL0AbZQ" hash="iRBVYA">Even little children can be taught the principle of security in “staying in back of the firing lines” or “not walking too close to the edge of the cliff.” Why should they offer themselves as casualties if they can avoid the danger zone? Teach them to avoid the very appearance of evil, such as not saying even slang expressions which may lead to taking the Lord’s name in vain; or dressing even a little immodestly which down the road may lead to improprieties; or partaking of substances that are not listed in the Word of Wisdom, yet are still harmful to the body; or holding back a little on tithes and offerings; or telling half-truths.</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p29" pid="M0D3oaAK2UydN_EDmkwkOg" hash="GkGFFA">“Keep the commandments! In this there is safety; in this there is peace.” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> 1985, no. 303.) While there is little of safety and peace in many parts of the world, we can find it in our hearts and in our homes as we do the works of righteousness. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:23</a>.)</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p30" pid="ZAEcLqahXki6rPJTIIPAvQ" hash="4m7pvA">We learn from Alma that the sons of Helaman remembered their mothers’ teachings and did obey them, and performed every work with exactness. They were strict to remember the Lord their God, keeping His commandments continually, and therefore were delivered from the hands of their enemies. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/56.47-48" class="scriptureRef">Alma 56:47–48</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/57.20-21" class="scriptureRef">Alma 57:20–21</a>.) Surely their mothers taught them truths that preserved their very lives.</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p31" pid="z4lVJg18lUuoXPfM3RFlJA" hash="zfqOTw">We are commanded to teach our children to pray and to walk uprightly before the Lord. You may remember the story that Elder Robert L. Simpson told about a three-year-old boy who knelt down with his daddy to say his bedtime prayers. Eyes were closed, heads were bowed, but no words were spoken for several moments. Soon the little boy climbed into his bed. The daddy opened his eyes and said, “But what about prayers?”</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p32" pid="akfncQ0JK0GL5ZsfryBUuQ" hash="7bW8gQ">And the boy answered, “I said my prayers.”</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p33" pid="-zR36hKI60GSVVjNkPt_6A" hash="H4OQww">“But I didn’t hear you,” said the daddy.</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p34" pid="qaVgcW7fB0GZUbsaISB9Hw" hash="X-ZL0g">Then followed the child’s classic comment, “But Daddy, I wasn’t talking to you.” (See <span class="emphasis">Proven Paths,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1974, p. 148.)</p>
          <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p35" pid="aZgPFyflzkKoDpOlfnZgQg" hash="JoWVhg">Sometimes children, being pure and holy, teach us something of our heavenly home. But as they grow, we need to remind them to walk by the rules, even though they may view them as restrictive. They will find that His yoke is easy and His burden is light (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/11.29-30" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 11:29–30</a>) compared to the consequences of disobedience.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="oXs5BOpmh0qfJYfVWdsHqw" hash="_1krNQ">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="RhT_fV7rz0O_3Jo9aMVwTQ" hash="fPPsuw">We Can Remember the Lord through Keeping Our Covenants. Anciently the Lord made covenants with His children to help them remember who they were and what was expected of them.</p>
          <p pid="pATIRAkEgU2wnQNrgdh2lg" hash="Z6qFbw">The children of Israel made covenants, and certain tokens were given to help them remember the Lord their God. But through disobedience they forgot, just like the Nephites forgot, and they reaped the consequences.</p>
          <p pid="CIWiMT49uEaJO33QgQKb8Q" hash="ByoVLA">In our day, we again have a chance to make covenants to keep us in remembrance that we are sons and daughters of God desiring to return to His presence.</p>
          <p pid="Uqc2sbFWv0OOkHnW44leHg" hash="X65A6A">Teaching the importance of ordinances and covenants cannot be taken casually by Latter-day Saints. Elder Boyd K. Packer shared his insight when he said: “Ordinances and covenants become our credentials for admission into His presence. To worthily receive them is the quest of a lifetime; to keep them thereafter is the challenge of mortality.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1987, p. 24.)</p>
          <p pid="UqeGWr5vhk62ZmVznf4zsw" hash="5-287w">We have the privilege of making sacred covenants at baptism and in the holy temples, with an invitation to renew them often. Each week we partake of the sacrament that we may “always remember him.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/4.3" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 4:3</a>, <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/5.2" class="scriptureRef">5:2</a>.) Also, returning to the temple as often as possible helps us remember the covenants we have made there.</p>
          <p pid="koF8NVQ__0ONUikWpDlXCQ" hash="MQHMCg">Keeping our covenants should make a difference in the way we live, the way we act, the way we speak, the way we dress, the way we treat each other. If we “always remember him,” we will “always have his Spirit to be with us.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/4.3" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 4:3</a>.) Then with that Spirit we will be viewed by the world as distinct and different in happy ways. None of us lives in a perfect home, and for most of us there is much room for improvement. Though often unheralded and unsung, mothers can feel joy, irrepressible joy, when within the walls of their own homes each person is trying to live the gospel and to remember the Savior.</p>
          <p pid="MI-DyAyR20qRBb0zX5TdVA" hash="tHBqXg">What joy a mother feels when her newly baptized eight-year-old daughter bears her testimony that she is willing to take upon her the name of Christ; or when a son at age twelve refuses breakfast because he’s fasting in order to choose his counselors as deacons quorum president; or when her adult daughters eagerly enter Relief Society, the Lord’s organization for women, to learn what their mother is learning about faith, family, and service—all because the teachings have been internalized and loving the Lord has top priority in their lives.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p36" pid="ATCifXABt0uQf3NjgCMBIA" hash="MFbH3w">The Lord loves you for being His partner in His plan. Be of good cheer as you perform your divinely ordained task of guiding the destiny of this generation, that they may then pass the baton of righteousness on to generations yet unborn.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him.p37" pid="3aisujpcZUy_MskEEJvYRQ" hash="a-o32A">As we go to our homes, sisters, may we ponder what has been said. How can we as daughters of God help bring souls unto Christ? How can we know and remember our Savior? How will the children know unless we teach them so? In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1989/10/remember-him</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1989-general-womens-meeting/1989-09-0020-joanne-b-doxey-64k-eng.mp3" length="6873290" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 1989 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
