<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Joe J. Christensen</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Joe J. Christensen.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Joe%20J.%20Christensen.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Joe J. Christensen.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1989 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1989 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Good Memories Are Real Blessings</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Brethren, it’s a marvelous privilege to be with you this evening. I’ve appreciated so much the messages that we have heard.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03245_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="6p1X7g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="3iVCnq1Jh0W5aPUGWn51nA" hash="JxBh5A">Good Memories Are Real Blessings</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="4xIpH_Vn6Uiw1x01YXjuyQ" hash="2eUxTA">Joe J. Christensen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2012.jpg" alt="Elder Joe J. Christensen" pid="PMc2757JqUOsbWF_vIuw-A" hash="LD9-nA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p1" pid="do9LYr3D3EuUBBlx5QzUoQ" hash="F8rrLg">Brethren, it’s a marvelous privilege to be with you this evening. I’ve appreciated so much the messages that we have heard.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p2" pid="_kGOiCJnKkmzZKmpCC3k7Q" hash="DX0jsA">Someone who was a little more poetic than theological said, “Memory is the one Garden of Eden out of which one need never be cast.” Good memories are real blessings. Tonight I would like to share a few memories that have made a real difference in my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p3" pid="mA_eK_mibUOaHuMtanSL_A" hash="EMoHKA">When I was a young man about the age of some of you deacons here, my dad was bishop of the ward in our little farming town of Banida in southeastern Idaho. I remember the first time he brought me with him to Salt Lake City to attend a general priesthood meeting. In those years, Dad always seemed to me to be really old. As I recognize now, he must have been around thirty-eight years of age. I was happy to be with him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p4" pid="bWzydGhi_kaV9-oavuxhxA" hash="zxsPbg">I remember we sat in the balcony there on the north side. Before the meeting started, Dad pointed out which one of the Brethren on the stand was President Heber J. Grant and which were his Counselors. I saw the Twelve Apostles and the other Brethren. And that night, a warm feeling of love and respect for the leaders of the Church came over me and has continued to grow to this day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p5" pid="xu6qQle0z0uzNyXndbShsg" hash="_GTYjQ">That night, I decided I wanted to do everything I could to support my dad as bishop. I didn’t want to do anything that would embarrass or disappoint him. To this day, I am grateful for those feelings that came to me that night.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p6" pid="khAzNLrfP0auF2zk8n2Ppw" hash="ov8mWg">None of us knows how long we are going to live. In the Book of Mormon, Alma asked the question, “Can ye look up to God at that day with a pure heart and clean hands?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.19" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:19</a>.) I remember when the need to have “clean hands and a pure heart” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/24.4" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 24:4</a>) became very meaningful to me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p7" pid="WM7zc2VgaUGxtZQkamq5nQ" hash="_O_Wag">It was just after my friend David Carlson and I had graduated from Preston High School. We were happy with the fact that it was the same school that Presidents Ezra Taft Benson and Harold B. Lee had attended when they were growing up. Even though they had changed the name from the Oneida Stake Academy to Preston High School, we still had some of our classes in the same building.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p8" pid="Nel7VDNOB0-aO45H7O36Vg" hash="uZTQpw">We thought that 1946 was the “golden year” of athletics at Preston High. That year our teams won the district championship in every sport, and in basketball our team won the state championship—and that was in the days when the small high schools played against the big ones.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p9" pid="Oy7rA962ME-n-IiEav9XFA" hash="y9tq8g">David was a good friend to me and, I think, to everybody in the school. He was a fine student. He worked hard and received excellent grades. He achieved in Scouting and seminary and was a well-coordinated athlete. David was a member of the basketball team, and his playing was one of the reasons our team won the state championship.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p10" pid="_N_phqjGSkqnxmcZj4VJaA" hash="VtTqnQ">Soon after high school graduation, David went to the hospital for what everyone thought was a routine operation, but there were some complications. Infection set in, and the next thing we heard was that he had died. We could not believe it. At age eighteen, David had died. What a shock! I still remember how painful it was to lose a good friend.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p11" pid="LYtsxNdK-UqhUXSrLDNHeg" hash="JIF7kg">His funeral was held in the stake center. Everyone seemed to come. It was like a crowded stake conference with standing room only.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p12" pid="v0Hhn4uRd0eKTZqQaECOPg" hash="dfVlzQ">Bishop Eberhard included a statement in his remarks that made a powerful impression on me. He pointed over to the sacrament table and said, “When David knelt to bless the sacrament, I knew that he knelt there with ‘clean hands and a pure heart.’ I never had to worry about what he had been doing the Saturday night before.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p13" pid="TI7KpInM1kSfKY7pqxMA8Q" hash="Ielcjg">I thought that was one of the finest compliments he could have paid to my friend, and I wanted to live in such a way that my bishop would not have to worry about what I had been doing the night before. I’m sure that all of us could benefit from making a similar decision.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p14" pid="F1vHBwBr5UC33HUy8JqV-g" hash="pRF8jg">Another memory taught me more about the value and importance of fulfilling a mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p15" pid="60afryUzhke1CJhfNC9DJQ" hash="Nv6Ksw">A few years ago, while serving as president of the Missionary Training Center in Provo, Utah, I had a delightful visit with one of the missionaries who came into my office. He was obviously older than the average young elder. He was about twenty-five years of age. He told me of his conversion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p16" pid="Vwdf6MCqs0G1ZbkfU22Kyw" hash="cATV1Q">When he was sixteen, he was baptized into the Church in Europe along with his mother. His father did not object to his wife’s and son’s joining the Church, even though he was not interested. He was a banker and wanted his son to prepare himself for a profession in the same area.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p17" pid="1rtUwJSN_0aT9fUvBl85hg" hash="sRaTEA">The young man loved studying the scriptures, but occasionally had some difficulty when his father would interrupt him when he was studying his seminary course and say, “Don’t waste your time studying those things. Study your regular school courses so that you can be accepted at the university.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p18" pid="fQ2T8mJyY0yDYb1tzxOP8Q" hash="Hmg_-g">The elder said, “One night later on, when I was about eighteen, I had a dream. I dreamed that I had been called on a mission to Japan. I felt so good about it. I really wanted to go. The next day, when I told my parents about my dream, my dad strongly objected. He said, “Oh, no! Don’t waste two years of your life on a mission. You need to get on with your university studies.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p19" pid="oo2aS0OglUaCVpDI1cmLpQ" hash="hfRjjA">Since he was too young to leave for a mission at that time anyway, he did go on with his university studies. He chose to come to Brigham Young University. He majored in finance and banking for his undergraduate degree and stayed to complete a master’s degree in business administration.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p20" pid="LE2zOmWMIkiCx3NBfRl9KA" hash="8axCYg">He was hired by an international banking firm in Germany and was doing very well as a promising junior executive, but the idea of filling a mission would not leave his mind, and so he went to visit with his bishop and stake president. When he told his stake president of the vivid dream he had years before about going on a mission to Japan, his stake president chuckled and said, “Well, I don’t think you will be going to Japan. Missionaries from here generally are called to some other country on the continent, and a few go over to the British Isles.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p21" pid="Xn7P1Rsyg0qJ-Zt6GkZjJw" hash="6FfDAg">When he received his call and his father heard of it, he came and tried to change his son’s mind because he thought that a two-year interruption would be a disaster for his son’s professional career. One of the bank executives came down from Frankfurt and tried to discourage him from leaving, saying something like, “My boy, do you know how much this will cost you in salary and opportunity loss? You ought to sit down and figure it out.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p22" pid="vo80Tsc9IUOgKLnYSxjOYw" hash="Hu59Vw">The elder said that he did that, and he had determined that the mission would cost him a very large amount of money—more than 150,000 dollars. Then tears came to his eyes, and he said, “But President, if it were to cost several times that amount, I would still be here, because I know that serving a mission is what the Lord wants me to do.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p23" pid="CB9T6aSi70eRTGpsC2ozGQ" hash="Kc1I4g">That elder was one of the few I remember who left the Missionary Training Center speaking what Japanese he had learned with a German accent. He was called to Japan. He served a successful mission, and I am confident that when he finished he found many international businesses that would like to hire a junior executive who can speak English, German, and Japanese—the major languages of the economic free world. Even if he didn’t earn an extra cent, he still knew that he had done what the Lord wanted him to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p24" pid="FSYnHywg30iMLptC0i6kGQ" hash="oIlH4Q">Through the Prophet Joseph Smith, the Lord revealed the scripture which we have already heard from Elder Banks this evening—“that the thing which will be of the most worth unto you will be to declare repentance unto this people, that you may bring souls unto me.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/15.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 15:6</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/16.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 16:6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p25" pid="ojwmG5s3oEyU-Sr9UcBRhA" hash="cnYkOA">Over the years we have been so impressed by the thousands of missionaries we have seen at the Missionary Training Center, at Ricks College, and elsewhere, who have demonstrated their willingness to serve their missions—and some of them, at great personal sacrifice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p26" pid="imFfmz1TSUilEh-_QJ7-Fg" hash="f1DKWg">Brethren, may it be that in our lives generally, and in our priesthood responsibilities specifically, we, like David, my good friend, will set the kind of example so that our bishops will not have to wonder or worry about what we have been doing the Saturday night before.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p27" pid="PwKQ1oMq_kmlNWT9JdbGuQ" hash="2i0n_Q">I am grateful for sons who still come with me to general priesthood sessions. You young brethren who are not with your fathers tonight, for whatever reason, can decide right now that when you are blessed with sons of your own, you will bring them to the general priesthood sessions wherever they may be broadcast.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p28" pid="hgs_LSfz30-TZQ7Q2gkiMw" hash="RTf4rw">As I look up into the balcony tonight, I see some of you young men who are seated with your fathers, and I remember—I remember that first time so long ago. Dad passed away four years ago, and especially at general priesthood session time I am reminded more forcefully of how much we miss him. May we strive never to do anything that would embarrass or disappoint our Father in Heaven or our parents, and it will help make more of our memories to be good ones, because good memories constitute the “one Garden of Eden out of which we need never be cast.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p29" pid="OH1IDR1Gr06rZ5MY-zBLdA" hash="6mi0Xw">Young brethren, we respect you. We have confidence that you will rise to the best that is in you, and we love you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings.p30" pid="yx6CVO8qfUOI_Qaj3RWUWA" hash="Vc6qXg">Our Heavenly Father lives. He also loves you and even knows you by name. Jesus is the Christ, and this is His church, led by the living prophets who are presiding at this general priesthood session. I share this testimony in the holy name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1989/10/good-memories-are-real-blessings</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1989-general-conference/1989-10-3040-elder-joe-j-christensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5261109" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1989 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rearing Children in a Polluted Environment</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Not long ago, I had an impromptu conversation with a group of young parents who exhibited a great deal of anxiety about rearing their children in our morally polluted environment. They asked for assistance in helping their children find their way in </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_93911_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="EnFEsw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="4vgXTon4y02LUPpYxFl0Xw" hash="M3Ad6w">Rearing Children in a Polluted Environment</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="295lO_r5aU2lBBnVBYotIQ" hash="2eUxTA">Joe J. Christensen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2012.jpg" alt="Elder Joe J. Christensen" pid="c-_uizGPiE6x7IakrE5ylg" hash="LD9-nA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p1" pid="qDm-x1JlA0KfVbL763DpnQ" hash="T8guZA">Not long ago, I had an impromptu conversation with a group of young parents who exhibited a great deal of anxiety about rearing their children in our morally polluted environment. They asked for assistance in helping their children find their way in a world that seems to be unraveling.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p2" pid="y8dtLzHBEUW_Tvey2sXQbw" hash="WcQZtA">We all hear and read a great deal these days about our polluted physical environment—acid rain, smog, toxic wastes. But these parents recognize that there is another kind of pollution that is much more dangerous—the moral and spiritual.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p3" pid="D4ydXSQmfEyb2Ou_rA99fQ" hash="LCl0qQ">In a recent conference, Elder Boyd K. Packer said, “As we test the <span class="emphasis">moral</span> environment, we find the <span class="emphasis">pollution</span> index is spiraling upward” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1992, p. 66). The Apostle Paul foresaw “that in the last days perilous times shall come” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/3.1" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 3:1</a>). And speaking of the last days, the prophet Moroni declared, “Yea, it shall come in a day when there shall be great pollutions upon the face of the earth” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/morm/8.31" class="scriptureRef">Morm. 8:31</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p4" pid="AQcLVI4R0kG7cMkim5y6kg" hash="Rim-RA">Sadly, the effects of this great pollution are perhaps most evident in the mass media, films, television, and popular music. Of this, Senator Robert D. Byrd said, “If we in this nation continue to sow the images of murder, violence, drug abuse, … perversion, [and] pornography … before the eyes of millions of children, year after year and day after day, we should not be surprised if the foundations of our society rot away as if from leprosy” (Michael Medved, <span class="emphasis">Hollywood vs. America,</span> New York: Harper Perennial, 1992, p. 194).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p5" pid="GXaOS5Z3kEav9X71t0CeIg" hash="5025OA">Although there are some uplifting exceptions, in most areas of the mass media there seems to be a declaration of war against almost everything the majority treasures most: the family, religion, and patriotism. Marriage is degraded, while premarital and extramarital relations are encouraged and glamorized. Profanity and the foulest of vulgar gutter language bombard the ears of all who listen. Reportedly, in one R-rated movie, the most common, vulgar four-letter word was spoken 256 times! Human life itself is trivialized by the constant barrage of violence and killings. Remember that anything that is not good for children is rarely good for adults.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p6" pid="pJW9_BkBG0q8oT14rbjOpA" hash="iETMBQ">In an unsuccessful effort to ward off teen pregnancy and social disease, birth control devices are freely distributed. I am convinced that this practice strongly communicates the basic message to many youth that “anything goes; just protect yourself in the process.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p7" pid="vzE1qwOC_0SbQZMUCikVzg" hash="5tYIrw">It is no wonder that young parents become very anxious as they attempt to fulfill their sacred trust in the face of such an onslaught of despicable influences. Unfortunately, these challenges confront members of the Church as well as nonmembers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p8" pid="O1f-4fU-tE6iVcA-YKPcLQ" hash="6rVO9A">Parents who really want to receive assistance must return to the basics—the fundamentals of the gospel. Among all that could be said, here are four specific suggestions that, if applied, can make a positive difference:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p9" pid="Pzymu7_ACESZBbL8qkaoCQ" hash="aFcqKw">First, <span class="emphasis">do not be afraid to set clear moral standards and guidelines.</span> Be sure to say no when it is needed. As Dr. John Rosemond counseled:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p10" pid="1-ITjts68EuS5IEn_KrROA" hash="phiq0Q">“[Give] your children regular, daily doses of Vitamin N. This vital nutrient consists simply of the most character-building two-letter word in the English language [<span class="emphasis">No</span>]. … Unfortunately, many, if not most, of today’s children suffer from Vitamin N deficiency. They’ve been overindulged by well-meaning parents who’ve given them far too much of what they want and far too little of what they truly need” (John K. Rosemond, <span class="emphasis">John Rosemond’s Six-Point Plan for Raising Happy, Healthy Children,</span> Kansas City, Mo.: Andrews &amp; McMeel, 1989, p. 114).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p11" pid="XngVqT_DEEqD30YxRsRWfw" hash="NrVbHg">Even though your children say, “Well, everyone else is going to stay out until one or two in the morning, and their parents don’t care. Why can’t I? Don’t you trust me?” let them know that there are some things that, as members of your family, you simply do not do. Some parents seem to be almost pathologically concerned about their children’s popularity and social acceptance and go along with many things that are really against their better judgment, such as expensive fads, immodest clothes, late hours, dating before age sixteen, R-rated movies, and so on. For children and parents, standing up for what is right may be lonely at times. There may be evenings alone, parties missed, and movies which go unseen. It may not always be fun. But parenting is not a popularity contest.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p12" pid="Fn3YrOSg9kilgjdWlRSrgg" hash="QCBYzA">You may need to get together with the parents of your children’s friends and mutually agree on more acceptable high standards of entertainment, hours, and activities. Your children may be frustrated at first, but in the end they will grow to appreciate you even more because you cared enough about them to set some wholesome guidelines and standards.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p13" pid="eTJu1R0MZUqBjojaA2OJjw" hash="7zzByQ">Second, <span class="emphasis">teach your children to work and to take responsibility. </span>Especially in urban settings, too many children are growing up in an environment where they do not have enough to do. They are like the young thirteen-year-old boy who was asked what he did all day in the summer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p14" pid="qw96evrKk02Qvy1XtdbzhA" hash="8yl4Qw">He said, “Well, I get up in the morning about ten or eleven. Then my mom gets me something to eat. Then maybe, I’ll go with some of the guys and play a little basketball, maybe watch TV, and then go down to the mall and ‘hang out’ for a while—sorta watch the girls and stuff.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p15" pid="x_IGeN9clEuqBT0xBpVioQ" hash="MC-yAQ">When asked what time he got to bed, he said, “Oh, usually about one or two o’clock. I go over to a friend’s house and watch some videos. It’s really neat, because my friend’s mom told the guy at the video shop that it was all right for her son to check out any video he wanted—including R-rated.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p16" pid="cmT5vU4gpUerx_MK4h1sVw" hash="vsUQgg">I feel great concern for the future of that young Latter-day Saint boy as well as for that of his friends.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p17" pid="2lsEAhMckU2Te9UpKXlorw" hash="yJtzBw">I like what President Spencer W. Kimball has said on this topic:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p18" pid="la0BRoD3bkKrTytifvh0UA" hash="KaFZFA">“The idle generation! Hours each day and nothing to do. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p19" pid="4ahECgx8gUC82v1h7_f5bw" hash="gal0Jw">“We want you parents to create work for your children. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p20" pid="PBcRDFNScUGX1XHnCLc9rg" hash="z8PDLA">“‘What can we do?’” they ask.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p21" pid="aETiNQBemU2nHhm6ixzdYQ" hash="0lLAtQ">“Do the shopping, work in the hospital, help the neighbors and the church custodian, wash dishes, vacuum the floors, make the beds, get the meals, learn to sew.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p22" pid="mfatcA1zsk677NuijVsZsg" hash="S6Xh7A">“Read good books, … clean the house, press your clothes, rake the leaves, shovel the snow, peddle papers.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p23" pid="uSQgCh4H5UukYq21rxj7tQ" hash="NoRqNg">Then he concludes:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p24" pid="dDnixz_vgUW3QzOPdiX5Nw" hash="iqVcNw">“Lawmakers in their overeagerness to protect the child have legislated until the pendulum has swung to the other extreme. But no law prohibits most work [here] suggested … , and parents can make work” (<span class="emphasis">The Teachings of Spencer W. Kimball,</span> ed. Edward L. Kimball, Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1982, pp. 360–61).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p25" pid="gITEg0xSDEiFVaVYPpcq6Q" hash="xpU0WQ">In addition, help your children learn self-discipline by such activities as learning to play a musical instrument or other demanding skill. I am reminded of the story of the salesman who came to a house one hot summer day. Through the screen door he could see a young boy practicing his scales on the piano. His baseball glove and hat were by the side of the piano bench. He said, “Say, boy, is your mother home?” To which the boy replied, “What do you think?” Thank heavens for conscientious parents!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p26" pid="RsqPbwaT-U6ah50TJDbiKA" hash="X6b_eQ">Every child should be helped to develop some skill or talent by which he or she can experience success and thus build self-esteem.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p27" pid="Qv6FfRiOxUqm5ZKFg3Lhlw" hash="rIaVbw">Missionaries who have learned to work hard and have developed self-discipline are much more successful.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.f2">
	<p pid="ATwKqz09EkuJtova7wz8zw" hash="dqD5zg">Third, create an environment in your family in which spiritual experiences can occur. For example:</p>
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="qbf2xPhN90yDJswYPXgt1w" hash="zMgQLw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="VA3dbJXHHk-hkaFb8LPqtQ" hash="h72JNA">Remember family prayer every day. With schedules as they are, you may need to have more than one prayer. Sending children out of your home without the spiritual protection of prayer is like sending them out into a blizzard without sufficient clothing.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="9gBLVH1hRkGULqWhrAhpUg" hash="Ac1plQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="NHshUqg-wUy_ZIymFfzu5Q" hash="BW14uw">Hold family home evenings <span class="emphasis">every week</span> without fail. This is a wonderful time to share your testimony with your children. Give them an opportunity to share their feelings about the gospel. Help them to learn to recognize when they feel the presence of the Spirit. Family home evenings will help create an island of refuge and security within your own home.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Rg0DQwFUiU2bWffWP1U_1Q" hash="nIc7Qw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="vIL28ayEaEWUoJ0K93HkRw" hash="vh0kww">Read the scriptures together daily as a family. There is real power in the scriptures.</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p28" pid="Qapose7PV0u2r1SZzuhI_A" hash="QBbgLw">Is the Book of Mormon a significant part of your reading? Count the number of rich promises President Marion G. Romney made to parents when he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p29" pid="mQ9UgDyin0y7MHtUJuG22A" hash="tb_ARA">“I feel certain that if, in our homes, parents will read from the Book of Mormon prayerfully and regularly, both by themselves and with their children, the spirit of that great book will come to permeate our homes. … The spirit of reverence will increase; mutual respect and consideration for each other will grow. The spirit of contention will depart. Parents will counsel their children in greater love and wisdom. Children will be more responsive and submissive to the counsel of their parents. Righteousness will increase. … The pure love of Christ … will abound in our homes and lives, bringing in their wake peace, joy, and happiness” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1980, p. 67).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p30" pid="hqb-5MRKgUW36_u9OKB3dw" hash="USunsw">We should not take these ten promises lightly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p31" pid="2lCblvXey0C1tjZK6ElmDQ" hash="oZ8uPw">Fourth, <span class="emphasis">follow the counsel of the prophets.</span> Listen to their messages at this conference and re-read their counsel to us from prior occasions. If your personal and family practices do not conform to the counsel received, then, for your own family’s sake, make some changes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p32" pid="7_W_TW7y5EemUkiGu6VdXg" hash="cTuDfQ">President Harold B. Lee said: “We must learn to give heed to the words and commandments that the Lord shall give through his prophet … [and quoting from the Doctrine and Covenants] ‘as if from mine own mouth, in all patience and faith’ (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/21.4-5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 21:4–5</a>).” He continued: “There will be some things that take patience and faith. You may not like what comes from the authority of the Church. It may contradict your political views. It may contradict your social views. It may interfere with some of your social life. … Your safety and ours depends upon whether or not we follow the ones whom the Lord has placed to preside over his church” (in Conference Report, Oct. 1970, pp. 152–53).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p33" pid="bvbLkOQQEkaUYy6T-rN56g" hash="YzjqFw">From a personal standpoint, of what value is it to have living prophets if we do not heed their counsel?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p34" pid="xoqYnhD9c0ioGPJXdw8PDg" hash="wVTS3A">Fathers and mothers, it is not too late to change. There is still hope. You can begin today to apply these suggestions and others you may add. We can help our children and grandchildren to survive spiritually and morally in a world where the pollution index continues to spiral upward. The intent is not to take our children out of the world but, as the Lord prayed, to keep them from evil (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.15" class="scriptureRef">John 17:15</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p35" pid="P9pn6w9Tgki2GebaPYnLZw" hash="UDYXpw">I know that our Heavenly Father lives. We are his spirit children, and he loves his family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p36" pid="a6p0kQCaMkSNamH8FRPgOA" hash="V5sY7Q">Jesus is the Christ, and this is his church, which is led by living prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment.p37" pid="_DOxGBa9yEKnl91FEEINvg" hash="49x3pg">Of this I sincerely testify in the name of Jesus the Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1993/10/rearing-children-in-a-polluted-environment</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1993-general-conference/1993-10-1040-elder-joe-j-christensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="6108092" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 1993 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marriage and the Great Plan of Happiness</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/04/marriage-and-the-great-plan-of-happiness?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Barbara and I have been blessed with six children. Some years ago, when we had taken all of them to visit with their grandparents, my father said, “Joe, I think you and Barbara have started something you can’t stop.”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/marriage-and-the-great-plan-of-happiness" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95905_000_027" doc-version="2" hash="ifgzjw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/marriage-and-the-great-plan-of-happiness.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="d2jy6z8XM0ismsQDvNCjbg" hash="BN-KMQ">Marriage and the Great Plan of Happiness</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="NH-uSIKAREK4eRJZ5vZpYw" hash="2eUxTA">Joe J. Christensen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/marriage-and-the-great-plan-of-happiness.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2012.jpg" alt="Elder Joe J. Christensen" pid="KP-6NL-_LkmbIdRJ6LGujg" hash="LD9-nA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/marriage-and-the-great-plan-of-happiness.p1" pid="ZmG0uoNW_kOKRByCfQ9yLQ" hash="rw5nuQ">Barbara and I have been blessed with six children. Some years ago, when we had taken all of them to visit with their grandparents, my father said, “Joe, I think you and Barbara have started something you can’t stop.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/marriage-and-the-great-plan-of-happiness.p2" pid="N8xHxbllkkOyVk7LkzI5NQ" hash="UivtiQ">At this Easter season we declare to all the world that Jesus is the Christ and that through his holy priesthood and its sealing power, marriages and families ideally need never stop—need never come to an end.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/marriage-and-the-great-plan-of-happiness.p3" pid="Xxmx28UsGEullZDxoJR0DQ" hash="yO1S3Q">Today I would like to speak to all of you about our marriages. Here are eight practical suggestions that, hopefully, may be of value in strengthening our marriages, now and in the future.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/marriage-and-the-great-plan-of-happiness.f2">
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="H1mEEnphdEuDtxS4kUS8KQ" hash="3punsw">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="sm-gT95_uUG9Xx2hcSewRQ" hash="RVl2YA">
            <span class="strong">Remember the central importance of your marriage.</span> Listen to these words from Elder Bruce R. McConkie on the importance of marriage in our Father in Heaven’s “great plan of happiness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/42.8" class="scriptureRef">Alma 42:8</a>):</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="E8b5I2M-bEufP8qRzP9d3Q" hash="Q_DPxQ">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="G1pEpn66xEWGGI7u597EUg" hash="QXT7jQ">
            <span class="strong">Pray for the success of your marriage.</span> Years ago, when it was common for a General Authority to tour a mission and interview all the missionaries, Elder Spencer W. Kimball, then a member of the Quorum of the Twelve, was visiting with an elder who was just about to finish his mission.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="H66YlXUXO0yFBtQSKQbW3w" hash="ErnVDg">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="Ss1IkuRT3kyxdMnDMTblHg" hash="Eh92JA">
            <span class="strong">Listen.</span> Make the time to listen to your spouse; even schedule it regularly. Visit with each other and assess how you are doing as a marriage partner.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="fOQ5GaYe5UaMsg5LIMwIvA" hash="YUNhaQ">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="SCaS6ouxm0Oa1hHCgAqNow" hash="R1t9ag">
            <span class="strong">Avoid “ceaseless pinpricking.”</span> Don’t be too critical of each other’s faults. Recognize that none of us is perfect. We all have a long way to go to become as Christlike as our leaders have urged us to become.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="2id4J2Sz0Ey5Vwqa_C-PkA" hash="xSIDKQ">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p pid="Q70WjreD0kKfCNRIVgunUQ" hash="Im32lw">
            <span class="strong">Keep your courtship alive.</span> Make time to do things together—just the two of you. As important as it is to be with the children as a family, you need regular weekly time alone together. Scheduling it will let your children know that you feel that your marriage is so important that you need to nurture it. That takes commitment, planning, and scheduling.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="E8eGlXQ6gUC8YkP13zXIIw" hash="ee2Yhw">
          <span class="label">6.</span>
          <p pid="UuvskgkwKU2bXgomw-RgYg" hash="wSSJZA">
            <span class="strong">Be quick to say, “I’m sorry.”</span> As hard as it is to form the words, be swift to say, “I apologize, and please forgive me,” even though you are not the one who is totally at fault. True love is developed by those who are willing to readily admit personal mistakes and offenses.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="88lhQ6rIi0qcmZxmGvkR3g" hash="J8yC9w">
          <span class="label">7.</span>
          <p pid="U5m0KeFerE-9Jln0Fhy-1Q" hash="lkBegQ">
            <span class="strong">Learn to live within your means.</span> Some of the most difficult challenges in marriage arise in the area of finances. “The American Bar Association … indicated that 89 percent of all divorces could be traced to quarrels and accusations over money” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> July 1975, p. 72). Be willing to postpone or forgo some purchases in order to stay within your budget. Pay your tithing first, and avoid debt insofar as possible. Remember that spending fifty dollars a month less than you receive equals happiness and spending fifty more equals misery. The time may have come to get out the scissors and your credit cards and perform what Elder Holland called some “plastic surgery” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> June 1986, p. 30).</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="tSNPOBpAt0qX1aKcn_WMuA" hash="JV3k9Q">
          <span class="label">8.</span>
          <p pid="UsdYQSEOmU2JNvnLZ0EWCw" hash="16887Q">
            <span class="strong">Be a true partner in home and family responsibilities.</span> Don’t be like the husband who sits around home expecting to be waited on, feeling that earning the living is his chore and that his wife alone is responsible for the house and taking care of the children. The task of caring for home and family is more than one person’s responsibility.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/marriage-and-the-great-plan-of-happiness.p4" pid="gFg4HO6xvUu1SXSZbptM4Q" hash="jVXs0A">In summary:</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/marriage-and-the-great-plan-of-happiness.f3">
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="9SOLqwuLYEuJ3kcpktLs0Q" hash="4HM9aA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="7NkVc7iU2EKUR68DpKssbw" hash="J-XgGg">Remember the central importance of your marriage.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="HtIOGkmZVU6KoB8DQxtcNQ" hash="1FNWfg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="NmVH_p2sUkWHGSwGvLqtYQ" hash="16_XlQ">Pray for its success.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="DYz3wfGbLkaWMXO34Ul_8A" hash="0ae5SA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="ascrrVfM80qwncN6Lk4D7A" hash="HPjE0w">Listen.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="zzV0dIiKyUOuUvd_s7Mdsw" hash="FmbzqQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="2d-03WH7TEOUp43ycKWI9w" hash="nbQZTw">Avoid “ceaseless pinpricking.”</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="jrYPNkjGXk2vd57S0ovNjA" hash="M0DRQQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="9smyH4dAWkOxwlPAlqsV0A" hash="A5d-aA">Keep your courtship alive.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="fFf3dHdktUemOvBB-ga2sQ" hash="mqVDHg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="lecP_Q1alkis93N8r2VlEw" hash="rvG83w">Be quick to say, “I’m sorry.”</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="sAuM41eGJkSHmTouThEJLQ" hash="SZ698Q">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="7Ie8ZJ_P6UC4h4CZ2apX5Q" hash="_9XChg">Learn to live within your means.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="_YYEqs04JEKFq7-CrNNWbQ" hash="B5nYPw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="z6yQ-005-kqJG2b77vgJ5A" hash="w_D8SQ">Be a true partner in home and family responsibilities.</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/marriage-and-the-great-plan-of-happiness.p5" pid="manuRtC7VUuGiqWfZO1JMg" hash="5JYM2Q">I testify that Jesus is the Christ. The tomb was empty on that third day, and “as in Adam all die, even so in Christ shall all be made alive” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/15.22" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 15:22</a>). Thus with gratitude for the sealing power within the restored gospel of Jesus Christ, we can confidently say with the poet, “I shall but love thee better after death” (Elizabeth Barrett Browning, “How Do I Love Thee?”). In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/04/marriage-and-the-great-plan-of-happiness</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1995-general-conference/1995-04-4030-elder-joe-j-christensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5637971" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 1995 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Savior Is Counting on You</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you?lang=eng</link>
      <description>A few years ago following general conference, our four-year-old grandson Andrew asked his mother, “Mommy, is Jesus counting on me?” His mother answered, “Oh yes, Andrew, Jesus  counting on you. He wants you to obey Mom and Dad, to do what is right, a</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_96911_000_017" doc-version="2" hash="y96CfQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="n8PFu-pgIU2mJdYQDvZxgw" hash="apMPXg">The Savior Is Counting on You</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="eAEMcJsKCUGRQyNQog-C2Q" hash="2eUxTA">Joe J. Christensen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2012.jpg" alt="Elder Joe J. Christensen" pid="aPsxYmJw_0O3_hXzZegbMw" hash="LD9-nA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p1" pid="8LmG-WZYi0-efV1pkK0cug" hash="jrNmPg">A few years ago following general conference, our four-year-old grandson Andrew asked his mother, “Mommy, is Jesus counting on me?” His mother answered, “Oh yes, Andrew, Jesus <span class="emphasis">is</span> counting on you. He wants you to obey Mom and Dad, to do what is right, and <span class="emphasis">especially</span> to be kind to your little brother, Benny.” This four-year-old thought about that for a few moments and said, “Mommy, tell Him <span class="emphasis">not</span> to count on me!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p2" pid="bmKySE8u1EakenlDwIURQQ" hash="AlaIZQ">Fortunately, by the time Andrew receives the Aaronic Priesthood, he will have come to know that Jesus <span class="emphasis">is</span> counting on him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p3" pid="4auEH4SLP0WMQt-m1cluaA" hash="Vk1QBw">Tonight let’s consider three important ways in which the Lord is counting on you who are privileged to bear the Aaronic Priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p4" pid="I6CpfwihFEi-hbqlX9FXMQ" hash="C83J7w">
        <span class="strong">First, the Savior is counting on you to be a champion of those who need you.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p5" pid="AyTh_5Hc10yOAYz_me0zPQ" hash="eibylg">In a high school not far from here, a young mentally handicapped student we will call Frank wanted so much to be accepted by the popular crowd. He would follow them around, always on the outside looking in, hoping to be included but never achieving it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p6" pid="K6Mx4C8b80qnOMPIldiRlQ" hash="YfLbxw">One day in the cafeteria, some of the more popular boys and girls encouraged Frank to get up on the table and dance. Thinking he would please them, he did it. In his awkward way, he twisted and twirled. The group yelled, clapped their hands, and laughed. They were laughing <span class="emphasis">at</span> him, and Frank thought they were laughing <span class="emphasis">with</span> him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p7" pid="bnBhLHHL7EGzhe8p7IdvmQ" hash="qRcfNQ">A few tables away, Dave was eating lunch with a friend and watching it all. He courageously leaped up, faced that crowd of tormentors, and through clenched teeth said, “I’ve had as much of this as I can stand!” He helped Frank down and said, “Frank, you come and have lunch with us.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p8" pid="-__Q0ioRc0GZ_q9Ms2n2IA" hash="YL4sTg">The Savior is counting on you to be a champion of those who need you, and they are all around you—in your school, in your neighborhood, in your family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p9" pid="uJXkYs1nZ0iZkpFj1XZLMg" hash="chrpZg">At a 20-year high school reunion, one of the graduates had a surprising conversation with one of her classmates that went something like this:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p10" pid="ZZs2v9npYU2uBBQDnYy1xA" hash="lP2ExQ">“I came to this reunion after all these years hoping you would be here so I could thank you. My high school experience was hard for me. You may not have known it, but you were the only friend I had in high school. I wondered if maybe the seminary teacher had assigned you to be nice to me. Did he?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p11" pid="Cr29S8C_eUS-Bl0rRvaX9Q" hash="hX2Sow">“No. He didn’t assign me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p12" pid="lM8uQxiTxU6blQ-BnNnf7A" hash="lXGmnA">“Well, you didn’t know it, but every day I looked for you because I knew that you would talk to me. You made me feel better about myself. Now I am married and have a large family. During these past years I have thought many times of what you meant to me, and I wanted to tell you that.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p13" pid="rMtsNtWhw0K2Pe-syE2eHg" hash="zlpIGA">There are those who wake up every morning dreading to go to school, or even to a Church activity, because they worry about how they will be treated. You have the power to change their lives for the better. You are a bearer of the priesthood of God, and the Lord is counting on you to be a builder and give them a lift. Think less about yourself and more about the power you have to assist others, even those within your own family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p14" pid="85BEzePX30GEj8OJlOFGKg" hash="m_32dA">A 14-year-old sister was all dressed up to go to a Young Women activity at a time in her life when she felt very unsure about herself. She was quietly and self-consciously inching her way toward the front door, hoping not to be noticed by all the young men in the living room who were visiting with her older brother Russell. She was given a life-changing boost when her older brother interrupted his conversation and said to her in front of all his friends, “My, Emily, you look pretty tonight!” A small thing? No. There are young women who claim that they would not have made it through those growing-up years without the encouragement and support of their older brothers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p15" pid="QGDxQJ01vE-PQLZ1K-4EWA" hash="P0cdnw">Last month in the area of Salt Lake City, a fellow Aaronic Priesthood bearer, Zachary Snarr, was brutally and senselessly murdered. Among the many wonderful things said about him by family and friends was that he rarely missed a day without telling his mother how much he loved her. His cheerful and loving nature around their home leaves them with priceless memories. Your mothers need you to be a champion of them. Never should a bearer of the Aaronic Priesthood be guilty of saying anything discourteous or disrespectful to his mother.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p16" pid="O5lKpcesCE2zXF06SJvyHA" hash="QoRKSQ">The scriptures teach us that whenever we are abusive, thoughtless, or unkind to others, “the devil laugheth, and his angels rejoice” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/9.2" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 9:2</a>); also, that “the heavens withdraw themselves; the Spirit of the Lord is grieved; and when it is withdrawn, Amen [or the end] to the priesthood or the authority of that man” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.37" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:37</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p17" pid="85wCCgncHE-qU5KUAJWRxg" hash="w3Bqew">Maybe you have thought that doing these little kindnesses doesn’t make much difference, but as Alma said, “By small and simple things are great things brought to pass” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.6" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:6</a>). We also read: “Be not weary in well-doing, for ye are laying the foundation of a great work. [<span class="emphasis">You</span> are a great work in progress.] And out of small things proceedeth that which is great” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.33" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:33</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p18" pid="lAerhALZ6UicSoOfRECoJg" hash="igi7VA">
        <span class="strong">Next, the Savior is counting on you to avoid the immoral trash that surrounds you in the media.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p19" pid="TsB3tpL6YEWohJRso_NxBA" hash="mrSpJg">Satan has made great inroads into the lives of some Latter-day Saints through the evil in the media. I am confident that the great majority of you have not been guilty of serious sexual sin, but many are placing themselves in a path that could lead to it. A bishop reported that he had observed that the spiritual level of the young priesthood bearers in his ward was declining. Through his personal interviews with them, he discovered that many of them were watching R-rated movies. When he asked them where they went to see such trash, they said, “We don’t go anywhere. We watch them at home. We have cable television, and when our parents are gone we watch anything we want to.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p20" pid="NMuNKxZFMUmIARwiSZuHBw" hash="rI2qPA">Fathers, you may want to reconsider having unrestricted cable or unsupervised television sets in your home and particularly in your children’s bedrooms.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p21" pid="uttUpPlQAEy4eOeMw_AJYg" hash="AKxiPA">It is very unreasonable to suppose that exposure to profanity, nudity, sex, and violence has no negative effects on us. We can’t roll around in the mud without getting dirty.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p22" pid="FPQHmhs7L0qm825BcamyKw" hash="NjKWnQ">It is a concern that some of our young Latter-day Saints, as well as their parents, regularly watch R-rated and other inappropriate movies and videos. One more reason why the “devil laugheth, and his angels rejoice” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/9.2" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 9:2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p23" pid="R11LJoES90W31eTA82Uefw" hash="xq-j7g">Just a few months ago the Lord’s prophet, President Gordon B. Hinckley, shared with the youth, and with all of us, this clear and unmistakable counsel:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p24" pid="DpfF2UFY20SMLyOBs5Q94w" hash="_A6bMA">“Be clean. I cannot emphasize that enough. Be clean. It is so very, very important, and you at your age are in such temptation all the time. It is thrown at you on television. It is thrown at you in books and magazines and videos. You do not have to rent them. Don’t do it. Just don’t do it. Don’t look at them. If somebody proposes that you sit around all night watching some of that sleazy stuff, you say, ‘It’s not for me.’ Stay away from it” (Denver, Colorado, youth meeting, 14 Apr. 1996).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p25" pid="fKkM9T_KV0aMUz1OTmLNcw" hash="zCHOmw">The Lord and his living prophets are counting on you to avoid the trash that surrounds you in the media. When anyone chooses to ignore or defiantly go against the counsel of the living prophet, he is on very shaky ground.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p26" pid="w-_vJ0qSoUqiQsOSqpjK9w" hash="CDHkkw">Remember that when Joseph was tempted by Potiphar’s wife to be immoral with her, he “fled, and got him out” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/39.12" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 39:12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p27" pid="ZZLZolldjEylYBYmoGXXRA" hash="U4F5Zw">Temptations are all around us, and today with the advent of the Internet, they are increasing. There is much that is positive in the world of the media, but there is so much that is negative. If we permit ourselves to become involved with the negative, there will be much more cause for the devil to laugh and his angels to rejoice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p28" pid="R-krsriz_kCi1JaCbhdUcw" hash="uDn5FQ">
        <span class="strong">Finally, the Savior is counting on you to be worthy to enter the temple and to fill an honorable mission.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p29" pid="arJGUDQ39kqdD-xjrRa09g" hash="uxk9QQ">An acquaintance of mine grew up not far from here. By the time he was 14 years old, he was over six feet tall and very uncoordinated. He said, “One afternoon when I was in a 10th-grade seminary class, the Spirit really touched me. I came to know that the gospel literally was true. I made up my mind that day that I wanted to serve the Lord in any way I could.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p30" pid="v3B3JObC8UWt0IxEZQs24w" hash="wVXIkw">By his senior year, he was well over six feet tall and much more coordinated. Many universities offered him scholarships to play basketball. After his first year playing at a university, he told his coach that he would like to be excused for two years to go on a mission. The coach said, “If you leave, you can be sure of one thing: you will never again wear one of our basketball uniforms!” Many thought that his “mission” ought to be playing basketball. Even some family members, including his parents, tried to convince him not to serve a mission. But he was totally committed. He was willing to give everything to the Lord—the scholarship, the applause of the fans, and the excitement of playing. He knew what the Lord was counting on him to do. He was called, and he served an honorable mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p31" pid="7v3qzfAVq0mW-VMfNA3V7Q" hash="bYOKgg">When he returned two years later, he was even taller and about 35 pounds heavier. His coach decided to repent. He was permitted to wear one of those basketball uniforms again, and in his senior year, his team not only won the conference championship but went on to the finals in national competition.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p32" pid="904hi5AyYEmE3XmEC7lQiA" hash="GndZhw">The Lord’s commandment to his Apostles was, “Go ye into all the world, and preach the gospel” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/16.15" class="scriptureRef">Mark 16:15</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p33" pid="FSilTRH5lEGKOEpG6362ow" hash="hwc2Wg">Modern prophets have taught that every young man who is physically and mentally able should prepare himself to serve an honorable mission. The Lord did not say, “Go on a mission if it fits your schedule, or if you happen to feel like it, or if it doesn’t interfere with your scholarship, your romance, or your educational plans.” Preaching the gospel is a commandment and not merely a suggestion. It is a blessing and a privilege and not a sacrifice. Remember, even though for some of you there may be very tempting reasons for you not to serve a full-time mission, the Lord and his prophets are counting on you.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.f2">
	<p pid="1NOE38lGwUOlu4cG45JKZw" hash="L0poWA">More than ever before in my life, I know that Jesus is the Christ. This is his Church and it is led by living prophets. The Lord and his prophets are counting on you to:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="wgoTy3Tngk2N0lS7AxQYDw" hash="5FiTrA">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="yh6I3uAyxE-lkoSoSuJ22A" hash="61Sucg">Be a champion of those who need you.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="n-w-hz8k7E6N8VbQNPZITg" hash="hTq94A">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="3cJPlZtqd0aSY-3EUSJhuw" hash="j2pInA">Avoid the trash that surrounds you in the media.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="xMCzjOYCJkeztTGQwB2oHw" hash="Ft9tAA">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="gv7RJZFVRECF1YPJOY9HbQ" hash="20wimQ">Be worthy to enter the temple and fill an honorable mission.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you.p34" pid="dORmit5vf022kvI6i4XYKQ" hash="23GiVg">I pray that the world will be a better place because you have lived in it. That is our task, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1996/10/the-savior-is-counting-on-you</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1996-general-conference/1996-10-3020-elder-joe-j-christensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5240017" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 1996 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greed, Selfishness, and Overindulgence</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I am confident that we will literally be called upon to make an accounting before God concerning how we have used [our resources] to bless lives and build the kingdom.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_99260_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="-4nt2A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="6n6z-ObTU0mTnpZbHjRsQg" hash="j-VHFA">Greed, Selfishness, and Overindulgence</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ZfbA6lqryk2ZTmo4qVzrVA" hash="2eUxTA">Joe J. Christensen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="61qumG39a0u-E85k9icdPQ" hash="L-PNew">I am confident that we will literally be called upon to make an accounting before God concerning how we have used [our resources] to bless lives and build the kingdom.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-e97.jpg" alt="Elder Joe J. Christensen" pid="pxHAQ7LqzkWFuYoqvOiYqw" hash="2sZjbA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p1" pid="SMs3zEoG4EGgjEF29Hr08w" hash="NcJydA">They say the gospel is to comfort the afflicted and to afflict the comforted. My purpose today is to speak to the comforted: the rich, the poor, and all of us in between.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p2" pid="iblww2fzn0eme2TyX1CM8g" hash="lxpBMQ">The Lord has said, “Wo unto you rich men, … for your riches will canker your souls.” He has also said, “Wo unto you poor men, whose hearts are not broken, … [and] whose eyes are full of greediness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p3" pid="4EUvyJjGeUa0d4YXaaNISw" hash="eutvIA">Many of you probably have heard this little prayer somebody wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p4" pid="acVCqxFYcEyRjxoecnHuFg" hash="MeABiA">“Dear God,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p5" pid="EH0NQim5rEK_7kpMLwahqg" hash="-0Ji4Q">“So far today I have done all right. I haven’t gossiped, haven’t lost my temper, haven’t been greedy, grumpy, nasty, selfish, or overly indulgent. But in a few minutes, Lord, I am going to get out of bed, and from then on, I am probably going to need a lot more help.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p6" pid="d6W2Q0SCQ0q3VlL9xZV0Tw" hash="Glpu8A">When it comes to overcoming being greedy, selfish, and overly indulgent, we all need a lot more help. In his candid manner, President Brigham Young said: “The worst fear … I have about this people is that they will get rich in this country, forget God and His people, wax fat, and kick themselves out of the Church. … My greater fear … is that they cannot stand wealth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p7" pid="4DWtvjBRrUOta6CU2xvp2A" hash="eOYY0A">Our prosperity brings some real challenges because many are getting rich, more of us are waxing fat, and as a result of greed, selfishness, and overindulgence, we could lose the Spirit and literally kick ourselves out of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p8" pid="bBbE6NX-RkWGsTWxASnZAw" hash="kE_tig">Money and material things are on the minds of almost everyone. As Morris Chalfant wrote: “The great [question] of the twentieth century is, ‘How can I acquire wealth?’ No question occupies a larger place in the minds and … hearts of … people today than this. … This is true of men in every station and in every walk of life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p9" pid="05cLznFv_UaByPsuC9dLQQ" hash="-nyFVw">Money in and of itself is not an evil, but as Paul taught Timothy, it is the <span class="emphasis">love</span> of money that is the root of all evil.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> There are some of the wealthy who deal with their prosperity very well using their resources to bless others and build the kingdom. For many, however, wealth presents major difficulties.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p10" pid="hEZhPKxVMEGmI2kRcMId1Q" hash="Xj_AAA">As we deal with the materialism that threatens us, here are four suggestions for each of us to consider:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p11" pid="2OcO8uB9w0GfHMRaAyQ4Ww" hash="m0bYOw">
        <span class="strong">First, we should not confuse wants with needs.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p12" pid="XmaAmZCAWkm0lGromBwrSg" hash="zB2p1A">My mother taught me an important lesson along these lines. For many years my father had a practice of trading for a new car every year. Then, shortly after World War II when grain prices increased, we were surprised one day when Dad drove home in a more expensive car.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p13" pid="Aldviqt7xkSbuXu4CW1RSg" hash="qD-C6g">One morning my mother asked, “How much more did the new car cost than the other one?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p14" pid="TlixKn1jvUuXS0IWiNKq3w" hash="HGzhxg">When Dad told her, my mother said, “Well, the other car has always been able to get me where I need to go. I think we ought to give the difference to someone who needs it more than we do.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p15" pid="2BooBffsqkGsiaTga5rcww" hash="GOJFeA">And so it was. The next year Dad returned to the less-expensive cars, and they continued their generous ways.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p16" pid="Jfw6GCIXvECEYId_v2qWVg" hash="-Rd0LA">If we are not careful, it is easy for our wants to become needs. Remember the line “There, there, little luxury, don’t you cry. You’ll be a necessity by and by.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p17" pid="FhYkjzrAQUODp9F3uXJIYA" hash="OU3LzA">
        <span class="strong">Second, we should avoid spoiling children by giving them too much.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p18" pid="I6yTm-MrlU2RpbrOcsaXww" hash="odfPbw">In our day, many children grow up with distorted values because we as parents overindulge them. Whether you are well-to-do or, like most of us, of more modest means, we as parents often attempt to provide children with almost everything they want thus taking away from them the blessing of anticipating, of longing for something they do not have. One of the most important things we can teach our children is to deny themselves. Instant gratification generally makes for weak people. How many truly great individuals do you know who never had to struggle?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p19" pid="5THvwqx-p0qdm_lSZRBwjw" hash="75fNJA">Elder Maxwell has voiced this concern when he said: “A few of our wonderful youth and young adults in the Church are unstretched. They have almost a free pass. Perks are provided, including cars complete with fuel and insurance—all paid for by parents who sometimes listen in vain for a few courteous and appreciative words. What is thus taken for granted … tends to underwrite selfishness and a sense of entitlement.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p20" pid="s307XEZoCkuym1xy7snzdg" hash="NI2sHg">A wise young mother said: “I choose not to give our children what I can afford to give them. I hold back for their sake.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p21" pid="tHTb_KqLSEi9d49Lmoax4A" hash="R6GUYQ">In the words of Fred Gosman, “Children who always get what they want will want as long as they live.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> And somewhere along the line it is important for the character development of our children to learn that “the earth still revolves around the sun” and not around them.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> Rather, we should train our children to ask themselves the question, How is the world a better place because they are in it?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p22" pid="gvwgst9N6EiFLi4XLsHxQw" hash="ihJ_NQ">We live in a world of entertainment in full color with a lot of fast action, a world in which many children grow up thinking that if it isn’t fun, it is boring and not worthwhile. Even in family activities, we need to strike a balance between play and work. Some of my most memorable experiences while growing up centered around family activities: learning how to shingle a roof, build a fence, or working in the garden. Rather than being all work and no play, for many of our children it is almost all play and very little work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p23" pid="U2Oprpw_1UOf--jTAlwbLw" hash="qUzdzw">As a consequence of overindulgence, many children leave homes ill-prepared to meet the real world. President Hinckley said: “Of course, we need to earn a living. The Lord told Adam that in the sweat of his face should he eat bread all the days of his life. It is important that we qualify ourselves to be self-reliant, particularly that every young man at the time of marriage be ready and able to assume the responsibilities of providing for his companion and for the children who may come to that home.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p24" pid="vVQx7ULEp0yhS4e-dTsSWw" hash="O4NSHA">All too many enter marriage who have never learned to cook, sew, or develop other important life skills. Ignorance of these needed skills, along with the lack of understanding of the management of money, sow the seeds for many failures in our children’s marriages.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p25" pid="ZW2Cnk9XdE-MkqQiID_mHA" hash="nm6I1Q">I fear that in many cases we are rearing children who are slaves to expensive fads and fashions. Remember the scripture, “For where your treasure is, there will your heart be also.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> How do we determine where our treasure is? To do so, we need to evaluate the amount of time, money, and thought we devote to something. Might it not be well to evaluate how much focus we place on shopping and spending?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p26" pid="q28rHtsR7Eyn2UQL2wrlkg" hash="MolGPQ">This does not mean that our children should not dress in some of the appropriate clothing that is in fashion because that can be very important to them. But they don’t need a closet full. As members of the Church, we have a responsibility to present ourselves in a well-groomed, attractive, and modest manner. With good planning, this can be done without being driven to spend extravagantly on our clothing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p27" pid="O985PhPIrUCI8Fd0acDIfQ" hash="OuJCRg">More than 10 times, the prophets in the Book of Mormon warn us about the problems of pride related to the nature of our clothing. Here is one example of them: “And it came to pass … that the people of the church began to wax proud, because of their exceeding riches, and their fine silks, and their fine-twined linen. … in all these things were they lifted up in the pride of their eyes, for they began to wear very costly apparel.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p28" pid="T4upQwSN80WgWSpBztE2Cg" hash="Ap2Mhg">We would do well if in all these areas of material things we and our children would follow the oft-quoted motto of our pioneer forebears to “fix it up, wear it out, make it do, or do without.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p29" pid="XPSniVi7ykyYCxebZp4jlQ" hash="xPrPPw">
        <span class="strong">Third, as we have heard so often, live modestly and avoid debt as if it were a plague.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p30" pid="QO496syo6EOJL1u0g9F9ow" hash="SCIrfw">President Hinckley recently reminded us of President Heber J. Grant’s statement: “If there is any one thing that will bring peace and contentment into the human heart, and into the family, it is to live within our means, and if there is any one thing that is grinding, and discouraging and disheartening it is to have debts and obligations that one cannot meet.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p31" pid="d1pfv7gQpkKbhuYgiBbcCg" hash="FHqaiA">Samuel Johnson said, “Do not accustom yourself to consider debt as an inconvenience, you will find it [to be] a calamity.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p32" pid="vhVKIE6AakmC3-m__Rw3Lg" hash="Z9LsgQ">How much house do we really need to accommodate our family comfortably? We should not endanger ourselves either spiritually or economically by acquiring homes which are ostentatious, feed our vanity, and go far beyond our needs.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p33" pid="HaUXcsaSM0a_9Q5kCmvGbw" hash="98vzAg">If we are to be self-reliant and in a position to share, obviously we must acquire some resources. If we live within our means and avoid debt, resources can be accumulated. There are those with average incomes who, over a lifetime, do amass some means, and there are those who receive large salaries who do not. What is the difference? It is simply spending less than they receive, saving along the way, and taking advantage of the power of compound interest.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p34" pid="15DydD1AH0euHp7rweXfhg" hash="uw8DBQ">Financial consultants indicate that “most people have it all wrong about wealth. … Wealth is not the same as income. If you make a good income each year and spend it all, you are not getting wealthier. You are just living high. Wealth is what you accumulate, not what you spend.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p35" pid="Th9_broNbEyttH739emSjA" hash="OCShLw">
        <span class="strong">Finally, be generous in giving and sharing with others.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p36" pid="KuHZD5xZukWq5D_RuoE-5Q" hash="OmrvJA">The more our hearts and minds are turned to assisting others less fortunate than we, the more we will avoid the spiritually cankering effects that result from greed, selfishness, and overindulgence. Our resources are a stewardship, not our possessions. I am confident that we will literally be called upon to make an accounting before God concerning how we have used them to bless lives and build the kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p37" pid="cpZQl7_KsEaD3SJn04Itkg" hash="5slj3g">The prophet Jacob provides us with some excellent counsel about how riches can be acquired and for what they should be used:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p38" pid="D30znAL4pk6tkdGnAXYb9Q" hash="lmOLVQ">“But before ye seek for riches, seek ye for the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p39" pid="q77Qrxt1QE6nizf41Iqi7g" hash="Gr0LGw">“And after ye have obtained a hope in Christ ye shall obtain riches, if ye seek them … for the intent to do good—to clothe the naked, and to feed the hungry, and to liberate the captive, and administer relief to the sick and the afflicted.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p40" pid="pSDFurGtPkCu58nAuoLxEQ" hash="bW2WKA">In addition to paying an honest tithing, we should be generous in assisting the poor. How much should we give? I appreciate the thought of C. S. Lewis on this subject. He said: “I am afraid the only safe rule is to give more than we can spare. … If our charities do not at all pinch or hamper us, … they are too small. There ought to be things we should like to do and cannot do because our charitable expenditure excludes them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p41" pid="lMeCFm9p7UibscqN_sQq9w" hash="QxWInA">There are many worthy individuals and causes to which we might contribute. We should give generously to the fast offering and humanitarian funds of the Church. And, if we desire our families to live lives of depth and meaning, we must have the courage to examine honestly where our treasures lie and avoid the pitfalls that result from greed, selfishness, and overindulgence.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.f2">
	<p pid="mKT8dJAEbkaj9t-EzK5LPQ" hash="preOUw">Let us each remember:</p>
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="Cgm5JWRd-0C7ml799vz38g" hash="NJ3E9A">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="A4JcT8MKwkm0d4ZbJEp9hA" hash="EsizBA">First: Not to confuse wants with needs.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="bGWhwbLADkGYPriqQX_V3g" hash="KdDstQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="iVs7j8BzDEGWM-UNSKVelA" hash="kuqi_Q">Second: Avoid spoiling our children.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Qv9pJLTCDUiC2MopKovnOg" hash="0uUk1g">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="gNE9bzVLnkOEniQ7LJ2Evg" hash="ACDjvA">Third: Live modestly and avoid debt.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="ZN-eCJ76_Ua381Ifxl0PQQ" hash="jdr6GQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="JoCDHc85xEWukhCVtPFULQ" hash="SSqoVw">Fourth: Be generous in giving to others.</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p42" pid="8zdkXSrvNUyRSkd7wEyYnw" hash="sRVAcQ">Giving really is at the heart of our faith. At this Easter time, we again commemorate that “God [our Heavenly Father] so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> who came to the earth and could have possessed any material thing but rather chose to give to all of us an example of a simple life free from any shade of greed, selfishness, or overindulgence. May we strive daily to live more like He lived, the ultimate example of a life of depth and meaning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence.p43" pid="YLg2WeCOKkCcoMMmlxU01g" hash="Nctm2A">I testify that Jesus is the Christ, this is His Church led by living prophets, and His tomb was literally empty on that third day. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1999/04/greed-selfishness-and-overindulgence</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1999-general-conference/1999-04-1030-elder-joe-j-christensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="6786075" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1999 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
