<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By John H. Groberg</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by John H. Groberg.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/John%20H.%20Groberg.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by John H. Groberg.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1976 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1976 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>On Accepting the Call</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/04/on-accepting-the-call?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brethren, on occasions such as this there is much to be felt, but little to be said. I feel it important that I say four things.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/on-accepting-the-call" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03070_000_020" doc-version="2" hash="Zzuarg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/on-accepting-the-call.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="TuVrTuyoOUyRi1TldslYpA" hash="kcey5w">On Accepting the Call</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="2YgMZYUVR0KvGslkCbzoQw" hash="kdP_xA">John H. Groberg</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/on-accepting-the-call.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2e6e.jpg" alt="Elder John H. Groberg" pid="j0b7yRGOt0WKn__jcKrfGQ" hash="h8GEfw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/on-accepting-the-call.p1" pid="qb-dF2sT_Eacgt43EfViDA" hash="3tinlQ">My dear brethren, on occasions such as this there is much to be felt, but little to be said. I feel it important that I say four things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/on-accepting-the-call.p2" pid="ZUKViZRu4EqvvNFn1hQhHA" hash="Cp0nSQ">First of all, publicly and in the presence of the Lord and his servants, I wish to accept the invitation that President Kimball has extended to spend the rest of my life in the service of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/on-accepting-the-call.p3" pid="QCtfA4Wj5UGf_BwuZmV-VQ" hash="WTRrNQ">Secondly, I want to ask for your help. I recognize that am weak and I need your help. As I have done some deep soul-searching over the last few days, I have come to the inescapable conclusion that many, if not most, of my so-called “accomplishments” have been much more the result of the efforts of others than they have of my own efforts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/on-accepting-the-call.p4" pid="FDFbv-1xrEK8IddYZSP-ww" hash="uIaiIw">We often hear of the need of our departed dead for us to go to the temple and do temple work for them, that is, we think of their dependence upon us. While I don’t have a complete understanding of these things, I want to bear my testimony that I am sure we have at least as great a dependence upon them, if not more so, than they do upon us. We need to help one another. Our salvation depends upon it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/on-accepting-the-call.p5" pid="PW6OQd78X0q9ZoQohV05rw" hash="mzBelA">Thirdly, I would like to express my appreciation for all those who have been so kind and patient with me, to the leaders of the Church who I know have gritted their teeth at times and watched the errors I have made and yet have patiently led me and directed me. I hope and pray that I may be at least as kind and as patient with others, in whatever responsibility I am given, as they have been with me. I express appreciation to my wife and children, my parents, friends, and neighbors—no one could have finer neighbors than we do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/on-accepting-the-call.p6" pid="pgtzv5fQK0CfgwUneZYEMA" hash="lZvXxA">It was mentioned that we should listen to our wives. They have qualities that we don’t have. In many cases womanly intuition should be listened to. When we were preparing to come down, my wife said, “Now, were we supposed to get anything in to the paper?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/on-accepting-the-call.p7" pid="Wvz61IQt8kaYPZxjzxbfbA" hash="lSoecQ">I said, “No, they said they have all the information they need.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/on-accepting-the-call.p8" pid="RW0I1DWtzkuCM8iFedkTyw" hash="yBg5CA">She said, “I’ll bet they get it wrong.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/on-accepting-the-call.p9" pid="qWRtKKYY2kWPZkHFNrd2Zw" hash="oZyRnw">Sure enough, when we opened up the <span class="emphasis">Church News,</span> they had shorted us two children. For your information, we have a little Jennie Marie and a Viki Ann who came after Thomas, who was mentioned in the paper. I told Jean that I would set the record straight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/on-accepting-the-call.p10" pid="c6cfaeja4Ey59vXUUjlpNA" hash="ph0RQQ">But I can’t say in words my appreciation for my wife and my children. Maybe just this: that I love her—I always have, and I always will and our children also.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/on-accepting-the-call.p11" pid="v0TJ6wjpuEykEM63131B8Q" hash="lZikaw">Lastly, I would like to bear my testimony that I know that our Father in heaven lives, and, maybe more importantly, I know that he loves us as his children. I know that Jesus is the Savior of the world. I know that he loves us. He is our friend, with all that that implies. He loves everyone. My particular experience has been more with the people of the islands. I would just like to say to the quiet, sweet-spirited people of the islands, my particular <span class="emphasis">Ofa Atu</span> (heartfelt love). You have softened my soul, saved my life, showed me the meaning of sacrifice and love, and given the incomparable blessing of faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/on-accepting-the-call.p12" pid="4gkJU4WAkkWUQ_bDZki5pg" hash="BpFiLw">I know that Joseph Smith is a prophet of God, that President Kimball is a prophet of God. I bear this testimony in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/04/on-accepting-the-call</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1976-general-conference/1976-04-3050-elder-john-h-groberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="4703280" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1976 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“There Is the Light”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters—and significantly that includes everyone—I ask for your faith and prayers, that that which is said and heard may be both said and heard under the influence of the Spirit of God, for I have long since learned that only as </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03076_000_020" doc-version="3" hash="iC99kQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="q6wuWNre9Eah03PLzTRGfQ" hash="DDo3JQ">“There Is the Light”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="2qJKxNAIAkqc5Kq7uisXOw" hash="kdP_xA">John H. Groberg</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2e6e.jpg" alt="Elder John H. Groberg" pid="S9wCv3GdCkWRZkAJs9hgDQ" hash="h8GEfw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p1" pid="s9Cos3zkWk6sybXLmBCuwA" hash="ItISsw">My dear brothers and sisters—and significantly that includes everyone—I ask for your faith and prayers, that that which is said and heard may be both said and heard under the influence of the Spirit of God, for I have long since learned that only as the Spirit conveys meaning does permanent good take place.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p2" pid="WOKd1HSZEUucc9O_dOE7XQ" hash="FJao_w">I would like to relate an experience and make an application for our day; for even though this event happened nearly twenty years ago to a small group in the South Pacific, the lesson learned there has become increasingly meaningful with the passage of time and is extremely important today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p3" pid="10meMyoeDkO6LjTHlwkowg" hash="aXNerA">I will speak in the first person for I would like to have you relive with me as much as possible this experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p4" pid="VbeQcXMNF0Kkv2LpEI_vfw" hash="ixWUPw">As a young missionary I was assigned as a district president to administer the affairs of the Church and preach the gospel in a group of fifteen small, scattered islands. We traveled almost exclusively by sailboat and learned to rely not only on the winds and the currents of the usually friendly seas, but especially on the love of our Father in heaven, as we sailed week after week and month after month from island to island to island. It was a glorious time, full of the normal challenges of seasickness, becalmings, strange languages, foods, and customs. But mostly it was a time of spiritual closeness to our Father in heaven, whose love and goodness so far overshadowed any temporary pain or problems as to make the latter shrink into obscurity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p5" pid="HFTKcOflbUmuFV_4LkNS5g" hash="b0DBeQ">On one occasion we received word that a missionary was very ill on a somewhat distant island. The weather was threatening but, feeling responsible, and after prayer, we left to investigate the situation. Extra heavy seas slowed our progress, and it was late afternoon before we arrived. The missionary was indeed very ill. Fervent prayer was followed by administration, during which the impression came very strongly to get him back to the hospital on the main island, and to do it now!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p6" pid="jVLYS3vkz0m3Jm1Rj-fQSA" hash="fWufBA">The weather had deteriorated to the point of a small gale. The seas were heavy, the clouds were thick, the wind was fierce, the hour was late, and the sun was sinking rapidly, betokening a long black night ahead. But the impression was strong—“Get back now”—and one learns to obey the all-important promptings of the Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p7" pid="7ztqp1FuVUafWd8Xu3XWCQ" hash="FmM5nA">There was much concern expressed and much talk about the darkness, the storm, and the formidable reef with its extremely narrow opening to the harbor we were attempting to gain. Some found reason to stay behind; but soon eight persons, including an ill missionary, a very experienced captain, and a somewhat concerned district president, boarded the boat and the spiritually prompted voyage to home base began.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p8" pid="9uUNz_q_akibPV8iYXAObg" hash="ZpnT2w">No sooner had we made our commitment to the open seas than the intensity of the storm seemed to increase sevenfold. The small gale now became a major storm. As the sun sank below the horizon, bringing with it darkness and gloom, so also did my spirit seem to sink into the darkness of doubt and apprehension. The thick clouds and driving rain increased the blackness of our already dark universe—no stars, no moon, no rest—only turmoil of sea and body and mind and spirit. And as we toiled on through that fearsome night, I found my spirit communing with the spirit of the father of an afflicted child in the New Testament, as he exclaimed, “Lord, I believe; help thou mine unbelief.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/9.24" class="scriptureRef">Mark 9:24</a>.) And He did, and He does, and He will. That I know.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p9" pid="R0KswpzUUUiwWPrfiAys7A" hash="E7py-w">As we rolled and tossed closer and closer to the reef, all eyes searched for the light that marked the opening—the only entry to our home. Where was it? The blackness of the night seemed to increase; the fierceness of the raging elements seemed to know no bounds. The rain slashed at our faces and tore at our eyes—eyes vainly searching for that life-giving light.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p10" pid="vObdtpWrKEm-eukIdJrrtA" hash="0l3a9A">Then I heard the chilling sound of the waves crashing and chewing against the reef! It was close—too close. Where was that light? Unless we hit the opening exactly, we would be smashed against the reef and ripped and torn by that thousand-toothed monster. It seemed that all the elements were savagely bent on our total destruction. Our eyes strained against the blackness, but we could not see the light.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p11" pid="jMOqKI48OUW1oyQtIft0JA" hash="QEmbYw">Some began to whimper, others to moan and cry, and one or two even to scream in hysteria. At the height of this panic, when many were pleading to turn to the left or to the right, when the tumultuous elements all but forced us to abandon life and hope, I looked at the captain—and there I saw the face of calmness, the ageless face of wisdom and experience, as his eyes penetrated the darkness ahead. Quietly his weather-roughened lips parted, and without moving his fixed gaze and just perceptibly shifting the wheel, he breathed those life-giving words, <span class="emphasis">“Ko e Maama e”</span> (“There is the light!”).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p12" pid="xM8tetanD0CnMC6WrnAj1A" hash="vAKW-g">I could not see the light, but the captain could see it. And I knew he could see it. Those eyes long experienced in ocean travel were not fooled by the madness of the storm nor were they influenced by the pleadings of those of lesser experience to turn to the left or to the right. And so with one last great swell we were hurtled through the opening and into calmer waters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p13" pid="ozUzmjkEpUebvrGwYEjn3g" hash="kmebOw">The roaring of the reef was now behind us. Its infamous plan of destruction had been foiled. We were in the protected harbor. We were home. Then and only then did we see through the darkness that one small light—exactly where the captain had said it was. Had we waited until we ourselves could see the light we would have been dashed to pieces, shredded on the reef of unbelief. But trusting in those experienced eyes, we lived.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p14" pid="FuKQij3jRESezA9OgKZGEQ" hash="zjh5nQ">And so the great lesson: There are those who, through years of experience and training, and by virtue of special divine callings, can see farther and better and more clearly—and can and will save us in those situations where serious injury or death—both spiritual and physical—would be upon us before we ourselves could see.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p15" pid="6PxPE0A1AUOpAl5Dzr_-7Q" hash="Yp4eHw">I sense in the world today an almost exact duplication of that voyage of nearly twenty years ago. We are in the midst of a major storm over moral values that will get worse before we arrive home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p16" pid="TNWq-yJnWUOguPP_QeEk6Q" hash="g1Vhvg">As just one example: We hear much of the so-called problem of overpopulation, of the possible future horrors it could bring. We hear claim and counterclaim, fancied fact and interpolated figures; we hear the call for so-called “planned families,” for “delayed families,” for “free” abortions, for personal aggrandizement in many ways. Now it is true that we have a sick world on our hands that needs help—but in delivering that patient to help we must not listen to the calculated plan of this or that professor, or to the pleading of some group, or to the hysterical screaming of some faction, or to any combination of manmade philosophies, but only to the calm voice of the prophet as he says, “Have your families in a normal way; accept all the spirits the Lord sees fit to send you; do not delay your families; always be considerate of one another; have nothing to do with the sin of abortion.” Therein is safety. He will guide us through this or any storm.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p17" pid="XJ2N-CLcfEaoVUJXV-K-MA" hash="AjLEyQ">As I think back, I thank the Lord for that wonderful Polynesian captain who saved my life and the life of the sick missionary I was charged with. I am eternally grateful for his experience (much of which, I am sure, was not pleasant). I am grateful for his wisdom, for his eyes, for his not yielding to the fury of the moment, but steadfastly holding the true course to safety.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p18" pid="W_cx_sYJH0GR_WROytTMiw" hash="FuZycw">I felt at the time that he was more than himself—he was more than the sum total of all of his experience. In some marvelous way at that moment of desperate need, he drew upon a power and a strength from generations of faithful, seagoing people that only those who know Polynesians well can begin to understand. My admiration and love for him and all other faithful descendants of father Lehi knows no bounds.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p19" pid="TUeXTy-ld0-kOIK9pr8zWg" hash="e9WKCA">In like manner, and with even deeper meaning, I thank the Lord for our great prophet-leader of today. In our moment of great need the Lord has provided one tested and molded and trained and instructed and clothed with divine authority, who in addition to the total of all his experience, which is great, draws upon the strength and power of not only generations of faithful leaders but also of angels and of gods.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p20" pid="hlvxOQbzVE6De5mvhpxIEA" hash="QQQbGg">I bear testimony that I know that God lives. I know that our Father in heaven loves us. I know that Jesus is the Christ, the Savior of the world. I know that He is our personal Savior, that He is our Friend—and I know He is our Helper: He will help us each personally and individually as we merit that help.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light.p21" pid="FiJz26nCuUuwQAL2cWbnhg" hash="LF0_DA">I know that Joseph Smith is a prophet of God. I testify that in our day Spencer W. Kimball is the man whose eyes see the light that can and will save us and the world. When all about us are sinking in darkness and fear and despair, when destruction seems close and the raging fury of men and demons ensnares us in seemingly insoluble problems, listen as he calmly says, “There is the light. This is the way.” I testify that he will so guide us safely home if we will but listen and obey. In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/10/there-is-the-light</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1976-general-conference/1976-10-3040-elder-john-h-groberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="5687743" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 1976 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Come Home, Felila”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, I ask for your faith and prayers that the Lord’s Spirit might touch our hearts as together we consider an item vital to our happiness here and hereafter.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03102_000_030" doc-version="2" hash="lzp0Fg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="5NfG4N6j9USaGkMDZf_Huw" hash="AkdlYA">“Come Home, Felila”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="_v5iqbMeB0SviPGAb6AF8w" hash="kdP_xA">John H. Groberg</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2e6e.jpg" alt="Elder John H. Groberg" pid="dHky1QkDcUOYehZEASuz4A" hash="h8GEfw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p1" pid="Ut1Jb-YsNU6XFfKa3ENTSQ" hash="5wVjNg">My dear brothers and sisters, I ask for your faith and prayers that the Lord’s Spirit might touch our hearts as together we consider an item vital to our happiness here and hereafter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p2" pid="aOVoln8UGk2MmLCAvXbNiQ" hash="ZGFNYQ">One of the greatest needs of mankind generally and of all of us individually is to have more and stronger faith in our Creator. To know that he is literally our Father and that he is kind and just and understands us and knows our needs is one of the greatest treasures we can possess. This treasure is obtained by faith—strong faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p3" pid="PcNYUkhl60e3IOh4ZVviKA" hash="Qh7QFA">Now it may seem easy to have faith in God when things are going well. But the law of growth requires constant effort and stretching. Thus, in order to have our faith strengthened, it must be stretched and tried and tested.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p4" pid="lQQb66Fw_EaxonBG6RgRTw" hash="585WKA">One of the areas of testing that comes to many of us is when something occurs over which we apparently have little or no control and which to us seems unfair.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p5" pid="K2MKMrcaTESyVL8SzdQNwQ" hash="tNZzfQ">For example, I have always been moved as I have seen those who are required to operate on less than their full faculties. I, along with some of you, have asked the question, Why? On many occasions when an accident has occurred, or a terrible illness, or an untimely death, or when a mentally retarded or physically handicapped child has been born, or some other seemingly difficult-to-explain situation has taken place, people have come to me and to others wanting reassurance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p6" pid="a1ITYnWCf0O6DXKOWMJ2qw" hash="MsSAgA">I, along with you, have taken great consolation in the scriptures as they tell us that not even a sparrow falls to the ground without our Father knowing. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/10.29" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 10:29</a>.) We believe the scriptures, but when it happens to <span class="emphasis">our</span> loved one or <span class="emphasis">our</span> friend, the question of why still rings. I do not have all the answers, but hopefully the following experience, which happened several years ago, may be helpful to some who are still battling the question of why.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p7" pid="_7B4nljuA0OkUGojC0DeNA" hash="hvUxmg">On a small Pacific island an infant girl was born to a faithful family. They called her Felila. There was happiness and joy as this grateful spirit made her debut into mortal life, but soon there were problems. Her head was abnormally large. The doctors diagnosed it as hydrocephalus. The questions of brain damage, of normalcy, of other problems all raised their haunting heads. After much fasting and prayer the elders quorum president approached the branch president, who in turn talked with the district president, who after adequate checking came to me as the mission president to see if there were some additional help available.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p8" pid="CSVS4CMNfUqxyR8hp_dhhA" hash="_tNmyw">The medical authorities were consulted, and it was determined that there was little if anything they could do locally. Letters were written, information was sent back and forth, x-rays were taken and analyzed. There was so much to do—so many questions to be answered, so many pieces to fit together. Finally after exasperatingly long delays, things began to fall into place. A family in Salt Lake agreed to accept full responsibility for the infant, even if it meant years of outpatient care; the doctors agreed on the possibility of her eventual recovery; the hospital accepted the case on a service basis; funds were raised for her air fare; some local travelers arranged their schedules to bring her right to the hospital. But there were other problems—visas, health certificates, reservations, passports.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p9" pid="dIlm-Dh2IUeIYTxP8kqvWQ" hash="LcrObA">All during these trying days the family, and the elders quorum, and even the whole branch continued to fast and pray. The time of departure of the infrequent airplane grew near.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p10" pid="uu-K_8MzK0KzizY2a5uVKA" hash="lVYu-w">One morning, amidst myriads of other pressing matters, I had the strong impression that I must take the time <span class="emphasis">now</span> and put forth the extra effort required to get everything done so she could go. I got on the overseas telephone. The consulate finally agreed to issue a visa; the airlines made a special reservation; the passport people agreed to waive the normal regulations; others gave that extra effort and cooperation; and soon all was in order.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p11" pid="tdyl6dRx00eutd22qyFy6w" hash="ntmu6Q">Normally I would have sent someone to bring the family in to sign the final papers, but again I felt strongly impressed that I should personally go and see the branch president. I located him in the early afternoon near the school where he was teaching. He was standing alone outside as though he were waiting for me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p12" pid="YN5MW64kc021XqEymySIcg" hash="48U7yQ">Excitedly I ran up to him: “Guess what? It’s all set. Miraculously everything has worked out and Felila can leave tomorrow. Please get word to the family immediately.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p13" pid="gOCAH68bckiXdacqsat_ZQ" hash="XYaf4Q">His calm, penetrating gaze quelled my exuberance. “It’s true,” I said. “I know it’s been long and there have been lots of disappointments, but she really is going now. What’s the matter?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p14" pid="3zUU6rfNZkaxp0b4AzVWNQ" hash="nelFbA">His steady gaze seemed to penetrate my very soul. Then softly in his liquid native tongue he informed me that when all the preparations had been made, when the hearts of so many had been stretched in service, when the goal of unity and selflessness had been achieved in those many hearts, when all had made the final commitment of others above self, at the height of all this activity that very morning, little Felila had quietly and unobtrusively slipped away—gone to that better care which so many had fasted and prayed and worked so long and hard for her to receive.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p15" pid="RbK01NFuJUa85HwaOXnx7Q" hash="SAgeFg">Gone? This morning? But all that work, all that time, all that fasting and praying and those strong feelings. Gone? No!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p16" pid="GwAN_cS02USTWKFf_cyppg" hash="_HN3tQ">Without once shifting his gaze, he, having more faith than I, offered a few words of truth and encouragement, then quietly turned and rejoined his class.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p17" pid="ZPp1uw_C50-jW46HY5799g" hash="8PZDeg">And I was left alone, or so it seemed. I moved slowly and heavily down that dusty trail. Why? Why? After all that work and that strong faith of so many and those impressions, why?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p18" pid="oTaBM4XpnkGF7p-tnc6s1w" hash="AalXqQ">I sensed the brightness of the sun and felt the warmth of the breeze as it lazily tossed the palm leaves and slowly shifted the silent clouds against the clear blue sky. A feeling came over me. I realized that the earth was beautiful, that life went on and was eternal. And while I cannot describe fully what happened next, part of the experience is proper to relate. The best explanation is contained in the phrase, “I was overcome by the Spirit.” It was as though one took me by the hand and led me to a high place and stood by me and said, “Look.” And I looked and beheld such beauty and magnificence as man cannot conceive. And I heard a voice, such a tender, compassionate voice—yet so unmistakably powerful—that all nature stood still and listened and obeyed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p19" pid="1YwuzH9WCEWy30Qacd7P_g" hash="tbSQDg">“Come home, Felila, my daughter. Come home to the care your loved ones have sought for you. I have heard their prayers and have known their fasting and love for you, and I answer, Come home, my daughter. You have finished your mission in life. Hearts have been softened; souls have been stretched; faith has been increased. Come home now, Felila.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p20" pid="g9zZpM5wP0qkS-o4C4tEVA" hash="AeRlxQ">He knew her! He knew her name. He knew all about her and about all those others. How perfect our Father’s love! He had heard the prayers. He had done what was best. He knew everything—which thing, though I believed, I never had supposed. In some marvelous way, which is beyond our mortal comprehension, he knows and understands all things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p21" pid="bis47sFetE-5IK8Vmyhh-A" hash="TFSs6w">My questions as to why—as to justice and reasons—were all at that moment completely swept away. They were so irrelevant, my questioning so totally out of place, like one trying to dig the Grand Canyon with a teaspoon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p22" pid="unbe5nyTRU6ogXKwLxGqYQ" hash="91Cpgw">Oh, how we must remember the words of Jacob as he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p23" pid="0BAO__MpZ0yj16Z0eqd2Hw" hash="je-rFg">“Behold, great and marvelous are the works of the Lord. How unsearchable are the depths of the mysteries of him; and it is impossible that man should find out all his ways. And no man knoweth of his ways save it be revealed unto him; wherefore, brethren, despise not the revelations of God. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p24" pid="TnbTH-d4x0mKokY4fUhnFQ" hash="Mta05g">“Seek not to counsel the Lord, but to take counsel from his hand. For behold, ye yourselves know that he counseleth in wisdom, and in justice, and in great mercy, over all his works.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.8,10" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:8, 10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p25" pid="ngP94B_hzkWPtIWXD4XKJQ" hash="luFcKA">I testify that there is total and complete justice in eternity. God’s dealings with man have no tinge of partiality or of favoritism or of capriciousness or of anything less than complete consistency and balance and perfectness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p26" pid="J9PgcyLkuUGBCVcZlPJd5Q" hash="zmpQmw">Some say, “But it has been years. We have fasted and prayed so long and so hard. What does the Lord expect?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p27" pid="OFLHNLikbESqfR7oh-3ZQw" hash="uUJ1Uw">There may be many answers. I give only one. That is: He expects more, and it will be for your eternal benefit and blessing. That I know. As we begin to comprehend eternity, we gain a whole new catalog of values.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p28" pid="NsGW4jGAJkWqpLCv_0uY4g" hash="dv-D_Q">To you who have the responsibility and the privilege and the opportunity of caring for others, may you through those long hours and days and years ever know, as I know, that the Lord understands.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p29" pid="gdlhXC_RykOeUrWSB7RpnQ" hash="58ZqiQ">Do not be discouraged; do not attempt to counsel the Lord. He determines, not you. He knows hearts and souls and needs. He measures intents and knows spirits.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p30" pid="UYjcdpRUiUuL4QsSIh7CBA" hash="5hoOsg">Caring is all-important—the intensity, the duration, the amount, the quality, the extent. For in God’s wisdom, caring creates faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila.p31" pid="798uUieaCk2bTrr4KJFAOg" hash="xLhm2w">Oh, may we all have a little Felila in our lives—and there are so many: the retarded, the infirm, those needing special help, both spiritually and physically, the aged, the infants,—all these to soften our hearts in love, to stretch our souls in tenderness, to confirm our worth in caring for others, and above all to strengthen our faith in him who knows all, even him who in caring totally gave his all, and in giving his all, lives forever, and in living forever, rules eternally, and in ruling eternally, cares omnipotently, whose coming and going is one eternal round I pray in his name, even the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1978/10/come-home-felila</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1978-general-conference/1978-10-5020-elder-john-h-groberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="5348273" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 1978 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing Your Personal and Family History</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brethren, I ask that our faith be united so the Lord’s spirit may touch our hearts.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03122_000_022" doc-version="2" hash="VecnNA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="nJEeRmqc6EmpH0PqaaCo6g" hash="ZPPZ0w">Writing Your Personal and Family History</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="vnVuF8gUI0aHc96PY0KNyA" hash="kdP_xA">John H. Groberg</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2e6e.jpg" alt="Elder John H. Groberg" pid="dSF7GyfvwEy47K7aKWyuBQ" hash="h8GEfw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p1" pid="4PGVfuSfVUWXnU1mq3RgTA" hash="w2bY1w">My dear brethren, I ask that our faith be united so the Lord’s spirit may touch our hearts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p2" pid="Gh7ggcyUE02yaqCBktQ14g" hash="lKqxqQ">I would like to begin by asking a question. (Don’t raise your hand; just think about it.) How many of you, regardless of age, have your personal and family histories up to date?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p3" pid="vVWTrqEvpUegSWdqDgGAEg" hash="5LSc-g">As bearers of the priesthood, we have an obligation to follow the counsel of the prophet. President Kimball has made it abundantly clear that it is very important to write our personal and family histories. It is so important that this August the Church is sponsoring, in Salt Lake City, a great World Conference on Records to help all of us, and the whole world, better understand the vital importance of these histories and to learn much about how to write them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p4" pid="ZPLyKjCmYEC-J0gzCDM4KA" hash="WRwniw">Why is the writing of personal and family histories so important? There are many reasons. I will focus on just a few.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p5" pid="4J-Ip5_kCkSn2pwvoJngPg" hash="DQt4fQ">By writing personal and family histories and doing the research required thereby, we inevitably have our hearts turned to our fathers as well as to our children. The Lord says this must happen, “lest I come and smite the earth with a curse” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/4.6" class="scriptureRef">Mal. 4:6</a>). Let us not be part of a curse.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p6" pid="pcFR6wetrEO4ShkN_Sejqw" hash="XKEiuw">Also, by writing personal and family histories, we are helped immeasurably in gaining a true, eternal perspective of life. Writing our histories with the proper blend of fact and feeling (and so often, feelings in spiritual things are the real facts) gives us a deep spiritual insight into the meaning and purpose of our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p7" pid="BuSOaQnw406Xi9bxCvjIwQ" hash="22HmvA">I wonder if, as in so many things, we don’t deny ourselves this deeper spiritual insight by simply neglecting to write our histories.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p8" pid="0cM8uPrJKEay8odsRpOPBQ" hash="ISsmjg">Some people say, “I don’t have anything to record. Nothing spiritual happens to me.” I say, “Start recording, and spiritual things will happen. They are there all the time, but we become more sensitive to them as we write.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p9" pid="1f8GGNYxSUS21IvesaYSFw" hash="gMh5-A">Writing our histories will certainly help us keep our eyes on the most important of all goals—even the goal of eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p10" pid="0uVmDG3Zf0uNMJ5Ug9eGdg" hash="nFyJaQ">As we contemplate what those before us have gone through that we might be here, as we sense their faith and courage and feel their love for us and our love for them, we realize what is really important. We begin to comprehend the eternity of the family. We gain great insight into the things of God, and we are not the same. We talk and act differently—for we have a deepened understanding of eternity. We realize that so-called problems are only what we see when we take our eye off our eternal goal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p11" pid="NlVhSzg3eUuqbZONDNncjg" hash="YGL-sw">The priesthood we hold is the power to bless others. The priesthood is eternal; thus, the blessings of the priesthood are eternal. Every use of the priesthood has eternal significance—including the writing of personal and family histories.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p12" pid="qMyiXoD_IkC89ylGOdh0dA" hash="Y0BZag">We have all been thrilled and humbled by the announcement of the new temples. I wonder how many personal histories written in the last few days have recorded great moving expressions of gratitude to God for earnestly prayed-for and sincerely sacrificed-for temples? I wonder how many personal histories will yet record such great feelings of gratitude as the future unfolds?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p13" pid="dwoJ4rFDeEKQ98taUKPVJg" hash="DNSMpA">Writing histories should be a great motivation to do what is right. You young men, how many of your histories record, “I will serve a mission; I will live worthy to go to the temple; I know President Kimball is a prophet; I will follow his direction”?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p14" pid="cCPbXy1YlkKOebaibvY3ww" hash="J2keUQ">I ask that every bearer of the priesthood resolve to do what is necessary to write in his personal history.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p15" pid="fa-sL9MuDE6QJ5dcWRVW7g" hash="V5ECug">“Today I went to the temple and received my endowments”; or, “Today I went to the temple, where our family was sealed together”; or, “Today I went to the temple and did the work for my great grandfather (or other ancestors)”; or, “Today I went to the temple with my brother or friend or neighbor and witnessed their sealing.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p16" pid="M8j4SUPtCUOFFsuPj14WJA" hash="OifmCg">If you resolve to do it, you will do it. Do not let anything stand in your way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p17" pid="2886ygs6xUC1DFZo8FSBuw" hash="1DGlsg">There is something eternal in the very nature of writing, as is so graphically illustrated by the scriptures themselves. In a very real sense, our properly written histories are a very important part of our family scripture and become a great source of spiritual strength to us and to our posterity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p18" pid="COYWLI0Ko02El8FdbM4e6w" hash="iNRIsA">For example, let me give you a brief incident from a family history in Hawaii. It involves sacrifice and temple blessings and true eternal perspective.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p19" pid="26LoJCoAaEOyZqgdQyLvsA" hash="Wf3WVA">In the early 1900s, a young father and his family joined the Church in Hawaii. He was enthused about his new-found religion, and after two years of membership both he and his eldest son held the priesthood. They prospered and enjoyed the fellowship of the little branch. They anxiously looked forward to being sealed as a family for eternity in the temple soon to be completed in Laie.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p20" pid="iPs86PLf60SNziH41pAlog" hash="VKE_FQ">Then, as so often happens, a test crossed their path. One of their daughters became ill with an unknown disease and was taken away to a strange hospital. People in Hawaii were understandably wary of unknown diseases, as such diseases had wrought so much havoc there.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p21" pid="zIpdnboKSUmuNN_WmzOaOg" hash="66r9tw">The concerned family went to church the next Sunday, looking forward to the strength and understanding they would receive from their fellow members. It was a small branch. This young father and his son very often took the responsibility for blessing and passing the sacrament. This was one such Sunday. They reverently broke the bread while the congregation sang the sacrament hymn. When the hymn was finished, the young father began to kneel to offer the sacrament prayer. Suddenly the branch president, realizing who was at the sacred table, sprang to his feet. He pointed his finger and cried, “Stop. You can’t touch the sacrament. Your daughter has an unknown disease. Leave immediately while someone else fixes new sacrament bread. We can’t have you here. Go.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p22" pid="wavnbtul2ECea57rKvj7rQ" hash="n1qqRw">How would you react? What would you do?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p23" pid="8BZfPV1FWUOr7NKWcrL85A" hash="ECmlTQ">The stunned father slowly stood up. He searchingly looked at the branch president, then at the congregation. Then, sensing the depth of anxiety and embarrassment from all, he motioned to his family and they quietly filed out of the chapel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p24" pid="OUX0fxIVZUCAch3iu4Mqgw" hash="Blv_EA">Not a word was said as, with faces to the ground, they moved along the dusty trail to their small home. The young son noticed the firmness in his father’s clenched fists and the tenseness of his set jaw. When they entered their home they all sat in a circle, and the father said, “We will be silent until I am ready to speak.” All sorts of thoughts went through the mind of this young boy. He envisioned his father coming up with many novel ways of getting revenge. Would they kill the branch president’s pigs, or burn his house, or join another church? He could hardly wait to see what would happen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p25" pid="yOEHn861hEm5MipfJhBgEQ" hash="kRt6QQ">Five minutes, ten minutes, fifteen minutes—not a sound. He glanced at his father. His eyes were closed, his mouth was set, his fingers clenched, but no sound. Twenty minutes, twenty-five minutes—still nothing. Then he noticed a slight relaxing of his father’s hands, a small tremor on his father’s lips, then a barely perceptible sob. He looked at his father—tears were trickling down his cheeks from closed eyes. Soon he noticed his mother was crying also, then one child, then another, and soon the whole family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p26" pid="HVwqwEO230-4peuvdDrsLQ" hash="iZnT-Q">Finally, the father opened his eyes, cleared his throat, and announced, “I am now ready to speak. Listen carefully.” He slowly turned to his wife and said, meaningfully, “I love you.” Then turning to each child, he told them individually, “I love you. I love all of you and I want us to be together, forever, as a family. And the only way that can be is for all of us to be good members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and be sealed by his holy priesthood in the temple. This is not the branch president’s church. It is the Church of Jesus Christ. We will not let any man or any amount of hurt or embarrassment or pride keep us from being together forever. Next Sunday we will go back to church. We will stay by ourselves until our daughter’s sickness is known, but we will go back.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p27" pid="ZBvBa7mQDEy9qNedfQOl7g" hash="aFAwtQ">This great man had proper eternal perspective.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p28" pid="-1aepgaXDkefwmH92XbWzg" hash="7hA67Q">The daughter’s health problem was resolved; the family did go to the temple when it was completed. The children did remain faithful and were likewise sealed to their own families in the temple as time went on. Today over 100 souls in this family are active members of the Church and call their father, grandfather, and great-grandfather blessed because he kept his eyes on eternity, because he used his priesthood to bless his family, and because he recorded his feelings. How the heart of this father turned to his children, and how his children’s hearts turned to him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p29" pid="IBxzvK8NI0S6qOXc3wcxig" hash="qBJPig">All of you have similar incidents in your families. Search them out. Record them. Live by them, and pass them on to your posterity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p30" pid="lBcMDQ6CDkanEjMPBdzSnQ" hash="EnMePA">I have a strong feeling that when this life is over, our personal and family histories and the influence they wield will be of much greater importance than we now think.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history.p31" pid="dhYD7AmdykuCNfcZ9YrD1A" hash="XxQaAA">Brethren, this is the work of the Lord. I testify that he lives and that he has great influence in our lives. May we have this understanding of eternity and see and feel and record his influence in our lives, I do humbly pray, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1980/04/writing-your-personal-and-family-history</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1980-general-conference/1980-04-3070-elder-john-h-groberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="4408581" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 1980 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Family Prayer</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, I ask for your faith and prayers as we consider a vitally important key to our happiness and success in life. I speak this morning on the importance and power of family prayer.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03148_000_023" doc-version="2" hash="D9UaXA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ZxR8hh-vcEaeoEqpq1drpQ" hash="w3CTUQ">The Power of Family Prayer</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="LNAMHGfFMEaWGVyrHqU-ow" hash="kdP_xA">John H. Groberg</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-269c.jpg" alt="Elder John H. Groberg" pid="9lkjdAuk_UC1VFBajRCZkg" hash="FMNYUQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p1" pid="LTbiJnGBIkKBFb0j8kVZTQ" hash="YLs0wg">My dear brothers and sisters, I ask for your faith and prayers as we consider a vitally important key to our happiness and success in life. I speak this morning on the importance and power of family prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p2" pid="4p3Z-o3Qi0O6-zoX23BaWA" hash="PISjBw">Our Father in Heaven wants us to have strong, loving families. One of the great helps he has given us to achieve this is family prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p3" pid="oKmhN7CBhUi5CpDTGRwH_g" hash="Omf0fg">All of us, single or married, are eternally part of some family—someway, somewhere, somehow—and much of our joy in life comes as we correctly recognize and properly develop those family relationships. We come to this earth charged with a mission: to learn to love and serve one another. To best help us accomplish this, God has placed us in families, for he knows that is where we can best learn to overcome selfishness and pride and to sacrifice for others and to make happiness and helpfulness and humility and love the very essence of our character.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p4" pid="x_HUaO_0SECnuZpdIUjW5g" hash="thLhIg">We learn that friends and neighbors come and go but family is forever, and as we learn this, we find that we are eternally our brother’s keeper and we begin to realize how much help we need. How we should thank God for the opportunity of family prayer!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p5" pid="xdBvKqP92E-F4w1EAL3LPQ" hash="o6p-kQ">Listen to the admonition of the Savior in Third Nephi: “Pray in your families unto the Father, always in my name, that your wives and your children may be blessed.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.21" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p6" pid="OSk1np4Fr0-9t1Wv3f3m4A" hash="zCzD4A">Can you detect that if we do not pray in our families always they may not be blessed—or at least not so fully? If we truly love our families we will constantly pray for them and with them. I know of no single activity that has more potential for unifying our families and bringing more love and divine direction into our homes than consistent, fervent family prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p7" pid="4jnR6NpeakKRjEzsdNPfFA" hash="P_BzeA">Think of the power for good as you gather your family together and thank God for all of his blessings. Think of the eternal significance of daily thanking him for each member of your family and asking him to guide and bless and protect each one. Think of the strength that will come to your family as, daily, one member or another pours out his or her soul in love to God for other family members.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p8" pid="hVXtEb8y4kOA4tlqeh-e1A" hash="2v0y8A">Of course, our prayers must be more than words, for as President Marion G. Romney has so clearly stated, “The efficacy of our prayers depends on how we care for one another.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign, </span>Nov. 1980, p. 93.) Family prayer is fully effective, then, only as we rise from our knees and, with increased love and understanding, take better care of each other.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p9" pid="opeO4TQQPk6VnReufLKLRg" hash="dI6O9w">We all want more love and unity in our families. We all need more help with some who may be wayward or in special need. We all desire more assurance of divine guidance and direction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p10" pid="T64DNU_tG0aMp6m8UaoXuw" hash="Gh2YEA">I promise you that as you consistently and fervently pray as a family, and as each member takes his or her turn and sincerely prays for others, impressions will come as to what you individually should do to help others. Thus, you can, in family prayer, receive personal and family revelation as to how to love and serve one another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p11" pid="WcnkQz7kX0qlmjksq__rgQ" hash="cBPaBA">Now, Satan will do everything he can to keep us from family prayer, or at least to see that our prayers are only intermittent and mechanical and without sincerity. In Daniel’s day, Satan influenced evil men to pass laws against praying. In our day, Satan’s efforts seem a little more subtle (although he is trying a little of that law business, too).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p12" pid="viWLE4Z7Q0qUCf0brtPOGw" hash="NrNX9A">But remember, the greatest schools on earth are individual homes. Yet how many homes voluntarily give up family prayer by allowing other less important things to take priority.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p13" pid="5kFmLeZPBUyVtp0t8rsLFg" hash="susHow">If Satan can get us thinking that our children are too young or too old, or if he can get us angry with one another or preoccupied with TV programs or over-crowded schedules or caught up in some other aspect of the press of modern life so that we do not have family prayer, he has effectively won on that point—even though many of the other things we do may be good in and of themselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p14" pid="RN5ua1oX80OClNQmffTN6w" hash="FpG43A">Satan doesn’t care how he stops us—just so he stops us. Ask yourself: How many times did you have family prayer this last week? Who is winning in your home? What’s the score? Don’t let the evil one win. You can overcome him with God’s help.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p15" pid="zymKyX4Rf0iWB-EW6OJDJw" hash="BKW9VA">I appeal with all the fervor of my soul to every family in the Church, every family in the nation, every family in the world, to organize your priorities so that God is first in your lives and to show this by having regular family prayer. There may be extenuating circumstances occasionally; but as a rule, we should have family prayer every morning and every evening.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p16" pid="i7b5temfWkWA_htBQS0itQ" hash="8gOR-A">Oh, if we would do this, if we would show our families and our God on a regular basis how much we love them, how much we appreciate them, how much we need their help, and how much we rely on His protection, one of the greatest changes for good to ever take place in the Church, in the nation, and in the world would occur. Don’t let anything stand in the way of consistent, fervent family prayer! Think of what you teach by having family prayer. Then think of what you teach by not having family prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p17" pid="_Zoj0cI1v0KR_9hyyFg4ig" hash="SZFY_Q">I testify to you that there is real power in family prayer. I testify that families can be brought together and can help and strengthen one another through family prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p18" pid="8yL7lDGArUCPXuDr4_MzCg" hash="_TjkGA">Let me illustrate this with an incident that happened some years ago. As a young man I was called on a mission to Tonga. Through a series of unusual circumstances, such as ship strikes, and so forth, it took three months to get to Tonga from Salt Lake. As I was the only one assigned to Tonga at that time, much of the journey was made alone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p19" pid="_c89gY1Q3kuhCZgttRI5Lg" hash="IGtlzg">Finally, in Samoa, the mission president put me on a boat to Fiji and assured me that he would telegraph ahead, and when I arrived in Suva two elders would meet me and put me on a boat to Tonga.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p20" pid="JtA1rE7T7EqbiYBz4hSsbg" hash="naAg0g">Even though I had been in transit for two and a half months at that time, that several-day voyage to Suva seemed extra-filled with trepidation. How I looked forward to seeing those two missionaries!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p21" pid="ty9smj7Xi0Kv89uv6VcH6A" hash="67Fjzg">The boat arrived in Suva early in the morning. I looked and looked, but could see no elders. An hour went by, then two, then three—still no elders. The captain kept telling me to get off the boat as they were leaving soon. I kept telling him that I would be met soon by two young men, but they didn’t come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p22" pid="_Afo4beJukiX4JwcwIENdg" hash="DLgMnA">Finally, noon arrived and the captain was ready to leave. “Get off,” he said, “you only have a ticket to Suva. I’m leaving, and you’re staying here.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p23" pid="YuM3TXeMdUa0SBNv4EInLw" hash="0OTF_g">With great fear I started down the gangplank only to be met by the immigration officials. “Let us see your visa, your onward ticket, and the money to keep you while here,” they demanded.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p24" pid="MpFG5TFGpkq8zCRRhF7MJg" hash="TTQntg">I had no visa. I had no onward ticket. I had not sufficient money. But I assured them that two young men would be there right away with whatever was needed. How I prayed! But they didn’t come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p25" pid="CM56EF27ok6RxRC-0y2QsQ" hash="nWQ4Ag">“Back on the ship then,” they insisted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p26" pid="yQbC4zyjUUaLWSxtzofuNw" hash="HCiKdQ">“Not on my ship,” bellowed the captain.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p27" pid="DOiHW-kRnESiqw97jhVYpA" hash="keHqpQ">I can remember standing in the middle of the gangplank, looking up at the folded arms and glaring eyes of the stern captain, and then looking down at the equally determined faces and set jaws of the immigration men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p28" pid="we3U5XgpWUGXTo2EgBzkLw" hash="q3UGUA">I looked at the ocean under the gangplank. I should have wondered how long I could tread water, but I was too scared to think of anything right then.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p29" pid="e3keyOBKOEKycmy_3_fwvw" hash="C29LWQ">In the end, the captain proved to be the toughest; and amidst cursing and yelling and banging of bags, the gangplank went up, the ship departed, and I found myself in the not-too-friendly hands of the immigration officials.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p30" pid="RB_1TXEvfUaneX0i34bb3g" hash="iv7pzw">There was a long discussion among them, most of it in a foreign tongue. Finally, one of the younger men, who seemed more friendly, came over and explained that for now I should move with my things into the “customs shed.” That’s where things go that aren’t really allowed into the country until duty or tax is paid on them. He assured me that he, too, felt that the two young men I referred to would soon be along and everything would be fine.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p31" pid="bwc37xXs70eDVQ1Tue2wFQ" hash="80YdkA">The afternoon wore on. I tried several times to contact the missionaries every way I knew how, but to no avail. I know missionaries are supposed to be brave, but right then I was scared and tired and hungry.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p32" pid="pTIQ4x3R80-3hgC_krD5EA" hash="2CE0Og">The sun was getting low, and it seemed the lower it got in the sky the lower my spirits became. I knew I wasn’t really in danger or in prison, but to one used to lots of freedom it seemed like it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p33" pid="ANfGHPgYXUGTASh8jaqsiw" hash="nPQBOg">The pungent odor of curry and copra and drying fish and the myriad other sights and sounds and smells of an oily tropical wharf seemed so foreign to the cool, fresh smells of my Idaho home. I knew I was homesick. I wanted to cry, but I knew that wouldn’t do any good.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p34" pid="3BF_I5MkWEaAv-RyNjGi8Q" hash="1tBHIg">Finally, the whirring of winches, the groaning of blocks and cables, the banging of cargo, and the sputtering of machines ceased. The dock workers began to leave, then the immigration people, until just a few watchmen and supervisors were left. It was silent now. I don’t know when I have felt more alone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p35" pid="THPlKFN0rUqd1p_z2Es3QQ" hash="irCkhQ">I tried to lie down on the dirty, uneven cement floor. I prayed to know what to do. There seemed to be no answer. I watched the last rays of sunlight as they broke through the clouds and blazed across the ocean and through the holes of the metal customs shed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p36" pid="Mal2ddN_AUacXpn0qEySQw" hash="7K8WnQ">“How long will the light last?” I thought. Then I wondered, “What will happen when those last rays disappear and fold into the night?” (Have you ever wanted to just sort of close your eyes and disappear—or have things around you change?) “But, no, I must have hope. Things <span class="emphasis">must</span> turn out all right.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p37" pid="lJVfhCJvC0WSdPCVZtxeBg" hash="h3VZsQ">Once more, I closed my eyes in prayer, when suddenly I felt almost transported. I didn’t see anything or hear anything, in a physical sense; but, in a more real way, I saw a family in far-off Idaho kneeling together in prayer; and I heard my mother, acting as mouth, say as clearly as anything can be heard, “And bless John on his mission.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p38" pid="vAS6Aakrvk61EwVqp8tZIA" hash="FMxLyg">As that faithful family called down the powers of heaven to bless their missionary son in a way they could not physically do, I testify that the powers of heaven did come down, and they lifted me up and, in a spiritual way, allowed me, for a brief moment, to once again join that family circle in prayer. I was one with them. I was literally swallowed up in the love and concern of a faithful family and sensed for a moment what being taken into Abraham’s bosom may be like. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/16.22" class="scriptureRef">Luke 16:22</a>.) I was given to understand also that there are other circles of love and concern unbounded by time or space to which we all belong and from which we can draw strength. God does not leave us entirely alone—ever!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p39" pid="ki2NKnO-rE200fb4POebcQ" hash="6e78sQ">Tears of joy flowed freely as I had restored to me the warmth of security, the light of love, and the strength of hope. And when I again felt the hard, uneven cement beneath me, there was no fear, no sorrow, no trepidation, only deep gratitude and certain assurance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p40" pid="s3jITqCYx0O5LCKDHkv_yg" hash="bK7qzA">To conclude the incident, within a half hour I saw the young immigration man who had befriended me coming towards the shed with two young elders behind him. It seemed that on his way home he just happened to run into two young Americans with white shirts and ties and told them about one just like them down at the wharf. Apparently the telegram never arrived, but they followed him down to the shed, and soon all was straightened out, and within a few weeks I landed in Tonga and was ready to begin my mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p41" pid="DcyHCaIxyU2i8T7WO2CSXA" hash="81EQjA">Brothers and sisters, I testify that there is great power in loving, consistent, fervent family prayer. Don’t deny your families this blessing. Don’t allow the strength that comes from family prayer to slip away from you and your loved ones through neglect.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p42" pid="XAF3qRiyOky3Iu7p5nIOPA" hash="0rNTOg">No matter what other inheritance you leave your family, give them the inheritance of knowing through experience that, forever, you will be praying for them and they for you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p43" pid="wvLXv2_-DUajdtpPXdZ-6A" hash="9ib6Sw">Call your families together. Make your family prayers a top priority item. It may be awkward at first, if you aren’t doing it now; and since Satan doesn’t want you to do it at all, he will throw all sorts of excuses and roadblocks at you; but just proceed and be persistent, and I promise you great blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p44" pid="1HIxxb2xF0C477L-iPMmyw" hash="W_0Vrw">Remember, all that we are commanded to do in this life is patterned after that of a better life. Do you think it a strange thought that maybe part of the power of family prayer is in the fact that we are part of a heavenly family, that they are interested in us, and that by tying in with them some way we get hold of something much bigger than ourselves?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p45" pid="v8AVt-pw20OjylVwJjdyig" hash="EAa5RQ">Think of the power of the thousands of prayers of parents and grandparents and back and back even to Jacob and Isaac and Abraham and beyond, all requesting essentially the same thing: “Bless my children. Bless my children. Bless my children.” Can you hear it as it rolls and echoes throughout all eternity?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p46" pid="AEg4bSYkUkSwjTM3M6rEmg" hash="bj8F3g">Let us all be part of that great power for good.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p47" pid="GSkzXxBmakmvc40RGOZxFg" hash="YgUTxA">I testify that time and space are no barriers to these righteous influences, and no matter where we are or what our situation is—even in the depths of discouragement, far from our loved ones—we too can feel and be strengthened by those soul-stirring words, “and bless John or Jane or whomever on his or her mission,” for indeed life is a mission. We are all here on assignment to learn to love and serve one another; and we can’t do this as well as we should unless we have consistent, fervent family prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p48" pid="txcJiZJwUEaEIem-0_8t6w" hash="1VHa2Q">I testify that God is our Father, that he lives and loves us, that he is the giver of all good things. I testify that Jesus lives and loves us, that he is the Son of God, the Christ, the Savior of the world, the head of this, his church. I testify that as we pray to the Father, in his name, all things are possible.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer.p49" pid="B3OVQr0DjUSpMJhK4XNVIg" hash="QTU3sw">May we all gather our families around us and consistently and fervently pray for one another and thus, in righteousness, feel the needs of others and then fill the needs of others, thereby fulfilling much of our mission in life, I do humbly pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1982/04/the-power-of-family-prayer</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1982-general-conference/1982-04-4030-elder-john-h-groberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="7264757" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1982 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Keeping the Sabbath Day Holy</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy?lang=eng</link>
      <description>How I pray for the Spirit of the Lord to continue to be with all of us, as it has been thus far.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03180_000_031" doc-version="2" hash="VLbzfA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="OZYq6lWMKUKF3jhtyaWIoA" hash="_xGbHA">The Power of Keeping the Sabbath Day Holy</h1><p class="authorName" guid="12197d92-51b8-4b0d-b0e4-dd0d4144d744" pid="1q4HHQ3bJUabUlhjJD13Gg" hash="kdP_xA">John H. Groberg</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="b8ebc6fd-774b-4b05-a06b-4588e089bc4f">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-269c.jpg" alt="Elder John H. Groberg" guid="0ef34a76-7802-4e6f-9f49-23f254a187c8" pid="Q2aN5lf2iUybBQ_3-Q6ssA" hash="FMNYUQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="JHAlY79mxEqyefGKSIpMqw" hash="QyEiAQ">How I pray for the Spirit of the Lord to continue to be with all of us, as it has been thus far.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="Ox-EmZVqg0ij87nl12U_Ng" hash="Aw2BNg">The injunction from God to “Remember the sabbath day, to keep it holy” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.8" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:8</a>) has been in force throughout human history. There is power in keeping the Sabbath day holy. I testify that God lives, that we are his children, that he loves us, and that he gives us commandments so he can bless us as we keep them and thereby have joy. As we keep the Sabbath day holy he will bless us, and we will achieve a quiet power for good as individuals, as families, and as nations, that we cannot obtain in any other way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="QneUvKSq90ejIEiX22McrA" hash="hzbFrQ">Let me give two examples:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="QY3vksnoe0q9fGYTx_Q32w" hash="tRbSng">The small island kingdom of Tonga lies immediately next to the international dateline, so it is the first country in the world to greet the Sabbath day. It is a small country and, in the counting of the world, a poor country. But years ago a wise Tongan king decreed that the Sabbath would be kept holy in Tonga forever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="HRmQ9sh6-kCsMJgp-pjndw" hash="MQwi2w">Modern civilization has come in many ways to Tonga. If one goes to the capital of Nuku’alofa on a weekday, he finds the usual heavy traffic of trucks and cars and the bustle of thousands of shoppers making their regular purchases from well-stocked stores and markets. One sees people line up to view the latest movies and to rent videos. One can watch modern buses whisk tourists off to catch their jet planes, or observe the speed and clarity of a satellite call to the United States. The streets are crowded and business is good. You might wonder, “What is so different about this town from hundreds of others like it throughout the world?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="nHO6Ttx3CUe2k_stv-u_Yg" hash="wvHAwA">But when Sunday dawns on the kingdom of Tonga, a transformation takes place. If one goes downtown, he sees deserted streets—no taxis or buses or crowds of people. All the stores, all the markets, all the movie theaters, all the offices are closed. No planes fly, no ships come in or out, no commerce takes place. No games are played. The people go to church. Tonga is remembering to keep the Sabbath day holy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="843Ub-lCbEmcoBo2FW7b0w" hash="E0B3ZQ">It is significant that the first country in the world to greet the holy Sabbath keeps the Sabbath holy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="zWNHETpGf0WVFngB3QtVBw" hash="Xlut2g">Has the Lord blessed them? Maybe the world cannot see his blessings, but in the ways that really count, he has blessed them abundantly. He has blessed them with the gospel of Jesus Christ, and a larger percentage of the population there belongs to the Church than in any other country.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="BMhOarpENkSEg9zcDHklbg" hash="pa2-Uw">Simple, well-kept chapels dot the land. Clean, smiling local missionaries are found everywhere. A beautiful, exceptionally well-attended temple stands in Tonga in fulfillment of promises made years and ages ago. And, as would be expected, their attendance at meetings and faithfulness in tithing are very near the top. Recently the Saints have been blessed with some fairly intense opposition that is having the effect of further sanctifying the true seekers of eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="MtYdXgWxVUeJSudKHNfCEQ" hash="z8-gYw">Does the Lord love and bless those who keep the Sabbath day holy? I testify that he does in eternally meaningful ways. I further testify that when we eventually see things through the proper perspective of eternal truth, we will be amazed at how much we were blessed in important—though often unperceived—ways through keeping the Sabbath holy; and to our sorrow we may sense how many blessings we kept from ourselves by not consistently keeping the Sabbath day holy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="AMOkzlpQtkWVxx9T3mSEMg" hash="lKjAQg">There is a direct correlation between the proper observance of the Sabbath and true reverence for God, which includes obedience to his other commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="18mesOviy0yhCtSYK00Ujw" hash="DV6tKQ">We can’t all live in Tonga, but we can all keep the Sabbath day holy and receive the blessings that come therefrom—and they come to us wherever we live, personally as well as collectively.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="Fyh-EK8zBk-2wqi1dsDlrA" hash="nCkDeA">Let me give another example from these very valleys:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="_gMvWG5t1E6sJQdnUSLzzA" hash="fuz3gg">Some time ago I was assigned to a conference in northern Utah in June. As I drove through Cache Valley on Saturday, I was struck by the beauty of that peaceful green valley. I marveled at the temple in Logan—such a serene, peaceful beacon in so many ways. As I continued north on that clear summer day, I was impressed with the green fields so rich with a variety of crops. I particularly noticed the great number of alfalfa fields and the constant activity in nearly all of them. What a pleasing sensation it was to smell that freshly mown hay and to see the straight rows and the orderly cutting of those meticulously groomed fields.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="8omHCeULm0qeZcRiSJ1wQA" hash="i9WleA">I pulled the car over to the side of the road at the top of one of the hills and got out. I found myself absorbed right into that beautiful valley. As far as I could see was a whole panorama of the same activity in every direction—hay being mowed and stacked and hauled.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="34EMjeRXG0GPIjEupamhNA" hash="C4KdDg">I finally drove on to the stake where we had a wonderful conference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="ivcaUsA7CkifRyT4cD19aA" hash="B1ZLtg">My parents live in southeast Idaho, and since I was already more than halfway there, I decided to drive up Sunday afternoon to visit them before returning home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="6JtYPDfR8UqszUxVCEOMmA" hash="_3IxbQ">So, after conference I started north through the rest of Cache Valley. Within a few miles I was in Idaho, but the scenery and feeling were just the same. I again became absorbed in the beauty of the green fields and the smell of fresh hay all around. Again, I stopped at the top of one of the hills and got out and looked as far as I could in all directions. It was just as beautiful—if not more so—than the day before. “Yes, even more beautiful,” I thought, “but why?” The sun and sky and the clouds and the fields were all the same. Why this deep feeling that this sight this Sunday afternoon was even more beautiful than the day before?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="UBjae5-zj0y4fA2oI4HkFQ" hash="L27hPQ">What was the difference? I noticed in the distance a small LDS chapel and a few cars starting to pull up to it. Then it struck me, rather peacefully but very effectively: “There is the difference. No one is mowing or hauling hay today.” I looked as far as I could and saw hay fields everywhere, tractors stopped, mowing machines idle, and trucks resting in the fields, but no one working—for it was the Sabbath and this was Cache Valley and these were largely good Latter- day Saint people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="rpFbF5x8i06p_vfJny1UcQ" hash="POrZmA">As I continued north, I saw everywhere hay to be cut and stacked and hauled and equipment and weather to do it, but no man or woman in the fields. The people of this valley were observing a higher law, and the Sabbath was being kept holy in Cache Valley.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="RTh_voEfIEqaVxSRp0U9TA" hash="X_YIMQ">I went by dozens, even hundreds, of farms with machines waiting in the fields—left Saturday evening by God-fearing men waiting for Monday to come and the whine of activity to resume. I wondered to myself, “Will someone break this spell, will someone be out in his fields working?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="YsxQT2SS6ke4o4kitDtBEQ" hash="R6VG3g">Each time I rounded a corner or came to the top of a hill, I would look and look and then breathe a sigh of relief—no one working.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="b0X0d47_lEaf7C_bjVUcQg" hash="mKI9bw">I went farther and farther north, realizing I was near the end of this beautiful valley. “Would anyone break the spell? Could it be a whole valley so dedicated to God that no one would work on the Sabbath?” The suspense became almost unbearable. Each curve I rounded or each hill I came over found me looking in almost fearful anticipation, then smiling as the same peaceful scene continued.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="l7mOq8oQJ0-4NDych9GRXQ" hash="4JyZSw">Finally I came to the last curve and the confluence with the main road that marked the end of Cache Valley. I looked and looked, but all was peaceful and quiet. I was so excited, I pulled the car over, got out, and in almost a Toyota-like jump I raised my hands and shouted, “You did it, Cache Valley. You did it! I have traversed your length. You didn’t know I was looking, but you did it—not one field being mowed, not one tractor at work, not one truck hauling. You did it!” (I recognize that I had been through only the northern end of the valley that Sunday, but it was still Cache Valley.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="o_kYgKnZ2kiM1hRu07hUbg" hash="Nap75w">I instinctively looked heavenward and said, “Did you see that? Did you see Cache Valley this Sunday afternoon?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="13Pk1sXrtE-Xra_BuoPDwA" hash="0exhHQ">Even though I didn’t hear anything, it was as though I sensed a response saying, “Yes, we know. We see everything.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="sIkCpKNRF0-LdmjfAKAlGw" hash="ZxmM9A">I had such a joyful feeling—almost ecstasy—as I drove north to a wonderful meeting with my parents before returning home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="0OP6uLxNf0SHaBV3BmDo_A" hash="DA6hwg">For some time after that, I couldn’t get that Sunday afternoon off my mind. I kept feeling, “You have observed and witnessed something very special, something truly significant: an entire valley keeping His Sabbath holy.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="WBMVMNvfIU6UhGAKD0nGLw" hash="Drq1TQ">It caused me deep reflection then and many times since, but like so many things it was moved further and further to the back of my mind with the press of many current problems. Winter came, and for all intents and purposes it slipped from my conscious memory.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="u98RG_WIo0eo3yf_N9nV-g" hash="8RS9gA">I continued to travel each weekend to various parts of the world. Many months later, I was assigned to a conference in a city noted for its particularly flagrant violations of God’s laws. The Saints there were wonderful, but oh, the decadence and debauchery that seemed to be all around them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="TqJ-ntTD9UqNvq13ceWibg" hash="3XyKOA">As I returned from the especially hectic weekend, I began reading in the scriptures. I thought about Sodom and Gomorrah. Could they have been much more wicked than this? And yet the Lord promised to spare them for fifty righteous souls—or even down to ten—but they were not found.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="LQJ_VeOuLkmy90HM_NkiTQ" hash="eP8XOw">I let my imagination go and seemed to see a band of destroying angels loosed from heaven—thundering across the land. And even before I had time to think about the situation, I seemed to see myself standing in front of these determined destroyers, declaring, “Hold, hold, hold”; and they held. “Go back,” I said: and their horses reared, their eyes flashing in impatience. The destroyers’ anxiousness showed, but they held.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="vDm-16DeGkaX2r3Parrc2A" hash="iOx0pA">The leader looked me squarely in the eye and challenged, “By what right do you ask us to hold? Have you not seen the evil of the land?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="TDicZKg1fUKWwtPk0tWWCQ" hash="i0ZvgQ">I replied, “Yes, I know of the sordidness of the world. I see the constant mocking of God’s laws, the merchandising on his holy day, the constant breaking of his commandments. I see the evil that exists almost universally. Yes, yes, all these things are true, still …” Then I became concerned. What right had I to ask them to hold?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="bxy0TeIbmUGYVZmhbvVhVw" hash="uk7hCA">My eyes began to fall from his penetrating gaze, but something inside kept searching, searching, until finally a laserlike beam locked on to a misty memory made many months ago and faithfully filed away for such a time as this. A vista of a beautiful green valley passed before me and moved to the front of my consciousness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="5rY1j8qYg0SXHdhNz__HnA" hash="Jkrtsw">I raised my eyes and met his as he again said, “What right do you have to ask us to hold?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="cjf_rw_KYkqjZSwxDKkZbQ" hash="l6elXA">Then with the confidence of sure knowledge and spiritual direction, I replied, “You must hold, for you see, I have been through Cache Valley on a Sunday afternoon.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="odCVOa3ZpkaOGwooBjLOVw" hash="MmA3IQ">There was no hesitation, no anger, no look of surprise, no disappointment, only obedience; and he turned and rejoined his group, and they left.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="G3exOF0QWUOzAHIGm_58wQ" hash="35lMNw">Oh, my dear brothers and sisters, there is power in keeping the Sabbath day holy—power to help others as well as ourselves. If we would have God’s blessings and protection as individuals, as families, as communities, and as nations, we must keep His Sabbath day holy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy.p" pid="IknMx_IAMUiBakHeIfC_Og" hash="i81n8A">May we all live that someday, someway, somewhere, somehow, as we face that which is very serious, we may be able to say, “Hold, hold, hold”; and, when challenged as to why (even by ourselves), be able—through obedience and the confidence of the Spirit—to say in our own way, “For I have been through Cache Valley on a Sunday afternoon,” I do humbly pray in the name of our Savior, who lives. I know he lives, even Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-269c.jpg" alt="Elder John H. Groberg" guid="0ef34a76-7802-4e6f-9f49-23f254a187c8" pid="9_QFv_JQGk6ZPOHr-Koz5A" hash="FMNYUQ1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="0ef34a76-7802-4e6f-9f49-23f254a187c8"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1984/10/the-power-of-keeping-the-sabbath-day-holy</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1984-general-conference/1984-10-5050-elder-john-h-groberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="6072648" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 1984 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Beauty and Importance of the Sacrament</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament?lang=eng</link>
      <description>One of the most important invitations ever issued to us and to all mankind is to “come unto Christ and be perfected in him.” (.) How do we do that? One of the most beautiful and important ways is through the ordinance of the sacrament.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03239_000_018" doc-version="2" hash="YJEvog">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="gJMexzdcuUKnCqdaYXK3wA" hash="cXlcJQ">The Beauty and Importance of the Sacrament</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Irp2jRKP2UKqBuPMyNDJ9A" hash="kdP_xA">John H. Groberg</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-269c.jpg" alt="Elder John H. Groberg" pid="XVzMCI-wQECOngWTWmJemA" hash="FMNYUQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p1" pid="tX7dtPl_1EGaH4b7X1wGlg" hash="1nvDMw">One of the most important invitations ever issued to us and to all mankind is to “come unto Christ and be perfected in him.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.32" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:32</a>.) How do we do that? One of the most beautiful and important ways is through the ordinance of the sacrament.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p2" pid="B7cGpYGWQEmbGzIR5tZ-iA" hash="7FkdYw">The Lord instituted the sacrament, as we know it today, during what we commonly call the Last Supper. In one sense, it was the last supper, but in another, it was the first supper—the beginning of many spiritual feasts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p3" pid="Oxge5qjqb0-zFF6FCV1cuQ" hash="Pzrbpg">The resurrected Lord instructed the Book of Mormon people:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p4" pid="qzKcxA9BtESjGhFg79SbaQ" hash="ERgdbA">“[Ye] shall break bread and bless it and give it unto the people of my church, unto all those who shall believe and be baptized in my name.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p5" pid="dHquGL5gsU6naG9LzTVybA" hash="0W0dmQ">“And this shall ye always observe to do, even as I have done. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p6" pid="3ublsFPQE0W6ID1JeDwOUg" hash="bCqyEQ">“And this shall ye do in remembrance of my body, which I have shown unto you. And it shall be a testimony unto the Father that ye do always remember me. And if ye do always remember me ye shall have my Spirit to be with you.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.5-7" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:5–7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p7" pid="2PaiAHedBkm5oGtOcpXmug" hash="9W9jmQ">The moving tenderness and deep significance of this transcendent event are still available to us today. But we must do as they did and follow the doctrine of Christ, which is to believe in Jesus, rely on him, repent of our sins, take his name upon us by being baptized in his church, receive the gift of the Holy Ghost, and faithfully follow Christ all of our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p8" pid="ebMYJisiuk6UC6zRFpjQvQ" hash="fahPqQ">He knows we need much help to do this, so he provides that the ordinance of the sacrament be repeated often.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p9" pid="AJ9XyMtlJU2AdhuvHCVrkQ" hash="GnuZ0g">This invitation of the Savior to come unto him is issued regularly and is universal. Everyone is included—men, women, and children. Old and young alike participate. None are barred except by themselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p10" pid="YPC0X7-nQEGmNyn_Q5ulxA" hash="bNZ8cw">The Lord said, “And ye see that I have commanded that none of you should go away, but rather have commanded that ye should come unto me.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.25" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p11" pid="oedKF4oeMU2Jm-upOVnx6A" hash="L0vP6g">But the Lord, who knows the terrible consequences of hypocrisy, also warned:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p12" pid="_NEMBRl0I0WEyHPBvfSiyA" hash="bnLEFA">“Ye shall not suffer any one knowingly to partake of my flesh and blood unworthily, …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p13" pid="6IxKhD8czEKmXf45ledZ4w" hash="8O7MSQ">“For whoso eateth and drinketh my flesh and blood unworthily eateth and drinketh damnation to his soul.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.28-29" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 18:28–29</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p14" pid="0QCaSTvg2UGiysOsSAfEuw" hash="HsPHMg">What does it mean to partake of the sacrament worthily? Or how do we know if we are unworthy?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p15" pid="bhYzDvbd-ESs7j6aVfDMzQ" hash="JdhpZw">If we desire to improve (which is to repent) and are not under priesthood restriction, then, in my opinion, we are worthy. If, however, we have no desire to improve, if we have no intention of following the guidance of the Spirit, we must ask: Are we worthy to partake, or are we making a mockery of the very purpose of the sacrament, which is to act as a catalyst for personal repentance and improvement? If we remember the Savior and all he has done and will do for us, we will improve our actions and thus come closer to him, which keeps us on the road to eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p16" pid="82X36x6pF0Sjr5JaBcXnwg" hash="cl6Tbg">If, however, we refuse to repent and improve, if we do not remember him and keep his commandments, then we have stopped our growth, and that is damnation to our souls.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p17" pid="m9Sac9KcakSEOoNtZN_Aag" hash="GMpEjA">The sacrament is an intensely personal experience, and we are the ones who knowingly are worthy or otherwise.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p18" pid="HcKnDyUlfk2VYFkP6SGtXQ" hash="EVjlCQ">Do you remember the feeling you had when you were baptized—that sweet, clean feeling of a pure soul, having been forgiven, washed clean through the merits of the Savior? If we partake of the sacrament worthily, we can feel that way regularly, for we renew that covenant, which includes his forgiveness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p19" pid="7B-2fCzsuUusD-W77uZS0A" hash="QaYtnA">Those who would deny themselves the blessing of the sacrament by not attending sacrament meeting or by not thinking of the Savior during the services surely must not understand the great opportunity to be forgiven, to have his Spirit to guide and comfort them! What more could anyone ask?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p20" pid="y_VapgP7L0GPxzBPFkWGgg" hash="WrBgnQ">As we worthily partake of the sacrament, we will sense those things we need to improve in and receive the help and determination to do so. No matter what our problems, the sacrament always gives hope.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p21" pid="dAGsDEBYgkSwEQ22YT8XvA" hash="gDW_FA">Most of these problems we must work out ourselves. For example, if we aren’t paying our tithing, we simply determine to start doing so. But for some problems, we must see our bishop—the Spirit will let us know which. Doing what the Spirit dictates always results in blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p22" pid="raD83MEVN0qpla70lvz_nQ" hash="aVpzbw">Let me give an example. Some years ago, a young couple we will call the Joneses visited with their bishop about a problem the wife had. The details are not important, but through the direction of the Spirit, the bishop’s decision was that, among other things, Sister Jones would not partake of the sacrament for a period of time while she worked out some attitudes and problems.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p23" pid="eYt1UL-XlU6HxuRLK27uWQ" hash="XfqkcQ">With lots of love and support, she continued to attend meetings with her family, and few but her husband and the bishop were aware of the situation or even noticed that week after week she did not partake of the sacrament. At first she didn’t feel much difference; but as time went on, she became more and more desirous to be worthy to partake of the sacrament. She thought she had repented before, but as the real soul-searching deepened and as her desire to worthily partake of the sacrament increased, true fundamental changes began to take place in her life and in her actions and in her thinking.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p24" pid="vVv3r0uaS02QIC0lyqyNZA" hash="Ron_9Q">More time passed. Finally, during one sacrament meeting, the Spirit bore witness to the bishop and to Brother and Sister Jones that the time had come for her to again partake of the sacrament. “Next Sunday,” the bishop said.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p25" pid="IlmHXcYmek-nqZulMQSrXA" hash="vx619w">Next Sunday came, and Sister Jones sat again with her family, nervous, yet excited and full of anticipation. “Am I really worthy? How I want to be!” she thought. The sacrament hymn was more meaningful than ever. She sang with such feeling that it was difficult to hold back the tears. And the sacrament prayers—how profound! She listened so intently that every word sank deep into her soul—to take his name, always remember him, keep his commandments, always have his Spirit. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.77,79" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:77, 79</a>.) “Oh, how I desire this,” she thought.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p26" pid="08OB2sLR7EuRYsO_u1z2oQ" hash="UxPXBg">The deacons began to move up and down the aisles, and the trays were passed from person to person across the rows. As one young deacon got closer and closer to her row, her heart began to pound harder and harder. Then the tray was coming down her very row. Now her husband was holding the tray in front of her! Tears streamed down her face. There was a barely audible sob of joy, “Oh!” as she reached for the emblem of the Lord’s love for her. The congregation did not hear the sob, but they did notice the tears in the bishop’s eyes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p27" pid="NQhFnLAbUEOc15hQa8XWYA" hash="xQgZfw">Life and hope and forgiveness and spiritual strength had been given and received. No one could be more worthy. Sister Jones truly <span class="emphasis">wanted</span> to have his Spirit. She <span class="emphasis">wanted</span> to take his name upon her. With all her heart, she <span class="emphasis">wanted</span> to remember him and keep his commandments. She <span class="emphasis">wanted</span> to repent, to improve, and to follow the guidance of his Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p28" pid="OqCDVLc2V0qVwFSxkczzSg" hash="zXT9MA">Think of it. Think of what could and should happen in your life, in your ward, in your stake, in the whole Church, in the whole world, if every Sunday individuals—hundreds, thousands, even millions—under the authority of the priesthood of God, took the sacrament worthily and thus repented and sincerely determined to better follow the guidance of the Lord’s Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p29" pid="mFdyjf0dRU2hd3RzFoPbIQ" hash="yD57sw">The life that would be given, the forgiveness that would be obtained, the spiritual strength that would be received! The light that would thus be generated would cause Zion to shine forth brilliantly and would prepare a people pure in heart, ready for the Lord’s second coming in a way that would be marvelous to behold.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p30" pid="BEzpBzIsxkaKi4QjK9fKUg" hash="BYOdBA">Brethren, as leaders we must do more to have more people attend sacrament meeting and partake of the sacrament with more worthiness! We must teach more fully, with deeper feeling and greater power, the doctrine of Christ as embodied in the sacrament.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p31" pid="c6Jw9pDtTUmbHZjZsddUuQ" hash="CjDotQ">You young men must be worthy and realize what a privilege you have to pass the bread and water, the emblems of the Lord’s love for all of us. Think of the blessings you offer—hope, love, joy, forgiveness, freedom, and everlasting life. What a contrast to so many youth who today pass other types of white substances and other kinds of liquids that bring gloom and failure, captivity and death in the deceitful guise of happiness! Oh, the goodness and mercy of our God as he overcomes the cunning of the evil one!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p32" pid="R3J2XZfF20eq9jAkakxXCw" hash="yAwZcA">I testify from the depths of my soul that these principles are true. Jesus did suffer and die for us. Through him, and only through him, can we have life and the joy thereof, both in time and in eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p33" pid="RyO2NT18QU6IimY1U7kSxQ" hash="Eo-8Ug">I love the Savior. I feel that as he hung upon the cross and looked out over the dark scene, he saw more than mocking soldiers and cruel taunters. He saw more than crying women and fearful friends. He remembered and saw even more than women at wells or crowds on hills or throngs by seashores. He saw more, much more. He, who knows all and has all power, saw through the stream of time. His huge, magnanimous, loving soul encompassed all eternity and took in all people and all times and all sins and all forgiveness and all everything. Yes, he saw down to you and to me and provided us an all-encompassing opportunity to escape the terrible consequences of death and sin.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p34" pid="PEnTKO-x7UCxXGp28S5n8g" hash="ZKvOGg">And even as he suffered for all of us, he voiced that most beautiful of all requests, “Father, forgive them.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/23.34" class="scriptureRef">Luke 23:34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p35" pid="Hd5LABiU_ESEP-mE16nFGg" hash="1qtcTg">We must do our part and cry with full fervor of soul, “Father, forgive me through the merits of thy Beloved Son as I partake of these emblems of his broken body and spilt blood for me. Please, Father, through him, forgive me! Help me to do better.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p36" pid="epMyUSWZcUa6k7T2_VcaGQ" hash="9Q3DSg">All life as we know it comes about through the joining of two separate elements—each necessary. The Savior, through his infinite atonement, provides that vital element for us. He asks us to provide the other element—even a broken heart and a contrite spirit—for he will not force us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p37" pid="MXFUWuUlV0akugB5aBzaWw" hash="TekJbg">Think of the symbolism. Think of the power for bringing about a newness of life by worthily partaking of the sacrament.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p38" pid="F50hzzQ_9kmxhPUJNr3eIQ" hash="wTQLcA">I testify that God our Father lives. I testify that Jesus is the Christ. I know he lives. I know he forgives. I know he loves. I know he smiles tenderly, pleadingly. I know he stands ready to help us—always. I know he guides and directs and blesses with unutterable blessings and unspeakable treasures of eternity. I know he gives knowledge of eternally important things if we desire. I know that worthily partaking of the sacrament is of eternal importance to him and to us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament.p39" pid="J1HVjmk0NUOpr6pyUycE7g" hash="528hVQ">Yes, I know he gives life—in all of its depth of meaning. As the emblems of his love are regularly presented before us, please let us hear, “Father, forgive them,” and respond, “Father, forgive me.” This leads to life—eternal life—in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1989/04/the-beauty-and-importance-of-the-sacrament</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1989-general-conference/1989-04-3020-elder-john-h-groberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="6316945" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 1989 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lord’s Wind</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The fourth article of faith states: “We believe that the first principles and ordinances of the Gospel are: first, Faith in the Lord Jesus Christ; second, Repentance; third, Baptism by immersion for the remission of sins; fourth, Laying on of hands f</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_93911_000_012" doc-version="2" hash="yGtXZw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="cIx7o3PLO02FRwUh1P0LYQ" hash="bxLs-A">The Lord’s Wind</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="TU4zoN8hnkWsHmH5PwefIQ" hash="kdP_xA">John H. Groberg</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2376.jpg" alt="Elder John H. Groberg" pid="HIZNPYJTyk6lWtP1WOL66g" hash="9aLtZQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p1" pid="5FtkyDmnuk6bFeN8MqhLQQ" hash="Imfylw">The fourth article of faith states: “We believe that the first principles and ordinances of the Gospel are: first, Faith in the Lord Jesus Christ; second, Repentance; third, Baptism by immersion for the remission of sins; fourth, Laying on of hands for the gift of the Holy Ghost.” [<a href="/scriptures/pgp/a-of-f/1.4" class="scriptureRef">A of F 1:4</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p2" pid="iXhLtWAhS0WqO0bTBTUWTA" hash="CI4_Rg">If we think deeply, we realize that the first principle—faith in the Lord Jesus Christ—underlies all else; that is, it takes faith in Christ to repent or be baptized or perform any other ordinances of the gospel. Jesus made saving repentance possible and He made baptism meaningful. If we have faith in Him, we will repent and be baptized. If we do not repent, or refuse to be baptized, or are unwilling to keep His commandments, it is because we do not have sufficient faith in Him. Thus, repentance, baptism, and all other principles and ordinances are not entirely separate but are actually extensions of our faith in Christ. Without faith in Him, we do little of eternal value. With faith in Him, our lives become focused on doing things of eternal value.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p3" pid="Py9Pl3pTZEi8ks8Gpq4fFQ" hash="Lor0FA">It takes deep and abiding faith in Christ to endure faithfully to the end of our mortal lives. Sometimes we pray for the strength to endure yet resist the very things that would give us that strength. Too often we seek the easy way, forgetting that strength comes from overcoming things that require us to put forth more effort than we normally would be inclined to do. The Apostle Paul said, “I can do all things through Christ which strengtheneth me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/philip/4.13" class="scriptureRef">Philip. 4:13</a>). Let me give an example:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p4" pid="Qf161BvSMUS_X-iheh6yGQ" hash="pYVhDw">Years ago, as a young missionary, I was assigned to a group of seventeen small islands in the South Pacific. At that time, the only means of travel between islands was by sailboat. Because of misunderstandings and traditions, it was difficult to find people willing to listen to us. However, one day a member told us that if we would be at a certain harbor on a particular island when the sun set the next day, a family would meet us there and listen to the discussions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p5" pid="etc6stzOyUyM6rjopgNaPw" hash="v74tLg">What joy that news brought! It was like finding a piece of gold. I was working alone at the time but quickly found four other members who were experienced sailors who agreed to take me to this island the next day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p6" pid="CGrNyN63uU2h6EgMFe_sdw" hash="2u-ehQ">Early the next morning the five of us started out. There was a nice breeze that moved us swiftly along the coast, through the opening in the reef, and out into the wide expanse of the vast Pacific Ocean.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p7" pid="m9chd4RvLEeJIVr_1xvA6A" hash="F-wdZw">We made good progress for a few hours, but as the sun climbed higher and the boat got farther from land, the wind began to play out and soon quit altogether, leaving us bobbing aimlessly on a smooth ocean.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p8" pid="QuxlFkoYskepJKKN0MGzOw" hash="7WbQbw">Those familiar with sailing know that to get anywhere, you need wind. Sometimes there are good breezes without storms and heavy seas, but often they go together. Sailors do not fear storms, for they contain the lifeblood of sailing—wind. What sailors fear is <span class="emphasis">no</span> wind, or being becalmed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p9" pid="JJxpDTFxOkq9AysP_-7XgQ" hash="Zqj8jQ">Time passed. The sun got higher, the sea calmer. Nothing moved. We soon realized that unless something changed, we would not arrive by sundown. I suggested that we pray and plead with the Lord to send some wind. What more righteous desire could a group of men have? I offered a prayer. When I finished, things seemed calmer than ever. We continued drifting.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p10" pid="VJWtT8cu0kO0tLdUcVw-pw" hash="uUzfcg">Then one of the older men suggested that everyone kneel and all unite their faith and prayers together, which we did. There was great struggling of spirit, but when the last person opened his eyes, nothing! No movement at all. The sails hung limp and listless. Even the slight ripple of the ocean against the side of the boat had ceased. The ocean seemed like a sea of glass.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p11" pid="yXHANfktgUqjeAsi6eZwWg" hash="ufeP0Q">Time was moving, and we were getting desperate. This same man now suggested that everyone kneel again in prayer and each person in turn offer a vocal prayer for the whole group. Many beautiful, pleading, faithful prayers ascended to heaven. But when the last one finished and everyone opened their eyes, the sun was still burning down with greater intensity than before. The ocean was like a giant mirror. It was almost as though Satan was laughing, saying, “See, you can’t go anywhere. There is no wind. You are in my power.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p12" pid="0mXfUkzKjUGIh1aKi79ibQ" hash="yx9uqQ">I thought, “There is a family at the harbor that wants to hear the gospel. We are here in the middle of the ocean and want to teach them. The Lord controls the elements. All that stands between us and the family is a little wind. Why won’t He send it? It’s a righteous desire.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p13" pid="fXZwnaVjfkqZ4IgCUQ2j8w" hash="F-01hw">As I was so wondering, I noticed this faithful older brother move to the rear of the boat. I watched as he unlashed the tiny lifeboat, placed two oars with pins in their places, and carefully lowered it over the side.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p14" pid="7PTEcodWzkiU_NkQNxfO2Q" hash="kBOQJQ">He looked at me and softly said, “Get in.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p15" pid="_qdLRywjg0S1mS69anhekA" hash="-hGppQ">I answered, “What are you doing? There is hardly room for two people in that tiny thing!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p16" pid="BHu9cLprpkqez0y3lR8CrQ" hash="z5-tXw">“Don’t waste any time or effort. Just get in. I am going to row you to shore, and we need to leave now to make it by sundown.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p17" pid="wLsw9PYhO0OP43t0xYOY_Q" hash="13a_rw">I looked at him incredulously, “Row me <span class="emphasis">where?</span>”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p18" pid="RiScsVFcs0K4H_QDn0re8Q" hash="LpxJ0A">“To the family that wants to hear the gospel. We have an assignment from the Lord. Get in.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p19" pid="uKh6iUXKZUKfSLUbbXUpSA" hash="XSqMNQ">I was dumbfounded. It was miles to shore. The sun was hot, and this man was old. But as I looked into the face of that faithful brother, I sensed an intensity in his gaze, an iron will in his very being, and a fixed determination in his voice as he said, “Before the sun sets this day, you will be teaching the gospel and bearing testimony to a family who wants to listen.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p20" pid="rKHiFqF13ES_xD89D1NYug" hash="AnCVCw">I again objected, “Look, you’re over three times my age. If this is to be, let me row.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p21" pid="9pZZDLu2Yka3ZU95SEOWiw" hash="ZubQDg">With that same look of determination and faith-induced will, the old man replied, “No. Leave it to me. Get in the boat. Don’t waste more time talking. Let’s go!” At his direction we got into the boat, with me in the front and the old man in the middle, his feet stretching to the end of the boat, his back to me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p22" pid="e0eA-06zu02o0-06cWxKXw" hash="RsrM1A">The glazed surface of the ocean was disturbed by the intrusion of this small boat and seemed to complain, “This is my territory. Stay out.” Not a wisp of air stirred, not a sound was heard except the creaking of oars and the rattling of pins as the small craft began to move away from the sailboat.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p23" pid="JfG89IbC1UuZC8bN6gdBKQ" hash="jopvRw">The old man bent his back and began to row. Dip. Pull. Lift. Dip. Pull. Lift. Each dip of the oar seemed to break the resolve of the mirrorlike ocean. Each pull of the oar moved the tiny skiff forward, separating the glassy seas to make way for the Lord’s messenger. Dip. Pull. Lift. The old man did not look up, rest, or talk, but hour after hour he rowed and rowed and rowed. The muscles of his back and arms, strengthened by faith and moved by unalterable determination, flexed in a marvelous cadence like a fine-tuned watch. It was beautiful. We moved quietly, relentlessly toward an inevitable destiny. The old man concentrated his efforts and energy on fulfilling the calling he had from the Lord—to get a missionary to a family that wanted to hear the gospel. He was the Lord’s wind that day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p24" pid="ynSXSPE7EkibpY5cVDIZEQ" hash="IzOCUg">Just as the sun dipped into the ocean, the skiff touched the shore of the harbor. A family <span class="emphasis">was</span> waiting. The old man spoke for the first time in hours and said, “Go. Teach them the truth. I’ll wait here.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p25" pid="VtnZzrJYs0y-78lwg5Lkyw" hash="n6NHmA">I waded ashore, met the family, went to their home, and taught them the gospel. As I bore testimony of the power of God in this church, my mind saw an old Tongan man rowing to a distant harbor and waiting patiently there. I testified with a fervor as great as any I have ever felt that God does give power to men and women to do His will if they will have faith in Him. I told the family, “When we exercise faith in the Lord Jesus Christ, we can do things we could not otherwise do. When our hearts are determined to do right, the Lord gives us the power to do so.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p26" pid="2TOgzzf7KUqD_9cKALgNEA" hash="TXPeRQ">The family believed and eventually was baptized.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p27" pid="qMBql0KxL06-7lvpFjCACg" hash="60k2KQ">In the annals of history, few will be aware of this small incident. Hardly anyone will know about this insignificant island, the family who waited, or the obscure, old man who never once complained of fatigue, aching arms, painful back, or a hurting body. He never talked about thirst, the scorching sun, or the heat of the day as he relentlessly rowed uncomplainingly hour after hour. He referred only to the privilege of being God’s agent in bringing a missionary to teach the truth to those who desired to hear. But God knows! He gave him the strength to be His wind that day, and He will give us the strength to be His wind when necessary.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p28" pid="1RUtTFZDy0ygOcE9N_HQ7w" hash="LF6-hQ">How often do we not do more because we pray for wind and none comes? We pray for good things and they don’t seem to happen, so we sit and wait and do no more. We should always pray for help, but we should always listen for inspiration and impressions to proceed in ways different from those we may have thought of. On the boat, five men prayed, but only one heard and acted. God does hear our prayers. God knows more than we do. He has infinitely greater experience than we have. We should never stop moving because we think our way is barred or the only door we can go through is closed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p29" pid="9n5augCyR0ipxWm_sZ-FxQ" hash="9jClOQ">No matter what our trials, we should never say, “It is enough.” Only God is entitled to say that. Our responsibility is to ask, “What more can I do?” then listen for the answer, and do it!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p30" pid="Ti30zAzTFESahgPuo-ttBg" hash="fBBxoQ">I’ll never forget that old man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p31" pid="wpUtYckKjkGuJPtXjggQwg" hash="YroGYg">I pray that we may always have increasing faith in the Lord Jesus Christ and demonstrate that faith by our actions. I know He lives and loves. I know He strengthens and encourages. I know He helps and heals. I know He forgives and saves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind.p32" pid="vjujcXKZWUuVmgeWr-lq9Q" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1993/10/the-lords-wind</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1993-general-conference/1993-10-2030-elder-john-h-groberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="5874068" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 1993 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Priesthood Power</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power?lang=eng</link>
      <description>While the power of the priesthood is unlimited, our individual power in the priesthood is limited by our degree of righteousness or purity.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029247_000_020" doc-version="2" hash="rstdmA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="8J-Wki5fHkih29YDrI1lSQ" hash="SIlhFA">Priesthood Power</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="vjIxLyVW_kaXXs4Wp5WBDQ" hash="kdP_xA">John H. Groberg</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="ezNKGp80Kk-otdzdwuKBVg" hash="t0V5YA">While the power of the priesthood is unlimited, our individual power in the priesthood is limited by our degree of righteousness or purity.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-63d.jpg" alt="Elder John H. Groberg" pid="74Olku7edEy0Tf2n_jYUrw" hash="e4ecvw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p1" pid="G4WIeQZQO0G1gfsf9_YBew" hash="iPr7hg">Fellow bearers of the priesthood everywhere: I hope we appreciate the priceless privilege of holding the priesthood of God. Its value is unfathomable.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p2" pid="WTwC1LOjAUCkgWJIbRqmSg" hash="a1AJlQ">Through its power, worlds—even universes—have, are, and will be created or organized. Through its power, ordinances are performed which, when accompanied by righteousness, allow families to be together forever, sins to be forgiven, the sick to be healed, the blind to see, and even life to be restored.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p3" pid="z0ZimujAk0qEyQ3CeaaHAQ" hash="bmDv8Q">God wants us, His sons, to hold His priesthood and learn to use it properly. He has explained that:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p4" pid="Jhr0HIv_8kuDhMXiHtoyeA" hash="nkeFvA">“No power or influence can or ought to be maintained by virtue of the priesthood, only by persuasion, by long-suffering, by gentleness and meekness, and by love unfeigned.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p5" pid="kdKzGKJJaEykvFR5PViydQ" hash="mLjVtA">“By kindness, and pure knowledge.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p6" pid="JOYZclnLPU64uGO8vfMBOw" hash="yzNW6A">For if we “exercise control or dominion or compulsion upon the souls of the children of men [especially our wives and children], in any degree of unrighteousness, behold, the heavens withdraw themselves; the Spirit of the Lord is grieved; and when it is withdrawn, Amen to the priesthood or the authority of that man.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p7" pid="0OjbGtuA9kWSmMsCyX0tmQ" hash="HexK7Q">Thus, we see that while the power <span class="emphasis">of</span> the priesthood is unlimited, our individual power <span class="emphasis">in</span> the priesthood is limited by our degree of righteousness or purity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p8" pid="Fv2-P26Fi0qMO7LjMJXNnQ" hash="YP-mFA">Just as clean wires, properly connected, are required to carry electrical power, so clean hands and pure hearts are required to carry priesthood power. Filth and grime slow or prevent the flow of electrical power. Unclean thoughts and actions interfere with individual priesthood power. When we are humble, clean, and pure of hand, heart, and mind, nothing righteous is impossible. An ancient Oriental saying declares, “If a man lives a pure life, nothing can destroy him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p9" pid="eiUuLxFQTEChHestvF4CQw" hash="51YBJg">In His love for us, God has decreed that any worthy man, regardless of wealth, education, color, cultural background, or language, may hold His priesthood. Thus, any properly ordained man who is clean in hand, heart, and mind can connect with the unlimited power of the priesthood. I learned this lesson well as a young missionary years ago in the South Pacific.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p10" pid="LzlqcrQt8Eqzc4yJkOhyMA" hash="s3Nhgw">My first assignment was to a small island hundreds of miles from headquarters, where no one spoke English, and I was the only white man. I was given a local companion named Feki who was then serving a building mission and was a priest in the Aaronic Priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p11" pid="-x8phE0TyUKHsqtvCpnYvg" hash="Bft-Dg">After eight seasick days and nights on a small, smelly boat, we arrived at Niuatoputapu. I struggled with the heat, the mosquitoes, the strange food, culture, and language, as well as homesickness. One afternoon we heard cries of anguish and saw a family bringing the limp, seemingly lifeless body of their eight-year-old son to us. They wailed out that he had fallen from a mango tree and would not respond to anything. The faithful father and mother put him in my arms and said, “You have the Melchizedek Priesthood; bring him back to us whole and well.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p12" pid="bSAppi3YnkeYTefG5bMnSg" hash="lGVQ0g">Though my knowledge of the language was still limited, I understood what they wanted, and I was scared. I wanted to run away, but the expressions of love and faith that shone from the eyes of the parents and brothers and sisters kept me glued to the spot.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p13" pid="AF7oyomJm0aTyjDXSn8egA" hash="IGgEWA">I looked expectantly at my companion. He shrugged and said, “I don’t have the proper authority. You and the branch president hold the Melchizedek Priesthood.” Grasping at that straw, I said, “Then this is the duty of the branch president.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p14" pid="OuaygG2AEUSRG9BaE1ZCrQ" hash="2aTBFQ">No sooner had I said this than the branch president walked up. He had heard the commotion and returned from his garden. He was sweaty and covered with dirt and mud. I turned and explained what had happened and tried to give the young boy to him. He stepped back and said, “I will go and wash and put on clean clothes; then we will bless him and see what God has to say.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p15" pid="ghJJJfM9CUu1TqpzJCl6nQ" hash="0b-QxA">In near panic, I cried, “Can’t you see? He needs help now!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p16" pid="Mce4ggyJgUS96fqitUceAw" hash="3re31g">He calmly replied: “I know he needs a blessing. When I have washed myself and put on clean clothes, I will bring consecrated oil, and we will approach God and see what His will is. I cannot—I will not—approach God with dirty hands and muddy clothes.” He turned and left me holding the boy. I was speechless.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p17" pid="KAbfwKQYVEq1s6DGuyrYXQ" hash="9r35TQ">Finally he returned, clean in body and dress and, I sensed, in heart as well. “Now,” he said, “I am clean, so we will approach the throne of God.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p18" pid="JgW5QSvLKEiB4suq0WCnew" hash="3iDkhg">That marvelous Tongan branch president, with clean hands and a pure heart, gave a beautiful and powerful priesthood blessing. I felt more like a witness than a participant. The words of the Psalmist came to my mind: “Who shall ascend into the hill of the Lord? …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p19" pid="5adsuDwIQUO0YFollXATHw" hash="-CLL1g">“He that hath clean hands, and a pure heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> On that tiny island a worthy priesthood holder ascended into the hill of the Lord, and the power of the priesthood came down from heaven and authorized a young boy’s life to continue.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p20" pid="Zcgat7Z5vE2dNRyj-W69Rg" hash="4kEK3w">With the fire of faith glowing from his eyes, the branch president told me what to do. Much additional faith and effort was required, but on the third day that little eight-year-old boy, full of life, was reunited with his family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p21" pid="QIgXWdmK8USNCL0fz5NLDQ" hash="dgIn2A">I hope you understand and feel these truths. This was a tiny island in the midst of a huge ocean—with no electricity, no hospital, no doctors—but none of that mattered. For in addition to great love and faith, there was a branch president who held the Melchizedek Priesthood, who understood the importance of cleanliness of hand and heart and its outward expression in cleanliness of body and dress, who exercised the priesthood in righteousness and purity according to the will of God. That day his individual power <span class="emphasis">in</span> the priesthood was sufficient to connect with the unlimited power <span class="emphasis">of</span> the priesthood over earthly life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p22" pid="dw3AqA1SA0ymMOL_Y3a-eQ" hash="V04qDA">When I look into the heavens at night and contemplate the endless galaxies therein, I am amazed at what a tiny dot our little earth is and how infinitesimally small I am. Yet I do not feel afraid, alone, insignificant, or distant from God. For I have witnessed His priesthood power connecting with clean hands and pure hearts on a tiny island in a vast ocean.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p23" pid="txINpB6cDkitn4dq0Wjydg" hash="I_o1WQ">Brethren, that connection is available to all of us, no matter where, when, or under what circumstances we live, so long as our hands, hearts, and minds are clean and pure. There is no individual power in the priesthood outside of individual purity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p24" pid="3ZqW1aZ_10-bbF-jTpTMOA" hash="PLKciQ">We simply must work harder at purifying our lives by serving others in more Christlike ways. There are always opportunities to serve—in our families, in the Church, on missions, in temples, and among our fellowmen. Noble service requires hard work, deep sacrifice, and complete unselfishness. The more the sacrifice, the greater the resultant purity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p25" pid="N_OAnXlG3kiF3P6T8XdF4w" hash="ZP5AuA">God, who is full of light, life, and love, wants us to hold and properly use His priesthood so we can transmit that light, life, and love to all about us. On the other hand, Satan, the prince of darkness, wants to hold back light, life, and love as much as he can. Since there is nothing Satan can do about the power <span class="emphasis">of</span> the priesthood, he concentrates his energy on trying to limit our individual power <span class="emphasis">in</span> the priesthood by attempting to dirty our hands, hearts, and minds through abuse, anger, neglect, pornography, selfishness, or any other evil he can entice us to think or do. He knows if he can sufficiently soil us individually, he can, to that degree, keep us from the purity needed to properly exercise the priesthood and thus bring more light, life, and love to this earth and all the inhabitants thereof—past, present, and future.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p26" pid="8HP5jMckZ0aGl8GgEP6u4w" hash="BbYWCA">Oh, brethren, please don’t sell your precious priesthood birthright for a mess of X- or R-rated pottage. Remember, the sand castles we build on the beaches of mortality, no matter how elaborate, will eventually be washed away by the tide. Only purity of hand, heart, and mind will allow us to tap into the ultimate power of the priesthood to truly bless others and eventually be able to build eternal mansions more beautiful and lasting than we can presently imagine.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p27" pid="l3Ppu75oEUODAYt93w5TtQ" hash="SZLqDw">I have learned for myself that God lives, that Jesus is the Christ, that He is my friend and your friend. I know that Jesus is the perfect personification of pure priesthood power. Follow Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p28" pid="Ysy-rbTtekGaR8tpzAm5hg" hash="a3LRPA">I pray that we may all serve with more purity of heart, that our individual power in the priesthood may eventually be full through the perfect love of Him whose priesthood we bear.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power.p29" pid="PKOepxHtRkGLWCdiS5Uv7g" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2001/04/priesthood-power</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2001-general-conference/2001-04-3030-elder-john-h-groberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="5205640" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2001 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of God’s Love</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Filled with His love, we can endure pain, quell fear, forgive freely, avoid contention, renew strength, and bless and help others.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030208_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="mWqWXQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="NP_63cGDLECctsC0dgEnnA" hash="JhoYGA">The Power of God’s Love</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="8JMlvVmoUUyfQIuCtYw2Nw" hash="kdP_xA">John H. Groberg</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="oGvbZraJBkyML2REAzwd0Q" hash="bt4cSA">Filled with His love, we can endure pain, quell fear, forgive freely, avoid contention, renew strength, and bless and help others.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-63d.jpg" alt="Elder John H. Groberg" pid="-DcwrR4cWkaufR-jHizA1g" hash="e4ecvw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p1" pid="HZ0xuqpvhkmoWjZemqLepQ" hash="jD_naw">What is it about true love that touches every heart? Why does the simple phrase “I love you” evoke such universal joy?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p2" pid="TB1vchkSH0qmqrSGPN9JkA" hash="MjrPKQ">Men give various reasons, but the real reason is that every person who comes to earth is a spirit son or daughter of God. Since all love emanates from God, we are born with the capacity and the desire to love and to be loved. One of the strongest connections we have with our premortal life is how much our Father and Jesus loved us and how much we loved Them. Even though a veil was drawn over our memory, whenever we sense true love, it awakens a longing that cannot be denied.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p3" pid="u-PTnBB1-0-WTGjP6IS1Lw" hash="7AGVdg">Responding to true love is part of our very being. We innately desire to reconnect here with the love we felt there. Only as we feel God’s love and fill our hearts with His love can we be truly happy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p4" pid="x70VPuv0k0-3hItnSMzyJA" hash="2X2P9w">God’s love fills the immensity of space; therefore, there is no shortage of love in the universe, only in our willingness to do what is needed to feel it. To do this, Jesus explained we must “love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, … soul, … strength, and … mind; and thy neighbour as thyself” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.27" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:27</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p5" pid="FbNVfD7evUqU98kbVJBLAA" hash="4C8VqQ">The more we obey God, the more we desire to help others. The more we help others, the more we love God and on and on. Conversely, the more we disobey God and the more selfish we are, the less love we feel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p6" pid="HbaNUaAwJkCKEUV4rzaY4g" hash="aYLYXQ">Trying to find lasting love without obeying God is like trying to quench thirst by drinking from an empty cup—you can go through the motions, but the thirst remains. Similarly, trying to find love without helping and sacrificing for others is like trying to live without eating—it is against the laws of nature and cannot succeed. We cannot fake love. It must become part of us. The prophet Mormon explained:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p7" pid="q_GxfU-TGEywfbYqkF50PQ" hash="7DmaAg">“Charity is the pure love of Christ, and it endureth forever; and whoso is found possessed of it at the last day, it shall be well with him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p8" pid="mUc8Wz8THUmgvSYgpMjk-Q" hash="YLsfiQ">“Wherefore, my beloved brethren, pray unto the Father with all the energy of heart, that ye may be filled with this love” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.47-48" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:47–48</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p9" pid="GEU5-xR2YkifIvLATsulfw" hash="8SLCGg">God is anxious to help us feel His love wherever we are. Let me give an example.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p10" pid="UCbz1HXHB0m2ohXM_dqbcA" hash="ETmzbA">As a young missionary I was assigned to a small island of about 700 inhabitants in a remote area of the South Pacific. To me the heat was oppressive, the mosquitoes were terrible, the mud was everywhere, the language was impossible, and the food was—well, “different.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p11" pid="aCYPIcskzkaEh_loTe-jCg" hash="5B5z1Q">After a few months our island was struck by a powerful hurricane. The devastation was massive. Crops were ruined, lives were lost, housing was blown away, and the telegraph station—our only link to the outside world—was destroyed. A small government boat normally came every month or two, so we rationed our food to last four or five weeks, hoping the boat would come. But no boat came. Every day we became weaker. There were acts of great kindness, but as the sixth and seventh weeks passed with very little food, our strength slipped noticeably. My native companion, Feki, helped me in every way he could, but as the eighth week commenced, I had no energy. I just sat under the shade of a tree and prayed and read scriptures and spent hours and hours pondering the things of eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p12" pid="MLQZRCZ2Tk6y6yPyivioLA" hash="wllmjg">The ninth week began with little outward change. However, there was a great inward change. I felt the Lord’s love more deeply than ever before and learned firsthand that His love “is the most desirable above all things … yea, and the most joyous to the soul” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/11.22-23" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 11:22–23</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p13" pid="guY2zSA0ZkGFU8OgcoNQ4Q" hash="NNbG2w">I was pretty much skin and bones by now. I remember watching, with deep reverence, my heart beating, my lungs breathing, and thinking what a marvelous body God has created to house our equally marvelous spirit! The thought of a permanent union of these two elements, made possible through the Savior’s love, atoning sacrifice, and Resurrection, was so inspiring and satisfying that any physical discomfort faded into oblivion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p14" pid="0Jgs6N0WCkKUlA9qJwTqXA" hash="iW1DZw">When we understand who God is, who we are, how He loves us, and what His plan is for us, fear evaporates. When we get the tiniest glimpse of these truths, our concern over worldly things vanishes. To think we actually fall for Satan’s lies that power, fame, or wealth is important is truly laughable—or would be were it not so sad.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p15" pid="zTEojBPqo0iPWflydzoxeg" hash="ZKEiRw">I learned that just as rockets must overcome the pull of gravity to roar into space, so we must overcome the pull of the world to soar into the eternal realms of understanding and love. I realized my mortal life might end there, but there was no panic. I knew life would continue, and whether here or there didn’t really matter. What did matter was how much love I had in my heart. I knew I needed more! I knew that our joy now and forever is inextricably tied to our capacity to love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p16" pid="x263IsO_o0uBkjv7blthEA" hash="FUeH_w">As these thoughts filled and lifted my soul, I gradually became aware of some excited voices. My companion Feki’s eyes were dancing as he said, “Kolipoki, a boat has arrived, and it is full of food. We are saved! Aren’t you excited?” I wasn’t sure, but since the boat had come, that must be God’s answer, so yes, I was happy. Feki gave me some food and said, “Here, eat.” I hesitated. I looked at the food. I looked at Feki. I looked into the sky and closed my eyes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p17" pid="pKZwQqxm8kWl3fLxEAxIaA" hash="w-pXDA">I felt something very deep. I was grateful my life here would go on as before; still, there was a wistful feeling—a subtle sense of postponement, as when darkness closes the brilliant colors of a perfect sunset and you realize you must wait for another evening to again enjoy such beauty.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p18" pid="NQMLlf2byUearnRfuD1rVg" hash="I9PE0Q">I wasn’t sure I wanted to open my eyes, but when I did I realized that God’s love had changed everything. The heat, the mud, the mosquitoes, the people, the language, the food were no longer challenges. Those who had tried to harm me were no longer my enemies. Everyone was my brother or sister. Being filled with God’s love <span class="emphasis">is</span> the most joyous of all things and is worth every cost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p19" pid="iUCu-O0xsUylHoxG8O5pZg" hash="stzSVw">I thanked God for this choice time and for the many reminders of His love—the sun, the moon, the stars, the earth, the birth of a child, the smile of a friend. I thanked Him for scriptures, for the privilege of prayer, and for that most marvelous reminder of His love—the sacrament.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p20" pid="fQwVpe0LZ0OeMeo9Ac1VLA" hash="lx-Ixw">I learned that as we sing the sacrament hymns with real intent, phrases like “How great the wisdom and the love” or “Dearly, dearly has he loved! And we must love him too” will swell our hearts with love and gratitude (see “How Great the Wisdom and the Love,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 195; “There Is a Green Hill Far Away,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 194). As we sincerely listen to the sacrament prayers, phrases such as “always remember him,” “keep his commandments,” “have his Spirit to be with them” will fill our hearts with an overwhelming desire to be better (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.77,79" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:77, 79</a>). Then when we partake of the bread and the water with a broken heart and a contrite spirit, I know we can feel and even hear those most wondrous words “I love you. I love you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p21" pid="9Umh75fovUGG1FBL6_F-lA" hash="z2ilpg">I thought I would never forget these feelings, but the pull of the world is strong and we tend to slip. But God continues to love us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p22" pid="zbYjt5elmUi6mK3qXgxSXA" hash="ldZmWg">Several months after I regained my strength, we were caught in another violent storm, only this time at sea. The waves became so big they flipped our small boat over, throwing the three of us into the raging, churning ocean. When I found myself in the middle of a tumultuous sea, I was surprised, scared, and a little upset. “Why has this happened?” I thought. “I’m a missionary. Where is my protection? Missionaries aren’t supposed to swim.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p23" pid="ezmHXEpve0qtsd3-LIJJow" hash="8M2eNQ">But swim I must if I wished to stay alive. Every time I complained I found myself underwater, so it didn’t take long to quit complaining. Things are how they are, and complaining doesn’t help. I needed every ounce of energy to keep my head above water and make it to shore. Having earned my Eagle Scout Award, I was a pretty confident swimmer, but over time the wind and the waves began to sap my strength. I never quit trying, but there came a time when my muscles simply would move no more.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p24" pid="36E1k38fpEKOjpH59C5ysg" hash="XVQjIg">I had a prayer in my heart, but still I began to sink. As I was going down for what could have been the last time, the Lord infused into my mind and heart a deep feeling of love for a very special person. It was as though I could see and hear her. Even though she was 8,000 miles away, the power of that love came rushing across those miles and, penetrating time and space, reached down and pulled me up—lifted me from the depths of darkness, despair, and death and brought me up to light and life and hope. With a sudden burst of energy I made it to shore, where I found my shipmates. Never underestimate the power of true love, for it knows no barriers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p25" pid="IarWckC0V06vH3ob1ZKT8g" hash="UaNJuA">When filled with God’s love, we can do and see and understand things that we could not otherwise do or see or understand. Filled with His love, we can endure pain, quell fear, forgive freely, avoid contention, renew strength, and bless and help others in ways surprising even to us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p26" pid="H9q9wgUqfUKF3mMr44yimA" hash="Z4us7g">Jesus Christ was filled with unfathomable love as He endured incomprehensible pain, cruelty, and injustice for us. Through His love for us, He rose above otherwise insurmountable barriers. His love knows no barriers. He invites us to follow Him and partake of His unlimited love so we too may rise above the pain and cruelty and injustice of this world and help and forgive and bless.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love.p27" pid="FsRw1vauAEu53YcWk_i0sQ" hash="aOD9CQ">I know He lives. I know He loves us. I know we can feel His love here and now. I know His voice is one of perfect mildness which penetrates to our very center. I know He smiles and is filled with compassion and love. I know He is full of gentleness, kindness, mercy, and desire to help. I love Him with all my heart. I testify that when we are ready, His pure love instantly moves across time and space, reaches down, and pulls us up from the depths of any tumultuous sea of darkness, sin, sorrow, death, or despair we may find ourselves in and brings us into the light and life and love of eternity. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2004/10/the-power-of-gods-love</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2004-general-conference/2004-10-1030-elder-john-h-groberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="6265971" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2004 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
