<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By John B. Dickson</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by John B. Dickson.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/John%20B.%20Dickson.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by John B. Dickson.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 1992 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Nobody Said That It Would Be Easy</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brethren of the priesthood, it is sincerely a great pleasure to stand before you this evening and share with you the feelings and gratitude that I have, to know that God lives and that he loves us, that Jesus Christ is our Elder Brother and S</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_92911_000_021" doc-version="2" hash="2im3Rw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="BxeMnwGwIUS7qoE0xAgLuQ" hash="uZAuPw">Nobody Said That It Would Be Easy</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="TCi4O8h2tUOFYfxIJo6q5w" hash="VaGLpQ">John B. Dickson</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2104.jpg" alt="Elder John B. Dickson" pid="HD9bbrv0OEuWTE9tOYN-KQ" hash="18bQ0Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy.p1" pid="tWlg_GVk4kugfP-1JkJ45w" hash="EMdsIw">My dear brethren of the priesthood, it is sincerely a great pleasure to stand before you this evening and share with you the feelings and gratitude that I have, to know that God lives and that he loves us, that Jesus Christ is our Elder Brother and Savior, and that there is a prophet on the earth that can authoritatively say, “Thus saith the Lord.” I treat with great reverence and humility the fact that the Lord has called me to serve as a Seventy and to witness to the world that Jesus is the Christ, and I will do my very best to move the work ahead, wherever I am assigned to labor.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy.p2" pid="vutrnb0AMkauHwH_aX9lOg" hash="Pg6cEA">I would like to speak to you about the importance of service in the kingdom of God and the importance of full-time mission service in the lives of our young men and older couples.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy.p3" pid="33S7pjrzzUyjuTZMGzcWiQ" hash="JSBkKQ">Without appearing to be self-serving, I would like to tell you young men of the Aaronic Priesthood a little about my call to a full-time mission. The year was 1962, and a call was received from President David O. McKay to serve in the Mexican Mission. Shortly after receiving the call, I learned that I had bone cancer in my right arm and that the probability of my living many weeks was extremely low. A blessing was received from a wonderful father, wherein he blessed me with my life and that the mission call would be fulfilled, and that I would have a family and be able to serve the Lord all my days.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy.p4" pid="AxfRE4kY2Em2oHgpOD5YCA" hash="W5mwSQ">The doctor congratulated me on being one who had great faith in the Savior but assured me that I didn’t realize the seriousness of what I had. As some of you have noticed, I only have one arm as a result of that problem; but ten months after having my arm amputated, I entered the Mexican Mission, full of excitement and ready to work. You see, young men, I had several years earlier committed to the Lord that I would serve a full-time mission and that I would not let anything stop me from fulfilling that call. Well, brethren, the doctor passed away twenty years ago, always amazed to see me still breathing, and he actually became quite interested in the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy.p5" pid="tPBWT1PgBkm47V9dL7ue3g" hash="WJYGKQ">Brethren, I want you to know that having one arm for nearly thirty years has been one of the greatest blessings of my life. It hasn’t been my greatest challenge, but it has been a great teacher to me, teaching me to be more patient and tolerant with others as I have had to learn to be more patient with myself. It has helped me to understand the necessity of our having challenges in life to help develop our character and stamina, helping us to become what the Lord ultimately wants us to become.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy.p6" pid="BeV1I2skXkCRELlkNRYEXg" hash="vsK12Q">Our challenges may be physical, spiritual, economic, or emotional, but if we will treat them as opportunities and stepping-stones in our progress, rather than barriers and stumbling blocks, our lives and growth will be wonderful. I have learned that between challenges it is very restful but that any real growth that I have ever enjoyed has always come with a challenge.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy.p7" pid="xKh6gAhbWUSWT7BgAry2mg" hash="W_KGsQ">There’s a little poem by an unknown author that we might think about when problems come our way. It is called “The Oyster.”</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="Sb2nslhpFEiw49k4wXDOGQ" hash="28nr8w">
            <span class="emphasis">There once was an oyster</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="b_w4bwRL_0SU9OIx5JF3EA" hash="d5DA6Q">
            <span class="emphasis">Whose story I’ll tell,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="JvDnmJiYr0e7taZ3mJEhdA" hash="BSr-uQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Who found that some sand</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="rxF0Qlhooka6lpNAIOj4sw" hash="UZSKig">
            <span class="emphasis">Had worked under his shell.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="nN0yXY4taECGBFZIPwFWMw" hash="pgRj-A">
            <span class="emphasis">Just one little grain</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="BaJ4CsYffEylPhAt7nta2A" hash="dgsiVw">
            <span class="emphasis">But it gave him a pain,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="7wIrvO6xYk6Hk4-c-_vlmg" hash="vWRJww">
            <span class="emphasis">For oysters have feelings</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="j1iFTMt8sEWV73CgZUzIAA" hash="skWyXw">
            <span class="emphasis">That are very plain.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="88upEK-LHUicKPDGOSBunA" hash="Kau2yw">
            <span class="emphasis">Now did he berate</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="zgXKEIWI-UGAJ0ZTs9R0Cg" hash="m4Zlxw">
            <span class="emphasis">This working of fate,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="NhQEvSBmQkqAj6bZcxl9sg" hash="eW0lig">
            <span class="emphasis">That left him in such a</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="gUXkzniAaE-g_jREQb7wVg" hash="3Q4nRA">
            <span class="emphasis">Deplorable state?</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="dHfC2hdtc0K1zyEFC-GRLQ" hash="FQstkQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Did he curse the government,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="ZQXBqMbuokqs2qUP9kEc-w" hash="6q0QUA">
            <span class="emphasis">Call for an election,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="CjTUrqdcmkOTW93kITSh3g" hash="pDQ6Aw">
            <span class="emphasis">And say that the sea</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="fomaCS0Mu0qlhRJJFMoSbg" hash="oq7jtQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Should have some protection?</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="ZFe8VtLsS0WFFPhaEej3mQ" hash="PzSFbA">
            <span class="emphasis">No! He said to himself</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="v35MqKSNiE69FeqCCaG-iw" hash="GKcv-A">
            <span class="emphasis">As he sat on the shelf,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="aIOJ3HrwdkiaNP1rwIdVxw" hash="lTBCqA">
            <span class="emphasis">“Since I cannot remove it,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="QDCrQEIoBU2Dpmci8foY7A" hash="oWO6iA">
            <span class="emphasis">I think I’ll improve it.”</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="jNx4NpA8cECGpUtrwqikhA" hash="wnZUSg">
            <span class="emphasis">Well, years passed by,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="_5ZdxqRDjUilfCYDDF1glg" hash="s7i4Yg">
            <span class="emphasis">As years always do,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="0xKTvaTCuUistBKISz-FEw" hash="vT5BIw">
            <span class="emphasis">Till he came to his destiny,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Vs95D_eYAEO_oFwiDeVy8Q" hash="11Eplg">
            <span class="emphasis">Oyster stew!</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="28WLJBY070605Cru1UiR8A" hash="fNlJ0A">
            <span class="emphasis">But the small grain of sand</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="TLT7C6yQjES-Pdd17kpd4A" hash="ULjV-g">
            <span class="emphasis">That bothered him so</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="ta_2esILAU6Px40vX5eDLA" hash="xpfePw">
            <span class="emphasis">Was a beautiful pearl</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="GREa4evllU-5cZoctzi-sg" hash="pbxbCw">
            <span class="emphasis">All richly aglow.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="1OdMIOVvK06KyPfUhTrk8w" hash="kmO3bw">
            <span class="emphasis">Now this tale has a moral,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="ilXF9U7MREOlftannvC-lg" hash="qYE3VQ">
            <span class="emphasis">For isn’t it grand,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="lpPPN4JbR0KV-1KgBgpD4A" hash="2cjetw">
            <span class="emphasis">What an oyster can do</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="r_ceXfiI_UmO5IPzWJulYA" hash="NWEvMQ">
            <span class="emphasis">With a small grain of sand?</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="04tT16ZhQkq062mUE5p5wA" hash="h5m0AA">
            <span class="emphasis">And what couldn’t we do</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="vzQQ9_jV9kCZUa6281pDGg" hash="WqXOiw">
            <span class="emphasis">If we’d only begin</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="ldy5fM-wTkWYZ567oCh_oA" hash="cI2Jbw">
            <span class="emphasis">With all of the things</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="hXrBM1pgVkO8oHYYafPThw" hash="Rr6R-w">
            <span class="emphasis">That get under our skin?</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy.p8" pid="3goRQRATUkGLA1sVjw4gdw" hash="IW7QPQ">Young men, how are you going to meet the challenges that face you and that might jeopardize an opportunity to serve? It might be vocational opportunities, a car, a girlfriend, an assorted variety of sins, or a myriad of other reasons. For the older brethren, it might be a yacht, camper, fishing plans, or maybe not wanting to miss some expected weddings and births. Whatever your individual challenges might be, I would invite you this very night to get on your knees and commit to your Heavenly Father that you will not allow anything to stop you from fulfilling that wonderful opportunity to serve a full-time mission. If you haven’t been called, let your bishop know of your desire to serve.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy.p9" pid="EiAMjBIioU65l8A0iBAQ3g" hash="U1_1Dw">When in the twenty-fifth chapter of Matthew the Lord said, “Inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.40" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:40</a>), he was talking about the importance of being of service to our fellowmen if we want to be worthy of his presence. What better way could there be to serve and to sacrifice than to accept a full-time mission call? At the same time, please realize that there are some handicaps and limitations that make other types of local service more practical than serving a full-time mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy.p10" pid="RLb3fmk0pkmVIksRo0KkwQ" hash="6hkpaQ">In the priesthood session of April conference, Elder Neal A. Maxwell said, “Now, my brethren, ‘these are [your] days’ (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/7.9" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 7:9</a>) in the history of the Church.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1992, p. 39.) Yes, my young brethren, these are your days, to be a part of 50,000, 75,000, and 100,000 missionaries serving in the army of the Lord, armed with peace, righteousness, and power.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy.p11" pid="RvPW624cDE6iUL3nUrl4IQ" hash="TtDMgA">While presiding over the Mexico City North Mission in the late seventies, we decided to open the work in an area called the Huasteca, where there was only one Latter-day Saint family in a vast area with several communities and small cities. After two years, there were 500 members of the Church in five branches and an organized district. This was done by a handful of nineteen- and twenty-year-old faithful missionaries and two wonderful couples, who gave of themselves to see that others of Heavenly Father’s children might know and understand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy.p12" pid="PGMaiNy8Dkiiar5EMFAHqA" hash="kYJU9w">After the missionaries had been in the Huasteca for about three weeks, we received a phone call from one of them, and we could tell that he was slightly discouraged, not having yet received any mail, being in a hot area with high humidity, and learning about a culture that was new to all of us. After we had talked for a minute or two, I reminded him that we had talked about the fact that it wouldn’t be easy. He said, “Oh, that’s right, President; that’s right. It wouldn’t be easy. I knew it wouldn’t be easy.” Well, he went ahead with great enthusiasm and concluded his very successful work there and was released to return home. A couple of months later, while he was at BYU, he and some of his former companions called Sister Dickson and me at the mission home in Mexico City at 2:30 in the morning, waking us from a very sound sleep. After a short conversation, I mentioned the fact that it was wonderful to talk with them but that it seemed a little late at night to be calling. He said, “I know, President, but you knew it wouldn’t be easy.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy.p13" pid="wSuLf_kcW0WC48pSGOL7mw" hash="zF1F4Q">Brethren, life is not intended to be easy, but I promise those that labor faithfully in the service of their fellowmen, and with determination handle every challenge properly and under the influence of the Spirit, that they will be blessed with feelings of happiness which will permeate their whole souls, and these, my brethren, are blessings that mold and build us and that can never be taken away.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy.p14" pid="_22pGimMU0-ry0IY4_NDjw" hash="1R4rdA">I leave you with my testimony of the truthfulness of the gospel of the Lord, Jesus Christ and my testimony of the blessings which accompany unselfish service and hard work that is done in his holy name, and I say it in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1992/10/nobody-said-that-it-would-be-easy</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1992-general-conference/1992-10-3040-elder-john-b-dickson-64k-eng.mp3" length="4474042" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 1992 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Introduction to the Church</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We declare that the great restoration that the ancient prophets spoke of began in 1820 when the Lord called a young man named Joseph Smith to reestablish the Church.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10033256_000_034" doc-version="2" hash="eWGhBw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="cPHXvxN-ekieqURt_nU9-A" hash="aunBbQ">A Brief Introduction to the Church</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="mELlTdt9gkaS8Bz9YUFO1g" hash="VaGLpQ">John B. Dickson</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="f-7ev5G7nU-AtNv8iXQkpQ" hash="FPbyFA">We declare that the great restoration that the ancient prophets spoke of began in 1820 when the Lord called a young man named Joseph Smith to reestablish the Church.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1769.jpg" alt="Elder John B. Dickson" pid="u8zjtt2NlUKiMVjRZva7wQ" hash="IwsFig" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p1" pid="na3Yj7pzdUqq3bne3oJrbg" hash="nCA54Q">It is exciting to be with you today in this beautiful Conference Center. I would like to give a brief synopsis of some of our beliefs to those who are learning about the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p2" pid="r5oqHjHn70aK0r8xP47DQA" hash="BX4gsA">The situation of many of you may be like that of my deceased father-in-law, Robert E. Jones, who joined the Church in 1960. He had been raised in a wonderful Christian home, where reading the Bible and adhering to Christian principles were a normal part of family life. At his mother’s knee he learned many truths, including the importance of having faith in Jesus Christ and following His example.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p3" pid="lxm0RcXX_UyCmlhp7Sa5uw" hash="eRxy3A">As he examined The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, he was able to retain truths formerly acquired, while enjoying a rich treasure of additional knowledge. I would like to mention 10 points that he understood that can also help you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p4" pid="n4sctOVvyUyYCZhya-nyRw" hash="y_eYVg">
        <span class="strong">1. God the Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, have a plan of happiness for the human family.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p5" pid="7CfAxz1Yc02lbYSUNzBeXQ" hash="Rzg5dQ">We proclaim that there truly is a God in heaven and that the human family lived with Him in a premortal existence. We are God’s children. He loves us and has prepared a plan whereby through His Son, Jesus Christ, we will enjoy blessings beyond this mortal life. These blessings include an immortal, glorious, resurrected body for all mankind and the opportunity to return to our Heavenly Father’s presence as eternal families for those who have faith in Jesus Christ and are obedient to the conditions of His gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p6" pid="rPeKNPdV00eKOS02Zoe5HQ" hash="JJEG1Q">
        <span class="strong">2. Jesus Christ organized His Church during His mortal ministry.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p7" pid="NMBOESvoPk2PnJwGIdIlwg" hash="w8m33w">The Bible helps us understand that Jesus organized His Church with apostles, prophets, pastors, teachers, and other Church officials who held the priesthood, which is the authority to act in God’s name. Their work was to bring all men to a “unity of the faith” regarding Jesus Christ and His teachings (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/4.13" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 4:13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p8" pid="UNOn_2IfHU-AEJ_QZ9nDZA" hash="uRENsw">
        <span class="strong">3. The Church of Christ and many simple truths were lost.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p9" pid="GKFQcm71PU-sdbVhu0ykcA" hash="Ahodfg">Several Bible prophets declared that there would be a “falling away” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-thes/2.3" class="scriptureRef">2 Thes. 2:3</a>) from the true gospel, a time when there would be a “famine” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/amos/8.11" class="scriptureRef">Amos 8:11</a>) regarding the word of God, and “divisions” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/11.18" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 11:18</a>) caused as “grievous wolves” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/20.29" class="scriptureRef">Acts 20:29</a>) would enter and disrupt the flock or the people of the Church. These prophecies became a reality when in the years following the Savior’s crucifixion, the Apostles were killed, the authority to direct the Church was eventually lost, and for many centuries, including the period known as the Dark Ages, the Church of Jesus Christ was not found on the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p10" pid="-s09hETVaEGy6g03tVeDnw" hash="2b8vRQ">
        <span class="strong">4. The hearts of men and a location were prepared for a restoration of the gospel.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p11" pid="sKnjMWi3pEG1ekqmUMj0Wg" hash="7ipsuQ">The closing of the Dark Ages took place as the Reformation unfolded, where brave men and women recognized the need to incorporate doctrines that Jesus had instituted back into the church. We are grateful for the great reformers such as Luther, Wycliffe, Wesley, Tyndale, and many others who helped set the stage for open religious dialogue, study of the scriptures, and the desire engendered in the hearts of good men and women for an expression of religious liberty. But their faith, their desire, their sacrifice, and even their martyrdom were insufficient to restore that which was lost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p12" pid="zL9EbqovRUSuUFJAAFVfVA" hash="qetRDg">The founding fathers of the United States of America were inspired in drafting a constitution that guarantees religious and other freedoms for all. Religious tolerance and changing attitudes helped prepare a people while the conditions created under the umbrella of the U.S. Constitution prepared a location where the restoration of the gospel could take place.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p13" pid="6UONVB5MHECe5LZoSP5rwA" hash="jo2m8g">
        <span class="strong">5. Latter-day events were anticipated by the prophets of old.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p14" pid="Z8rNJLsju0SrlfjQkSHzwA" hash="a3-ddA">Old Testament prophets spoke of the last days as an era when all the ordinances and blessings of the gospel would be available to man. Daniel, Jeremiah, Joel, Ezekiel, Malachi, and other ancient prophets spoke of the great events that would take place in our day. Isaiah spoke of the marvelous work and a wonder that would come to pass, referring to the promised restoration of the gospel of Jesus Christ (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/29.14" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 29:14</a>). The Apostle Peter spoke of the restitution of all things in the latter days (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/3.21" class="scriptureRef">Acts 3:21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p15" pid="XVTH3iOoS063b23xtnna-Q" hash="j0YWYA">
        <span class="strong">6. The gospel of Jesus Christ has been restored in its fulness.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p16" pid="53lvg6HmxkGowM8g91Indw" hash="W06uRg">We declare that the great restoration that the ancient prophets spoke of began in 1820 when the Lord called a young man named Joseph Smith to reestablish the Church. The Restoration began as Joseph, perplexed by the confusion among the churches of his day, sought to know which church was true. I solemnly declare that, in a sacred grove of trees in upstate New York, this young man was visited by the Father and the Son and was told he was to join none of the existing churches. He learned that he was to be an instrument in the hands of God to again establish the Church of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p17" pid="jrs6xTXbl0CkpXBlETmfsQ" hash="VcC8Zw">In time Joseph received the priesthood of God, giving him the authority to organize the Church once again. The Church now exists with apostles, prophets, and others who have authority to administer the ordinances of the gospel. Since its organization on the sixth of April of 1830, the Church has begun to fill the whole earth, as the ancient prophet Daniel had prophesied (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/dan/2.45" class="scriptureRef">Dan. 2:45</a>). We now find ourselves on the threshold of unprecedented growth where millions are receiving this good news and are joining the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p18" pid="0fkqSOyBCEG3lEzKO6RBaQ" hash="sRV9qw">
        <span class="strong">7. Another witness of Christ has been given to our generation.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p19" pid="_SEj9NHT7E6tEd6_Z26BlQ" hash="y1CuEw">In 1827 Joseph Smith received ancient metal plates from which the Book of Mormon was translated. It contains a history of God’s dealings with His people in ancient America and stands beside the Bible as another witness of Jesus Christ. From its pages we learn more fundamental truths about the nature of God, the mission of His Son, and His plan for His children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p20" pid="_GwNqUQnDkK1dRgrhtLkiA" hash="eUC8dw">
        <span class="strong">8. The family can be eternal.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p21" pid="jgKqN716JEOqNMvO-tOzRw" hash="3Tdtlw">An exciting truth that has been revealed again in our day is that “the family is central to the Creator’s plan for the eternal destiny of His children” and that families can be eternal (“The Family: A Proclamation to the World”). Authority has been conferred upon man once again, whereby in sacred temples a man can be eternally sealed to his wife, a woman to her husband, parents to their children, and the extended family eternally linked together.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p22" pid="Y6SefC0GCEekL6st6qWe_Q" hash="JzRr1Q">Dear friends and neighbors, we know that you love your families as we love ours, and we are pleased to share these sacred truths with you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p23" pid="-Ll4DDm_HE6P0m2hCc-ncw" hash="qx5bzg">
        <span class="strong">9. People have been called of God to teach you.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p24" pid="k4MUiebVD0iFKD_O9fX4iw" hash="ZB8l1w">Approximately 60,000 young men and women on missions worldwide are called to teach interested parties about the doctrine of the Church. They pay their own way and for a time set themselves apart from worldly pursuits in order to teach you. If you will invite them, they will teach you and answer your questions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p25" pid="-hWpe1Zg50C1fZqOmZ29cw" hash="ei2R8Q">
        <span class="strong">10. You can know with assurance that these things are true.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p26" pid="viqhsa9Cq0Wt0fcPz48Ckg" hash="eHgFtQ">A time-tested, heaven-inspired solution to knowing the truth about the Book of Mormon or other matters is set forth by Moroni, the last Book of Mormon prophet. He said: “And when ye shall receive these things, I would exhort you that ye would ask God, the Eternal Father, in the name of Christ, if these things are not true; and if ye shall ask with a sincere heart, with real intent, having faith in Christ, he will manifest the truth of it unto you, by the power of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p27" pid="h-tIdG9OZE-NigzPE9KfGA" hash="oQgxBA">“And by the power of the Holy Ghost ye may know the truth of all things” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.4-5" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:4–5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p28" pid="LHEOAsYgE0-rrfyXGOCtmw" hash="PBqzSw">My father-in-law, myself, and millions of others have put Moroni’s declaration and promise to the test and found that these things are true. My sincere promise is that you can do as Moroni has prompted and experience the same rewarding result.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church.p29" pid="YPVn0ijMEU6T4B6GujeTWw" hash="XlHXgg">I humbly declare that Jesus is the Christ, the literal Son of God, and that His gospel has been restored to the earth in our day for the benefit and blessing of all mankind, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2000/04/a-brief-introduction-to-the-church</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2000-general-conference/2000-04-5050-elder-john-b-dickson-64k-eng.mp3" length="5459481" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2000 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commitment to the Lord</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Now is the time to commit yourself to the Lord as to what you will become during this mortal probation.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008333_000_008" doc-version="2" hash="AjEeRw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="YjdXme0hh0qlpzFSXjL7Hg" hash="P8cyNg">Commitment to the Lord</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="ASHztjCfK0at_Rp_jArbzQ" hash="VaGLpQ">John B. Dickson</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="_IqNBAJutk2YPb-iFQ-qUA" hash="GH71fA">Now is the time to commit yourself to the Lord as to what you will become during this mortal probation.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/DicksonJB_02.jpg" alt="Elder John B. Dickson" pid="VQ5RjboohkaHtjQ83jfDdg" hash="zQv_0A" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord.p1" pid="vNesMx2zOEm7t6IJVEvueg" hash="7gHuww">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="14"></span>Good morning, brothers and sisters. I would like to address the youth of the Church this morning as Sister Dickson and I would counsel our own family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord.p2" pid="Bnv9IQEheU-Jy4AC9ETTqw" hash="uf7QHg">We know that you are an exceptionally bright generation of youth that will soon take our place as leaders in the home, the workplace, the community, and the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord.p3" pid="_aMqlscZ-EmqTaF_JDgZjA" hash="sdZ-uQ">Your Heavenly Father loves each of you and has sent you to earth with a purpose. He has revealed a plan of happiness that, if followed, will ultimately bring you home to His presence, having triumphed over the trials and challenges of this world. Committing yourself now to live by the pattern the Lord has set will give you great strength in the proper use of your moral agency. The sincere commitments you make to yourself and to the Lord will be vital. We learn from the book of Psalms to “commit thy way unto the Lord; … and he shall bring it to pass” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/37.5" class="scriptureRef">Psalm 37:5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord.p4" pid="fzhGdOqpPkibV-Z7ZhLkmA" hash="jp9H_w">You have come into this world at a time that has been anticipated from the beginning—a time prior to the Second Coming of the Lord, in which, on one hand, the gospel of Jesus Christ has been restored in its fulness and, on the other, there is great turmoil, confusion, and wickedness. The proving ground that you were born into is wonderful, affording great opportunities, but at the same time there is danger in abundance, even danger to one’s very soul. Now is the time to commit yourself to the Lord as to what you will become during this mortal probation. Along with your parents, living prophets, and the scriptures, the Holy Ghost will help you distinguish between right and wrong so correct decisions can be made.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord.p5" pid="8MuY-xJ42UWFyV2tU6Tvwg" hash="ehA_Hw">Hopefully you will prayerfully study the pamphlet <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth</span> and review and carry with you, in your wallet or purse, the abbreviated copy of the pamphlet. Great happiness will come to you in this life and eternally if you decide now to live after the pattern that is set forth in its pages.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord.p6" pid="nEXo2ZizqEixOraAhD1sGQ" hash="5UKNNw">Let me help you understand how this pattern of making early commitments can help you by relating the experience of one Church leader. As a young man he decided that he would always keep the Word of Wisdom and never use alcohol or tobacco. He does not remember what prompted him to make that important commitment at the time, but a crucial victory was won in his heart, and on his knees he made a commitment with the Lord to always keep that commandment. Over the years there were invitations to use these substances, but he learned that “no, thank you” was a good answer. There was no personal battle over the Word of Wisdom because years before he had made a commitment in his heart, and he had sincerely made a commitment to the Lord to obey that law.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord.p7" pid="rtnloJYLvUWsXF5Cp5SyHA" hash="w18oVQ">As you seek to receive Heavenly Father’s blessings regarding the Word of Wisdom, include a commitment to never touch the illegal drugs that are prevalent in today’s society. The adversary will have very little power to tempt you with things that you have never touched.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord.p8" pid="2dtgNOhr10ukbFvjp37EKA" hash="hwWlcQ">As members of the Church we have been baptized and have made a covenant to take upon us the name of Jesus Christ and keep God’s commandments. If mistakes are made, the gospel allows us to sincerely repent and be forgiven. Your commitment can begin from where you are presently, whether young or old, including repenting and forsaking sin where mistakes have already been made.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord.p9" pid="RE_8FHkDzEa7R4Fw1n6h5g" hash="b6N4EQ">The Lord promises great, eternal blessings to His righteous, repentant children, but knowing there is great danger here in this life, He has commanded us, saying, “Beware concerning yourselves, to give diligent heed to the words of eternal life” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.43" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:43</a>). Because He loves us and wants us back, this commandment <span class="pageBreak" page-number="15"></span>to “beware concerning [ourselves]” prompts us to be careful concerning everything about us—the type of social settings we enter, what we see and read, the media and entertainment we choose, the music we listen to, and more.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord.p10" pid="56hUar8Dt0aoayIFTV90ug" hash="EGtD1g">Setting a pattern of early commitment is very important. For example, to receive the blessings promised to those who pay tithes and offerings, you should commit now to pay tithing on all earnings. Paying tithing helps us become less selfish and more like our Heavenly Father, who wants to share all that He has with His righteous children. Making that decision will be extremely important. It is interesting to note that, like tithing, every commandment is designed for your eternal happiness and to help you become more like your Father in Heaven. Decide now to be like Nephi of old, who was absolutely determined to “go and do the things which the Lord [had] commanded” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 3:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord.p11" pid="ewKFuV6WU022Lit_UnKXqA" hash="zLJNpg">Let us now consider other commitments that will bless your lives. Wouldn’t it be wonderful if, in spite of what others at school might be doing, from this moment forward you would be known for your absolute integrity and clean language? Decide now that you will never cheat; that your language will be pure; that as long as you live, vulgar words or jokes will never come from your lips. These are commitments you can make in the quiet of your room and upon your knees. Success will come to you as you earnestly, prayerfully, and humbly approach the Lord. The scriptures teach, “Be thou humble; and the Lord thy God shall lead thee by the hand, and give thee answer to thy prayers” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/112.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 112:10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord.p12" pid="ZCtEIeSL-Ue6VouS-qh9vA" hash="iu9JsQ">You would also want to make commitments regarding modesty of dress and how to act while dating. Keeping the Lord’s standards is always easier when you have already determined how you will act when faced with decisions in the presence of a date, friends, or peers. Some individuals may not understand your standards as you follow righteous principles and keep your commitments, but they will truly respect and admire you and wish that they were more like you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord.p13" pid="HSU92E-TdEaFXacE1T_ISg" hash="fGqOyw">Other standards to ponder and commit to are absolute moral cleanliness and sexual purity, Sabbath observance, preparation for missions and the temple, and a determination to always partake of the sacrament worthily.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord.p14" pid="dt0W2PP9PE2-CpMmoxVRXw" hash="e4ga6Q">President Hinckley loves the youth and has constantly encouraged you to follow the standards the Lord has set. Following a living prophet’s encouragement and counsel will lead you on a path to eternal or everlasting happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord.p15" pid="hBBPkJdNWEa7yjQ4CMycjg" hash="fcYGIw">As you commit now to do the will of the Lord, He will help and strengthen you. Your faith, trust, and desire to follow Him will be your greatest key to success. I know our Heavenly Father loves each of you and that He truly sent His Only Begotten Son to help you and that you can gloriously succeed as you sincerely commit to follow Him. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/04/commitment-to-the-lord</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2007-general-conference/2007-04-1060-elder-john-b-dickson-64k-eng.mp3" length="3846727" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2007 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gospel to All the World</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Church has moved steadily across the world from nation to nation, culture to culture, people to people, on the Lord’s calendar and in His time.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10785_000_27dickson" doc-version="2" hash="vGuwXQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="-Ucg1oObKESEe_QrlQDVdA" hash="0KIXGQ">The Gospel to All the World</h1><p class="authorName" pid="6-YSBvT3sUOPvRQ-nsb-cA" hash="Cb6J3g">By Elder John B. Dickson</p><p class="kicker" pid="4jIIIomCtkecDQif8fFhxg" hash="dfKjvQ">The Church has moved steadily across the world from nation to nation, culture to culture, people to people, on the Lord’s calendar and in His time.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" pid="KpFDAHzSgEKOC9pffwxvYQ" hash="aO5-Ww">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p5" pid="zydSSODtWEK--cNuKsNRqw" hash="Gy0rsA"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="39"></span>The Savior’s mortal ministry was complete. His suffering in Gethsemane and on the cross was over. We learn from Acts 1 that He had ministered for 40 days after His Resurrection, “being seen” of the Apostles and “speaking of … things pertaining to the kingdom of God” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/1.3" class="scriptureRef">Acts 1:3</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p6" pid="fOwGu7ht00Kbp0O50O4RUg" hash="sbICYA">He told them that “ye shall receive power, after that the Holy Ghost is come upon you: and ye shall be witnesses unto me both in Jerusalem, and in all Judaea, and in Samaria, and unto the uttermost part of the earth” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/1.8" class="scriptureRef">Acts 1:8</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p7" pid="ZMfP4E0w1Eu9s5WlWUJIIw" hash="n6HQEw">Shortly thereafter, “he was taken up; and a cloud received him out of their sight.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p8" pid="feRPW-KCF0Gt-g5EyZyrrw" hash="tehi_g">“And while they looked steadfastly toward heaven as he went up, behold, two men stood by them in white apparel;</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p9" pid="dWGTjDiqz0CNzJb-6JDeEw" hash="k82nlQ">“Which also said, Ye men of Galilee, why stand ye gazing up into heaven? this same Jesus, which is taken up from you into heaven, shall so come in like manner as ye have seen him go into heaven” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/1.9-11" class="scriptureRef">Acts 1:9–11</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p10" pid="1PuJbhJy10uHGtGd1z5NJw" hash="gjb-JQ">Indeed, the Savior would come again in His Second Coming, but in the meantime, the gospel of Jesus Christ was to go to “the uttermost part of the earth.”</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p11" pid="crvwAqZDC0-cipFNk8AVEg" hash="E8Jcyw">From Matthew we learn of a special mandate to the Apostles to take the gospel to all nations:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p12" pid="yMILo6jkvkGS8048Q_RE_A" hash="-vhRDw">“And Jesus came and spake unto them, saying, All power is given unto me in heaven and in earth.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p13" pid="-IcwPoZdskqo-HCMu0NycQ" hash="2PrsLw">“Go ye therefore, and teach all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/28.18-19" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 28:18–19</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p14" pid="add7HkzptUCXZt3iQtJT1Q" hash="YN6E6A">During the early days of the Church, in the meridian of time, the gospel was taken to the house of Israel only; then revelation came to Peter, the senior Apostle, that the time had come to take the gospel beyond Israel and unto the Gentiles. The 10th and 11th chapters of Acts help us understand the process and pattern whereby this needed expansion of the Church to more of God’s children was made known to its presiding officers and the general membership.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p15" pid="zgaFOZzhoUGRjqYldIOhXw" hash="v9TFGA">Using Cornelius, who was a Gentile, a centurion, and a good man, the Lord impressed upon Peter that the gospel would go to the Gentiles, a concept new and foreign to the Saints of that day. The revelation making that change in the affairs of the Church came to Peter, the senior Apostle. We know that the gospel then went rapidly to the nations of the Gentiles.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p16" pid="H684lGNRZUm0Iby09Akg-w" hash="leHSoA">An example of the expansion of the Church at that time was the conversion of Paul, who became the great Apostle to the Gentiles. He had a vision while on the road to Damascus, where he saw a light and heard a voice, repented of his sins, and was called of God (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/22.6-18" class="scriptureRef">Acts 22:6–18</a>) and then became a tremendous force in spreading the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p17" pid="qirg8earTUm4HgWraBBzJg" hash="nMr_Pw">Now let us move 1,800 years forward to the time of the Restoration of the gospel, or the restitution of all things prior to the Second Coming. I testify that through the Prophet Joseph Smith, the Church has been restored and continues to move forward under the direction of the First Presidency and the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles. Their mandate to take the gospel to the world is the same as that of the Apostles of old.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p18" pid="x6bsgnNwrEKANqHsO7X7Zw" hash="_Y8g0g">From the time of the organization of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints in 1830, the Church has moved steadily across the world from nation to nation, culture to culture, people to people, on the Lord’s calendar and in His time.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p19" pid="XNeFQc85REWwCP6ZzWSVtA" hash="MnwlUw">In 1978, following the established pattern of revelation through the senior Apostle, President Spencer W. Kimball, came a revelation, this time on extending priesthood blessings to all worthy males across the world. This means that in our day all of Heavenly Father’s children worldwide can partake of all of the blessings of <span class="pageBreak" page-number="40"></span>the restored gospel. How appropriate to the kingdom of God on earth in the days approaching Christ’s Second Coming.</p>
				<span class="story">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p20" pid="_zcUh6LTn0Kn6rMCc3sbgA" hash="4d7Dpg">On a personal note, I had just been called as a mission president and Sister Dickson and I were about to take our family to Mexico when Elder Richard G. Scott, at the time a member of the Seventy, told me of the coming forth of this special revelation. I remember tears coming to my eyes as he related to me what had happened. I was pleased beyond words, as I knew it was right and that the time had come for all mankind to have access to all of the ordinances, covenants, and blessings of the gospel.</p>
				</span>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p21" pid="5DdX9e9sgkaiNIkUPLHl-w" hash="2_CCXQ">That was almost 35 years ago, and little did I know at the time that I would spend several years of my ministry in the Seventy in the Africa West Area of the Church, among a believing, faithful people whose lives would be so affected by the 1978 revelation on priesthood. Sister Dickson and I have lived there for four years, and the experience has been wonderful and life changing for us.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p22" pid="8XQrh_jw_0yLNqRTQiJJ2A" hash="RTpQoQ">As a people, West Africans believe in God, have absolutely no shame in declaring and sharing their belief with others, and have tremendous leadership capacity. They are coming into the Church by the hundreds, and every week or so a couple of wards or branches are created somewhere in the Africa West Area with, in nearly every case, all-African priesthood and auxiliary leadership.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p23" pid="YzqNS_gfs0y1DynsIT2n_A" hash="fF7tLw">How I wish you could join the Saints in the temple in Aba, Nigeria, or Accra, Ghana, where you would sense the commitment of the Saints and come to know the all-African temple presidencies. Or how I wish I could introduce you to the African Area Seventies, who are assembled with us here in the Conference Center today and are attorneys, professors, and business managers, or have you become acquainted with the African stake and ward leaders and their families.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p24" pid="mId0a59jsEW-99_qLh1l-w" hash="oST5ig">Across Africa, to join a Sunday School, auxiliary, or priesthood class is a sacred experience, where the Church curriculum is followed and there is great gospel understanding, teaching, and learning by the Spirit.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p25" pid="NDLxTrTfg0GuteBMQNWBCg" hash="p6lxRA">The gospel in Africa is going to a happy people, very unencumbered by the trappings that affect the lives of many in the West. They are not concerned about having endless material possessions.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p26" pid="KU6zn3VXlUuP74tUlzJLnQ" hash="1GGRUg">It has been said of Africans that they have very little of that which matters least and a great deal of that which matters most. They have little interest in enormous homes and the finest cars but great interest in knowing their Heavenly Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, and in having eternal families. As a natural result of their faith, the Lord is lifting them in meaningful ways.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p27" pid="Yey6Y3gO50ixTcfOO7yJ0A" hash="fk71Gg"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="41"></span>Knowing them as we do, we are not surprised that they would be such an important part of the expansion of the Church of Jesus Christ in the last days. Given that Daniel, the Old Testament prophet, envisioned the kingdom of God in the last days “roll[ing] forth unto the ends of the earth, as [a] stone which is cut out of the mountain without hands [would] roll forth, until it [had] filled the whole earth” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/65.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 65:2</a>), it is very fitting that our wonderful African brothers and sisters would be an important part of the fulfillment of that prophecy and that the revelations making it so would follow the Lord’s established patterns.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world.p28" pid="8LhsohtAHUSJClbLiSHeaw" hash="6ETetw">I testify that our Heavenly Father loves all of His children, that Jesus is the Christ, and that the gospel is available to all, both the living and the dead. In the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2013/04/the-gospel-to-all-the-world</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2013-general-conference/2013-04-2070-elder-john-b-dickson-64k-eng.mp3" length="4356771" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
