<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By John H. Vandenberg</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by John H. Vandenberg.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/John%20H.%20Vandenberg.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by John H. Vandenberg.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1971 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1971 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>My Brother’s Keeper</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper?lang=eng</link>
      <description>A young mother, having had the trying experience of losing a little child in an accident, came to a church leader for a blessing to comfort her in her grief. As she left, she asked through her tears, “Must there always be pain in this life?”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03006_000_4020" doc-version="2" hash="4fvfiA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="9g1xsY3Ik0a6G9sy-U9O9Q" hash="2ylqVg">My Brother’s Keeper</h1><p class="authorName" guid="a8f5128c-8278-4a4e-bac6-29cbf1c2c3f7" pid="_EEMP5gFv0qfYjcEPWuzkg" hash="BFZRqQ">John H. Vandenberg</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="150913e7-e997-478a-bed3-32c053d0ad58">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-244c.jpg" alt="Bishop John H. Vandenberg" guid="fb3067c8-4e87-497b-bc6b-eeeb8909402c" pid="cRsSRoEXh0-JQQHtEa7MUA" hash="nQf8sQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p1" guid="7195580b-3d3f-410a-863b-c7b5da47308b" pid="ti0tyi_wYEKNrgx5URBLSw" hash="JhMGyQ">A young mother, having had the trying experience of losing a little child in an accident, came to a church leader for a blessing to comfort her in her grief. As she left, she asked through her tears, “Must there always be pain in this life?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p2" guid="2d6b40fc-e83a-4890-a443-70af7f83fc43" pid="D9bIhSroC0WYOCi3AXnEHQ" hash="bG7rLw">As we consider this question, let us recall the first family on earth. We read in the Bible that Eve “conceived, and bare Cain, and said, I have gotten a man from the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p3" guid="fd3fcc22-47a9-44b0-9a85-58aad6211002" pid="ZMCaTAcye0uL3RC00Us59A" hash="YGdPfA">“And she again bare his brother Abel. And Abel was a keeper of sheep, but Cain was a tiller of the ground.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p4" guid="b43e8d09-fdd5-4efb-8b6c-5ae36d4ea83b" pid="boLzYAk0H0i5yPy9N3mghA" hash="GvU9uA">And in the process of time Cain became wroth because the Lord had respect unto Abel’s offering of the firstlings of his flock, but unto Cain’s offering of the fruit of the ground he had not respect.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p5" guid="2ac62f22-e893-4266-986b-31e529a7ba6e" pid="AUVMTesZ5EK4OlCynlvsng" hash="e3jzyA">“And Cain talked with Abel, his brother: and it came to pass, when they were in the field, that Cain rose up against Abel his brother, and slew him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p6" guid="29f2ead4-570b-42fd-8b5c-0837f6094ab2" pid="wjjOdQj1w0GYA032kJXQmA" hash="p6IcrQ">“And the Lord said unto Cain, Where is Abel thy brother? And he said, I know not: Am I my brother’s keeper?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p7" guid="aa6bda21-b2c5-460d-8401-0fcfbe8d4e24" pid="hqScTXansEy6wt9A3q8F3g" hash="DQxSWA">“And [the Lord] said, What hast thou done? the voice of thy brother’s blood crieth unto me from the ground.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/4.1-10" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 4:1–10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p8" guid="60cc729d-6da3-4c55-81d9-17046c486460" pid="tnZpqQWxikS4tLjxTLUEJw" hash="jB9RxA">Pain, sorrow, and tragedy trave been with the human race ever since this event. Yet from this episode in the scriptures there is brought to our attention the question, “Am I my brother’s keeper?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p9" guid="e3769693-92d6-4906-9a9f-da4d6c1dfd8b" pid="XrFFGAq7q0yOMYR2BedVWg" hash="8nT5oQ">What do we think about that question? What charge has the Lord given us relating to it? Let us refer to 1 John, chapter 3:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p10" guid="8dced534-ade4-450d-873a-ea247998409b" pid="fCAK6_q34k2lnThYsW1k1w" hash="z3hgOQ">“For this is the message that ye heard from the beginning, that we should love one another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p11" guid="659eb139-fc69-4154-8857-7bcf3324d3aa" pid="sYF_IV_umUC7GnKw6g26Mg" hash="ZwbTcA">“We know that we have passed from death unto life, because we love the brethren. He that loveth not his brother abideth in death.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p12" guid="fdb75993-b461-4f5e-ad13-b2daac0fcfc5" pid="Xf2fpCqaL02NGLvPunsJwA" hash="P6lE-A">“Hereby perceive we the love of God, because he laid down his life for us: and we ought to lay down our lives for the brethren.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p13" guid="370e78bf-8601-470d-bf41-639855e28ea1" pid="ju1dLYg70EWMPDx3GfbD-g" hash="Grhmkw">“My little children, let us not love in word, neither in tongue; but in deed and in truth.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-jn/3.11,14,16,18" class="scriptureRef">1 Jn. 3:11, 14, 16, 18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p14" guid="1a3b899f-f60a-42c1-b226-eb6785cfaae4" pid="_U1UkfNvT0C6zIsCxHBFcQ" hash="aM5t7Q">What is the seed of mother love? Is it not sacrifice? Such love is considered to be the deepest and most tender. Is this because a mother passes through the valley of the shadow of death to give birth to her child and is continually sacrificing for that child’s welfare?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p15" guid="0ed677e7-1eb4-4f39-81e9-327c1d97cf17" pid="OSJ0kvnskUGjMQFCWCxoHA" hash="8g3XHg">Is this why Christ loves the world? Because he toiled to make it? Because he sacrificed his life for the world and its people? We are told that “God so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.16" class="scriptureRef">John 3:16</a>) to save it from ruin, and the Son was willing to suffer for the salvation of that for which he had toiled.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p16" guid="13a3a3ce-79e6-453c-8f29-32265788a064" pid="UW1rJEhJeEGXbwbKDNrw9A" hash="W9ChGQ">We all love that for which we sacrifice. Giving and serving to the point of sacrifice creates love. The term <span class="emphasis">religion </span>encompasses concern for our brethren, as we are told in James 1:27: “Pure religion and undefiled before God and the Father is this, To visit the fatherless and widows in their affliction. …” [<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.27" class="scriptureRef">James 1:27</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p17" guid="d53da782-e482-4a42-8dd4-c1f7ad332124" pid="YwezS8MN0EubU25NtlFgvw" hash="4my7Mw">When people say, “Religion is all right for some, but I am not religious, and it means nothing to me,” is it because they have not experienced the uplift that comes from sacrificing for and serving their fellowmen?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p18" guid="d69a0c63-284a-41e2-b0cb-c32313ec3c49" pid="kqa_UMLlk0y0M5XDK7-2lw" hash="70Vq0Q">Perhaps they have simply not recognized the needs of their neighbors. Everyone has a need. Man does not stand alone. Edwin Markham puts the basic needs of man before us clearly and simply in these words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p19" guid="bc700e6d-0816-4a9b-af42-a3d3fcef5ff4" pid="LSosQ3r_pU2zKcDIzOedoA" hash="B0DOTw">“Three things must a man possess if his soul would live and know life’s perfect good—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p20" guid="5425d960-a7fa-4ba7-941e-df3763f17b67" pid="ZnqtMJLRsUuMuCoaentxjg" hash="2oHpJg">“Three things would the all-supplying Father give—bread, beauty and brotherhood.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p21" guid="407f2501-ee94-47c9-8f05-535c77c3d055" pid="TKezhv-6oEmxiHGo1MemCA" hash="MWTRlA">Truly our Father in heaven has made it possible for us to receive our daily bread, for he said, referring to the keeping of his commandments:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p22" guid="d145c21b-1eed-470a-bc32-af54705b7231" pid="9re1skuHGUu8Sb7SyLOqkw" hash="J6Nm6w">“Verily I say, that inasmuch as ye do this, the fulness of the earth is yours, the beasts of the field and the fowls of the air, and that which climbeth upon the trees and walketh upon the earth;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p23" guid="87cac6bd-d5db-4644-acae-8be10dfb49ca" pid="-p7iHCIFoEmYnpmJ3dejAQ" hash="sTNoMg">“… whether for food or for raiment, or for houses, or for barns, or for orchards, or for gardens, or for vineyards;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p24" guid="aab0ae14-3a35-4768-91f9-7f1e9fe9fb21" pid="kKz2tyyq5E6rO1digAA__A" hash="g1Q2zg">“Yea, all things which come of the earth, in the season thereof, are made for the benefit and the use of man, both to please the eye and to gladden the heart;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p25" guid="bbcc976c-e079-40ef-8b45-1bf46a850c3f" pid="WVCUwSJuEUi1Fjuv6PeWMQ" hash="wOAm6A">“Yea, for food and for raiment, for taste and for smell, to strengthen the body and to enliven the soul.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p26" guid="7ce1e993-4a08-43c4-8c51-c7263361239a" pid="b8VZlqEMIUOcEPpHtCwtnQ" hash="gdduJg">“And it pleaseth God that he hath given all these things unto man. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p27" guid="da62445c-0245-477f-8130-286ff4188e51" pid="Ow67jMGJPEiiFjwTD4e5PQ" hash="vOKVBw">“And in nothing doth man offend God, or against none is his wrath kindled, save those who confess not his hand in all things, and obey not his commandments.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.16-21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:16–21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p28" guid="e7b68650-def2-4caa-9844-02f3fb364ff2" pid="HtMAjoANJ0qRwvKkYZiVrA" hash="ZhoY0Q">Since God has been so good to us, he has asked us to be good to our brethren who may not be so fortunate as we, for he has admonished us: “And behold, thou wilt remember the poor, and consecrate of thy properties for their support that which thou hast to impart unto them. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p29" guid="c0fc8907-8bf7-44ad-b59c-2f545af29be3" pid="O_z5XrNEI0Gy0WGIgZMvwQ" hash="M9wGeg">“And inasmuch as ye impart of your substance unto the poor, ye will do it unto me; and they shall be laid before the bishop of my church. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.30-31" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:30–31</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p30" guid="9de88c4b-e3eb-4fd9-b419-ae51fd198e6e" pid="V18femQdVUS7gUw4ZuM5FQ" hash="wnIVDA">This commandment of providing for our needy brethren is found in the principle of fasting, as we read in the <span class="emphasis">Documentary History of the Church:</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p31" guid="ccf40506-c1f7-4f60-bd17-674503cbb1d9" pid="bHjUcKbAHEGHnjDbl2tRMA" hash="_glEVA">“Let this be an ensample to all saints, and there will never be any lack for bread: When the poor are starving, let those who have, fast one day and give what they otherwise would have eaten to the bishops for the poor, and every one will abound for a long time; and this is one great and important principle of fasts, approved of the Lord. And so long as the saints will all live to this principle with glad hearts and cheerful countenances they will always have an abundance.” (Vol. 7, p. 413.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p32" guid="a1cf46d4-6ed6-4f94-9928-e80648b7fb86" pid="Fn06aZX7l0-Q4J6kg8UXwg" hash="bno0yw">Brigham Young addressed the Saints as follows:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p33" guid="93c2d316-afee-4a8f-a208-a598492b650a" pid="PqIXz05h9U6u3goh6jyBLg" hash="B-MZ6A">“You know that the first Thursday<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_*">*</span> in each month we hold as a fast day. How many here know the origin of this day? Before tithing was paid, the poor were supported by donations. They came to Joseph and wanted help, in Kirtland, and he said there should be a fast day, which was decided upon. It was to be held once a month, as it is now, and all that would have been eaten that day, of flour, or meat, or fruit, or anything else, was to be carried to the fast meeting and put into the hands of a person selected for the purpose of taking care of it and distributing it among the poor. If we were to do this now faithfully, do you think the poor would lack for flour, or butter, or cheese, or meat, or sugar, or anything they needed to eat? No, there would be more than could be used by all the poor among us. It is economy in us to take this course, and do better by our poor brethren and sisters than they have hitherto been done by. Let this be published in our newspapers. Let it be sent forth to the people that on the first Thursday of each month, the fast day, all that would be eaten by husbands and wives and children and servants should be put in the hands of the Bishop for the sustenance of the poor. I am willing to do my share as well as the rest, and if there are no poor in my ward, I am willing to divide with those wards where there are poor. If the sisters will look out for rooms for those sisters who need to be taken care of, and see them provided for, you will find that we will possess more comfort and more peace in our hearts, and our spirits will be buoyant and light, full of joy and peace. The Bishops should, through their teachers, see that every family in their wards who is able, should donate what they would naturally consume on fast day to the poor.” (<span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses, </span>vol. 12, pp. 115–16.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p34" guid="58fc7867-d0c6-4c56-878c-1ceb6bbde088" pid="8R2FIj3glk-eRapY4FwqeA" hash="8AMfvA">I encourage the bishops to hold this principle before their people today in order that we may more fully supply the essential bread and other needs of our brethren who are in unfortunate circumstances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p35" guid="0e622591-c16c-4a62-9a99-e6c4f719a337" pid="lW0SjLgHSUWo80-sbOl-Ag" hash="e7-Zqg">Edwin Markham, you remember, said that our all-supplying Father would give us not only bread, but also beauty and brotherhood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p36" guid="2ff17a16-34ca-4894-be2b-87e569a415e4" pid="NaqPAKt9PUCr59aX432UYg" hash="atrMKQ">Has the Lord supplied mankind with beauty? Anyone who doubts it need only to open his eyes to the sunrise and the sunset and his ears to the sound of rain and wind, to marvel at the colors of the flowers and the rainbow, to perceive the variety in the scenery of the desert and the forest, the fields of grain, the mountains, rivers, and oceans. At this time of year we are beginning to thrill with the new life of springtime, and as we loose ourselves in the teeming life about us, we become a part of it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p37" guid="d90037e4-129b-422c-bbf3-67bc283dac0d" pid="70GeH2tsMEChpx2bikOpwA" hash="NDlL6Q">All the earth, with no sterility in it, gladdens the heart. In our concern as our brother’s keeper, we can help one another understand the gift of beauty which is ours. Let us take the time to see and to feel and to enjoy all that God has created for us. Margaret L. White brings this responsibility to our minds as we follow her words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p38" guid="b152ddda-1f19-4f3c-88dc-902e3a6dd1fd" pid="Vtwg1fw0yEef8ZtVIRVkgA" hash="NK98rQ">“I took a little child’s hand to lead him to the Father. My heart was full of gratitude for the glad privilege. We walked slowly. I suited my steps to the short steps of the child. We spoke of the things the child noticed. Sometimes we picked the Father’s flowers and stroked their soft petals and loved their bright colors. Sometimes it was one of the Father’s birds. We watched it build its nest. We saw the eggs that were laid. We wondered, elated at the care it gave its young. Often we told stories of the Father. I told them to the child, and the child told them again to me. We told them, the child and I, over and over again. Sometimes we stopped to rest, leaning against one of the Father’s trees, and letting his cool air cool our brows, and never speaking. And then, in the twilight, we met the Father. The child’s eyes shone. He looked lovingly, trustingly, eagerly up to the Father’s face. He put his hand into the Father’s hand. I was for the moment forgotten. I was content.” (Lucy Gertsch, comp., <span class="emphasis">Minute Masterpieces </span>[Bookcraft, 1953], p. 99.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p39" guid="8910d450-6ea0-4c08-be7f-f874753393ed" pid="XSTGsXOJSE6WYd7RmNkAQQ" hash="NZm9kw">Beauty—a gift of the all-supplying Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p40" guid="8b35a4c2-ebc4-4021-acfc-c1a0157495b7" pid="nHzY0aOACEOJNJKqwPRm7g" hash="R_qSyw">What of brotherhood, the third need of man—perhaps the greatest need? Surely in this modern world, where hate and envy seem to abound, the call to “love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind” and to “love thy neighbour as thyself” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.37,39" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:37, 39</a>) is essential if peace is ever to be found.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p41" guid="0a447e0c-10fb-448d-bbfd-54ceb739c6b4" pid="wsX-VJ-L6ku-7l4J5b32EA" hash="FPii9A">It seems that man knows no bounds to the physical conveniences he can produce. We boast how our knowledge is expanding as new discoveries are made which open up the materialistic world. Yet progress in solving the problem of how to live with our brethren seems so slow in comparison.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p42" guid="06080efc-8592-4557-a32d-d8241a7c216d" pid="uTxopUv4yUGtH20e8Jui1A" hash="WL2Znw">One of many stories to be found in the scriptures relating to love of brethren is that of the book of Esther, the story of the beautiful Jewess who found favor with the king and became queen. Haman, who had been set above all the princes, became wroth when Mordecai, the uncle of Esther, refused to bow down to him, and made a plan to destroy all the Jews. Mordecai, having heard the proclamation of death, sent word to Queen Esther to “charge her that she should go in unto the king, to make supplication unto him, and to make request before him for her people.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p43" guid="db02d289-16b2-46f2-89e2-759adfa97ca6" pid="zqLc2fYhZkmTUCo9GzD3XA" hash="jySvUQ">Esther explained the law and replied “that whosoever, whether man or woman, shall come unto the king into the inner court, who is not called … put him to death, except such to whom the king shall hold out the golden sceptre, that he may live: but I have not been called to come in unto the king these thirty days.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p44" guid="a81c46e8-ba26-4d27-b02b-b8bdf02ff64b" pid="xPdnqfEVgESjgR_unfB9yA" hash="TiwshA">Mordecai replied, “… thou and thy father’s house shall be destroyed.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p45" guid="e492a78f-4fe6-42d1-8068-df8a514577c1" pid="XoT4gUntK06icDBeBozyEA" hash="zMW0pw">At this, Esther realized her responsibility for her brethren and answered, “Go, gather together all the Jews that are present in Shushan, and fast ye for me, and neither eat nor drink three days, night or day: I also and my maidens will fast likewise; and so I will go in unto the king, which is not according to the law: and if I perish, I perish.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/esth/4.8,11,14,16" class="scriptureRef">Esth. 4:8, 11, 14, 16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p46" guid="562ee334-691e-49a1-8ab3-e7342d66bb58" pid="FTWbkttuL06sPI7n7tNXVQ" hash="-t0J-A">As a result of this decision to put the matter into the hands of the Lord, Esther was able to perform this great service for her brethren and save them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p47" guid="ab3b1aa5-b46e-455e-843f-9f4b3c93d51e" pid="V2EI67fbjkabTCpXAjzF1g" hash="RhWdig">Our brethren are with us constantly, and we must not only be mindful of them, but also of the stranger in our midst. Let us be reminded of this obligation by these words of Burton Hillis:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p48" guid="c45ade9b-e553-4292-bcac-4f189069da35" pid="sj_jETHU9UqzyAcRdN0MrA" hash="w1TxjQ">“If there is a stranger in your neighborhood today, better check up on him. He may need a friend. If he is still a stranger tomorrow, better check up on your neighborhood.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p49" guid="0bea1b38-d2db-4cdf-80a8-b5a0c47abcfc" pid="1_T_Jqx7NE-hpYOUmMreuQ" hash="xHGmlg">An example of brotherhood in action occurred a few weeks ago in the San Fernando Valley in California. The major jolt of the earthquake was at six o’clock in the morning; but home teachers, Relief Society leaders, and priesthood quorums almost immediately began to do their part in helping hundreds who were evacuated from their homes. Many of these families found refuge in the homes of Church members.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p50" guid="a9534ce5-0b98-417c-b478-b2596141eee5" pid="DBm-xrpX9kKPjQ9P6EYwLg" hash="9TrI-w">Within thirty minutes a pair of home teachers stopped by their bishop’s home to check for special instructions before making a quick survey of their assigned families. Other home teachers called priesthood leaders, who in turn reported to bishops, and bishops reported to stake presidents. Within six hours after the first jolt, some wards could account for most of their members.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p51" guid="c11ca041-2044-4db5-a0fd-276592a0013b" pid="H4K6W6x9R0OjEqqhOgvReA" hash="bSuuYQ">Stake presidents attempted to pinpoint the hardest hit areas and offer assistance where it was most needed. A priests quorum in Granada Hills moved a family with seven children to another home. A first counselor in the bishopric woke up as his chimney toppled onto his roof, breaking through some of the rafters and knocking a hole in his ceiling; but he said, “I wasn’t as concerned about that as I was my neighbor’s home, which immediately caught fire. No one had any water, so we got up on our roofs to beat out sparks.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p52" guid="afabd2d1-9ce3-4209-b8dd-9995e94d1d4e" pid="C03IRmijhEe7mq_jPliaaQ" hash="2MmhVg">A bishop who was on his way to work when the quake struck was concerned about being unable to contact his home or ward members for several hours. But in his absence the priesthood members had gone into action, and by early afternoon every family in the ward had been contacted. His wife reported that as soon as the telephone was restored to order, she had constant calls from families offering to take evacuated people into their homes. “People have been great,” she reported. “It renews your faith the way they pitch in when the chips are down.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p53" guid="d4da9103-1f31-4d96-8f04-b091f59b4647" pid="7evW7NoP-kGvOH-aIgzyrw" hash="vGuxWg">The chips are down someplace every day, although not always so drastically. The Lord knows that we need one another, and for that reason he has made us brothers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper.p54" guid="931bb53c-0ce0-497a-bdd2-50b9265f8afa" pid="h3-TkjrW2kmhMSwM46HhwA" hash="aOGbAw">Let us show our appreciation for these basic needs our Father in heaven has supplied by living that which we profess to believe and truly being our brother’s keeper. If we are to enter again into God’s presence, it will be by reaching out to others, for you cannot reach closer to God than you can to your fellowmen, which I testify in the name Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/04/my-brothers-keeper</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1971-general-conference/1971-04-4020-bishop-john-h-vandenberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="8852046" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1971 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Turn Heavenward Our Eyes”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In the Book of Job we read where the Lord spoke to Job and said:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03012_000_6020" doc-version="2" hash="c3EBLQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="5tlSEkOyBE6AX3dqlFi3og" hash="6EhXUg">“Turn Heavenward Our Eyes”</h1><p class="authorName" guid="a8f5128c-8278-4a4e-bac6-29cbf1c2c3f7" pid="g4mtP488gU6JGL4KuljXOw" hash="BFZRqQ">John H. Vandenberg</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="e91a5651-4a5e-427c-a128-12011cdfbf1f">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-244c.jpg" alt="Conference photo" guid="d3f14bce-f938-42b8-a435-6cc8457f7f78" pid="SaCgIeFgYEmYE_kbSoIF4Q" hash="nQf8sQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p1" guid="57dac20b-4b82-47b7-88c1-428d46521d98" pid="8CR6AKizEkOG_irQZzj3CA" hash="PEr4Pg">In the Book of Job we read where the Lord spoke to Job and said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p2" guid="2e7662af-7f43-4411-9f2b-93d1e0ea3dcf" pid="j6Yi2WSOjEG9rjSvtggSMQ" hash="Q5CDKQ">“Gird up now thy loins like a man; for I will demand of thee, and answer thou me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p3" guid="b57e5a0c-5a35-4a02-9237-564abacb23b0" pid="zDke5Q5QikmrxfM45-PVcg" hash="DGs_3A">“Where wast thou when I laid the foundations of the earth? declare, if thou hast understanding.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p4" guid="52dc6a0b-fa1b-45cb-a063-3341f3be47a1" pid="wzgtNiI_uEuKZSwVc56MYQ" hash="AD9zmQ">“Who hath laid the measures thereof, if thou knowest? or who hath stretched the line upon it?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p5" guid="0fbc37c6-3828-4ea9-a566-f7a77615c609" pid="SzmAf4nyok6Z7c5VZofTJw" hash="8z0Zow">“Whereupon are the foundations thereof fastened? or who laid the corner stone thereof;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p6" guid="502d4a49-4b8a-4ea4-8e30-7fafe1c3a0e0" pid="7ZMzq0PxbEGsMeAppAD5MQ" hash="NWwupQ">“When the morning stars sang together, and all the sons of God shouted for joy?” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/job/38.3-7" class="scriptureRef">Job 38:3–7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p7" guid="66b96117-9d93-458c-a576-78e570fcd049" pid="KZKtWL7TaU25lv33MOmsvg" hash="iF9Bgw">This bit of scripture, we believe, alludes to our preexistence with God when we, in his presence, rejoiced at his announcing to us, his children, the plan of the creation of the earth on which the human race would dwell. We believe that, as the plan was presented, we agreed to it and received the privilege of progressing in our eternal existence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p8" guid="1336f8f2-d2ff-44fe-b07f-1125ae0c1454" pid="MnZUWZqvM0aNlv2AlhdkHg" hash="j6asCg">William Wordsworth must have given a great deal of thought to the mystery of life when he was inspired to write his “Ode on Intimations of Immortality,” in which he says:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.f1" guid="3f0b6ab1-d1df-4192-a7a3-b2c77d1cdc83">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="2maobnZpL0GQn9jkQ2LNTQ" hash="0ctmcw">“Our birth is but a sleep and a forgetting</p>
          <p class="line" pid="YVYXyCIxeEes6Ycjk1lmdw" hash="fNsoIA">The Soul that rises with us, our life’s Star,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="zoNOIXooME24z2oW9HUFCw" hash="TW3NYg">Hath had elsewhere its setting,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="Lwt7-FGALU21oX6GLHPtIw" hash="HboaxA">And cometh from afar:</p>
          <p class="line" pid="pwZh_6dq2Ea1NYC-mTYaCg" hash="Y0hQ3Q">Not in entire forgetfulness,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="s9Aj_GJvW0q2qwXKr8T7cA" hash="ZqOoew">And not in utter nakedness,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="4msmuAdoh0WztfAHeqRutw" hash="yJYRBQ">But trailing clouds of glory do we come</p>
          <p class="line" pid="NoO60t00AUilXQIEj2RYbQ" hash="Du4nDg">From God, who is our home:</p>
          <p class="line" pid="5Clx1Dx-Tkur_4Ks483HsQ" hash="YfYAug">Heaven lies about us in our infancy!</p>
          <p class="line" pid="mU7DFDk8QUGbzKA62ee0Vg" hash="jvebYg">Shades of the prison-house begin to close</p>
          <p class="line" pid="Qdyomqo-BU-KmkZ0Bwipnw" hash="Fb26yw">Upon the growing Boy,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="sLTosmKThEeqy_tBJcI45g" hash="LEGWpw">But he beholds the light, and whence it flows,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="i9hV34YaW0eiaiH0A2RakA" hash="beRZjw">He sees it in his joy;</p>
          <p class="line" pid="aeYNw0YxvEmMruP87xL1Xg" hash="7CyyGg">The Youth, who daily farther from the east</p>
          <p class="line" pid="ISRKqeO_S02oviC2gEmVbw" hash="UFL9vg">Must travel, still is Nature’s Priest,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="dQrLoWupm0iblcevFwktOQ" hash="Jit2MQ">And by the vision splendidIs on his way attended;</p>
          <p class="line" pid="SIpdxaIdakeAH3G_MuHknQ" hash="d71GBA">At length the Man perceives it die away,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="aO7KS7yj5EmTSR21CjbwlA" hash="RrRgRg">And fade into the light of common day.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="LvlQtXww60WDe3ep2tRmaA" hash="R7Qu6Q">Earth fills her lap with pleasures of her own;</p>
          <p class="line" pid="JB_oVRckbEK7a2I9uVkspg" hash="z4dTeQ">Yearnings she hath in her own natural kind,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="SavddXo-LEOUsrxDiBVCqA" hash="69SXOA">And, even with something of a Mother’s mind,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="cqv9Zzy6akKHL7KmcH-_dA" hash="3a6ijA">And no unworthy aim,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="5oEn6rI6f0imIn4e5FFSkg" hash="ji75Qw">The homely Nurse doth all she can</p>
          <p class="line" pid="7xfnMaK1BEqNjdyIy1swgw" hash="Btzq3g">To make her Foster-child, her Inmate Man,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="Q6k00pz7LkCZrhaHoR9JrQ" hash="0BTwNA">Forget the glories he hath known,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="B1ahV74jBEOpK-UcTmQypA" hash="oGKC6A">And that imperial palace whence he came.”</p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p9" guid="f8e0c905-b013-412d-90ef-21c6773f1d7a" pid="ChUffztEdEmVnE3w448Usg" hash="_iP7FA">Henry Ward Beecher has said: “God asks no man whether he will accept life. That is not his choice. He must take it. The only choice is how.” Parenthetically, I would say we did make the choice to come to earth. God does not force his children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p10" guid="840a888e-253b-412a-ad53-325b02a59082" pid="tsdpRlHa_EqLdBA3AcVugQ" hash="3wCbwA">The choice we are now concerned with is how we are going to live our lives. We have the agency to make that choice as we react to the conditions in which we find ourselves during our life span. We must make choices, as we are surrounded by the elements and resources of the earth as well as by the people with whom we associate. From the words of the prophets to the words of the atheists, the question is: How will we emerge? Will we rise or fall? Will we fulfill our life’s purpose, or will it be wasted?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p11" guid="1c0dc70b-ab5c-458b-997d-57b1a6a8f8e5" pid="nSx_w1miY0WkvLfUk8TMQw" hash="GgEERg">In accepting life, we must relate to the world as it is—to the struggle between good and evil. There are, of course, some who would have us believe that there is no such thing as good or evil, but this philosophy runs counter to the natural laws of opposites that exist, such as heat and cold, light and dark, gravitation and vacuum, and many others. We need to use our eyes that we may see, our ears that we may hear, and our minds that we may be able to think and make our own decisions as we sift out the chaff of all we see and hear, so that we may know the truth of that which we feel in our hearts, as it is affirmed by the Holy Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p12" guid="e4871625-78dc-4fb4-82b8-a4cd5b49cc1c" pid="kRc7kNriYk-ZO1dhBL8r9A" hash="HoPQvg">Faith in God is a prerequisite to the influence of the Holy Spirit. To have a belief in God is the foundation of a full and happy life. Without this belief, life can be wasted. Evidence of God’s existence spreads throughout the universe.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p13" guid="0bc167b6-5fb6-4977-8413-c8c6e9311c91" pid="QFQ5l_6-LkaSMJWyPLxp1A" hash="N5rFRQ">Abraham Lincoln said: “I can see how it might be possible for a man to look down upon the earth and be an atheist, but I cannot conceive how he could look up into the heavens and say there is no God.” I believe I know what Lincoln meant when he made that statement.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p14" guid="e58a167f-2d63-4a81-9df6-152660f37b4c" pid="7e9SYoeS20i4djbSAx-uCQ" hash="DWKzEg">Some years ago I accepted an invitation to a fathers and sons outing, where the participants spent an arduous but interesting day mounted on horses on a trip to Bloomington Lake in the mountains of Bear Lake County, Idaho. Late at night, after the campfires had all burned out and everyone had settled down under the open heavens, I lay on my back, gazing overhead. It was a moonless night, and I have never seen such a beautiful sight. The heavens were alive with the brightness of stars and planets. How small I felt in comparison to that vast universe! A sense of appreciation came over me as I thought of God’s glory, of his handiwork, the earth, the heavens, all created for one purpose—his children, mankind. That experience has remained with me. I was overwhelmed by the magnitude of it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p15" guid="b5c24147-7823-48dd-aaf7-b32959e75524" pid="e5N6nMqNnECTgUoFEV2G6Q" hash="g6sYUQ">It calls to mind an incident I read that tells of the naturalist, William Beebe, who made a visit to another naturalist whose name was Theodore Roosevelt. In describing the visit, William Beebe said that each evening, after a talk in Roosevelt’s home at Sagamore Hill, the two men would go out on the lawn and gaze up at the sky to see who could first detect that faint spot of light-mist beyond the lower left-hand corner of the Great Square of Pegasus. Then one or the other would recite: “That is the Spiral Galaxy of Andromeda. It is as large as our Milky Way. It is one of a hundred million galaxies. It is 750,000 light-years away. It consists of one hundred billion suns, each larger than our sun.” After an interval Beebe reported that Mr. Roosevelt would grin at him and say, “Now I think we are small enough. Let’s go to bed.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p16" guid="ab559ad8-dcaa-44ea-b046-7db7d1b4c746" pid="REhGGR7KQUGZCs2rCdznyg" hash="rAdiXQ">Can you imagine how Moses felt when he said: “Now, for this cause I know that man is nothing, which thing I never had supposed” after he “was caught up into an exceedingly high mountain, And he saw God face to face, and he talked with him”? (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.10,1-2" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:10, 1–2</a>.) We read in the first chapter of Moses that “Moses looked, and beheld the world upon which he was created; and Moses beheld the world and the ends thereof, and all the children of men which are, and which were created; of the same he greatly marveled and wondered.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.8" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p17" guid="060ce2c6-b84c-42b3-93b0-42ea99ce2d57" pid="prrNHir_AUuMyQVlXgyzwg" hash="KAetIw">And then Satan appeared and tempted Moses and commanded in a loud voice: “I am the Only Begotten, worship me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p18" guid="bc532ee2-7cd6-41b3-afd3-ca0720c2d663" pid="rZri-Slzk0Oib_ruVoPKtg" hash="xta33g">“And … Moses began to fear exceedingly; and … he saw the bitterness of hell. Nevertheless, calling upon God, he received strength, and he commanded, saying: Depart from me, Satan, for this one God only will I worship, which is the God of glory.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p19" guid="1b5274f9-0fee-416b-97ad-12a5347eb3ff" pid="3qKxCX4_50KhDay8zDM48Q" hash="DGK0oA">“And now Satan began to tremble, and the earth shook; and Moses … called upon God, saying: In the name of the Only Begotten, depart hence, Satan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p20" guid="b32e2241-08cb-4461-85b9-7b9b1b716fa4" pid="KrFf2UiFVEmTHVy8AgcjYA" hash="BEAHjw">“And … Satan cried with a loud voice … and he departed hence, even from the presence of Moses. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p21" guid="f55d6000-8539-41f1-84d3-9af48c13d4c8" pid="Pvbig1xdHUCr_g7sJYM21A" hash="mj9Qzw">“And … when Satan had departed … Moses lifted up his eyes unto heaven, being filled with the Holy Ghost, which beareth record of the Father and the Son;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p22" guid="217a397f-e707-42cb-8168-61c2815e1565" pid="k7ZZr42y8Eu7yy_dfE6S_Q" hash="2TGnig">“And calling upon the name of God, he beheld his glow again, for it was upon him. …”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p23" guid="d4bb645c-a823-479d-b9dd-7db63e98477a" pid="jyYdMBxW8ka4JSB7EocJOA" hash="f_TbSQ">And Moses beheld the earth and the inhabitants thereof. And he beheld many lands. And “Moses called upon God, saying: Tell me, I pray thee, why these things are so, and by what thou madest them?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p24" guid="0c8f141d-9e47-4a39-8882-ab8d3e1b7857" pid="FAmXIDDBBEuvcgfiDmHOhw" hash="tzh7Qw">“And behold, the glory of the Lord was upon Moses, so that Moses stood in the presence of God, and talked with him face to face. And the Lord God said unto Moses: For mine own purpose have I made these things. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p25" guid="0e11471e-13ff-40d9-a451-e2212cd544fc" pid="eSpDKmnnoUuSPd6xAB5mFw" hash="-4FdnQ">“And by the word of my power have I created them. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p26" guid="0a27df89-e78c-4d1c-9a15-3a12c8fca4b2" pid="L-eT9tcS0k6KaGGSFs6xbg" hash="cSSR_Q">“And worlds without number have I created; and I also created them for mine own purpose; and by the Son I created them, which is mine Only Begotten. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p27" guid="8c0eaf80-2f27-431b-bd8a-76e4fd13d7da" pid="9wsKo0EACEyLV9jCWM2H0Q" hash="W4FfqQ">“But only an account of this earth, and the inhabitants thereof, give I unto you. For behold, there are many worlds that have passed away by the word of my power. And there are many that now stand, and innumerable are they unto man; but all things are numbered unto me, for they are mine and I know them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p28" guid="93d0f149-9d68-4b96-99d7-3536eb8d6c91" pid="BuQfx0IQjUy4VgnjQ_SAsw" hash="fjapaA">“And … Moses spake unto the Lord, saying: Be merciful unto thy servant, O God, and tell me concerning this earth, and the inhabitants thereof, and also the heavens, and then thy servant will be content.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p29" guid="33a561f9-be83-476f-ac48-9d4cab898297" pid="KbCYeHZQIEOBq-g5uBvh9A" hash="-Ar5lw">“And the Lord God spake unto Moses, saying: The heavens, they are many, and they cannot be numbered unto man; but they are numbered unto me, for they are mine.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p30" guid="9b62a573-d8f8-4563-930d-da37ae58204b" pid="JyBbonBIUEeCk-hEYm4i2A" hash="moFFfQ">“And as one earth shall pass away, and the heavens thereof even so shall another come; and there is no end to my works, neither to my words.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p31" guid="bf0546c0-0bcb-4a17-9710-3aa1698cddd9" pid="zbyjAvPoQ0qrDujJiXqG4A" hash="o3tRow">“For behold, this is my work and my glory—to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.19-22,24-25,30-33,35-39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:19–22, 24–25, 30–33, 35–39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p32" guid="edcca59d-fd5e-4a63-9d18-9f95d38a55e4" pid="uQj4-NBWOk2jTT7Pgl1_-g" hash="7v3G-g">Think of the impact of that statement. All the creations of God were made for this one purpose—to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of his children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p33" guid="f96f28f7-538b-4e2c-a4b8-33c2b9a19e08" pid="yVQLgs-fxUSpG7qN4P0qAw" hash="nbmHAg">Moses became aware of the magnitude of the creation and its purpose firsthand, by talking face to face with God and beholding his works. There are few who have had that experience. But others have beheld God’s majesty through his works. Abraham Lincoln stated his conviction when he said that he could not conceive how anyone could look up into the heavens and say there is no God. I had an unforgettable witness to God’s handiwork as I lay on my back in the mountains of Bear Lake County, Idaho. No doubt many could concur in such an experience, for it has been said, “We must, despite ourselves, turn heavenward our eyes.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p34" guid="2520add1-63a1-4672-aa0d-0d4c1b01f6d0" pid="JLWeG2vBbU-8sa-e8UURdA" hash="nwtkhg">As the Lord talked to Moses, he told him of the creation of the earth and how he formed man and instructed him to teach his children to know good from evil and to teach them “that all men, everywhere, must repent, or they can in nowise inherit the kingdom of God, for no unclean thing can dwell there. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p35" guid="f5b96ffd-8ada-424f-a17e-1123d5024a11" pid="vdzqKTV9006diPg3e_NNYQ" hash="4CtTeQ">“… I give unto you a commandment to teach these things freely unto your children, saying:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p36" guid="116d1cc2-5ba9-4405-a8a8-73db3db2ecde" pid="zmBxsfGegU25oBnRDkk6_g" hash="5wEC-g">“That by reason of transgression cometh the fall, which fall bringeth death, and inasmuch as ye were born into the world by water, and blood, and the spirit, which I have made, and so became of dust a living soul, even so ye must be born again into the kingdom of heaven, of water, and of the Spirit, and be cleansed by blood, even the blood of mine Only Begotten; that ye might be sanctified from all sin, and enjoy the words of eternal life in this world, and eternal life in the world to come, even immortal glory;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p37" guid="661bdb01-3d0c-4a5b-8276-ecb4874df834" pid="y8gn-oYHS06VnDRKgUrcUw" hash="5dLurg">“For by the water ye keep the commandment; by the Spirit ye are justified, and by the blood ye are sanctified;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p38" guid="1d226b08-b400-4334-aa0d-c723375ca6d0" pid="XQjSxA_6jEqESygYXVODSA" hash="rO0sSA">“Therefore it is given to abide in you; the record of heaven; the Comforter; the peaceable things of immortal glory; the truth of all things; that which quickeneth all things, which maketh alive all things; that which knoweth all things, and hath all power according to wisdom, mercy, truth, justice, and judgment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p39" guid="6895f4e8-05a6-48a3-9026-8ef7ddbcd959" pid="vCeDdWXNX0eAZ9ybNzE54A" hash="Lcj2BQ">“And now, behold, I say unto you: This is the plan of salvation unto all men, through the blood of mine Only Begotten, who shall come in the meridian of time.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/6.57-62" class="scriptureRef">Moses 6:57–62</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p40" guid="a2bc0477-e705-4881-8442-42ed13d97b75" pid="TNd04odCqUujM0THaQ2z1Q" hash="ehcDgw">And so the creation of the world, the plan of salvation—all this is for us. It behooves all parents to know of it, that they may respond to desires of the child that are so aptly stated by Mamie Gene Cole in her poem “The Child’s Appeal”:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.f2" guid="ba058bec-b8b8-480b-bab9-a29758c53048">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="4inHH8WubkiTYmAIgSdO2g" hash="SvZO4g">“I am the Child.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="CkQ9HcfAIUqLpa_TQ1Rxjg" hash="z6H_og">All the world waits for my coming.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="jOb9mxl8Rk2gLQnrCZrdEA" hash="xip5Og">All the earth watches with interest to see what I shall become.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="8vrq9bfelEie0C_ADdCCEQ" hash="5esyUA">Civilization hangs in the balance,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="Alb5730wmUSpunl7MEK-LA" hash="n3y6wg">For what I am, the world of tomorrow will be.</p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="GVyiS5hKj0WEbNS4mUBX-g" hash="SvZO4g1">“I am the Child.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="QCnPq7JgHEG_ano3Q7QB_g" hash="cfB9QA">I have come into your world, about which I know nothing.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="8iD8SrehQ0qehn9yL917kg" hash="IzkA4g">Why I came I know not;</p>
          <p class="line" pid="w6Qg8s4TH0u712ZglrEScA" hash="Mpx31Q">How I came I know not;</p>
          <p class="line" pid="h0EpE3r-jkaHSM1GLes1Lg" hash="1-fGTA">I am curious; I am interested.</p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="LujShk95tUaVUsSW8n39NA" hash="SvZO4g2">“I am the Child.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="xGpEh3tUsEuamyMAEp7EBw" hash="qmU9-Q">You hold in your hand my destiny.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="BUHn7gji3ESE5Gqifno-ZQ" hash="dCZiwA">You determine, largely, whether I shall succeed or fail.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="u2yXMLr95EOvd4mccz01Xg" hash="nVTigw">Give me, I pray you, those things that make for happiness.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="8qmXf2MQn0O-tMuFBFj1CA" hash="4zRWSA">Train me, I beg you, that I may be a blessing to the world.”</p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p41" guid="eac73c5a-aa42-4103-ba9f-38797c929a99" pid="7lRdTenm1EeplCpzG4Q6yQ" hash="abXW9A">What a responsibility for a mother and father, to answer this appeal from their child: “Give me, I pray you, those things that make for happiness.” The first thing that comes to mind is that we cannot give that which we do not have. Do we, as parents, have those things that make for happiness, the basis of which is the understanding of God’s plan as revealed to Moses, and try to live our lives in accordance to that plan?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p42" guid="4be860aa-9810-42be-8121-d18b7db0ddb7" pid="U0xqKj41QkecTmuVaE7yyA" hash="avFILA">Do you think of yourself as a happy person? A young man once made a list of all the things he thought would bring happiness in life. He included such things as wealth, fame, honor, success, and love. It was quite a long list, and he thought he had covered everything; but when he showed it proudly to an elderly friend, he was told, “You have left out the most important thing of all—peace of mind.” The young man said he could not, at that time, understand how right his friend was.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p43" guid="60b733d9-6f93-4deb-ab08-a5854e185e5d" pid="O9LMI9tmW0egy5MpjuBi3A" hash="Gi8K3A">Peace of mind, a clear conscience, was declared by President David O. McKay as the first condition of happiness. He said: “It is glorious when you can lie down at night with a clear conscience that you have done your best not to offend anyone and have injured no one. … These and countless other virtues and conditions are all wrapped up in the Gospel of Jesus Christ.” (<span class="emphasis">Man May Know for Himself</span> [Deseret Book Co., 1967], p. 458.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p44" guid="3843c15e-6910-4557-a9e0-a48d770b32ef" pid="F9jzsZUIH0mjr6xdp_L1vQ" hash="oBvr9w">Some other conditions that make for happiness are the ability to follow that which you know to be true, to control your appetites and passions, to be able to make your own decisions, to feel no envy of another, to be able to commune with God in prayer, and to be free from bonds, and to be master of yourself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p45" guid="c4d22467-0677-4639-89a8-da36f95588a4" pid="ZPRIEM4EvkK0QBCnXa-ugQ" hash="6CEotg">The second appeal of the child to his parents—train me to be a blessing to the world—is companion to happiness, for it calls for action by the individual in an expression of service, of losing himself in helping his fellowman.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p46" guid="04ac8f98-c5a1-4e63-a2cc-8a343ed36732" pid="jeyWcdp5nkmigZEDhRelww" hash="-e0kZw">You’ve heard that statement that each of us is either a part of the problem or a part of the answer, with the understanding that this world is beset with problems. If you are a part of the answer, then you are a blessing to the world and can train your children to follow in your footsteps. Those who are a blessing to the world will try to do these things: (1) lend a helping hand, (2) refrain from infringing upon the rights of others, (3) obey God’s laws and the laws of the land, (4) stand up for the right and fight against evil, and (5) share the truth with others, remembering, and remembering well, that the greatest gift of God is his plan of salvation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes.p47" guid="4b8efff1-9322-4480-a4a2-f4a5ea0c1a8c" pid="nWJ7X3rN00G8jCoFKyo28g" hash="amtkdA">May we guide our lives and those of our children in this direction, I pray humbly in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/10/turn-heavenward-our-eyes</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1971-general-conference/1971-10-6020-bishop-john-h-vandenberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="9373588" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 1971 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whence Cometh Our Peace?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace?lang=eng</link>
      <description>This morning as I walked into the Tabernacle, one of the attendant brethren said to me, “Bishop, I am looking forward to hearing your speech this afternoon.” And then he added, “You are the last one.”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03020_000_7060" doc-version="2" hash="9dcqag"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="N51pXAkIekqSPpgv5Wq52g" hash="AKBVeA">Whence Cometh Our Peace?</h1><p class="authorName" guid="a8f5128c-8278-4a4e-bac6-29cbf1c2c3f7" pid="Ms57DJ7DkkC4-zTIQL3XOw" hash="BFZRqQ">John H. Vandenberg</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="e857a639-c215-46c8-95ff-2e5e7e1f3ffe">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-244c.jpg" alt="Elder John H. Vandenberg" guid="6545f2ab-27b7-46f9-a1c7-52db72366c86" pid="8k9Z68WS_Eag94fe2tGF3g" hash="nQf8sQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p1" guid="aeb6876f-8e9b-425f-9b0f-dbf5eda5a226" pid="71HDfTd0x0OFQ3asme_90Q" hash="Wnndag">This morning as I walked into the Tabernacle, one of the attendant brethren said to me, “Bishop, I am looking forward to hearing your speech this afternoon.” And then he added, “You are the last one.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p2" guid="fe2f5a03-0f5e-4622-b77f-c08402cd239a" pid="EwcX_FczD0uAFwMDFM1yhg" hash="x7zRsw">I suppose he had in mind that this great conference has brought so many things, so many good things—the testimonies of the prophets, seers, and revelators, exciting changes, and testimonies of the brethren that God lives and that Jesus is the Christ—to the extent that our cups truly run over.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p3" guid="8969ef12-a495-423c-b397-c62f72cb26ac" pid="E_4l2TW0UECoDzNPj8N8-Q" hash="-QLkYA">What a blessing it is to set a course and work diligently at it. This past decade I have had the privilege of working with two wonderful men. You have seen the good works and heard the good words of Elder Robert L. Simpson and Bishop Victor L. Brown. This isn’t a parting or a farewell, but I will always cherish the experience I have had in working with these two wonderful men of God. God bless them, and God bless the Church for their service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p4" guid="7334309b-4759-492a-8f67-866c87ebc80d" pid="8vA4SW7hLkefQIr0vvK9GA" hash="gLmpzQ">I know that we are led by revelation. It comes to us through the prophet of God, Joseph Fielding Smith. I have thought a good deal about this, because I know that he is a prophet and that his counselors serve God as they serve with President Smith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p5" guid="87b77f1f-e529-43ce-9a2c-cd9036f33526" pid="j5EyExIu90qdmyb8Hvbgiw" hash="bMs_dA">In thinking what I might say at this conference, I wasn’t aware that this change in my assignment was coming. I was down in Hawaii recently, and a young Hawaiian girl approached us and greeted us with both arms uplifted, holding up two fingers of each hand. I asked her what the sign meant, and with a broad smile she immediately replied, “Peace.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p6" guid="24b4b41a-4d5f-463f-9bec-630921b00491" pid="73BIJF97MkqRygRw12l6Sw" hash="IkaoDg">In traveling the highways, we often observe passing automobiles in which young occupants display the same sign at windows. We see the word <span class="emphasis">peace </span>painted on walls, fences, sidewalks, and, at times, in psychedelic colors on vehicles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p7" guid="6ac46d84-1a86-4bb6-a954-98b68a38d8c0" pid="fIRfn9OlmUG1FaNDyPfStw" hash="VAlyHg">We wonder at the apparent interest in peace by the current generation. Is it any different from that of generations past? What do we mean by this expression of peace? Is it a passing fad, or is there deep determination for its accomplishment?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p8" guid="8923f932-ac47-4171-b007-a29736a5df62" pid="4A5P0HayPUmz8wa99QL5NA" hash="90upUA">Peace was placed in two categories by the Master. You will recall his words to his disciples during the days before his crucifixion. He had admonished them to keep his commandments and had promised to send them another Comforter, the Spirit of truth, which is the Holy Ghost, who would teach them all things and bring all things to their remembrance that he had said unto them. Then he said, “Peace I leave with you, my peace I give unto you: not as the world giveth, give I unto you. Let not your heart be troubled, neither let it be afraid.” (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.15-27" class="scriptureRef">John 14:15–27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p9" guid="1198575e-01a8-4578-ba57-a23b27559086" pid="4rYK-kXx_kKyPW1Doch-vw" hash="MutuEw">What did the Savior mean when he said “not as the world giveth”? What kind of peace has the world to give?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p10" guid="0cbae412-2976-4f5c-b35b-1dfb1a910ab0" pid="aGk1RdZvgkOg6BFFTkTjWw" hash="-LfAow">Certainly it is true that many are searching for peace in the world, and yet some follow paths in their search that could only lead in the opposite direction—paths of avarice, ambition, envy, anger, and pride. Surely the greatest enemy of peace is selfishness and with it the desire to pile up treasures on earth. This brings to mind the parable by the Good Teacher as found in the Gospel of Luke:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p11" guid="a1e4a205-9699-4c29-8f9d-e6d8f729b365" pid="sQ3igPxp8Uyy6JTmxQQoTw" hash="Oc9seA">“And one of the company said unto him, Master, speak to my brother, that he divide the inheritance with me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p12" guid="edafe884-0268-4139-8c7d-905938be4b02" pid="XR2J-eOgHUSJ7IQ-HNFWqA" hash="b_Rr0g">“And he said unto him, Man, who made me a judge or a divider over you?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p13" guid="c7dd8e20-3029-4cbf-abe7-100dc50f3773" pid="AdFh_xbabE6WZZvnkRe6tg" hash="5oudPw">“And he said unto them, Take heed, and beware of covetousness: for a man’s life consisteth not in the abundance of the things which he possesseth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p14" guid="105533cc-a8b8-4a27-bb86-a31137914f54" pid="e6hSLGa5Q0eCy8YXTqLX_Q" hash="_1MEvw">“And he spake a parable unto them, saying, The ground of a certain rich man brought forth plentifully:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p15" guid="4397f1f3-8840-444a-8f37-3f8ca2f41342" pid="IfcWboCeRkmWbty5LYIjyw" hash="eKH9XA">“And he thought within himself, saying, What shall I do, because I have no room where to bestow my fruits?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p16" guid="159685a6-415a-461d-ba94-04675116afba" pid="d6yxRp_Lq02Da6g8GAujgA" hash="bKVVCQ">“And he said, This will I do: I will pull down my barns, and build greater, and there will I bestow all my fruits and my goods.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p17" guid="83d8e854-81e6-4589-aff7-88582ea926f3" pid="U_YiW2CLE026uvbCpykCPw" hash="y0EbOw">“And I will say to my soul, Soul, thou hast much goods laid up for many years; take thine ease, eat, drink, and be merry.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p18" guid="0eab679d-f2f5-4931-bc00-63f7fc527685" pid="5q7tIEpajEmsrPcMZnijLQ" hash="_p81VQ">“But God said unto him, Thou fool, this night thy soul shall be required of thee: then whose shall those things be, which thou hast provided?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p19" guid="7351a172-4e71-4637-94dc-e8746a07614f" pid="h4j-6qmh6UuUJJVlMYLHvw" hash="8WA3Pg">“So is he that layeth up treasure for himself, and is not rich toward God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/12.13-21" class="scriptureRef">Luke 12:13–21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p20" guid="016e5613-116a-4e6a-9e44-bf78083bdbb1" pid="1NPRvcf28068ueo3sKFbOA" hash="2NjiiQ">How can we be rich toward God? Does this refer to the laying up of treasures in heaven by living his commandments—love of God and of our fellowmen? Wouldn’t living each day with these objectives in mind bring into our lives that peace spoken of by the Savior? Aren’t we all too much inclined to be encumbered about by many things and forget those things that are most needful?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p21" guid="e1094bd3-f44e-4ac1-8b62-eb95006b49cf" pid="KfM8Wq_dW0yvwG1tit1b8A" hash="bNTLDg">Henry David Thoreau thought so, for we read in his book <span class="emphasis">Walden:</span> “The mass of men lead lives of quiet desperation. … Most of the luxuries, and many of the so called comforts of life, are not only not indispensable, but positive hindrances to the elevation of mankind.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p22" guid="fd121767-78c9-4de4-87f8-ffa6911a18b9" pid="mK2OqMY8Tkmm2gW2p4_ACw" hash="d4P5rw">And Joshua Liebman wrote similarly in his little book <span class="emphasis">Peace of Mind: </span>“A man may have a home, possessions, a charming family, and yet find all these things ashy to his taste because he has been outstripped in the marathon race by some other runners to the golden tape line. It is not that he does not possess enough for his wants, but that others possess more. It is the more that haunts him, makes him depreciate himself and minimize his real achievements.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p23" guid="9ec66f90-f8fa-421c-a60d-b63d1274cf6f" pid="4R2e2wcwIEy9pJACfci23w" hash="AV2d9A">“The time has come when a man must say to himself: ‘I am no longer going to be interested in how much power or wealth another man possesses so long as I can attain enough for the dignity and security of my family and myself. I am going to break through this vicious circle which always asks the question of life in a comparative degree: Who is bigger? Who is richer? Who has more? I am going to set my goals for myself rather than borrow them from others. …”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p24" guid="7f0d7b07-e7e9-44b3-92cb-16fae1015278" pid="PUvr_nn7NEq9XxCBc64agQ" hash="kV4YSA">I believe that this is one thing we can learn from our youth today. They have, in many cases, set simpler values and seen through the transitory worth of material things. They recognize that ambition that leads men to seek power and domination over others brings not peace, but frustration. Certainly history is replete with examples of the rise and fall of ambitious men, and during temporary relief from hostilities between nations the cry always rises, “Now we will have peace.” How many wars have been termed “a war to end all wars”?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p25" guid="5e511317-dee3-4832-a3ec-b43f6dd55917" pid="A5mid9maNkqzH7Sko09bJg" hash="pt7rhw">Yet an encyclopedia shows that during the period from 1496 <small>B.C.</small> to <small>A.D.</small> 1861 there were 227 years of peace compared with 3,130 years of war. Ambition, either privately or collectively, gives little hope for the achievement of peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p26" guid="86e1da95-f0c4-47b1-81e3-e5bd75dde626" pid="A1i2ZCDa4kKzj8PvRiu8jg" hash="8lUhzA">Today we have a universal search for peace—a generation of peace; yet most of those who discard the grasping, selfish race for power know not where to turn to find a way of life to take its place.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p27" guid="5b35ffd0-3501-4cb7-9f68-134441664a9a" pid="6d3YtNpEWUivlhf1RzK5fA" hash="y_g52w">But peace cannot be achieved by making a sign or by writing words on fences. It must come first and most completely to the individual through his own efforts in keeping the commandments of our Lord and Savior, for God made all men to enjoy such peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p28" guid="efb4d4de-054e-4781-a33a-8867b20c5d96" pid="Pj3vh0r9_Ea-r5681aNWtA" hash="h_oXow">Just as running madly after worldly things does not bring peace, neither does sitting idly. Because our modern conveniences often leave us much time beyond that which is necessary to sustain ourselves and our families, it becomes important not to spend this time idly; for there is much to be done if we are to partake of the Lord’s peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p29" guid="d803f558-feb9-483d-b16d-a647db86f0b5" pid="psx8H8sDLUe0RBBlBohnzg" hash="zW6Xtw">Probably there is no quicker way to enjoy inner peace than by serving one another. There is recorded in history a marvelous period of time when this peace did indeed banish avarice, ambition, envy, anger, and pride from men’s hearts. It was shortly after the Savior’s visit to the American continent after his death and resurrection. We read:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p30" guid="f698b6f6-ad13-4fef-8caf-4cc83dd477b1" pid="xgZX6Tq2UkCj4z72NioqEw" hash="XGHyGg">“… the people were all converted unto the Lord … and there were no contentions and disputations among them, and every man did deal justly one with another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p31" guid="6f6e9fe8-709d-4742-92b1-e7abe6d56e8f" pid="n7ccfpBTokyx67WlDSDeFQ" hash="mjbaHg">“And they had all things common among them; therefore there were not rich and poor, bond and free, but they were all made free, and partakers of the heavenly gift.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p32" guid="48acd972-7079-4d54-a2df-f89054274af6" pid="sPayPNo_3Ey15Pc9oqfVRA" hash="NKOQcg">“And there were great and marvelous works wrought by the disciples of Jesus, insomuch that they did heal the sick, and raise the dead, and cause the lame to walk, and the blind to receive their sight, and the deaf to hear. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p33" guid="5a12ec60-9d20-42f8-abfb-a25f075902e4" pid="YdPkyw5vXkKucYKtWfvtBw" hash="cQDFcg">“And the Lord did prosper them exceedingly in the land. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p34" guid="364defcd-82f9-485b-ab9e-d26e0f252c80" pid="VrXiJvsLfkmmY3u1z9XaaQ" hash="lLB-Gw">“And now, behold, it came to pass that the people of Nephi did wax strong, and did multiply exceedingly fast, and became an exceedingly fair and delightsome people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p35" guid="a7b5f872-0da0-4347-ab88-211f60ead05a" pid="GqFOhvTkXE-LOWS03LH_gg" hash="zYsHqQ">“And they were married, and given in marriage, and were blessed according to the multitude of the promises which the Lord had made unto them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p36" guid="aaeff928-d8de-40f7-8ff8-08be64a05256" pid="H5auy0Kse0uXWT2TKL3UbA" hash="VhFAXA">“And they did not walk any more after the performances and ordinances of the law of Moses; but they did walk after the commandments which they had received from their Lord and their God, continuing in fasting and prayer, and in meeting together oft both to pray and to hear the word of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p37" guid="c60cfba8-2fe9-4ba2-b426-eff5e69a5909" pid="bzrinuXDZEmqOLJKhy-wQA" hash="-hCIfQ">“And it came to pass that there was no contention among all the people, in all the land; but there were mighty miracles wrought among the disciples of Jesus.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p38" guid="cf5a166a-54de-469d-9d95-151aa842c584" pid="69GOUUaBpkOhVY7s2-j94Q" hash="McaV1Q">“And it came to pass that there was no contention in the land, because of the love of God which did dwell in the hearts of the people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p39" guid="ec665318-8487-4cc4-981f-199149223658" pid="hGmae4OmW0iLp21B96-rtQ" hash="a4lZKw">“And there were no envyings, nor strifes, nor tumults, nor whoredoms, nor lyings, nor murders, nor any manner of lasciviousness; and surely there could not be a happier people among all the people who had been created by the hand of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p40" guid="401f2cee-1bd1-4603-93db-94cb379e9968" pid="GUOM7SkOEUe7bQadnPsowg" hash="3Rh_Sw">“There were no robbers, nor murderers, neither were there Lamanites, nor any manner of -ites; but they were in one, the children of Christ, and heirs to the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p41" guid="3c7e7c7d-9013-4039-873a-f0dbb193c7d0" pid="XG1pGk2bg0ieCx-zMZwqiA" hash="cDrb2A">“And how blessed were they! For the Lord did bless them in all their doings; yea, even they were blessed and prospered until an hundred and ten years had passed away; and the first generation from Christ had passed away, and there was no contention in all the land.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p42" guid="70c059c9-06cc-4567-8019-39e6beff0861" pid="4VLMes8ujUOfpBQnurFMZQ" hash="wcjJig">“… Nephi, he that kept this last record, … kept it eighty and four years, and there was still peace in the land, save it were a small part of the people. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p43" guid="a64995c8-fbb8-4cc2-85c7-add35df9f818" pid="4lbhGP9YQUyp6ELwh3wsXA" hash="JBGWNA">“And it came to pass that two hundred years had passed away. …” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/4-ne/1.2-3,5,7,10-11,12-13,15-20,22" class="scriptureRef">4 Ne. 1:2–3, 5, 7, 10–11, 12–13, 15–20, 22</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p44" guid="7fb36e2e-9265-44e2-9b62-c00a771c780d" pid="qDsKtoDzfUWOlov-dfeHdQ" hash="d0T8bg">This was indeed a fortunate people whose history is contained in the Book of Mormon, a book which covers nearly three thousand years and which reveals that only during those periods of time when the people were keeping God’s commandments did they enjoy peace, love, happiness, and prosperity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p45" guid="1359b96b-adc2-447e-80f4-6ddba500273a" pid="oOT8HhVMRU2_R6cKzhS6Cg" hash="UFJU3Q">Today man’s greatest desire and hope is to find a life of peace and joy, progress, and freedom, which can only be found in the gospel of Jesus Christ. Yet, paradoxically, we live in a world where war, destruction, contention, law-breaking, and immorality surround us, and many become lost. One of these, a young woman, tells her story in the current issue of the <span class="emphasis">New Era</span> magazine for youth. How fortunate she was in finding the true gospel of Christ to show her the way out of the confusion in which she had wandered; and what gratitude she expresses to those caring young people who showed her the way!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p46" guid="f1f30ce0-ca4d-4004-9b62-60080bbfa40a" pid="H9orq9fwxEymm9_l7LOgOw" hash="u4BLhQ">As members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, we accept as positive knowledge from God the fact that each human being lived in a preexistent spiritual world as a child of God and came to this mortal life for a great and necessary part of eternal life. This mortality provides the opportunity to choose the right and to obtain knowledge by faith in the revealed plan of God, which will bring peace and freedom for mortal as well as eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p47" guid="e3fa2753-4d25-49a6-8ab1-fc2e5e7437c7" pid="-pXb-jkRwkqwJ7Wc-NQSlw" hash="O92Ucw">We accept as a fact that God has revealed through his chosen prophets the way of life which leads to peace, which is the gospel of Jesus Christ. Human passions for mortal gratification, including selfishness, envy, anger, and pride, must be replaced by spiritual ideals, and sin must become abhorrent to us, for we know that all we do here will affect our lives in eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p48" guid="b79c1328-5998-431d-bb8b-9f074e985209" pid="0dazSVsHZUSdkWG-gDmjEg" hash="aeoZEg">We believe that only through this knowledge and way of life can an individual or a nation achieve that peace which is so desired and sought after.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p49" guid="54da9c77-5a6c-4364-9efa-2a7955056b2a" pid="XNVxAanpAU-INiOGySV4Wg" hash="Vo0JhA">And so we say to this generation, which is so verbally calling for peace, that this thought toward peace today is indeed significant, for it is true that peace is in our hands—our own personal peace as well as in great measure the peace of our world. Believe in it, work for it, live for it; for in it, as you follow through and work for the establishment of peace first in your own souls, you will then have true peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p50" guid="6a710ff8-aa1a-4ffe-ba69-ce4856b36ed7" pid="OCFK1vyr80mDXqSnhiF13w" hash="6KLR9w">Now as we go from this great conference, brothers and sisters, let us go recognizing that our cup is filled to overflowing. We have been charged with the great messages of God’s prophet. We have been charged with the testimonies of the brethren. We have been charged with the Spirit of God, which has been in our presence and is now in our presence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p51" guid="2640e3cf-4af4-4c30-b64d-f79a36665e44" pid="oVlpH22XDUGzKCM4AjrwaQ" hash="60ycmw">Let us go forth with our personal testimonies, to which I wish to add mine, that I know that God lives, that Jesus is the Christ, and that we live and serve, if we but will, under the direction of God’s prophet, Joseph Fielding Smith, supported by two other prophets, Harold B. Lee and Nathan Eldon Tanner, and supported by thirteen other prophets, the Quorum of the Twelve and the patriarch.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace.p52" guid="da6c3638-94c2-4533-b738-175d81dc3565" pid="MFpeBWcRrkirjW8gjo509w" hash="uTiDGA">God be with you and bless you as we go forth to carry out our assignments, whatever they are, I humbly pray, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/04/whence-cometh-our-peace</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1972-general-conference/1972-04-7060-elder-john-h-vandenberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="9362405" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Somebody</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The dignity of the proceedings of this solemn assembly causes me to have the comforting assurance that the Lord, in his goodness, continues to provide inspired leadership and divine guidance to his church, the purpose of which is to build his kingdom</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03027_000_1030" doc-version="2" hash="3tVHFg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="Xcv4UTlveUaEYAJJdcIqyg" hash="M7Qkqg">Becoming a Somebody</h1><p class="authorName" guid="a8f5128c-8278-4a4e-bac6-29cbf1c2c3f7" pid="k3OgK_Tdy0-CV8fITJ4W_Q" hash="BFZRqQ">John H. Vandenberg</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="10d0d57e-9f4e-4a6e-8d88-5c02728c96a2">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p1" guid="d76f6f6b-7a0c-49d0-ac4d-3a6473773b3a" pid="k2xntIsxzEiakDCirJZx6Q" hash="GQHaHQ">The dignity of the proceedings of this solemn assembly causes me to have the comforting assurance that the Lord, in his goodness, continues to provide inspired leadership and divine guidance to his church, the purpose of which is to build his kingdom upon the earth and serve his children. His church extends the invitation to all who so desire to partake of the power of the gospel, which will lift an individual out of oblivion and, in so doing, will give a feeling of satisfaction and happiness not to be found elsewhere. It provides the sources of control for self-improvement, a stable character, and a truly successful life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p2" guid="14fdd1a3-85b2-4b79-b9b2-82d3a48c1111" pid="_uxiOG9MkEOD67q-ohqd8g" hash="5pVeAw">Who is there who has reached that point in life where he can afford to allow himself to stop growing or to stop improving? Although I never had the privilege of meeting her, I am told that my wife’s mother often repeated the adage to her children: “If you consider yourself a nobody and do nothing to improve yourself to become a somebody, you truly will end up being a nobody.” She, no doubt, understood the power and capacity of every soul for self-improvement.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p3" guid="c6901815-725b-4fd7-92ac-3b3e36aa5746" pid="qmH5zfNl2UCj9IZZyEEr9g" hash="wVRqaw">It is highly doubtful that there is even one soul upon the earth, regardless of station or age, who does not have ample room for personal growth and improvement. Quoting the words of one of the Lord’s prophets: “If we are no better tomorrow than we are today, we are not very useful.” (David O. McKay, <span class="emphasis">Pathways to Happiness </span>[Bookcraft, 1957], p. 292.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p4" guid="2f574c87-4509-4aa6-b052-b0eb76c46672" pid="P_EtPDkBpU2qAGsK9xzZgQ" hash="O35c_A">The sad part of humanity seems to be the utter lack of desire, in the lives of many, to really do something about enlarging the vistas of their existence. A distinguished doctor made the observation that “for the great majority of people, the good life is identical with trivial entertainment, cheap music, superficial writing, and an unending stream of visual trash. Their life is divorced from an enthusiastic faith in the future. It is focused on immediate pleasures sustained by a simplification of the grave problems pressing upon them.” (Dr. E. A. Gutkind, <span class="emphasis">Quote—the Weekly Digest, </span>vol. 51, no. 4, quote 32.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p5" guid="eb8bc417-cabd-44ce-88b1-04104c5be666" pid="COK_HxASu0uLUE8qu0XdUg" hash="U6hV7Q">Rather than accepting the challenge to change and grow, this type of person seemingly refuses to recognize the need to constructively reorganize portions of his life. One wonders, will the time ever come that will cause a reflection back on their lives? If so, their reaction could very well be as is expressed in a newspaper cartoon, under the heading “Ziggy,” which said: “It’s kind of a disappointment, after reflecting on your life, to finally come face-to-face with yourself in a mud puddle.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p6" guid="7959458c-6bb9-406f-9d33-08cf5bb152d6" pid="16iBl8Sas06RlMIyrTXSvQ" hash="CAPtHA">Listening to a commentator recently, I was impressed by a related idea. His comments included the following:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p7" guid="c62a7b17-aaad-481f-aef7-b74d60f7a7a3" pid="VRRCedXfDUaHzbYtm8wH5w" hash="qOhsrg">“Lin Yutang, the famous Chinese philosopher, has written: ‘We do not know a nation until we know its pleasures of life, just as we do not know a man until we know how he spends his leisure. It is when a man ceases to do the things he has to do, and does the things he likes to do, that the character is revealed. It is when the repressions of society and business are gone and when the goads of money and fame and ambition are lifted, and a man’s spirit wanders where it listeth, that we see the inner man, his real self.’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p8" guid="5ff775a2-8a49-4ee5-b836-4c1f7c94910a" pid="ITjYn34mSkyF5gXrFqZDxg" hash="bh_3Gw">Then he continued: “Have you ever thought much about that? Your leisure gives you away. I used to know a man who was head of a very large commercial empire. Beginning with nothing but ambition, he became a multimillionaire and, finally, retired as head of his far-flung company. He bought a large and magnificent yacht with which to cruise the world. And do you know what he did with his free time? He read salacious paperbacks and got falling-down drunk and had to be carried to bed, unconscious, every night. He’s dead now. His leisure gave him away. There was nothing there … just nothing at all. He was a one idea man. Once he was away from that idea, he was a lost child in the wilderness. He didn’t enjoy his yacht … travel meant nothing to him. He was a pitiful, unhappy cypher. Not because he was rich … there are thousands, millions just like him in every walk of life. It was just that his millions, which gave him access to the whole world, were worthless to him and accentuated his nothingness.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p9" guid="a6d25571-e5c7-4c48-b48a-c1fad76de778" pid="yIP24pQ8MkqbdZoNHQ0KZg" hash="xNckzg">Then the commentator asked the question: “What do you do with your leisure time? It’s a good idea to examine carefully this important segment of your life. It exposes the real person—but not the finished person. We can change. …” (Earl Nightingale, “Our Changing World,” No. 2459. Used by permission.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p10" guid="cdacaae6-5f9d-4f3c-ad65-99c48bb745db" pid="3lWn9viFbUS0LXp4zDwf7g" hash="VmcLew">Change is what it will take to bring any individual out of the dilemma of living with principles of error. I believe the greatest force in the world to cause such a change is the gospel of Jesus Christ. The apostle Paul experienced one of the greatest such changes that took place in any man, and he concluded: “For I am not ashamed of the gospel of Christ: for it is the power of God unto salvation to every one that believeth. …” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/1.16" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 1:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p11" guid="93496faa-74e5-4cc7-9b84-ff6190827afd" pid="gGeQWAFAO0iCPBsQYjXhuA" hash="LfirHg">The fourth Article of Faith reads: “We believe that the first principles and ordinances of the Gospel are: first, Faith in the Lord Jesus Christ; second, Repentance; third, Baptism by immersion for the remission of sins; fourth, Laying on of hands for the gift of the Holy Ghost.” [<a href="/scriptures/pgp/a-of-f/1.4" class="scriptureRef">A of F 1:4</a>.] As we briefly consider each of these principles, we will be aware of the power embodied in each of them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p12" guid="eaeabd84-5045-40de-8ca7-fac732f4c3bf" pid="yRC-5Ut_JEuJ-g9ZzlDqFQ" hash="0ms-RA">Faith is a principle of power. It is the cause of action. A prime example was taught by the Savior as we read in the seventeenth chapter of Matthew:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p13" guid="fc2e018a-6c05-4686-8d32-f3a3b35e16a5" pid="Ri18SGYywEOHG2jixSkcdQ" hash="FL4V2Q">“And when they were come to the multitude, there came to him a certain man, kneeling down to him, and saying,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p14" guid="c821ff9b-24de-47af-891c-685642a45d8d" pid="AIIuWb2mN0uJB4glif3JoQ" hash="PgXiUQ">“Lord, have mercy on my son: for he is lunatick, and sore vexed: for ofttimes he falleth into the fire, and oft into the water.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p15" guid="730a2ac6-0532-48da-8a2e-3e435de1209c" pid="GN0q568D2UqqaF8KsWedKw" hash="jMK2-A">“And I brought him to thy disciples, and they could not cure him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p16" guid="6bd60418-5173-40cf-bd88-caf6108a0725" pid="dNtk05E3O0qia9vzHskInA" hash="-WaolQ">“And Jesus rebuked the devil; and he departed out of him: and the child was cured from that very hour.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p17" guid="0be0a3bf-7eb6-4305-84a2-be09863c4a0d" pid="HVBntxoMwkSmeVAC4eWEeA" hash="vqChPw">“Then came the disciples to Jesus apart, and said, Why could not we cast him out?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p18" guid="44726adf-a494-41d0-b36a-87ddba943286" pid="o8pAZf3Z20ehlB_3NzqlGg" hash="hNpcMQ">“And Jesus said unto them, because of your unbelief: for verily I say unto you, If ye have faith as a grain of mustard seed, ye shall say unto this mountain, Remove hence to yonder place; and it shall remove; and nothing shall be impossible unto you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p19" guid="e30a6416-68aa-488f-9840-5483a144c9a4" pid="0aNEKHVLPkycIRTxyF4Msg" hash="cKBKOw">“Howbeit this kind goeth not out but by prayer and fasting.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/17.14-16,18-20" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 17:14–16, 18–20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p20" guid="3a6bae6b-24cf-4052-b79f-5d3ea1d37e4a" pid="bKMI3q8RLkqWnjoqOzQnwA" hash="P319iw">The evidence of the power of faith is clearly defined by the Savior. Faith in God will cause the miracle of change and set the course of action on the true purpose of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p21" guid="35433e33-5943-4d53-a627-e83026774d0a" pid="HnN9PcjbdEy2ahzBaMv5rw" hash="PS0P9Q">Repentance follows faith as naturally as the day follows dawn. The poet writes: “The morning breaks, the shadows flee.” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns, </span>no. 269.) Repentance is the very essence of change; it embodies the powerful principle of obedience to God’s law and discipline of self. When applied to our lives, it provides a cleansing joy which surges through us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p22" guid="4642b989-e2eb-4b9e-bc0c-2096f0e8dccb" pid="2xpRRwFYxU6kXR0hziR_zg" hash="ssQXGg">It has been said: “Disgrace clings to no man after repenting, any more than feet defiled with mud of the world, come yet soiled and polluted from the cleansing bath.” (Spurgeon.) King Benjamin gives further emphasis to this thought:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p23" guid="15ea60ae-915a-49bf-a5cb-d116f3969c32" pid="RWWzt4ZZGUaCTIw6R0iz0g" hash="hOxESA">“And again, believe that ye must repent of your sins and forsake them, and humble yourselves before God; and ask in sincerity of heart that he would forgive you; and now, if you believe all these things see that ye do them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p24" guid="13421865-ad5d-42a0-9e44-bc7b4979880e" pid="FCV23JBRn0mH9ANAYIcBRw" hash="h4RUOw">“And behold, I say unto you that if ye do this ye shall always rejoice, and be filled with the love of God, and always retain a remission of your sins; and ye shall grow in knowledge of the glory of him that created you. …” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.10,12" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:10, 12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p25" guid="28b28785-568c-4290-b644-c9cf713dcecd" pid="yjAtA-SmIk-6JeElJd-Wdg" hash="hgRNfg">Baptism requires obedience to the law of God. The divine fiat has been to call all men to repent and be baptized. Baptism is a companion to repentance. It is a principle and an ordinance of the gospel, and when complied with, it is the power of entering into the kingdom of God on earth. Jesus complied with this ordinance to fulfill all righteousness. The prophet Nephi said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p26" guid="1c818a88-35d5-4d75-98c7-dc95e165e1ad" pid="nMtiN21Rn0aLv5Z2Jp_20w" hash="SToztQ">“And now, if the Lamb of God, he being holy, should have need to be baptized by water, to fulfil all righteousness, O then, how much more need have we, being unholy, to be baptized, yea, even by water!” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.5" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p27" guid="0dbd6252-6932-4141-aba1-6e02d396c7fd" pid="pOZA1SPiL0KuXif098etdQ" hash="wrodqQ">The efficacy of the ordinance of baptism is unquestionable as it cleanses the reborn person.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p28" guid="667d28f4-a53b-4120-9777-54397d81ceb5" pid="gHksB-WsRkWe4-cbx4ePRQ" hash="AMFZzA">Baptism prepares the individual to receive the rebirth of the spirit, the laying on of hands, for the gift of the Holy Ghost. Joseph Fielding Smith brings to mind these words from the Prophet Joseph Smith:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p29" guid="f96c7abe-75c6-4dfe-b875-08258c5a7bb3" pid="Wg4pVtJI9UOY7tEZkSkBBA" hash="3I4NbA">
        <span class="emphasis">“There is a difference between the Holy Ghost and the gift of the Holy Ghost.</span> Cornelius received the Holy Ghost before he was baptized, which was the convincing power of God unto him of the truth of the Gospel, but he could not receive the gift of the Holy Ghost until after he was baptized. Had he not taken this sign or ordinance upon him, the Holy Ghost which convinced him of the truth of God, would have left him. Until he obeyed these ordinances and received the gift of the Holy Ghost, by the laying on of hands, according to the order of God, he could not have healed the sick or commanded an evil spirit to come out of a man, and it obey him. …” President Smith says further: “It mattereth not whether we live long or short on the earth after we come to a knowledge of these principles and obey them unto the end.” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith </span>[Deseret Book, 1961], p. 199.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p30" guid="eb58fce8-d323-4ae6-977d-773a5d08a4cf" pid="WY4Qit0JpUOf5C8FVaXhcg" hash="_-uang">In these principles we find the unfailing power to change. As to the effective use of our leisure time, we have, in the gospel, unnumbered opportunities. As one acquires knowledge of the gospel principles and pursues his course, he can successfully apply those principles to his individual circumstances, whether his position be one of great or meager possessions; whether it be early in life, during his economic production period, or in retirement. The gospel is meant to temper life and to bring it into true balance and fruition.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p31" guid="d0a233f9-d4c1-464b-ab7d-b214974b54f9" pid="r4NP_YuhSEaS9c8YN4R6lw" hash="PFZ4Bg">The Lord has decreed that “the Church hath need of every member.” (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.110" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:110</a>.) This implies development of its members by participation in the programmed activities of children and youth, filling the numerous teaching opportunities, administration assignments, fulfillment of member duties, the fulfillment of priesthood duties, not forgetting to visit the homes of members (which, until this day, has not been attended to as the Lord directed), searching out the records of ancestors, and temple participation, all of which are only part of the never-ending list of activities with which to fill our leisure hours.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p32" guid="86498e29-938a-44c4-8072-c417ada77402" pid="qEmyBT07eEep9fovFw6aKg" hash="79iWLA">The individual power is attested to in this scripture: “Verily I say, men should be anxiously engaged in a good cause, and do many things of their own free will, and bring to pass much righteousness; For the power is in them, wherein they are agents unto themselves. And inasmuch as men do good they shall in nowise lose their reward.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.27-28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:27–28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p33" guid="80aca00c-c50a-4f71-b245-2f58a6a8ae98" pid="0h80F5y5Q0itZRYTnX7WZA" hash="t9MIoQ">As we consider the aspects of growth and achievement, the word <span class="emphasis">success </span>obviously comes to the fore—success as it applies in terms of the world. Success or failure can carry most of us either to the peaks of happiness or to the depths of despair. People will do almost anything to keep from being branded a failure.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p34" guid="804f020f-dd93-44e2-ab30-40eb4b29f1bb" pid="RqE2G_J6mkOEQp_0BnNpFg" hash="cqUvYg">If a man achieves worldly success and does not blend into his life a program of self-improvement to bring about a sensible balance, he no doubt will end up as a failure. He may win the honor of men, but what about his salvation—his eternal future? Think back on the example of the man with the yacht. Was he successful? Worldly-wise, yes! But when it comes to the things that count, wasn’t he more like the man who “spent all his life letting down empty buckets into empty wells; and he is frittering away his age in trying to draw them up again”? (Sydney Smith in John Bartlett’s <span class="emphasis">Familiar Quotations, </span>p. 523.) Such people seek fulfillment and meaning in their lives but are unable to find it, because they themselves have misplaced their values.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p35" guid="4c55b697-45c1-435e-8367-a7b14680d2a5" pid="mM_rgFB4OkuV0ykV34TFJQ" hash="4hJXPA">Recently at a stake priesthood meeting I was greeted by two good convert brethren from the Netherlands, one of whom I like to think I had some participation in his conversion. I turned to him and asked: “Have you ever been sorry for having joined the Church?” His eyes brightened, and he responded with happy enthusiasm, saying, “No, never!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p36" guid="22c58165-e2ea-4612-a8dd-9c7539c3cdab" pid="VL80IlPBCUO4PjiSz8qWLA" hash="hRHkNg">Here, in my opinion, was a successful man. No doubt he had many vicissitudes in his life. His worldly possessions were probably minimal, but his good works—treasures in heaven—are innumerable. Here is evidence of just one of the thousands—millions—who have had similar experiences of becoming a “somebody.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody.p37" guid="b7824749-6727-4a3f-937e-69fedcb9a5b5" pid="0HtXJzJabEKP0XUXnx3E9A" hash="2hXytw">And I ask you, brethren, sisters, where would we be, where would you be, where would I be, if it were not for the power of the gospel of Christ? I bear witness to its power and I do so in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/10/becoming-a-somebody</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1972-general-conference/1972-10-1040-elder-john-h-vandenberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="6893262" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 1972 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Agency of Man</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man?lang=eng</link>
      <description>It was a wintry Sunday morning in northern New York. The temperature was several degrees below freezing. The walks were icy; roads were blocked with heavy snowdrifts. No one came to church that morning except the minister and an 89-year-old woman, wh</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03033_000_2030" doc-version="2" hash="f-5S7w"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="DOkfYEmov0m3ZaF8EkNgwg" hash="TbK3Fw">The Agency of Man</h1><p class="authorName" guid="a8f5128c-8278-4a4e-bac6-29cbf1c2c3f7" pid="84NYOBnsWUWZKKcVhMbkNA" hash="BFZRqQ">John H. Vandenberg</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="3ccb7b22-819a-4dea-bd08-253a7fd4ca3b">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p1" guid="1ac6c7e7-09c8-4343-879e-d3925675ce4c" pid="5PkUj0CRTU-ruzkuTbLaQA" hash="q704YQ">It was a wintry Sunday morning in northern New York. The temperature was several degrees below freezing. The walks were icy; roads were blocked with heavy snowdrifts. No one came to church that morning except the minister and an 89-year-old woman, who had hobbled ten blocks from where she lived.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p2" guid="0ef1be7d-75ce-4b86-b543-9dc2352363e1" pid="j2pFXIWZT0u-tvAa4zzomA" hash="HO08wA">Surprised at seeing her, the minister called her by name and asked: “How did you get here on such a stormy morning?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p3" guid="d3789dca-a86e-47a8-8311-02722843e182" pid="SKBjFzoblkevMXTX-_N4Rg" hash="DPThBg">“My heart gets here first,” was the cheerful reply, “and then it’s easy for the rest of me.” (<span class="emphasis">Quote, </span>January 26, 1973, p. 5.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p4" guid="7a7089d1-dcf7-457e-a718-a4fbe553f57d" pid="DcUdbQGN-kus10hlea_KoQ" hash="yObETQ">This simple illustration brings to mind that all individuals are confronted with decisions to make every day, and whatever the choice, it is commensurate with the persuasion of the heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p5" guid="fbce0ac5-4b0e-47eb-8e31-b782c38e15bc" pid="gVojihPCMk6NkJPeqoJc0w" hash="k5xLfg">These persuasions of the heart are related to two opposing forces constantly at work within every human being. They are the forces of good and evil, which the Master referred to as God and mammon. Coupled with these forces is the individual’s power to reason, which only man, of all God’s creations, possesses. This enables him to make choices. It is man’s control valve of what he wants to be. The forces governed by his own reasoning determine the nature and quality of the choice made. Thus, that which we call character is formed. We refer to this privilege of choice as the agency of man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p6" guid="819d6fa6-3734-4158-9f1e-6dd48d54b85a" pid="lwkcxeR_6kOGAyPBGLk4Ww" hash="le-1Ng">It has been said that “every day is election day, for throughout every hour of every day we each exercise our right of choice. We don’t have to have a local or national election in order to elect or vote. … A man’s election can determine the deciding vote for or against his own success. … You elect to gain a thorough knowledge of your business or you don’t. You elect to be honest or you don’t. You elect to save a part of what you earn or you don’t. You elect to always do your best or you don’t. And by your own election you will be defeated or you will succeed.” (Jim Love, <span class="emphasis">R&amp;R Magazine, </span>Research and Review Service of America, Inc., vol. 10, p. 64.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p7" guid="79832396-f3df-473c-8a3b-b9a71e8fa0b4" pid="0qGqJvJxK0m8cyeM-2DCwA" hash="je4L1Q">Our Father in heaven was aware of the reality of this principle of agency in the beginning. We read from the scriptures in some detail:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p8" guid="e18ea554-e71f-4664-8514-b95fb03d2c25" pid="hYJAUI3NwkaBwYB_9CSDYA" hash="cwZwcg">“Now the Lord had shown unto me, Abraham, the intelligences that were organized before the world was; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p9" guid="fc271d03-f7b3-4415-8428-bc7d9fe1d779" pid="KnKAL3Sqg0aFcckYwFJ5PQ" hash="P7cx3w">“And God saw these souls that they were good. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p10" guid="9c35eda0-356a-4bbb-a2b2-2be6a1fb83b1" pid="ninHdtHXokOtDsjZ1EbmlA" hash="qVYDSQ">“And there stood one among them that was like unto God, and he said unto those who were with him: We will go down, for there is space there, and we will take of these materials, and we will make an earth whereon these may dwell;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p11" guid="36e2e895-d295-48c5-b284-92f40fbf355a" pid="g9QoHjen8kSJonLwiJfKlw" hash="otfHCw">“And we will prove them herewith, to see if they will do all things whatsoever the Lord their God shall command them;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p12" guid="0bb20178-8c7f-4cf8-8636-c96f63a23b7d" pid="jWSh3W4PTE6D3INQH_Rcpg" hash="82W1jA">“And they who keep their first estate shall be added upon; … and they who keep their second estate shall have glory added upon their heads for ever and ever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p13" guid="332c6938-d022-4f7f-bc2e-4c8733fb2892" pid="NYkiW_Hzok--uREaTtau8w" hash="adSguQ">“And the Lord said: Whom shall I send? And one answered like unto the Son of Man: Here am I, send me.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.22-27" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:22–27</a>.) And that one said, “Father, thy will be done, and the glory be thine forever.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/4.2" class="scriptureRef">Moses 4:2</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p14" guid="308b0620-b573-4352-b0b9-252cf5ae6c02" pid="dEu4xsiHsEqGLkuGp8UNUA" hash="nGBy1w">“… And another answered and said: Here am I, send me.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.27" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p15" guid="a4d6cced-4061-42d0-8e2f-5bd645d62222" pid="RJ87Dov91UO-5Zhm-FQs5A" hash="C9yk3g">“I will be thy son, and I will redeem all mankind, that one soul shall not be lost, and surely I will do it; wherefore give me thine honor.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/4.1" class="scriptureRef">Moses 4:1</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p16" guid="5c073d85-06f0-43d3-9de9-9083b625472c" pid="VFRtuVDK3kal8OrYZlm89g" hash="JWuyoQ">“… And the Lord said: I will send the first.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p17" guid="9e6fb0ad-7e7f-492c-9465-483a7817c6e9" pid="3b5YbqUhcUaRDgnATQFnFg" hash="RTMl0A">“And the second was angry, and kept not his first estate. …” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.27-28" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:27–28</a>.) “And he became Satan, … the father of all lies, to deceive and to blind men, and to lead them captive at his will, even as many as would not hearken unto my voice.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/4.4" class="scriptureRef">Moses 4:4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p18" guid="25b66a02-c74e-466f-aa1e-f46a9ddceb2e" pid="P0xKZJrnhkGg0VxTR4l_uQ" hash="pkmxhg">Satan rebelled against God and “sought to destroy the agency of man, which I, the Lord God, had given him. …” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/4.3" class="scriptureRef">Moses 4:3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p19" guid="67889dbe-a6a2-481f-b982-2e3cf9ef4017" pid="HypHLAn98UGyf9-TplOgQA" hash="cf-7-w">Unfortunately, many do not realize the quality and blessing of that gift of agency of man. If we would but reason the matter, we would come to realize as is expressed in this thought: “Choice is an element of human dignity. Without the power of choice, a man is a lot less than a man. Without the exercise of choice a man never discovers what he can be or what he can do. Choice is the key to the future.” (George E. Farling, “Youth Can’t, But Must,” <span class="emphasis">Weslyan Methodist.)</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p20" guid="23579f2d-3a44-41dd-bbdb-c8171acadd1a" pid="nPsb52S6kUC32P8pxbgOVg" hash="GaWo2g">Since the authorship of the agency of man is God’s, should we not look to him for the best media to help us to control our choices? The media he has given to us are the words spoken by his prophets, as are recorded in the scriptures. Jesus confirms this in responding to the recreant Jews of his time, who accused him of breaking the Sabbath by healing a man on that day. He included in his rebuke to them these words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p21" guid="e7ca1abd-8294-4039-91b8-f8e91ca44439" pid="lNU2jtYCe0uV8Ss5k-RoMA" hash="-IZn8A">“And the Father himself, which hath sent me, hath borne witness of me. Ye have neither heard his voice at any time, nor seen his shape.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p22" guid="597d06c7-2706-42da-a678-b868172ff0e7" pid="UTSTsDbxdEGYlGokuZ9hlg" hash="1fMMoA">“And ye have not his word abiding in you: for whom he hath sent, him ye believe not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p23" guid="1c282f9d-3f13-4761-9601-1ce186b96b69" pid="sL1iap8Yk0-RjIwO9oW_bQ" hash="zsCvyQ">“Search the scriptures; for in them ye think ye have eternal life: and they are they which testify of me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p24" guid="63445e6c-af0c-4688-8672-0cfaff14a792" pid="JJILBcnAg02e5P1iz1q9mg" hash="9uyMgQ">“And ye will not come to me, that ye might have life.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.37-40" class="scriptureRef">John 5:37–40</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p25" guid="4cdb450f-173a-49ad-b239-9daaa48948e8" pid="v3gPX2sovESxE_Op4WujZQ" hash="LOxCSw">The guide to the answer to their problem was to be found in the scriptures. He rebuked them for not accepting the scriptures that they had. The guide to the solution to every problem of life is to be found there. The knowledge on which to pursue our reasoning is in them. Listen to the counsel of Paul to Timothy:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p26" guid="325f9856-ed4d-446d-bbe7-549f313191ea" pid="LyyaG9FuD0KZdU4DltZPBA" hash="Vn5TkQ">“And that from a child thou hast known the holy scriptures, which are able to make thee wise unto salvation through faith which is in Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p27" guid="d95ce29b-ebd9-4b60-9188-26e4a659c716" pid="9cSKaq5XjEmBLhICqAJjcg" hash="GyXxPQ">“All scripture is given by inspiration of God, and is profitable for doctrine, for reproof, for correction, for instruction in righteousness:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p28" guid="e34afe5e-1b95-40c0-bb90-a62cc8d472d2" pid="Hl5fsA5wPkS689tw15SP6Q" hash="hcryAQ">“That the man of God may be perfect, throughly furnished unto all good works.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/3.15-17" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 3:15–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p29" guid="929dd221-d420-4be3-b626-c2119c6d101d" pid="ebASTeOuN0qg9ln3yRfz1g" hash="pFXGEQ">As fellow workers for the cause of building the kingdom of God, they are our source of faith, commitment, determination, and leadership; doctrine for the foundation of our decisions. Let us refer to the scriptures for a few well-known examples to illustrate. I refer to the example of the faith of Job, a very affluent, God-fearing man, having much of the world’s goods and a fine family. Overnight, he suffered the sudden loss of all his earthly possessions and his children and then responded to the situation with faith and realism.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p30" guid="e23af2ac-a72e-4fff-af17-14ff563f5274" pid="y5BgOKAQH0mRKRnaZIKdOQ" hash="igCOAw">He “rent his mantle, and shaved his head, and fell down upon the ground, and worshipped,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p31" guid="5c3a040f-7fe8-4c67-aaf8-c1200a7c0c0f" pid="R6Roj-uNNEKs82uCcnGBZg" hash="fqK_5g">“And said, Naked came I out of my mother’s womb, and naked shall I return thither: the Lord gave, and the Lord hath taken away; blessed be the name of the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/job/1.20-21" class="scriptureRef">Job 1:20–21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p32" guid="95cea15e-1503-4b97-82bb-56b1968f687b" pid="uoWAjqok20GuQUIj2EcBHg" hash="it4VhQ">Then upon being rendered with bodily affliction and poor health, his own wife chided him and said to him, “Dost thou still retain thine integrity? curse God, and die.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p33" guid="27c0cc20-b85e-4627-8672-2910a462ed05" pid="9oCt4Xc1j0aomp5B5DBA4Q" hash="jaHmzA">Job answered, “Thou speakest as one of the foolish women speaketh. What? shall we receive good at the hand of God, and shall we not receive evil?” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/job/2.9-10" class="scriptureRef">Job 2:9–10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p34" guid="70a41f81-9a9a-4c5b-add2-49dfc9c33699" pid="lV4ABCB2QEavkVwcVwCwCg" hash="rfl17A">And then in the midst of all his afflictions, Job gave this testimony: “For I know that my redeemer liveth, and that he shall stand at the latter day upon the earth: And though after my skin worms destroy this body, yet in my flesh shall I see God.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/job/19.25-26" class="scriptureRef">Job 19:25–26</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p35" guid="009572a2-1e98-4d0e-a9cd-f515690f19f6" pid="Z2PyEBvdXEe6wngX4bTe_A" hash="jxdG0Q">As to commitment, is there a more touching example of devotion than Ruth to her mother-in-law, Naomi, as Naomi pled with Ruth to return to her own people following the death of her husband, when Ruth clave unto her and said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p36" guid="00f54d55-2ead-4e56-94e0-75f0a59d2065" pid="haUo58YNikuoBBSL4miXVg" hash="qar3dQ">“Intreat me not to leave thee, or to return from following after thee: for whither thou goest, I will go; and where thou lodgest, I will lodge: thy people shall be my people, and thy God my God:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p37" guid="f585b349-f075-41d5-ae28-bd8061f37ca6" pid="TPe5LVLg4UyLWoIX8pMm1Q" hash="l1KOUA">“Where thou diest, will I die, and there will I be buried: the Lord do so to me, and more also, if ought but death part thee and me.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ruth/1.16-17" class="scriptureRef">Ruth 1:16–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p38" guid="3da547c5-b995-43e4-86d7-69c6646ce9db" pid="fNHcfqCKXkSTxck0eI4VXg" hash="ngHxVA">And Queen Esther, in her determination to save her kindred people from destruction, seeking God’s help through fasting, instructed Mordecai: “Go, gather together all the Jews that are present in Shushan, and fast ye for me, and neither eat nor drink three days, night or day: I also and my maidens will fast likewise; and so will I go in unto the king, which is not according to the law: and if I perish, I perish.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/esth/4.16" class="scriptureRef">Esth. 4:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p39" guid="58a27970-e19a-44f9-b058-6a19324f009a" pid="ycxclDxsHEGEZ_XFkLcLjQ" hash="CVdu-w">And Joshua the leader, as he turned the hearts of the belligerent people by his example of choice, spoke to them: “Now therefore fear the Lord, and serve him in sincerity and in truth: and put away the gods which your fathers served on the other side of the flood, and in Egypt; and serve ye the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p40" guid="7c957bee-cac2-4c84-a004-0b5f43cf177d" pid="JfTCLU-fkkKDIsA7FUuHrw" hash="pDPqhQ">“And if it seem evil unto you to serve the Lord, choose you this day whom ye will serve; whether the gods which your fathers served that were on the other side of the flood, or the gods of the Amorites, in whose land ye dwell: but as for me and my house, we will serve the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p41" guid="b89ff52d-237e-4aca-b587-d1b9cdd2d31c" pid="ohfrvduH302GT72YGvVazw" hash="B-y02Q">“And the people answered and said, God forbid that we should forsake the Lord, to serve other gods;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p42" guid="07ff95d5-9d93-47aa-8aab-71fb76536fed" pid="U1tKY0gYp0a7dAWN41ROEQ" hash="ydD5GA">“And the people said unto Joshua, The Lord our God will we serve, and his voice will we obey.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/24.14-16,24" class="scriptureRef">Josh. 24:14–16, 24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p43" guid="4bc72261-fd41-4d10-9024-c856b410a392" pid="dv78KIoThEOiGb7hAZCBIA" hash="zzabJA">These are but a few of the unnumbered examples to be found in the scriptures, but even as we examine these few evidences of outstanding characters, our spirits receive the inspiration of their strength. Reasoning tells us that the development of their lives had to be built on making proper choices. They were established on truth. Their examples teach us celestial lessons.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p44" guid="340d8a76-395f-455a-9843-56c187c71c64" pid="4JXL7L8CeEmURAvhCQ5_BA" hash="zJDHVQ">The Lord’s call to us is: “Come now, and let us reason together. …” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/1.18" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 1:18</a>.) He wants us to listen to and consider his doctrine. The scriptures tell us this: “… that men might be made partakers of the glories which were to be revealed, the Lord sent forth the fulness of his gospel, his everlasting covenant, reasoning in plainness and simplicity.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/133.57" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 133:57</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p45" guid="032e7f0a-8894-4438-846d-90a59dd60252" pid="pRuLKvCrg02xAptT1UK2gw" hash="DhbCjw">He wants us to become acquainted with his gospel, to test it, to prove it, to participate in it, and to use it as a base on which to make our decisions. This is that men might base their choices on truth. When reason is joined with truth, there is convincing logic that sets up the path in our hearts that leads upward and onward to a nobler life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p46" guid="0a0a40e2-8c00-42b0-8aad-d10f9aecba0d" pid="b66Lz9NjIUy4Xyz8aKD4Bw" hash="au2VEQ">Reason is only compatible with truth. Error and evil, no matter how one may try to reason with it, still remain error and evil leading to chaos. It is difficult to understand that anyone, after examining the truth, could “say unto God, Depart from us; for we desire not the knowledge of thy ways.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/job/21.14" class="scriptureRef">Job 21:14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p47" guid="e07976e7-ecc9-4dc5-897c-a8cd560fcc95" pid="J3yO7O1aHU6poGtlWa4q7w" hash="YMFP6w">One of the sad expressions of the scriptures is when Christ said: “O Jerusalem, Jerusalem, thou that killest the prophets, and stonest them which are sent unto thee, how often would I have gathered thy children together, even as a hen gathereth her chickens under her wings, and ye would not! Behold, your house is left unto you desolate.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/23.title" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 23: 37–38</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p48" guid="16b05d7d-874e-474f-874c-40f8da25a104" pid="l9naBjgvOUiBL38wgdupqQ" hash="Eu6I0Q">The expression is applicable in this day to those who deliberately will not come and reason with the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p49" guid="6b5578c9-8775-4f21-9eac-7b9641aafd70" pid="DFNu3ucb6EWyjYQ8pp1kTQ" hash="qLcoJQ">Let us incline our hearts toward God, that we may receive these words of John:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p50" guid="7b670c5f-6403-41a9-a988-4554c5bff68b" pid="7a0oyuqvIUyxhwY-lsO2Cw" hash="rpAc_g">“Beloved, if our heart condemn us not, then have we confidence toward God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p51" guid="0206a09b-da1a-4282-b64b-fdc83ccfe300" pid="yy0M4GS0mUy6V1fhY6pVhQ" hash="jTTx1A">“And whatsoever we ask, we receive of him, because we keep his commandments, and do those things that are pleasing in his sight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p52" guid="9e34e0d0-8ab8-4bd6-8208-527396b2f093" pid="45uH8rODoU2vcTQfWyOTkw" hash="RdG-og">“And this is his commandment, That we should believe on the name of his Son Jesus Christ, and love one another, as he gave us commandment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p53" guid="69550827-93da-4065-9e8a-7dd4b1350052" pid="PfljSS3MgEeBRADV0I1w7Q" hash="JZtETA">“And he that keepeth his commandments dwelleth in him, and he in him. And hereby we know that he abideth in us, by the Spirit which he hath given us.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-jn/3.21-24" class="scriptureRef">1 Jn. 3:21–24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man.p54" guid="ff1a89ce-c86f-4429-bb77-ef652e95b194" pid="BikluMHIgEyL7N23BLH9fg" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1973/04/the-agency-of-man</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1973-general-conference/1973-04-2060-elder-john-h-vandenberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="6509814" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 1973 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Touchstone of Truth</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Visiting with some of the members of the Church at the Munich conference last summer, a young lady, a recent convert, queried: “Since we are members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, why do we refer to ourselves as Mormons?”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03044_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="j61-RA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="8qMLDnZ7hkGdrlPpZG6fKg" hash="l9bFUA">Touchstone of Truth</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="3U4joucgh0K0EgnbekD7Ng" hash="BFZRqQ">John H. Vandenberg</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p1" pid="wUMSu6iumUGMkXljKSOrjw" hash="GKwA9A">Visiting with some of the members of the Church at the Munich conference last summer, a young lady, a recent convert, queried: “Since we are members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, why do we refer to ourselves as Mormons?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p2" pid="WL49VepUr02sN8Y2m9Jccg" hash="4ZykyA">Joseph Fielding Smith, in responding to a similar question, said: “The Nephites believed in Christ; they wrote and prophesied of him and his mission, and while there is no opprobrium that can justly be attached to one who believes in the Book of Mormon, there is no valid reason why Latter-day Saints should speak of themselves as ‘Mormons’ or of the Church as the ‘Mormon Church.’ … The mission of [the Church is] persuading people to believe in Christ, the Son of God, and of becoming members of His Church—the [true] church of Jesus Christ [of Latter-day Saints].” (Joseph Fielding Smith, <span class="emphasis">Answers to Gospel Questions,</span> Deseret Book Co., 1971, vol. 4, pp. 174–75.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p3" pid="h2QlTVj-i0-BoQD0qNj89Q" hash="irE9jQ">A flashback in my mind recalled to my memory an incident when two business acquaintances entered my office and greeted me with, “You’re a Mormon; tell us, where does the word <span class="emphasis">Mormon</span> come from and what is its meaning?” My response was, “The word <span class="emphasis">Mormon</span> was the name of an ancient prophet of God. He lived on the American continent a few hundred years after the advent of Christ. He had at his disposal a continuous religious and historical record of the people who had migrated to, and lived for hundreds of years on, the American continents. Mormon made an abridgment of these records, which contained the fullness of the gospel of Jesus Christ. The record was engraved on gold plates and deposited in a hill known as Cumorah, located in what we now know to be the state of New York. In this latter day, under divine direction, Joseph Smith obtained the plates and translated them by the power of God. This abridgment was titled the Book of Mormon. The meaning of the word, as given by Joseph Smith, is ‘more good.’” (See <span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith,</span> p. 300.) The gentlemen seemed interested, thanked me, and departed without further comment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p4" pid="0LMB7ffoTk-DnBckbE-pTQ" hash="oOUKGw">In retrospect I have recalled this experience and pondered over the words <span class="emphasis">more good,</span> which undoubtedly mean “an extension of the good.” Joseph Smith, in commenting on the subject, referred to the Bible as being “good.” As to the Book of Mormon, he stated: “It may be well to observe here, that the Lord greatly encouraged and strengthened the faith of his little flock, which had embraced the fulness of the everlasting Gospel, as revealed to them in the Book of Mormon, by giving some more extended information upon the scriptures. …” (<span class="emphasis">Documentary History of the Church,</span> vol. 1, pp. 131–32.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p5" pid="u1c_zWAbFk2lNvYgSUsRpg" hash="IIhZhQ">Religious history confirms through the Bible that the very basic truths—(1) the nature of the Godhead and (2) revelation through the prophets—which are essential to the salvation of mankind, were available to the religious leaders through the centuries before and after the advent of the Savior. Yet because of transgressions there was a turning away from these truths, and there was a fulfillment of the prediction of the apostle Paul, who said: “Now we beseech you, brethren, by the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ, and by our gathering together unto him,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p6" pid="HIAJNj7H0EGbalq8veldcg" hash="1s_tJA">“That ye be not soon shaken in mind, or be troubled, neither by spirit, nor by word, nor by letter as from us, as that day of Christ is at hand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p7" pid="EAPGeSuc50CcApaOK3WK-A" hash="Hb5B2w">“Let no man deceive you by any means: for that day shall not come, except there come a falling away first, and that man of sin be revealed, the son of perdition.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-thes/2.1-3" class="scriptureRef">2 Thes. 2:1–3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p8" pid="dIikcA5ggk2xVOnVA7UlUA" hash="JRmzNA">President Joseph Fielding Smith summed up well what had happened as he said: “It should be remembered that the entire Christian world in 1820 had lost the true doctrine concerning God. The simple truth which was understood so clearly by the apostles and saints of old had been lost in the mysteries of an apostate world. All the ancient prophets, and the apostles of Jesus Christ had a clear understanding that the Father and the Son were separate personages, as our scriptures so clearly teach. Through apostasy this knowledge was lost, and in the year 325 <small>A.D.</small>, a strange doctrine was introduced and soon spread throughout the Christian world. This doctrine confounded the persons of the Godhead, and distorted the true doctrine of God.” (Joseph Fielding Smith, <span class="emphasis">Answers to Gospel Questions,</span> vol. 3, p. 117.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p9" pid="dTuvfxe0cUiFebW9U0DCGg" hash="F6wN_w">There is no question that Jesus taught the very nature of God the Father, God the Son, and God the Holy Ghost—three personages of form and substance, individual and distinct. He taught that the true knowledge of the Godhead was essential to eternal life. He included in a prayer to his Father in heaven: “And this is life eternal, that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17:3</a>.) Other references in the scriptures substantiate the individuality of the Holy Ghost. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/3.15" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 3:15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p10" pid="uL87mvhzr0iRU5RGoOP6DQ" hash="J5yK3g">Yet in the light of this truth there was a “strange doctrine” introduced of man-made creeds. Says one: “There is but one God, the Creator of heaven and earth, the supreme, incorporeal, uncreated being, who exists of himself and is infinite in all his attributes. …” Says another: “There is one living and true God, everlasting, without body, parts, or passions; of infinite power, wisdom, and goodness.” Yet another says: “God is as he reveals himself. He is creative reality … He is expressive act … He is responsive power … He is one God experienced in a trinitarian fashion.” (Alvin R. Dyer, <span class="emphasis">The Meaning of Truth,</span> Deseret Book Co., 1961, p. 50.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p11" pid="Tx2jeEmknkWR29Vi30SJqA" hash="VQQkRQ">These are but a few examples of the extent of the departure from the true teachings of the scriptures. Now the Book of Mormon gives us an extension and reaffirmation of the true corporeal nature of a member of the Godhead. Jesus speaks to the brother of Jared, saying: “… therefore I show myself unto you. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p12" pid="6lxatqcs7k-LM3ntEcZ5sQ" hash="Xr7UbA">“… Behold, I am Jesus Christ …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p13" pid="M19qwolCzUeKX3zMYKD7QA" hash="td-BoA">“And never have I showed myself unto man whom I have created, for never has man believed in me as thou hast. Seest thou that ye are created after mine own image? …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p14" pid="bBNvy0ghPECQ7LRd0uPhBA" hash="YOclcQ">“Behold, this body, which ye now behold, is the body of my spirit; … and even as I appear unto thee to be in the spirit will I appear unto my people in the flesh.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/3.13-16" class="scriptureRef">Ether 3:13–16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p15" pid="ozsCESKMcEajJHZmaHehyg" hash="fK4GeA">Two thousand years later, this same Jesus came to earth in the same form and said: “… he that hath seen me hath seen the Father. …” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.9" class="scriptureRef">John 14:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p16" pid="QPTJkvKjWEm4n2NoWAE14A" hash="JcqRQQ">This corporeal individuality was substantiated by the Prophet Joseph Smith who had the revealing experience of seeing the Father and the Son in corporeal form and conversing with them. He specifically states: “The Father has a body of flesh and bones as tangible as man’s; the Son also; but the Holy Ghost has not a body of flesh and bones, but is a personage of Spirit. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/130.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 130:22</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p17" pid="L1U0Qjxo30-Eo6PuaolxdA" hash="bz8Gxw">Another basic scriptural truth is that Jesus taught that his church was founded upon the rock of revelation (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/16.16-18" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 16:16–18</a>), in harmony with the words of the prophet Amos, who declared: “Surely the Lord God will do nothing, but he revealeth his secret unto his servants the prophets.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/amos/3.7" class="scriptureRef">Amos 3:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p18" pid="8yrPy3Kgt0OusA7SpO6pcQ" hash="Rs7a4Q">There seems to be astonishment among mankind generally that God would speak again in this latter day. “The heavens are closed,” they declare. It was a dark day when the religious leaders declared that revelation had ceased and when they presumed that mankind could negotiate his way by his own wisdom, leaning on the arm of flesh. But “‘The world by wisdom know not God,’ so the world by speculation are destitute of revelation. …” (<span class="emphasis">DHC,</span> vol. 5, p. 400.) It was a glorious day when the doctrine of revelation was again restored to mankind in this latter day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p19" pid="4GpD0Lopa0q9DudqTkmuEw" hash="qTTcWA">Again the Book of Mormon gives us this expansion of this doctrine:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p20" pid="od9AUCaujUuAq01z16BT2Q" hash="RQVRww">“Behold, great and marvelous are the works of the Lord. How unsearchable are the depths of the mysteries of him; and it is impossible that man should find out all his ways. And no man knoweth of his ways save it be revealed unto him; wherefore, brethren, despise not the revelations of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p21" pid="uhatTHsmykiuTlH-Sh3mvQ" hash="YStGVw">“Wherefore, brethren, seek not to counsel the Lord, but to take counsel from his hand. For behold, ye yourselves know that he counseleth in wisdom, and in justice, and in great mercy, over all his works.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.8,10" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:8, 10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p22" pid="SbzmVZ6dJ0KVkhutI4zaFA" hash="ZLeD5Q">The whole purpose of the gospel is to teach men that the most important thing in life is life itself and that man may pursue happiness. “… Men are, that they might have joy” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.25" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:25</a>) is the decree of the Lord. The purpose of the Book of Mormon is to convince both Jew and gentile that Jesus is the Christ, for only through him can salvation, eternal life, and eternal joy be obtained.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p23" pid="nuoWmhWNNkGWgk26hApSLA" hash="8vXOXQ">There is great comfort in the knowledge of truth, for truth has the quality of certainty and authority. It has been said that “‘no pleasure is comparable to the standing upon the vantage ground of truth’ (a hill not to be commanded, and where the air is always clear and serene), ‘and to see the errors, and wanderings, and mists, and tempests, in the vale below’: so always that this prospect be with pity, and not with swelling pride. Certainly, it is heaven upon earth, to have a man’s mind move in charity, rest in providence, and turn upon the poles of truth.” (Francis Bacon, “On Truth.”)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p24" pid="fSsgDyGPu0KpgVfSNma_hw" hash="0PwB2Q">The Prophet Joseph Smith stood upon that vantage ground and spoke with authority. He said: “… The boldness of my plans and measures can readily be tested by the touchstone of … truth, for truth is a matter of fact; and the fact is, that by the power of God I translated the Book of Mormon from hieroglyphics, the knowledge of which was lost to the world; in which wonderful event I stood alone, an unlearned youth, to combat the worldly wisdom and multiplied ignorance of eighteen centuries with a new revelation, which (if they would receive the everlasting Gospel) would open the eyes of more than eight hundred millions of people, and make ‘plain the old paths,’ wherein ‘if a man walk in all the ordinances of God blameless’ he shall inherit eternal life. …” (George Q. Cannon, <span class="emphasis">Life of Joseph Smith the Prophet,</span> Deseret Book Co., 1964, p. 460.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p25" pid="chX-gf1Ek068BEAl_4ig5g" hash="PVe8MA">And further he said: “I told the brethren that the Book of Mormon was the most correct of any book on earth, and the keystone of our religion, and a man would get nearer to God by abiding by its precepts, than by any other book.” (<span class="emphasis">DHC,</span> vol. 4, p. 461.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p26" pid="MBjWPqDgOEeQJeNHhXl5Kg" hash="id-n2w">The promise is to every man that he may know the truth if he will accept the challenge to test it by the “touchstone of truth.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p27" pid="zX_sVb7TdEuQB9LzlX06tQ" hash="eo-9-A">So were the words of Jesus: “… My doctrine is not mine, but his that sent me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p28" pid="amuCghsSCEGrOpK18pDVSQ" hash="ubI3BA">“If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it be of God, or whether I speak of myself.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/7.16-17" class="scriptureRef">John 7:16–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p29" pid="RbG_iyOAgUWRMvFvfiujiQ" hash="GD49_w">So were the words of Mormon: “… I would exhort you that ye would ask God, the Eternal Father, in the name of Christ, if these things are not true; and if ye shall ask with a sincere heart, with real intent, having faith in Christ, he will manifest the truth of it unto you, by the power of the Holy Ghost.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.4" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p30" pid="WGD6MYnqB0az1OgkHpwsBA" hash="DwzUXQ">Many souls who have directed their inquiries in this manner can attest to the truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p31" pid="LneDgD-KvEuPU8b60fAS4w" hash="DxX4jw">With certainty the Book of Mormon is a pure and holy record, having been recorded by prophets under the guidance of our Heavenly Father, having been hid up for hundreds of years unto the Lord, having been revealed and translated by the power of God in the latter day. It is an undefiled record, undisturbed by the wisdom of man, uncorrupted by the designs of men—a light on a hill to beckon all to come unto Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p32" pid="WBLOdnND00K4FhdwpxSmDA" hash="obv7Wg">Yes, we talk of Mormon; we respect him as a man of God. We accept his recorded doctrine as divine. He stands among the great men of God. His great book written under divine command stands without blemish. It is truth. Its teachings give strength and gladness to the heart. Yet it is not likely that Mormon would desire the true church to be called after him, for he testified of Jesus Christ and his mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth.p33" pid="UvTZZOVRf0awvZV3wAOZyQ" hash="zryw-A">May we ponder the privilege of being members of the Church of Jesus Christ and live according to its precepts, I humbly pray, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/04/touchstone-of-truth</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1974-general-conference/1974-04-1030-elder-john-h-vandenberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="6225579" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 1974 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Truth Will Emerge Victorious</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious?lang=eng</link>
      <description>A few weeks ago while driving north along the Wasatch Front here in Utah on an early Sunday morning, I was conscious of the sun just rising over the mountains to the east. The valley to the west, was flooded by the rays of the sun, and inspirational </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03050_000_036" doc-version="2" hash="7E4GcA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Rb0r3SPfo0GUKjHhyJ_Mxg" hash="RVlWuw">Truth Will Emerge Victorious</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="WPHUoN9kQU2SzTghLaBiYQ" hash="BFZRqQ">John H. Vandenberg</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-244c.jpg" alt="Elder John H. Vandenberg" pid="vN6UlnR4rU2DADFE3beuGw" hash="nQf8sQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p1" pid="FinGP4dkVEmc8SdKQC9GCw" hash="dRxZKQ">A few weeks ago while driving north along the Wasatch Front here in Utah on an early Sunday morning, I was conscious of the sun just rising over the mountains to the east. The valley to the west, was flooded by the rays of the sun, and inspirational music was flowing from the radio. A feeling of well-being prevailed within me. My thoughts dwelt on the goodness of being alive. The music ended in the usual way. It was time for the news. During the next several minutes the announcer commented, as I remember, on a burglary, a shooting, an accident, a hijacking, people being held hostage, and worry over the economic conditions. The news brought to my attention that the world could be full of peace, but that it was not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p2" pid="OO5cXEx7bEKtF8GY9Q3W2A" hash="_DoChA">Naturally, one fond of peace wonders why this is so, recognizing that if there were no people on earth, all would be quiet and peaceful. But then there would be no purpose in the earth. We know that its purpose is to receive God’s children where they may dwell in mortality and prove themselves in the test against the forces of good and evil. In this process there will be strife as well as peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p3" pid="CRq2p7cVdUG8dLD5chVeKw" hash="ZJIOwA">There is concern among society for the mounting trouble, the violation, and the turning away from the long-established moral codes. As one has said, “The living faith of the dead has become the dead faith of the living.” (John Thompson, “Is There a Prophet in the Land?” as quoted in <span class="emphasis">Quote, The Weekly Digest,</span> 24 July 1966, p. 6.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p4" pid="UwLWKEwvIUCf9wJCmw7ACw" hash="krtPXg">Fortunately, there are many who know the value of faith in God and testify to its power to direct their lives, although it is recognized that “truth is forever on the scaffold and wrong is on the throne.” (James Russell Lowell, “The Present Crisis.”) We join in that knowledge, and it is our purpose to constantly labor for the cause of truth with the assurance and promise that it will emerge victorious in the end.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p5" pid="fvSDKi50sEGh_Vbx1BujhQ" hash="mBe1mw">God has revealed to his prophets his laws and commandments as they are now spread on the pages of religious history. From them we may learn the course which people and nations have followed when those laws and commandments have been violated, and we should not in this day think we can circumvent them. On the contrary, they will help us solve any dilemma in which we personally or nationally may find ourselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p6" pid="nCQaOgUW2UOk2EIza-c1uw" hash="ciTcrw">Jesus rebuked the Jews, who in their dilemma sought to kill him, saying: “Search the scriptures; for in them ye think ye have eternal life: and they are they which testify of me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.39" class="scriptureRef">John 5:39</a>.) He gave us the keys to the fulfillment of life—search and think. Search for ideas. Search for examples. Search for testimony. Then apply the results and implant them into our intellects that they may generate within us a living faith in God, our Eternal Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p7" pid="B1rHg67CjEeWYokiZFEpvQ" hash="kZrskQ">This thought comes to mind and I quote: “Faith is a belief in testimony. It is not a leap in the dark. God does not ask any man to believe without giving him something to believe in. You might as well ask a man to see without eyes, as bid him believe without giving him something to believe.” (D. L. Moody, as quoted in <span class="emphasis">Quote, The Weekly Digest,</span> 19 July 1964, p. 5.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p8" pid="kLcWoILgN0e2l0ybhR2gqA" hash="Hl7mjA">Where do we find those testimonies? Our Father in heaven has brought down through the ages the Holy Bible, and in this dispensation of the fulness of times, he has caused other scriptures to be brought forth. One such scripture is the volume known as the Book of Mormon. Its origin begins with the establishment of a new nation spun off from Israel 600 years before Christ, just before the impending destruction of Jerusalem. In the introductory pages of that scripture, the importance of the exercise of faith is highlighted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p9" pid="3IDswYMNgUuzsaGHwAv7Qw" hash="w8dg8A">Lehi, a religious leader, being warned in a dream of the coming destruction of Jerusalem because of the wickedness of the people, was directed to take his family into the wilderness. This he did, and while there, received further instruction from the Lord to direct his four sons to return to Jerusalem to obtain a record from one known as Laban. Two attempts to obtain the record were thwarted. Then Nephi, the more spiritual and faithful of the sons, under the power and conviction of his commitment to his Heavenly Father, which was, “I will go and do the things which the Lord hath commanded, for I know that the Lord giveth no commandments unto the children of men, save he shall prepare a way for them that they may accomplish the thing which he commandeth them” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 3:7</a>), proceeded to venture again, alone, into the night to obtain the record.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p10" pid="gWHjpPBjakOR5bMt1tq8Cw" hash="aRuN1A">The scriptures state, “I, Nephi, crept into the city and went forth towards the house of Laban. And I was led by the Spirit, not knowing beforehand the things which I should do. … And as I came near unto the house of Laban I beheld a man, and he had fallen to the earth before me, for he was drunken with wine. And … I found that it was Laban.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p11" pid="QRRpNJK8AEapibqFJsjDEQ" hash="WzJ8pQ">“I beheld his sword, and I drew it forth from the sheath thereof. … And it came to pass that I was constrained by the Spirit that I should kill Laban; … and I shrunk and would that I might not slay him. … And … the Spirit said unto me again: Slay him, for the Lord hath delivered him into thy hands; behold the Lord slayeth the wicked to bring forth his righteous purposes. It is better that one man should perish than that a nation should dwindle and perish in unbelief.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p12" pid="Ldu0JQN0l0iZBC1WhOJhuA" hash="2IbaWg">“I remembered the words of the Lord … unto me … Inasmuch as thy seed shall keep my commandments, they shall prosper in the land of promise. … And I also thought that they could not keep the commandments of the Lord according to the law of Moses, save they should have the law. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p13" pid="B_7TKZ8y60-qn-aFGqUv3g" hash="knMG0Q">“I knew that the Lord had delivered Laban into my hands for this cause.” (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/4.5-17" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 4:5–17</a>.) Nephi obtained the records and in due course brought them to his father, Lehi.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p14" pid="jyAa60oJeUSkbgC20TLCVg" hash="g7D1QQ">Lehi and his wife Sariah rejoiced at the return of their sons and gave thanks unto God. Then “Lehi, took the records … and he did search them from the beginning. … They did contain the five books of Moses, … also a record of the Jews from the beginning, even down to … the reign of Zedekiah, king of Judah; … prophecies of the holy prophets, from the beginning, even down to the commencement of the reign of Zedekiah; … a genealogy of his [Lehi’s] fathers; wherefore he knew that he was a descendant of … that Joseph who was the son of Jacob.” (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/5.10-14" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 5:10–14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p15" pid="Ml9fQ26pL0qtmBN3roozUQ" hash="Y-c8Tg">Perhaps Lehi read the blessing of Joseph, received under the hand of Jacob. “Joseph is a fruitful bough, even a fruitful bough by a well; whose branches run over the wall” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/49.22" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 49:22</a>), and he knew that he was in the process of fulfilling that blessing in establishing a new nation which would “run over the wall” to a new promised land and would bring them to the continents now known as America.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p16" pid="w4oJ1slbL0-S0V18EtNDNw" hash="Hz7DMw">The obtained records were the foundation records they carried with them, to which was added continuous revelation received by Lehi and his posterity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p17" pid="w31sVgwGp0CB1Ig8PcdEtw" hash="KlTr8w">All scriptures set the moral code for mankind to live by. They are available to all, having been translated into many languages. Those who choose not to use them, not to give heed to the prophets, and cast aside the spiritual benefits, will surely dwindle in unbelief and perish. It has been said, “If we strike from mankind the principle of faith … men would have no more history than a flock of sheep.” (H. V. Prochnow and H. V. Prochnow, Jr., <span class="emphasis">The Public Speakers Treasure Chest,</span> New York: Harper and Row, 1942, p. 383.) On the contrary, those who choose them and live by them will live. “The just shall live by his faith,” so Habakkuk tells us. (<a href="/scriptures/ot/hab/2.4" class="scriptureRef">Hab. 2:4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p18" pid="IUisrExAaUiD7VhiSsg4Vw" hash="OXhatg">A confirmation testimony is presented to us in the lives of the twins, Esau and Jacob, born to Isaac and Rebekah. Esau, the elder, despised his birthright and sold it for a mess of pottage, married among the Canaanites, contrary to the desires of his parents, and sought to kill his brother Jacob, and turned from God’s teachings. As one writer put it, “Esau is a <span class="emphasis">profane person,</span> [<a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/12.16" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 12:16</a>.] with no conscience of a birthright, no faith in the future, no capacity for vision; dead to the unseen, and clamoring only for the satisfaction of his appetites.” (Sir George Adam Smith, <span class="emphasis">The Book of the Twelve Prophets,</span> vol. 2, Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, Dow and Company, Inc., 1929, p. 182.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p19" pid="v-d2lNp3oECEX6sE2kjtpQ" hash="lA1b-w">Jacob, the younger, honored the birthright which he obtained by bargaining, sought the blessing of God, and desired to serve him. He became the progenitor of the 12 tribes of Israel, and his name is honored to this day. From Jacob came Joseph, from Joseph came Ephraim and Manasseh, and through the lineage of Manasseh came Lehi. And from Lehi came the great posterity and civilization accounted for in the Book of Mormon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p20" pid="dCap_ShZN0yYMMMgQbw_YQ" hash="geKv7g">This record coincides with the plan of the Lord concerning another prophet, Daniel. Daniel was one who excelled in the use of the power of faith and gives us this testimony:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p21" pid="QUNmf_jOuk2A_QElunLybg" hash="TFeziw">“In the second year of the reign of Nebuchadnezzar Nebuchadnezzar dreamed dreams, wherewith his spirit was troubled.” Then the king called all who might recall and interpret the dream with the charge, “If ye will not make known unto me the dream, … ye shall be cut in pieces.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p22" pid="Ls2GBdxBz02HcZ5ov4sxZg" hash="hf8pbQ">Since none could give answer, when Daniel heard of the decree, he “went to his house, and made the thing known to … his companions: That they would desire mercies of the God of heaven concerning this secret. … Then was the secret revealed unto Daniel in a night vision.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p23" pid="RNoZPGeqOUyV5rjYD-oRdg" hash="7_cVpg">Then he went to the king and made the dream known, reciting in detail what the king had dreamed concerning the great image, ending with these words: “Thou sawest till that a stone was cut out without hands, which smote the image upon his feet that were of iron and clay, and brake them to pieces.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p24" pid="ckg3OB-8jESvgEsI56LNbA" hash="GkeJyQ">“Then was the iron, the clay, the brass, the silver, and the gold, broken to pieces together, and became like the chaff of the summer threshing floors; and the wind carried them away, that no place was found for them: and the stone that smote the image became a great mountain, and filled the whole earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p25" pid="0rkdVT7hIkG_bqw6h9qvWQ" hash="undtaA">“This is the dream; and we will tell the interpretation thereof before the king. … Thou art this head of gold. And after thee shall arise another kingdom inferior to thee, and another third kingdom of brass, which shall bear rule over all the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p26" pid="SZrgKIQbWECRlE-RTt2NiA" hash="1GApaw">“And the fourth kingdom shall be strong as iron; forasmuch as iron breaketh in pieces and subdueth all things: and as iron that breaketh all these, shall it break in pieces and bruise.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p27" pid="SQojAjOnK0e73KksU9IWNg" hash="TtjaTg">“And whereas thou sawest the feet and toes, part of potters’ clay, and part of iron, the kingdom shall be divided; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p28" pid="Bx9yOYUbAk2n9aPaCTNpGQ" hash="EQqPJQ">“So the kingdom shall be partly strong, and partly broken.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p29" pid="rQJMDngHwUmmn9B9kp_wug" hash="vZhFig">“They shall mingle themselves with the seed of men: but they shall not cleave one to another, even as iron is not mixed with clay.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p30" pid="K6kZw-vgR068f9LYqyAxPA" hash="Oru3uw">“And in the days of these kings shall the God of heaven set up a kingdom which shall never be destroyed: and the kingdom shall not be left to other people, but it shall break in pieces and consume all these kingdoms, and it shall stand for ever. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p31" pid="stYzpEHTL029A0QJYBKedw" hash="xAgLMg">“The dream is certain, and the interpretation thereof sure.” (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/dan/2.1-45" class="scriptureRef">Dan. 2:1–45</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p32" pid="saiHRGxK1UyGuZHR2-6gCg" hash="vvOb6Q">It was not a figment of the imagination of Daniel. The king testified, “Of a truth it is, that your God is a God of gods, and a Lord of kings, and a revealer of secrets, seeing thou couldest reveal this secret.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/dan/2.47" class="scriptureRef">Dan. 2:47</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p33" pid="9uB1Cse0OUGs1XPCp8BwVA" hash="P9nnLA">The recalling of this dream and the interpretation thereof were made possible through the exercise of Daniel’s faith. A careful study of history confirms that it is prophecy come to pass.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p34" pid="_pCd8BtR7EGMJHkNwxbJ1A" hash="86dE1g">By faith, a young man in the year 1820 became an instrument in the hands of the Lord in establishing the kingdom proclaimed by Daniel. Joseph Smith searching scriptures found this truth written by the apostle James:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p35" pid="aqrb3v7o2E6HXxQMCfCGag" hash="47_z1w">“If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask of God, that giveth to all men liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p36" pid="mtRg3jQOBEej_xfJs9HQTw" hash="34J5bw">“But let him ask in faith, nothing wavering. For he that wavereth is like a wave of the sea driven with the wind and tossed.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.5-6" class="scriptureRef">James 1:5–6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious.p37" pid="bofpBDlP3Eqpk6HaDaJHnQ" hash="6uRclw">After reading that passage of scripture Joseph Smith sought a grove of trees in which to make inquiry. In response to his supplication to God, a marvelous vision opened up to him wherein he saw and conversed with two personages, God the Father, and his Son Jesus Christ. From this personal visitation and ensuing instruction, which included the translation and publication of the Book of Mormon as the keystone, the kingdom as proclaimed by Daniel was established. It is The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. It began in obscurity, but it is now rolling forth throughout the free world, inviting all to come unto Christ. I bear this witness to this truth in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/10/truth-will-emerge-victorious</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1974-general-conference/1974-10-6040-elder-john-h-vandenberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="6739619" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 1974 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Cleanse Our Souls</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In a small hall in the city of Liverpool, England, during the winter of 1925–26, a group of missionaries destined to various parts of Great Britain and the European continent were gathered to receive counsel and instruction from Elder James E. Talmag</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03063_000_019" doc-version="3" hash="WBKCYA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="ICx-7LVsd0C9cJRV5Cqo-A" hash="_ivwpA">To Cleanse Our Souls</h1><p class="authorName" pid="q12YXYw0vUqt8mYeK1c83Q" hash="BFZRqQ">John H. Vandenberg</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-244c.jpg" alt="Elder John H. Vandenberg" pid="7eSRITxoDkWgjfVUiYXiUA" hash="nQf8sQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p1" pid="4X5laU5tH0C-_1NXRO173w" hash="e2lntw">In a small hall in the city of Liverpool, England, during the winter of 1925–26, a group of missionaries destined to various parts of Great Britain and the European continent were gathered to receive counsel and instruction from Elder James E. Talmage the European Mission president. Part of the counsel given included this cautionary advice: “Since you have come from modest-size western communities in America you will, no doubt, observe some customs and methods which differ from those you are used to, which may cause you to want to criticize them. Be careful that you do not. Remember, you are the foreigner in a foreign land. You are their guests. You will soon find that such customs and methods are good. They are the results of proven experiences. It is better to observe with a learning eye.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p2" pid="vX-89RTULku7I8tUC0tbKw" hash="QtKzCA">Having been one of those missionaries, assigned to the Netherlands, during my time spent there I found that the counsel given was wise. From my arrival till my departure, I learned much from my observations. I visited many of its cities, observed their clean surroundings, the picturesque buildings, the many well-maintained waterways and canals. Above all, I experienced an association with a happy people. I observed many people proceeding to the large and beautiful churches on the Sabbath day. The people were cheerful and prosperous, living under a parliamentary system of government. I learned of their history. We, as missionaries, were permitted to freely move about in our proselyting efforts. Here was a nation which had fought eighty long years, with much sacrifice, to gain religious freedom. Here was a nation which had close ties with America, for had they not given refuge to the Pilgrims who came to avoid religious persecution in England and after a few years moved on to the shores of America? There is no doubt that many people from the Netherlands emigrated to America, and with their love of liberty and their faith in God contributed much to some of the American colonies which were established so that their citizens could worship God according to their consciences.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p3" pid="1ovJC5i-Qkujw3ff7KXkKQ" hash="Z26_Mw">The thought has occurred to me that the Father of our Country, George Washington, was not unaware of the struggle of the European nations, the Netherlands included, in breaking the bonds of bigotry. Certainly, as well tutored as he was, it would be unlikely for him not to have been informed of a nation which had fought eighty years in the effort. He had very strong feelings about the subject of religion. In rereading a required assignment of my high school days, which was a study of his farewell address delivered to Congress in 1796, I am impressed with his forthrightness. May I call attention to some of his thoughts on the subject? He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p4" pid="q29w_-V5U0qHz2M-IY6Egg" hash="DIaFlg">“Of all the dispositions and habits which lead to political prosperity, religion and morality are indispensable supports. In vain would that man claim the tribute of patriotism who should labour to subvert these great pillars of human happiness—these firmest props of the duties of men and citizens. The mere politician, equally with the pious man, ought to respect and cherish them. … Let it simply be asked, Where is the security for property, for reputation, for life, if the sense of religious obligation <span class="emphasis">desert</span> the oaths which are the instrument of investigation in courts of justice? And let us with caution indulge the supposition that morality can be maintained without religion. Whatever may be conceded to the influence of refined education on minds of peculiar structure, reason and experience both forbid us to expect that that national morality can prevail in exclusion of religious principle.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p5" pid="sdpsCBIG-kakGoIAPF3BXg" hash="DZZOng">“It is substantially true that virtue or morality is a necessary spring of popular government. The rule indeed extends with more or less force to every species of free government. Who that is a sincere friend to it can look with indifference upon attempts to shake the foundation of the fabric?” (See <span class="emphasis">Documents of American History,</span> New York: Meredith Corporation, 1968, p. 173.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p6" pid="yUDnU6B340W5nxY5wCVB4g" hash="ogHMQQ">Surely the happiness and felicity of the people of the Netherlands was commensurate to their application of the powers of religion and virtue. Associated with this nature of the people, I observed their sensitivity to cleanliness. As we proselyted from door to door, we became aware of the areas where the people lived. They took extreme care to keep their dwellings and their surroundings in excellent condition. Never did they allow debris to accumulate in their streets. Never did they allow their refuse receptacles to remain standing in the streets; their laws prohibited it. That was fifty years ago. I was pleased to learn that this sensitivity still prevails, according to a recent newspaper article which reads in part:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p7" pid="iePiiMLtBUKzk6HpMCavGw" hash="D-JLTA">“The first thing any American notices in Holland is what’s missing. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p8" pid="KbOi_CSvM0O0CX60WVRvYQ" hash="I4NLiw">“As usual, of course, the dirt is missing, and the tin cans and the pages of old newspapers blowing in the gutters. The drunks are missing also, and the wine bottles in alleyways, the half-starved dogs, the odors that ought to emanate from so much slow-running water.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p9" pid="RrOBBtS4J0G0A02fPQdW4w" hash="cE80Ug">“The Dutch have always known what to do about pollution, waste and ugliness. They forbid it.” (Tom Broden, “Holland: Taking the Tension Out of Life,” <span class="emphasis">Washington Post,</span> June 7, 1975, p. A-11.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p10" pid="hoFEq0AbGEibOVFSXemBsQ" hash="6Njs0w">Though their dwellings might have been modest, extreme care was taken to keep them clean. Frequently, on our morning tours, we would find the women polishing the brass on the doors, scrubbing the entrances to their homes, and in most instances extending the scrubbing to the sidewalks. One need not ask why, as it was obvious that the custom was prompted by the knowledge that if you walk a clean street you will not collect dirt and impurities to carry into the home. Perhaps the same idea might as well be applied to the mind—a continuous scrubbing to wipe out the impurities that might enter into it so that the soul might not be contaminated.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p11" pid="wZWifWtHxkaKoxbXEmsjEw" hash="ZmNsng">As I observed this custom of cleanliness, I was quick to remember the “why” of the admonition given to me in my boyhood days as I sought to neglect the daily routine of washing the hands and face. “Cleanliness is next to godliness,” came the gentle reminder from my parents. I heard that so often I thought it was scripture, and it was not until later in life that I found it to be a statement in a sermon of John Wesley. And I’d like to inject in your minds here—there is indeed an alliance between physical cleanliness and spiritual cleanliness, just as the clean body, clean home, and clean surroundings stay the spread of disease, so the clean mind, clean thoughts and acts stay the spread of evil. A progressive statement from the Hebrew Fathers reads, “The doctrines of religion are resolved into carefulness, carefulness into vigorousness; vigorousness into guiltlessness; guiltlessness into abstemiousness; abstemiousness into cleanliness; cleanliness into Godliness.” (Burton Stevenson, ed., <span class="emphasis">The Home Book of Quotations,</span> New York: Dodd, Mead, 1956, 279.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p12" pid="TmYdmF2BYk6-4tkv3EoEcQ" hash="ut8tOg">The purpose of scripture or the doctrines of religion is to keep people from dwindling in unbelief and to ultimately help bring their souls into a state of cleanliness, that they may dwell with their Father in heaven in the eternities. It is a step-by-step process. Paul refers to the doctrines in his epistle to the Hebrew saints in that specific manner:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p13" pid="y0B_R4hfHUGcNAoFX-Pz0g" hash="7EyVsw">“Therefore not leaving the principles of the doctrine of Christ, let us go on unto perfection; not laying again the foundation of repentance from dead works, and of faith toward God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p14" pid="7tO5nfE_vkyvyZT0EAf-Og" hash="FbOfQg">“Of the doctrine of baptisms, of laying on of hands, and of the resurrection of the dead, and of eternal judgement.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p15" pid="68sqFlUbDUm2UEiCRhur1g" hash="PQlZhA">“And we will go on to perfection.” (JST, Heb. 6:1–3.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p16" pid="BQCtD8YGHUePVsgufvmxzg" hash="HjAg3g">But a more specific presentation of the doctrine was set forth in the beginning, when God spoke to Adam. This is the scripture:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p17" pid="217pbyVGZUiC0KfMvUtKew" hash="3zau9g">“Wherefore teach it unto your children, that all men, everywhere, must repent, or they can in nowise inherit the kingdom of God, for no unclean thing can dwell there, or dwell in his presence. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p18" pid="Vp2lgrfpe02_Ioj-9B9qOQ" hash="tjM88w">“Therefore I give unto you a commandment, to teach these things freely unto your children, saying:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p19" pid="PIV6rsci7UmHSMiUy-oVVw" hash="WRnJxg">“That by reason of transgression cometh the fall, which fall bringeth death, and inasmuch as ye were born into the world by water, and blood, and spirit, which I have made, and so became of dust a living soul, even so ye must be born again into the kingdom of heaven, of water, and the Spirit, and be cleansed by blood, even the blood of mine Only Begotten; that ye might be sanctified from all sin, and enjoy the words of eternal life in this world, and eternal life in the world to come, even immortal glory;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p20" pid="G5BEYkJ3CUWjG99RVuak5A" hash="BrwaBQ">“For by the water ye keep the commandment; by the Spirit ye are justified, and by the blood ye are sanctified.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/6.57-60" class="scriptureRef">Moses 6:57–60</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p21" pid="Mwm_Ah8NpEqSijoS_SZK3A" hash="UM05HA">A religious doctrine, to mean something to anyone, must have the solid foundation of being true. If it is built on myth, superstition, supposition, imagination, or on the commandments of men, it will not have substance. We may be concerned today with the decline of morality and integrity in our modern society, but when the ideas of faith become principles without works instead of a living fountain, when religion is only membership in a church for status purposes, what else can be expected? It is time for all mankind to ask of God, since he is our Creator, “What do you require of us?” The answer to that question has been given. Jesus taught what his Father taught—that “all men … must repent, or they can in nowise inherit the kingdom of God, for no unclean thing can dwell there.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/6.57" class="scriptureRef">Moses 6:57</a>.) He taught the plan of salvation and encouraged mankind to “Come, follow me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/18.22" class="scriptureRef">Luke 18:22</a>.) He said, “My doctrine is not mine, but his that sent me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p22" pid="7xzb2jy2kkO_zLQK7KaI-Q" hash="ftHAxQ">“If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it be of God or whether I speak of myself.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/7.16-17" class="scriptureRef">John 7:16–17</a>.) The doctrine taught by the Savior has never faltered.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p23" pid="WjJyYqCDV0aalZS9IiXpAg" hash="RpWaIQ">The gospel is the governing principle of the individual; it was designed for him, to give certainty to his life and to explain the purpose of his existence and the eternal nature of it. Through adherence to its laws and ordinances he may become a citizen of the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p24" pid="wiI5Pc1fJEqBgrMHDijtzQ" hash="msV_rA">The principles of the progressive steps to be taken were alluded to in Paul’s words previously presented. The progressive process to be followed might well be as outlined in the words of the Hebrew Fathers. They can be put to the test. They will, in fact, when applied, bring a person to that state of cleanliness demanded by our Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p25" pid="NajAkjAri0iBfkKvjO8zsQ" hash="AJZj7w">Using the doctrine heretofore recited from the scripture of God’s presentation to Adam, it behooves all to carefully study the doctrine as admonished by the ancient prophet, Moroni. He presents a formula which can be recommended for all scripture study:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p26" pid="qjItB0ERFE2qF7aW8wUcUw" hash="WY1ZoA">“Behold, I would exhort you that when ye shall read these things, … that ye would remember how merciful the Lord hath been unto the children of men, from the creation of Adam even down unto the time that ye shall receive these things, and ponder it in your hearts. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls.p27" pid="heYpsAfpBkOskQpVpomuYg" hash="fZrxcw">“I would exhort you that ye would ask God, the Eternal Father, in the name of Christ, if these things are not true; and if ye shall ask with a sincere heart, with real intent, having faith in Christ, he will manifest the truth of it unto you, by the power of the Holy Ghost.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.3-4" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:3–4</a>.) I so witness and testify, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/10/to-cleanse-our-souls</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1975-general-conference/1975-10-3040-elder-john-h-vandenberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="11945701" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1975 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Are Your Greatest Treasure</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Recently, in handling some souvenirs which I possess, I held in my hand a pocket piece which reminded me of a pleasant experience.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03070_000_012" doc-version="2" hash="cJYTbA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="L4sArF_1zEOqsVY9lL7w_A" hash="0QU_Fg">You Are Your Greatest Treasure</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="hgPr1PIvrkegiYJiD0hxFg" hash="BFZRqQ">John H. Vandenberg</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-244c.jpg" alt="Elder John H. Vandenberg" pid="G8pbv-EQrk2ctbOn5WvZ_g" hash="nQf8sQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p1" pid="Wh970xtuZEOGp_QwNULqsw" hash="roFQLw">Recently, in handling some souvenirs which I possess, I held in my hand a pocket piece which reminded me of a pleasant experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p2" pid="w_ZXpffP60OFRukA_MNv3A" hash="52-W8A">Several years ago, boarding an aircraft in Denver to return to Salt Lake City, having been invited to be a member of the Church Building Committee, I met a member of our staff making the same journey. With him was a gentleman he had chanced to meet. Seated in the aircraft together, we engaged ourselves in conversation. I asked the gentleman about his present occupation. He informed us that he was a building engineer, presently engaged in building a church in one of the larger cities in the state of Texas. He recounted to us some of the frustrating experiences that he and their finance committee had in raising funds from the members of his church; they had tried most everything such as direct solicitations, dinners, bazaars, some games of chance—none of which was very successful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p3" pid="tfwgyfOn60mn5vB7nqY8iQ" hash="qdyuBg">To solve the financial problem, they called a special meeting. It was during this meeting, he said, that they had come upon a capital idea, after someone had suggested going to the scriptures to try the Lord’s way. The scripture came from Malachi:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p4" pid="5yyPGxQSJEK1p1gigtdP_w" hash="sw-BDQ">“Bring ye all the tithes into the storehouse, that there may be meat in mine house, and prove me now herewith, saith the Lord of hosts, if I will not open you the windows of heaven, and pour you out a blessing, that there shall not be room enough to receive it.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/3.10" class="scriptureRef">Mal. 3:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p5" pid="FGysRzB8oUmWL483P0iIbQ" hash="2_L9jg">From this the committee conceived a unique idea of getting that message to their members by coining a pocket piece made of copper with a coating to make it appear as a bright gold coin, about the size of a fifty-cent piece, inscribed on one side with the words, “One tenth is the Lord’s” and on the other side, “Bring ye all the tithes and I will pour you out a blessing that there shall not be room enough to receive it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p6" pid="O_GPDcplT02v0y1r7CJsBw" hash="ie0QIA">These coins, he said, were distributed to the members. The thought was that as the men would reach into their pockets and the ladies into their purses for change, the bright gold coin would be the first item they would see, and it would remind them of their duty. He smiled and handed to each of us the souvenir coin and said: “This was successful! The people have responded and now we are moving ahead with our project.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p7" pid="J92Pc0K9d0y50-v0zI98iQ" hash="6t6Q0w">As he said that, I thought, “A true principle discovered, properly applied, brings a correct result.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p8" pid="gJeqFMrKKkK2a-vM5R_bOA" hash="YcA4kA">After some pause, he turned the conversation to us and queried of us as to our present endeavors, to which we replied: “Coincidentally, we too are engaged in building churches, employed by The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p9" pid="gR1WB8c-_0Sbs_liwFqTuA" hash="jukHQQ">“How many churches are you building?” he asked.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p10" pid="trdMdw9MK0KTEFso3vJ0CA" hash="U40xcw">“At present, a few hundred,” was the reply.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p11" pid="DvZ0ZC1s6Uer511ZHJXLxw" hash="xXI3oA">A surprised look appeared on his face. “That’s a lot of buildings! How in the world do you pay for them? Where do you get the money?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p12" pid="ICtxC3fDsE6QYcoWt5q8Yg" hash="J_i7NA">“From our Church membership, and coincidentally again, the great secret you discovered in the principle of tithing has been a tenet of the Lord’s Church from the early days of its restoration,” was the reply.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p13" pid="sf4NWqsY1U2XTEFWld_C3w" hash="YvwFRg">This afforded an extensive discussion of the great devotion of the Latter-day Saints, not only in paying their tithing, their fast offerings, additional construction funds, temple funds, welfare funds, budgets, missionary funds, etc., but also of their giving much of their free time in Church services, in the administration of and participation in the Church programs. We explained the extensive missionary program and the devotion of our young people to it. He seemed intensely interested, sat back in his seat, and thoughtfully said: “That’s amazing! You must have something we do not have.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p14" pid="KtPGfOVXt0aSANc_3S4dtw" hash="xeR-ZA">Again the question arises, what really is the difference that causes such devotion? Let us go to Joseph Smith for an answer. In December 1839 he was in Washington in company with others trying to obtain redress of grievances for the Saints. In corresponding with his brother Hyrum, he stated that they had had an interview with the president of the United States and reported, and I quote: “In our interview with the President, he interrogated us wherein we differed in our religion from other religions of the day. Brother Joseph said we differed in mode of baptism, and the gift of the Holy Ghost by the laying on of hands. We considered that all other considerations were contained in the gift of the Holy Ghost.” (<span class="emphasis">History of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints,</span> 4:42.) That is the gift conveyed to each member as he is confirmed into the Church. Those who respond to that gift are guided by it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p15" pid="z2Skit5u0Eii4BLOVyq0JQ" hash="FUE5hQ">The power of the Holy Ghost was alluded to in the Savior’s instructions to his disciples as he spoke to them:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p16" pid="cwr5KfI8Qk6KPjh_CvStWA" hash="Kb84Rg">“Nevertheless I tell you the truth; It is expedient for you that I go away: for if I go not away, the Comforter will not come unto you; but if I depart, I will send him unto you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p17" pid="3WusbNx_C0SaK5BSAemyGg" hash="_pWd0g">“And when he is come, he will reprove the world of sin, and of righteousness, and of judgment. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p18" pid="9_HW4PlbP0moNsmAbjZucA" hash="GwHhkw">“I have yet many things to say unto you, but ye cannot bear them now.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p19" pid="3cq-15PwCky4eqkG-h6FEw" hash="hFX6vg">“Howbeit when he, the Spirit of truth, is come, he will guide you into all truth.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/16.7-8,12-13" class="scriptureRef">John 16:7–8, 12–13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p20" pid="KGdScoLsvUy9V2u6hawIGA" hash="gjzMQw">It is through the Holy Ghost that members receive the knowledge and witness of the truth. So influenced, they willingly and voluntarily support the cause of the restored gospel of Jesus Christ. Whatever is required of them, they respond and feel comfortable about it. How else should it be? The price is paid, as portrayed in the simple parable:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p21" pid="uX8UsCSOWk6M8YMbKs1IoQ" hash="6Ey3Sw">“Again, the kingdom of heaven is like unto a merchant man, seeking goodly pearls:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p22" pid="Mz5o-Ltla0KEc3mXCSd6Xg" hash="SqFS2g">“Who, when he had found one pearl of great price, went and sold all that he had, and bought it.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/13.45-46" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 13:45–46</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p23" pid="g7furllJn02SHV9R3l07cw" hash="b0R0wg">Joseph Smith, speaking on the subject, so expressed himself: “Such was, and always will be, the situation of the saints of God, that unless they have an actual knowledge that the course they are pursuing is according to the will of God they will grow weary in their minds, and faint, for such has been, and always will be, the opposition in the hearts of unbelievers and those that know not God. … For a man to lay down his all … requires more than mere belief or supposition that he is doing the will of God; but actual knowledge, realizing that, when these sufferings are ended, he will enter into eternal rest, and be a partaker of the glory of God. … Let us here observe,” he continues, “that a religion that does not require the sacrifice of all things never has power sufficient to produce the faith necessary unto life and salvation.” (<span class="emphasis">Lectures on Faith,</span> 6:4, 5, 7.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p24" pid="JdXrSMYuJkeEDLa9Qg954w" hash="AonFHA">From certain vantage points, some are privileged to see the growth and vitality of the living Church. In that movement it is seen that faith is increasing in the earth, that God’s everlasting covenant is established, and that the fulness of the gospel is being proclaimed. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:21</a>.) This is in harmony with the revelation given through the Prophet Joseph Smith, while spending some of his most burdensome times in the Liberty Jail during the winter and spring of 1838–39. In the midst of that dark world he declared:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p25" pid="v083q_rwM0-p2USQitGeEw" hash="Pj8r9Q">“How long can rolling waters remain impure? What power shall stay the heavens? As well might man stretch forth his puny arm to stop the Missouri river in its decreed course, or to turn it up stream, as to hinder the Almighty from pouring down knowledge from heaven upon the heads of the Latter-day Saints.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.33" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p26" pid="5RRvZY4NpkS_Bc-dQ7N7hw" hash="qP8APg">This knowledge which the Almighty pours down upon the heads of the Saints relates to that lost knowledge of the true nature of the Father and of his Son, Jesus Christ: the true purposes and meaning of life; the true doctrines of the gospel, which, when accepted, establish faith in God so essential to eternal life. In the prayer Jesus offered in behalf of his disciples and all believers, he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p27" pid="pqcJGvSBVU6N2RFPxh_hTA" hash="vdkAGQ">“And this is life eternal, that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17:3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p28" pid="MXF0pGqC_EONJzO_CAexqg" hash="eGFZNw">The whole purpose of the gospel plan is to inform mankind that they might act in accord with its principles; it is to help the individual find himself, to bring into his life an answer to his dilemmas. Said one, concerning such a dilemma: “Your greatest problem is yourself. You are also your greatest treasure. If you can get yourself determined upon—find out what you are and what you are for, and if you can discover and develop the elements of value in your nature—your life will take on the beauty of orderliness. … I say ‘if you can,’ for this procedure takes wisdom, and wisdom is a fruit that ripens slowly. Perhaps you are not yet wise, perhaps you are still incapable of self-analysis, perhaps you are confused amid the surface and appearances of life, perhaps your code of conduct is based on the custom of the times and the sayings of alleged sages, perhaps you are disheartened and discouraged, even in frenzy of retreat before the things in your life which seem to oppose you and beat you back. But even so, this is but a condition or mood which is not final. The condition will right itself, the mood will pass.” (Richard Wightman)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p29" pid="_EQAHqBO2kSBQ-fzFgK_yg" hash="G3PZvw">The gospel in its fulness provides the help needed to “get yourself determined upon—to find out what you are and what you are for.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p30" pid="k8pZ50u18k2a6U-BgiiNYA" hash="oQzU7g">King Benjamin, a prophet in the Book of Mormon, speaking of the attributes of God, said: “If the knowledge of the goodness of God … has awakened you to a sense of your … fallen state, …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p31" pid="jZ45uXO2A0GzJ6Xs-bSE1Q" hash="D5mmfA">“This is the means whereby salvation cometh. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p32" pid="TTDvNiAxrUyAmFByazc4NA" hash="kR-ecg">“Believe in God; believe that he is, and that he created all things, both in heaven and in earth; believe that he has all wisdom, and all power, both in heaven and in earth; believe that man doth not comprehend all the things which the Lord can comprehend.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p33" pid="PPXR5cfayU-1DOJYoYE0kg" hash="VmnUIA">“And again, believe that ye must repent of your sins and forsake them, and humble yourselves before God; and ask in sincerity of heart that he would forgive you; and now, if you believe all these things see that ye do them.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.5,8-10" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:5, 8–10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p34" pid="bURShNVzdkiE4nfzpcw9rQ" hash="S8Nzug">Using this scripture as a base and pursuing a course which the Savior referred to as being “strait” and “narrow” (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.14" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 7:14</a>) will bring one to realize that “he himself is his greatest treasure.” Millions have so testified under the power of the Holy Ghost, as they have subscribed themselves to the true doctrine and joined with others in the true Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure.p35" pid="KKc3nhA2Dkq8Jo4LjEebmA" hash="vyOBsw">May God bless us and help us to understand this I humbly pray, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/04/you-are-your-greatest-treasure</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1976-general-conference/1976-04-2060-elder-john-h-vandenberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="5461472" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1976 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“What Is Truth?”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth?lang=eng</link>
      <description>It has been but seven days since throngs of people attended those special worship services, hearing songs and sermons, commemorating that most important event—the crucifixion and resurrection of our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03096_000_027" doc-version="2" hash="cZJ6gA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="NoFxodnWmkWEm8FKYpInyw" hash="NTb7sQ">“What Is Truth?”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="-1WYxKDwJEKKkEheNO-jUg" hash="BFZRqQ">John H. Vandenberg</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-244c.jpg" alt="Elder John H. Vandenberg" pid="OG9I1BtxUUOCOXx8DpBcng" hash="nQf8sQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p1" pid="kOrO5LnF1UmjaSjt2WkFTg" hash="fSb3Tg">It has been but seven days since throngs of people attended those special worship services, hearing songs and sermons, commemorating that most important event—the crucifixion and resurrection of our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p2" pid="FZ3VWc-Z4kC-QYZhFS4Kog" hash="bMslWw">In reviewing and pondering that miracle, my thoughts have been drawn to the episode after the Jews had bound Jesus and led Him to the judgment hall.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p3" pid="Za1ds1ZTVk6ekTvx4USGGA" hash="0IZ2OA">It is recorded in the scripture:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p4" pid="yC-K9Yf_DEiDzpD4itxSEQ" hash="MOUezg">“Then Pilate entered into the judgment hall … and called Jesus, and said to him, Art thou the King of the Jews?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p5" pid="0hb_yMDn3EGFbBuLPC1gog" hash="siDKKA">“Jesus answered him, Sayest thou this thing of thyself, or did others tell it thee of me?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p6" pid="nBsEqPP_r0-Mbnz7KENTIA" hash="ceqF3w">“Pilate answered, Am I a Jew? Thine own nation and the chief priests have delivered thee unto me: what hast thou done?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p7" pid="EOkZ50a3u0ePNZha7bdejw" hash="r3vGVQ">“Jesus answered, My kingdom is not of this world: if my kingdom were of this world, then would my servants fight, that I should not be delivered to the Jews: but now is my kingdom not from hence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p8" pid="FkzYVVR2X0CYE5ZnHnlf_w" hash="Zy2kxg">“Pilate therefore said unto him, Art thou a king then? Jesus answered, Thou sayest that I am a king. To this end was I born, and for this cause came I into the world, that I should bear witness unto the truth. Every one that is of the truth heareth my voice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p9" pid="loQowNxfekazKYlaH-TpAQ" hash="h2ZxCQ">“Pilate saith unto him, What is truth? And when he had said this, he went out again unto the Jews, and saith unto them, I find in him no fault at all.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/18.33-38" class="scriptureRef">John 18:33–38</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p10" pid="P9yWg6FVvkectYAyxqPm8g" hash="CciC7w">Further negotiations, however, between Pilate and the accusers of Jesus brought about the crucifixion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p11" pid="08F1KX5aTUe13v4lkexJwQ" hash="ce0jvg">With the question “What is truth?” Pilate left Jesus standing alone, without granting Him the courtesy of reply. One wonders why. Such action leads one to believe that Pilate feared the truth, perhaps as others might fear it—not being willing to face up to it, not wishing to take upon themselves the discipline and responsibility demanded by truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p12" pid="w6S20q7ag02kYAWgUj1vyw" hash="aM-nkQ">Jesus said, “Every one that is of the truth heareth my voice.” Those who are “of the truth” are those who sincerely seek after it. All of mankind should be seekers after truth for it is the supreme essence of their lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p13" pid="HLwFpZbtkEK_CkQ_T1qUUQ" hash="NPPxgQ">One author expresses such a thought with these words: “Yet truth, which only doth judge itself, teacheth that the inquiry of truth, which is the love-making or wooing of it, the knowledge of truth, which is the presence of it, and the belief of truth, which is the enjoying of it, is the sovereign good of human nature.” (Francis Bacon, “Essay of Truth,” <span class="emphasis">Harvard Classics Vol. 3: Bacon, Milton’s Prose, Thos. Browne,</span> New York: P. F. Collier and Son, Co., 1909, p. 8.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p14" pid="HDDn4AvBqEKigMKv7dGUuA" hash="MlH6zw">In harmony with that thought an ancient poet wrote: “‘It is a pleasure to stand upon the shore and to see ships tossed upon the sea; a pleasure to stand in the window of a castle and to see a battle and the adventures thereof below: but no pleasure is comparable to the standing upon the vantage ground of truth’ (a hill not to be commanded, and where the air is always clear and serene), ‘and to see the errors and wanderings and mists and tempests in the vale below’; so always that this prospect be with pity, and not with swelling or pride. Certainly, it is heaven upon earth, to have a man’s mind move in charity, rest in providence, and turn upon the poles of truth.” (Bacon, quoting Lucretius, in “Essay of Truth,” p. 8.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p15" pid="TNmsQ5jP302ITedCY-366A" hash="jEl__w">It is fitting that we remember the words of Jesus: “And for this cause came I into the world, that I should bear witness unto the truth.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/18.37" class="scriptureRef">John 18:37</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p16" pid="fs4yx9lD-kOWlpmfO-hYiA" hash="sibwxg">Truth is knowledge! “This is life eternal, that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17:3</a>.) Truth defined is found in the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p17" pid="eBXW3JJDdUKZ-2Dm5d-OOA" hash="EOBOLw">During the Savior’s ministry on earth, He organized His church, choosing humble but sincere men to be His apostles; He lived with them; He made journeys with them; He taught them; He performed miracles before them; He ordained them, granting authority and power—all preparatory to sending them into the world to declare His gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p18" pid="5aPHuy3vJE2ArftLWFIYww" hash="jTH5Fg">On a certain occasion as He journeyed with them, “Jesus came into the coasts of Caesarea Philippi, [and] he asked his disciples, saying, Whom do men say that I the Son of man am?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p19" pid="fsBRAfr9EEmWQwawgqy8Fw" hash="j7ecPg">“And they said, Some say that thou art John the Baptist: some, Elias; and others, Jeremias, or one of the prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p20" pid="9nxhypPBcEK7TtTU-BS_EQ" hash="zYTRdg">“He saith unto them, But whom say ye that I am?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p21" pid="ZCRE80QxNUCmhbs-17NZeg" hash="3d-4RA">“And Simon Peter answered and said, Thou art the Christ, the Son of the Living God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p22" pid="DpezfXwQ3UW1w6iYHzYr4w" hash="aEVsHg">“And Jesus answered and said unto him, Blessed art thou, Simon Bar-jona: for flesh and blood hath not revealed it unto thee, but my Father which is in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p23" pid="oDX-vp8E2kO3wDbwYJk6Rg" hash="jO1D1A">“And I say also unto thee, That thou art Peter, and upon this rock I will build my church; and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/16.13-18" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 16:13–18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p24" pid="gT84lQyQaU-HaegxmHsOoA" hash="bQEmGg">The rock of revelation is the foundation of His church. The principle of revelation is indispensable in the living church. This principle is inherent in the affairs of God as He directs His children through His prophets. The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints was restored under the power and authority of divine revelation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p25" pid="lx3_9lvhQEOqEQ6Cu-wWGQ" hash="SnX8Dw">Early in the nineteenth century a sincere young man whose name was Joseph Smith, a seeker after truth, found in the Epistle of James (which was written to the “twelve tribes which are scattered abroad” [<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.1" class="scriptureRef">James 1:1</a>]) these powerful words: “If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask of God, that giveth to all men liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p26" pid="qhGSci-Z5EWxJDO6j-Z5OQ" hash="lfXiEQ">“But let him ask in faith, nothing wavering. For he that wavereth is like a wave of the sea driven with the wind and tossed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p27" pid="om7H5ZDE8EaT6jG3cN7yzg" hash="4C3K3w">“For let not that man think that he shall receive any thing of the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.5-7" class="scriptureRef">James 1:5–7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p28" pid="fu1g4lmHckKOvn8e35F3fQ" hash="IiD3Ng">With that heavenly invitation to truth, Joseph Smith ventured into the sphere of prayer and received the knowledge of the Father and the Son, two personalities, and instructions from the voice of the Savior. In response to his inquiry Joseph was told that none of the churches existent were true, that “they draw near to me with their lips, but their hearts are far from me, they teach for doctrines the commandments of men, having a form of godliness, but they deny the power thereof.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.19" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p29" pid="zmzVygtdC0qKYQeNurXtJw" hash="2AnXUw">Further instruction came to him at that time that he would be God’s instrument in restoring His true church upon the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p30" pid="GDSRP2p7E0uQi5znIFDubA" hash="14iMMQ">“Surely the Lord God will do nothing, but he revealeth his secret unto his servants the prophets.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/amos/3.7" class="scriptureRef">Amos 3:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p31" pid="r7PtvIghQ0Gh3t6KVUttHQ" hash="pTP3BA">Sometime later in 1841, eleven years after the organization of the restored church, Joseph Smith was requested to set forth a brief statement of the belief of its members. This statement is known as the Articles of Faith. The eighth and ninth articles of that statement express our belief with respect to revelation from the divine source. It says:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p32" pid="la2pfhpJmEiuAepjSbLlZg" hash="QPHKow">“We believe the Bible to be the word of God as far as it is translated correctly; we also believe the Book of Mormon to be the word of God. [<a href="/scriptures/pgp/a-of-f/1.8" class="scriptureRef">A of F 1:8</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p33" pid="UYkK-2hLlkaRAd3gtDLcPQ" hash="eWFDjA">“We believe all that God has revealed, all that He does now reveal, and we believe that He will yet reveal many great and important things pertaining to the Kingdom of God.” [<a href="/scriptures/pgp/a-of-f/1.9" class="scriptureRef">A of F 1:9</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p34" pid="U42L1oseGECiostuKRZsNQ" hash="ZmRWAw">We know that the Bible is a compilation of the available revealed messages received by the prophets from God for the benefit and guidance of God’s children here on earth. The Bible is the foundation of our religious library. It has been brought to us in an honorable manner and is sorely needed in this modern world. It contains much of what we need to know. How would we have known of Jesus had the record been lost? Think of the revealing words of John:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p35" pid="wSw3zA5hFEadgwO5KU8uEQ" hash="J_mHZw">“In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p36" pid="uVv6bGJctU6CjuRnU6KypA" hash="4MAl9A">“The same was in the beginning with God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p37" pid="6A6YhJ1-Q0qqsRkbi1OV-Q" hash="lNhZQg">“All things were made by him; and without him was not any thing made that was made.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p38" pid="8h6rUtJFYkmr3D78AFvfEQ" hash="b5yW-g">“In him was life; and the life was the light of men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p39" pid="H9J1HUGFkECKi96SOsT9Tg" hash="n0CdGQ">“He was in the world, and the world was made by him, and the world knew him not.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/1.1-4,10" class="scriptureRef">John 1:1–4, 10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p40" pid="8isEz2-wbU-_RZ3H53mnVg" hash="Nj5l9Q">Jesus was the Creator of this world and all things pertaining to it. He was Jehovah who revealed His will to the prophets, thus ushering in all of the gospel dispensations that have occurred.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p41" pid="w1YaywUFC02eS1Wt8tbipA" hash="YPEeOw">The Bible, however, does not contain <span class="emphasis">all</span> the revelation that has ever been given.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p42" pid="T4LnRi7wAkiur_GpV2uvmQ" hash="jWcRPQ">Through modern revelation the Book of Mormon was brought forth through the Prophet Joseph Smith. It stands as a new witness of Jesus Christ and discloses that His gospel was known to the ancient inhabitants of the Americas and that He visited the Americas after His ascension. These inhabitants were known to Him as “other sheep of my fold” (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/10.16" class="scriptureRef">John 10:16</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/15.21" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 15:21</a>) for they carried in their veins the blood of Israel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p43" pid="1wbzQQXSqU-kenKDv7CnmA" hash="5pqLyA">Through modern revelation we now know that Adam received the gospel. It has been revealed that “Adam and Eve, his wife, called upon the name of the Lord, and they heard the voice of the Lord … speaking unto them, and they saw him not; for they were shut out of his presence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p44" pid="3nmyriOKd0q1zZqOf1KYZg" hash="YIOxKQ">“And he gave unto them commandments, that they should worship the Lord their God, and should offer the firstlings of their flocks, for an offering unto the Lord. And Adam was obedient unto the commandments of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p45" pid="JS9P5FW_DEaKP8nH4bDsYA" hash="RdYDGA">“And after many days an angel of the Lord appeared unto Adam, saying: Why dost thou offer sacrifices unto the Lord? And Adam said unto him: I know not, save the Lord commanded me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p46" pid="OCuLb2xxsEGB_0GZmJuJfg" hash="-V1Juw">“And then the angel spake, saying: This thing is a similitude of the sacrifice of the Only Begotten of the Father, which is full of grace and truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p47" pid="NNTqVE52IUSHMZ1E2r8Jcw" hash="o5a0Dg">“Wherefore, thou shalt do all that thou doest in the name of the Son, and thou shalt repent and call upon God in the name of the Son forevermore.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p48" pid="4NEcBFLTIE6f7m_lMhF8Hw" hash="0pSlnQ">“And in that day the Holy Ghost fell upon Adam, which beareth record of the Father and the Son, saying: I am the Only Begotten of the Father from the beginning, henceforth and forever, that as thou hast fallen thou mayest be redeemed, and all mankind, even as many as will.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/5.4-9" class="scriptureRef">Moses 5:4–9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p49" pid="8WAP78KJ9E-MlHNu0SzNTQ" hash="Cy3AZQ">We now know more concerning Enoch. The Bible gives but little information about this great prophet. Latter-day revelation tells of his work among his people. Says Enoch, “The Lord which spake with me, the same is the God of heaven, and he is my God, and your God.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/6.43" class="scriptureRef">Moses 6:43</a>.) He explained to Enoch the whole plan of salvation, the gospel of Jesus Christ as it had been declared to father Adam.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p50" pid="F_HiEAmY0UK12-nmApouOA" hash="y4q87Q">We now know more of Noah, that the “Lord ordained Noah after his own order, and commanded him that he should go forth and declare his Gospel unto the children of men, even as it was given unto Enoch.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p51" pid="g8CxTPtrV02IiNkvyRXTkQ" hash="Mtvp-Q">“Noah continued his preaching, … saying: Hearken, and give heed unto my words;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p52" pid="RSCFreEVckGH7gjxbFVsng" hash="-Epfdg">“Believe and repent of your sins and be baptized in the name of Jesus Christ, the Son of God, even as our fathers, and ye shall receive the Holy Ghost, that ye may have all things made manifest; and if ye do not this, the floods will come in upon you; nevertheless they hearkened not.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/8.19,23-24" class="scriptureRef">Moses 8:19, 23–24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p53" pid="nFA9InbwCEKa4cyI5T0VMA" hash="p3tyFw">Now we know more of Abraham, as Jehovah spoke to him and said: “My name is Jehovah, and I know the end from the beginning; therefore my hand shall be over thee.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p54" pid="9Pi95n_bCk2t3uxFZZmkWw" hash="b8mOXg">“And I will make of thee a great nation, … and thou shalt be a blessing unto thy seed after thee, that in their hands they shall bear this ministry and Priesthood unto all nations.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/2.8-9" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 2:8–9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p55" pid="hmgNTY7HHUekiwH5z8cDUw" hash="h3--_w">He declared to Abraham the vision of the preexistence of mankind: “Now the Lord had shown unto me … the intelligences that were organized before the world was; and among all these there were many of the noble and great ones;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p56" pid="q6tjbITgbUupwio0kKJ5fw" hash="SD67hA">“And God saw these souls that they were good … and he said unto me: Abraham, thou art one of them; thou wast chosen before thou wast born.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.22-23" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:22–23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p57" pid="hTS1czI590u8Kx0fa43xAg" hash="QMgABg">Were we to continue to review all of the modern revelations, we would come to realize that this is now the time of which Paul revealed to the Ephesians “that in the dispensation of the fulness of times he might gather together in one all things in Christ, both which are in heaven and which are on earth.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/1.10" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 1:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p58" pid="0PT6MrqCrUqkLI0js0U0WA" hash="gq5rDQ">The gospel reveals to us the need for Jesus to offer Himself as a sacrifice for the sins of men that all mankind may be redeemed, that man may be saved by believing in Him, by believing in all of His teachings, and by being obedient to them, and by being true hearers of the voice of Jesus. It is a lifelong task to hear, to learn, to obey all the vast truths, for the gospel reaches into the eternities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p59" pid="JAxC4BRflEKdbJMU2XBv2w" hash="4SNciA">It has been said of our belief in divine revelation that “this declaration of religious belief in the Divine fountain of Truth, and His revelation thereof to man, embraces all truth in the universe: whether revealed or yet to be revealed; whether made known through the inspiration of the Almighty that ‘giveth understanding’ to the spirit of man in his discoveries and developments in the material things of life; or whether manifest in things visible or in things invisible to mortal eyes. It embraces every scientific truth, every historic truth, every truth in philosophy, or logic, or demonstrable fact. That is the scope of revealed religion. It is the system of law and order which prevails under heavenly control. It is the Gospel of the Lord Jesus Christ.” (James H. Anderson, <span class="emphasis">God’s Covenant Race,</span> 2nd ed., Salt Lake City: Deseret News Press, 1938, p. 132.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p60" pid="IDP6nFiZwEyUfe-27OgY6Q" hash="5B1VRg">We invite all to consider the truths spoken from this pulpit, with the suggestion of an ancient poet who said, “Fly no opinion because it is new, but strictly search, reject it if false, embrace it if ’tis true.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p61" pid="cwX4MYL3IUmnUI4wFOZE-g" hash="YIO1lA">May that be done in the attitude of prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth.p62" pid="uhoh-BSQOEiqy5mUCnp8WQ" hash="z2cLnQ">I bear witness to the truth, that revelation and prayer are indispensable in attaining eternal life, and this I do in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1978/04/what-is-truth</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1978-general-conference/1978-04-4030-elder-john-h-vandenberg-64k-eng.mp3" length="7378982" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 1978 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
