<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Jorge F. Zeballos</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Jorge F. Zeballos.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Jorge%20F.%20Zeballos.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Jorge F. Zeballos.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2009 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2009 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Attempting the Impossible</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Eternal life is to live with our Father and with our families forevermore. Should not this promise be the greatest incentive to do the best within our reach?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50019113_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="fRTiNw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Z3Gq4_wwIUyKk0Gpb4cPiA" hash="0OdI_A">Attempting the Impossible</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="l54salMxGkWQiStBZXnVAA" hash="b3r4zA">Jorge F. Zeballos</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="q7DbeR0GLUeDLxJZoSuEbw" hash="mfS78A">Eternal life is to live with our Father and with our families forevermore. Should not this promise be the greatest incentive to do the best within our reach?</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible.p1" pid="nAzhN4JMgUqdynIDKuNtAw" hash="3yV0bg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="33"></span>When the twelve disciples were called in the Americas, the Lord Jesus Christ commanded them: “Therefore I would that ye should be perfect even as I, or your Father who is in heaven is perfect.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> The Savior had recently finalized His successful, selfless, and transcendental mission on earth. This allowed Him to declare with authority that He and His Father, our Father, are the models to be followed by each one of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible.p2" pid="P63Ei7eTCE6P-6L1t2faIQ" hash="gRjPUg">From a purely human point of view, at first this seems to be an impossible task. However, it begins to appear possible upon understanding that in order to achieve it, we are not alone. The most marvelous and powerful helps for which a human being may seek are always available. First is the generous and loving hand of the Eternal Father, who desires that we return to His presence forever. As our Father, He is always willing and desirous to forgive our errors and weaknesses and the sins we commit, subject only to total and sincere repentance. And as a complement to that—and as the maximum manifestation of His immense love for each one of His children—He provides us with the consequences of the singular work wrought by the Savior, namely the Atonement, brought about by an obedient Son always willing to do the Father’s will in benefit to each one of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible.p3" pid="2JjVnNQwoUi3sfWQhoMX_Q" hash="WMuDWA">The Lord revealed to the Prophet Joseph Smith the following: “And, if you keep my commandments and endure to the end you shall have eternal life, which gift is the greatest of all the gifts of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> This divine promise is possible to achieve. Eternal life is to live with our Father and with our families forevermore.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Should not this promise be the greatest incentive to do the best within our reach and give the best of ourselves in pursuit of what has been promised to us?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible.p4" pid="t5jLXzI5DkGmYWfQDRyBLQ" hash="ik2y0A">At the dawning of the Restoration, when this marvelous work was about to appear among the children of men, the Lord said, “Therefore, O ye that embark in the service of God, see that ye serve him with all your heart, might, mind and strength, that ye may stand blameless before God at the last day.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> With all our heart, with all our might, with all our mind, and with all our strength—that is to say, with all our being.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible.p5" pid="tq8Virr8GE2lH683qVquSQ" hash="Cx6jhA">President David O. McKay said that the rich rewards come only to the strenuous strugglers.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> These rewards will be for those who nurture faith in Jesus Christ and comply with His will to work, sacrifice, and give all they have received to strengthen and build the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible.p6" pid="UUiwkA3be0KGSd0MKICQUQ" hash="VAQezg">The fulfillment of the divine promise to have eternal life, to achieve perfection, and to be happy forevermore in the family unit is subject to the sincere demonstration of our faith in Jesus Christ, obedience to the commandments, perseverance, and diligence throughout our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible.p7" pid="9mvEGbm_yUyp2e9AAw7gqg" hash="tPlimQ">The Lord does not expect that we do what we cannot achieve. The command to become perfect, as He is, encourages us to achieve the best of ourselves, to discover and develop the talents and attributes with which we are blessed by a loving Eternal Father, who invites us to realize our potential as children of God. He knows us; He knows of our capacities and our limitations. The invitation and challenge to become perfect, to achieve eternal life is for all mankind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible.p8" pid="_a0JMgpOBkimIQ7mR78jVA" hash="fIL17g">Immediately after teaching that “it is not requisite that a man should run faster than he has strength,” King Benjamin indicated that “it is expedient that he should be diligent, that thereby he might win the prize.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> God will not require more than the best we can give because that would not be just, but neither can He accept less than that because that would not be just either. Therefore, let us always <span class="pageBreak" page-number="34"></span>give the best we can in the service of God and our fellowmen. Let us serve in our families and in our callings in the Church in the best manner possible. Let us do the best we can and each day be a little better.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible.p9" pid="b1HGjVOTy0e_bUwRWl54JA" hash="4wx46A">Salvation and eternal life would not be possible if it were not for the Atonement, brought about by our Savior, to whom we owe everything. But in order for these supreme blessings to be effective in our lives, we should first do our part, “for we know that it is by grace that we are saved, after all we can do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> Let us with faith, enthusiasm, dedication, responsibility, and love do all that is within our reach, and we will be doing all that is possible to achieve the impossible—that is, to achieve what for the human mind is impossible but with the divine intervention of our loving Father and the infinite sacrifice brought about by our Savior becomes the greatest gift, the most glorious of realities, to live forever with God and with our families.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible.p10" pid="BzuWqi8ZbkCs9yFM04YrHw" hash="fuyj-A">I pray that each one of us will remember and permanently renew, by partaking worthily of the sacrament, the commitment we made with our Heavenly Father the moment we entered the waters of baptism and when we received each one of the ordinances of the restored gospel. I pray that we will do the best we can in our roles as spouses, parents, children, brothers and sisters; in our callings; in sharing the gospel; in rescuing those who have drifted; in working for the salvation of our ancestors; in our work; and in our daily lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible.p11" pid="5nTkVwk7t0GGQ1LyyvyE1A" hash="75qNQQ">I pray that our lives allow us to declare, as the Apostle Paul, “I have fought a good fight, I have finished my course, I have kept the faith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible.p12" pid="b5REEuqNd0WsfRkg4MAffg" hash="pNAt7Q">As we do so, we will be fulfilling the requirements defined by our Father in Heaven to bless us more than ever before, in this life as much as in life in the eternities. He yearns to give us all that He has, even make us participants of His greatest gift, which is eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible.p13" pid="J09V_qcEWkqOufF6CwJQTQ" hash="YWxbQA">Even when, from a purely human perspective, perfection can appear an impossible challenge to achieve, I testify that our Father and our Savior have made known to us that it is possible to achieve the impossible. Yes, it is possible to achieve eternal life. Yes, it is possible to be happy now and forever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible.p14" pid="Wbf_KFItT0qEvre5aweCtA" hash="Ddxu9Q">The author of the perfect plan that contains these glorious promises is our Father in Heaven, and He lives. His Son, Jesus Christ, took upon Himself the weight of our sins and the injustices that are committed in the world to the end that we can be free from the consequences. I know our Lord Jesus Christ lives. The gospel and the priesthood have been restored to the earth for the last time, through the Prophet Joseph Smith. Today we have the enormous blessing of apostles and prophets called by God to direct us on the road to return to our Father. President Thomas S. Monson has been called to lead this great work in these days. He is a prophet of God. Of that I testify in the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2009/10/attempting-the-impossible</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2009-general-conference/2009-10-2040-elder-jorge-f-zeballos-64k-eng.mp3" length="4228075" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2009 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If You Will Be Responsible</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder JorgeF. Zeballos shares four key principles to help us be responsible to our Father in Heaven and become like Him.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_12565_000_55zeballos" doc-version="6" hash="gYm6SA">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="Wez8dB6mVUyKAnyE5sNYFQ" hash="Ms_J5w">If You Will Be Responsible</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p2" pid="w2FNelFQ_ki_-1P5FOgZqw" hash="sukaOA">By Elder Jorge F. Zeballos</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p3" pid="E6Iz4CYkkEeW-TS5MXiL-g" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=QSkCuXVy0UibKuMPa0OivQ"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" type="jpg" uri="jorge-f-zeballos-10.jpg" translate="no" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456484/d778c5f3dd54444098c0427cd414161a/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456484/d778c5f3dd54444098c0427cd414161a/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456484/d778c5f3dd54444098c0427cd414161a/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x279="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456484/d778c5f3dd54444098c0427cd414161a/200x279.jpg" data-src-320x447="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456484/d778c5f3dd54444098c0427cd414161a/320x447.jpg" data-src-460x642="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456484/d778c5f3dd54444098c0427cd414161a/460x642.jpg" data-src-640x894="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456484/d778c5f3dd54444098c0427cd414161a/640x894.jpg" data-src-1024x1430="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456484/d778c5f3dd54444098c0427cd414161a/1024x1430.jpg" data-src-2048x2861="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456484/d778c5f3dd54444098c0427cd414161a/2048x2861.jpg" data-src-3726x5206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456484/d778c5f3dd54444098c0427cd414161a/3726x5206.jpg" pid="QSkCuXVy0UibKuMPa0OivQ" hash="Ccteuw"></img></a>
		</div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="3Ne5_aLxxUeyJiw2UJ5NwA" hash="hjunaA">Let us press forward by learning our duty, making correct decisions, acting according to those decisions, and accepting the will of our Father.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="mFF1qUc_00qgTu6oCEVMrg" hash="sukaOA1">By Elder Jorge F. Zeballos</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="ilDjuakzCU6SMFucvZeA9Q" hash="Mgrnhg">
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p5" pid="7kymRLw21Uem07H4NU44Xg" hash="e41OFQ">I was only 12 years old when the missionaries arrived for the first time to preach in the city where I was born in northern Chile. One Sunday, after I had been attending the small branch for six months, a missionary offered me the bread as he was passing the sacrament. I looked at him and softly said, “I can’t.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p6" pid="I8mCzEfASEKH8CG_JUQ7NQ" hash="TdftbA">“Why not?” he replied.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p7" pid="EdK9d46XdU69VlKXa271hQ" hash="AOmBZw">I told him, “Because I am not a member of the Church.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p8" pid="f3BZ7FE_JUiNLCIo09veiQ" hash="3bwFAw">The missionary couldn’t believe it. His eyes were shining. I suppose he thought, “But this young man is in every single meeting! How can he not be a member of the Church?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p9" pid="IvQmQc4Kb0CTNMQzZTU1Vg" hash="zRAsPg">The following day, the missionaries were in my home, and they did everything they could to teach my whole family. But since my family was not interested, it was only my weekly Church attendance for more than six months that made the missionaries feel confident enough to continue. Finally, the great moment I had been waiting for came when they invited me to become a member of the Church of Jesus Christ. The missionaries explained to me that since I was a minor, I would need my parents’ permission. I went with the missionaries to see my father, thinking that his loving answer would be “Son, when you are of legal age, you will be able to make your own decisions.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p10" pid="41gawgnwLUqQhU2RiI88Dw" hash="RqDa0w">While the missionaries spoke with him, I prayed fervently for his heart to be touched so he would give me the permission I wanted. His answer to the missionaries was the following: “Elders, over the past six months, I have seen my son Jorge get up early every Sunday morning, put on his best clothes, and walk to church. I have seen only a good influence from the Church in his life.” Then, addressing me, he surprised me by saying, “Son, if you will be responsible for this decision, then you have my permission to be baptized.” I hugged my father, gave him a kiss, and thanked him for what he was doing. The next day I was baptized. Last week was the 47th anniversary of that important moment in my life.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p11" pid="1nnxvpaFHkWkOdNtw-1gGg" hash="HFzyEA">What responsibility do we have as members of the Church of Jesus Christ? President Joseph Fielding Smith expressed it as follows: “We have these two great responsibilities. … First, to seek our own salvation; and, second, our duty to our fellow men.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p12" pid="IwP-NKLoNkaC5Bz8uG1tsQ" hash="RA6d1w">These, then, are the main responsibilities that our Father has assigned to us: seeking our own salvation and that of others, with the understanding that in this statement, <span class="emphasis">salvation</span> means reaching the highest degree of glory that our Father has provided for His obedient children.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> These responsibilities that have been entrusted to us—and which we have freely accepted—must define our priorities, our desires, our decisions, and our daily conduct.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p13" pid="RvKiYNRd2kKHgXN6k4yVrA" hash="AeIoCA">For someone who has come to understand that, because of the Atonement of Jesus Christ, exaltation is truly within reach, failing to obtain it constitutes damnation. Thus, the opposite of salvation is damnation, just like the opposite of success is failure. President Thomas S. Monson has taught us that “men cannot really long rest content with mediocrity once they see excellence is within their reach.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> How, then, could we be content with anything short of exaltation if we know that exaltation is possible?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p14" pid="9bHJbSZInk6N414XARtvAQ" hash="-mhptg">Allow me to share four key principles that will help us fulfill our desire to be responsible to our Father in Heaven as well as respond to His expectation that we become as He is.</p>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.t1">
			<h2 pid="EfRNkOWdxUGPNFHI9yJfRQ" hash="cNBuVw">1. Learning Our Duty</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p16" pid="SfDj0JbTnEOUBA30dlnENA" hash="G8BbIw">If we are to do God’s will, if we are to be responsible to Him, we must begin by learning, understanding, accepting, and living according to His will for us. The Lord has said, “Wherefore, now let every man learn his duty, and to act in the office in which he is appointed, in all diligence.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Having the desire to do what is right is not enough if we do not make sure to understand what our Father expects from us and wants us to do.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p17" pid="FqwIDiCgMUCul6FAqHye8g" hash="Vbo8TA">In the story of Alice in Wonderland, Alice does not know which way to go, so she asks the Cheshire Cat, “Would you tell me, please, which way I ought to go from here?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p18" pid="C_OI0L2zcE2LkVlzHu8vFw" hash="tfR91g">The cat replies, “That depends a good deal on where you want to get to.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p19" pid="PyYZVz7gtEOWZQ8MH1dKNQ" hash="yEDgqQ">Alice says, “I don’t much care where.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p20" pid="Y3dH-GzCQ0q_vkPALffQRQ" hash="qd94Bg">“Then it doesn’t matter which way you go,” says the cat.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p21" pid="QPtX6aqAFU62NHUgnd2bfA" hash="e70fgg">However, we know that the path that leads to the “tree, whose fruit [is] desirable to make one happy”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> —“the way, which leadeth unto life”—is narrow. It takes effort to journey along the path, and “few there be that find it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p22" pid="ZfMZ08hh4UOscqHpbZZR_w" hash="jlyALA">Nephi teaches us that “the words of Christ will tell you all things what ye should do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Then he adds that “the Holy Ghost … will show unto you all things what ye should do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Thus, the sources that allow us to learn our duty are the words of Christ that we receive through ancient and modern prophets and the personal revelation that we receive through the Holy Ghost.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.t2">
			<h2 pid="zKhvg9f-7kS-8DpfjVsDDA" hash="lcPebQ">2. Making the Decision</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p24" pid="xaYjLWYk-0ymvYTO6fUMuA" hash="82PrgA">Whether we have learned about the Restoration of the gospel, a particular commandment, the duties associated with serving in a calling, or the covenants we make in the temple, the choice is ours whether or not we act according to that new knowledge. Each person chooses freely for himself or herself to enter into a sacred covenant such as baptism or the temple ordinances. Because swearing oaths was a normal part of people’s religious lives in antiquity, the old law stated that “ye shall not swear by my name falsely.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> However, in the meridian of time, the Savior taught a higher way of keeping our commitments when He said that <span class="emphasis">yes</span> meant yes and <span class="emphasis">no</span> meant no.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> A person’s word ought to be sufficient to establish his or her truthfulness and commitment toward someone else—and even more so when that someone else is our Father in Heaven. Honoring a commitment becomes the manifestation of the truthfulness and honesty of our word.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.t3">
			<h2 pid="3Hfa0x-92UGdCzmZ3SHg_w" hash="fRpFmQ">3. Acting Accordingly</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p26" pid="8a3fNRDy-0O8zPNz8It4rg" hash="Zhgxvg">After learning our duty and making the decisions that are associated with that learning and understanding, we must act accordingly.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p27" pid="IP-nrxUT4EyL-UTkT-T7xA" hash="CE3V-Q">A powerful example of the firm determination to meet His commitment with His Father comes from the Savior’s experience of having a man sick with palsy brought to Him to be healed. “When Jesus saw their faith, he said unto the sick of the palsy, Son, thy sins be forgiven thee.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> We know that the Atonement of Jesus Christ is essential to receiving forgiveness for our sins, but during the episode of the healing of the man with palsy, that grand event had not yet taken place; the Savior’s suffering in Gethsemane and on the cross had not yet happened. However, Jesus not only blessed the man with palsy with the ability to stand up and walk, but He also granted him forgiveness for his sins, thereby giving an unequivocal sign that He would not fail, that He would fulfill the commitment He had made with His Father, and that in Gethsemane and on the cross He would do what He had promised to do.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p28" pid="rSRsbQVcQkqNMqXfrSHBnQ" hash="wfYHyw">The path that we have chosen to walk is narrow. Along the way are challenges that will require our faith in Jesus Christ and our best efforts to stay on the path and press forward. We need to repent and be obedient and patient, even if we do not understand all the circumstances that surround us. We must forgive others and live in accordance with what we have learned and with the choices we have made.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.t4" pid="_B5DXXP93Ua-GVEW5RdYJQ" hash="c7P1Gw">
			<h2 pid="qPj4wOiwMU6f0lXC6fs94Q" hash="zuC6WA">4. Willingly Accepting the Father’s Will</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p30" pid="z8kYyHE_EUuZoHFMskHieQ" hash="MqsnEA">Discipleship requires us not only to learn our duty, make correct decisions, and act in accordance with them, but also essential is our developing the willingness and the ability to accept God’s will, even if it does not match our righteous desires or preferences.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p31" pid="Jy2b4e57IEiZvYz_kziDlQ" hash="-_3kRw">I am impressed by and admire the attitude of the leper who came to the Lord, “beseeching him, and kneeling down to him, and saying unto him, If thou wilt, thou canst make me clean.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> The leper did not demand anything, even though his desires might have been righteous; he was simply willing to accept the will of the Lord.</p>
			<span class="story">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p32" pid="zF_QtvRtnEC1VwERYpvaNQ" hash="1BEc2w">Some years ago a dear, faithful couple who are friends of mine were blessed with the arrival of a long-yearned-for son, for whom they had been praying for a long time. That home was filled with joy while our friends and their daughter, who was their only other child back then, enjoyed the company of the newly arrived little boy. One day, however, something unexpected happened: the little boy, who was only about three years old, suddenly went into a coma. As soon as I learned of the situation, I called my friend to express our support at that difficult time. But his reply was a lesson to me. He said, “If it is the Father’s will to take him to Him, then it is all right with us.” My friend’s words contained not the slightest degree of complaint, rebelliousness, or discontent. Quite the contrary, all I could feel in his words was gratitude to God for having allowed them to enjoy their little son for that brief time, as well as his total willingness to accept the Father’s will for them. A few days later, that little one was taken to his celestial mansion.</p>
			</span>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p33" pid="Ymbq0TrLVUK7UJsmpSTJeg" hash="hjunaA1">Let us press forward by learning our duty, making correct decisions, acting according to those decisions, and accepting the will of our Father.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible.p34" pid="EjhYiFDSJ029xpX9TyzzZQ" hash="otzODA">How grateful and happy I am for the decision that my father let me make 47 years ago. Over time, I have come to understand that the condition he gave me—to be responsible for that decision—meant being responsible to my Heavenly Father and seeking my own salvation and that of my fellowmen, thereby becoming more as my Father expects and wants me to become. On this very special day, I testify that God our Father and His Beloved Son live. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/04/if-you-will-be-responsible</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2015-general-conference/2015-04-5050-elder-jorge-f-zeballos-64k-eng.mp3" length="5098699" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
