<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Joseph Anderson</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Joseph Anderson.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Joseph%20Anderson.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Joseph Anderson.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Eternal Joy Is Eternal Growth</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We are living in what may be termed one of the most important periods in the history of the world. This is the dispensation of the fulness of times, a time when the keys of all former dispensations have been given to the prophets of the restoration; </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03006_000_5020" doc-version="2" hash="4VMqjA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="68ZYdX2IhUqZ-pILr91EIA" hash="qrQmug">Eternal Joy Is Eternal Growth</h1><p class="authorName" guid="946f0450-6e3f-43c6-a915-52104b03023b" pid="ial4LZqFZ0qm09Pz_vMmUg" hash="11x1hw">Joseph Anderson</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="88ae2466-8c34-454d-a71b-bcc73ca5c725">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2416.jpg" alt="Elder Joseph Anderson" guid="c9a4228a-b9d3-4e85-a43f-91e990e95fa2" pid="aU-xqW4Lf0igbMyos4sS2w" hash="XyrnKQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p1" guid="9b7afcd6-123b-41e7-a53c-ecfe8e3b42f8" pid="ILah-PkIYUab9brOZOWXLg" hash="mkTKSw">We are living in what may be termed one of the most important periods in the history of the world. This is the dispensation of the fulness of times, a time when the keys of all former dispensations have been given to the prophets of the restoration; a time when God has spoken from the heavens, angels have appeared to man; a time when men and women have the Holy Ghost conferred upon them. Moroni has said that by the power of the Holy Ghost we may know the truth of all things. There is need for this great power in the earth today—this steering power. It is our duty and responsibility to live worthy of the blessings that we enjoy. Where much is given, much is required. We are required to live exemplary lives, to keep the commandments of the Lord, and it is also our responsibility to carry the true gospel message to all mankind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p2" guid="e1a3194b-8d66-4ec5-ba67-a341651c1625" pid="j1rCT-cJyE2Kva2nuRxw5g" hash="Ieg_Hg">A prophet of the Book of Mormon said: “… men are, that they might have joy.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.25" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:25</a>.) Pleasure is not necessarily joy. Lehi was undoubtedly not speaking of temporary pleasure, but of eternal joy. In referring to man he was not limiting his existence to mortality. He was speaking of eternal man. Man can have joy in accomplishment, particularly eternal accomplishment. If he fails to live in such a way as to receive the blessing of eternal life in the kingdom of his Father, he will reap misery and disappointment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p3" guid="1d2dd3db-436d-4d0f-91e1-760c3b87a41b" pid="uLXHnA9ec0qYteKUXHWn1g" hash="_ZB3aw">The Lord showed unto Abraham the intelligences that were organized before the world was. And God saw these souls, that they were good, and he stood in the midst of them, and he said unto those who were with him (there were many noble and great ones):</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p4" guid="6a4049f5-98ba-4a0f-b158-7f59cf0441b6" pid="yNV42zZTUkSszG87CfwjEA" hash="_DUGVQ">“We will go down, for there is space there, and we will take of these materials, and we will make an earth whereon these may dwell;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p5" guid="6d7d89bc-fa14-4973-a56d-ba0135bedc83" pid="oAKmiB3YGEWAi9fhysaB9Q" hash="otfHCw">“And we will prove them herewith, to see if they will do all things whatsoever the Lord their God shall command them;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p6" guid="7c7792d9-0ab6-49fa-91ec-939876663c71" pid="O5oqkgmse0eCt0aL2DBeEg" hash="YHdF6A">“And they who keep their first estate shall be added upon; and they who keep not their first estate shall not have glory in the same kingdom with those who keep their first estate; and they who keep their second estate shall have glory added upon their heads for ever and ever.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.24-26" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:24–26</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p7" guid="0749f9e2-8864-41cc-ba48-1eed5ef4f19e" pid="yPsZsTr6eEu7Z0IJQfFkUQ" hash="gtK90w">There were many there who did not keep their first estate, their spiritual existence, who were disobedient, and as a result they were not added upon; they did not have the privilege of passing through this second estate. They had their free agency, and they chose the course for which Lucifer contended.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p8" guid="3b484af4-901a-47e0-9b73-313e64272133" pid="UAsdzbkiqkaemnNb0D-UFw" hash="4vyvLw">And there are many in this second estate who will not keep this estate and therefore cannot expect to have glory added upon their heads for ever and ever, because they have not kept the commandments which the Lord their God has given them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p9" guid="d730609f-320a-4163-9e05-35394c01af27" pid="JNNxW0cu7UuLLWPle--x3g" hash="gLYRSA">These commandments are given for our welfare and blessing here as well as hereafter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p10" guid="b61fae3a-0aab-468c-869a-4c9a84f8e0c7" pid="IcDoqUERtk-HuipAgsdi4w" hash="puUukQ">We must pay a price for everything we get, whether of a temporal or spiritual nature, and we generally get about what we pay for. If, for instance, I should purchase a suit of clothes, in order to get the best material, the best style, and the proper fit, I must pay a higher price than if I am satisfied with a suit made of shoddy material and poor workmanship. Likewise if I desire to purchase a home, an automobile, or whatever it may be. If I seek intellectual values, I must pay the price by study, research, by devoted effort and ofttimes sacrifice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p11" guid="2fc1d841-ce53-4032-b4aa-04f0dc3962bf" pid="hGpXNYah8E2C2Tel2-jeCA" hash="l43l3Q">The same is true of spiritual values. One cannot expect to inherit eternal life if he is not willing to pay the price and to do the things required for such salvation and exaltation. We are told that “there is a law, irrevocably decreed in heaven before the foundations of this world, upon which all blessings are predicated—And when we obtain any blessing from God, it is by obedience to that law upon which it is predicated.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/130.20-21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 130:20–21</a>.) Our goal is salvation in the celestial kingdom of our Heavenly Father and to receive the glory that awaits the faithful there.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p12" guid="c79cf70e-cd16-448a-babc-02b4d730d945" pid="sEIdRIZoSUaGDVRg6_kZAw" hash="K_X7hg">The Savior of the world unselfishly and willingly paid the utmost price, even that of his own blood, in order that mankind might be redeemed from the grave. Death before that time was a matter of serious concern. The grave seemingly had won a victory. There was indeed the sting of death. His offering made it possible for us to come forth from the grave, to break the bondage of the tomb. He bought us with a price, the price being his own blood. He has also set the price which we must pay in order to obtain salvation in his presence and that of our Heavenly Father, and that price is the keeping of his commandments. Those commandments are God’s laws—nature’s laws too—and the breaking of them brings penalties; observance brings the promised blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p13" guid="d9c17083-0ecf-4891-8fb1-6670b49e1436" pid="GxnQNzQahkqXRAWdM-IXiQ" hash="1YDICQ">The Lord has told us, “… my yoke is easy, and my burden is light.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/11.30" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 11:30</a>.) This does not mean that one can receive exaltation in the kingdom of our Heavenly Father at bargain prices. There are those who offer such bargains, but one gets merely what he pays for. If we are to attain eternal life in our Father’s kingdom, it is not sufficient that we have mere passive belief in our Lord and Savior and his great redeeming sacrifice. Surely one cannot expect to receive the greatest blessings that the Father has in store for his faithful children by paying bargain prices.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p14" guid="3dd5ef3e-1f99-46ce-8efc-cea6b17b2df9" pid="2-SMqMmZEkeoi8wYvpTuzg" hash="kYLXTg">There are those who seem to take the attitude that inasmuch as they have been baptized by immersion and by one having proper authority, and have had hands laid upon their heads for the reception of the Holy Ghost, their salvation is assured. Others seem to think that if they have had the priesthood conferred upon them, there is nothing further required at their hands. Aren’t we as badly mistaken when we fail to live the life of a Latter-day Saint, after we come into the Church, as are those who think that mere belief in the Lord is sufficient? Where much is given, much is required, and if after the light of Christ comes into our souls we allow that light to become dimmed, we are under greater condemnation than those who have not had the light. Of what good is the priesthood to one if he does not honor it and live worthy of that great power?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p15" guid="a2035ff9-bcce-4c02-88ee-479082e99703" pid="vnJfcpQYq0KnYyIIaVLtmg" hash="_Eh_Og">The gospel is the power of God unto salvation unto everyone that believes and obeys it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p16" guid="d464da21-638a-41fe-bc94-ce9b163270df" pid="xsX3EGZSBUqUs3LuHhVMyQ" hash="ZvBsdg">The injunction to those who accept the gospel is that they “add to [their] faith virtue; and to virtue knowledge;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p17" guid="3b3f200a-374e-48e4-8e8d-2ee3797b421e" pid="PEL01V6t2UuMt3HplPrr2A" hash="WHF5uw">“And to knowledge temperance; and to temperance patience; and to patience godliness;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p18" guid="e00c7a3e-360a-452f-a798-8bb4d6e241d3" pid="PGahcw4OuUW-zB8g3umsxw" hash="BcMapQ">“And to godliness brotherly kindness; and to brotherly kindness charity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p19" guid="9d68707a-9a86-41ae-b5a7-b084492f7326" pid="k0cba6fkJ0qvi1UDdIONLA" hash="NXacnA">“For if these things be in you, and abound, they make you that ye shall neither be barren nor unfruitful in the knowledge of our Lord Jesus Christ.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-pet/1.5-8" class="scriptureRef">2 Pet. 1:5–8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p20" guid="d14c1afa-22e7-4394-b728-0ba9187bbceb" pid="LVbdYYkEQkGN3hysQWw5oA" hash="DaODlQ">Just as in this enlightened age the inventive mind and the creative hand have added greatly to man’s obligations, so has the fact that the Spirit of the Lord has borne testimony to our souls of the truth of this work added greatly to our responsibilities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p21" guid="6387e13c-1d31-4f51-b324-a73395a59bd8" pid="_vSsXqLjzkukBqCSLl3IBA" hash="YzxDfg">In his Sermon on the Mount the Lord said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p22" guid="3b1f1055-da98-4e5e-bbe9-f1925fca0c07" pid="MSlcKQA2L0ulwZw7TBrpcA" hash="GEHPJA">“Not every one that saith unto me, Lord, Lord, shall enter into the kingdom of heaven; but he that doeth the will of my Father which is in heaven.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p23" guid="e036405e-8683-47e0-871b-7357eee331a0" pid="30h-kmK3HE2DylcvOX7Hpw" hash="_1q9FQ">And again:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p24" guid="807a84aa-ec09-46aa-9d90-a55468488487" pid="ljvRaMFOuUqC3DFGpEzWLQ" hash="mpAa5g">“Therefore whosoever heareth these sayings of mine, and doeth them, I will liken him unto a wise man, which built his house upon a rock:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p25" guid="4023d263-f771-424f-923d-570da1eebc9d" pid="ocdiapO07kypdmEfFfc5bA" hash="boT1ww">“And the rain descended, and the floods came, and the winds blew, and beat upon that house; and it fell not: for it was founded upon a rock.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p26" guid="cd3f1eae-7a9a-49ad-8524-90c5f01549c2" pid="zYuQNDfn2kGD_vi9BnWCyw" hash="LNi1dg">“And every one that heareth these sayings of mine, and doeth them not, shall be likened unto a foolish man, which built his house upon the sand:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p27" guid="c343c7c6-ccb1-429c-9866-5daeb0577875" pid="mzGbZPLZ7Ua7MIaMuZ0ZAg" hash="EcF7oQ">“And the rain descended, and the floods came, and the winds blew, and beat upon that house; and it fell: and great was the fall of it.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.21,24-27" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 7:21, 24–27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p28" guid="1b5045b3-bf3b-465b-989d-e33dcad3a7ee" pid="1rvcPJAYwUKj6xSQ9tlQpQ" hash="B4Gd2A">The Lord has given us in this dispensation a life-giving, life-shaping purpose when he gave us the gospel of Jesus Christ. The gospel is given for the benefit of man. We too must have the necessities of life. We are living in the time of a great civilization. It is only natural and proper that we should desire the things that make life wholesome and pleasurable; but with all our struggle for the necessities and luxuries of life, we must not overlook the great purpose of life, which is eternal salvation and exaltation of the souls of men. Like Israel of old, we are a peculiar people. We are peculiar in the sense that we believe in constant revelation from God and that he is revealing to us his truth. The ultimate goal of life is to assist in the fulfillment of God’s plan for his children, the salvation of human souls, and that, of course, pertains to our own souls also. It is our responsibility to bring a knowledge of these things to our Father’s children wherever they may be, to bring to them a living knowledge of the truth. It is also important that we go into the temples of the Lord and do vicarious work for those who have passed to the great beyond so that they too may have the blessings that we enjoy if they accept the message when it is brought to them in the spirit world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p29" guid="280c0f78-3e5e-46b2-ba93-9b941721f601" pid="4MsekoQ9yEW_1zsLJ-wRIQ" hash="wzU12A">Life is largely worthless unless it is held together, given shape and form by some great purpose, and there is no greater purpose than that of helping our fellowmen as well as ourselves to attain the glorious salvation which our Lord has promised to his obedient children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p30" guid="30905163-44b4-4ba3-8c78-df3b2a1ade8e" pid="m3eL52Z_k0OL87Ji42MHxA" hash="xdyD3w">The possibility of salvation applies to all of God’s children, both the living and those who have passed to the existence beyond. The conditions upon which salvation in our Heavenly Father’s kingdom may be attained are incorporated in the plan that was formulated in the heavens before we came here, and there is no possibility of such salvation without obedience to that plan. We must accept Jesus Christ as the author of our salvation. The salvation that I am thinking of, the salvation that Latter-day Saints seek, is eternal life in the presence of our Heavenly Father and his divine Son, not only eternal existence but eternal growth and activity. This is the joy of which Lehi spoke.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p31" guid="77810482-6cd3-4fb3-9742-c947d1c84f5d" pid="IUqBfbsPz0WiL3TPdTTi7w" hash="uJHk8g">Truly, “the kingdom of heaven is like unto a merchant man, seeking goodly pearls: Who, when he had found one pearl of great price, went and sold all that he had, and bought it.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/13.45-46" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 13:45–46</a>.) May the Lord bless and inspire us in our efforts to attain this goal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth.p32" guid="b7e3fd6f-148e-4135-8755-8c3623274331" pid="xdDSmevtdEeQptCzWTS3yQ" hash="uiiRog">I testify that Jesus is the Christ and that he is the author of the restored gospel, the plan of life and salvation, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/04/eternal-joy-is-eternal-growth</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1971-general-conference/1971-04-5020-elder-joseph-anderson-64k-eng.mp3" length="6174861" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Living Christ</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I sincerely hope and pray that I may have the Spirit of the Lord to be with me as I speak to you this afternoon.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03012_000_7020" doc-version="2" hash="h0g6xw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="dB3YCAf2KEyuWC08eQP1EA" hash="FIMtqQ">The Living Christ</h1><p class="authorName" guid="946f0450-6e3f-43c6-a915-52104b03023b" pid="KlitO9GJREOpc3fYvz-TyA" hash="11x1hw">Joseph Anderson</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="fe6c7622-1c8f-4d27-947b-137ee4627e4b">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2416.jpg" alt="Conference photo" guid="babc4c07-706a-4660-9d35-deb768990a2d" pid="najb88pyZEm-q0VPL027Hw" hash="XyrnKQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p1" guid="53481161-ebd2-400f-b6d9-f9a1bbc15f2b" pid="BCqpzl_LgEyArUMwzWUctw" hash="o3QHCw">I sincerely hope and pray that I may have the Spirit of the Lord to be with me as I speak to you this afternoon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p2" guid="f8a51c8c-373c-41f6-a7f1-36c74bce50b3" pid="4U7sSRNL60aqNWD68uYE6Q" hash="-KCGAA">Many thoughtful people are deeply concerned about the religious and social conditions that prevail in our society. It is the contention of some students of history and men of learning that our civilization is rapidly deteriorating and we are drifting into a decadent period of existence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p3" guid="608e102e-4ff8-491f-85d4-e8bde62b9bea" pid="tpbsQotihUGlY5XpFoSlPA" hash="ZsF3_g">We have made remarkable progress in scientific research and education, in transportation and communication. Science has found the cure for many dread diseases, alleviated pain, and lengthened the span of life. Superstition has been overcome to a great extent and we have been blessed with such comforts of life as our forefathers never dreamed possible. But in spite of these remarkable developments, there is great confusion and uncertainty in the realm of religion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p4" guid="2ee3a28d-d29f-4b73-ad0f-535cd931faf5" pid="tDwx77GjxkefHvWh0JfxUA" hash="1rWmVA">The thing that is needed more than anything else today is a return to faith in the Lord Jesus Christ and in the gospel plan that he gave. Today, as perhaps seldom if ever before, civilization is in need of a knowledge of the true and living God. Yes, the cure for the ills that beset the world today is true religion. We need the humility of prayer, and a determination to learn God’s will and to keep the commandments that he has given. We need faith that our Savior lives, faith in his redeeming sacrifice. In other words, Christ and his teachings should become the center of our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p5" guid="16a4c2e9-eea4-4ed4-8a5e-a84379495ad4" pid="0M8yonNBd0akxRqiUzpzUQ" hash="xkixjg">Our late president, President David O. McKay, in an interview with a leading journalist sometime ago, was asked: “If you had the power to grant unto America one great wish, what would it be?” His answer was: “I would wish that America had a testimony of the Lord Jesus Christ and would obey his principles; that would bring peace on earth. I believe that is the greatest blessing that can be given.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p6" guid="da279557-5a33-4ed7-a9a2-6d84e3c4cc26" pid="-KirGltbNkOlkIIlxgEtDA" hash="n8MS0g">Do we need Jesus today? Do we need his teachings? If we are to survive, if our civilization is to persist, we must accept him and his inspiration and guidance. Someone has said that “the world needs a bath in Christ’s pure religion. Only a dedication to Christ can wash the dirt out of our society.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p7" guid="e0b9c8c4-d0e5-4f5b-a17c-95c8153142da" pid="33qSUYGTbUuVJCBD79WHVg" hash="i3a0jQ">A noted lecturer and traveler was recently asked: “What is the greatest message that could be broadcast to the world today?” And he answered that the greatest message would be the message that God has again spoken to man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p8" guid="137244fa-0f9c-427f-8178-131880366291" pid="UdYDf8J8nkyh6qIEwf1Ysw" hash="7ssV-Q">There are those who have wished that they might have had the privilege of living when the Savior was upon the earth, that they might have known him and heard the sound of his voice and felt the touch of his hands. Yes, it would have been a great privilege and blessing to have been with him when he walked upon the earth had we been among his followers and had faith in his mission. Very few at that time recognized him as the creator of heaven and earth and the Savior of mankind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p9" guid="a02b410d-511a-4cc6-af88-99efefa0cd77" pid="K5yxAxUl902gr12BE4Fhxg" hash="wzskzA">It would have been a marvelous experience to have been as closely associated with him as were his disciples, but even they did not fully appreciate his mission. Though he explained his mission to them and told them that he would lay down his life for the salvation of mankind, that he would come forth again from the tomb on the third day, that he would take upon himself the sins of all mankind, it was difficult for his followers to understand these things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p10" guid="aa02cfed-d730-4e4e-b595-02aae6670b8f" pid="MKTzifTHXEyuIDsfkLx-XQ" hash="D79AtQ">After his crucifixion and his body was placed in the tomb, Peter and others of the apostles returned to their nets and their fishing. Those in other occupations no doubt manifested a similar attitude. They did get a glimpse of his Messiahship on one occasion before his crucifixion when Jesus asked his disciples:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p11" guid="bd5afd26-9d18-477d-80f3-4f34afedcdbd" pid="EdzejPs8wEWHEXlNV8n59A" hash="m6MlUQ">“Whom do men say that I the Son of man am?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p12" guid="9a058f71-5bd7-436c-abc7-f8cba357bbe0" pid="QlWH_0jJmUyBG92f0wWDAA" hash="j7ecPg">“And they said, Some say that thou art John the Baptist; some, Elias; and others, Jeremias, or one of the prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p13" guid="098ee75d-bdf4-468e-9aed-938f959b0de1" pid="2kHxgfS7qEG7k5b2k7T75A" hash="zYTRdg">“He saith unto them, But whom say ye that I am?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p14" guid="af62db7f-beb1-4be9-87bd-4e0f7c4e41e4" pid="x3P6P5hQyUuxeOc8wZ8Pug" hash="3d-4RA">“And Simon Peter answered and said, Thou art the Christ, the Son of the living God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p15" guid="789d90e0-4c58-4a72-ada8-990e19a8a883" pid="nr3FkpBFHEqCfUFr-AVqGQ" hash="tNK7fg">“And Jesus answered and said unto him, Blessed art thou, Simon Bar-jona: for flesh and blood hath not revealed it unto thee, but my Father which is in heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/16.13-17" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 16:13–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p16" guid="5c3df3de-97b6-4dcb-b195-89f57e7b71f0" pid="AgfEImmg8kuE88EYXETljw" hash="Xxz9aw">Peter and others were permitted to witness the Master’s transfiguration, and they had seen the wonderful miracles that he had performed; yet it was not until after his resurrection and his appearance and association with them prior to his ascension and after they had been endowed with the Holy Ghost on the day of Pentecost that they were prepared to proclaim to the world without fear that he was the Christ, the Son of the living God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p17" guid="27eab986-6cf4-4e1d-9145-9eff08ca793e" pid="yn7T26Aof0Kt1iIGlTk2ug" hash="olmylQ">The holy scriptures tell us that following his resurrection, the risen Lord was seen by Mary Magdalene at the sepulcher. (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/20.16" class="scriptureRef">John 20:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p18" guid="b662f01c-638c-433d-b214-b19462c7e8d0" pid="CQV6iiSOMkiSnY65Ag74Dg" hash="gQRu3w">He appeared unto two of his disciples as they walked and went into the country, and they knew not that it was he.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p19" guid="8d839eb2-6bbf-4adb-a838-a785eaf12777" pid="dQmZAwQRxEKgZEkivySY8A" hash="bkC1aQ">He appeared to his apostles on several different occasions following his resurrection, and, according to Apostle Paul, he was seen by above five hundred brethren at once. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/15.title" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p20" guid="e4c815c3-ef1f-49c8-8cb5-c608896f2477" pid="g3RUrtM9_0CcYKEHgf6ePg" hash="TjNRmA">Yes, and following his resurrection and ascension, he appeared to the people on this the American continent and established his church and proclaimed his gospel to the people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p21" guid="f87b2433-b743-40b2-9a3e-98dbb4f29c80" pid="MbgsVaWb0E6H7i79ps8Rfg" hash="HhSKIw">Through his prophets on this continent, the Lord told the Nephites before he came into the world that at the time of his birth there would be great lights in heaven, insomuch that the night before his birth there would be no darkness and it would appear to man as if it were day. The record tells us that this is just what happened on this continent at the time of his birth. Christ, the light of the world, was born; the influence of that light permeated the whole earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p22" guid="fcfb6d79-432b-47d6-bd38-b7d4a570cc2a" pid="QIY_LiFBZ0G5dLxMQOsQeA" hash="dqcZVQ">And then at the time of his death and crucifixion, as had been prophesied by Samuel the Lamanite, there was darkness upon this continent for three days while Christ’s body lay in the tomb. There was thick darkness over the face of the entire land. The light of Christ had gone out of the world, and darkness, thick darkness, covered the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p23" guid="d2d5a079-bbda-4f10-acd3-724eb8aeccc2" pid="oGVQcGXTPkKtBDfDTHy2WA" hash="IW74og">And so it is with our own lives when we have the Spirit of the Lord, which we can only have if we keep his commandments. There is light in our souls; there is joy and happiness. But when we fail to keep the Lord’s commandments and wickedness prevails, darkness comes into our lives, and great is the darkness when the Spirit of the Lord withdraws from us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p24" guid="93a281c7-7ead-40b4-9806-7b8ca0c87d6e" pid="Q66B5OzOEkaH2haeXDc05A" hash="YGe0tQ">Nearly two thousand years have passed since that time, and in our dispensation the resurrected Christ, our Lord and Savior, has appeared to men again. The dispensation in which we live was introduced by the appearance of the Father and his Beloved Son to a boy in the woods near Palmyra, New York, in answer to sincere and humble prayer. The heavens were opened and he beheld with his eyes and heard with his ears the voices of God the Father and his Son Jesus Christ, two separate individuals. Light and knowledge were revealed to the boy regarding God and the restoration of his kingdom that could come from no other source. It was the introduction of the last dispensation of the gospel, the dispensation of the fulness of times.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p25" guid="8da07fd4-0eb9-402b-b8d4-ee313e80d795" pid="33hRrYBXM0OB6Fwc95q2Zg" hash="ptGGcA">The Savior has also appeared to men at other times in this dispensation. As recorded in the 76th section of the Doctrine and Covenants, he appeared to Joseph Smith and Sidney Rigdon in vision in February 1832, and they bear witness of this occasion to the following effect:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p26" guid="8bb39bd6-d2b0-4913-8f98-bdf10c465a35" pid="VIAvsUU0Y0y00-BYHTkISg" hash="DkHgJQ">“And now, after the many testimonies which have been given of him, this is the testimony, last of all, which we give of him: That he lives!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p27" guid="465aa13f-ad8d-4698-bae5-81132e00f80e" pid="RMQUWg811USpMGyCM5GIZA" hash="E7qA3w">“For we saw him, even on the right hand of God; and we heard the voice bearing record that he is the Only Begotten of the Father—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p28" guid="0fff6c10-88e3-4c54-9023-f820abf14c44" pid="e1bPPQ19LEu_TzEM492gOw" hash="HuUMpw">“That by him, and through him, and of him, the worlds are and were created, and the inhabitants thereof are begotten sons and daughters unto God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.22-24" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:22–24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p29" guid="0fcfef9c-e35f-4072-82a0-a9f548d6fd55" pid="rout_UJ14Ee-Yq243y8xrQ" hash="_1q9FQ">And again:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p30" guid="0e824cc9-7f1b-49d3-bb3e-3a637f665d2f" pid="TeFVHbn_20SsZT2IXPse6Q" hash="hbCAlA">“And this is the gospel, the glad tidings, which the voice out of the heavens bore record unto us—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p31" guid="4ff22154-5c06-4897-a334-b3ce7e6e1a3f" pid="mBvCQuEi_ECC-fZWB-RdBw" hash="FrB5Pw">“That he came into the world, even Jesus, to be crucified for the world, and to bear the sins of the world, and to sanctify the world, and to cleanse it from all unrighteousness;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p32" guid="a705ab66-4e6f-4d80-8c4c-5f88757ccf2c" pid="-oKp2dFoYUGbRFRHbsikfw" hash="VQI-zg">“That through him all might be saved whom the Father had put into his power and made by him.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.40-42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:40–42</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p33" guid="9e6fe4c1-40ee-4d9d-ba48-ce2b23785447" pid="gNturXPfaUG-_SexQ71btg" hash="E3QeGQ">Then again, in the 110th section of the Doctrine and Covenants the Prophet Joseph and Oliver Cowdery relate this experience:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p34" guid="7426b1eb-1d07-4f35-bc46-e7ed137778b4" pid="khRUuBicMkC1rElUAT_vpg" hash="t95bqA">“The veil was taken from our minds, and the eyes of our understanding were opened.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p35" guid="d11f1d10-1623-4168-8d89-3a9ec235ced8" pid="apMYHRXCMkK-s9dEdT_6Dg" hash="3ytSuA">“We saw the Lord standing upon the breastwork of the pulpit, before us; and under his feet was a paved work of pure gold, in color like amber.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p36" guid="a41ad650-0071-4927-a8c4-1fe3e5b80e9d" pid="TssOaZElsESBoBvD8c-qPg" hash="lsTGsw">“His eyes were as a flame of fire; the hair of his head was white like the pure snow; his countenance shone above the brightness of the sun; and his voice was as the sound of the rushing of great waters, even the voice of Jehovah, saying:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p37" guid="0d607238-965c-444f-947a-d62dbc6b394f" pid="JsfY2yCydEenlgQwQNye3w" hash="8qnJjw">“I am the first and the last; I am he who liveth, I am he who was slain; I am your advocate with the Father.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/110.1-4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 110:1–4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p38" guid="4872c82b-01de-415a-988b-adfae1fa2b79" pid="0gKenJOnMkG35_S5L6LxjQ" hash="p_J1qw">Others in this dispensation have seen the Lord. We are not restricted to the testimonies of Joseph Smith, Sidney Rigdon, Oliver Cowdery, and others who have seen the Lord in this day and time. We may and do know for ourselves that Jesus the Christ does live, that he is the mediator between us and the Father. We have that gift and power that Peter had when he said: “Thou art the Christ, the Son of the living God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/16.16" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 16:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p39" guid="76e6d10f-7380-4b1f-a259-05aa6ca24e1c" pid="CBj8V02lUEWafdJedRs83Q" hash="AEjM2w">We have had hands laid upon our heads by men of divine authority, men holding the priesthood of God, which has been restored to earth in our time, and have received the gift of the Holy Ghost, which is the spirit of prophecy and revelation. The Holy Ghost manifests and bears witness concerning the existence of the Father and the Son and the truth of the restored gospel of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p40" guid="ee0f0916-f800-4c93-959c-9f861c9a8976" pid="6d4T6AAzvUODPPh5fB_iSg" hash="3fFqpA">Yes, the world needs contact with the heavens in this day and age. The world needs a prophet. Little does the world generally realize that the Lord is revealing his mind and will through his living prophets today. As Latter-day Saints and members of the Lord’s church, we are truly a light set upon a hill, and it is our privilege and responsibility to assist in the great work of the Savior in bringing to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p41" guid="eac63300-e9d1-4c5e-9468-209e134b4842" pid="fh_0BqHa_02U9iLvbpShAw" hash="tJjOEA">It is of the utmost importance that we as Latter-day Saints have the light of truth, which comes from the Lord himself, burning within our souls, and that that light shall so shine that others may be led to find the way to salvation, exaltation, and eternal life. Jesus has said: “I am the light of the world: he that followeth me shall not walk in darkness, but shall have the light of life.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.12" class="scriptureRef">John 8:12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p42" guid="6a0140e3-53de-4be0-8d83-d95976fb28d3" pid="PZZLQ28CsEivT-aLXV3gtw" hash="zIwpYQ">Our message to the world, which we have been proclaiming for more than 140 years, is that God lives and that Jesus was and is the living Christ; that the heavens have been opened to man; that the Father and the Son have appeared in this dispensation; that the plan of life and salvation has been restored; that the time of the Savior’s second coming is near at hand; that the Lord, through his church, is preparing the way for that appearance; and that the only way in which peace can come to the earth is through obedience to the restored teachings of Jesus Christ. Yes, I testify to you that he is the Prince of Peace, and it is his will that all mankind may hear this message and give heed thereto.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ.p43" guid="590f88c1-8ba7-441b-969d-b430e677f8ec" pid="4bDupN17uE6PjmTm0ugX5g" hash="zzpIsQ">May the peace that passeth understanding come into the hearts of men and women everywhere through a knowledge of these things, I humbly pray in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/10/the-living-christ</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1971-general-conference/1971-10-7020-elder-joseph-anderson-64k-eng.mp3" length="6992563" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man’s Eternal Horizon</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon?lang=eng</link>
      <description>It has been truly said that the greatest asset of a man or a nation is faith, that the men who built this country and made it prosper during its darkest days were men with unshakable faith, men of courage, men of vision, men who always looked forward</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03020_000_4050" doc-version="2" hash="2RfXdA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="TJoOHeJG00a3SgbOkDGqMA" hash="J8BnIg">Man’s Eternal Horizon</h1><p class="authorName" guid="946f0450-6e3f-43c6-a915-52104b03023b" pid="PgBqgl6w20mWrj1tT8iQlQ" hash="11x1hw">Joseph Anderson</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="0e5894ce-2931-4a30-af83-b2b4bf01fd28">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2416.jpg" alt="Elder Joseph Anderson" guid="66fb14ae-300d-40e3-b578-de337d60bb3f" pid="fQXSwUeZ6UyIYKJvMn1cAg" hash="XyrnKQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p1" guid="84e328e8-5f5f-46b9-a540-64d51f09027c" pid="OW0Qb2uMgEayLVVHBVztzA" hash="2IusWQ">It has been truly said that the greatest asset of a man or a nation is faith, that the men who built this country and made it prosper during its darkest days were men with unshakable faith, men of courage, men of vision, men who always looked forward and never backward.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p2" guid="98bf65c1-f6b1-4088-8389-8ad07230c049" pid="i6jx0o3yiE2cwwHzLYM0ww" hash="5EZmyw">The same can be said in truth of those who established this church under the inspiration and revelation of the Lord and of those who have built upon the foundation they laid. They too were and are men of unfailing testimony and unwavering faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p3" guid="3f8261dd-faa1-4b1e-804f-db5743859e59" pid="n-pWTLjEKUmBRcitkmPLnQ" hash="fOZtWg">I think perhaps there has never been greater need for faith than is the need today, particularly faith in divine leadership. Members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, as a general rule, have faith in divine leadership, but the world needs faith in God, that he rules the world; and the people of this nation and the world need that faith, faith in the God of this land and faith in the God of the world, who is Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p4" guid="e21e6820-7c2f-49a8-9699-d0c0971f0e26" pid="TV_ia_erOkW6FnkglE9VPg" hash="hp0IeA">Many of us have had the experience of being on a ship traveling on the ocean. As we look in the various directions, we can see nothing but water. As far as the mortal eye can see, the sky comes down and meets the water. The sun comes up on the horizon, and in the evening the sun sets on the horizon. The same is true when we are on the ground; the limit of our vision is the horizon. Is it not true also that the limit of our spiritual perception is the horizon we see?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p5" guid="f190f83a-bb9d-442f-a2cc-a63b5064c0df" pid="AckY9_PFYUCAmSfbvoZc-w" hash="mCH7rg">What about our spiritual horizon? Is it limited to our present struggle for the things of this world? Is it limited to an acquisition of things of the flesh? Is our horizon limited to our competition with a money-mad world, to the obtaining of the worldly things of life, or does it reach out to an eternity with God and our loved ones in the life to come?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p6" guid="2f8d46bf-e97a-4dc4-a536-7c40fbffce4b" pid="WUdd-aA47UKV7dVBCgUtBQ" hash="fPy6rQ">Our horizon should extend to an unlimited future beyond death—out beyond those things of a temporal nature. Our horizon of the future should not be confused with the close-up horizon of present conditions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p7" guid="7101285e-a2cb-4b5b-bd29-8055ee28e87b" pid="i8mv-LQvLUegPlBG3gIQCQ" hash="yBjL7A">Our philosophy of life contemplates an eternity of life—life without beginning before we came here, life without end hereafter. Our happiness here and hereafter depends upon our actions here. We should therefore seek the finer things of life. The road leading to eternal life must be paved with obedience to the commandments of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p8" guid="0c0424bd-3ff3-4c18-b4a9-3d71258767b1" pid="ZenVFpL5sE-KJT_eOAQlxQ" hash="sUabbA">We once dwelt in the presence of our Father, in the spirit, and we rejoiced at the opportunity to come to earth and take upon ourselves mortality and pass through the experiences we here encounter, that we might prove ourselves worthy of greater experiences and greater blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p9" guid="5f691fe4-17ad-4be5-9897-853845a3e081" pid="ti9R7W0yPkCoZdTQu3FY5Q" hash="ynwEJw">While here we are not to enjoy the presence of our Father, but we can communicate with him, and we can hear his voice if that becomes necessary. The Holy Ghost is given to us as our guide and companion and monitor, if we live worthy of that blessing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p10" guid="914185ad-4cf5-439f-bbc9-fe1c6ecc3792" pid="tNtDX7ius0qFxm-svSB1Bg" hash="EKpQpw">It seems difficult for some to have faith in an eternal being and that he can communicate with man, that he hears and answers our prayers, that he is the Father of our spirits, for we are dual beings, spiritual and physical; that he loves us; that he has given us commandments which, if we accept and live them, will result in mortal as well as eternal blessings to us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p11" guid="2d2928fe-7c83-445e-b516-228bdb63003b" pid="_xyUocD1502zyyRfXzqEcw" hash="QB9CFA">There was a time when men would have laughed to scorn anyone who would have said that in time to come we would be able to sit in our homes and watch and see and hear by means of television and radio things that are transpiring today in our own country, in Europe or Asia, South America or Africa; that these conference proceedings would be telecast to the listening world by means of remarkable electronic devices.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p12" guid="8eb54dbf-c7e4-45ff-8468-a7d69c303c41" pid="9Z0FI6k1jU6iUfKTEhAQSw" hash="P2yT-Q">In our time we have seen men walk on the moon and heard the messages they have sent over the great expanse of space between us and the moon and witnessed pictures they were transmitting.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p13" guid="5f05dce0-9eb7-4707-9745-751c661717c5" pid="_scV_NoTd0i6403VTU54oQ" hash="01bgnw">These things have been accomplished by faith, by work, and by intelligence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p14" guid="fdfa4154-54da-4454-8af2-419e7188d851" pid="fg6z28MZDUehLEfzzvr8fA" hash="jgG16Q">Can we talk with God?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p15" guid="7df90d79-9803-47cf-b03b-d57e8fcab73e" pid="kcy30DnIQ0uL7GgleAVSRA" hash="jK6BuQ">Can our prayers, even in thought as well as word, ascend to the Father of us all, and does he have the power to make answer thereto?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p16" guid="e63656db-e676-4df8-b9b2-b7e585bd3d47" pid="PdV4lPqXOkalZhxORooq6g" hash="KPUonA">We lived by sight in the spirit state before we came here; we are walking by faith in this mortal existence. The Spirit of God bears witness to the spirit of man that we are God’s children; that he loves us; and that there is a purpose to earth life, a great and mighty purpose, a glorious purpose; that by keeping the commandments that he has given us we may gain knowledge and understanding; that we may gain experience by overcoming the opposition with which we must contend; that we shall resurrect from the grave in the due time of the Lord and eventually return into his presence if we live worthily. This is the long-distance horizon we should keep in view.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p17" guid="814445b9-cb0e-4c01-b247-0ca3c8332fef" pid="aM7_-2DsckiBrMkKUKmcqQ" hash="ZcrT3g">Alma, a Book of Mormon prophet, relates an experience in his time about a people who were cast out of the synagogues because of the coarseness of their apparel, a people who were poor as to the things of this world and were also poor in heart. They came unto Alma, explaining their situation, and asked what they should do. Alma answered by explaining to them the principle of faith and teaching them the word of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p18" guid="7f2d66f0-3888-4547-abfa-363ca2e82adb" pid="8eUoCsJ_UUq4rJ0b1BGAKg" hash="ef8EhA">Concerning faith he states that “faith is not to have a perfect knowledge of things; therefore if ye have faith ye hope for things which are not seen, which are true.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.21" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p19" guid="2e0190db-99ea-4209-8664-6d1239ddf7ea" pid="bnQPsLN0cUu5uSIhjvoJmg" hash="CBUAMA">Alma then goes on to compare his words, which are truly the word of God and the gospel of salvation, to a seed that a man plants in the soil. He suggests that if we will give place that a seed may be planted in our hearts, and not cast it out or resist the Spirit of the Lord, if it is a true seed it will swell within the breast; and when one feels this swelling motion he cannot do otherwise than admit that the seed is a good seed, for it enlargeth the soul and beginneth to enlighten one’s understanding, and it becomes delicious to the individual. Further, when the seed, or the word, or the gospel, swells and sprouts and begins to grow in your soul, you know it is a good seed, and therefore your knowledge is perfect; it is no longer faith but knowledge.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p20" guid="6dffbdf8-ded7-45f5-85bc-49bc7c6b3ae8" pid="tBAWqAhFGE2Xtjv8BXlQyw" hash="tA59Nw">People sometimes say that one cannot know that the gospel is true. As indicated by Alma, if, when you hear the word of God, you do not cast it out by unbelief or resist the Spirit of the Lord, the swellings within your breast, its enlargement of your soul and its enlightening of your understanding are of such a nature that they cause you to know that it is the truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p21" guid="5498cbc6-b5f0-49da-a082-0a980735c75b" pid="LMwbKG56N02yriWg1HRDrg" hash="wdN73w">However, this is only a beginning. You must nourish the seed; in other words, you must nourish the testimony that you have that it is true, by living the teachings of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p22" guid="616cb80b-0d15-4afd-a237-0483e7e080d3" pid="LjB4Soyab06onipRaB2yPw" hash="5bkr9A">If you will do this, this ancient prophet tells us, the seed will grow into a tree and bring forth fruit. But if the tree is neglected, it will not take root; and when the heat of the sun cometh and scorcheth it, it will wither and die. This is not because the seed or the word of God was not true nor because the fruit thereof would not be desirable, but it is because the ground was barren and the plant or the tree was not nourished, in which event one cannot have the fruit thereof that he otherwise would obtain.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p23" guid="f8b17bf3-0efd-4cd6-b36c-62f8539cd806" pid="5YRsINLyTkW0Ecw2tkm0HQ" hash="1qXZIA">If, however, you have faith and patience to nourish the word, or the tree, as time goes on you may pluck the fruit thereof, which is most precious and delicious to the taste.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p24" guid="7112e397-86b5-4758-8a19-721fa3015c1f" pid="IlaHg8REBkCSdX3A9JSU3g" hash="6D0zvg">I testify to you that if you do these things—truly try this experiment regarding the word of God as contained in the gospel of Jesus Christ and live in accordance with the commandments therein set forth, nourishing the truths of the gospel—you shall have the privilege of feasting upon this fruit; your faith will be fully rewarded and will develop into a sure knowledge of the truth of the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p25" guid="ab72170f-ee84-4939-91f9-ed19495c6343" pid="dmKZbs1iYEWkYuI1fXnvKA" hash="frs7og">We testify that when occasion requires, the voice of God can be heard by the Lord’s latter-day prophets; that they can tune in through the instrument of faith; and that even you and I can see beyond the veil, if it is in accordance with the Lord’s will and if we are in tune with the Infinite.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p26" guid="fde65ea9-1fa0-47d2-abf5-9482ab4cc148" pid="5OKvqyjZ_06mlhjZb6Pshw" hash="E5gPpg">The Latter-day Saints believe and teach that without the experience of mortal life, its problems and accomplishments, and without a resurrected body, the spirit of man cannot have a fullness of joy. Our philosophy of life contemplates an eternity of existence—life without beginning in the preexistent world and life hereafter throughout the eternities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p27" guid="a73b66f2-6afb-4380-a808-925734863c42" pid="MDWK1lAlFkemqb9vhcKWlg" hash="GLUtbw">Our happiness in this life and in the life to come depends upon our actions here. If we are to attain the goal of eternal salvation and exaltation in the kingdom of our Heavenly Father, we must hold fast to the iron rod, which is the word of God, and render obedience to the commandments of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p28" guid="ddf1271c-1d31-4bb9-abe8-8c55ebeed240" pid="2GVh6AG-9Emxu_pgl8CXDA" hash="jxMPXQ">It is reported that on one occasion when Sir Isaac Newton was thinking seriously concerning the nature of light, he cut a hole in a window blind and a ray of light entered his room. He held a triangular piece of glass in the range of the light, and there were reflected in great beauty all the colors of the rainbow. And for the first time man learned that all of the glorious colors of the universe are locked up in a ray of white light.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p29" guid="465a309d-cfd7-4a16-a2d5-70ddb3226fa0" pid="qCQJjYpWd0-T9_m_IDEVMg" hash="DRXeVw">It is important that we live all the principles of the gospel and obey all the commandments that the Lord has given us if we are to grow more nearly like our Father and his Beloved Son. We cannot say, “Oh, I believe in missionary work—it is important; I am thoroughly converted to the welfare plan or the wonderful social program of the Church for its young people; but I don’t believe that Joseph Smith was a prophet or that our present prophets are guided by revelation from the Lord.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p30" guid="61c4ca5b-eed9-464a-a1de-c6b8b4e5c689" pid="HzEVi4Pme06ds2r7m5xU5w" hash="Dx2GWg">Some may say, “I believe the Book of Mormon, but I can’t believe that it was received from an angel as Joseph said it was.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p31" guid="b595bef7-ed05-43af-89df-e683d5808225" pid="qwCgXjMxkk2FpO3QUn73VA" hash="CzK38g">With a wavering faith of that kind, how can such a person expect to have the true light of Christ, the true understanding and light of the gospel? How can he expect to receive the blessings that the Lord has promised to the faithful? If he leaves out any one of these principles, he does not get pure white light. If he fails to have faith in all the principles of the gospel and does not have faith to live in accordance therewith, he cannot expect to get the pure light of the gospel in his heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p32" guid="d11d18cd-17be-4a0b-8a7f-d217c4f3e1e4" pid="RE6lVDOke0yIrqp2-WBvug" hash="1j1Gcw">If you truly have faith in God sufficient to impel you to keep his commandments, you will draw nearer to him and he will come nearer to you, and your faith will become knowledge, and the limit of your horizon will extend into the eternal world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon.p33" guid="95f45392-e41e-4d38-8b56-20f74b08fa59" pid="__myxZvqUEyLvzzaBWfFoA" hash="jS1WbA">May we grow in faith through the love and blessing of our Lord and Savior. May we keep the commandments that he has given us, that we may ultimately find salvation and exaltation in his celestial kingdom, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/04/mans-eternal-horizon</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1972-general-conference/1972-04-4050-elder-joseph-anderson-64k-eng.mp3" length="6061867" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Light and Knowledge to the World</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In the year 1820 a young man 14 years of age was very greatly disturbed in his mind as to which of all the various religious denominations was acknowledged by God as his church. He had been engaged sincerely in searching for the true church, and he h</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03027_000_2030" doc-version="2" hash="EWyiVQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="YoJl5KAqdE2c-lRllSD_FQ" hash="Zd6XbA">Light and Knowledge to the World</h1><p class="authorName" guid="946f0450-6e3f-43c6-a915-52104b03023b" pid="xpTZvMaqT0GIJF-J-HYsiA" hash="11x1hw">Joseph Anderson</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="f26d784f-df22-48de-9068-8b536bfe0e5e">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p1" guid="e2300bc1-7863-4c54-b502-d858ef62b4b2" pid="H17U0wRxQk-i11dqbFP1gw" hash="x1crAw">In the year 1820 a young man 14 years of age was very greatly disturbed in his mind as to which of all the various religious denominations was acknowledged by God as his church. He had been engaged sincerely in searching for the true church, and he had read the statement of James as contained in the New Testament: “If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask of God, that giveth to all men liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given him.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.5" class="scriptureRef">James 1:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p2" guid="ab1ba880-029b-4b09-ae89-217d45b3034b" pid="JukiXeP48UmvPuWFrs1VCg" hash="hQV0bg">In his confusion, having a sincere and earnest desire, and with unwavering faith, the boy called upon the Lord in prayer. Joseph said he had scarcely started to pray when he was seized upon by some power which entirely overcame him and which had the astonishing effect of binding his tongue so that he could not speak. Thick darkness gathered around him, and he thought he would be destroyed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p3" guid="3eb04fa7-d235-4f40-af35-cdfd0017cfee" pid="etQbds10HUqrw3EnN-BtgA" hash="LEXYDA">Exerting all his power to call upon the Lord to deliver him from the power which had seized him, and when he was ready to sink into despair, he saw a pillar of light exactly over his head, above the brightness of the sun, in which light he saw two Personages, and they spoke to him. (See <a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.16-17" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:16–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p4" guid="917a493b-8bd6-4810-9d71-fb407338088c" pid="1i-nhkrwxEKL0ElfGnq50Q" hash="bXwvIA">Think of the great contrast: overpowering darkness as compared with the brightness of the sun—the power of the adversary as opposed to the glory of God. Certainly darkness would be dissipated by the appearance and in the presence of those two divine Personages, the Father and the Son, whose brightness and glory defy all description.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p5" guid="991b929c-b138-418f-81b9-3b765f935abb" pid="-iFW3yyLakK-18NA1qmRtQ" hash="YE_BhQ">In answer to the boy’s question as to which of all the sects was right and which he should join, the Father, pointing to his Son, asked Joseph to hear him. The Son, the Savior of the world, Jesus the Christ, the resurrected Lord, answered Joseph by saying that he should join none of the existing churches and denominations, that they were all wrong.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p6" guid="7b04b297-caba-4ebb-80c1-4ed4bb35aa39" pid="El3kxXCzCU6PGFRX79Y3Aw" hash="E8Iv-A">The day was dawning when the gospel in its fullness was to be restored to mankind, when the light of heaven was to fill the entire earth, a time to come in which nothing would be withheld, when everything which had been kept from the understanding of man from the beginning of time would be made known; a time about which the prophets of old have spoken; a time when in very deed a great and a marvelous work and wonder would come forth among the children of men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p7" guid="6e5ee3c6-d7e5-47ad-8491-3e6876874426" pid="UJ6q02McP0K5aJ21X4TMzw" hash="6hO5mw">According to our understanding of holy writ, God the Eternal Father has manifested himself to his earthly prophets on very few occasions since the time of Adam. The following instances may be recalled.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p8" guid="2b742daa-f611-4b12-a901-9dd9f88d28ba" pid="1KmaiQi3okmBhHJGy8JKRg" hash="Dm69ow">When Jesus was baptized in the River Jordan, as he came up out of the water a voice from heaven was heard saying: “This is my beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/3.17" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 3:17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p9" guid="45b4a16d-431d-466f-9055-b8621ea76627" pid="pas700bHDEaEyLAAyjim6w" hash="0s9ZQQ">At the time of the transfiguration, the voice of the Father was again heard: “This is my beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased; hear ye him.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/17.5" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 17:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p10" guid="2b1e52ac-afc9-4d9f-9fee-3c7e2bcb9bbe" pid="pQJE_TqbP0GjkklywtNwGg" hash="ukcp5w">When the resurrected Christ was introduced by the Father to the Nephites on the Western Hemisphere, the following language was used: “Behold my Beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased, in whom I have glorified my name—hear ye him.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.7" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p11" guid="da14884b-d4ad-43cf-acec-e81aaef7384c" pid="xs2P8JjdhUauZRd4mxR8uA" hash="j-3Txw">Since the Savior’s appearance to the Nephites, there is no scriptural account of the voice of the Father being heard again among men until the Father and the Son appeared unto the boy Joseph in the spring of 1820, at which time, according to Joseph Smith, the Father again bore testimony in the following language: <span class="emphasis">“This is My Beloved Son. Hear Him!</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.17" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p12" guid="7caca080-a612-4245-a384-2bc426347a9c" pid="WT_0d52EVEC2r0gXxBYA3w" hash="MQVJZg">As Joseph was calling upon the Lord in prayer more than three years later, a messenger from the Lord appeared in his room surrounded by light, which light continued to increase until the room was lighter than at noonday. On this occasion and subsequent appearances, the angel made reference to a book written upon plates of gold that was deposited in the Hill Cumorah in the state of New York, which plates, when translated, became the Book of Mormon, a new scripture, a new and important witness for Christ. On the occasion of the angel’s first appearance he quoted to Joseph various verses and prophecies from the Bible, among which was the second chapter of Joel, from the 28th verse to the last, part of which reads as follows:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p13" guid="03cfdbca-4b0b-4f7a-adeb-548a66d3b9aa" pid="Qhn1wFe_ZEizXOqMU1DIQg" hash="I0jsWA">“And it shall come to pass afterward, that I will pour out my spirit upon all flesh; and your sons and your daughters shall prophesy, and your old men shall dream dreams, your young men shall see visions:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p14" guid="ca3c51d9-e478-4dcd-9289-dcec6f9b3ba8" pid="AzdPeq0YZkiJFT4CQ8OmZw" hash="fWcFjQ">“And also upon the servants and upon the handmaids in those days will I pour out my spirit.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/joel/2.28-29" class="scriptureRef">Joel 2:28–29</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p15" guid="796381e7-43fe-4ef2-a1ad-f9caa0af702f" pid="CFZnkrYJfk6hrrEL_iHVKg" hash="s4dgYQ">The priesthood of God, which had been taken from the earth because of apostasy, was restored to Joseph Smith and Oliver Cowdery in 1829, also by heavenly messengers, namely, by John the Baptist and by Peter, James, and John, the presiding authority in the earth after the death of the Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p16" guid="4b04ff51-487a-4fe4-9c91-ad9ec4853110" pid="L9UE0lahQUaIy4jJUPftyQ" hash="Q2oywg">Before the Church was organized April 6, 1830, the Lord gave a revelation through this young man, the prophet of the Lord, to his father, Joseph Smith, Sr., in which the Lord said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p17" guid="01d1e312-f9d2-44f2-81cc-9408a759bdc1" pid="DTnkXXo3oEu3xhXb3mKgQw" hash="5gzwmQ">“Now behold, a marvelous work is about to come forth among the children of men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p18" guid="524c361b-576c-4097-949a-10eedad2c330" pid="EPwHho9VUEWz74Kh8CkjqA" hash="cmF3qw">“Therefore, O ye that embark in the service of God, see that ye serve him with all your heart, might, mind and strength, that ye may stand blameless before God at the last day.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/4.1-2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 4:1–2</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p19" guid="a8461f2a-8950-4792-9e47-9df55be03916" pid="2v84cEW6TkC2TtPe2nPeKw" hash="n3JiRg">Similar advice and counsel was given to others at about the same time through revelation from the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p20" guid="9f910efc-bb53-4024-adfe-87eb78d363cf" pid="30vadfZorkKxJujw_feXwA" hash="cbeRFA">To Joseph Smith was given the commission and the authorization from heaven to restore to earth the doctrine, organization, and authority of Christ’s church to a people who had lost the fundamentals of true religion. Joseph Smith’s successors have built and are building upon the foundation that Joseph laid through revelation from God in proclaiming its truth to all the world and in preparing a people to meet the Savior when he shall come to reign upon the earth a thousand years in peace and righteousness. Elder Harold B. Lee, whom we have sustained in this conference as a prophet, seer, and revelator and President of this church, is God’s representative, the mouthpiece of the Lord to his people today, a man whom we love, a man whom we can sustain and support with all our hearts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p21" guid="01365ac7-430f-480e-b301-15cb53cab03d" pid="8U-PSjDzO0G_Lyzr_gZNNQ" hash="RQA5jw">The revealed word of God to Joseph, and particularly the words of the Prophet Joel, have been and are being fulfilled relative to the pouring out of the Spirit of the Lord upon all flesh. I quote from our late President Joseph Fielding Smith:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p22" guid="5ae70b1c-ea2e-4833-a8e6-0c89250f19de" pid="_-p5no9EhkCNagszdVrNQA" hash="6Olf0g">“The Lord said he would pour out his Spirit upon <span class="emphasis">all </span>flesh. <span class="emphasis">That does not mean that upon all flesh the Holy Ghost should be sent, </span>and that they should be participants in the blessings which those are privileged to receive who have been baptized and endowed and become members of the Church; but <span class="emphasis">the Lord would pour out his blessings and his Spirit upon all people and use them to accomplish his purposes.” </span>(<span class="emphasis">Doctrines of Salvation </span>[Bookcraft, 1954], vol. 1, p. 176.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p23" guid="e8d7ebfb-0a3f-4cfd-960e-63b7fca9af3b" pid="3SnAtPU4T0yrr01uKgG8yg" hash="HsNH_A">Marvelous scientific developments have come since the heavens were opened to that 14-year-old boy, when this dispensation, the dispensation of the fulness of times, was ushered in.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p24" guid="111bd006-3549-473e-bc55-5d5cfb422aaa" pid="kURiJDEcNEWyGEw3Bvaxsw" hash="yYq_vg">Since the true knowledge of God was revealed in that mighty vision, the Lord has in very deed, in many respects, poured out his Spirit upon all flesh.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p25" guid="e6ceaccf-7c25-43fc-8580-fa5f570500e6" pid="MbkAxzZ6J0KoOoiFui_L4Q" hash="vy0H9w">Human beings very much like ourselves have lived upon this earth since the days of Adam. Their physical strength no doubt has been equal to our own. Abraham of old had superior wisdom and knowledge, and others like unto him. There have been among the inhabitants of this world men and women of significant intelligence, those who built the pyramids, those to whom the Lord gave understanding regarding the heavenly bodies, men of faith, good men, religious men, great thinkers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p26" guid="8090fbab-916a-4890-900e-efcd825cb215" pid="nGVFz6fWvk673fkVCJbkxA" hash="aexgCw">Yet down through the generations of time mankind have not had the comforts and conveniences, they have not had the opportunities that we enjoy. Men, women, and children obtained an existence by toiling with crude instruments long hours under most trying circumstances. In spite of their fertile lands, nations and kingdoms suffered greatly from famines, and dread diseases and pestilences have decimated peoples.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p27" guid="cb9f64e6-f784-4276-96a4-43245e91ba69" pid="R6WPxeZ9ukak2fICr_YxDQ" hash="FfX_Hg">Since the opening of the heavens, as indicated, man has conquered the darkness of night through the development of the electric light, the incandescent light, the neon light, etc.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p28" guid="9c680b5c-59a7-4b73-92db-43f07c7a489e" pid="sasIm5PiJUicojwt_nHZeg" hash="aCCGcw">Gas lamps were a laboratory novelty in the early life of Joseph Smith and his followers, and the electric light as invented by Edison was not given to man until 1879 and 1880.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p29" guid="960aea1a-4754-4a80-8b88-85059217937a" pid="SNgVJzdjPUuK4rReNHufWw" hash="9eUT5A">Great strides have been made in conquering pain and disease. The life of man has been prolonged, and pain alleviated through the use of anesthetics, medical and surgical discovery and development, refrigeration, sanitation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p30" guid="f0bf4d1a-36fe-4873-a2b2-a803515e25ba" pid="rbKaHvkapECcFXBk6l2Y4w" hash="VksARA">Think of the great advances in transportation, railroads, steamships, automobiles, airplanes, jet planes, and so on.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p31" guid="383237ec-18b1-4756-910a-dec699179601" pid="oKdqhyhU8EC6LhbVRl_7FA" hash="PQXf2w">We have the marvelous means of communication, such as the telegraph, the telephone, radio, television, Telstar broadcasting, and now space exploration and space satellite technology.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p32" guid="cec2984a-62b0-42c7-abad-ebb699c62a7d" pid="qJf5b446o0-EwIBdKy6JvA" hash="Y6hyKw">Surely, we can say with Morse when he sent the first message by telegraph in 1844, over a forty-mile line, “What Hath God Wrought!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p33" guid="05c26e3f-3b70-4073-bb3b-15226fa633ac" pid="w7J03PcSckuihQeQxov1gw" hash="079BYw">The glory of God is intelligence; in other words, light and truth. All intelligence comes from God, and anyone whose mind is opened to the development of inventions for the benefit and blessing of mankind receives that light and truth through study, through research, through inspiration and guidance from the Spirit of the Lord, whether that individual be a Morse, an Edison, an Alexander Graham Bell, an Orville or Wilbur Wright, or whoever he may be.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p34" guid="8f47a9e5-ad80-49c1-b2d2-487def0af5e7" pid="A6YI9ZZuoEi_1Jzx4mPgNQ" hash="csgSNg">How important it is that we have the light of truth which comes from the Lord himself! In fact, he has said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p35" guid="de560770-4c37-46f6-8a15-f0b6e31d6a7b" pid="NUlHB_29hkqkwUfCpWPw8w" hash="HHcGXw">“And that which doth not edify is not of God, and is darkness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p36" guid="bfc992f7-27ac-438b-9af3-60fed1058c9b" pid="blNdL8IV2EOgGG21MZBnGw" hash="E-KYJw">“That which is of God is light; and he that receiveth light, and continueth in God, receiveth more light; and that light groweth brighter and brighter until the perfect day.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/50.23-24" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 50:23–24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p37" guid="57c0acbc-ecf7-44aa-ac64-807e672a77ab" pid="LEkFKVcBUUyICAZSMRIljQ" hash="_N7uCQ">The greatest need of the world today is an understanding of the true and living God, to know that he lives, that he rules in the heavens, that he is our Heavenly Father, the Father of our spirits, and that Jesus Christ is his Beloved Son, the Savior and Redeemer of the world; that he is the creator of the universe.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p38" guid="b4d03e84-3270-4696-ab42-b4e32b065bba" pid="P0zrvF64ZUuk8Nt4bM4rrQ" hash="vM7FAA">There is confusion in the minds of many people as to just what is the nature of the God we should worship and serve. This is life eternal, to know the only true God and Jesus Christ, those great personages whom Joseph saw in that heavenly vision. This knowledge brings joy and satisfaction to the soul. It is intended for all mankind. We are told that ultimately every knee shall bow and every tongue confess that Jesus is the Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p39" guid="7b0927b3-62a4-432c-9d95-32a3f4e528c3" pid="SUadklvDCkWSKogacmcPcQ" hash="wpk4NQ">God the Father and his beloved Son have manifested themselves in this dispensation. Heavenly messengers have personally restored the priesthood of God, the power to act in his name. The Spirit of God is operating upon the minds of men and women everywhere. Light and knowledge are being poured out upon the inhabitants of the earth. Marvelous scientific developments are being used to make possible and speed up the preaching of the restored gospel to mankind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p40" guid="d86367de-159f-4d30-98b3-90e5a5460da3" pid="oNsQ-_4AAEW5BqHbRrhIWQ" hash="aU6PWg">Temples are being built and ordinances performed therein in accordance with the plan of life and salvation which pertains to all mankind, both the living and the dead. Yes, a great and a marvelous work has come forth among the children of men, and God is pouring out his Spirit upon all flesh.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world.p41" guid="24c36096-3bab-4ca4-971d-b348037d06d6" pid="UhaCSfe-UUaEKUNdjIfCbg" hash="6PE0kQ">I testify to these truths in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/10/light-and-knowledge-to-the-world</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1972-general-conference/1972-10-2030-elder-joseph-anderson-64k-eng.mp3" length="6232798" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Rock of Revelation</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Enoch, the sixth from Adam, was most certainly one of the great prophets of all time, for he walked and talked with the Lord for three hundred years, according to the scriptures. Imagine the understanding that entered his mind, the enlargement of his</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03033_000_6040" doc-version="2" hash="OQoVjw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="AAsJSTtLA0KV_EtWGM_1Uw" hash="sjTzUA">The Rock of Revelation</h1><p class="authorName" guid="946f0450-6e3f-43c6-a915-52104b03023b" pid="8TryPWLfeE-NTEn23cTQMw" hash="11x1hw">Joseph Anderson</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="aa787452-a2a8-4ca6-9d38-117353eb1c8a">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p1" guid="aa5ad7af-e1ad-4ea2-908a-1ec8e1d58699" pid="ZHcMmhsB1UmEEfdxtZhu3A" hash="VfT72Q">Enoch, the sixth from Adam, was most certainly one of the great prophets of all time, for he walked and talked with the Lord for three hundred years, according to the scriptures. Imagine the understanding that entered his mind, the enlargement of his soul, and the eternal truths that were revealed to him by the Creator of the earth and the heavens.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p2" guid="6a8900cd-2b7e-42ce-9e34-214f36eb7684" pid="hL48iKYfkkGe5twtWXYenw" hash="5JNbFw">In the Book of Moses in the Pearl of Great Price, we read:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p3" guid="7d884046-d073-49f1-85de-80723d5c236c" pid="V_9eNu6c8E61we2WDir1fg" hash="rXIBiw">“And I saw the Lord; and he stood before my face, and he talked with me, even as a man talketh one with another, face to face; and he said unto me: Look, and I will show unto thee the world for the space of many generations.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/7.4" class="scriptureRef">Moses 7:4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p4" guid="c53370b6-0fd4-4e58-b981-339061146529" pid="Gwsdh7ACAUaWVshT4W1Omg" hash="xnP2vg">The Lord showed unto Enoch all the inhabitants of the earth, and he told him all the doings of the children of men. He saw the wickedness of the people, the flood which covered the earth in the days of Noah. He saw the day of the coming of the Son of Man in the flesh in the meridian of time; he beheld him lifted upon the cross; he saw the mourning of the creations of God and heard the earth groan; and in answer to Enoch’s inquiry and pleading, the Lord said to Enoch:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p5" guid="7b9d1a16-eacb-445a-8f5c-f53134503016" pid="ruEwjnYk1USjaen4Y-XKrg" hash="UmGKqw">“As I live, even so will I come in the last days, in the days of wickedness and vengeance. … the day shall come that the earth shall rest, but before that day the heavens shall be darkened, and a veil of darkness shall cover the earth; and the heavens shall shake, and also the earth; and great tribulations shall be among the children of men, but my people will I preserve.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/7.60-61" class="scriptureRef">Moses 7:60–61</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p6" guid="56f77854-6632-4135-8459-3ea5ec97c453" pid="jcbP7Uz8AUOLyrg5-ESLUQ" hash="Z5QERw">Our Father and his Beloved Son knew before man was placed upon the earth, and before this world was created, the story of man’s existence upon this earth—the plan of life here and salvation and exaltation in the life to come. The dispensations of time were understood, the purpose of earth life was known, and the development of that plan was fully charted. Otherwise, how could the Lord show unto Enoch, as he did to other prophets also, the history of this world, including the families that should dwell upon the earth throughout the centuries of its existence?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p7" guid="b7ccebba-edd2-43f7-b083-f1f478142686" pid="4BfjKSaLa0qZziQxQeMduA" hash="3S4hHg">In the Book of Abraham we read:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p8" guid="ee0cbebb-c681-4736-b4f8-43a2b6b17e5d" pid="TCPGE1SFakKfR5LsAhlanw" hash="6IQYGg">“Now the Lord had shown unto me, Abraham, the intelligences that were organized before the world was; and among all these there were many of the noble and great ones;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p9" guid="610ed6d3-ee7e-449f-9bb3-7c5cfecf54a6" pid="m-MlxnQICUem4DCTi1Us7w" hash="_pbnJA">“And God saw these souls that they were good, and he stood in the midst of them, and he said: These I will make my rulers; for he stood among those that were spirits, and he saw that they were good; and he said unto me: Abraham, thou art one of them; thou wast chosen before thou wast born.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.22-23" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:22–23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p10" guid="3ed1a81f-f418-4560-8f88-2fa04f289682" pid="7JpRRNCmnkKT9itzGBsiOw" hash="IgXQ1Q">In the first chapter of the book of Jeremiah in the Bible, the Lord, in speaking to the prophet Jeremiah, said: “Before I formed thee in the belly I knew thee; and before thou camest forth out of the womb I sanctified thee, and I ordained thee a prophet unto the nations.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/jer/1.5" class="scriptureRef">Jer. 1:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p11" guid="48549732-521e-4ebc-b7b8-68db3b9611ad" pid="h6PcppqMM0G0iZN3ollO9g" hash="RiraBw">Not only did the Lord know who were to be his rulers, but undoubtedly there was a chart or outline prepared showing the times of the various dispensations of the gospel, the things that would happen in those dispensations, and the conditions that would precede those periods of time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p12" guid="21d47692-1261-4818-b82c-6e2311058fb1" pid="i8Gq7C5h3USzrN7tR4oEcw" hash="sG4f-g">The scriptures record the prophecies of God’s servants relative to these things. And from the time of Adam, the Lord through his prophets has foretold the events that would precede his second coming, the time when the gospel of our Lord should be restored to earth and proclaimed to all mankind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p13" guid="c2462bdc-12e7-4232-bd19-1a94d0356a84" pid="wWl9FxEDzkSr2lyK1Bh-ZA" hash="GA6CEw">When King Nebuchadnezzar of Babylon conquered Israel, he arranged to have brought to Babylon some of the princes of Israel; the record says: “Children in whom was no blemish, but well favoured, and skilful in all wisdom, and cunning in knowledge, and understanding science. …” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/dan/1.4" class="scriptureRef">Dan. 1:4</a>.) Among these princes who were brought into Babylon was the Hebrew prophet, Daniel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p14" guid="7ffabf70-3a6d-4692-bc50-66d68ba9209c" pid="H9GHJ0Izd0666tE7DzjRxA" hash="F9inbA">In the book of Daniel in the Bible, we read of a dream that Nebuchadnezzar had, which dream gave him great concern. The account says that upon awakening he was unable to recall the dream. He called upon the wise men of Babylon, the magicians, the sorcerers and Chaldeans, to tell him the dream and to give him the interpretation thereof. This, of course, was an unusual request, and these wise men were greatly agitated; they were unable to comply with the king’s demand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p15" guid="ac904bd0-6354-46f4-a74f-674cb37c6ef9" pid="eQ7NGjyptkSRhh8lMXV6eg" hash="U2YHoQ">The king had told them that if they did not make these things known to him, they would be destroyed. Daniel, recognizing the predicament, inquired of the Lord and was inspired by him to make known to Nebuchadnezzar the information he requested. He recalled to the king the dream and gave him the interpretation thereof.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p16" guid="f9400595-1505-4c6f-bbe0-8b914a6596f9" pid="_hBkq8UYy0K3jaalF7DMMA" hash="jWlA1Q">In his dream Nebuchadnezzar had seen a great image like unto a man. The head of the image was of gold and represented the Babylonian kingdom of Nebuchadnezzar. The other various parts of the image represented the kingdoms that would follow. The account relates that, among other things, Daniel reminded the king: “Thou sawest till that a stone was cut out without hands, which smote the image upon his feet that were of iron and clay, and brake them to pieces.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/dan/2.34" class="scriptureRef">Dan. 2:34</a>.) He further said that “in the days of these kings shall the God of heaven set up a kingdom, which shall never be destroyed. …” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/dan/2.44" class="scriptureRef">Dan. 2:44</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p17" guid="90fbbebe-f2f6-49ec-b6cc-8bf467d1ec6f" pid="HsR_7nFOvUSQ75PD8kSfyQ" hash="g88SUw">The Lord knew in the days of Nebuchadnezzar the kingdoms that would come forth upon the earth. He knew the time when his kingdom, God’s kingdom, would be set up. He knew those choice souls, his prophets in this dispensation, Joseph Smith and those who have succeeded him. He knew and knows today the destiny of his church and kingdom, that it will roll forth and accomplish the purposes indicated in that remarkable dream.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p18" guid="5fbca18d-d196-4577-9747-5d3fbd706208" pid="Xgmn2jF25E2NppAY1BOiuw" hash="iwiyfg">How is it possible that in our day through his patriarchs and prophets the Lord can and does make known conditions pertaining to the future? How can they foretell that certain persons will be apostles and prophets in his church, even when such individuals are merely small children or young men at the time of the foretelling?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p19" guid="c1f77a58-8ddc-40f5-8015-69c53ce7da69" pid="g1QDVj0Lx0-f8ZEdN52_oQ" hash="uYrIFg">As an illustration, it was made known to Presidents Joseph F. Smith, Heber J. Grant, David O. McKay, and others that they would one day be in the leading councils of the Church, that they would be apostles of the Lord Jesus Christ, that they would become presidents of the Church in this dispensation. And to many others it has been made known that they would be appointed to positions of eminence, which predictions have been fulfilled.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p20" guid="f5c7bcc3-febb-47af-ac87-7a2fa1c97112" pid="duDKRxJBa02dfoIo8s5XIg" hash="UY46Tw">“… both Presidents Wilford Woodruff and Lorenzo Snow had prophesied that Joseph F. Smith [the father of President Joseph Fielding Smith] would sometime become president of the Church. Thirty-seven years earlier in the Hawaiian Islands when President Snow, then a member of the Council of Twelve, nearly lost his life by drowning, he declared that the Lord made known to him ‘that this young man, Joseph F. Smith … would some day be the Prophet of God on the earth.’ President Woodruff was once relating to a group of children some incidents in the life of the Prophet Joseph Smith. ‘He turned to Elder Joseph F. Smith and asked him to arise to his feet. Elder Smith complied. “Look at him, children,” Wilford Woodruff said, “… He will become the President of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. I want everyone of you to remember what I have told you this morning.”’” (Joseph Fielding Smith, Jr., and John J Stewart, <span class="emphasis">The Life of Joseph Fielding Smith </span>[Deseret Book Co., 1972], p. 124.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p21" guid="1ce84930-ee8d-460b-8c44-70e12080be0f" pid="9upkoC_JlkOWbgG_B4S79Q" hash="iJZslg">When Heber J. Grant, who became the seventh president of the Church, was a child playing on the floor in a Relief Society meeting, Eliza R. Snow, who was truly a prophetess, gave him a blessing in tongues, which was interpreted by Sister Zina Y. Card, to the effect that that little boy would someday be an apostle of the Lord Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p22" guid="93e65856-aa6a-49ee-9db6-d854cb808eef" pid="COvo8dgM7USaRt9tTDYTwg" hash="lyBgEg">On another occasion Heber C. Kimball, one of the counselors to President Brigham Young in the First Presidency of the Church, stood that same boy on a table and prophesied that someday he would be a greater man in the Church than his father, and his father, Jedediah M. Grant, was a counselor to President Brigham Young.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p23" guid="53f94ce1-d2bb-464e-9899-5f1652669bb0" pid="b-QFPGKJmEiPRW3kNvkjUA" hash="KNanHA">Again, when Brother Grant, at the age of 24 years, was president of the Tooele Stake, Patriarch John Rowberry gave him a patriarchal blessing in which he was told that he would someday be in the leading councils of the Church; and after the blessing was given, he told Brother Grant: “Heber, I dare not tell you what I saw when I had my hands upon your head.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p24" guid="44a7e263-2575-4731-a2b6-57384ae8ae48" pid="HbLhmjK8H0OPGRw97qtnUw" hash="hOtBzA">Brother Grant later, after becoming president of the Church, said that when Brother Rowberry made that statement it went through his mind just as if a voice said it, “You will someday be the president of the Church.” Brother Grant thought it was such a presumption on his part to even think such a thought that he never mentioned it to anyone until after he did become president of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p25" guid="27379560-1e86-4449-9164-6c0f89af1f78" pid="6wfp7iTWc0umTm-ZbCRqJA" hash="-PsUNA">On one occasion, when President David O. McKay was in his youth serving as a missionary in the land of Scotland, a very spiritual missionary meeting was held under the direction of Elder James McMurrin, a counselor in the mission presidency. As testimonies were borne and spiritual experiences mentioned, President McMurrin turned to President McKay and said: “Elder McKay, I’ll say to you as the Savior said to Peter, ‘Satan hath desired to have you, that he may sift you as wheat: But I have prayed for thee, that thy faith fail not: and when thou art converted, strengthen thy brethren.’” He then said, “If you are faithful you will yet stand in the leading councils of the Church.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p26" guid="d57b374a-f4c7-4ed1-a49d-7dd7a175eb52" pid="rYD1CCou60-cc_oWVQ203Q" hash="YUMiCQ">Other similar experiences could be related.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p27" guid="c6b0ee3b-bad6-4c7f-a876-0dabb973ca5b" pid="VgIbuHXGi06LeMAwoyrYoQ" hash="vQeA2A">As was the case with Abraham and Jeremiah and others of the ancient prophets, these men, leaders of God’s kingdom in this dispensation, were chosen before they were born to represent him in this last dispensation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p28" guid="4f093c13-36c2-4f3b-b24e-b5c9ebe1eec2" pid="Qr0P2vroB0OAwuqW_m1oFQ" hash="JiSfwg">It is interesting to read the history of the past wherein are related conditions leading up to the ushering in of this dispensation of the gospel: the work that was done by the reformers, Luther, Calvin, Knox, and others; the manner in which the way was opened for the printing of the Bible so that the people generally could have the privilege of reading God’s word: the miraculous development of the art of printing; how the spirit of people who wanted to worship God according to the dictates of their conscience; the coming of the Pilgrim fathers to this land in search of freedom and liberty; the war for independence; the establishment of the Constitution—all looking forward to the time and preparing the way for the restoration of the gospel, the opening of this dispensation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p29" guid="a7e7bddb-bcba-451f-9708-9c4d5dca3609" pid="NISILd0XjUmckkYQ-0TycA" hash="KcwRrQ">The dispensation of the fulness of times was introduced upon the earth by the visit to the boy Joseph Smith of the Father and the Son and other heavenly beings. Darkness was dissipated and there came an outpouring of light and intelligence. The kingdom of God, as indicated in the dream of Nebuchadnezzar, has been established upon the earth and is rolling forth as the stone cut out of the mountain without hands, and it will continue to do so, looking forward to the time of the coming of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p30" guid="0caddbd5-246f-4923-b7c3-1eb7ec63f9f3" pid="NTTq-aAkXUCyLj1UtoPEKg" hash="0dRmQA">Through his experience and his omniscience, our Heavenly Father knows the end from the beginning. Through his prophets he has revealed and does reveal the history of mankind, the timetable of life upon this planet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p31" guid="5b8fee28-d9bf-430b-8ab7-1e563c7de469" pid="zWlEXqNA1EahOymbRddkPg" hash="C9KEvQ">This is the dispensation of the fulness of times, when the keys of all former dispensations have been given to the prophets of the restoration, a time when God has spoken from the heavens and angels have appeared to man, a time when men and women have the Holy Ghost conferred upon them, and by the power of the Holy Ghost we may know the truth of all things. There is need for this great power in the earth today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation.p32" guid="ba619f4d-ac9c-43f8-b036-f77887ff00cf" pid="qvRFUsU7PUeM95btaE6XPg" hash="rPe7iA">The history of this world is in fulfillment of the plan prepared in the heavens before this earth was created. That which the world calls Mormonism is based upon the rock of revelation. It is the gospel of Jesus Christ, the eternal truth, the plan of life and salvation. I testify to these things in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1973/04/the-rock-of-revelation</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1973-general-conference/1973-04-6040-elder-joseph-anderson-64k-eng.mp3" length="6543733" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 1973 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strength of the Spirit</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As we listened to the remarks of President Kimball, there came into my mind the words of the hymn Latter-day Saints love to sing:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03044_000_004" doc-version="3" hash="zZQAtA">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.head">
		<h1 class="title" pid="jfI1fIte3Eyu0uuBtyXtjQ" hash="bhva-A">Strength of the Spirit</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="_GfMkSkJukKFW1w8TRPVQA" hash="bQfhog">Elder Joseph Anderson</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.t1">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p1" pid="Uyow1wdrI0uYQ6YyikK5AQ" hash="n1zuYg">As we listened to the remarks of President Kimball, there came into my mind the words of the hymn Latter-day Saints love to sing:</p>
			<div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.f2">
				<div class="stanza">
					<p class="line" pid="4g6ZQ4ooC02MWnMtde3Avg" hash="OUHGlA">“We thank thee, O God, for a prophet</p>
					<p class="line" pid="W_xRRPYOuEShbtowUAE2Ow" hash="7zCw1Q">To guide us in these latter days.</p>
					<p class="line" pid="GaMT24U6oE-LVPImqwymlQ" hash="ZqiOeA">We thank thee for sending the gospel</p>
					<p class="line" pid="WHedmPl4q0mepmqs2royBA" hash="2CpECA">To lighten our minds with its rays.”</p>
				</div>
			</div>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p2" pid="ROjgH1EO5UyUD_xKXLYxGw" hash="TptObg">It would seem of the utmost importance that thinking people everywhere should conscientiously reflect upon their spiritual assets. Man is a dual being, spiritual and physical. Whether it be an individual or a nation, he or it cannot achieve permanent success or happiness without spirituality. Paul said: “For to be carnally minded is death; but to be spiritually minded is life and peace.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/8.6" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 8:6</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p3" pid="sytj0CbNWkKz0H-AIj3C_w" hash="c0E-zA">There is a constant battle between the things of the flesh and the things of God—the desire for peace and the attractions of the flesh. It is also a well-known fact that in times of prosperity man is often tempted to forget God, but in days of trial and sorrow he prays unto the Lord that his countenance may smile upon him and that the Lord will remember him in the days of his affliction. This pertains to peoples as well as individuals.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p4" pid="KQ9P6em8jEKs3VLqHNYrpw" hash="19HT_w">The world needs today a return to the outmoded standards of character. We need to return to a faith in God and a determination to serve him.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p5" pid="XSZ8vMCoh0i6AS7Bd0X_DA" hash="Wc58Dw">The following excerpt from a statement in the <span class="emphasis">Evening and Morning Star</span> of July 1832 is as pertinent today as it was at the time it was first published:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p6" pid="t4tVEtkqyUmcvr9w3dlSZQ" hash="ejeQvA">“The old world was destroyed for rejecting the revelations of God given to them through Noah. The Israelites were destroyed in the wilderness for despising the revelations given to them through Moses; and Christ said that the world, in the days of the apostles, would be condemned for not receiving the word of God through them: thus we see that the judgments of God in the past ages have come upon the people, not so much for neglecting the revelations given to their forefathers, as for rejecting those given immediately to themselves.” (<span class="emphasis">Documentary History of the Church,</span> vol. 1, pp. 277–78.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p7" pid="yCaIRQK5t0mJZ3loYFYadQ" hash="2umjSA">We are living in an important time in the history of mankind and in the history of the Church. People are confused. There was a time when they were willing to accept the word of their ministers and religious advisers, but that time is changing. Regretfully, some ministers of religion are as confused as are the members of their flocks, and, among other mistaken ideas, have come out against the Ten Commandments, declaring that they are out of date and irrelevant to modern society.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p8" pid="TNyTmgfu4kaa1BNkERDIWg" hash="hYBd4Q">As recorded by Matthew, the Lord said to the people at that time:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p9" pid="0iGbn8_yAEG5WyGqXdtASw" hash="yEcN3Q">“For verily I say unto you, Till heaven and earth pass, one jot or one tittle shall in no wise pass from the law, till all be fulfilled.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p10" pid="Av3M4jNaVUeeiPOsvW9jGg" hash="rTC4IQ">“Whosoever therefore shall break one of these least commandments, and shall teach men so, he shall be called the least in the kingdom of heaven: but whosoever shall do and teach them, the same shall be called great in the kingdom of heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.18-19" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:18–19</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p11" pid="6eT8tSWyH06EiLYGkpet5A" hash="hUVoOA">In our own modern scriptures, we read:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p12" pid="8P7GJYd9XEqZg2lIPejJYA" hash="A14VWw">“And now, behold, I speak unto the church. Thou shalt not kill; and he that kills shall not have forgiveness in this world, nor in the world to come.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p13" pid="MLTbL41gAUerKBmuNZGulA" hash="kAI-pg">“Thou shalt not steal; and he that stealeth and will not repent shall be cast out.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.18,20" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:18, 20</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p14" pid="mZFMhFBnu0in3lGDRMRj2Q" hash="_1q9FQ">And again:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p15" pid="PXX1_E-IHEOEu46QJjSuTw" hash="WUHi5g">“Thou shalt love thy neighbor as thyself. Thou shalt not steal; neither commit adultery, nor kill, nor do anything like unto it.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:6</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p16" pid="MDsqnlTjJUCQJvckSWdqtA" hash="D56fRA">We are living in a time of unrest, or fear, in many respects. Men with money are in doubt as to how they should invest it so that it may be safe. Parents of children are concerned as to where their children are and what they are thinking and doing. Men and women of religious faith are seeking a church, a doctrine that will satisfy their longing and their desire to find a religion that will satisfy their yearning.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p17" pid="nYKETb0LjUOQCj84jwZYWA" hash="2Zu2sw">“But as the days of Noe were, so shall also the coming of the Son of man be.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p18" pid="gM7octbXjEqdD8tC1-NPJg" hash="4MGF-w">“For as in the days that were before the flood they were eating and drinking, marrying and giving in marriage, until the day that Noe entered into the ark,</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p19" pid="u7KwBmclskWTA86LQ4DbPg" hash="8FbwMQ">“And knew not until the flood came, and took them all away; so shall also the coming of the Son of man be …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p20" pid="ONyetkhwU0eAOcLKXV3IYA" hash="MdTj4Q">“Therefore be ye also ready: for in such an hour as ye think not the Son of man cometh.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/24.37-39,44" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 24:37–39, 44</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p21" pid="p9QlyKFcBEeT5oXnSR-zcg" hash="HYleMA">We cannot expect permanent peace, nor will it come until such time as the hearts of men are turned to peace, and men will not have peace in their hearts until they no longer permit selfishness to be their ruling power. Until men recognize God as the ruler of the universe and his Son Jesus Christ to be the Savior and Redeemer of the world, Satan will reign in the hearts of men. Man must love God and his neighbor as himself. Man the world o’er must recognize that we are all the children of God, truly brothers and sisters, before peace in the true sense will prevail upon the earth.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p22" pid="9F8_V0WtR0SafWprWXGcDQ" hash="GSV8mA">The following is an excerpt from President McKay’s remarks at the Christmas program in the Church Office Building, December 22, 1961:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p23" pid="D0_0mfqVd0u991V2OuBiUA" hash="8RDpnQ">“Jesus taught that God-like character is not a thing of favor or chance, it is a natural result of continued effort and right thinking, the effect of long cherished association with God-like thoughts. … That man is not at peace who is untrue to the whisperings of Christ and the promptings of his conscience. He cannot be at peace when he is untrue to his better self, when he transgresses the law of righteousness in any way, either in dealing with himself or indulging his passions, his appetites, yielding in any way to the temptations of the flesh, or whether he is untrue to a trust imposed upon him, transgressing the law of righteousness in dealing with his fellowmen. Peace does not come to the transgressor of law; peace comes by obedience to law, and it is that message which Jesus would have us portray among men. Peace is to the individual that he may be at peace with his God, perfect harmony existing between himself and law, the righteous laws to which he is subject and from which he can never escape. … Life is a struggle, really a struggle to gain mastery over these tendencies, the animal part of our being.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p24" pid="Njmyq-bM10mUmOPPJJ95aQ" hash="ozWCBQ">No one can have complete peace in his heart who shuts out of his heart and soul, by harboring immoral thoughts or indulging in improper conduct, those thoughts and actions that pertain to a godlike life. By neglecting to give heed to the will of God as revealed through the prophets of the Lord, by succumbing to the wiles of the adversary and indulging in unrighteous behavior, by yielding to evil passions and destructive appetites, by failure to give heed to the revealed will of the Lord, one cannot enjoy the peace of which the Lord spoke when he said: “Peace I leave with you, my peace I give unto you. …” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.27" class="scriptureRef">John 14:27</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p25" pid="Dw_aXhT28USs0r3wNce1yw" hash="HCaTow">The commandments which have been given by the Lord to his prophets in this dispensation pertain to eternal truth and set forth the mind and will of the Lord to his people in this day and age, which is the dispensation of the fulness of times, preparing a people to be worthy to meet the Lord when he shall come again in power and in glory. There are those who would desire to destroy this great nation and its liberties for which our forefathers struggled and fought and bled, and there are also those whose great ambition is to cast reflection and doubt upon the revelations and teachings of the Church. They seriously question God’s revealed word and seem to have no desire for or interest in matters pertaining to the Spirit, which are of an eternal nature.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p26" pid="PrhsFAkpzU2iT6p60PTqDQ" hash="Q50zhQ">The Lord has revealed to us in our time a life-shaping purpose in the restored gospel of Jesus Christ. It is given to us to bless mankind. It is our responsibility to carry its message, the message of salvation and exaltation, the message of freedom and happiness, to all mankind, that none may be left without excuse. He that is warned must warn his neighbor. While it is only natural and proper that we should desire and seek those things of a temporal nature that tend to make mortal life wholesome and pleasurable, it is of the utmost importance that we keep in mind the great purpose of life, which is to prepare us for eternal life—the salvation and exaltation of the souls of God’s children.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p27" pid="LU1QE7ZDIEOdF68xlAVpnQ" hash="YMxMkA">Like ancient Israel, modern Israel is a peculiar people in that we believe and know that we have constant revelation from God, revealing to us those things that are of eternal value, those things which pertain to the salvation of our own souls. There is no greater service in which we can be engaged than that of helping our fellowmen and ourselves to attain the glorious salvation which is dependent upon obedience to the principles of righteousness which he has revealed.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p28" pid="I4jJA56qtUOn5xXUFFdQ9g" hash="gkNqYw">Many years ago with President Heber J. Grant and others it was my privilege to witness work that was being carried forward in the construction of the Hoover Dam near Las Vegas, Nevada. Some of those present at that time, including President Grant, went to the top of the dam on a makeshift elevator as far as it was completed at that time, and they then climbed a ladder still higher where the concrete was being poured. This concrete, which consisted of boulders and rocks, was held together by cement. Without the cement, which held the rocks together, the dam could not have been made effective in holding back that great stream of water. There would be just a pile or mass of boulders which would have been washed away when the flood waters came against it. But with the cement, a dam curving between the deep sides of the canyon was built in accordance with mathematical principles, one that now holds back the water and brings it into control and provides water for the thirsty land and makes possible, through the great turbines that were built, the creation of electricity to bring light and blessing to peoples far and wide.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p29" pid="WG0zb1vL-U29dE5WSqVZUw" hash="r3EJeQ">Our lives consist of this act and that act, this experience and that, one accomplishment after another. But if we are to accomplish the great purpose of our earth life, we must have power to resist the forces of the evil one; we must overcome the weaknesses of the flesh; we must distinguish between the physical desires and the spiritual strength, which latter provides the cement that makes possible the accomplishment of life’s purposes and goal.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p30" pid="sYPhmOzZW0ixEvBthuVtJg" hash="LcFffg">And what is that life-giving purpose, that goal toward which we should all be striving? It is the gospel of Jesus Christ as restored to man in this great dispensation. It is, of course, necessary that we have the physical necessities of life. It is natural that we should want the things that make life, physical life, desirable and pleasurable. But if in obtaining such things we neglect those things that are of eternal worth, the spiritual part of life, then we have mistaken the chaff for the wheat of life. We have failed to recognize the eternal purpose of our existence. We have neglected the cement which is necessary if we are to build a life that will make our calling and election sure—yes, eternal life in the presence of our Heavenly Father.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit.p31" pid="UqKCOjbaok2CfuFgBFVk2Q" hash="iVh3FQ">Again may I say it is of the utmost importance that people everywhere reflect upon their spiritual assets and spiritual strength, thus preparing themselves for eternal life in the kingdom of our Heavenly Father. That we may do this I humbly pray in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/04/strength-of-the-spirit</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1974-general-conference/1974-04-1020-elder-joseph-anderson-64k-eng.mp3" length="6403281" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 1974 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Testimony of Christ</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Mankind’s greatest need today is a sincere conviction that Jesus Christ was and is in very deed the Savior and Redeemer of the world; that he is the Son of the Father, the firstborn in the spirit and the Only Begotten in the flesh; that it was necess</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03050_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="rUjfFA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="3PxcRr-VGUuFcumijJlH1g" hash="mCZ4WQ">A Testimony of Christ</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="yKGXL3HvQ0G8-Lvt97MPnA" hash="bQfhog">Elder Joseph Anderson</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2416.jpg" alt="Elder Joseph Anderson" pid="GIyFtZLtu0C_rGVPzHiVMg" hash="XyrnKQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p1" pid="F9CTsqDt0EmBI5KlQGVwjg" hash="PvZJbw">Mankind’s greatest need today is a sincere conviction that Jesus Christ was and is in very deed the Savior and Redeemer of the world; that he is the Son of the Father, the firstborn in the spirit and the Only Begotten in the flesh; that it was necessary and a part of God’s plan before the world was created, that he should come to earth and take upon himself mortality, mend the law broken by Adam and Eve, and provide for us the plan whereby we might resurrect from the grave and return into the presence of our Heavenly Father from whence we came.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p2" pid="cAE6ShB8MEW0yDuy3EkfmQ" hash="M1tfFw">We read in the first chapter of the gospel according to John: “In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God. The same was in the beginning with God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/1.1-2" class="scriptureRef">John 1:1–2</a>.) This would indicate that Christ, Jehovah, the Great I Am, was with the Father in that early state of existence; he was the firstborn of his spirit children. He was taught by the Father during that incalculable time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p3" pid="zETEOYmtUkSl1L-Gk7hB1A" hash="GNVlfw">Before we came here we lived in the heavens in the spirit state as children of our Heavenly Father. The poet Wordsworth caught a flash from the eternal semaphore when he wrote:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="fqWXxag0UUOR59bjJwHJOg" hash="0ctmcw">Our birth is but a sleep and a forgetting:</p>
          <p class="line" pid="TIKHUr8VJEicClasjVAx0g" hash="fNsoIA">The soul that rises with us, our life’s star.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="YHwQr2ugc0SfQddObgtkIg" hash="TW3NYg">Hath had elsewhere its setting,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="DkEbrRkigkyJfzt2Gxt7WA" hash="HboaxA">And cometh from afar:</p>
          <p class="line" pid="URXygghqqUq7MFpeB9krmQ" hash="Y0hQ3Q">Not in entire forgetfulness.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="CqbFfm0RfkSfE1KPq3v9CQ" hash="ZqOoew">And not in utter nakedness.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="CO04nedh20GjNMDxxqzHfw" hash="yJYRBQ">But trailing clouds of glory do we come</p>
          <p class="line" pid="Nyn6QjUQ3kyoINKh_eoi8w" hash="Du4nDg">From God, who is our home.</p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p4" pid="sN90eAJeJka8iXEi0QgPhg" hash="GxW8TA">We knew the Father of our spirits as well as we know our earthly father here. We knew our elder brother Jehovah and we also knew Lucifer, who too was a son of the morning. We lived by sight at that time. That visual knowledge, the remembrance of that estate, has been taken from our minds, and we are now required to live by faith. As stated in the hymn:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.f3">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="dYHKTGZXQEGT_5Q0cE98rg" hash="8xW0Tw">For a wise and glorious purpose</p>
          <p class="line" pid="twwD904reEWPWUHX64VP9Q" hash="JTZBTQ">Thou hast placed us here on earth</p>
          <p class="line" pid="SLO21kL_ok6xjRhAMxYg5g" hash="Mqf-bQ">And withheld the recollection</p>
          <p class="line" pid="fLWeAAUkaUGjWYlG6YjUjQ" hash="YC7x7A">Of our former friends and birth.</p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p5" pid="_sr5ZBN6UE-Lwvx1Z8_-Lw" hash="lkmJng">It is a glorious program and plan, instituted in the councils of heaven, whereby we might have the blessed privilege of taking upon us mortality, its challenges and its experiences.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p6" pid="mP-ZpaG48Ui6UoV01oN-RQ" hash="fYNkUQ">In that previous existence we had our free agency. In the councils where consideration was given to the matter of the creation and the peopling of this earth, the Father presented an unselfish plan. It had been used in other worlds. Jehovah said: “Father, thy will be done, and the glory be thine forever.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/4.2" class="scriptureRef">Moses 4:2</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p7" pid="wMbVoiiNh0GOyJW-BeevZg" hash="rJwB9Q">Lucifer, however, contended for an amendment to the plan whereby we would all be saved by compulsion. This was contrary to free agency. His was an ambitious proposal and one which involved granting to him, Lucifer, the honor that belongs to the Father. The scriptures tell us he said: “Behold, here am I, send me, I will be thy son, and I will redeem all mankind, that one soul shall not be lost, and surely I will do it; wherefore give me thine honor.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/4.1" class="scriptureRef">Moses 4:1</a>.) This would destroy the right to free agency and the opportunity for growth and development. It would be contrary to the Father’s purpose in giving his children the opportunity to become like unto him through their own faithfulness and efforts. It was a selfish and presumptive proposal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p8" pid="cZfVJWU-NkW7aosKA3K3Uw" hash="5EugiA">We are given to understand that whereas in the preexistence, in that spiritual estate, the spirits had their free agency, there were different degrees of obedience, various grades of righteousness. Lucifer exercised his free agency when he rebelled against the Father, but he had to pay the penalty for that rebellion and is still doing so, as are those spirits who followed him. They were denied the privilege of taking upon themselves mortality, and this has been a great curse and disappointment to them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p9" pid="diAziM21ZUqu8vKBp8476w" hash="04iT7w">“How art thou fallen from heaven, O Lucifer, son of the morning! …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p10" pid="gDTiZ656eUekQ813WH1O2Q" hash="Ftq-Dg">“For thou hast said in thine heart, I will ascend into heaven. I will exalt my throne above the stars of God: …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p11" pid="bSZCL-xeJkebN7iJvcY6Dg" hash="RAQAjw">“I will ascend above the heights of the clouds: I will be like the most High.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p12" pid="0blCSpTa2EOF-Cp6nlfNKQ" hash="Idt5iA">“Yet thou shalt be brought down to hell, to the sides of the pit.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/14.12-15" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 14:12–15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p13" pid="DvtbWVgOo0SODXYxvKURzQ" hash="WBOJzw">When those spirits who followed Jehovah were sent to earth to take upon themselves mortality, they were by no means of equal capacity nor similar in dispositions. There were different degrees of faithfulness among those who were given the opportunity and blessing of taking upon themselves mortal life. They were, however, considered sufficiently worthy to receive this earth-life experience in order that they might prove whether they would do all things whatsoever the Lord their God should command them. By so doing, by rendering obedience to the plan of life and salvation, they would receive life eternal, they would return into the presence of their Heavenly Father and receive his plaudit and the reward of the faithful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p14" pid="R4sHcPSrmESXrGKoDMPlEg" hash="gjV8gg">God, with his foreknowledge and his acquaintance with his children in their premortal state, knew that some would succumb to the wiles and temptations of Lucifer, that many would fall by the wayside. It was also known by the Father before they came here that of their own free will and choice Adam and Eve would partake of the forbidden fruit, which would open the way for God’s spirit children to take upon themselves mortality. Accordingly, the necessity for a Redeemer and a redemption was understood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p15" pid="FFA8t9H_Pkm1ujnFP1mkOg" hash="5s1ysw">It was necessary that an atonement be made for the transgression of Adam, that mankind might not be required to suffer for Adam’s transgression, for which they, Adam’s posterity, were in no way responsible. Adam’s disobedience was a transgression inasmuch as he had broken a law, but it became a great blessing in that it opened the way whereby man could be, could partake of earth-life privilege, and, in connection therewith, exercise his free agency and work out his salvation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p16" pid="9zWQ3pwqCkuQUMZ5Xbl0kA" hash="TxVHsQ">God was willing that his Beloved Son should take upon himself the responsibility of that mission, namely, to atone for the sin of Adam and Eve which brought about the fall, and, also, that mankind might receive forgiveness for their individual sins, provided they would keep the commandments upon which salvation and exaltation were based.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p17" pid="FEHDlfIj-0aoIStnbDHPyQ" hash="KNoLLA">When Jesus was upon the earth in the meridian of time, very few recognized him as the Creator of heaven and earth and the Savior and Redeemer of mankind. Even his disciples did not fully appreciate his mission and—though he told them that he would lay down his life for the salvation of mankind, that he was and is the author of salvation unto all them that obey him, that he would come forth unto newness of life from the tomb, a resurrected being—it was difficult for them to grasp these things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p18" pid="EgcHUGsYxEWB4vaTPe9KNA" hash="v-faQQ">We are not dependent alone upon the account given by his apostles and others in the New Testament. We have other records and testimonies. We have the Book of Mormon, which, according to the foreword in that account, was given “to show unto the remnant of the House of Israel what great things the Lord hath done for their fathers; and that they may know the covenants of the Lord, that they are not cast off forever—and also to the convincing of the Jew and Gentile that Jesus is the Christ, the Eternal God, manifesting himself unto all nations.” (Book of Mormon title page.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p19" pid="he7PvXo1E0GW1R9NQrwDYQ" hash="4T-ecw">An account is given in this record of the appearance of the Savior after his resurrection to his people upon this continent, at which time he taught them the gospel, the plan of life and salvation, similar to that which he gave to the people on the eastern continent. The Book of Mormon record also relates the conditions that existed upon this hemisphere at the time of Jesus’ birth in Bethlehem and at the time of his death.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p20" pid="i5KSeJsiHEGP7l-Rx8gWDg" hash="0rCLsQ">Upon his appearance to the Nephites, he stretched forth his hand and spoke unto the people saying:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p21" pid="ozKetEZaE0qVtnufHoe2cQ" hash="20pE4g">“Behold, I am Jesus Christ, whom the prophets testified shall come into the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p22" pid="6NXyyMJjcEKt8dcnFan9TA" hash="WaMTZw">“And behold, I am the light and the life of the world; and I have drunk out of that bitter cup which the Father hath given me, and have glorified the Father in taking upon me the sins of the world, in the which I have suffered the will of the Father in all things from the beginning.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.10-11" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:10–11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p23" pid="IkLzQZ1G5keF_hXZHZantw" hash="mHRj6w">The Church has the further scripture about the Only Begotten and his mission as contained in the Pearl of Great Price. How fortunate we are that we have the biblical account, the Book of Mormon account, and the accounts given to Abraham and Enoch and Moses as related in the Pearl of Great Price regarding the birth and death of the Savior and his great mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p24" pid="krOAepsMTU6lDrlv2NZhTA" hash="tFHhcQ">This same Jesus, the resurrected Christ, has appeared to man in this dispensation on various occasions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p25" pid="FoYu1WXiPUy1WlW7b8x2XA" hash="Sw-CmQ">We have the further testimony of the truth of these manifestations and of the restored gospel in its fullness by virtue of the whisperings and promptings of the Holy Ghost, for the gift of the Holy Ghost has been conferred upon us by authority restored from heaven by those who held that power and authority in the meridian of time—namely, Peter, James, and John—and that knowledge is certain and cannot be successfully refuted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p26" pid="iyEbz7rHXECXoAGDp5xF3g" hash="Uw6ALg">In The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints we worship the living Christ. We know that he came forth from the tomb, that he is a resurrected being, that he is our advocate with the Father, that only through him and by obedience to the gospel he has given us can we return into his presence and that of the Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p27" pid="HgSfvLfVN0ei5vePmGYx6w" hash="R1UdIA">Jesus Christ is our Redeemer and Savior. He was begotten of the Father in the spirit, the Firstborn of the Father, and is the Only Begotten of the Father in the flesh. He is our elder brother. He is the second member of the Godhead. He was the Creator of heaven and earth under the direction of the Father. He is the Jehovah of the Old Testament. He is Jesus of Nazareth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p28" pid="GbNYnIggSkOMca0-kp0WzA" hash="g2HE_A">He is the Way, the Truth, and the Life. He is the Light of the world. He is the Author of our salvation. He was chosen before the foundation of the world to be the Lamb slain as an offering for our sins. Ultimately every knee must bow and every tongue confess that he is the Christ. He died on the cross to atone for the sin of Adam, that we might receive forgiveness for our sins if we would accept him and keep the commandments that he has given us, the plan of life and salvation. He arose from the tomb, the first fruits of the resurrection, thereby making possible that all mankind may live again in a resurrected state after mortal death. Yes, “God so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son, that whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.16" class="scriptureRef">John 3:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p29" pid="n-y3_KkT8k2CcDugX3XDWw" hash="-rixiQ">It is his work and his glory to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man, which is salvation and exaltation in the presence of God the Father and his Son Jesus Christ. (See <a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p30" pid="kK10B5EeHU-K7AbCmYjhQw" hash="AYWB_A">It is our mission and our responsibility to carry this message to the world. It is our work and our glory to assist our Savior in the accomplishment of the mission that he accepted in the council of the heavens before the earth was created.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p31" pid="7k7TqyBSTUC2TDzlThhpNg" hash="tWQM8w">He will come to earth again, as foretold by the prophets, this time in power and great glory, to reign and rule a thousand years in peace and righteousness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ.p32" pid="myx5q7Yp0k6NcyiaRF7k6A" hash="G8NP-g">I testify to the truth of these things. I know that our Redeemer lives, and I bear this testimony in faith and in all sincerity, in the name of our Savior and Redeemer, Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/10/a-testimony-of-christ</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1974-general-conference/1974-10-7020-elder-joseph-anderson-64k-eng.mp3" length="6435056" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 1974 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Road to Happiness</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Everyone is striving to be happy but the number who truly achieve that goal is limited.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03057_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="KvkdUA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="6N_i5IgH00qjin_M9Z7UGQ" hash="uZF1kg">The Road to Happiness</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="CqdE7v8tBkis1LzLeuWFwA" hash="bQfhog">Elder Joseph Anderson</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2416.jpg" alt="Elder Joseph Anderson" pid="Dg6O8DqEQkupB9FyXwmfGQ" hash="XyrnKQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p1" pid="vXRQe-YqF02owED4iECoSQ" hash="jgsY2A">Everyone is striving to be happy but the number who truly achieve that goal is limited.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p2" pid="PpCZ2tpqmk-t77qjrhK37Q" hash="IoC5Tw">Lehi, a Book of Mormon prophet, has said that men are that they might have joy. There is a great difference between joy and pleasure. To a certain degree, at least, joy and happiness are synonymous.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p3" pid="Wz969QFqV02OdVBXXlneXg" hash="rWuJwg">Why aren’t people happy? Too many adopt the theory that happiness is dependent upon the obtaining of material things and the enjoyment of worldly pleasures: the accumulation of wealth, the achievement of fame, the ownership of palatial homes and earthly possessions, etc.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p4" pid="zsA5FdHa9Ey-GciFUBl8DQ" hash="RiQEaw">A wise man of old relates in Ecclesiastes his efforts to find profit from his labors. He said he gave his heart to seek out and search by wisdom concerning all things that are done under heaven. He mentioned that he had seen all the works that are done under the sun, and behold, said he, all was vanity and vexation of spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p5" pid="yXUVkjv66k6eHi0EYwEfEg" hash="CtRVZw">He sought mirth, the enjoyment of pleasure, and behold, he said, this also is vanity. He builded him houses, planted vineyards, made gardens and orchards, employed servants and handmaidens, and had great possessions of cattle. He obtained singers and instruments, musicians and music, and whatsoever his eyes desired, that he obtained. Then he looked at all the works that his hands had wrought and on the labor that he had performed, and behold, he said, all was vanity and vexation of spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p6" pid="jAwHDSwmR0ma0wZIUaqlTQ" hash="VLItgA">After all his thinking and his accomplishments and efforts, his final conclusion is set forth in the following language:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p7" pid="3jVmiIYddkecFlGOQa_G0w" hash="JZy2-g">“Let us hear the conclusion of the whole matter: Fear God, and keep his commandments: for this is the whole duty of man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p8" pid="sVbIxFr_70eiu61U396Xqg" hash="epTt3A">“For God shall bring every work into judgment, with every secret thing, whether it be good, or whether it be evil.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/eccl/12.13-14" class="scriptureRef">Eccl. 12:13–14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p9" pid="5r2k2U_raEWjIdGSXytHyQ" hash="nvFU4g">Who are the happy people today? Not those who forsake the Lord and devote themselves entirely to the pleasures of life and the physical things of the world. The truly happy people are those who have faith in the Lord and keep the laws of the gospel, those who forget self in their desire and effort to bless others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p10" pid="W1C_FUg6GE-toq7UqwRgXQ" hash="vsgNHg">Our Heavenly Father loves his children. He wants us to be happy, and he has shown us the way. I recall a lecture given in the Salt Lake Tabernacle some years ago in which the speaker said that, in reading the four Gospels, he discovered that Jesus, in referring to God, always called him Father: our Father, your Father, my Father, the Father; and that in these four Gospels Jesus used the word <span class="emphasis">Father</span> 148 times in referring to God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p11" pid="qgmpI9cx-E6ZEoFD888Cxg" hash="b-rgqQ">Many of us are fathers—fathers of the mortal bodies of our children. The greatest treasures we have are our children. When they are happy and successful, we are happy. When they depart from the straight and narrow path, the hearts of the parents are saddened.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p12" pid="scqhDu7dxkuUvGBtAVBNTg" hash="EBs9mg">Our Lord has told us by revelation through the Prophet Joseph Smith regarding the worth of souls:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p13" pid="45ezQA1NtkeZUMakxLBQrA" hash="q4aTzw">“Remember the worth of souls is great in the sight of God;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p14" pid="YefzdVQ4C0iCK4xC8gjNYg" hash="ACNDug">“For, behold, the Lord your Redeemer suffered death in the flesh; wherefore he suffered the pain of all men, that all men might repent and come unto him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p15" pid="_8xIXSx2X0WRWl3gROrpfQ" hash="YbpMog">“And he hath risen again from the dead, that he might bring all men unto him, on conditions of repentance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p16" pid="_2L5-8WlSEuw8F4tJ15wPA" hash="KkVdzQ">“And how great is his joy in the soul that repenteth.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.10-13" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:10–13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p17" pid="kl_qTD4h6kOrx8kuJ8xoDw" hash="wZrSOQ">The Lord has restored the gospel, which is the true plan of life, salvation, and exaltation. He has given us no law, advice, counsel, or commandment that is not for our blessing and happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p18" pid="msE5LVW9nU28V_1E_VBBgw" hash="5Ss1YA">As an illustration, every one of the Ten Commandments, if lived, will bring joy and satisfaction. This does not mean we will not have problems. The Lord has said that all things work together for the good of him who loves the Lord. Some people take the view that the Ten Commandments are outmoded. It is true that they are not adopted into the lives of some people, but the commandments that were given by Jehovah on Mount Sinai are light, are truth, eternal truth, and failure to observe them brings the opposite of joy and happiness. The same may be said of all truth given us by the Lord. Wickedness never was happiness and never will be. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/41.10" class="scriptureRef">Alma 41:10</a>.) It has been said: “It is a statistical fact that the wicked work harder to reach hell than the righteous do to enter heaven.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p19" pid="EMQewRJD6kOhY-d32p6YEw" hash="ov8lzA">The Psalmist has said: “Oh that men would praise the Lord for his goodness, and for his wonderful works to the children of men!” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/107.8" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 107:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p20" pid="weY3mzM-pUqBr9i_a8fTFg" hash="xUYjgg">Since the beginning of this dispensation, the Lord, through his latter-day leaders and prophets, has been warning the people of the approaching storms. He has warned of the dangers involved in the use of alcoholic beverages, tobacco, and other harmful things. He has warned against the lowering of the moral standards and against all kinds of iniquity. We have been told that we must have respect for law and order, yet the people of this nation and other nations have arrived at a condition where crime is increasing at a rapid rate. “The whole world lieth in sin, and groaneth under darkness and under the bondage of sin.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.49" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:49</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p21" pid="zY1VHCUXRkiO4D9dg5lplQ" hash="FVC5Ew">We are fast approaching the time—and perhaps have reached it when our lives are in danger from hoodlums, gangsters, and other evil-minded persons, when lawlessness is so commonplace that our properties, our holdings, our rights and privileges, are in jeopardy. When we destroy the principles of honesty, integrity, and morality, our civilization is most certainly on the verge of losing the power to preserve itself. According to the history of the past, other nations reached great eminence and power, but because of the wickedness of their people, they lost the glory that they formerly had. Such was the case with ancient Greece, Rome, and the civilizations that once flourished on this American continent.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p22" pid="y9XJnA0nMEGK0n8MA8mizQ" hash="yAP0GQ">In the Book of Mormon we read of the establishment of the Lord’s church upon the Western Hemisphere by Christ himself after his resurrection, and in speaking of the conditions that prevailed, the following is recorded:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p23" pid="x96-bARYK0GspzFO5Dl8pw" hash="McaV1Q">“And it came to pass that there was no contention in the land, because of the love of God which did dwell in the hearts of the people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p24" pid="1lkicQYduU6V2lBTRcaz1g" hash="J8cFkA">“And there were no envyings, nor strifes, nor tumults, nor whoredoms, nor lyings, nor murders, nor any manner of lasciviousness; and surely there could not be a <span class="emphasis">happier</span> people among all the people who had been created by the hand of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/4-ne/1.15-16" class="scriptureRef">4 Ne. 1:15–16</a>. Italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p25" pid="5S7EgN6RfUKjfo2I1DzKzg" hash="n7S-RA">After about 210 years had passed away following the coming of the Savior, “they [the people] did deny the more parts of his gospel, insomuch that they did receive all manner of wickedness.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/4-ne/1.27" class="scriptureRef">4 Ne. 1:27</a>.) As a result of their wickedness there were wars and contentions, and finally destruction came upon the descendants of Lehi who occupied this continent.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p26" pid="1Ph3ra7PNUuYIOI90SCGxg" hash="3gfhpg">One of the dangers facing the world is the deterioration of the home and the family. Latter-day Saints look upon the family as the greatest institution of civilization. Subversion of this great institution can do nothing less than bring destruction upon the world. The plan of life and salvation teaches that marriage is for time and eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p27" pid="P5ZyHrlVe0aET8KJH8x42A" hash="FwmVqg">The very purpose of life is that we might take upon ourselves mortality, that we might prove ourselves to see if we will do the things that the Lord has commanded us. And one of the things that the Lord has commanded us to do is to multiply and replenish the earth, that we might have joy in our posterity, not only in this life but throughout all eternity. When Eve was given to Adam as a wife and helpmate, there was no death. It was an eternal union, and it must needs be that the family relationship continue throughout eternity if we are to have eternal joy. The eternity of the marriage covenant can be made possible in the temples of the Lord by those having proper authority from the Lord to perform that holy ordinance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p28" pid="0KvzH2N5-0aaMBG4_cMIgg" hash="RwB2Nw">This is a glorious world in which we live. It was created by God through his only Begotten Son, with its heavenly bodies and their functions. The earth with its abundance of flowers, its adornment of beautiful trees and shrubs; the majestic mountains; the mighty oceans; the sun and its great functions; the stars and planets in the heavens—yes, they are all the handiwork of God. All these things bid us have joy. Man, however, is the greatest of all God’s creations. The Lord God told Moses: “This is my work and my glory—to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>.) Man is God’s son, his daughter. All these other things are just provisions for the accomplishment of his great purpose.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p29" pid="KHoJ9rgkRUq-cZgSXpB9uA" hash="D-dpgw">There is a difference between immortality and eternal life. We cannot accomplish the immortality of our souls; that has been brought to pass by the atonement of our Redeemer and Savior. Immortality is to live forever, but immortality does not necessarily include eternal life. Eternal life does include immortality. Eternal life is to live with God in his celestial kingdom, in his presence. That is a very important part of our mission, but we can have eternal life only through the exercise of our free agency and through obedience to the gospel plan. This is the principal purpose of our coming here, that we might overcome, that we might keep the commandments the Lord has given us, and that we might render service in his kingdom. Only by doing these things will it be made possible for God to accomplish his work—the purpose for which the world was created and the purpose of our existence upon this earth. We must yield obedience to the will of God, his gospel, the power of God unto salvation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p30" pid="Gz3twXlbKkyMs9Q4YvYTxQ" hash="H6eAFA">One has true joy when he knows that he pleases God, and again, when he is assured that God is pleased with him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness.p31" pid="zUSH3PTeB0mSknjG12Smmg" hash="wR64SA">The day will come when the Lord shall compensate every man according to his work. His arm shall be revealed. May we adopt and follow the true road to happiness, which is to fear God and keep his commandments and thereby attain the great goal given us by the Lord, namely, life eternal and everlasting joy in the presence of our Heavenly Father and his Beloved Son, I humbly pray in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/04/the-road-to-happiness</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1975-general-conference/1975-04-2080-elder-joseph-anderson-64k-eng.mp3" length="5892991" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Matter of Personal Testimony</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony?lang=eng</link>
      <description>One of the peculiarities of members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is the matter of personal testimony. It is quite customary for faithful members of the Church to testify to their faith and knowledge of the truth of this work whe</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03070_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="TH00Lw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Ec2mT5p0ZEKzYix_jZzm-A" hash="RBN41w">The Matter of Personal Testimony</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="r96lQGWdFE6Hyhxf4V29pA" hash="bQfhog">Elder Joseph Anderson</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2416.jpg" alt="Elder Joseph Anderson" pid="8RrqPheLkUyQu6s_lNc7cA" hash="XyrnKQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p1" pid="YOI3UbW0S0610ivUNaQS8w" hash="k2LKUg">One of the peculiarities of members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is the matter of personal testimony. It is quite customary for faithful members of the Church to testify to their faith and knowledge of the truth of this work wherever and whenever opportunity occurs. It is desirable and expected that before one joins the Church he will have an individual assurance of the truth of the doctrines we teach, that the gospel we proclaim is the restored plan of life and salvation, that it is not a new religion but the eternal gospel, the keys, principles, and doctrines of which were restored to men on earth by heavenly messengers who held these keys and this authority in previous dispensations and when the Lord and his apostles were upon the earth in the meridian of time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p2" pid="7lYeLd51n0GGBw-t_Q-36A" hash="9isb6Q">People who are inclined to rely entirely upon reason in reaching conclusions find it difficult to accept as reliable those things that cannot be proved by the five senses. Paul may have had this in mind when he said, “For what man knoweth the things of a man, save the spirit of man which is in him? even so the things of God knoweth no man, but the Spirit of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/2.11" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 2:11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p3" pid="FzM8GjZqpEmi1_ZLOjr5Mw" hash="5Eo3_w">The English poet, John Dryden, has said:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="Qgn-IOMSnUqE2tF0DLYhzw" hash="1WlmvA">
            <span class="emphasis">Dim as the borrow’d beams of moon and stars</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="lGXSYECQY0-mVsQ8ay6n1g" hash="di4mDA">
            <span class="emphasis">To lonely, weary, wand’ring travelers,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="kkTfBx6_IEaroFryJhaLcg" hash="2MbXsA">
            <span class="emphasis">Is Reason to the soul; and, as on high</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="YSoU7crdcUaOn3UO1Lab6A" hash="NNU1Gg">
            <span class="emphasis">Those rolling fires discover but the sky,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="asDCX41jgU6cHwTrkHnQIQ" hash="-LdflA">
            <span class="emphasis">Not light us here, so reason’s glimmering ray</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="S364S4sn90u5ww93ao7iKA" hash="GeHPEw">
            <span class="emphasis">Was lent, not to assure our doubtful way,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="5DPPwf7UU0SE6iWTjXEeeQ" hash="KMpOOw">
            <span class="emphasis">But guide us upward to a better day.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="SvWZoOwVMUSFnbFmEHZcAA" hash="ZI-KdA">
            <span class="emphasis">And as those nightly tapers disappear,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="M6qEugWUUkup0MNPHpaLGg" hash="cRd_UQ">
            <span class="emphasis">When day’s bright lord ascends our hemisphere;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="vyynya4UNkCQAGnarYsoIA" hash="dGzytQ">
            <span class="emphasis">So pale grows Reason at Religion’s sight;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="23Xdu5U5qE-DX-FOfyZqew" hash="mUnNag">
            <span class="emphasis">So dies, and so dissolves in supernatural light.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p4" pid="vKCFZz9RsEW_T7uynsDIIg" hash="zcVOtg">Moroni, in bidding farewell to the Lamanites, left this testimony as recorded in the Book of Mormon:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p5" pid="jJyWj2L690eMHYWyiSVa2g" hash="-00-mQ">“And when ye shall receive these things, I would exhort you that ye would ask God, the Eternal Father, in the name of Christ, if these things are not true; and if ye shall ask with a sincere heart, with real intent, having faith in Christ, he will manifest the truth of it unto you, by the power of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p6" pid="8RK9-ozSBEyYNakgtqUGhA" hash="1bO-7g">“And by the power of the Holy Ghost ye may know the truth of all things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p7" pid="m9YsiN7f50ukbIKfOueHVA" hash="ssrtzw">“And ye may know that he is, by the power of the Holy Ghost; wherefore I would exhort you that ye deny not the power of God; for he worketh by power, according to the faith of the children of men, the same today and tomorrow, and forever.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.4-5,7" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:4–5, 7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p8" pid="63GzUMEm_EemY80vyDDtgQ" hash="SfCDOA">I recall reading a few years ago that a prominent prelate of one of the Christian churches in Salt Lake City, who has since passed away, expressed a feeling of admiration and respect for members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and their standards of life, but he said he did not favor their policy of testimony bearing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p9" pid="j-6c7gIKukuTNC8OXcD79Q" hash="dMFqAg">Notwithstanding the many and great miracles the disciples of our Lord had seen Him perform, there were times when they seem to have had some doubts in their minds concerning their Lord and Master, whether he was truly and indeed the Christ of whom the prophets had spoken. On one occasion, however, the scriptures tell us that “when Jesus came into the coasts of Caesarea Philippi, he asked his disciples, saying, Whom do men say that I the Son of man am?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p10" pid="5XdWPonRj0SJypyUTrFMNA" hash="j7ecPg">“And they said, Some say that thou art John the Baptist: some, Elias: and others, Jeremias, or one of the prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p11" pid="50jbFa4bm0y8riSWgG7R8A" hash="zYTRdg">“He saith unto them, But whom say ye that I am?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p12" pid="jIX5e9PMCEOTZAqEIGyclQ" hash="q7N_Bw">This question was truly a faith-testing one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p13" pid="ceKJBvy2mEObdBILTIHecg" hash="3d-4RA">“And Simon Peter answered and said, Thou art the Christ, the Son of the living God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p14" pid="ICAz2LCWRkCasPpovvko4Q" hash="OdUurQ">“And Jesus said unto him, Blessed art thou, Simon Bar-jona: for flesh and blood hath not revealed it unto thee, but my Father which is in heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/16.13-17" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 16:13–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p15" pid="iU-OqDDZ60617vmZ2dC8Ug" hash="XVt0gg">That testimony which came as a revelation to Peter from the Father has come down to us through the years and is an indication to us as to how we may know that Jesus is the Christ. In the same way we may know and bear testimony also to the truth of the restored gospel, that that same Jesus lives today and is our Redeemer and Savior. It may be revealed to man by God through the gift and power of the Holy Ghost, for by that means can we know all things that it is expedient for us to know. The source of that testimony is the rock of revelation upon which the church of Christ is built, and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it. As indicated by the Savior, flesh and blood do not reveal these things to many but they come only by revelation from our Father in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p16" pid="6Q0mSRupt0m4UpC0ASkz4w" hash="6hm3kg">Our testimony of the truth of this work is unique, and it is perhaps our principal source of strength in proclaiming the gospel message to the world. That testimony must be firm and true. It must be built upon the rock of revelation. It must be such as to withstand the winds of criticism and the storms of persecution that may be hurled against the Church. It must be made firm by a righteous life. As we grow in understanding of the gospel of the Lord Jesus Christ, our understanding of the purpose of life increases and our faith in God’s representatives is magnified in our minds.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p17" pid="qU6IznmdjU-L7crD-cNJTw" hash="RbUKMg">Our missionaries as they go into the world with the message of the restoration bear testimony to the truth of this latter-day work. These testimonies must be more than mere words: they must be true convictions. And when they come from the heart and soul as they should do, they have an impact on the thinking of their listeners that cannot easily be cast aside, because those testimonies come with the accompaniment of the Holy Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p18" pid="PBsAzovFfE-XKY8X8Pch8Q" hash="-Ms_aQ">Emerson said: “The vice of our theology is seen in the claim that the Bible is a closed book, and that the age of inspiration is past.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p19" pid="Z1SN_NWlYkuO2IfWqak-Dg" hash="bZ98UQ">The strength of this church does not depend alone upon the prophets and apostles of earlier dispensations nor upon the testimony of the General Authorities of the present. The strength of this church is in the testimony and faith of its members, and every member may have that testimony if he will seek it through study and sincere prayer and if he will keep the commandments the Lord has given us. That testimony will become a knowledge of the truth of this work. Through righteous living and unselfish service, it will grow stronger day by day and will develop into a knowledge that nothing but carelessness or sin can weaken or destroy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p20" pid="se4vqIYFLUe0AoTQjHjazg" hash="ekbUNg">One of the former presidents of the Church, President David O. McKay, has said in regard to this subject, “A testimony of the gospel of Jesus Christ is the most sacred, the most precious gift in our lives, obtained only by adherence to the principles of the gospel, not by following the paths of the world. You may get momentary pleasures by following the enticements of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p21" pid="j95elFY4r0WBieVWESZ0Ww" hash="9wWcZQ">“You may get transitory pleasure, yes; but you cannot find joy—you cannot find happiness. Happiness is found only along that well-beaten track, narrow as it is, though strait, which leads to life eternal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p22" pid="Bq_fR_98n022vSJwYD14-g" hash="O28htA">“That is my testimony to you. Sometimes there are obstacles; there is persecution; there is self-denial; there will be tears because you are coming constantly in contact with these enticements, with these worldly ideals, and you have to overcome them; and, for the moment, there will seem to be sacrifice, but it is only temporary. The Lord never forsakes those who seek him. It may not come just the way you think, but it will come. The Lord will certainly fulfill his promise to you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p23" pid="dbZlXEKTiEK0G-DBwqEcgw" hash="y6Xazg">With further reference to testimony and his own testimony he said, “But the testimony that this work is divine had come not through manifestation, great and glorified as it was [he is speaking now of a special manifestation that had come to him], but through obedience to God’s will, in harmony with Christ’s promise: ‘If any man will do his will he shall know of the doctrine, whether it be of God, or whether I speak of myself.’” (David O. McKay, <span class="emphasis">Treasures of Life,</span> Deseret Book Co., 1962, pp. 229–31.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p24" pid="0ql3fxLjHU67M9KJLTIH0Q" hash="W2BL-g">Through the gift and power of the Holy Ghost, testimony has come into the hearts and souls of millions of Latter-day Saints since the Church was organized in 1830—that Jesus is the Christ; that he lives; that he is the Firstborn of the Father in the spirit and the Only Begotten of the Father in the flesh; that he is our Redeemer and Savior; that he is the Author of the eternal plan of life and salvation; that he is our Elder Brother; that in answer to Joseph Smith’s humble prayer (Joseph was a boy of fourteen at the time) our Heavenly Father and his son Jesus Christ, glorified heavenly beings of flesh and bones, appeared to him in the grove near Palmyra, New York, in 1820; that Joseph’s account of this experience is true. These people have testified that the Holy Ghost has made manifest unto them that Joseph Smith was a prophet of the living God, chosen before the foundation of the earth was laid to be the instrument in the hands of the Lord in preparing the way for the restoration of the gospel of Jesus Christ in this dispensation, the dispensation of the fulness of times. Further, that those who have succeeded the Prophet Joseph Smith as prophets of the Lord’s church, including Spencer W. Kimball, our present prophet and president, have held and do hold the keys to the kingdom of God upon the earth, which, among other things, give authority for and the responsibility of carrying the message of the restored gospel to all mankind that no one may be left without an excuse. The Prophet Joseph sealed his testimony with his blood, as many others have done since the gospel was restored to earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony.p25" pid="4lNzTELr7kK-vYnQqOlU3A" hash="ELlTmA">After an association of more than fifty years with the leaders of the Church here upon the earth—prophets, seers, and revelators of this dispensation—during which period of time I have witnessed the inspiration and revelation of the Lord to his servants, I add my testimony that the Spirit of the Lord has borne witness to my soul that these things are true. I testify that if we can bring our eternal spirits into attune with the promptings of God’s Holy Spirit, the hand of God may be made visible; and the listening ear so attuned may be responsive to the celestial whisperings of the voice of God, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/04/the-matter-of-personal-testimony</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1976-general-conference/1976-04-6050-elder-joseph-anderson-64k-eng.mp3" length="11927803" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1976 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Are a Covenant-making People</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Righteous Israel, ancient and modern, has always been a covenant-making people.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03076_000_037" doc-version="3" hash="GF93gw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="a8cFtPyTdUSfXaX9LWFZYA" hash="_owx4A">We Are a Covenant-making People</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="yhYogjD3REui_JtiD6N3xw" hash="bQfhog">Elder Joseph Anderson</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2416.jpg" alt="Elder Joseph Anderson" pid="Rfkz6z9BiUii5DJTSoLt5g" hash="XyrnKQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p1" pid="lgyhmG7aXkyMcKEXlAAO4g" hash="gkN77A">Righteous Israel, ancient and modern, has always been a covenant-making people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p2" pid="_ITipBCeOUaNDMjh3Sx0VQ" hash="GtXpiQ">Ancient Israel worshiped a living God, a personal God, a God in whose image they had been created. In this respect they were different from all other peoples.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p3" pid="Q-hSanw4EkiL5LBfas3Sog" hash="5Z5y0w">Another difference was the observance of the weekly Sabbath. Jehovah told Israel that other nations would recognize this as a distinguishing feature.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p4" pid="3rDgv1dCkESkpaMJBe80yw" hash="IywPbA">Jehovah commanded Israel that they should pay a tenth of their increase as tithing. This, too, was an important distinguishing feature of God’s people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p5" pid="HEixYNbrHkO9vJgvJHedmA" hash="e8a7iw">The Lord entered into covenant with Abraham, stating that He would make of him a great nation and make his name great. He said: “I will bless them that bless thee, and curse him that curseth thee: and in thee shall all families of the earth be blessed.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/12.3" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 12:3</a>.) This was an everlasting covenant, and it was confirmed upon Isaac and later upon Jacob who was called Israel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p6" pid="z0omNX3HE0WqVjKgOjykdg" hash="0_usvg">This covenant has been literally realized so far as Abraham’s posterity are concerned. It is also being fulfilled in that through him and his descendants all the nations of the earth have been blessed. The children of Israel have been scattered throughout all the nations. A further fulfillment of the blessing is that the Redeemer came through Abraham’s lineage, and through the mission and sacrifice of the Savior all the people of the earth have been or will be blessed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p7" pid="LN_3V2xyCEaJwZzbA0A-lQ" hash="b2QDpA">The Lord also made covenant with Abraham as follows: “Unto thy seed have I given this land, from the river of Egypt unto the great river, the river Euphrates.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/15.18" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 15:18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p8" pid="7ICaz2oxjkisLs8ZsHYYfQ" hash="U6j8uQ">At the present time the descendants of Abraham are contending over that land and that blessing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p9" pid="ErLimgjE_0uawVf7Wzjuhw" hash="0jGXjQ">“And Moses went up unto God, and the Lord called unto him out of the mountain, saying, Thus shalt thou say to the house of Jacob, and tell the children of Israel;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p10" pid="fPXZz7-5o028LGvnibw5tg" hash="UrMYdA">“Ye have seen what I did unto the Egyptians, and how I bare you on eagles’ wings, and brought you unto myself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p11" pid="uGqCo_JexEyGtd5cUrSLdw" hash="YUJ0Jw">“Now therefore, if ye will obey my voice indeed, and keep my covenant, then ye shall be a peculiar treasure unto me above all people: for the earth is mine:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p12" pid="EwJUJWvyx0eEDtUIWRV6kQ" hash="1gVAcw">“And ye shall be unto me a kingdom of priests, and an holy nation. These are the words which thou shalt speak unto the children of Israel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p13" pid="BTzksyTZxUGeolJXzVyFgA" hash="dkFvXQ">“And Moses came and called for the elders of the people, and laid before their faces all these words which the Lord commanded him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p14" pid="WRhQeWJ1n0eiqXppx0-f7w" hash="hlgcHw">“And all the people answered together, and said, All that the Lord hath spoken we will do. And Moses returned the words of the people unto the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/19.3-8" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 19:3–8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p15" pid="L6GTNGeqJk-A_6m8HHwzTQ" hash="IA8imQ">However, Israel of old failed to keep the covenants, and as a result the Lord was displeased with them and calamities befell them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p16" pid="CFIzxjws20Su02JGB28sHg" hash="01AGfg">The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints in this day is a covenant-making people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p17" pid="v_NNquDtAEOuYhPnh5QcGA" hash="O4yiIg">The gospel is the everlasting covenant. In the very first section of the Doctrine and Covenants, the Lord, speaking through the Prophet Joseph Smith, said: “I the Lord, knowing the calamity which should come upon the inhabitants of the earth, called upon my servant, Joseph Smith, Jun., and spake unto him from heaven, and gave him commandments; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p18" pid="eYcV7YT03Ueq_XYvr8tGcg" hash="NnJ61Q">“That mine everlasting covenant might be established;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p19" pid="DWj4Qj7Y9EWX4iUIyUox-A" hash="Efg4zQ">“That the fulness of my gospel might be proclaimed by the weak and the simple unto the ends of the world, and before kings and rulers.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.17,22-23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:17, 22–23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p20" pid="cfXE9vuNQES4otSTIjhW6g" hash="OYIGrw">And in the twenty-second section of the Doctrine and Covenants the Lord says: “This is a new and an everlasting covenant, even that which was from the beginning” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/22.1" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 22:1</a>), meaning the gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p21" pid="ao0vMuZp5UipxakQkWGIfg" hash="srZ8PQ">Again in the forty-fifth section the Lord says: “And even so I have sent mine everlasting covenant into the world, to be a light to the world, and to be a standard for my people, and for the Gentiles to seek to it, and to be a messenger before my face to prepare the way before me.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/45.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 45:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p22" pid="Ee8P3a1ln0GGl58z9YkPig" hash="uAVzuw">Baptism by water is a part of that covenant—that everlasting covenant. Before entering into the waters of baptism one must learn about the gospel. He must have faith in it, that it is what the Lord says it is, His everlasting covenant, a light to the world, a light to His people. One must prove his faith and sincerity by repentance, by laying aside his evil ways before entering into the covenant of baptism. This holy ordinance, to be valid, must be performed by one having proper authority from Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p23" pid="wbT7V_HgDUSm2RuT4FjCDQ" hash="xaRtNQ">Following baptism by immersion we must have hands laid upon our heads by authorized servants of the Lord for the reception of the Holy Ghost. We are then prepared to receive for our individual guidance such inspiration and even revelation as may be expedient.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p24" pid="EUKhk_7jPE-Ykn_0gSuZpQ" hash="dbpMNg">These covenants all pertain to keeping the commandments of the Lord, and the blessings promised are dependent thereon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p25" pid="7VMun0lAhEiAhXmqrh2CiQ" hash="JvVKhA">In that spiritual existence before we came here, as recorded in the book of Abraham, the Gods said: “And we will prove them herewith, to see if they will do all things whatsoever the Lord their God shall command them;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p26" pid="Y5k_QQhoy0GL_KkkKn2MUg" hash="JnACSg">“And they who keep their first estate shall be added upon; and they who keep not their first estate shall not have glory in the same kingdom with those who keep their first estate; and they who keep their second estate [this estate] shall have glory added upon their heads for ever and ever.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.25-26" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:25–26</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p27" pid="hAJKUDP1_kqfpverwxETwg" hash="bh8b6Q">When we enter into the waters of baptism we enter into covenant with the Lord that we will keep the commandments that He has given us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p28" pid="EyCGfcCzqUCyiusDtbyElQ" hash="25zenA">When we partake of the sacrament we renew that covenant; we partake of these emblems in remembrance of the atoning sacrifice of our Lord and Savior; we express a willingness to take upon us His name, the name of our Lord and Master, our Savior, Jesus Christ; and we covenant that we will always remember Him, that we will keep the commandments which He has given us. He, the Lord, covenants with us that if we will do these things we shall have His Spirit to be with us. He will most certainly keep His part of the covenant if we keep ours.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p29" pid="uB9YTAlsck25YML-HxCoEg" hash="j3-ifA">As was the case with ancient Israel, the payment of tithing is a distinguishing part of the everlasting covenant as revealed to modern Israel in this day and age. The Lord has declared: “Behold, now it is called today until the coming of the Son of Man, and verily it is a day of sacrifice, and a day for the tithing of my people; for he that is tithed shall not be burned at his coming.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p30" pid="lJYsZomoh0iYwf2mezxKgw" hash="nxrHlw">On August 7, 1831, the Lord gave a commandment to the Church regarding the observance of the Sabbath day:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p31" pid="bCiDleLb6kyWxKTnKZMX1Q" hash="Q3O1ag">“And that thou mayest more fully keep thyself unspotted from the world, thou shalt go to the house of prayer and offer up thy sacraments upon my holy day;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p32" pid="fPn5P6V8jUS4ND_dYF2uqA" hash="l40wEg">“For verily this is a day appointed unto you to rest from your labors, and to pay thy devotions unto the Most High;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p33" pid="tXoj5remz0SI4P5buUW1rA" hash="hOn1QA">“Nevertheless thy vows shall be offered up in righteousness on all days and at all times;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p34" pid="-vfTadk-D0qN2lKP4DlcgA" hash="uV9KJA">“But remember that on this, the Lord’s day, thou shalt offer thine oblations and thy sacraments unto the Most High, confessing thy sins unto thy brethren, and before the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p35" pid="x2JBQ9ECEUm8G63Wfv-7Fw" hash="NJsJtQ">“And on this day thou shalt do none other thing, only let thy food be prepared with singleness of heart that thy fasting may be perfect, or, in other words, that thy joy may be full.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.9-13" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:9–13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p36" pid="Ezt51rD5UUm0Hhl41FH5DA" hash="XYv9Mw">This commandment is followed by a promise that if we will do these things the fulness of the earth will be ours. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:16</a>.) The Lord outlines in detail what the fulness of the earth comprehends.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p37" pid="S8MuvG07TUy8EUWdSzDf1w" hash="bk4cXA">Are we living up to this commandment? And if not, are we entitled to the blessings that accrue to those who keep their covenants with the Lord? The Lord says: “But learn that he who doeth the works of righteousness shall receive his reward, even peace in this world, and eternal life in the world to come.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p38" pid="BVTcN3AbP0aLk8Zm6cz0pw" hash="SBs07g">When we receive the priesthood we receive it with a covenant and promise. The Lord has told us, as recorded in the Doctrine and Covenants:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p39" pid="Fx4Tp_6cbkK939YtKiHMXw" hash="dSvYag">“For whoso is faithful unto the obtaining these two priesthoods [Melchizedek and Aaronic] of which I have spoken, and the magnifying their calling, are sanctified by the Spirit unto the renewing of their bodies. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p40" pid="PNGDb7rV5UWtrUBYhEFmOQ" hash="1IrAuA">“And also all they who receive this priesthood receive me, saith the Lord;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p41" pid="YzZY2gKQoUSSpsWywqLncA" hash="jM_-CQ">“For he that receiveth my servants receiveth me;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p42" pid="UpahkuT-U06ObYdOdd4P5A" hash="SuovCg">“And he that receiveth me receiveth my Father;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p43" pid="UlSCHcc2RkutDeW91F8L3w" hash="gIjG3g">“And he that receiveth my Father receiveth my Father’s kingdom; therefore all that my Father hath shall be given unto him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p44" pid="JU3-r6auHki7uLS-qSRcvg" hash="frv9fg">“And this is according to the oath and covenant which belongeth to the priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p45" pid="UYUiHSNWCEG7RXHrKSSbyw" hash="fpOZrA">“Therefore, all those who receive the priesthood, receive this oath and covenant of my Father, which he cannot break, neither can it be moved.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.33,35-40" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:33, 35–40</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p46" pid="YxoP2zDusEeHN0eVPzDbog" hash="pql0HA">There are among us those who break this covenant after receiving it and turn therefrom. We plead with them to repent and seek forgiveness of their folly and make themselves worthy of the blessings that are promised to those who honor their priesthood covenants and keep the commandments of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p47" pid="qYlJi1dnd0O5MY0w0m5ttQ" hash="kioCkQ">The Lord has made known to us by a revelation through the Prophet Joseph Smith that in the celestial kingdom there are three heavens or degrees of glory, and that in order to attain the highest degree of glory in our Heavenly Father’s kingdom a man must enter into the new and everlasting covenant of marriage. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/132.15-21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 132:15–21</a>.) In other words, he must be married for all eternity. The Lord explains that in order to receive a blessing at His hands, we must abide the law appointed for that blessing. He has said, “There is a law, irrevocably decreed in heaven before the foundations of this world, upon which all blessings are predicated—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p48" pid="BMOMiENhH0mcxwDwZG_wLQ" hash="bhRL8g">“And when we obtain any blessing from God, it is by obedience to that law upon which it is predicated.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/130.20-21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 130:20–21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p49" pid="cTcjOFzVmEu0H1iaCel9NA" hash="EpHUzQ">It must be understood that the covenant of marriage must be made and entered into and sealed by the Holy Spirit of Promise through the medium of him whom the Lord has appointed and authorized to hold this power on the earth in these last days. The covenant pertaining to the eternity of the family unit is one of utmost importance. If we are to return into the presence of our Eternal Father and His Beloved Son and obtain eternal life, we must honor the covenant pertaining thereto. An ancient Book of Mormon prophet has said, “Adam fell that men might be; and men are, that they might have joy.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.25" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:25</a>.) In order to have true joy, the joy that our Father desires us to have, we must honor the covenants and the commandments involved in the gospel—the new and everlasting covenant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p50" pid="qWSLZKY-QUqBEKoILLcAwQ" hash="AEMvug">The Prophet Joseph Smith, the first prophet of this dispensation, said, “Happiness is the object and design of our existence; and will be the end thereof, if we pursue the path that leads to it; and this path is virtue, uprightness, faithfulness, holiness, and keeping all the commandments of God.” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith,</span> p. 255.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people.p51" pid="JyQC-Fwr7E2NQSpE9WinVQ" hash="jaXzMA">God lives, Jesus is the Christ, Spencer W. Kimball is His living prophet. The everlasting gospel of our Lord and Master, which is the new and everlasting covenant, has been restored to earth. It is the plan of life and salvation. To these things I testify in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/10/we-are-a-covenant-making-people</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1976-general-conference/1976-10-6040-elder-joseph-anderson-64k-eng.mp3" length="6402452" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 1976 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Being “Anxiously Engaged”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Lord has told us that “men should be anxiously engaged in a good cause, and do many things of their own free will, and bring to pass much righteousness;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03096_000_033" doc-version="2" hash="PhFU0g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ZlpBL8cEcUOMQaRKwjRxaA" hash="XwikQg">Being “Anxiously Engaged”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="PXG2YMe6eUS3cM9nYpR8-w" hash="bQfhog">Elder Joseph Anderson</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2416.jpg" alt="Elder Joseph Anderson" pid="1x7llcuqN0at-bhe_dT_sg" hash="XyrnKQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p1" pid="tU0qf9hPm0e6EZ32L5xHag" hash="WEReDA">The Lord has told us that “men should be anxiously engaged in a good cause, and do many things of their own free will, and bring to pass much righteousness;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p2" pid="R7QekWWZCUGIicnG0fYHXA" hash="-ipZbg">“For the power is in them, wherein they are agents unto themselves. And inasmuch as men do good they shall in nowise lose their reward.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.27-28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:27–28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p3" pid="1EcewFIFc0etJ39tRociew" hash="hPObCA">This quotation refers to nonmembers as well as Church members; all men and women have the power to do good. It is of the utmost importance that they have the desire and determination to live righteously. We should not be employed at any time in service that is not a good cause. When members of the Church are engaged in doing something that is evil or contrary to a good cause, we are not living up to the obligations we took upon ourselves in the waters of baptism. Very many people in the world, not of our church, are engaged in a good cause and are trying to bring forth much righteousness. Those who are endeavoring to improve mankind, who teach faith in God and the living of a goodly life, are engaged in a good cause and shall not lose their reward therefore.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p4" pid="Zmo_EnAqCE2eJIrnV8cLJA" hash="sye3lw">If we would have the blessings that the Lord would like to bestow upon us, we must have faith in the Lord Jesus Christ; we must have a knowledge of the true and living God; we must repent of our past sins, overcome any incorrect understanding; we must humble ourselves before God, and make covenants with him, and be obedient to those covenants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p5" pid="WrWOO99UDkOvaSE79DZo9Q" hash="Lutwqg">President George Albert Smith, one of our former presidents and a man without guile, used to say in substance: We do not ask our nonmember friends to forsake anything that is true that they have in their churches or in their lives, but we would like them to add to the good they already have the eternal truths of the gospel. If they will do so, they will have a joy and happiness beyond anything they have heretofore had. (See <span class="emphasis">Sharing the Gospel with Others,</span> comp. Preston Nibley, Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1948, pp. 12–13.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p6" pid="LhEF2wfqHE2qaj43rAWC-g" hash="2BOZWA">The gospel of Christ includes all truth, visible or invisible to the naked eye. It is possible for all men to repent of their sins unless they commit the unpardonable sin. They may receive the blessings of a righteous life if they will only determine to keep the Lord’s commandments, if they will humble themselves and seek his help and guidance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p7" pid="YLJqVtxCmESJZ19_VMnajA" hash="GnX-ag">I like to think that people generally want to do good; they feel happier when they are doing good. Sin never was happiness. It builds up an iron curtain between man and God. The Lord gave us the right pattern when he said, “Do unto others as you would that men should do unto you.” (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.12" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 7:12</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/6.31" class="scriptureRef">Luke 6:31</a>.) The Lord has given us no commandment that is not for our good and benefit and that does not bring satisfaction and happiness if we follow it. We need the help of the Lord, and he will give us that help if we seek it and follow the course that he has provided.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p8" pid="JnqLk2P8hkOIGUaA3oYqbQ" hash="wkqRHg">Our young missionaries who go into the world to preach the gospel return home happy because they have been in the service of the Lord, trying to bless mankind. The Lord has been with them. His Spirit has guided them. They are clean-lived; they are not like the carnal world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p9" pid="_EfVgzIaN0K68JPOasmnog" hash="9Ntz7g">We take the sacrament in remembrance of the suffering of our Lord and covenant to keep his commandments that we may always have his Spirit to be with us. His Spirit will not lead us to do anything that is evil but will encourage us to do good, and by following that persuasion and by maintaining that guidance, we will grow in nearness to the Lord; we will grow in good deeds; and we will overcome the flesh. A man who has the companionship of the Spirit of the Lord is a happy man. He can be a thoughtful and faithful patriarch and leader in his home and family; he is a good neighbor; he can be an influence for good among his neighbors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p10" pid="ZF1KsYzX6kybvqbtg-vA-g" hash="ykm_Zw">The hymns that we sing have an influence for good upon our lives. The music of the Tabernacle Choir has a faith-promoting and cultural influence upon the listeners. The spirit with which the Choir sings the words and melodies of our own hymns and of compositions by other inspired people creates a desire upon those who listen or participate to serve the Lord. The inspired hymns that we sing in our congregations are prayers and songs of rejoicing unto our Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p11" pid="myKraU7NokunG8N9P4LMaQ" hash="VXIhPw">Men are crying, “peace, peace,” but there is no peace. We are living in times that are trying the hearts of men. We need not be afraid if we are on the Lord’s side. It is not wise for us to put off the day of preparation and to think the Lord will delay his coming. It is true we do not know the day nor the hour, the month nor the year, but we do recognize the signs that he has given us as an indication of the nearness of that great event.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p12" pid="sVUv_w3JZkKeiMTp-wzx8A" hash="ufGOAg">How can we be prepared for that day? We must keep the commandments of the Lord; we must be engaged in a good cause, endeavoring to bring forth much righteousness. We must warn our fellowmen. We must teach our children true doctrines and lead them in the paths of rectitude.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p13" pid="vqXFSOtzf02xAj1uyceIaQ" hash="YX36Jw">The Lord has said to this people: “After your testimony cometh wrath and indignation upon the people.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.88" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:88</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p14" pid="uwyec43cnUSSSSOsL3VT0g" hash="UmXTLA">It is innate in human nature that when we have something interesting in life, something precious, something vital, we desire to share it with those whom we love. We have the gospel of the Lord Jesus Christ, which is the most precious thing, the most important thing in all the world. We love the gospel of our Lord, we love our Father’s children, and we want to share the gospel with them because it will bring joy and happiness to their souls. If accepted and lived, it will bring salvation and exaltation in his kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p15" pid="Os0nwCnEMESLU1IDMT8FSQ" hash="UiqPPQ">Our church, Christ’s church, is a sharing church. We have the responsibility of doing all in our power to save the souls of men, to bring them to a knowledge of God, and to assist the Lord in accomplishing his great purpose. The application of the teachings of the Master, as set forth in his gospel, is the only thing in the world that can save the world. Man needs the spiritual phases of life more than he does the material or physical if he is to be happy. The principles of the gospel are given for the definite purpose of bringing happiness and joy to man in this life and an eternity of joy in the hereafter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p16" pid="LlDNbm8DJEewxLXijrKeyw" hash="5F67ig">Why are we so greatly interested in influencing our fellowmen to serve God and keep his commandments? They are God’s children; they are our brothers and sisters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p17" pid="XRPOvwilhkeCm-Zx774xMQ" hash="FNSJ6g">The late Dr. James E. Talmage, a member of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles, has given us this inspirational thought:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p18" pid="QWr1zvrqLEmaGuSgG3lFSw" hash="6hmdVA">“What is man in this boundless setting of sublime splendor? I answer you: Potentially now, actually to be, he is greater and grander, more precious according to the arithmetic of God, than all the planets and suns of space. For him were they created; they are the handiwork of God; man is His son! In this world man is given dominion over a few things; it is his privilege to achieve supremacy over many things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p19" pid="2l3xeln6D0WZejgMk-rJSg" hash="pJKDng">“… Incomprehensibly grand as are the physical creations of the earth and space, they have been brought into existence as means to an end, necessary to the realization of the supreme purpose, which in the words of the Creator is thus declared:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p20" pid="RTQ0TxyPLkqE7QM0kGqprw" hash="dLB4Rw">“‘For behold, this is my work and my glory—to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.’ (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>.)” (“The Earth to Be Redeemed,” <span class="emphasis">Sunday Night Talks by Radio,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret News Press, 1931, pp. 357–58.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p21" pid="oMGWza4M2UKukch6xwf_GA" hash="9PKZ1A">Think of the great tragedy, the terrible responsibility, that men take upon themselves when they treat so lightly, as is sometimes the case, the destruction of human life. The penalty is an eternal one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p22" pid="pRhpy5SMqEqAiN2QY-6sKQ" hash="m7UJcg">Charles Kingsley has said: “Nothing that man ever invents will absolve him from the universal necessity of being good as God is good; righteous as God is righteous; and holy as God is holy.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p23" pid="2Vq1vJJsW0e-_vikbgJFJQ" hash="owmgKA">Our Savior, without any effort on our part, through his great atoning sacrifice and in his great love and compassion for us, made it possible for all mankind to come forth from the grave, thus opening the door to immortality for all mankind. Had he not given his life for our salvation, death would most certainly have a terrible sting, and the grave would win an awful victory. Man would be robbed of the blessing and attainment of immortality and eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p24" pid="Lgny38ktTkGWFEbIKEjCdw" hash="ykQfug">But what about eternal life? One might take the view that immortality and eternal life are synonymous. It is true that immortality is part of eternal life, but if we are to have eternal life in the true sense, we must render obedience to the gospel of Jesus Christ, the plan of life and salvation which he has revealed. Only thereby can we obtain the reward of exaltation and eternal life in the presence of our Heavenly Father in his celestial kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p25" pid="PJLEHEQqgE2oTlptJRf8CQ" hash="NINqmw">The reward for doing good is joy and happiness in this life and eternal life in the great hereafter. To do good is to keep the commandments the Lord has given us. The gospel is the true way of life, the teachings of our Lord and Savior, the light of the world. That which is contrary thereto is darkness and regret.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged.p26" pid="X0Q3llaN5kCZjD-7LnWQ5w" hash="fEozUQ">I bear testimony that this is the Lord’s work, that the gospel of Jesus Christ has been restored to earth with its keys, powers, and authorities, that it is the Lord’s work and glory to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1978/04/being-anxiously-engaged</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1978-general-conference/1978-04-5040-elder-joseph-anderson-64k-eng.mp3" length="11107989" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 1978 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidents of the Church</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I feel greatly honored in being invited to bear testimony regarding my acquaintance and relationship with the leadership of the Church during the past nearly sixty-five years.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03206_000_017" doc-version="2" hash="0eTaYw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="sEbud2t5s0elBbzc5blZXg" hash="CEJYww">Presidents of the Church</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="BtMQpRU2H0mx_WzA8briwQ" hash="bQfhog">Elder Joseph Anderson</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2416.jpg" alt="Elder Joseph Anderson" pid="Fol8AGxCEEKT39DEunPFnQ" hash="XyrnKQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.p1" pid="heJMJG6fK06rqo4Wm_y9Bg" hash="_4D8ng">I feel greatly honored in being invited to bear testimony regarding my acquaintance and relationship with the leadership of the Church during the past nearly sixty-five years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.p2" pid="-feYj7kTx0iJcOoUuC2N8Q" hash="DTd2_w">The major part of my life has been devoted to association with prophets of the living God. It was in February 1922 that I became the secretary to the President of the Church, President Heber J. Grant, and I continued in that position until he passed away in 1945.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.p3" pid="B8KtFF-IBkuG1o67-6tN9A" hash="rTCudQ">During the administrations of his successors, George Albert Smith, David O. McKay, Joseph Fielding Smith, and Harold B. Lee, I was secretary to the First Presidency; and I have served as a General Authority since 1970 with Presidents Joseph Fielding Smith, Harold B. Lee, Spencer W. Kimball, and Ezra Taft Benson. Over the years, these men have been sustained by the Church as prophets, seers, and revelators. Whenever the gospel has been on earth, there have been prophets of God, men holding the priesthood of God, through whom the Lord has made known His will.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.p4" pid="hnEstztE9UuFbafVWVSQcg" hash="VZpmIg">What a glorious blessing it has been to serve with prophets and their associates! I think of the General Authorities today. I can testify to you that they are truly men of God. When we meet in the quorum and other meetings with these Brethren, the Spirit of the Lord is there in rich measure; particularly is this the case when we meet in the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.p5" pid="uMpnBYX8akS2Is1xK46YLw" hash="TLyYlQ">What about the Prophet Joseph Smith? Do you believe that he was a prophet? I want to testify that he was perhaps the greatest prophet who ever lived, except, of course, the Savior of the world. He gave the world a knowledge of the true and living God. Through Joseph, the Lord introduced this, the greatest of all dispensations, the dispensation of the fulness of times. John the Baptist restored the keys of the Aaronic Priesthood, and Peter, James, and John restored the keys of the Melchizedek Priesthood. Joseph saw the Father and the Son, and at the dedication of the Kirtland Temple, Moses, Elias, and Elijah appeared to him and restored to him the keys of former dispensations. This is the last dispensation, a time of preparation for the coming of the Lord Jesus Christ in glory—His second coming. There were given to Joseph Smith the keys for carrying the message of life and salvation to the living and the dead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.p6" pid="lCIVt6hfaU2gcMS7bJLCaA" hash="OtEPpQ">The following is an excerpt from Joseph Smith’s letter written in 1842 to Mr. John Wentworth of Chicago:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.p7" pid="VGxnN5wc4Uyra5fYZnLpFQ" hash="I_uK4Q">“No unhallowed hand can stop the work from progressing; persecutions may rage, mobs may combine, armies may assemble, calumny may defame, but the truth of God will go forth boldly, nobly, and independent, till it has penetrated every continent, visited every clime, swept every country, and sounded in every ear, till the purposes of God shall be accomplished, and the Great Jehovah shall say the work is done” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 4:540).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.p8" pid="pDSc7uBj70eyorxXlmVOKw" hash="EUaaHw">Those who have succeeded the Prophet Joseph Smith have been given these same keys that I have mentioned. Each of these Brethren of the General Authorities has been called of God, by prophecy and by the laying on of hands by those who are in authority to preach the gospel and administer in the ordinances thereof. They are set apart from all other men upon this earth. They are authorized by ordination to do things that no other men upon this earth can do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.p9" pid="AWswcVcfT0CZqucP1u6uig" hash="YHFI6w">President Lee said upon one occasion that just as the waters are purest at the mountain source, the purest word of God, and the least apt to be polluted, is that which comes from the lips of the living prophets who are set up to guide Israel in our own day and time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.p10" pid="CmWRzQU08EyA6h3ejwFTSQ" hash="1gjnIA">What a great prophet is our present President, Ezra Taft Benson, who, with his counselors, the Council of the Twelve, other General Authorities, and other inspired leadership, is directing the work of God under inspiration and revelation from the Lord Jesus Christ, who is our Savior and Redeemer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.p11" pid="zoPfSKprDUys5lvBYBaO4Q" hash="fLRpAA">It has been my good fortune and blessing to have become somewhat acquainted with all the Presidents of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.p12" pid="nrN6JLjHGkGMUejcNc79eA" hash="-CfqmA">During my association with President Grant, we did much traveling together—on occasion going by train to New York and other places which required our being together in a drawing room on the train, normally for several days at a time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.p13" pid="8RwdpuQ510W0oS6SgJQeDw" hash="W1CDPQ">President Grant became an Apostle in the days of John Taylor, who was with the Prophet Joseph in Carthage Jail at the time of the Prophet Joseph’s martyrdom. President Grant knew Brigham Young, Orson Pratt, Wilford Woodruff, Lorenzo Snow, and others who served as Apostles during the leadership of the Prophet Joseph. President Grant retold to me on various occasions the testimonies and experiences of those great men regarding the Prophet Joseph and the manifestations they personally enjoyed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.p14" pid="E_s5kuGwmkCEq_kRQbo4-g" hash="N9I8Vg">It was also my privilege to have in my custody the records of the General Authority council meetings held in the temple, which later council meetings I recorded during my many years as secretary. Yes, I have known all these Brethren in a very real sense.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.p15" pid="OOsbMhsiR0uYKlfwvBwB2Q" hash="-mZumQ">The Savior, in praying to our Heavenly Father just before his crucifixion, said, “This is life eternal, that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17:3</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.p16" pid="-FzlWad_BEWOQD_3Oz57lw" hash="sfmQyA">These Brethren to whom I have referred know God and Jesus Christ, whom He has sent.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church.p17" pid="jvF3yzTXwE6swzA6NOElmQ" hash="6rttKg">I know that God lives, that Jesus is the Christ, that these Brethren whom I have mentioned were and are true prophets of the living God and have served and do serve under the direction of the Lord, who is the true head of the Church. I say this in the name of our Lord, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1986/10/presidents-of-the-church</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1986-general-conference/1986-10-3020-elder-joseph-anderson-64k-eng.mp3" length="3890967" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1986 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
