<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Joy D. Jones</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Joy D. Jones.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Joy%20D.%20Jones.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Joy D. Jones.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>A Sin-Resistant Generation</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sister Jones teaches that we can help children be valiant and sin resistant.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60003501_000_52jones" doc-version="1" hash="sTN7-Q">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="EX9ESkDh4E2SUKey1YR0ew" hash="Y_uW_A">A Sin-Resistant Generation</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p2" pid="UaghXImZkUCiGMBonOX_cA" hash="NAAz5g1">By Joy D. Jones</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p3" pid="V44l4guzzkexQWNq8dwpLA" hash="amFNAg">Primary General President</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="q5iEgGsJvEyBSXR2a-NMDQ" hash="NaTkJA">As you teach, lead, and love children, you can receive personal revelation that will aid you in creating and arming valiant, sin-resistant children.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="NHx9S6QdYESLNpQ8J-yW2w" hash="NAAz5g">By Joy D. Jones</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p5" pid="kdoYoU3Bv0WOqemEZYsZCQ" hash="dP72uw">A year and a half ago, President Russell M. Nelson spoke of the need “to teach and help raise a sin-resistant generation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> That phrase—“a sin-resistant generation”—struck a deep spiritual chord within me.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p6" pid="4LupW0k_NEqCnpptShPwVQ" hash="E-3qpg">We honor children who strive to live pure and obedient lives. I have witnessed the strength of many children throughout the world. They stand resilient, “steadfast and immovable”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> in a variety of challenging circumstances and environments. These children understand their divine identity, feel Heavenly Father’s love for them, and seek to obey His will.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p7" pid="qipDaBzca0mSfGruU5_xRQ" hash="6xZHQQ">However, there are children who struggle to stand “steadfast and immovable” and whose delicate minds are being wounded.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> They are being attacked on every side by “the fiery darts of the adversary”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> and are in need of reinforcement and support. They are an overwhelming motivation for us to step up and wage a war against sin in our effort to bring our children unto Christ.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p8" pid="nQPTDzeiokyGPkpe_JFD6A" hash="qyh5RQ">Listen to the words of Elder Bruce R. McConkie nearly 43 years ago:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p9" pid="TwF8O4VFnE2IGxL47Csivw" hash="MBB_gQ">“As members of the Church, we are engaged in a mighty conflict. We are at war. We have enlisted in the cause of Christ to fight against Lucifer. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p10" pid="X8QBCvS0XE-9luoW4iH4lw" hash="ESpj2g">“The great war that rages on every side and which unfortunately is resulting in many casualties, some fatal, is no new thing. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p11" pid="x4UIIYSxRkavbklR3GCN5g" hash="29L9cQ">“Now there neither are nor can be any neutrals in this war.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p12" pid="JQeEPooH0UelqpRllBTsFg" hash="AY5n2g">Today the war continues with increased intensity. The battle touches us all, and our children are on the front lines facing the opposing forces. Thus, the need intensifies for us to strengthen our spiritual strategies.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p13" pid="gxmfgDzui0Kg80P2nNy0Gg" hash="Pec0rg">Fortifying children to become sin-resistant is a task and a blessing for parents, grandparents, family members, teachers, and leaders. We each bear responsibility to help. However, the Lord has specifically instructed <span class="emphasis">parents</span> to teach their children “to understand the doctrine of repentance, faith in Christ the Son of the living God, and of baptism and the gift of the Holy Ghost” and “to pray, and to walk uprightly before the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p14" pid="2y93dZ6o2EewuQJIZDS2zg" hash="lzraTQ">How to “bring up [our] children in light and truth”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> may be a challenging question since it is individualized for each family and each child, but Heavenly Father has given universal guidelines that will help us. The Spirit will inspire us in the most effective ways we can spiritually inoculate our children.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p15" pid="H_M947Ja6EOvBpVg3m-0lw" hash="zGhs0Q">To begin, having a vision of the importance of this responsibility is essential. We must understand our—and their—divine identity and purpose before we can help our children see <span class="emphasis">who</span> they are and <span class="emphasis">why </span>they are here. We must help them know without question that they are sons and daughters of a loving Heavenly Father and that He has divine expectations of them.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p16" pid="l6jMUSbDFEyg9DAyE7Lx5A" hash="uw0B6A">Second, understanding the doctrine of repentance is essential for becoming resistant to sin. Being sin-resistant doesn’t mean being sinless, but it does imply being continually repentant, vigilant, and valiant. Perhaps being sin-resistant comes as a blessing from repeatedly resisting sin. As James said, “Resist the devil, and he will flee from you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p17" pid="KPw0FPCdiE6Dv0FY2wZIGA" hash="bQvXTQ">The stripling warriors “were exceedingly valiant for courage … ; but behold, this was not all—they were … true at all times in whatsoever thing they were entrusted. Yea, … they had been taught to keep the commandments of God and to walk uprightly before him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> These young men went to war carrying Christlike virtues as weapons against their adversaries. President Thomas S. Monson reminded us that “the call for courage comes constantly to each of us. Every day of our lives courage is needed—not just for the momentous events but more often as we make decisions or respond to circumstances around us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p18" pid="DpfgtqV8GkCiSNVx5vrnyw" hash="mu5QYQ">Our children don spiritual armor as they establish patterns of personal daily discipleship. Perhaps we underestimate the abilities of children to grasp the concept of daily discipleship. President Henry B. Eyring counseled us to “start early and be steady.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> So a third key to helping children become sin-resistant is to begin at very early ages to lovingly infuse them with basic gospel doctrines and principles—from the scriptures, the Articles of Faith, the <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth </span>booklet, Primary songs, hymns, and our own personal testimonies—that will lead children to the Savior.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p19" pid="7bXYrEftaky_bhiMVwYWTQ" hash="p8F-ZQ">Creating consistent habits of prayer, scripture study, family home evening, and Sabbath worship leads to wholeness, internal consistency, and strong moral values—in other words, spiritual integrity. In today’s world where integrity has all but disappeared, our children deserve to understand what true integrity is and why it is so important—especially as we prepare them to make and keep sacred covenants at baptism and in the temple. As <span class="emphasis">Preach My Gospel</span> teaches, “Keeping commitments prepares people [including very young people] to make and keep sacred covenants.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p20" pid="id8dYX-lFEuoCjnvm46VFg" hash="EhjdPg">Elder Jeffrey R. Holland has taught, “When we talk about covenant keeping, we are talking about the heart and soul of our purpose in mortality.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> There is unusual power in making and keeping covenants with our Heavenly Father. The adversary knows this, so he has obscured the concept of covenant making.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> Helping children understand, make, and keep sacred covenants is another key in creating a sin-resistant generation.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p21" pid="Fb7KH2_wN0mAj--lBXxqmg" hash="Vv1jrA">How do we prepare our children to make and keep sacred covenants as they enter and progress along the covenant path? Teaching children to keep simple promises when they are young will empower them to keep holy covenants later in life.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p22" pid="W5uQK1JRD02ElLGePY8KzQ" hash="C7zSSw">Let me share a simple example: In family home evening, a father asked, “How are we getting along as a family?” Five-year-old Lizzie complained that her big brother, Kevin, was teasing her too much and hurting her feelings. Kevin reluctantly admitted that Lizzie was right. Kevin’s mother asked him what he could do to get along better with his sister. Kevin thought and decided he would promise Lizzie that he would go one whole day without teasing her.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p23" pid="NHzv_ZDH4k6yvsq_Fu-e6w" hash="du7h4g">At the end of the next day as everyone gathered for family prayer, Kevin’s dad asked Kevin how he had done. Kevin’s response was “Dad, I kept my promise!” Lizzie happily agreed, and the family congratulated Kevin.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p24" pid="LoGozI6pUkq8IibR1JEewA" hash="tgv0Dw">Kevin’s mother then suggested that if he could keep his promise for one day, why couldn’t he do it for two days? Kevin agreed to try it again. Two days passed, Kevin was successful in keeping his promise, and Lizzie was even more thankful! When his father asked why he was keeping his promises so well, Kevin said, “I kept my promise because I said I would.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p25" pid="ooUFMcQIaUCqBEdazVyGwQ" hash="xwNtwQ">A succession of small, successfully kept promises leads to integrity. The consistent practice of promise keeping is spiritual preparation for children to receive their first covenant of baptism and the gift of the Holy Ghost, wherein they covenant to serve God and keep His commandments.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> Promises and covenants are inseparable.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p26" pid="71wfidJfckidAtO0RoP9NA" hash="rV_uoQ">In the book of Daniel, we learn of Shadrach, Meshach, and Abed-nego refusing to worship King Nebuchadnezzar’s idol.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> The king warned them that they would be cast into a burning fiery furnace if they didn’t comply. They refused and said:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p27" pid="ku87F09yekCl-bhN-_5CaQ" hash="ckg1RQ">“If it be so, our God whom we serve is able to deliver us from the burning fiery furnace. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p28" pid="z787iGo7EUqrh0lRrVh_5Q" hash="KJML8w">“But if not, be it known unto thee, O king, that we will not serve thy gods.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p29" pid="C75PHLDgRkCp5O3bKxbNjw" hash="HrrolQ">“But if not.” Consider the meaning of these three words and how they relate to keeping covenants. These three young men were not basing their obedience upon being delivered. Even if they were not delivered, they would keep their promise to the Lord because they said they would. Keeping our covenants is always independent of our situation. These three young men, just as the stripling warriors, are wonderful examples of sin-resistance for our children.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p30" pid="akSgPtziWU-TUtsS_xewGw" hash="z5rdUg">How do these examples apply in our homes and to our families? “Line upon line, precept upon precept,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> we help children taste success in small bites. As they keep their promises, they feel the Spirit in their lives. Elder Joseph B. Wirthlin taught that “the consummate reward of integrity is the constant companionship of the Holy Ghost.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> Then shall our children’s “confidence wax strong in the presence of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> Out of the well of integrity springs an empowered, sin-resistant generation.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p31" pid="fgX467SYvEqpyz5IdFCGDA" hash="_nFj4A">Brothers and sisters, hold your little ones close—so close that they see your daily religious behavior and watch you keeping your promises and covenants. “Children are great imitators, so give them something great to imitate.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> We are indeed helping to teach and raise a sin-resistant generation unto the Lord promise by promise and covenant by covenant.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation.p32" pid="spDAvjpo_kKy0dRSkWaNVw" hash="wIYwBg">I testify that Jesus Christ leads this Church. As you teach, lead, and love children in the Savior’s way, you can receive personal revelation that will aid you in creating and arming valiant, sin-resistant children. My prayer is that our children will echo the words of Nephi: “Wilt thou make me that I may shake at the appearance of sin?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> I testify that our Savior atoned for the sins of the world<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span>—because He said He would—and that He loves us more than we mere mortals can even comprehend<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span>—because He said He would. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2017/04/a-sin-resistant-generation</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2017-general-conference/2017-04-4020-joy-d-jones-64k-eng.mp3" length="5495261" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Value beyond Measure</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sister Jones teaches that the Spirit can confirm to us the truth of our divine worth. Our love for the Savior can help us overcome weaknesses and self-doubts.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60003502_000_13jones" doc-version="1" hash="iAtInw">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="Su8BPsJCuk6XCzL8FlpStw" hash="exevxg">Value beyond Measure</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p2" pid="lusg6ARxLEGiqv8xIbcYKQ" hash="NAAz5g1">By Joy D. Jones</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p3" pid="bcF7eDy3PE-a8FZR6z4bkg" hash="amFNAg">Primary General President</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="X6YWOTqTGkmzYEfmTRFQlQ" hash="V2kN2w">We can frequently savor the sweet whisperings of the Holy Ghost verifying the truth of our spiritual worth.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="3lygAEi6kE65H61tAM6ZIA" hash="NAAz5g">By Joy D. Jones</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p5" pid="gBc-yXKc_ky1zYtcHrhptw" hash="-aA_KA">While visiting the country of Sierra Leone in West Africa, I participated in a meeting conducted by a stake Primary leader. Mariama led with such love, grace, and confidence that it was easy to assume she had long been a member of the Church. Mariama, however, was a fairly recent convert.</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=bCy9kTeniU2wjm35nYilIQ"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972176/9b77515f5d154b68b314afe8b24b2d32/100x112.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x56="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972176/9b77515f5d154b68b314afe8b24b2d32/50x56.jpg" data-src-100x112="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972176/9b77515f5d154b68b314afe8b24b2d32/100x112.jpg" data-src-200x225="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972176/9b77515f5d154b68b314afe8b24b2d32/200x225.jpg" data-src-320x360="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972176/9b77515f5d154b68b314afe8b24b2d32/320x360.jpg" data-src-460x517="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972176/9b77515f5d154b68b314afe8b24b2d32/460x517.jpg" data-src-640x720="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972176/9b77515f5d154b68b314afe8b24b2d32/640x720.jpg" data-src-1024x1152="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972176/9b77515f5d154b68b314afe8b24b2d32/1024x1152.jpg" data-src-1600x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972176/9b77515f5d154b68b314afe8b24b2d32/1600x1800.jpg" altText="Mariama and her daughter" pid="bCy9kTeniU2wjm35nYilIQ" hash="AAAAAA2"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p6" pid="IYwMD90NH0uYMshD-UE4Mw" hash="j0jrzQ">Her younger sister joined the Church and invited Mariama to attend a Church class with her. Mariama was deeply impressed by the message. The lesson was on the law of chastity. She asked to have the missionaries teach her more and soon received a testimony of the Prophet Joseph Smith. She was baptized in 2014, and her daughter was baptized last month. Imagine, the two fundamental teachings that led to Mariama’s conversion were the law of chastity and the Prophet Joseph Smith, two points the world often sees as irrelevant, outdated, or inconvenient. But Mariama testified that she was like a moth attracted to the light. She said, “When I found the gospel, I found myself.” She discovered her worth through divine principles. Her value as a daughter of God was revealed to her through the Holy Ghost.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p7" pid="ucR0Cl5kdku5MCwwCKDz7Q" hash="blmfcA">Now let’s meet the Singh sisters from India. Renu, on the far right, the first of five sisters to join the Church, shared these thoughts:</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=aVYRUjs2ckmSAuKwHgu50g"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972178/a0f448ae03334ead80f6b014d0835d04/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972178/a0f448ae03334ead80f6b014d0835d04/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972178/a0f448ae03334ead80f6b014d0835d04/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972178/a0f448ae03334ead80f6b014d0835d04/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972178/a0f448ae03334ead80f6b014d0835d04/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972178/a0f448ae03334ead80f6b014d0835d04/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972178/a0f448ae03334ead80f6b014d0835d04/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972178/a0f448ae03334ead80f6b014d0835d04/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972178/a0f448ae03334ead80f6b014d0835d04/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972178/a0f448ae03334ead80f6b014d0835d04/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Singh sisters" pid="aVYRUjs2ckmSAuKwHgu50g" hash="AAAAAA1"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p8" pid="n_1r3j4kpUqa_4wV616M7Q" hash="U-O1SA">“Before I started investigating the Church, I didn’t really feel that I was very special. I was just one of many people, and my society and culture didn’t really teach me that I had any value as an individual. When I learned the gospel and learned that I was a daughter of our Heavenly Father, it changed me. Suddenly I felt so special—God had actually created me and had created my soul and my life with value and purpose.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p9" pid="fQjUT0Tln0qtqdzOxidEdA" hash="eXZWdA">“Before I had the gospel in my life, I was always trying to prove to others that I was someone special. But when I learned the truth, that I am a daughter of God, I didn’t have to prove anything to anyone. I knew that I was special. … Don’t ever think that you are nothing.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p10" pid="6Nt56Glwf0yh_v_tYXboiQ" hash="Tx7yTQ">President Thomas S. Monson said it perfectly when he quoted these words: “The worth of a soul is its capacity to become as God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=6hCuE4HHtk2e1eJGR3PI-w"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972180/a5983896ecb54f21a508429f80cb1693/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972180/a5983896ecb54f21a508429f80cb1693/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972180/a5983896ecb54f21a508429f80cb1693/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972180/a5983896ecb54f21a508429f80cb1693/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972180/a5983896ecb54f21a508429f80cb1693/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972180/a5983896ecb54f21a508429f80cb1693/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972180/a5983896ecb54f21a508429f80cb1693/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972180/a5983896ecb54f21a508429f80cb1693/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972180/a5983896ecb54f21a508429f80cb1693/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1972180/a5983896ecb54f21a508429f80cb1693/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Taiana" pid="6hCuE4HHtk2e1eJGR3PI-w" hash="AAAAAA"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p11" pid="CWIxE5jbPEyHHnq3iWtt_A" hash="_VNY2g">I was recently blessed to meet another young woman who understands this same truth. Her name is Taiana. I met her at Primary Children’s Hospital in Salt Lake City. Taiana was a junior in high school when she was diagnosed with cancer. She fought a brave battle for 18 months before passing away a few short weeks ago. Taiana was full of light and love. She was known for her contagious smile and her trademark “double thumbs-up.” When others asked, “Why you, Taiana?” her response was, “Why not me?” Taiana sought to become like her Savior, whom she so dearly loved. During our visits, I learned that Taiana understood her divine worth. Knowing she was a daughter of God gave her peace and courage to face her overwhelming trial in the positive way she did.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p12" pid="Ojj6r0yO6kuM2tG__CaMhA" hash="J58rYA">Mariama, Renu, and Taiana teach us that the Spirit will confirm to each of us individually our divine worth. Truly knowing that you are a daughter of God will affect every aspect of your life and guide you in the service you render each day. President Spencer W. Kimball explained in these glorious words:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p13" pid="2Mh6SBubOk2fZjKR2S4cww" hash="8px4Ew">“God is your Father. He loves you. He and your mother in heaven value you beyond any measure. … You are unique. One of a kind, made of the eternal intelligence which gives you claim upon eternal life.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p14" pid="eDaPRo-9wU2KU6LKX4n9Jg" hash="D_aXUQ">“Let there be no question in your mind about your value as an individual. The whole intent of the gospel plan is to provide an opportunity for each of you to reach your fullest potential, which is eternal progression and the possibility of godhood.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p15" pid="IKk8pql2_E6A1evs_Z2_aA" hash="kCYERg">Let me point out the need to differentiate between two critical words: <span class="emphasis">worth</span> and <span class="emphasis">worthiness.</span> They are not the same. Spiritual <span class="emphasis">worth</span> means to value ourselves the way Heavenly Father values us, not as the world values us. Our worth was determined before we ever came to this earth. “God’s love is infinite and it will endure forever.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p16" pid="69JlQTvp-EmjfwXgha0T-w" hash="uMXdoQ">On the other hand, <span class="emphasis">worthiness</span> is achieved through obedience. If we sin, we are less worthy, but we are never worth less! We continue to repent and strive to be like Jesus with our worth intact. As President Brigham Young taught: “The least, the most inferior spirit now upon the earth … is worth worlds.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> No matter what, we always have worth in the eyes of our Heavenly Father.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p17" pid="l8wUpxw7ikCwmCYCavR1gg" hash="OMYa1Q">Despite this marvelous truth, how many of us struggle, from time to time, with negative thoughts or feelings about ourselves? I do. It’s an easy trap. Satan is the father of all lies, especially when it comes to misrepresentations about our own divine nature and purpose. Thinking small about ourselves does not serve us well. Instead it holds us back. As we’ve often been taught, “No one can make you feel inferior without your consent.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> We can stop comparing our worst to someone else’s best. “Comparison is the thief of joy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p18" pid="1Qt_Gvc710SDUuUwqJgZNA" hash="qX3tGA">In contrast, the Lord assures us that when we have virtuous thoughts, He will bless us with confidence, even the confidence to know who we really are. There’s never been a more crucial time to heed His words. “Let virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly,” He said. “Then shall thy confidence wax strong in the presence of God; and … the Holy Ghost shall be thy constant companion.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p19" pid="EUguk_ur6kCMZ9TP-IDyzA" hash="EhmMdQ">The Lord revealed this additional truth to the Prophet Joseph Smith: “He that receiveth of God, let him account it of God; and let him rejoice that he is accounted of God worthy to receive.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> When we feel the Spirit, as this verse explains, we recognize that what we feel comes from our Heavenly Father. We acknowledge Him and praise Him for blessing us. We then rejoice that we are counted worthy to receive.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p20" pid="5Etb7ZRgUECFmco5DOjE6A" hash="RQLN7g">Imagine that you are reading the scriptures one morning and the Spirit softly whispers to you that what you are reading is true. Can you recognize the Spirit and be happy that you felt His love and were worthy to receive?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p21" pid="UDcEphQ3bkmdBbXu0Uo4JQ" hash="KQRH_A">Mothers, you might be kneeling next to your four-year-old as he says his bedtime prayer. A feeling flows over you as you listen. You feel warmth and peace. The feeling is brief, but you recognize that you, at that moment, are counted worthy to receive. We may seldom, if ever, receive huge spiritual manifestations in our lives; but we can frequently savor the sweet whisperings of the Holy Ghost verifying the truth of our spiritual worth.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p22" pid="Izz3IlH8REywtmn07N_lZA" hash="TcSWLQ">The Lord explained the relationship between our worth and His great atoning sacrifice when He said:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p23" pid="cGJplppLkUC5AMLrDdRP0w" hash="q4aTzw">“Remember the worth of souls is great in the sight of God;</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p24" pid="0vnOgMyQvEO0mYq01z0Eww" hash="7eYhGw">“For, behold, the Lord your Redeemer suffered death in the flesh; wherefore he suffered the pain of all men, that all men might repent and come unto him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p25" pid="MH6zSJXzPEWjRCMNBQXZGw" hash="cfzSpA">Sisters, because of what He did for us, “we are bound to him by loving ties.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> He said, “My Father sent me that I might be lifted up upon the cross; and after that I had been lifted up upon the cross, that I might draw all men unto me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p26" pid="XQ6MdemUjk-4p1cDflexYw" hash="sgcszg">King Benjamin also explained this binding connection with our Savior: “And lo, he shall suffer temptations, and pain of body, hunger, thirst, and fatigue, even more than man can suffer, except it be unto death; for behold, blood cometh from every pore, so great shall be his anguish for the wickedness and the abominations of his people.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> That suffering and the results of that suffering fill our hearts with love and gratitude. Elder Paul E. Koelliker taught, “As we remove the distractions that pull us toward the world and exercise our agency to seek Him, we open our hearts to a celestial force which draws us toward Him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> If the love we feel for the Savior and what He did for us is greater than the energy we give to weaknesses, self-doubts, or bad habits, then He will help us overcome the things which cause suffering in our lives. He saves us from ourselves.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p27" pid="PKt4BKrui0OhOhYw3MVOMg" hash="YEjEKg">Let me reemphasize: if the pull of the world is stronger than the faith and trust we have in the Savior, then the pull of the world will prevail every time. If we choose to focus on our negative thoughts and doubt our worth instead of clinging to the Savior, it becomes more difficult to feel the impressions of the Holy Ghost.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure.p28" pid="dfDHKHF4wEOXDoZf832row" hash="2RaNXg">Sisters, let’s not be confused about who we are! While it is often easier to be spiritually passive than it is to put forth the spiritual effort to remember and embrace our divine identity, we cannot afford that indulgence in these latter days. May we, as sisters, “be faithful in Christ; … may Christ lift [us] up, and may his sufferings and death, … and his mercy and long-suffering, and the hope of his glory and of eternal life, rest in [our minds] forever.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> As the Savior lifts us to higher ground, we can see more clearly not only who we are but also that we are closer to Him than we ever imagined. In the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2017/10/value-beyond-measure</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2017-general-conference/2017-09-0030-joy-d-jones-64k-eng.mp3" length="5784883" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
