<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Julie B. Beck</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Julie B. Beck.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Julie%20B.%20Beck.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Julie B. Beck.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2003 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>There Is Hope Smiling Brightly before Us</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us?lang=eng</link>
      <description>You can wake up every day … with hope smiling brightly before you because you have a Savior.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030371_000_038" doc-version="2" hash="1Qnwxg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="3ebi15ADM0CQ3cZxXWV20g" hash="JQxGiA">There Is Hope Smiling Brightly before Us</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="07hlx5To7Eu8hc-lHps5HA" hash="6A7qTw">Julie B. Beck</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="F6BXzGR05UuopHtMvgrmHg" hash="7UKZDw">You can wake up every day … with hope smiling brightly before you because you have a Savior.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-aa3.jpg" alt="Julie B. Beck" pid="ItL05Do34Uq6x7bXM1HtpQ" hash="HbaGuw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.p1" pid="Bw49NxrxWkW6s2a4wWTA3g" hash="sW0EyQ">A few days before our oldest granddaughter was born, her parents were wondering if the baby would be a boy or girl. At church the following Sunday, they sang these words: “There is hope smiling brightly before us” (“We Thank Thee, O God, for a Prophet,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 19). With sudden knowledge they turned to each other and said, “It’s a girl!” When the baby was born, they named her Hope.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.p2" pid="Nu48fMl1_kK9psx1yjZEmw" hash="JGjEcg">Hope, who is so appropriately named, is now five years old. She wakes up every day looking forward to new adventures. She is in her first year of school, and she has so much she wants to learn. The “brightness of hope” shines from her eyes (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.20" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:20</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.p3" pid="_h4SGt5BiEaCcULoFmhjAQ" hash="8vRL8w">In the past few weeks I have met with many of you young women. I have visited with you about your talents, your struggles, and your dreams for the future. In my mind I still see your faces. I see the happy face of the young woman who has been a member of the Church for only six months. I see the lonely face of a girl who is the only member of the Church in her family, waiting by herself at the bus stop. I see the worried face of a girl who asked, “Can I ever be worthy to go to the temple?” And I see the tired faces of young women who got out of bed very early for seminary. Some of you are excited about life, and some of you are troubled about your challenges and your future. As I talked with you, I was looking to see if the brightness of hope was shining in your eyes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.p4" pid="KZTJ9NKyikG-ykkRA0gPBA" hash="TKlmcQ">I wonder sometimes if you remember that you are daughters of a Heavenly Father who loves you. When you were baptized, you followed the example of your Savior, and you entered the way back to your heavenly home. Nephi says that you are now “in this strait and narrow path which leads to eternal life; yea, ye have entered in by the gate” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.18" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:18</a>). Since you are already in that path, you just need to stay in it, and in order to stay in, you must have hope, a bright hope smiling before you and lighting your way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.p5" pid="O8oIu4DnfkqQXF9ydKt-oA" hash="q6s53A">Mormon asks, “What is it … ye shall hope for?” His answer tells us of the three great hopes: “Ye shall have hope through the atonement of Christ and the power of his resurrection, to be raised unto life eternal” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.41" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:41</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.p6" pid="O3gJ3YyeHEC4jMRsXKXnSQ" hash="TZ6_WQ">When you were baptized, you became participants in the first great hope, the Atonement of Christ. Every time you worthily partake of the sacrament, you have the opportunity to begin again and do a little better. It is like burying the old, unworthy part of yourself and starting over with a new life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.p7" pid="C8PHSfhN7Uay5OM4kLa1Ww" hash="peeIBg">I talked to two young women who literally did bury their old ways. They owned some clothing that was not up to the standard of covenant daughters of God, so they dug a deep hole in the ground, placed all of their immodest clothing in the hole, and buried it!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.p8" pid="AJLOjyLXgECU0onSZZPqSg" hash="B1UgtQ">Your hope and faith in the Savior will increase as you repent and make personal changes that are the equivalent of burying your own sins. You may also want to enlist the help of your parents and your bishop as you work to become better. When you repent and worthily partake of the sacrament, you can then “walk in newness of life” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/6.4" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 6:4</a>). There is hope smiling brightly before you because of the Atonement of Christ. Because you have been baptized, you are already in the way to eternal life. Just stay in!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.p9" pid="4WfgzNyQA0u1-tbO7FbF9Q" hash="CUXQaw">The second great hope is the Resurrection. You are all promised that through our Savior Jesus Christ you will be resurrected, and you know that when this life is over, there is still much more life to be lived.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.p10" pid="Ba0hFbiyrkqfWFfHGqE4_g" hash="IOLRqA">My niece Katie was a hopeful 20-year-old university student with many talents and plans for the future. Four years ago Katie died in an auto accident. Though our family still feels much homesickness for her, we know that we will be with her again, and we are not worried about her. In Katie’s wallet was her temple recommend, given to her by her bishop so she could be baptized for her ancestors. Katie was worthy. Not long before Katie died she wrote these words: “If this were my last day on earth, this is the record I would leave. Make each day meaningful. … Stay close to the Lord. Gain all the knowledge you can about the scriptures, the gospel, the creations of the Lord. … Give of yourself … and <span class="emphasis">always</span> remember Christ for His example and His Atonement and strive each day to be like Him.” Katie had entered in the way that leads to eternal life, and she had stayed in.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.p11" pid="ilb7XQz0XEik5xSL9BbPIg" hash="nNNGCQ">Because of Christ there is hope smiling brightly before you, and you need not worry too much about sickness, death, poverty, or other afflictions. The Lord will take care of you. Your responsibility is to keep the commandments, feast upon the words of Christ, and stay in the path to your heavenly home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.p12" pid="aonhbkqUp0OFGzSWbSiS_g" hash="MCvoOA">With the hope of the Atonement and the Resurrection, you have a third great hope, the hope of eternal life. Because you have a Savior, you can plan for a future that extends beyond this life. If you keep the commandments, you are promised eternal life. You can also prepare yourself by studying and learning and by becoming “acquainted with all good books, and … languages, … and people” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/90.15" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 90:15</a>). You understand that “whatever principle of intelligence we attain unto in this life, it will rise with us in the resurrection” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/130.18" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 130:18</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.p13" pid="mfgF8GPR_E2lH1P5NzencA" hash="F5DqRg">I have been blessed to have a mother who has spent her life preparing to meet God. She understands the principles of creating, learning, and serving in this life. Her motto has been “Welcome the task that makes you go beyond yourself, and you will grow.” Let me tell you a few highlights from her adventure-filled life. In her youth she lived in the wild Uinta Mountains, where her father worked. She learned to cut tall trees, fish, and camp in the outdoors. During the winter she attended school in the city, played on a basketball team, and learned to play the trumpet. She went to the university and became a nurse. After she was married, she went on a mission with her husband to Brazil, where she learned to speak Portuguese. She has traveled to many countries and has taught the gospel to thousands. She studies the scriptures daily, has written several family history books, works in the temple, keeps track of 62 grandchildren, and can cook 600 doughnuts in one morning!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.p14" pid="x8oNsjyyaUSnvIEQ9TEdZA" hash="dDc2BQ">My mother has stayed in the Savior’s path with unshaken faith in Him (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.19" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:19</a>) all the days of her life. She wakes up every day looking forward to new adventures. For her, life is so interesting, and she still has so much to learn.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.p15" pid="Tp6ITJNS2kuGrQMaGEVwJA" hash="41x2pA">Because you have a Savior, you also believe in a happy, eternal life of creating, serving, and learning. You are already in the strait and narrow path, and there is hope smiling brightly before you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.p16" pid="ewzyMOML90etbAOSY0Aq0g" hash="E2AT0w">A few years ago, I was with my noble 97-year-old grandmother. As she sat curled in her wheelchair, weak and nearly blind, she talked quietly of her life. I said: “This is a wicked world. There are so many temptations and challenges. Is it possible to stay worthy and return to our Heavenly Father?” She slowly raised herself tall and erect and said in a commanding voice: “Yes! You must! That’s why you’re here!” Thank you, Grandma, for teaching me about hope.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us.p17" pid="YWJg853U-kSHMV2JlEzGQg" hash="S0hNhQ">Like Katie, my mother, and five-year-old Hope, you can wake up every day looking forward to new adventures with hope smiling brightly before you because you have a Savior. You are baptized in His Church, The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. You just need to stay in, pressing forward with a brightness of hope to your heavenly home. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2003/04/there-is-hope-smiling-brightly-before-us</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2003-general-young-women-meeting/2003-03-0020-julie-b-beck-64k-eng.mp3" length="4862104" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2003 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Soul Delighteth in the Scriptures</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2004/04/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures?lang=eng</link>
      <description>If you have not already developed the habit of daily scripture study, start now and keep studying.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10031248_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="oMhtfw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="I7ao--MvV0OV7XCnYZ90-A" hash="Duyxyg">My Soul Delighteth in the Scriptures</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="UWDVp0MedkK93wLyxdMgKQ" hash="6A7qTw">Julie B. Beck</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="Ntao921CwUe7D0LXyUB-Xw" hash="bBh6pA">If you have not already developed the habit of daily scripture study, start now and keep studying.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-f1.jpg" alt="Julie B. Beck" pid="qsq5ZwJOh0uZ6gHy0uqxWg" hash="X4wZRA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p1" pid="WY1hVXtNL0iJfupLFjWf1A" hash="8EGLHg">When I was a new bride, I asked my mother-in-law, who is a very good cook, if she would teach me how to make her delicious dinner rolls. With a sparkle in her eye, she replied that it took 25 years to learn to make a good roll! Then she added, “You had better start making some.” I followed her advice, and we have enjoyed many good dinner rolls at our house.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p2" pid="1KsNICSrDUaM1qUgjUfgcg" hash="QmOfxg">At about that same time, I was invited to a lunch for all of the Relief Society sisters in my ward who had read either the Book of Mormon or a short Church history book. I had become casual in my scripture reading, so I qualified to attend the luncheon by reading the short book because it was easier and took less time. As I was eating my lunch, I had a powerful feeling that though the history book was a good one, I should have read the Book of Mormon. The Holy Ghost was prompting me to change my scripture reading habits. That very day I began to read the Book of Mormon, and I have never stopped reading it. Though I do not consider myself to be an expert, I truly love reading all the scriptures, and I am grateful I started the lifetime habit of reading them. It would be impossible to learn the lessons the scriptures contain by reading them only one time through or studying selected verses in a class.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p3" pid="rESYbCIeJkWgmvMu48_KZg" hash="IRxH-g">Roll making is a great homemaking skill. As I bake them, a sweet aroma fills the house. I am able to show my love for my family by sharing something I created. When I study the scriptures, the Spirit of the Lord fills my home. I gain important understanding, which I then share with my family, and my love for them increases. The Lord has told us that our time should “be devoted to the studying of the scriptures” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/26.1" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 26:1</a>) and that “the Book of Mormon and the holy scriptures are given … for [our] instruction” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/33.16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 33:16</a>). Every woman can be a gospel doctrine instructor in her home, and every sister in the Church needs gospel knowledge as a leader and teacher. If you have not already developed the habit of daily scripture study, start now and keep studying in order to be prepared for your responsibilities in this life and in the eternities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p4" pid="R2PxsgO5wkqWdTOZ9Tx0Kg" hash="Fu8Xpw">My early attempts at making rolls and scripture reading were not always successful, but over time it got easier. For both pursuits I needed to learn proper techniques and gain an understanding of the ingredients. The key was starting and doing it again and again. One good way to start studying the scriptures is to “liken” them to ourselves (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/19.23" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 19:23</a>). Some people start by choosing a subject in the Topical Guide that they need to know more about. Or they start at the beginning of a book of scripture and look for specific teachings as they read through.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p5" pid="P-vLJFds00etqp7H9kTQEA" hash="gcilxg">For instance, when I was called to serve as a Young Women leader, I bought a new set of scriptures, and as I read and marked those scriptures, I looked for things that would help me in my calling. Sometimes I put colored pieces of paper in my scriptures so I have quick access to topics or themes I am studying. I have paper tabs in my scriptures for many of my favorite verses about repentance and the Atonement so I can find them easily as I ponder during the sacrament each week. I usually make notes about what I am learning. Sometimes I keep those notes in my scriptures, and sometimes I write what I am learning in a separate notebook.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p6" pid="lMpThxpX3UO0S6myDuFcKA" hash="glXKAw">Once in a while I invest in a new copy of the Book of Mormon. When I start reading that new book, I make notes in the margins so I have a record of what I am learning as I study. To help me remember what I am learning, I draw lines to connect ideas. I shade verses and underline key words. When I find ideas that relate to each other, I make a scripture chain to link those ideas (see “Scripture Linking,” <span class="emphasis">Teaching, No Greater Call</span> [1999], 58). I like to think of my scriptures as a workbook, so sometimes I record where I was when I gained an insight or the name of the person who taught me. That way the experience is refreshed in my memory when I read that passage again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p7" pid="9K7oxcV5bUmNj3z-TD-AdQ" hash="Xn31mQ">Many of you study foreign languages. You might like to start reading the Book of Mormon in another language. When you read the scriptures in another language, you learn what the words mean in a new way. Some people start by finding answers to their questions. They want to know who they are and what they should be doing with their lives. A friend of mine suggested that I start looking for questions that the Lord asks <span class="emphasis">us</span> in the scriptures and ponder them (see John S. Tanner, “Responding to the Lord’s Questions,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Apr. 2002, 26). Since then I have discovered many important questions such as “What desirest thou?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/11.2" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 11:2</a>) and “What think ye of Christ?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.42" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:42</a>). I keep a list of those questions in the back of my scriptures. I often choose one to think about in quiet moments because pondering enlightens my mind that I “might understand the scriptures” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/24.45" class="scriptureRef">Luke 24:45</a>). When I do not have my scriptures nearby, then I start my study by reviewing teachings I have memorized. By reciting the Articles of Faith or other verses to myself, I am able to keep them in my memory bank.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p8" pid="18KTxgNeBkmR-7h6N5kOpw" hash="SDuS4w">Whichever way a person starts studying the scriptures, the key to unlocking important knowledge is to keep studying. I never tire of discovering the rich treasures of truth in the scriptures because they teach with “plainness, even as plain as word can be” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/32.7" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 32:7</a>). The scriptures testify of Christ (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.39" class="scriptureRef">John 5:39</a>). They tell us all things we should do (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/32.3" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 32:3</a>). They “make [us] wise unto salvation” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/3.15" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 3:15</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p9" pid="2--wDjpMskS6I4uxIjFmuQ" hash="bCXd2w">Through my scripture reading and the prayers that accompany my study, I have gained knowledge which brings me peace and helps me keep my energies focused on eternal priorities. Because I started reading the scriptures daily, I have learned about my Heavenly Father, His Son Jesus Christ, and what I need to do to be like Them. I have learned about the Holy Ghost and how to qualify for His companionship. I have learned about my identity as a daughter of God. Essentially, I have learned who I am, why I am here on earth, and what I should be doing with my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p10" pid="CJsS_FLirEeuj3FEt4DaFA" hash="wGYjOw">As a youth, the Prophet Joseph Smith had a great question weighing on his mind. He started reading the scriptures and found a solution in the Bible (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.5" class="scriptureRef">James 1:5</a>). He said, “Never did any passage of scripture come with more power to the heart of man than this did at this time to mine.” He reflected on it “again and again” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.12" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:12</a>). Because Joseph acted upon what he read in the scriptures, he learned about Heavenly Father, His Son Jesus Christ, the Holy Ghost, and his identity as a son of God. Joseph learned who he was, why he was here on earth, and what he needed to do in this life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p11" pid="dYMvi4h4ZUiXhMF3aVmMGw" hash="x_qboQ">The scriptures are so important that Nephi risked his life to obtain a copy of them. He wanted to “see, and hear, and know” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/10.17" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 10:17</a>). He “searched [the scriptures] and found that they were desirable [and] of great worth” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/5.21" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 5:21</a>). In the scriptures he learned about “the doings of the Lord in other lands, among people of old” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/19.22" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 19:22</a>). He started a study of the scriptures and learned about Heavenly Father, His Son Jesus Christ, the Holy Ghost, and his identity as a son of God. He learned who he was and what to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p12" pid="dQYDTxvYFEyCF_Joz4YlBg" hash="ZPnFcg">I have great confidence in the young women of the Church. Through your habit of daily scripture study, you will be “led to believe the holy scriptures, yea, the prophecies of the holy prophets, which are written” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/15.7" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 15:7</a>). You will be the mothers and leaders who will help prepare the next generation with gospel understanding and testimony. Your children will be men and women of faith who will continue to build the kingdom of God on the earth because of what you teach them from the scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures.p13" pid="x4QHlA-6WEaZ-2bc7A2hzQ" hash="sNXDhA">If reading the scriptures is not already a habit with you, today is a great day to start. It did not really take 25 years to learn to make good dinner rolls. I just needed the encouragement to get started. Homemade rolls have brought much enjoyment to my family. But the greater joy has come from the habit of daily scripture reading which I started so many years ago. Some days I have a lot of time to contemplate the scriptures. Other days I reflect on a few verses. Just as eating and breathing sustain my physical body, the scriptures feed and give life to my spirit. I can now echo Nephi and say: “My soul delighteth in the scriptures, and my heart pondereth them. … Behold, my soul delighteth in the things of the Lord; and my heart pondereth continually upon the things which I have seen and heard” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/4.15-16" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 4:15–16</a>). In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2004/04/my-soul-delighteth-in-the-scriptures</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2004-general-young-women-meeting/2004-03-0020-julie-b-beck-64k-eng.mp3" length="9260242" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2004 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A “Mother Heart”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2004/04/a-mother-heart?lang=eng</link>
      <description>By developing a mother heart, each girl and woman prepares for her divine, eternal mission of motherhood.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/a-mother-heart" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10031248_000_028" doc-version="2" hash="3dgkMQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/a-mother-heart.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ye-8Yzb5SESbb7cmXlljcQ" hash="fhHL7g">A “Mother Heart”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="7V_EAFA5S0eNLRCwYfRTxQ" hash="6A7qTw">Julie B. Beck</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="fUdIFfTlSEWctk2O4bGlUg" hash="GQ44ew">By developing a mother heart, each girl and woman prepares for her divine, eternal mission of motherhood.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/a-mother-heart.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-f1.jpg" alt="Julie B. Beck" pid="9JOEHxg3PkKwltGTrGCfCg" hash="X4wZRA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/a-mother-heart.p1" pid="AHiuCvh68kK4cTbdAS2DUQ" hash="JE-5OA">I have often heard my father describe my mother as a woman with a “mother heart,” and that is true. Her mothering influence has been felt by many hundreds, perhaps thousands of people, and she has refined the role of nurturer to an art form. Her testimony of the restored gospel of Jesus Christ and strong sense of identity and purpose have guided her life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/a-mother-heart.p2" pid="5KRTwS17gEu_cEm3-Ejwog" hash="tDYJ2g">She took longer than most women to find her husband, but during her single years she had devoted her life to progress. Though it was uncommon at the time, she was university educated and advancing in a career. Following her marriage, children arrived in quick succession; and in a short span of years, she was the mother of a large family. All the knowledge she had acquired, all her natural abilities and gifts, all her skills were channeled into an organization that had no earthly bounds. As a covenant-keeping daughter of God, she had prepared all her life for motherhood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/a-mother-heart.p3" pid="crZJ4eQ8zUOTEPOWLQoang" hash="PsW0Og">What is a mother heart and how is one acquired? We learn about some of those qualities in the scriptures. To paraphrase Proverbs: “Who can find a … woman [with a mother heart]? for her price is far above rubies. … She … worketh willingly with her hands. … With the fruit of her hands she planteth a vineyard. … She stretcheth out her hand to the poor. … Strength and honour are her clothing. … She openeth her mouth with wisdom; and in her tongue is the law of kindness. She looketh well to the ways of her household, and eateth not the bread of idleness” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/31.10,13,16,20,25-27" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 31:10, 13, 16, 20, 25–27</a>). A woman with a mother heart has a testimony of the restored gospel, and she teaches the principles of the gospel without equivocation. She is keeping sacred covenants made in holy temples. Her talents and skills are shared unselfishly. She gains as much education as her circumstances will allow, improving her mind and spirit with the desire to teach what she learns to the generations who follow her.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/a-mother-heart.p4" pid="ULccObhiBEq71D41iR3O4g" hash="zftr_w">If she has children, she is a “goodly parent” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/1.1" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 1:1</a>) who lives and teaches standards of behavior exactly in line with the teachings of living prophets. She teaches her “children to pray, and to walk uprightly before the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:28</a>). Rather than listening to the voices and partial truths of the world, she knows that gospel standards are based on eternal, unchangeable truths. She believes that to be “primarily responsible for the nurture of [her] children” is a vital, dignified, and “sacred responsibilit[y]” (“The Family: A Proclamation to the World,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> Oct. 1998, 24; <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1995, 102). To nurture and feed them physically is as much an honor as to nurture and feed them spiritually. She is “not weary in well-doing” and delights to serve her family, because she knows that “out of small things proceedeth that which is great” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.33" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:33</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/a-mother-heart.p5" pid="RKdNJ1NvAEmqMuyFc08AxQ" hash="ZX-Hkw">Oh, that every girl and woman would have a testimony of her potential for eternal motherhood as she keeps her earthly covenants. “Each is a beloved … daughter of heavenly parents, and, as such, each has a divine … destiny” (“The Family: A Proclamation to the World”). As spirit daughters of God, women “received their first lessons in the world of spirits and were prepared to come forth” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/138.56" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 138:56</a>) on the earth. They were among the “noble and great ones” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/138.55" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 138:55</a>) who “shouted for joy” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/job/38.7" class="scriptureRef">Job 38:7</a>) at the creation of the earth because they would be given a physical body with the opportunity to be proven in a mortal sphere (see <a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.25" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:25</a>). They wished to work side by side with righteous men to accomplish eternal goals that neither can attain independently.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/a-mother-heart.p6" pid="0y6ds4EnKESsLO8YWRkAhw" hash="DUI4hg">Female roles did not begin on earth, and they do not end here. A woman who treasures motherhood on earth will treasure motherhood in the world to come, and “where [her] treasure is, there will [her] heart be also” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.21" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 6:21</a>). By developing a mother heart, each girl and woman prepares for her divine, eternal mission of motherhood. “Whatever principle of intelligence [she] attain[s] unto in this life, it will rise with [her] in the resurrection. And if a person gains more knowledge and intelligence in this life through [her] diligence and obedience than another, [she] will have so much the advantage in the world to come” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/130.18-19" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 130:18–19</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/a-mother-heart.p7" pid="brLTdnOek0y21vYdiiMeNA" hash="EJ-qeA">In my experience I have seen that some of the truest mother hearts beat in the breasts of women who will not rear their own children in this life, but they know that “all things must come to pass in their time” and that they “are laying the foundation of a great work” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.32-33" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:32–33</a>). As they keep their covenants, they are investing in a grand, prestigious future because they know that “they who keep their second estate shall have glory added upon their heads for ever and ever” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.26" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:26</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/a-mother-heart.p8" pid="TQ4WiKeooUa_kwD6FviSZA" hash="AmKWJw">I was recently at a park where I met a group of women with mother hearts. They were young, covenant-keeping women. They were bright and had obtained advanced degrees from respected universities. Now they were devoting their considerable gifts to planning dinner that evening and sharing housekeeping ideas. They were teaching two-year-olds to be kind to one another. They were soothing babies, kissing bruised knees, and wiping tears. I asked one of those mothers how it came about that she could transfer her talents so cheerfully into the role of motherhood. She replied, “I know who I am, and I know what I am supposed to do. The rest just follows.” That young mother will build faith and character in the next generation one family prayer at a time, one scripture study session, one book read aloud, one song, one family meal after another. She is involved in a great work. She knows that “children are an heritage of the Lord” and “happy is the [woman] that hath [a] quiver full of them” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/127.3,5" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 127:3, 5</a>). She knows that the influence of righteous, conscientious, persistent, daily mothering is far more lasting, far more powerful, far more influential than any earthly position or institution invented by man. She has the vision that, if worthy, she has the potential to be blessed as Rebekah of old to be “the mother of thousands of millions” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/24.60" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 24:60</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/a-mother-heart.p9" pid="YJpxen1XM0iZc6J7nNjB0g" hash="aY5GUg">Covenant-keeping women with mother hearts know that whether motherhood comes early or late; whether they are blessed with a “quiver full” of children here in mortality or not; whether they are single, married, or left to carry the responsibility of parenthood alone—in holy temples they are “endowed with power from on high” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.32" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:32</a>), and with that endowment they received the promised blessings and are “persuaded of them, and embraced them” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/11.13" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 11:13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/a-mother-heart.p10" pid="cZks8DXle0Sgs5qw9GqG-A" hash="OZR08A">Every girl and woman who makes and keeps sacred covenants can have a mother heart. There is no limit to what a woman with a mother heart can accomplish. Righteous women have changed the course of history and will continue to do so, and their influence will spread and grow exponentially throughout the eternities. How grateful I am to the Lord for trusting women with the divine mission of motherhood. Like Mother Eve I am “glad” (see <a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/5.11" class="scriptureRef">Moses 5:11</a>) to know these things. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2004/04/a-mother-heart</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2004-general-conference/2004-04-4040-julie-b-beck-64k-eng.mp3" length="3903495" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2004 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Work for Me to Do</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Lord sent an angel to Joseph Smith to tell him that he had a work to do. That work continues today in us.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10032029_000_038" doc-version="2" hash="gjAT6g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="uLyXW0v-FU2gsA0cbEVvhw" hash="mgdJXQ">A Work for Me to Do</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="II1iyEJjJE2MJE5ADR6TIQ" hash="6A7qTw">Julie B. Beck</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="k-MAz-rKk0CPNckIsI21KA" hash="3BMvHw">The Lord sent an angel to Joseph Smith to tell him that he had a work to do. That work continues today in us.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-f1.jpg" alt="Julie B. Beck" pid="FT2IMhtfYkOaObNh2T9NeA" hash="X4wZRA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.p1" pid="5loEz1tv_kC8Gq8qWa181Q" hash="ZLDcdg">I remember a family home evening lesson when I was a girl where my father taught us of the visit of the angel Moroni to the Prophet Joseph Smith. He said that after a sincere prayer, an angel appeared at Joseph’s bedside. The angel was a messenger sent from God, his name was Moroni, and he told Joseph that God had a work for him to do (see <a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.33" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:33</a>). I remember my father teaching that “Joseph did not say, ‘Oh no, Angel, I just wanted to know which church was true. I did not know I needed to <span class="emphasis">do</span> something!’” But of course Joseph needed to do something. He had a special calling from the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.p2" pid="qS8Bb5Q1Dkuu-DAwlU29jw" hash="8f3VHA">What Joseph did was remarkable. He began life as a simple farm boy, but through him the Book of Mormon was brought forth and translated, the priesthood and its keys were restored to earth, The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints was organized, and holy temples began to be built. Through Joseph Smith all the ordinances the children of our Heavenly Father need for their salvation are now upon the earth. <span class="emphasis">This</span> was the day of miracles spoken of in Moroni (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.35-37" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:35–37</a>) and the marvelous work and wonder foretold to Nephi centuries ago (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/14.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 14:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.p3" pid="_BULEF_2Y0Go2A-7nemesg" hash="gh_-Cg">The work Joseph started was carried on by early members of the Church who had faith in the Lord Jesus Christ and His restored gospel. Through their efforts the gospel of Jesus Christ began to spread over all the earth. <span class="emphasis">They</span> truly did a marvelous work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.p4" pid="Gb4mNJ3K9UudrrcwCKHYeg" hash="K-wVGQ">But the day of miracles is not over, and the marvelous work is still going on. When we were baptized, each of us became part of that work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.p5" pid="FWMt3dCqwUyH7glvF0cYtA" hash="YQEIpg">This past year as I have visited with members of the Church, I have seen that through the faith and work of simple people, the Lord’s covenant is being established on the earth (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.17-23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:17–23</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.p6" pid="3oa42Jm4S0mfbVHt8rj0sA" hash="RvKLRg">There is a young woman in Korea who is the first member of the Church in her family. She held her well-worn Personal Progress book and said she dreamed of having a gospel-centered family. A Young Women president in Armenia is carrying out the Young Women program faithfully although she does not have a <span class="emphasis">Church Handbook of Instructions</span> written in her language.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.p7" pid="IbxVnfSkLk6TGVQFo5RwRA" hash="8OJZPg">Members in Russia go to the temple regularly. They save their rubles and travel for days by bus, train, and boat to get to the nearest temple in Sweden.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.p8" pid="G9AWcd6yGk6YDeJXTV7uyw" hash="aQh_0A">My nine-year-old niece, Kimberly, talked so enthusiastically about the Church to her friend that her friend said, “I want to sign up for your church. Where do I sign up?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.p9" pid="8skPQk7e3E2-z0VlpvlDtg" hash="WdKaaQ">The young men and young women in my own ward are developing leadership skills and talents. They are willing to sing, play musical instruments, give talks, participate in service projects, and do any number of other things so that they can be part of this marvelous work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.p10" pid="_wbJ3tgkI0WyAh0URWdfDg" hash="xJUSkw">And then there was the young man in Bogotá who said, “I speak on behalf of the young men of Colombia. We are worthy and we are preparing to serve!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.p11" pid="nVu2h_vcpU-8U1WcWZ82-g" hash="NRtm4g">I have been where the Church is small and where it is large in numbers, where it is new and where it is well established, but the responsibility of each one of us is the same: we are part of the true, restored gospel of Jesus Christ. We have a work to do. We serve in simple ways, our testimonies grow, and we are part of this day of miracles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.p12" pid="6aFy4Xc5yESSdQkOwrsqiw" hash="Eqj9Fg">In my own lifetime I have been a witness to the miracle of the restored gospel. When I was a young girl my family moved to São Paulo, Brazil, where my father had been called to preside over the Brazilian Mission. It was an exciting time for me and a great place to grow up. A favorite game for my brothers and me was to dress up and pretend to be missionaries. We spent hours scribbling our own missionary pamphlets and “preaching” and “transferring” all over the yard. For five years the nightly conversations around our dinner table centered on missionary work, and I listened intently to stories of faith told by missionaries. Even at that age I knew I was part of a great work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.p13" pid="mBcVqfrx-Emx5eXeKc9aRg" hash="tG5NSg">There were only about 3,000 members of the Church in Brazil when we arrived there. I remember being in a very small Primary with a few other children, singing the same five songs every week, as those were the only ones translated into Portuguese. Two of my favorite songs were “A Luz Divina,” or “The Light Divine” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 305), and something about a bunny in the middle of the woods (see “The Little Rabbit,” <span class="emphasis">Children’s Friend,</span> June 1955, 257).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.p14" pid="IsujuQCUR0mzmxTMEMVapw" hash="ocz-Ow">In many ways our experience was similar to the early pioneers. We had no hymnbooks or pictures or lesson manuals sent from the headquarters of the Church. Everything that was needed to teach the gospel in Portuguese was written and printed in our mission home. All of us, even the children, were pressed into service to help assemble mission newsletters and lessons. No one shipped the Church to us. The prophet did not send us stake presidents or bishops. He did not send Relief Society presidents or youth programs. The Church in Brazil was made from the same material that the pioneers started with. The material to build the Church was in the people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.p15" pid="6hYkoRvxQEGoHPbcpVxEuA" hash="-2Ef3w">During our years in Brazil, we saw great growth come to the Church. Thousands became Latter-day Saints. Soon the mission was divided, districts and branches were organized, and new chapels were built. The new members were enthusiastic, and they grew in faith and became more experienced in the manner of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.p16" pid="yUnWIJ7BeEKbUaMYup0DuA" hash="YB0dPw">A lot of years passed, and then last year I returned to Brazil to attend the rededication of the São Paulo temple. At that time I learned that there were 187 stakes in Brazil. There are now 26 missions, 4 temples, and almost 1 million members. Imagine my surprise when I walked into a stadium filled with over 60,000 members who had gathered to hear President Gordon B. Hinckley and celebrate the temple dedication. To me it was a miracle to see thousands of youth dancing and singing together. As I watched that joyful celebration, I kept saying to myself, “This is amazing! This is a miracle! How did this miracle happen?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.p17" pid="o-VHPwnF20CWLUXNVWO1dw" hash="p83jIg">I marveled all that night at what I had seen. Then, the next morning at the temple dedication, I had a reunion with my Primary teacher, Sister Gloria Silveira. That was when I knew how the miracle had come about. As a new convert with no prior Church experience, Sister Silveira had come to Primary prepared to share her simple testimony and teach me the Articles of Faith in Portuguese. She and her husband, Humberto, are still faithful. They have served in many Church callings over the years, and they are still serving. When I saw Sister Silveira, I realized that the Church in Brazil had grown because of her and thousands like her. She and Brother Silveira represent people everywhere who have faith in the Lord Jesus Christ and His gospel. They have grown in knowledge and skill, and they have served in the Church (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.80" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:80</a>). They have shared the gospel with friends (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/30.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 30:5</a>). They work in the temple (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/138.48" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 138:48</a>). They taught their five children correct principles (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:28</a>). Of their 43 descendants, 15 have served full-time missions. Their grandchildren are now marrying in the temple, and their great-grandchildren are the fourth generation of Silveiras who are part of the marvelous work that was started by Joseph Smith. Because of them, faith has increased in the earth. They are an example of the miracle the Lord spoke about when He said that His gospel would be proclaimed by the weak and the simple (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:23</a>) and that by small and simple means great things are brought to pass (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/16.29" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 16:29</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do.p18" pid="zc-KfU1TfUGkNi-k75qZdQ" hash="ceoMVA">The Lord sent an angel to Joseph Smith to tell him that he had a work to do. That work continues today in us and is directed by President Gordon B. Hinckley, a living prophet, who said: “Glorious is this work. It will bless the life of every man, woman, boy, and girl who embraces it” (“Missionary Service,” <span class="emphasis">Worldwide Leadership Training Meeting,</span> Jan. 11, 2003, 21). “God be thanked for His marvelous bestowal of testimony, authority, and doctrine associated with this, the restored Church of Jesus Christ” (“The Marvelous Foundation of Our Faith,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 2002, 81). In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2005/04/a-work-for-me-to-do</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2005-general-young-women-meeting/2005-03-0020-julie-b-beck-64k-eng.mp3" length="8805048" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2005 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Have a Noble Birthright</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright?lang=eng</link>
      <description>You can learn more about your life and mission on earth by preparing to receive and then studying your patriarchal blessing.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006561_000_037" doc-version="3" hash="CJqVJw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="Z7Pq9F5v20WP5ujmuggPlA" hash="WhlSvQ">You Have a Noble Birthright</h1><p class="authorName" uuid="6d9c1d63-34fd-4f70-a560-8d52351a12d5" pid="iEgMVoawJ0eTbOwHQUhJJg" hash="6A7qTw">Julie B. Beck</p><p class="kicker" pid="6bVhnwNdIkS10KYxgKPF0A" hash="Jl2Orw">You can learn more about your life and mission on earth by preparing to receive and then studying your patriarchal blessing.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" uuid="2d0ba1b5-4796-40e1-b73c-638473a4c648">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.t1" uuid="">
      <img src="en2006lp.nfo-o-cb.jpg" alt="Julie B. Beck" uuid="da673a87-5fc8-46c0-a926-227128b184e8" pid="jyCRm6k6KEKCGoXEcVLnew" hash="ZLrjJQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p1" uuid="66c74631-96b1-4b67-9178-be562667e295" pid="VGrxQWXUx0SPqho0VHy4Iw" hash="1vZgVw">This past year I have seen the light of God shining in the faces of you young women so many times. I have seen it in large devotionals from Brazil to the Dominican Republic. I have seen it as you have pulled handcarts on pioneer treks. I have seen your light as I have sung and played games with you at camp. I have seen that light of God shining in the faces of girls in the baptistries of temples from Mexico to Utah. Your light has made a difference to me and many others. You have light because you are literally spirit daughters of Deity, “offspring of exalted parents”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> with a divine nature and an eternal destiny.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> You received your first lessons in the world of spirits from your heavenly parents.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> You have been sent to earth to “prove” yourselves.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p2" uuid="b2f2278a-7722-48c9-aa27-587a38929d1a" pid="mFJucJYc30SNGWBDj0_Ufw" hash="5Auzhw">You are in a season of your life when you are making some of your most important decisions. Because you are being bombarded with so many incorrect messages about who you are, you need some additional guidance. You can learn more about your life and mission on earth and the light that is in you by preparing to receive and then studying your patriarchal blessing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p3" uuid="48564085-e909-4145-8d6e-b55efb5848ba" pid="5obtxcvgqkah503GvS5nDA" hash="331KXQ">You are never too young to start learning about patriarchal blessings.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> I am glad I received my blessing before I was too heavily influenced by the confusing and incorrect messages in the world. I came away from that experience with the comforting assurance that the Lord loved me and knew me, and from that day onward I began to think more often in terms of eternity than popularity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p4" uuid="de5ec893-bb61-4443-a23a-3d9ee1a4851c" pid="RlUdDsNfd0O1fl5ArYBtng" hash="NGOAng">This is the season for young women to prepare and then receive their patriarchal blessing. Your bishop and parents can help you decide when the right time is for you, because the age and readiness are different for each person.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> When you understand the meaning and purpose of a patriarchal blessing and have a sincere desire to do the work of the Lord, you should be mature enough to receive your blessing.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> Sometimes people wait longer than is needed to receive their blessing, thinking that they need to qualify for it in some special way. If you can qualify to receive a recommend to do baptisms at the temple, then you should be able to qualify for a patriarchal blessing. It is important to prepare for your blessing with fasting and prayer so that your spirit is humble and teachable. Your personal preparation is very important.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p5" uuid="5061a43b-62a1-4005-b584-01b81e542e4e" pid="0_m32Xz_KkyzxVjAiGwqXQ" hash="TnVNAg">When you receive your blessing, you get a glimpse of eternity. You begin to see a picture of what lies ahead for you because your blessing will refer to your eternal purpose and journey. The patriarch who gives you your blessing does not know what your blessing will be until he gives it. He depends on the Spirit to tell him what to say. In your blessing, you are told about your ancestry in the house of Israel. That’s your family line and your family line is sometimes called a tribe. All of the tribes go back to the great patriarch Abraham. Your lineage is important. It means that you are included in the promises given to Abraham that through him all the nations of the world would be blessed.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p6" uuid="b3485165-e976-4092-9f45-0a6e6b2a9064" pid="NWX4ye5fv0K4U4KHLUmY1w" hash="qufX5g">Your lineage is a “blood relationship.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> That makes you literally “children of the prophets”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> with a noble birthright. That is why we often say that you are “youth of the noble birthright”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> and belong to a royal, “chosen generation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p7" uuid="d7a6f146-5305-48ee-9eac-47cbee97ec5b" pid="8W9P-t88qk6DuK9jqKXeHA" hash="Wes4YA">A friend of mine said: “When I joined the Church at age 16, I began to learn about my identity. I received my patriarchal blessing and was told I was of the house of Israel. At the time, I did not know what that meant, but over the years I have come to learn that I have a great privilege to be directly descended from the prophets. I have a precious heritage and the best opportunities.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p8" uuid="10eb6220-89bd-46c3-b7ec-651fe9b753bc" pid="eqvAiVp0Ikevs1g97oop8Q" hash="1iKncQ">Like Abraham, you seek a blessing so you can possess greater knowledge and receive instructions from the Lord.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> When you receive your blessing, you will discover that the Lord knows you by name. In the early days of the Church, many people wanted Joseph Smith to ask the Lord for a specific direction in their lives. Some of those revelations are now part of the Doctrine and Covenants. Just like the early Saints, you can regard your patriarchal blessing as your own “personal scripture.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> You should keep it sacred and not share it outside of your immediate family.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p9" uuid="a76cc5fe-a30d-4982-b8fb-24605f7d8b30" pid="lf6Eh5dGkUeFP45hlcSpSg" hash="fdgFzg">The patriarch can foresee the development and conditions of your life and can give you a blessing that relates to those. As one young woman told me, “There were things said about me in my blessing that even my parents did not know.” President James E. Faust said that each patriarchal blessing is inspired, “personal revelation from God.” Each is “a star to follow, … an anchor to our souls.” They reveal our capabilities and potential.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p10" uuid="2af23f47-a5ab-4c43-a8b8-2eee7ce64222" pid="y8j8vLT3nk-Ok7_D2LvGAw" hash="y8qstg">President Packer says that our blessings are a “[paragraph] from the book of [our] possibilities.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> President Monson calls our blessing “a Liahona of light.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p11" uuid="80d6da0a-4646-41a8-acee-3cbfab6cc8c9" pid="CZ3Xsm6OyUCh3fT12KZW5Q" hash="EvrwKA">Because a patriarchal blessing is not meant to be a prediction of all that will occur in the life of the recipient, we should seek and follow the guidance of the Holy Ghost to receive greater understanding for our course in life. The teachings of the gospel are always a guide to a full understanding of our destiny and privileges. For example, patriarchal blessings may not mention that a person will be married or have children, but we are taught in the gospel to marry in the temple and have families. We can follow these gospel teachings on our own, without specific personal direction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p12" uuid="864fc640-9029-4880-8a48-55b4f649a6de" pid="RiowP8G7J02YoKAHL5jHTg" hash="LlGXdQ">When I was in high school, a counselor read the results of my test scores and told me she did not think I would do well in college. But after I prayerfully studied my patriarchal blessing, I felt I should not abandon my lifelong goal. So, because I had insight into the Lord’s plan for me, I had hope in my heart, and I was able to move ahead confidently. I discovered that I was successful in that setting, and I earned a university diploma. When we know who we are and what we are supposed to do, it is easier to make important decisions about education, careers, and marriage. It is easier to shine our light in our families, with our friends, and in all other places.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p13" uuid="c4b8263f-4573-4306-bfa2-c271850d6b86" pid="lgYABZpmjEOH1K_zsoxyqg" hash="fgX3RA">The Savior said: “Verily, verily, I say unto you, I give unto you to be the light of this people. A city that is set on a hill cannot be hid.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p14" uuid="f852e4cc-9d78-4e82-9b51-8ca0c4295a5c" pid="TvJt-7CzvE-4LPjoj7jbkg" hash="-3VR_Q">“Behold, do men light a candle and put it under a bushel? Nay, but on a candlestick, and it giveth light to all that are in the house;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p15" uuid="4aa361af-9c62-47e7-8d5a-9a634e70d852" pid="Fh013jca6USMSXtkkZPHTw" hash="SCE6ig">“Therefore let your light so shine before this people, that they may see your good works and glorify your Father who is in heaven.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p16" uuid="2c9d3809-d834-4c1f-a0cd-1bfe924fe5be" pid="7ZmSXZQpzUCEJCWULplpOA" hash="3cat_g">When you know who you are and what you should be doing with your life, you don’t want to hide your light.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p17" uuid="7d14aa4f-dc69-4a4c-a784-05a56c4b7ce5" pid="dDCvG8HXOkm_mFYQ7IS39w" hash="DVTraA">For instance, you would not want to “hide your light” by wearing clothing that diminishes your royal potential. You would not use improper language or stories or mar your body with tattoos or other procedures debasing for a daughter of royal birth. You would not cheapen your birthright by taking into your body any substance that is harmful or addictive. Neither would you view or participate in any behavior which is immoral and lowers your noble stature. You seek all that is praiseworthy and virtuous and lovely and of good report<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> because you know you have a noble heritage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p18" uuid="a44bdcb1-f197-4f01-bc57-a6fe2e54f629" pid="QV7LIvRLrEGmPX3noTYenQ" hash="7RNzFg">You are treasured children of the promise. If you will keep the Lord’s statutes and commandments and hearken to His voice, He has promised that He will make you high above the nations in name and honor and praise.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> Your patriarchal blessing should inspire you to make changes in your life when they are needed. It contains promises that you can receive only through your faithfulness. If you are not faithful, you cannot plan on your blessing being fulfilled.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p19" uuid="655312c5-ad42-44c9-93a1-39be1bcca077" pid="7111am3p2EiRpVx4-_csLg" hash="F3-SwA">Sometimes young women think that because they have made mistakes, they are not worthy to receive a patriarchal blessing or that they have disqualified themselves from the blessing they have already been given. Remember, the foundational teaching of the Lord Jesus Christ is faith in Him and His power to atone for our sins. “Satan wants you to think that you cannot repent, but that is absolutely not true.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> When we take the sacrament each week, we commit to change our lives for the better. We should always be trying to become a new person who is more like our Savior Jesus Christ. The Apostle Paul calls this “[walking] in newness of life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> If you have made serious mistakes that could disqualify you from your noble birthright, be willing to take your tears of sorrow to your bishop. He is your friend in the repentance process and is set apart to act as a judge here on earth in the place of the Savior, who is the Eternal Judge. Repentance is like a giant eraser, and it can erase permanent ink! It is not easy, but it is possible.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> The Lord said, “He who has repented of his sins, the same is forgiven, and I, the Lord, remember them no more.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright.p20" uuid="5352fde6-9043-4ad8-b567-b3d388affe6d" pid="WxWATE8_D0y0XVBBukLSkQ" hash="nf0CBw">Young women, your patriarchal blessing will help you know that you have a noble birthright. As you get older, you will see the prophecies in your blessing taking shape in your life. The Lord has important and exciting things for you to do. This is your time to “arise and shine forth, that [your] light may be a standard for the nations.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26">26</span> “Therefore let your light so shine before this people, that they may see your good works and glorify your Father who is in heaven.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_27">27</span> In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/04/you-have-a-noble-birthright</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2006-general-young-women-meeting/2006-03-0020-julie-b-beck-64k-eng.mp3" length="9928223" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2006 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Outpouring of Blessings</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings?lang=eng</link>
      <description>All faithful members are equally blessed by the outpouring of blessings they receive through priesthood ordinances.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006561_000_005" doc-version="3" hash="pD8mgw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="AJ3sgm_A6Ee56NAasXjwow" hash="_DnAOA">An Outpouring of Blessings</h1><p class="authorName" uuid="6d9c1d63-34fd-4f70-a560-8d52351a12d5" pid="bkIIbBVo70ewiyVbOQfb5A" hash="6A7qTw">Julie B. Beck</p><p class="kicker" pid="xbGWpcwZb0qS0s08lzo1gA" hash="WjAgKw">All faithful members are equally blessed by the outpouring of blessings they receive through priesthood ordinances.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" uuid="5fe9637a-fd11-41b1-acb8-297586c853ad">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.t1" uuid="">
      <img src="en2006lp.nfo-o-cb.jpg" alt="Julie B. Beck" uuid="863467b0-d2cc-4d3a-a894-4d7f07b134fa" pid="5ciyT2HzR020v6bwJ7su6g" hash="ZLrjJQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p1" uuid="0bc26728-dd97-4d23-bf9c-0a8775d59641" pid="zP9WZ5u_OU2wN0LjoFxeDw" hash="aVFAyg">In Kirtland, when the remaining priesthood keys were restored, the Lord said, “This is the beginning of the blessing which shall be poured out upon the heads of my people.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> I am grateful for the outpouring of blessings that has come to each of us through the priesthood of God. By the power of the priesthood, this world and everything in it, including each of us, were created. The priesthood is intricately woven into who we are and have ever been.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> As sons and daughters of God, we each have unique responsibilities and roles, and through the blessings of the priesthood, we are all given equal partnership, gifts, and blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p2" uuid="b0cc08ce-a69c-48df-8279-c2f49e6fb6a0" pid="2tXu9GtkPU6ht2dFOS6rfQ" hash="fRFy9w">Last fall our oldest granddaughter was baptized and confirmed a member of the Church. After she received the Holy Ghost, her newest sister was blessed and given a name. The following month, another new granddaughter was named and blessed. Since then I have reflected often on the privileges those little girls enjoy because the priesthood of God has been restored.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p3" uuid="a285b1d5-3a28-4247-97f8-9c58d92ee396" pid="Ww0gXARRaEywtYfSb8r8gg" hash="hdTHig">I hope our granddaughters and grandsons grow up knowing that they are not and have never been third-party observers of the priesthood. The blessings of the priesthood, which “are available to men and women alike,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> are woven in and through and around their lives. Each of them is blessed by sacred ordinances, and each of them can enjoy the blessings of spiritual gifts by virtue of the priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p4" uuid="af7b87b2-856e-490b-a2f8-ba0c2d45c71a" pid="Gt5DRMd8ike8JwgZLwJI5A" hash="Bk6huw">All faithful members of the Lord’s Church are equally blessed by priesthood ordinances. The first ordinance<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> in a child’s life usually takes place when he or she is a baby and is given a name and a blessing. When children reach the age of accountability, they are baptized. There is not a separate baptism for boys and girls. The same baptismal ordinance is performed for a young girl and a young boy, who are baptized in the same font. When those children are confirmed and receive the Holy Ghost, the same power is given to each of them. They qualify for the help of that holy power through their faithfulness and not in any other way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p5" uuid="4123a6c9-6622-4d9a-a83e-1753ae42d59c" pid="HEQsKG2NakSKuC-bKTWWdA" hash="rGbFfg">As members of the Church, we are equal before the Lord as we partake of the sacrament. Through our faith in Jesus Christ and the power of His Atonement made possible because of that ordinance, we can all repent and become better.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p6" uuid="cd19c8e6-5d05-46d5-b27e-02dac0d3fa79" pid="VTPRnrHp0U6n6eLm-r77ow" hash="SrBuFA">Each of us is equally entitled to a priesthood blessing when we are sick or need added support from the Lord in our lives. A young woman who desires a patriarchal blessing is equally entitled to know her lineage and potential as a young man her same age. The blessings that come to each of them through Abraham are powerful and important.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p7" uuid="c9113fcc-a5fa-4e6c-96c2-52c49cd08fff" pid="j473VxierUywKpxmmbaigQ" hash="4OxQEQ">We teach all young men and young women to prepare to go to the temple so they can “receive the blessings of [the] fathers that [they] may be entitled to the highest blessings of the priesthood.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> When one of my nieces received her temple endowment a few months ago, she exclaimed with joy: “I made it! All of my life I have been taught about preparing for the temple, and I made it!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p8" uuid="58c0c50f-1e22-46c6-bf37-77df431003ea" pid="oRMaPzu5skaxdjSorDWIHw" hash="a1KI8g">Every man and woman who is willing to serve the Lord and can qualify for a temple recommend makes covenants of obedience and sacrifice. Each is endowed “with power from on high.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p9" uuid="32b093b2-94aa-4f03-b05b-27ca1ec6650c" pid="7FkSrl0vXE2-iCfQef7Wvw" hash="EeX0MA">Every elder and sister who receives a mission call is set apart to do the Lord’s work, and each is given authority to preach the gospel of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p10" uuid="f7d58b30-c906-42e5-a80a-36795a2767c3" pid="iQa7ZnNOKU6fxbxYC7qRxQ" hash="pnJFOQ">A man and a woman who enter into the full partnership of a covenant temple marriage share equally in the blessings of that covenant if they are faithful.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> The Lord has said that their covenant will be in force after this life, and together they are promised power and exaltation.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p11" uuid="9e2e92c4-28ea-4576-b193-a2809681897e" pid="gQTDmOnE6Ei8XrXLpRXjXw" hash="uldzaQ">President Ezra Taft Benson said, “When our children obey the Lord and go to the temple to receive their blessings and enter into the marriage covenant, they enter into the same <span class="emphasis">order of the priesthood</span> that God instituted in the very beginning with father Adam.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p12" uuid="b9b17795-bc21-4b16-9556-2be070fbf9f0" pid="i-QByYiwg0CUdpXyncmkdg" hash="1QQhBQ">I saw the power of priesthood blessings when I visited a family where the young father lay dying. Surrounding him were his wife and beautiful daughters. On each wall of that room was at least one picture of the family or the temple. The mother testified of their blessings when she said: “We are empowered and protected by our covenants. Our family will endure forever. The Lord is watching over us, and we are not alone.” All faithful members are equally blessed by the outpouring of blessings they receive through priesthood ordinances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p13" uuid="0e1e1c7e-4963-4e3c-a5b9-efa9cf855b9d" pid="I_XvnDogv0C3jSXqqV3kzw" hash="0jcv2w">Because the priesthood has been restored, we also share equally in the blessings of spiritual gifts. The Lord gives us these gifts for our own benefit<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> and to help each other.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p14" uuid="5c1815a6-d366-416d-bc53-010891da2094" pid="B6Gnn5ACSEuqMkGv8P8MKQ" hash="0nfdNw">Moroni said that “there are different ways that these gifts are administered; but it is the same God who worketh all in all; and they are given by the manifestations of the Spirit of God unto men, to profit them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p15" uuid="fc526862-68e4-4946-8fd4-2762771aa3d1" pid="zHA-EfI9o0m0rqvSEiT8OQ" hash="Au0tZg">“For behold, to one is given by the Spirit of God, that he may teach the word of wisdom;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p16" uuid="d65063f5-e278-461a-8335-20e9718d8b36" pid="8_wnu-5lV0iSLUNknWz8rA" hash="6Xl1kQ">“And to another, that he may teach the word of knowledge by the same Spirit;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p17" uuid="163a71bb-c4d0-4e29-a61b-3a7213f6d74a" pid="5l0aLKuTWUWl7RA32z6xcQ" hash="JUJfvA">“And to another, exceedingly great faith; and to another, the gifts of healing by the same Spirit.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p18" uuid="4323c77c-e846-435a-abb7-8be21535f241" pid="n-V1n4mTDk2c0CnsiTIarQ" hash="V56nyA">As I have tried to learn Spanish and remember Portuguese (which I knew as a child), I have prayed for and felt the help of the Lord as I communicate in those tongues. I have heard other Church leaders and missionaries bear powerful testimonies in languages they have barely studied. I know people who are given the spiritual gift of a believing spirit. When they hear the gospel, it rings true in their hearts. I know others who are given the gift of wisdom or the ability to use knowledge in righteous ways. Some have the ability to work miracles, some are gifted healers, and others have great discernment.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p19" uuid="bd84bf71-ebac-4a73-94e0-d592f6492356" pid="N4cCsqL9CUWdgk4chwAQKA" hash="WMbmgQ">When I was a little girl, I often experienced serious illness. My father was always willing and worthy to use the priesthood power he held to bless me. But I have also felt that my mother’s special gifts contributed to my healing. She was truly gifted in her ability to minister to my needs and help me get well. Her great faith that the Lord would lead her to answers about medical treatment was a comfort to me. How blessed I was to have two parents who lovingly used their spiritual gifts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p20" uuid="0cb3dbc9-d97b-4867-9851-e80a6dc98e08" pid="aZ8zkAPNuUCX86p4_WsKHg" hash="LOWCkA">President Wilford Woodruff said that “it is the privilege of every man and woman in this kingdom to enjoy the spirit of prophecy, which is the Spirit of God; and to the faithful it reveals such things as are necessary for their comfort and consolation, and to guide them in their daily duties.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p21" uuid="bac74ce1-3c21-49d2-8b4a-ea7888683a1a" pid="A6RY_PdK-0GUrnNrZ8R8GA" hash="S0_7yg">The blessings of the priesthood make it possible for every person who is set apart to serve in any office in the Lord’s Church to receive “authority, responsibility, and blessings connected with the office.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p22" uuid="c5f945c5-0733-4ef7-b329-75a024283a73" pid="0C5F0FKJR0q915oUnUKCqQ" hash="H1Bm8g">Spiritual gifts are numerous and varied and come to us as we seek them and use them appropriately. We enjoy them because of the power of the Holy Ghost, which is in and around and woven through our lives.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p23" uuid="0a19e06e-a755-46b6-8eb9-cd23fde033f0" pid="du64zg7nskuEm4FLVmMFAA" hash="MsPxwQ">Through the blessings of the priesthood, the Lord shows us that He is “no respecter of persons.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> In my travels, I usually have the chance to visit members in their homes. Some of those homes are very basic dwellings. At first I would say to myself: “Why am I blessed with a house that has electricity and plumbing when this family does not even have water near their home? Does the Lord love them less than He loves me?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p24" uuid="4b02a905-f909-44b0-a734-c1f1b7ae8a1a" pid="Y8Ru0u4ptk62A_2GR08wIQ" hash="enGCaw">Then one day I sat in a temple next to a sister who lives in a humble house. I spent two hours at her side. I looked often into her beautiful eyes and saw the love of the Lord in them. As we finished our work in the temple, I had a powerful realization. In all of the eternal blessings, in all of our most important privileges and opportunities, we were equals. I had been “baptized unto repentance,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> and so had she. I had spiritual gifts, and so did she. I had the opportunity to repent, and so did she. I had received the Holy Ghost, and so had she. I had received temple ordinances, and so had she. If both of us had left this world together at that moment, we would have arrived equal before the Lord in our blessings and potential.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p25" uuid="fced1f66-2679-40c5-82d4-69b5e111c8e4" pid="tzmD4Qnjekqt-_vyU0akDA" hash="ku5QoA">Priesthood blessings are the great equalizer. Those blessings are the same for men and women, for boys and girls; they are the same for married and single, rich and poor, for the intellectual and the illiterate, for the well-known and the obscure.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings.p26" uuid="b9352293-63c9-4d44-9b16-4db3f5a2e953" pid="A8Jc82TrrEOS-F7GLus5bg" hash="DbXuBg">I am grateful that through the infinite fairness and love of God, all men and women were given equal partnership, gifts, blessings, and potential through priesthood ordinances and spiritual gifts. Because of the priesthood, which is woven in and around and through our lives, every power, every covenant we need to do our life’s work and walk back to our heavenly home has been poured out upon our heads. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/04/an-outpouring-of-blessings</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2006-general-conference/2006-04-1030-julie-b-beck-64k-eng.mp3" length="5341989" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering, Repenting, and Changing</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The easiest, quickest path to happiness and peace is to repent and change as soon as we can.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008333_000_042" doc-version="2" hash="VKUNXw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="jmZPBCWp20-pMmxOSS5qYA" hash="Lafkqw">Remembering, Repenting, and Changing</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="8jvxnSvOYEqoW-FBM2fSzg" hash="6A7qTw">Julie B. Beck</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="V-ujK3efNUeFcnCFRUmi1A" hash="xbpciQ">The easiest, quickest path to happiness and peace is to repent and change as soon as we can.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/BeckJB_03.jpg" alt="Julie B. Beck" pid="Fo09KAvwf0SnrmHvW8t6iw" hash="4hAyHA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p1" pid="CoWQScQxhEmePNpRLD2yNQ" hash="cFi4_A">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="109"></span>I am grateful for our Savior and the invitation we all have to “come unto Christ, and be perfected in him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> I hope I can convey to you some of what I have been thinking and feeling about remembering Him, repenting, and changing. I think I can best express what is in my heart by telling you about three women and then discussing some lessons I have learned from their stories.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p2" pid="QVaBVnclh0OIGMJLnWzfTg" hash="FqDy2w">I will begin with Ruth May Fox, who was a Young Women general president many years ago. She served in that calling until she was 84 years old. Sister Fox was born in England, and when she was 13, she walked almost every step to the Salt Lake Valley with a group of pioneers. Her mother died when she was a baby, so she spent the first dozen years of her life living with a number of different families. She must have been a difficult child to manage, because her grandmother called her a “bad maid” and refused to take care of her.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p3" pid="pwE4r_t9PUSSMvHOS2SuMA" hash="Xim3Fw">Eventually, Ruth married and had 12 children. She shared her firm testimony with her children and taught gospel lessons while she worked beside them, but she admitted that her older children sometimes received harsh discipline because she had a quick temper and she did not always “count [to] ten”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> when she was provoked. She worked hard to master this weakness and came to be known for her kind heart and service to others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p4" pid="YA3fzSfjjUu6_4mvbzGEfw" hash="ic1INA">Sister Fox lived to be 104 years old. In her long life she experienced great joys and difficult trials, and she taught that “life brings some hard lessons. The sturdiest plants are not grown under glass, and strength of character is not derived from the avoidance of problems.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p5" pid="BA7_9r66Ak6gmpJfU-eEDA" hash="zRl9aQ">Last year I climbed Independence <span class="pageBreak" page-number="110"></span>Rock in Wyoming to find where Sister Fox had carved her name at age 13 when she was on her journey to the Salt Lake Valley. The weather from the last 140 years has almost erased it, but I was able to just make out “Ruth May 1867.” I wanted to know more about this great leader and disciple of Jesus Christ who worked all her life to improve herself and whose motto was “the Kingdom of God or nothing”!<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p6" pid="YRTMgeyh80GMegFboGJIfg" hash="Yihc6Q">My next story is about a woman I will call Mary. She was the daughter of faithful pioneer parents who had sacrificed much for the gospel. She had been married in the temple and was the mother of 10 children. She was a talented woman who taught her children how to pray, to work hard, and to love each other. She paid her tithing, and the family rode to church together on Sunday in their wagon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p7" pid="71E_g48L5kuN95FDSwKH1g" hash="RGHM4Q">Though she knew it was contrary to the Word of Wisdom, she developed the habit of drinking coffee and kept a coffee pot on the back of her stove. She claimed that “the Lord will not keep me out of heaven for a little cup of coffee.” But, because of that little cup of coffee, she could not qualify for a temple recommend, and neither could those of her children who drank coffee with her. Though she lived to a good old age and did eventually qualify to reenter and serve in the temple, only one of her 10 children had a worthy temple marriage, and a great number of her posterity, which is now in its fifth generation, live outside of the blessings of the restored gospel she believed in and her forefathers sacrificed so much for.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p8" pid="OBvmFASBVES0Guh8CvhO6A" hash="7Z8PSQ">The last story is about Christina (not her real name), who had been baptized and sealed to her family when she was a young girl, but somewhere along the way the family stopped living the gospel. Now she was in her late teens, and she had been making some wrong choices and was very unhappy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p9" pid="8Rj8tcPVvUGQq60wiQtUTw" hash="WtjSEA">One day I gave her a Personal Progress book and said, “This book will help you incorporate qualities of Christ in your life so you can make the changes you desire. I invite you to begin to work in your book today and then bring it with you to the youth fireside tonight and share with me what you have learned.” That night she said with tears in her eyes, “Today I started <span class="emphasis">my</span> personal progress.” She has written to me a few times since that day. She began going back to Sunday meetings, Mutual, and seminary. In a couple of weeks her sister and mother attended church with her. Later the father joined them, and now the entire family has been back to the temple together.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p10" pid="fGapnGXYkEaYzdgyHL_YMw" hash="n2sWMQ">So what were some lessons I learned from these stories about remembering, repenting, and changing?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p11" pid="Q3R2cfabp06NrBLKlt7lXA" hash="vHQTaw">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">The first lesson is that everyone makes mistakes.</span>
</span>
        <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> Not long ago I was with an eight-year-old girl on the day of her baptism. At the end of the day <span class="pageBreak" page-number="111"></span>she said with all confidence, “I have been baptized for a whole day, and I haven’t sinned once!” But her perfect day did not last forever, and I am sure she is learning by now, like we all learn, that as hard as we try, we do not always avoid every bad situation, every wrong choice, or control ourselves as we should. I often hear about the chosen, royal generation of this dispensation, but I have never heard it called the perfect generation. Teenagers are especially vulnerable because the power of Satan is real, and they are making their first big, independent choices. Consequently, they are also making their first big mistakes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p12" pid="xusm5I4LdUC3thsR6g-okw" hash="TLwdJg">This is what happened to Corianton in the Book of Mormon. Corianton was supposed to be serving a faithful mission, but he thought he was strong enough and smart enough to handle risky situations and bad company, and he got himself into big trouble and big sin when he started going to the wrong places, with the wrong people, doing the wrong things.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p13" pid="ctNFjrtVu0OPeoYmxAzNJQ" hash="ouKBvQ">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">My second lesson is that repentance isn’t optional.</span>
</span> We are commanded to repent.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> The Savior taught that unless we repent and “become as a little child, … [we] can in nowise inherit the kingdom of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> We must not let one little cup of coffee, one bad habit, one bad choice, one wrong decision derail us for a lifetime.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p14" pid="Gtn2LQ3oNkO9m7BkVWiofQ" hash="rTvY0g">Sometimes people get casual about repenting. I have heard some people say that repenting is too hard. Others say they are tired of feeling guilty or have been offended by a leader who was helping them repent. Sometimes people give up when they have made mistakes and come to believe that there is no hope for them. Some people imagine that they will feel better about themselves if they just leave the restored gospel and go away.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p15" pid="V2PeBwCYfE-6GQu-_LRkng" hash="9L4JoQ">It is Satan who puts hopeless thoughts into the hearts of those who have made mistakes. The Lord Jesus Christ always gives us hope. He says:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p16" pid="CsTHzVN5ikOEUFlmfNgwAg" hash="sBsRsA">“Thou wast chosen to do the work of the Lord, but because of transgression, if thou art not aware thou wilt fall.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p17" pid="qNRVawaTPEShSb9jufWlWw" hash="RxNB7Q">“But remember, God is merciful; therefore, repent of that which thou hast done which is contrary to the commandment which I gave you, and thou art still chosen, and art again called to the work.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p18" pid="3rXADI_P2kK8zKZTmOuavg" hash="xbpciQ1">The easiest, quickest path to happiness and peace is to repent and change as soon as we can.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p19" pid="6v1bhhOfwUKoL8L8GXyBBw" hash="g5Piwg">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">Lesson three is that we don’t do it alone.</span>
</span> It is not possible to make real change all by ourselves. Our own willpower and our own good intentions are not enough. When we make mistakes or choose poorly, we must have the help of our Savior to get back on track. We partake of the sacrament week after week to show our faith in His power to change us. We confess our sins and promise to forsake them.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p20" pid="ek855MWWRUuPmL7plnGVmw" hash="AFNWbA">When our best efforts are not quite enough, it is through His grace that we receive the strength to keep trying.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> The Lord says: “If men come unto me I will show unto them their weakness. I give unto men weakness that they may be humble; and my grace is sufficient for all men that humble themselves before me; for if they humble themselves before me, and have faith in me, then will I make weak things become strong unto them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p21" pid="_leot6NkeEi27w9n0umLbw" hash="yAX-Gw">When we seek the Lord’s help to change us, then we have this promise: “He who has repented of his sins, the same is forgiven, and I, the Lord, remember them no more.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> The Lord does not give up on us. He says, “Come unto me, all ye that labour and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> The joy and peace we receive when we know we have been forgiven is a divine blessing. That peace comes in the Lord’s time and in His way, but it does come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p22" pid="ifGPu2vjWU2ECQmlLgPnDQ" hash="UYssyg">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">My last lesson is that we can change.</span>
</span> Every day is a new opportunity to remember our Savior and follow His example. Without repenting, we cannot progress.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> That is why repentance is the second principle of the gospel.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p23" pid="zyeF4NAUiEONTtsfpPGyTw" hash="qavdRg">Instead of making excuses for a weakness, we work each day to develop good habits and Christlike qualities. President Spencer W. Kimball said, “The cultivation of Christlike qualities is a demanding and relentless task—it is not for the seasonal worker or for those who will not stretch themselves, again <span class="pageBreak" page-number="112"></span>and again.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> I learned from Christina that developing Christlike qualities in our lives is a sign that we are changing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p24" pid="6D5n9y9J_0q6bmS5AhLA6A" hash="sA4Vyw">Because we are all mortal, we all make mistakes. Repentance is not optional, but we don’t do it alone. We have a Savior to help us repent. By developing His qualities in our lives, we know we are making changes that help us come closer to Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p25" pid="zKrHCGuQSUCHe8cRGO5IYA" hash="9ANhjA">Sister Fox said that the gospel was her “mantle of protection against temptation, [her] consolation in sorrow, [her] joy and glory throughout all [her] days, and [her] hope of eternal life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> She took as her motto “the Kingdom of God or nothing” because she knew that by embracing the gospel with her whole heart, she could receive the promise the Savior gave to us all: “Whoso repenteth and is baptized in my name shall be filled; and if he endureth to the end, behold, him will I hold guiltless before my Father at that day when I shall stand to judge the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing.p26" pid="4IfUz-HXjEiyd7-p_552Pg" hash="RA-tbA">It is through repenting that I have come to know the Savior, and it is as I seek His help to change me that my faith and dependence on Him increase. I bear testimony of His reality and power in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/04/remembering-repenting-and-changing</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2007-general-young-women-meeting/2007-03-0020-julie-b-beck-64k-eng.mp3" length="5880246" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2007 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Latter-day Saint Women Do Best: Stand Strong and Immovable</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We must stand strong and immovable in faith, strong and immovable in family, and strong and immovable in relief.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008332_000_041" doc-version="2" hash="zadRlA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="6wLqc8cBhEaLd1a_dks8cA" hash="3ZJO2w">What Latter-day Saint Women Do Best: Stand Strong and Immovable</h1><p class="authorName" guid="6d9c1d63-34fd-4f70-a560-8d52351a12d5" pid="5zCRwcqhF0uKrlrrLysTSw" hash="6A7qTw">Julie B. Beck</p><p class="kicker" pid="1Y9Ar0-CjEOuKaUeZynAng" hash="HxTSOQ">We must stand strong and immovable in faith, strong and immovable in family, and strong and immovable in relief.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="f3431c60-b29b-4ef5-9ea2-fba8feaf9f13">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/BeckJB_03.jpg" alt="Julie B. Beck" guid="ba341c38-3dc1-4a62-bbd2-3fe973aca060" pid="YZBTx73K4USJ0EtJVqsoWQ" hash="4hAyHA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="hxmpz7PL40CR9MXjE3SsxA" hash="9DrdQw">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="109"></span>My dear sisters, I approach this awesome responsibility with a prayer in my heart. I have a testimony of the true restored gospel of Jesus Christ. The Savior is our leader and exemplar, our rock, our strength, and our advocate. Any part I can play in helping Him and His ordained prophet is a blessing in my life. I have always had a great love and respect for the sisters of this society, and I believe that the women of this Church are the finest, most capable women in the world. Please know of my love for you—the magnificent women of this Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="ILL9aa2nykWyw8RNE4rbWw" hash="t3eirw">President Hinckley said in a worldwide leadership training meeting: “I am convinced there is no other organization anywhere to match the Relief Society of this Church. It has a membership of more than five million women across the earth. If they will be united and speak with one voice, their strength will be incalculable. … It is so tremendously important that the women of the Church stand strong and immovable for that which is correct and proper under the plan of the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="PjwaOdn0hEiP7A7gsfXyvA" hash="yNMb-g">I have pondered and studied this inspiring charge, and I have sought answers regarding how the women of this Church could fulfill President Hinckley’s challenge and promise. How can they speak with one voice and stand strong and immovable for those things which are correct and proper? Within the plan of the Lord there are specific things Latter-day Saint women must do because they are daughters of God, chosen to come to the earth at a time which has been called “a very difficult season in the history of the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="wr3SMyBKikqldjOoSClOmQ" hash="VuwUHg">In order to do our part as women under the Lord’s plan, we must stand strong and immovable in <span class="emphasis">faith,</span> strong and immovable in <span class="emphasis">family,</span> and strong and immovable in <span class="emphasis">relief.</span> We must excel in these three important areas which set us apart as the Lord’s disciples. Through Relief Society we practice being disciples of Christ. We learn what He would have us learn, we do what He would have us do, and we become what He would have us become. When we gather with this focus, the work of Relief Society is relevant whatever your circumstance—whether you are 18 or 88, single or married, have children or not, or whether you live in Bountiful, Utah, or Bangalore, India.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.t2" guid="98c7eb1d-0b7e-4c74-b450-464a62c99d0f">
        <h3 class="title" guid="0056e639-5000-4ad8-937b-51ba0719c721" pid="rivF8KnQrEyfdMnLkMZNbg" hash="qSDyyA">Stand Strong and Immovable in Faith</h3>
        <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.f1"><p pid="qritc0GP2kGWt-WRR5eF1w" hash="5TfbOQ">First, Latter-day Saint women must be strong and immovable in their faith. They can and should excel in living and sharing their testimonies of the Lord Jesus Christ and His restored gospel. We do this as we:</p><ol class="number" guid="bfdd9d80-4edc-48c7-8770-53a9240f50c3"><li guid="cde2b721-caeb-4d79-b20a-5d013b9e5859" pid="FagXgzj3Ck6lMTPTxzvSFg" hash="URwboA">
            <span class="label">1.</span>
            <p guid="01ed3ae0-b1fa-4c8a-abf8-0202315b2257" pid="pGcGHbpEzkSMzWi_9FwC-A" hash="Yn6diA">Make and keep covenants with Him.</p>
          </li><li guid="4bbc6b2a-bb8a-430c-8b98-a7616e934155" pid="9yXVTVPZgEiWk5aQC4OL1A" hash="eF358g">
            <span class="label">2.</span>
            <p guid="cc129d10-ee5f-4c6e-985e-634aee90faf5" pid="PeCITtZnv0Sk1lAhOIXB9g" hash="CZSMbQ">Are worthy and worship in His temples.</p>
          </li><li guid="a3e4771b-7053-495f-9816-7b150d466606" pid="--oTdr57HUyTxb2XzBRDng" hash="a1QjRQ">
            <span class="label">3.</span>
            <p guid="32544dcb-927e-468e-a286-64bfeb28a467" pid="WQmXJ9h7mU-knokaUVJIrQ" hash="GL7RNA">Study His doctrine in the scriptures and the words of prophets.</p>
          </li><li guid="fe716522-1438-4a3c-894a-2e6e589071b9" pid="kKTjXD8sDU69L39_bdowbg" hash="nH0WLw">
            <span class="label">4.</span>
            <p guid="627dda24-bef7-4e69-8d0b-4989d0ea43a0" pid="kO2duITgJ0a0vJhZ3KJNuw" hash="dQ9zbA">Qualify for, recognize, and follow the Holy Ghost.</p>
          </li><li guid="7d1dc8a3-162d-41dd-87c2-a89b2c45c687" pid="XGndK7QTm0WuLJhInx83LQ" hash="1lQtdw">
            <span class="label">5.</span>
            <p guid="37fc1452-17a0-4c48-bdb8-d88a013af3d5" pid="BIqmSTqn-EKQRBdArvzi_Q" hash="58ebwg">Share and defend His gospel.</p>
          </li><li guid="c41d366b-ee09-4422-817b-e7626c0c91af" pid="uJugV9DGNUy4NpyQ_Xdt-A" hash="dzAlOw">
            <span class="label">6.</span>
            <p guid="0d195c0e-2019-4fe5-b6bf-2e61118e63eb" pid="y5AMN5X0pUiAbOLbRNymxQ" hash="jMST0A">Participate in sincere personal and family prayer.</p>
          </li><li guid="07419dba-06f4-49fa-9fd9-5f4a627f4860" pid="ZbCvtJxcjkWb74fDQ0HBDw" hash="e_nejw">
            <span class="label">7.</span>
            <p guid="7ee67c5c-c90d-4297-b0e3-ca26d0a7addb" pid="t12LRqomAUKSmsoSRETiow" hash="JcC6qg">Have family home evening.</p>
          </li><li guid="2ee3b90d-5ab0-491c-87a5-1f9e2fe11197" pid="LF6AJPRRBk-5G9zKfJ2etw" hash="6Qh58w">
            <span class="label">8.</span>
            <p guid="0e06a5e1-0730-402e-8015-9dc1c45852a4" pid="85Kw66A3lE6U5XHS0ccIkw" hash="o3waBQ">Live principles of self-reliance and provident living.</p>
          </li></ol></div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="QIiQ4HurMUSKbdOlZyrwqw" hash="bPoeRw">These are <span class="emphasis">essential</span> things which must be done before <span class="emphasis">nonessential</span> things. <span class="pageBreak" page-number="110"></span>These are simple, indispensable practices that almost seem mundane when we talk about them. However, they are marks of discipleship which have always been foundational for Relief Society sisters. No one can do these things for us—these are <span class="emphasis">personal</span> practices and habits that set us apart as strong and immovable for that which is correct.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="HYnLnyBqCUODJVOTbmqTUA" hash="nj8FYw">What a different world and Church this would be if every Latter-day Saint sister excelled at making, renewing, and keeping covenants; if every sister qualified for a temple recommend and worshipped more often in temples; if every sister studied the scriptures and doctrines of Christ and knew them so well that she could teach and defend those doctrines at any time or place. Think of our combined strength if every sister had sincere prayer every morning and night or, better yet, prayed unceasingly as the Lord has commanded. If every family had family prayer daily and had a family home evening once a week, we would be stronger. If every sister was self-reliant enough to be able to give freely of her knowledge, talents, and resources and if every sister’s discipleship was reflected by what she said and what she wore, we would be immovable in that which is correct.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.t3" guid="996d26f4-c6c1-41d3-aef9-4cb2e39bf2ca">
        <h3 class="title" guid="c86d7155-55bf-4e4d-a79f-27aff377571a" pid="pcrncAVof0ebKY7TBYIKDQ" hash="Ugw0BQ">Stand Strong and Immovable in Family</h3>
        <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.f2"><p pid="ms581JO2ak2e5EWj45Bnrw" hash="w7CYFw">Second, Latter-day Saint women must be strong and immovable in family. They can and should do families better than anyone else. We, as disciples of Christ, can and should be the very best in the world at upholding, nourishing, and protecting families. We do this as we:</p><ol class="number" guid="c0b90856-b14b-4ec5-863d-3d27a4a4f909"><li guid="f4f3caaf-f5cf-4581-b5fa-69a6875a5d4b" pid="FfXTTyJVdk6UiJDYvFNvsA" hash="3xrPdQ">
            <span class="label">1.</span>
            <p guid="b081d1c0-c07c-44cd-9f16-917e5d11d48d" pid="OVujHhM_e0uIVBZqBAV6nA" hash="kkPNMA">Understand and defend the divine roles of women.</p>
          </li><li guid="afab7130-2ae6-49fa-ad1f-503f4cb05838" pid="xzSi-XthLk-5tMwBd60cMA" hash="uO0p2Q">
            <span class="label">2.</span>
            <p guid="7c316872-29ae-400d-8283-61a878de9e7d" pid="md0cv4VqYUmsLxyHXkenyg" hash="ZTN1BQ">Embrace the blessings of the priesthood.</p>
          </li><li guid="ec4ada70-675b-49d1-b708-527a54b0b6bf" pid="aSosFormbkWtpe3wnot36w" hash="ZaKnLw">
            <span class="label">3.</span>
            <p guid="198f87a3-5fac-4cb6-b629-fddfd601335d" pid="Vg8jIovXyEWYnE1x4avTtw" hash="WjWXrg">Form eternal families.</p>
          </li><li guid="859d5ead-a838-480f-80a5-4c7e95fed5e4" pid="w8LvrQXGgECrLyoDxKZhDg" hash="WC4bzQ">
            <span class="label">4.</span>
            <p guid="2b87d2e0-55cf-499f-87b4-0d605b66c8ac" pid="bcB0r6sIZUCajm-Hh5tG4Q" hash="0PT29w">Maintain strong marriages.</p>
          </li><li guid="029ab742-85a3-4d5e-9be6-36bbe58f15c0" pid="RrriCq_570OHefpjLF5Pyg" hash="LvSv_Q">
            <span class="label">5.</span>
            <p guid="a29c7781-0ea2-4a96-b2d3-876e1fdb63d2" pid="RPwMA6cB9062OUHyyxHctg" hash="saKQsQ">Bear and rear children.</p>
          </li><li guid="aab230ad-7bca-465b-ad06-0b730f31f4f5" pid="btFKfXdTlUCYGdAtTuuV8A" hash="pKbU3Q">
            <span class="label">6.</span>
            <p guid="a8a3b793-8e3a-4feb-ab63-60e5a347e6fb" pid="yVc3ZU30fkycS6G3ZMrtfQ" hash="SSweTQ">Express love for and nurture family members.</p>
          </li><li guid="1a38d4df-7a17-410b-b94d-9edada137045" pid="12AeuXj-SUqUJZTp2H_4ag" hash="ngzyAA">
            <span class="label">7.</span>
            <p guid="d8da0f51-e32d-4f32-bcda-861bbf8bcfae" pid="zLZvZtfBl0aGCHzV-i3W_w" hash="yuqpHQ">Accept responsibility to prepare a righteous rising generation.</p>
          </li><li guid="9c1e48d0-9f3b-416c-bda1-d4dbf8b04ad7" pid="N-e4yZL9oUm_JlREwyKO-A" hash="9Za18w">
            <span class="label">8.</span>
            <p guid="8fdaa458-b844-41ba-bb15-15abe6e491be" pid="8zNyIgCa50qXNutdmA7P_w" hash="1bnheA">Know, live, and defend the doctrine of the family.</p>
          </li><li guid="d8f78a66-6c7f-404e-a877-c40645932b42" pid="A1CHKJxa10KnT1YpsU0Cqw" hash="b2wYNg">
            <span class="label">9.</span>
            <p guid="08d7175a-1755-4375-95d1-4f5bb22d86da" pid="lsw7gF4BUkauNDeNEm5rKA" hash="eoBRqg">Search out and perform temple ordinances for extended family members.</p>
          </li></ol></div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="B-7CFaYWvk6BoA_WfYaLSQ" hash="iqbTeQ">As a disciple of Jesus Christ, <span class="emphasis">every</span> woman in this Church is given the responsibility for upholding, nurturing, and protecting families. Women have distinct assignments given to them from before the foundation of the world. And as a covenant-keeping Latter-day Saint woman, you know that raising your voice in defense of the doctrine of the family<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> is critical to the strength of families the world over.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="E-buccC9eEWQCnnwCeUd9w" hash="a2eu6A">Knowing and defending the divine roles of women is so important in a world where women are bombarded with false messages about their identity. Popular media figures on the radio and television set themselves up as authorities and spokespersons for women. While these media messages may contain elements of truth, most preach a gospel of individual fulfillment and self-worship, often misleading women regarding their true identity and worth. These voices offer a counterfeit happiness, and as a result, many women are miserable, lonely, and confused.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="riDUT81fQ0iSVKLBYe177A" hash="CReADA">The only place Latter-day Saint women will learn the whole and complete truth about their indispensable role in the plan of happiness is in this Church and its doctrine. We know that in the great premortal conflict we sided with our Savior, Jesus Christ, to preserve our potential to belong to eternal families. We know we are daughters of God, and we know what we are to do. Women find true happiness when they understand and delight in their unique role within the plan of salvation. The things women can and should do very best are championed and taught without apology here. We believe in the formation of eternal families. That means we believe in getting married. We know that the commandment to multiply and replenish the earth remains in force. That means we believe in having children. We have faith that with the Lord’s help we can be successful in rearing and teaching children. These are vital responsibilities in the plan of happiness, and when women embrace those roles with all their hearts, they are happy! Knowing and defending the truth about families is the privilege of <span class="emphasis">every</span> sister in this Church.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="8aSILUl46k--yHKepPqbAg" hash="x1FTOQ">Because families are eternal, we cannot afford to be casual or complacent about those relationships. Much of the great work of this society in the past has been centered in helping Latter-day Saint women strengthen families, with emphasis on improving our nurturing skills—homemaking skills, parenting skills, and marriage skills. Families mean work, but they are our great work—and we are not afraid of work. This is what we do best; no one does families better than the sisters of this Relief Society. We uphold, nourish, and protect them.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.t4" guid="4b9ecd6b-303f-422b-872c-56cfdbcc1730">
        <h3 class="title" guid="231552b1-d6ff-4756-bfbe-5651368d1474" pid="LK0RGlhnCkGj1OkOtvzhBA" hash="QaEfiA">Stand Strong and Immovable in Relief</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="cZ94jxzkOEOrC6G6l7mTPw" hash="OQ-HTQ">
          <span class="pageBreak" page-number="111"></span>Third, Latter-day Saint women must be strong and immovable in relief. We are a <span class="emphasis">Relief</span> Society, and we should be the best women in the world at providing relief. This has been our special province from the beginning. The word <span class="emphasis">relief</span> means “to lift up, lighten.” It means “a raising [up].” “The notion is ‘to raise (someone) out of trouble.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Our service and the relief that we offer are a sign that we are the Lord’s disciples and we are members of His true restored Church. It is a privilege to be part of this worldwide organization for women, whose name describes what we are meant to do: provide <span class="emphasis">relief.</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="0LEtdZAku02uh2XeL2Kd5A" hash="34XH8w">Joseph Smith said that the women of this Church were organized to provide for “the relief of the poor, the destitute, the widow and the orphan, and for the exercise of all benevolent purposes”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> and “not only to relieve the poor, but to save souls.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> That relief effort was further defined by Elder John A. Widtsoe as “relief of poverty, relief of illness, relief of doubt, relief of ignorance—relief of all that hinders the joy and progress of woman.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="ozakbBZCGU2AW3rOXZ6kcw" hash="tvGSiQ">Notwithstanding the important relief efforts of the past, the greatest and most important work for the women of this Church still lies ahead. The earth must be prepared to receive the Lord Jesus Christ, and we must help with this preparation in the midst of wars, turmoil, natural calamities, and an increase of evil. There has not been a time in the history of the world when a full-scale relief effort was more needed. Because we are disciples of Jesus Christ and we have made covenants with Him, we are already committed by covenant to participate in that relief effort.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="yVnWAtoj2UCA6Nxlki9ICQ" hash="Gd4Emw">You are each unique and precious. Each of you has your own burdens and challenges, which give you the blessing of turning to the Lord for help. We also have the opportunity to assist the Lord by providing relief for others, which is the greatest, fastest solution to loneliness and hopelessness and a sure way to obtain the companionship of the Spirit. All we need to do to start offering relief is get on our knees and ask, “Who needs my help?” Every sister—married or single, young or old—is needed in this relief effort, and it is what we should do better than anyone else.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.t5" guid="b989128f-b891-4e97-a2b0-3465e1a1d9c3">
        <h3 class="title" guid="ffd2f8f5-1e6b-4c01-bc53-ec10405570aa" pid="N-qJCekcR06y71Qy9qxGdg" hash="oHxfBg">Strong and Immovable Leaders</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="lnEivgvQTkON4_RpHPyS7A" hash="joSGxA">Now, some thoughts for you great Relief Society presidencies, who serve so faithfully. You have an exciting responsibility and hold a sacred trust as you carry out the work of Relief Society. Yours is the obligation to help Latter-day Saint women excel in <span class="emphasis">faith, family,</span> and <span class="emphasis">relief.</span> You will help the gospel become a great and compelling interest to the women of the Church. You will help the women perfect homemaking, parenting, and marriage skills so they can fully live the gospel in their own homes.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="_JvXjVmgGUG7tJHoRUhCJA" hash="Ja2dcQ">Every called and set apart Relief Society leader has the right and authority to be guided in fulfilling her inspired assignment to best meet the needs of those she serves.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> You will receive the help of the Holy <span class="pageBreak" page-number="112"></span>Spirit as you focus on essentials and will be given the courage to forego the frivolous.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="2YaRClESAECyJwplkiQ6mg" hash="La9EGQ">Every leader knows that families are being hit hard by the storms of this world, storms such as addictions, debt, unfaithfulness, and disobedience. The Savior saw our day as “the beginning of sorrows,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> when many would be deceived. He told of wars and rumors of wars, famines, earthquakes, and pestilences. This describes the world we live in today, and it is essential that the women of this Church take hold of their responsibility to be prepared in all things.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="BDQisIuOk0aadMh4b5gyKg" hash="fdb-RA">As leaders of Relief Society, you can help every sister in every home in every ward and branch become self-reliant. They should be laying up a store of money, food, and skills, which will sustain them and their families in perilous times. The Church has provided you great helps, such as self-reliance pamphlets, to get you started. This is part of your work.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="2gsQuk77DUqr1YM0mYdY0w" hash="qLC4Eg">You have the privilege to counsel in unity with priesthood leaders to plan a defense and refuge against those storms and tailor a relief effort for the specific needs of your people. The friendship and sociality that make life so much sweeter will be a natural by-product of our efforts. Focusing on relief will always build sociality, whereas focusing on sociality may not always bring relief.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="Gj-kpc8l3kmt1IrzbM8sCw" hash="zizOmg">When we gather for any purpose under the banner of Relief Society, we must spend our precious time and consecrated funds for the purpose of helping sisters do what we should do best. In our Sunday Relief Society meetings, openings should be brief and invite the Spirit to be with us. We need every possible minute to study the gospel together so we can be best in our responsibilities. All Relief Society conferences, activities, gatherings, and meetings must focus on helping sisters do what they should do best. President Hinckley’s plea to us is:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="9iKr57qFZEWdyqt4OpEiVw" hash="pWrMuw">“We have a greater challenge than we realize. …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="uVwmMN_vUEWeKWkLCXjpoA" hash="OupenA">“… ‘Do the best you can.’ But I want to emphasize that it be the very best. … We are capable of doing so much better. …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="fgRGg6kESU2K5260onExEA" hash="DPCk4A">“… We must get on our knees and plead with the Lord for help and strength and direction. We must then stand on our feet and move forward.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.p" pid="ZCZ0KZ0oMUqHO_WYiHoZ4g" hash="PoSXzQ">My dear sisters, our prophet, whom I sustain with all my heart, has said that there is a better way than the way of the world. He has called upon the women of the Church to stand together for righteousness. He has said that if we are united and speak with one voice, our strength will be incalculable. I have expressed to him my confidence that the women of this Church will stand strong and immovable in our faith in Jesus Christ and His restored gospel; strong and immovable in upholding, nourishing, and protecting our families; and strong and immovable in providing relief. May the Lord bless us as we do this most essential work of women is my prayer in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable.f3"><title>Notes</title><ol class="number" guid=""><li guid="95e3a105-21e6-41b5-8c34-8a05095a4b7c" pid="M21FRMPqj0SAZy8nGfnF5Q" hash="INOgmQ1">
        <span class="label">1.</span>
        <p guid="9980d755-b86f-44ca-a6bc-c4be19ca4529" pid="WnacM1IPxUetaCVkMo29sw" hash="Y9Yxfg">“Standing Strong and Immovable,” <span class="emphasis">Worldwide Leadership Training Meeting,</span> Jan. 10, 2004, 20.</p>
      </li><li guid="b5dd277f-e92b-421f-ba31-ceb331e8db9b" pid="WvNbOB54UkqaFLmr5ls8Qw" hash="wew37A1">
        <span class="label">2.</span>
        <p guid="9bd63195-e33b-4ab9-acbd-f56aea5fcb90" pid="XHj_bjv0eEGFkOhZdr086Q" hash="E3Is2w">
          <span class="emphasis">Worldwide Leadership Training Meeting,</span> Jan. 10, 2004, 20.</p>
      </li><li guid="e4cfb93d-f0d2-4609-937c-598aca9aeeb3" pid="EUNPDlOQfEaDflXZIkM6wQ" hash="75kY2A1">
        <span class="label">3.</span>
        <p guid="93543fd4-bc8d-4d44-96af-c5cd80b41b8c" pid="YxgLH9f-7ESheiXdlXhg8g" hash="JUZHtg">See “The Family: A Proclamation to the World,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> Oct. 2004, 49; <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1995, 102.</p>
      </li><li guid="78f47413-675b-4b2c-8c0e-1ed0e151b156" pid="_LaL1TkL4k667eUnfj8SuA" hash="2BoriA1">
        <span class="label">4.</span>
        <p guid="9e7b0ffa-18c0-4cad-a1f3-2f61ea7f0eb0" pid="YXuZrte_FEmRzAgb0C1YUA" hash="7RXlag">See Online Etymology Dictionary, “relief,” “relieve,” www.etymonline.com.</p>
      </li><li guid="45dbacde-67f6-42fb-a294-4815f422a5b2" pid="fyrETZlcCUSAbb-tWgfoEQ" hash="JfyXNA1">
        <span class="label">5.</span>
        <p guid="1d3efd3f-643b-40fe-93d9-0541094f9fee" pid="FAL7dZujrUSm6XJPzklEuQ" hash="1NoVWA">
          <span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 4:567.</p>
      </li><li guid="e4883bd6-6ba1-42be-8b12-f12ea2d4b7ca" pid="Pmjt6ROhHk-yuryub1K9Nw" hash="uTQWew1">
        <span class="label">6.</span>
        <p guid="a8c8e51c-5773-4c25-970d-0bfe3b37f885" pid="sKg17dS5LEKmriLwASgyDw" hash="N5TVOg">
          <span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 5:25.</p>
      </li><li guid="eb86932f-9588-4b96-b6ea-4c935ebc4301" pid="cFtfSwT590G77A1SEiJI3w" hash="-Sa4kg1">
        <span class="label">7.</span>
        <p guid="2dbb4216-ba5f-4b05-bdd0-32d00355ef9a" pid="L8XGkoJoyUi4Qb243UhyNQ" hash="yqp7LA">
          <span class="emphasis">Evidences and Reconciliations,</span> arr. G. Homer Durham, 3 vols. in 1 (1960), 308.</p>
      </li><li guid="5f3bfe74-90d4-4c96-81d5-ceac37291783" pid="ViXOnRWrEEeI0SD3XfA-JA" hash="fyzPWw1">
        <span class="label">8.</span>
        <p guid="694e4e74-d9b6-41a4-a2d0-22d573b8cf37" pid="Fge1vQZ2WUGFzN3SLk-zng" hash="aTjz4w">See Richard G. Scott, “The Doctrinal Foundation of the Auxiliaries,” <span class="emphasis">Worldwide Leadership Training Meeting,</span> Jan. 10, 2004, 8; see also <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Aug. 2005, 67.</p>
      </li><li guid="9ce0e7de-2705-4dc5-86b7-e36709ad3cb0" pid="t6MBRZ_xyU2x8nr0awFwxQ" hash="dU_5nw1">
        <span class="label">9.</span>
        <p guid="6e9ed487-6b76-4089-b87e-e8cb772b6be7" pid="F-njNqd47U6G0ZPHPoevXw" hash="658F8g">
          <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/24.8" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 24:8</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/24.3-7" class="scriptureRef">vv. 3–7</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-tim/4.1-2" class="scriptureRef">1 Timothy 4:1–2</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/3.1-5" class="scriptureRef">2 Timothy 3:1–5</a>.</p>
      </li><li guid="9b78366a-cdca-44c6-a25b-0ddba7c609d2" pid="IBGcna1IxkmOO61IR_Aceg" hash="vhOirQ1">
        <span class="label">10.</span>
        <p guid="6c7868ef-f06b-4c40-8db6-ccdf87cb1d02" pid="OcCBruvKOEq6KWcP73tYSQ" hash="2Kf30w">
          <span class="emphasis">Worldwide Leadership Training Meeting,</span> Jan. 10, 2004, 21.</p>
      </li></ol></div>
    <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/BeckJB_03.jpg" alt="Julie B. Beck" guid="ba341c38-3dc1-4a62-bbd2-3fe973aca060" pid="pEEGcRlZ1kuBS1YiyVg8Vw" hash="4hAyHA1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="ba341c38-3dc1-4a62-bbd2-3fe973aca060"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/10/what-latter-day-saint-women-do-best-stand-strong-and-immovable</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2007-general-relief-society-meeting/2007-09-0010-julie-b-beck-64k-eng.mp3" length="15648697" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2007 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mothers Who Know</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know?lang=eng</link>
      <description>There is eternal influence and power in motherhood.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008332_000_028" doc-version="2" hash="LMT8Bg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="RH6DP5jxNU2gFOIDuYnqJg" hash="XTxEmQ">Mothers Who Know</h1><p class="authorName" guid="6d9c1d63-34fd-4f70-a560-8d52351a12d5" pid="FOk9_JYtFEaEnpJMmQ-n0A" hash="6A7qTw">Julie B. Beck</p><p class="kicker" pid="uoFQjni7xUCCW0KQIN9ynw" hash="taFhOw">There is eternal influence and power in motherhood.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="2a22e35a-6830-46ab-a1e9-17afc4c9aa36">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/BeckJB_03.jpg" alt="Julie B. Beck" guid="1718fc45-daf8-468c-bbdd-b13e9da92de1" pid="Bd0w6yPS-U2ydJjesc39dg" hash="4hAyHA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.p" pid="RffuvTxT9EqDlvW7Ggk9cA" hash="Ol2KYw">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="76"></span>In the Book of Mormon we read about 2,000 exemplary young men who were exceedingly valiant, courageous, and strong. “Yea, they were men of truth and soberness, for they had been taught to keep the commandments of God and to walk uprightly before him” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/53.21" class="scriptureRef">Alma 53:21</a>). These faithful young men paid tribute to their mothers. They said, “Our mothers knew it” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/56.48" class="scriptureRef">Alma 56:48</a>). I would suspect that the mothers of Captain Moroni, Mosiah, Mormon, and other great leaders also knew.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.p" pid="vjLoRXP8W0ekQgVC7eqd2w" hash="tpO0xQ">The responsibility mothers have today has never required more vigilance. More than at any time in the history of the world, we need mothers who know. Children are being born into a world where they “wrestle not against flesh and blood, but against principalities, against powers, against the rulers of the darkness of this world, against spiritual wickedness in high places” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/6.12" class="scriptureRef">Ephesians 6:12</a>).<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> However, mothers need not fear. When mothers know who they are and who God is and have made covenants with Him, they will have great power and influence for good on their children.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.t2" guid="6f695e57-ef8a-46a2-8a36-c5d645c9d6fb">
        <h3 class="title" guid="5fc55f34-706e-4187-9e3b-b0a11f6cd084" pid="GAzhbv6sHE6xAN58NBhekA" hash="2rl2aA">Mothers Who Know Bear Children</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.p" pid="FJ_3Ek6FJ0CCRz1M24dg0A" hash="D7Wrvg">Mothers who know desire to bear children. Whereas in many cultures in the world children are “becoming less valued,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> in the culture of the gospel we still believe in having children. Prophets, seers, and revelators who were sustained at this conference have declared that “God’s commandment for His children to multiply and replenish the earth remains in force.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> President Ezra Taft Benson taught that young couples should not postpone having children and that “in the eternal perspective, children—not possessions, not position, not prestige—are our greatest jewels.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.p" pid="eK5CHZijLEOWXYYkQ-pMTw" hash="yHnnBg">Faithful daughters of God desire children. In the scriptures we read of Eve (see <a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/4.26" class="scriptureRef">Moses 4:26</a>), Sarah (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/17.16" class="scriptureRef">Genesis 17:16</a>), Rebekah (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/24.60" class="scriptureRef">Genesis 24:60</a>), and Mary (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/11.13-20" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 11:13–20</a>), who were foreordained to be mothers before children were born to them. Some women are not given the responsibility of bearing children in mortality, but just as Hannah of the Old Testament prayed fervently for her child (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/1-sam/1.11" class="scriptureRef">1 Samuel 1:11</a>), the value women place on motherhood in this life and the attributes of motherhood they attain here will rise with them in the Resurrection (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/130.18" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 130:18</a>). Women who desire and work toward that blessing in this life are promised they will receive it for all eternity, and eternity is much, much longer than mortality. There is eternal influence and power in motherhood.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.t3" guid="2e9d0085-4a2b-47f4-b3cb-555d543d3c12">
        <h3 class="title" guid="9d4f28b9-5194-4b10-82bb-384948ae4c5d" pid="bSmmtw5ULEShe5BVtUz0Eg" hash="HbzEWw">Mothers Who Know Honor Sacred Ordinances and Covenants</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.p" pid="ujr0jE20zUuMpMN-_hv5hA" hash="7AShsg">Mothers who know honor sacred ordinances and covenants. I have visited sacrament meetings in some of the poorest places on the earth where mothers have dressed with great care in their Sunday best despite walking for miles on dusty streets and using worn-out public transportation. They bring daughters in clean and ironed dresses with hair brushed to perfection; their sons wear white shirts and ties and have missionary haircuts. These mothers know they are going to sacrament meeting, where covenants are renewed. These mothers have made and honor temple covenants. They know that if they are not pointing their children to the temple, they are not pointing them toward desired eternal goals. These mothers have influence and power.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.t4" guid="3439c651-4ccf-4b96-a5f9-7490f2ad34db">
        <h3 class="title" guid="7ac4c586-4b5d-4fae-bb58-ed93bdd12c75" pid="1Y3CDaukY0-HDXdKz3rhuw" hash="CBPm1w">Mothers Who Know Are Nurturers</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.p" pid="FBcczv3JNEiv9Do6Zh13fA" hash="mzOffg">Mothers who know are nurturers. This is their special assignment and role under the plan of happiness.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> To nurture means to cultivate, care for, and make grow. Therefore, mothers who know create a climate for spiritual and temporal growth in their homes. Another word for <span class="emphasis">nurturing </span><span class="pageBreak" page-number="77"></span>is <span class="emphasis">homemaking.</span> Homemaking includes cooking, washing clothes and dishes, and keeping an orderly home. Home is where women have the most power and influence; therefore, Latter-day Saint women should be the best homemakers in the world. Working beside children in homemaking tasks creates opportunities to teach and model qualities children should emulate. Nurturing mothers are knowledgeable, but all the education women attain will avail them nothing if they do not have the skill to make a home that creates a climate for spiritual growth. Growth happens best in a “house of order,” and women should pattern their homes after the Lord’s house (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/109.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 109</a>). Nurturing requires organization, patience, love, and work. Helping growth occur through nurturing is truly a powerful and influential role bestowed on women.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.t5" guid="d7d59367-ec8d-4823-8974-362688a8cc8d">
        <h3 class="title" guid="6badb7fe-6cc1-42ed-951c-8fd9888e99e6" pid="Za5pWl4sAECGmVmhmwX5aQ" hash="zz61PA">Mothers Who Know Are Leaders</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.p" pid="z2-_ZvwSrEmrZ3eG1R_UJA" hash="irF5JQ">Mothers who know are leaders. In equal partnership with their husbands, they lead a great and eternal organization. These mothers plan for the future of their organization. They plan for missions, temple marriages, and education. They plan for prayer, scripture study, and family home evening. Mothers who know build children into future leaders and are the primary examples of what leaders look like. They do not abandon their plan by succumbing to social pressure and worldly models of parenting. These wise mothers who know are selective about their own activities and involvement to conserve their limited strength in order to maximize their influence where it matters most.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.t6" guid="f2bdbfa7-f88e-4eb5-b440-dcc95d161b4d">
        <h3 class="title" guid="b41cd9fd-d58b-4518-8b15-add0c77e4301" pid="c3viTtIla0GX9UDF8_R7YA" hash="TYidCQ">Mothers Who Know Are Teachers</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.p" pid="K06O1nRXNUmg_gMVIg-e8g" hash="wKV7pQ">Mothers who know are always teachers. Since they are not babysitters, they are never off duty. A well-taught friend told me that he did not learn anything at church that he had not already learned at home. His parents used family scripture study, prayer, family home evening, mealtimes, and other gatherings to teach. Think of the power of our future missionary force if mothers considered their homes as a pre–missionary training center. Then the doctrines of the gospel taught in the MTC would be a review and not a revelation. That is influence; that is power.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.t7" guid="47360e3b-d565-4751-b9a5-116cffc2ed6a">
        <h3 class="title" guid="c8cb479b-3ad8-47d9-83d9-78317c368f78" pid="lp6SfaIZfUaJZCdFLBHPKw" hash="CSKf_A">Mothers Who Know Do Less</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.p" pid="ZV3nPrLS1UCbtpOuy2Rb4w" hash="naZIHQ">Mothers who know do less. They permit less of what will not bear good fruit eternally. They allow less media in their homes, less distraction, less activity that draws their children away from their home. Mothers who know are willing to live on less and consume less of the world’s goods in order to spend more time with their children—more <span class="pageBreak" page-number="78"></span>time eating together, more time working together, more time reading together, more time talking, laughing, singing, and exemplifying. These mothers choose carefully and do not try to choose it all. Their goal is to prepare a rising generation of children who will take the gospel of Jesus Christ into the entire world. Their goal is to prepare future fathers and mothers who will be builders of the Lord’s kingdom for the next 50 years. That is influence; that is power.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.t8" guid="0f787a60-19aa-4062-b11d-4dc1b33c39d3">
        <h3 class="title" guid="6d04a911-14fc-4b05-9fd2-774647252da9" pid="Go82zAYd50aCAgDC3E3Xeg" hash="9pfZWw">Mothers Who Know Stand Strong and Immovable</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.p" pid="rOnAjfKkGEab2UooBMmk2g" hash="S2ijBQ">Who will prepare this righteous generation of sons and daughters? Latter-day Saint women will do this—women who know and love the Lord and bear testimony of Him, women who are strong and immovable and who do not give up during difficult and discouraging times. We are led by an inspired prophet of God who has called upon the women of the Church to “stand strong and immovable for that which is correct and proper under the plan of the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> He has asked us to “begin in [our] own homes”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> to teach children the ways of truth. Latter-day Saint women should be the very best in the world at upholding, nurturing, and protecting families. I have every confidence that our women will do this and will come to be known as mothers who “knew” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/56.48" class="scriptureRef">Alma 56:48</a>). In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know.f1"><title>Notes</title><ol class="number" guid=""><li guid="bce253bd-d639-4db6-b479-60aebc871364" pid="3AKmYcO6NkSQyIclWipzFg" hash="DSb_oA1">
        <span class="label">1.</span>
        <p guid="2d6e90fa-b5c6-4f22-8bc1-5658989daf55" pid="t_fL5ultakqhj5sAApB-8A" hash="eG0UOA">See Gordon B. Hinckley, “Standing Strong and Immovable,” <span class="emphasis">Worldwide Leadership Training Meeting,</span> Jan. 10, 2004, 21.</p>
      </li><li guid="e69d5848-905e-4a58-969f-56ced00938c7" pid="x9YR5ugBkkSOS36x25TXjg" hash="kwxu8g1">
        <span class="label">2.</span>
        <p guid="a7cd5254-5653-4ebe-96e7-1fc7a628bf25" pid="kxd3f-AjXEOCE5QIVuCX_Q" hash="QpvYbg">James E. Faust, “Challenges Facing the Family,” <span class="emphasis">Worldwide Leadership Training Meeting,</span> Jan. 10, 2004, 2.</p>
      </li><li guid="7153ba7f-1df0-4d5b-b1c7-a8c40e6744ee" pid="mbDLueKRBEaKgwD4BCQsIQ" hash="AsRaKg1">
        <span class="label">3.</span>
        <p guid="dc850032-9b83-49df-aae0-acf645e65d3a" pid="RddCccdvIESo9tRsi2PVFA" hash="vRzK7g">“The Family: A Proclamation to the World,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> Oct. 2004, 49; <span class="emphasis">Ensign, </span>Nov. 1995, 102.</p>
      </li><li guid="c3d8c101-5436-440e-adad-a3f27a20861b" pid="ysGwoiF0iUiwVsQHGuGCgQ" hash="ZnkLvw1">
        <span class="label">4.</span>
        <p guid="9fa5d3f6-a9e7-4d7c-b386-d7f8c2d60529" pid="mzHsPVvq9U-qAxd2xKv0rg" hash="WlvQvA">
          <span class="emphasis">To the Mothers in Zion</span> (pamphlet, 1987), 3.</p>
      </li><li guid="3e47cb3e-7cee-451b-ae01-c6926c617e08" pid="8O4khnPiME2zovtKJI53VQ" hash="4zPBIQ1">
        <span class="label">5.</span>
        <p guid="c9daa727-fb2f-4e01-a865-cdcfea7b57f6" pid="S4e5pYkpKkSpSS0KWSuiNA" hash="UdvTqg">See “The Family: A Proclamation to the World.”</p>
      </li><li guid="afc35f5c-1c78-4bc4-a731-f1e552a3be8e" pid="_kWLSf6WrE2hZU2Gnz0Ymw" hash="gngLsw1">
        <span class="label">6.</span>
        <p guid="c87f7ddd-2dfc-4272-bb91-9afc2461e199" pid="3g1t7FdXMUG5BF6yXoLsZg" hash="pRi3pQ">Gordon B. Hinckley, <span class="emphasis">Worldwide Leadership Training Meeting,</span> Jan. 10, 2004, 20.</p>
      </li><li guid="9a0e45b6-d1e2-47ed-9510-e37474a5c4d1" pid="Tbi86GK7uE6EISxiCnQWWw" hash="FEgMxA1">
        <span class="label">7.</span>
        <p guid="a5dfa128-d14d-453b-8a29-ac62af510d3d" pid="5D-c7bx-o06xuyuSZ6B8pw" hash="pRi3pQ1">Gordon B. Hinckley, <span class="emphasis">Worldwide Leadership Training Meeting,</span> Jan. 10, 2004, 20.</p>
      </li></ol></div>
    <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/BeckJB_03.jpg" alt="Julie B. Beck" guid="1718fc45-daf8-468c-bbdd-b13e9da92de1" pid="lWZOF1JX4k6b7nZIXlXhVw" hash="4hAyHA1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="1718fc45-daf8-468c-bbdd-b13e9da92de1"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/10/mothers-who-know</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2007-general-conference/2007-10-4040-julie-b-beck-64k-eng.mp3" length="4114346" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2007 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fulfilling the Purpose of Relief Society</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Relief Society was established by the Lord to organize, teach, and inspire His daughters to prepare for the blessings of eternal life.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00009501_000_036" doc-version="2" hash="E4w9sg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="xW3X6uXitEOnm5jC-lPQyg" hash="482yOA">Fulfilling the Purpose of Relief Society</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="mqItNqbuvECyCwVDBnAarg" hash="6A7qTw">Julie B. Beck</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="lJVIQOlJmE2pLVSgMOOCAQ" hash="YthtYQ">Relief Society was established by the Lord to organize, teach, and inspire His daughters to prepare for the blessings of eternal life.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p1" pid="av_R3Eyu8kqzLkHfDPgJIA" hash="ciR99Q">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="108"></span>Our dear sisters, what a beautiful sight you are and how grateful we are to be with you. Our love and appreciation for you are profound.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p2" pid="Ifb3lqbj4E6rmUJYrf6hNw" hash="_E9h2A">As a Relief Society general presidency, we have had the opportunity this past year to visit you around the world. We have counseled with you in Germany, Denmark, Australia, and Ghana. We have prayed with you in Singapore, Hong Kong, India, and Sri Lanka. We have been uplifted and edified with you in Brazil, Chile, Puerto Rico, Canada, and the United States.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p3" pid="Wd6JRAEZ3EyhsfHdBU4kjg" hash="5RqSUA">We rejoice in the knowledge that you are going about doing good, as the Savior did. You are doing a magnificent work. Yet we feel impressed to say that there is more to be done. We have sought inspiration from the Lord to know how to assist the priesthood in building up the kingdom of God on the earth. It is time for Relief Society to fulfill its purpose as never before. To move forward and achieve what the Lord desires, we must clearly understand the purpose of Relief Society.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p4" pid="pOQk2Wv3Y0K8DtYfer6ypw" hash="ipHOtA">I will begin by reviewing some of the history of Relief Society in order to explain why Relief Society was established. I will then outline three responsibilities that every Relief Society sister shares. Finally, I will explain how the Lord expects us to fulfill the divine commission that we have received, both at an individual level and an organizational level.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="-MO-ve26dEen0QbYUda1DQ" hash="-8R1JQ">I. Why Relief Society Was Established</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p5" pid="ezMDRlPQcEaHR02Nu6TPjg" hash="qwB1Sg">It is impossible to understand why we have an organization for women in the Church without having an understanding of the Restoration of the gospel of Jesus Christ. The Lord, knowing about the calamities that would come to pass in these latter days, spoke to His servant Joseph Smith Jr. “and gave him commandments; …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p6" pid="xM7YPg71YEuMm_Qr-TGxBQ" hash="xJaZbA">“That faith … might increase in the earth;</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p7" pid="mfZ-Rr_tPEy61Q_atCKmeg" hash="mI0XHQ">“That [His] everlasting covenant might be established;</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p8" pid="jsuVbMmmvUydQuBC33IJCg" hash="rh6XjA">“That the fulness of [His] gospel might be proclaimed by the weak and the simple unto the ends of the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p9" pid="bOEIN--kOEuCWBISYpU4IA" hash="fUSXQg">The work of the Lord is accomplished as His gospel is “preached unto every nation, and kindred, and tongue, and people”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> and as His everlasting covenant is established through the ordinances of the temple.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p10" pid="qZA5xsfhV0mwETtnyY-ZMg" hash="sRVrSw">Just as the Savior invited Mary and Martha of New Testament times<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> to participate in His work, women of this dispensation have an official commission to participate in the Lord’s work. From the earliest days of the Restoration, women were active in helping build up the Church by supporting missionary efforts, contributing to the construction of temples, and establishing communities where the Saints could worship together. The organization of Relief Society in 1842 mobilized the collective power of the women and their specific assignments to build the Lord’s kingdom, just as the organization of priesthood quorums gave men specific responsibilities.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p11" pid="gSe9tITTD0iPjZfHDHn4Ew" hash="1VRNgg">Since its organization, Relief Society has spread throughout the world and has been called “the largest, and by all measure, the greatest women’s organization on earth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> We know through the Prophet Joseph Smith that Relief Society was a formal part of the Restoration and that a similar organization for women existed in the Church anciently.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> President Joseph F. Smith taught that Relief Society was <span class="pageBreak" page-number="109"></span>“divinely made, divinely authorized, divinely instituted, divinely ordained of God,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> “according to the law of heaven,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> to help the Lord “bring to pass the … eternal life of man.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p12" pid="5dU1WM6260SUd2I9RD1xwg" hash="YPesXg">Through Relief Society, women have an official role in the Church with great responsibilities, “including working in the temple and teaching the gospel.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Further, Relief Society is to help women “plant and make grow … a testimony of [Jesus] Christ and of the Gospel,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> “strengthen the family and the home,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> and “attend to all family duties.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> It has responsibility to take care of the “necessities of the poor, the sick and the needy,” but President Joseph F. Smith said that the larger part of its work is “to look after the spiritual welfare [and salvation] … of all the female members of the Church.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p13" pid="6FntzzKS5UWeXZMwfelrfg" hash="CLIMYw">To summarize, the purpose of Relief Society, as established by the Lord, is to organize, teach, and inspire His daughters to prepare them for the blessings of eternal life. I would like to say that again. The purpose of Relief Society, as established by the Lord, is to organize, teach, and inspire His daughters to prepare them for the blessings of eternal life.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="oNAyzVLVTEmM3U3KFjdEMA" hash="6f6oTg">II. Our Responsibilities</h3>
        <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.f2">
	  <p pid="B8uD6xBKTUyZG6tP_GKkTQ" hash="3qGCTw">To fulfill the purpose of Relief Society, the Lord has commissioned each Relief Society sister and the organization as a whole to:</p>
	  <ol class="number">
	    <li pid="_xPuWOkgxEmucPzg4ir8RQ" hash="CBS2Bg">
            <span class="label">1.</span>
            <p pid="czqsz7HkGEGVMaFqofG4qA" hash="pzl-hg">Increase in faith and personal righteousness.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="VGcXB628c0S5tcgyi87EVA" hash="3b6pzg">
            <span class="label">2.</span>
            <p pid="dGBh6AJ-6EC-Ko0ZoFPxZg" hash="yE67pA">Strengthen families and homes.</p>
          </li>
	    <li pid="tg7Hr3SFV0KXc8iLIIw8qQ" hash="Q9O0Jg">
            <span class="label">3.</span>
            <p pid="moTAaDhirkeHdCkTHCmrKg" hash="xQvOQg">Serve the Lord and His children.</p>
          </li>
	  </ol>
	</div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p14" pid="53SrD-clXkCVTVUIyJ5vbA" hash="8lHOjg">Each one of these responsibilities supports and reinforces the other two. When we increase our faith, the result of that effort strengthens our family. When we serve the Lord and His children, our faith and capacity for righteousness increase. The three responsibilities are inseparably connected. Let’s begin with the first responsibility.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p15" pid="x658oGhe3ka18jn9Kiuv4Q" hash="0UCTnQ">
          <span class="strong">1. Increase in faith and personal righteousness.</span> To do our part under the plan of the Lord, we are to increase our faith and personal righteousness. Membership in the Church requires faith, which we nourish throughout our lives with great “diligence, and patience, and long-suffering.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> In the common heritage we share, we have remarkable examples of faith in the early women of the Church. Early pioneer women were driven from homes and persecuted because of their faith. Others survived fires and floods. They crossed oceans and walked thousands of miles, tolerating dirt, illness, and near starvation to help build the Lord’s kingdom on <span class="pageBreak" page-number="110"></span>the earth. Many of them buried husbands, children, parents, and siblings along the way. Why did they do this? They did it because the fire of their faith burned in their souls. These remarkable women were not seeking fine clothing, greater leisure, large earthly mansions, or more possessions. Like you, they had a conviction and a testimony that the restored gospel of Jesus Christ was true and that the Lord needed them to do their part in establishing His kingdom on the earth. Their pursuit of personal righteousness was a daily effort to become more like the Savior through repentance, scripture study, prayer, obedience to commandments, and through seeking after everything “virtuous, lovely, or of good report or praiseworthy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p16" pid="Ctr8pkoOr0G_2d-iT_1iIA" hash="w6GSTw">
          <span class="strong">2. Strengthen families and homes.</span> Our second responsibility is to strengthen families and homes. Families worldwide are being assaulted and weakened by corrupt practices and false teachings. Therefore, whether we are married or single, old or young, we have a duty to defend and practice the truths found in “The Family: A Proclamation to the World.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p17" pid="C5j6YYbU5kCA1EOikwtEGQ" hash="twjufg">The First Presidency has counseled, “However worthy and appropriate other demands or activities may be, they must not be permitted to displace the divinely-appointed duties that only parents and families can adequately perform.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> Children being born now are growing up in an increasingly sinful world. Our homes are to be their refuge from the daily encounters they have with evil.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p18" pid="ZPM-hXshFkitvyRlodOB8Q" hash="NoehDw">Relief Society should be organized, aligned, and mobilized to strengthen families and help our homes to be sacred sanctuaries from the world. I learned this years ago when I was newly married. My parents, who had been my neighbors, announced that they would be moving to another part of the world. I had relied on my mother’s nurturing, wise, and encouraging example. Now she was going to be gone for a long time. This was before e-mail, fax machines, cell phones, and Web cameras, and mail delivery was notoriously slow. One day before she left, I sat weeping with her and asked, “Who will be my mother?” Mother thought carefully, and with the Spirit and power of revelation which comes to women of this kind, she said to me, “If I never come back, if you never see me again, if I’m never able to teach you another thing, you tie yourself to Relief Society. Relief Society will be your mother.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p19" pid="ir4lDXl5SkaMH-uHuXrx3g" hash="QQtC2g">Mother knew that if I was sick, the sisters would take care of me, and when I had my babies, they would help me. But my mother’s greatest hope was that the sisters in Relief Society would be powerful, spiritual leaders for me. I began from that time to learn abundantly from women of stature and faith.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p20" pid="S7Ut6qF6xE26vDRELUxRpg" hash="Ilxmzw">Three different women held the calling of Relief Society president in my wards during the years my parents were away. Alta Chamberlain invited me to teach time management and home organization to the other sisters, perhaps because she saw that I needed to improve those skills. Jeanne Horne encouraged me to complete my first serious personal study of the Book of Mormon. Norma Healey gave me my first assignments at the cannery and taught me much about service. These wonderful women understood the purpose of Relief Society.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p21" pid="kq9K-X9LkUi6AVzWdX23Wg" hash="Z_5RYg">
          <span class="strong">3. Serve the Lord and His children.</span> A third responsibility of all women of the Church is to serve the Lord and His children. It is interesting to me that during the years my mother was away, I served as the ward Primary president and later as the ward Young Women president. I was a member of the ward council, working under the direction of the bishopric. President Boyd K. Packer taught us that “just as [the service of many brethren in the Aaronic Priesthood] strengthens the Higher Priesthood, … to unselfishly render this service [in Young Women and Primary] is to show devotion to Relief Society.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> When we serve in another auxiliary, we are not released from the sisterhood of Relief Society. Because we do not go in or out of Relief Society, we are always connected to the purpose and responsibilities of Relief Society and are blessed by all opportunities to be examples and faith-filled shepherds to our Father’s children.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p22" pid="2SezYqMX506g-r7JmhDuxw" hash="mEjy6A">Relief Society has within its commission some of the most remarkable service opportunities on earth, which are available to <span class="emphasis">all</span> sisters. In my travels across the world, I have seen that the thousands upon thousands of you who do not currently have a husband or children are an incredible reservoir of faith, talent, and dedication. No one is better positioned than you to work in temples, serve missions, teach the rising generation, and help those who are downtrodden. The Lord <span class="emphasis">needs</span> you.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p23" pid="PZOVkdQdPUevRy8cggFjbw" hash="vEFQWw">
          <span class="pageBreak" page-number="111"></span>I have also marveled at the youth and energy of you who are just arriving in Relief Society from the Young Women program. I have seen how your hearts yearn to make a difference for good in the world. I often imagine the potential of what could be happening with family history work, for example, if you shared your technical skills with older sisters (like me!). We simply cannot afford to squander your youthful and energetic power by suggesting you sit by, watching older and more experienced women do all of the planning, organizing, and work of Relief Society.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="U3351dC1qUCUjMp4xLoRtQ" hash="Klm8fA">III. Fulfilling the Purpose</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p24" pid="r4YawzYlIk6W29DKkC4jdQ" hash="kejuQg">We can do the work of the Lord in His way when we seek, receive, and act on personal revelation. Without personal revelation, we cannot succeed. If we heed personal revelation, we cannot fail. The prophet Nephi instructs us that the Holy Ghost will show us “all things what [we] should do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> It was prophesied that in the latter days the Lord would pour out His Spirit upon His handmaids.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> This will happen as we allow ourselves to be still enough and quiet enough to listen to the voice of the Spirit. Elder Neal A. Maxwell taught us that receiving revelation for our calling and in our personal lives “requires serious mental effort on our part. … Revelation is not a matter of pushing buttons, but of pushing ourselves, often aided by fasting, scripture study, and personal pondering.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p25" pid="twwdn5WkF0ilLEEhYMqv5w" hash="DAZuPg">“Most of all, revelation requires us to have a sufficient degree of personal righteousness, so that on occasion revelation may come to the righteous, unsolicited.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="vqiGZj1Bt0GgTn8AjCB6CA" hash="SD_huQ">IV. Conclusion</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p26" pid="8WacuqKyfEOazu3m0Eyueg" hash="eWY7dQ">President Spencer W. Kimball stated a number of years ago that “there is a power in this organization that has not yet been fully exercised to strengthen the homes of Zion and build the Kingdom of God—nor will it until both the sisters and the priesthood catch the vision of Relief Society.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> Relief Society was established by the Lord to organize, teach, and inspire His daughters to prepare for the blessings of eternal life. Our aim is to support the women of the Church in their individual responsibilities by ensuring that every meeting, every lesson, and every activity we undertake helps them increase in faith and personal righteousness, strengthen their families and their homes, and serve the Lord and His children.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society.p27" pid="ATkwk26lrUy3fcOfcnnCqg" hash="lhk-cQ">The only way we can accomplish this is by seeking, receiving, and acting on personal revelation. The real power in this great worldwide sisterhood lies within each woman. Though we may see ourselves as weak and simple, we all share a noble heritage and can develop a faith that is equal to that of remarkable, faithful women who have gone before us. We have a vital role to play in helping build the kingdom of God and preparing for the Lord’s coming. In fact, the Lord cannot accomplish His work without the help of His daughters. Because of that, the Lord expects us to increase our offering. He expects us to fulfill the purpose of Relief Society as never before. I am grateful to testify of the truthfulness of the restored gospel of Jesus Christ and of a living prophet today who leads His work. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2008/10/fulfilling-the-purpose-of-relief-society</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2008-general-relief-society-meeting/2008-09-0010-julie-b-beck-64k-eng.mp3" length="7846214" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relief Society: A Sacred Work</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Ours is a work of salvation, service, and becoming a holy people.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work" custom-dq="true" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50019113_000_038" doc-version="2" hash="cX-TQw"><no-search><custom-dq>45000</custom-dq></no-search><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="btg5vfRRPUKs9tNkm3UuMA" hash="otmdlg">Relief Society: A Sacred Work</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="tTFZaGUpbUyrqI9ARFhLtg" hash="6A7qTw">Julie B. Beck</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="bRX1BHU0bUO1zRMmlYcgCw" hash="2Atifg">Ours is a work of salvation, service, and becoming a holy people.</p>
  </div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p1" pid="LmxwocNuCU2zPZDJcqhj6g" hash="LLqiqA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="110"></span>This is a beautiful gathering of Relief Society women. Since our last general meeting, I have been blessed to visit many of you. Thank you for your faithful lives and dedicated service. In recent general Relief Society meetings, we have been taught how strong and immovable Latter-day Saint women know and fulfill the purpose of Relief Society.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Tonight I hope to enlarge our testimony and understanding of Relief Society as a faith-based work. I will speak of the purpose of this work and the way we accomplish it.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.f2">
	<p pid="kPlvecm0YUeZaX2u7ZiLnQ" hash="5v0oOQ">We know that the purpose of Relief Society as established by the Lord is to prepare women for the blessings of eternal life by helping them:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="KyfPCEpN7EuAHH1tYIBl0g" hash="sqBnHg">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="Qlm7t7FOVECMfFz4snhyAw" hash="OwEs5g">Increase their faith and personal righteousness.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="ZOH3s0XRxECJ9tB77rdAFA" hash="zwTM6w">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="CziYYvPnFEmGtvKRVKSrcg" hash="9jfQ4w">Strengthen their families and homes.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="EE-604KYzEmiC8vVXXYPdA" hash="Q9O0Jg">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="7qKiR7RWK0KcvMZqUxAlvQ" hash="xQvOQg">Serve the Lord and His children.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p2" pid="39LuZcnSjEOIsj7mzWf2wQ" hash="zPX41g">The history, purpose, and work of Relief Society are unique among all women’s organizations. In 1942, for the centennial of the Relief Society, the First Presidency of the Church said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p3" pid="1QQbSozHhUWOm4s-QCbIPA" hash="gfw-Vw">“No other woman’s organization in all the earth has had such a birth. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p4" pid="D5Z4BrXYQESqdKPFyXpOqg" hash="RROfZg">“Members [of Relief Society] should permit neither hostile nor competitive interests of any kind to detract from the duties and obligations, the privileges and honors, the opportunities and achievements of membership in this great Society.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p5" pid="M6tWScrS90W3fGI0BfQryw" hash="O9Wi1Q">If our membership in Relief Society is so important, we need to know what sets us apart from every other woman’s group or organization. Everything we do in Relief Society matters because Heavenly Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, visited Joseph Smith and, through him, the fulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ was restored to the earth. Relief Society is part of that restoration. The Prophet Joseph Smith defined the purpose of <span class="pageBreak" page-number="111"></span>the Relief Society and instructed the sisters in their purpose, just as he taught priesthood leaders in Kirtland and Nauvoo their priesthood purpose and work. Ours is an organization that continues to be led today by prophets, seers, and revelators.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p6" pid="gO67ITcMTEKhsPzGE5XPhQ" hash="ZBFAaw">Relief Society is unique because it was organized after the “pattern of the priesthood”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> and we operate on a general and local level under the direction of priesthood leaders. We work in partnership with priesthood leaders, who hold keys which give them authority to preside in the name of the Lord. We operate in the manner of the priesthood—which means that we seek, receive, and act on revelation; make decisions in councils; and concern ourselves with caring for individuals one by one. Ours is the priesthood purpose to prepare ourselves for the blessings of eternal life by making and keeping covenants. Therefore, like our brethren who hold the priesthood, ours is a work of salvation, service, and becoming a holy people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p7" pid="FRkz7fivm0S0qUScCq1c5g" hash="gPeTIA">President Boyd K. Packer has taught that “the Relief Society has very broad responsibilities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p8" pid="olknUQxUhUad4yP71WA1_g" hash="RQaNqg">“Attendance at the Sunday meeting is but a small part of your duty. Some of you have not understood this and have set aside much of what Relief Society has meant over the years—the sisterhood, the charitable and practical parts of it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p9" pid="_wTFxZ4mIEaT-6bmjVGwyw" hash="15b21A">He explained:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p10" pid="T2qdfdbgsUeXkU61BDDkDg" hash="DpR3RQ">“The Relief Society, the Prophet [Joseph] told us, is organized after the pattern of the priesthood. When a man holds the priesthood, … it requires full dedication and loyalty. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p11" pid="F6vtFCyMgUiT7F5OTSWSAg" hash="y9xX0Q">“Membership in the priesthood magnifies the man and the boy. Wherever he is, whatever he does, no matter with whom he associates, he is expected to honor his priesthood. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p12" pid="JDV2lqZ_UEa5LzzTSy4w7w" hash="Q1doXg">“If you sisters follow after that pattern, … you will serve your organization, your cause—the Relief Society. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p13" pid="pm8CAAKR5Ei6NJ9uc7R70g" hash="gPlsFQ">“Service in the Relief Society magnifies and sanctifies each individual sister. Your membership in Relief Society should be ever with you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="yEDGS8I7sUWPSMV5NDgQ0w" hash="7OKqhQ">Working in the Lord’s Way</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p14" pid="kY1ikzr96UCBPZv97qhrjw" hash="LNPY6A">When our purpose is clear, it naturally follows that there is an appropriate way to carry out our responsibilities. Let us review how the faith-based work of Relief Society is to be administered. One of the most precious commodities we all have is time. Most women have many responsibilities and never have sufficient time to do everything their hearts and minds want to do. We show respect for the Lord and the sisters when we use Relief Society time in an inspired way.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p15" pid="6_eg1ZUuJUeWmpj6yftrPQ" hash="pEISVQ">President Dieter F. Uchtdorf taught: “A wise man once distinguished between ‘the noble art of getting things done’ and ‘a nobler art of leaving things undone.’ True ‘wisdom in life,’ he taught, consists of ‘the elimination of non-essentials.’” President Uchtdorf then asked: “What are the nonessential things that clutter your days and steal your time? What are the habits you may have developed that do not serve a useful purpose? What are the unfinished or unstarted things that could add vigor, <span class="pageBreak" page-number="112"></span>meaning, and joy to your life?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> We can apply his questions to all Relief Society meetings and work.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="PAiro1rwmEujgbJkKSI-oQ" hash="PbcstA">Relief Society Sunday Meetings</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p16" pid="Xqj-JX-q_EW856qirb6rVQ" hash="U__9_w">We hold the weekly meeting of our society on Sundays as part of our regular three-hour block of meetings. It is amazing to contemplate that every Sunday, all around the world, thousands of groups of sisters are gathering to increase their faith, strengthen their families, and coordinate their efforts to provide relief. Our Sunday meetings are only 50 minutes in length, so we begin those meetings by taking care of essential business that will help us be more unified and effective in our Relief Society work. We keep our business brief, dignified, organized, and in keeping with who we are and what we are to do.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p17" pid="PEB2OTJFDUWvrj1A3RDKVg" hash="MIZsfw">Just as the sisters in the first Relief Society meetings received instruction from prophets and apostles, we study the words of Church leaders today. What a blessing it is to have correlated resources that teach doctrine and principles to help us live the gospel in our personal lives and homes. Because this work is based on faith, Relief Society lessons are most effective when inspired teaching takes place and “[she] that preacheth and [she] that receiveth, understand one another, and both are edified and rejoice together.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="Or9xZJogGk2x30qnb4jFvQ" hash="ECRNDA">Additional Relief Society Meetings</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p18" pid="OF37pJ_vxEypMt77rqvQRQ" hash="3pDy6A">All of our meetings and activities are meetings of Relief Society sisters. For the past number of years, we have called additional Relief Society meetings home, family, and personal enrichment meetings. In response to concerns about the complexity of that title and the different interpretations about the purpose of those meetings, a decision has been made that the name “home, family, and personal enrichment” will be discontinued effective now. In counsel with the First Presidency and the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles, it was determined that rather than give these additional Relief Society meetings a new title, all such meetings and activities will now be referred to simply as Relief Society meetings. Individual Relief Society meetings that are held during the week can be called whatever they are: Relief Society service, classes, projects, conferences, or workshops.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p19" pid="j4s0EWMN2E-jKzQ3RcAhGQ" hash="-UfIQw">These additional meetings can be valuable supplements to Sunday instruction, especially for sisters who serve in Primary or Young Women or who are unable to attend Sunday meetings. These meetings also provide a wonderful place to bring our friends of other faiths and to include Relief Society sisters who do not actively participate in the Church. All Relief Society members and their friends are invited and welcome. However, sisters should not be made to feel that attendance at these meetings is mandatory.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p20" pid="BW1AIPSUEkaGroND7xakbA" hash="5naH3Q">Under the direction of the bishop, the ward Relief Society presidency can use these meetings to address spiritual and temporal needs of individuals and families in the ward and to strengthen sisterhood and unity.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p21" pid="paltodvst0uMnZO9d1NRtQ" hash="9pfAxg">When sisters meet for Relief Society meetings during the week, they have the opportunity to learn and accomplish the charitable and practical responsibilities of the Relief Society. This is where they learn and practice skills that will help them increase their faith and personal righteousness, strengthen families and homes, and provide service to those in need. These meetings are meant to be instrumental in teaching the skills and responsibilities of womanhood and motherhood in the Lord’s plan. It is here that women learn and apply principles of provident living and spiritual and temporal self-reliance, and they also increase in sisterhood and unity as they teach one another and serve together.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p22" pid="BWInADZV9Uihpuhj6DEQkQ" hash="Ms-ypg">The ward Relief Society president oversees all Relief Society meetings. As part of this responsibility, she counsels regularly with the bishop regarding how these meetings can help meet the needs of individuals and families in the ward.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p23" pid="SZMbVQqTGkKWQemC3liVHg" hash="IEB9Yg">The Relief Society presidency prayerfully considers how often they should hold Relief Society meetings during the week and where they should hold them. They then make a recommendation to the bishop, taking into consideration the time commitments of sisters, family circumstances, travel distance and cost, financial cost to the ward, safety, and other local circumstances.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p24" pid="KXfzHdbxFUKg_WTmxZV2Nw" hash="lfxZ-g">These meetings are usually held at a time other than on Sunday or on Monday evening. They are generally held monthly, but the Relief Society presidency may recommend that the meetings be held more often or less frequently. Efforts should be made to meet at least quarterly. At least one member of the ward Relief Society presidency should be in attendance at every meeting. Under the direction of the stake presidency, the stake Relief Society presidency may plan and carry out one or two stake Relief Society meetings each year for all Relief Society sisters in the stake.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p25" pid="AE0SB967L06uIB_6dxxhEg" hash="nxr_oA">Relief Society leaders prayerfully counsel together about the topics that will strengthen sisters and their families and about the best ways to teach those topics. The Relief Society president ensures that these plans are approved by the bishop. She also ensures that the plans are consistent with current policies about activities, including policies about finances. Although the Relief Society president oversees these meetings, she may ask her first or second counselor to assist her. She may also recommend another sister in the ward to be called to serve as the Relief Society meeting coordinator to help the presidency plan and carry them out.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p26" pid="zTPEAHfVXUidX5L2YJ1ZFw" hash="E24ddw">
          <span class="pageBreak" page-number="113"></span>Meetings can focus on one topic or be divided into more than one class or activity. Generally, teachers at these meetings should be members of the ward or stake. Each year, one meeting may commemorate the founding of the Relief Society and focus on its history and purposes.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p27" pid="Ts3L9fi2qE6hnPrz2Q26ew" hash="Yh4sqw">In planning Relief Society meetings held during the week, leaders give priority to topics that will fulfill Relief Society purposes, such as marriage and family, homemaking, provident living and self-reliance, compassionate service, temple and family history, sharing the gospel, and other subjects requested by the bishop.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p28" pid="xJpnzY47oEqawjbAf31C4A" hash="9UysiQ">When we plan, we ask what the Lord needs us to learn and become in order to be prepared for eternal life. In the wisdom of the Lord, every ward has its own unique characteristics, which no other ward shares. This can be compared to the DNA that identifies every human being as unique. Every bishop has the responsibility for his specific ward. Each ward Relief Society president has a calling to assist one bishop. Each bishop and Relief Society presidency have had hands laid on their heads to receive inspiration for their particular responsibilities and not for any other ward or group of Relief Society sisters.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p29" pid="mu0KC1y4EUeAXiY9vj2hUw" hash="sgDR9Q">If we work with this understanding, we will seek revelation and work in companionship with a bishop to fulfill the purposes of Relief Society in our own wards. As a result of operating in this way, if sisters and families need to be prepared for emergencies, the Relief Society can organize, teach, and inspire that preparation. If sisters and families need to prepare for the temple, the Relief Society can organize, teach, and inspire sisters to do that. If a bishop needs young single adult women to share the gospel and bring their friends back into activity, the Relief Society can organize, teach, and inspire that work. If mothers need to learn how to nurture and care for their children, the Relief Society can organize, teach, and inspire that work. If sisters need to learn and improve homemaking skills that will help their homes become a center of spiritual strength, then the Relief Society can organize, teach, and inspire that work. As has happened throughout our history, if priesthood leaders need to accomplish something significant, they can call upon the Relief Society to help them.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p30" pid="Jn7b-u8YaUW8zxVV8OBoQA" hash="1DxJkg">Using Relief Society meetings appropriately will increase the ability of the Relief Society to work in powerful ways with priesthood leaders in every ward. As Joseph Smith said in the Doctrine and Covenants:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p31" pid="vqh7l9Obv0OtYdqvVmCX0w" hash="dv1PUg">“Let no man count them as small things; for there is much which lieth in futurity, pertaining to the saints, which depends upon these things.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p32" pid="5iGkRq_zEUan2kcVu1Jd1g" hash="EhZTYw">“You know, [sisters], that a very large ship is benefited very much by a very small helm in the time of a storm, by being kept workways with the wind and the waves.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p33" pid="rUoOLDTcBEqMazioaRlsGg" hash="E3Yo3w">Relief Society and priesthood leaders, this message will serve as your current official policy regarding additional Relief Society meetings. Should you have questions regarding anything we have taught here after studying this message, please counsel together in your own wards and stakes to discover the solutions you need.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="1X65FpFEnk2kVu2b3wOOFA" hash="wzJyIg">Visiting Teaching</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p34" pid="NDNwSjESskS2-XgO9wzwKQ" hash="qmoyYg">Much of the essential Relief Society work we do doesn’t happen in meetings. Let’s focus now on learning about visiting teaching. Because we follow the example and teachings of Jesus Christ, we value this sacred assignment to love, know, serve, understand, teach, and minister in His behalf. This is one duty we have in the Church where we are certain to have the help of the Lord if we ask for it. This is one responsibility that is certain to increase our faith and personal righteousness and strengthen our own homes and families as we become partners with the Lord. A sister in this Church has no other responsibility outside of her family that has the potential to do as much good as does visiting teaching.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p35" pid="STg4OIUeqEeHnrBNeEe3Uw" hash="Z4uKOg">Because this is the Lord’s program of individual watchcare for His daughters, the policies regarding visiting <span class="pageBreak" page-number="114"></span>teaching are approved by the First Presidency as outlined in the <span class="emphasis">Church Handbook of Instructions.</span> Because visiting teaching focuses on individual sisters, Relief Society leaders do not organize women into groups for the purpose of visiting teaching.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p36" pid="qevNP2PjZEq0-xhqZHSjzA" hash="KaZszg">The bishop, who is the ordained shepherd of the ward, cannot possibly watch over all of the Lord’s sheep at one time. He is dependent on inspired visiting teachers to help him. We know we should each choose to be a friend to everyone in our ward, but the bishop and Relief Society president have the responsibility to receive revelation as to who should be assigned to watch over and strengthen each individual sister. Ideally, every sister should watch over and strengthen at least one other sister in her ward. It is our blessing to pray for another sister and receive inspiration as to how the Lord would have us care for one of His daughters.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p37" pid="iWAWIgodC0OGVtkpiIcX8Q" hash="Ehj2Tg">Visiting teaching becomes the Lord’s work when our focus is on people rather than percentages. In reality, visiting teaching is never finished. It is more a way of life than a task. Faithfully serving as a visiting teacher is evidence of our discipleship. We demonstrate our faith and follow a pattern established by the Lord as we report on our assignment every month. If our watchcare were primarily about reporting that every sister in the ward heard the Visiting Teaching Message printed each month in the <span class="emphasis">Ensign</span> and <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> it would be much more efficient to read it aloud to everyone in a sacrament meeting. Our reports are most helpful to the bishop and the Relief Society president when we inform them of the spiritual and temporal well-being of sisters and how we have been able to serve and love them.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p38" pid="HYLNZvb5jUa3tSWJTIeK-g" hash="dRwGOg">How grateful I am for all of my visiting teachers who, over the years, have demonstrated their faith as they have served, taught, strengthened, and loved me in inspired ways.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.t6">
        <h3 class="title" pid="qaoca75lvkKahWYFYI0EhA" hash="hpw0zQ">Welfare and Compassionate Service</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p39" pid="jlUvmzYxQkWxjz14AVIf6Q" hash="FAjUyg">Our compassionate service and assistance with the welfare needs of individuals and families are an outgrowth of visiting teaching. A Relief Society president learns of the needs of people in her ward through visiting teachers and her own visits to ward members. Sometimes she organizes us to help others, and at other times we serve “according to [our] natures,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> following the promptings of the Holy Ghost. Many years ago I learned from Sister Camilla Kimball, wife of President Spencer W. Kimball, to “never suppress a generous thought.” By following her counsel, we can know with certainty that our Father in Heaven knows us personally because He sends us to be His hands and heart to those in need. As we do so, our faith in Him is strengthened.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.t7">
        <h3 class="title" pid="dzG1wy_dSE-uA-EzN8PyEQ" hash="JZFLeA">Conclusion</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p40" pid="mJnsMJm_f0qpDgHI8bDi0w" hash="BqLSkQ">We live in a happy and exciting time of growth in the history of the Church, and Relief Society is part of making that history. Joseph Smith said, “Let every man, woman and child realize the importance of the work, and act as if success depended on his individual exertion alone; let all feel an interest in it, and then consider they live in a day, the contemplation of which animated the bosoms of kings, Prophets, and righteous men thousands of years ago—the prospect of which inspired their sweetest notes, and most exalted lays, and caused them to break out in such rapturous strains as are recorded in the Scriptures.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work.p41" pid="LIo2FvVt-0K8xbEzSxHSKQ" hash="61L98Q">I rejoice to know that the Lord loves us enough to guide us in this work through prophets, seers, and revelators and that we belong to a Church that operates with continuing revelation. I feel a certainty that as each sister does her part to ensure that the purposes of Relief Society are fulfilled, angels will be our associates and we will be participants in amazing miracles. We celebrate and give thanks for the essential, sacred work we have been given, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2009/10/relief-society-a-sacred-work</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2009-general-relief-society-meeting/2009-09-0010-julie-b-beck-64k-eng.mp3" length="9747101" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“And upon the Handmaids in Those Days Will I Pour Out My Spirit”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We know we are successful if we live so that we qualify for, receive, and know how to follow the Spirit.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021388_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="AK1miA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="TkYwcXF-rUKleVE4URRyfw" hash="V5gVRw">“And upon the Handmaids in Those Days Will I Pour Out My Spirit”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="oD_fN8w47kqYzVhWv8Bt3A" hash="6A7qTw">Julie B. Beck</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="1UHZ0Q88JUiXwxJMlK5ZJQ" hash="eebCug">We know we are successful if we live so that we qualify for, receive, and know how to follow the Spirit.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.p1" pid="9Qa56tm0j0OvxwxQQ91Utg" hash="3yBJbg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="10"></span>In the past year I have met thousands of Latter-day Saint women in many countries. The list of challenges these sisters face is lengthy and sobering. There are family troubles, economic tests, calamities, accidents, and illnesses. There is much distraction and not enough peace and joy. Despite popular media messages to the contrary, no one is rich enough, beautiful enough, or clever enough to avoid a mortal experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.p2" pid="pQeBgaVLt0meHpi_at_KjA" hash="FA5_aw">The questions sisters ask are serious and insightful. They articulate uneasiness about the future, sorrow for unrealized expectations, some indecision, and diminished feelings of self-worth. They also reflect a deep desire to do what is right.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.p3" pid="fasEuayki0yuI_LCzP9csQ" hash="P12xCg">There has grown in me an overwhelming testimony of the value of daughters of God. So much depends on them. In my visits with the sisters, I have felt that there has never been a greater need for increased faith and personal righteousness. There has never been a greater need for strong families and homes. There has never been more that could be done to help others who are in need. How does one increase faith, strengthen families, and provide relief?<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> How does a woman in our day find answers to her own questions and stand strong and immovable against incredible opposition and difficulty?</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="icO6zF2Dj0aRJV5Wr1RMgg" hash="1QTF5A">Personal Revelation</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.p4" pid="bvfRx3GR70mz8qOJtXU20A" hash="VFJUkA">A good woman knows that she does not have enough time, energy, or opportunity to take care of all of the people or do all of the worthy things her heart yearns to do. Life is not calm for most women, and each day seems to require the accomplishment of a million things, most of which are important. A good woman must constantly resist alluring and deceptive messages from many sources telling her that she is entitled to more time away from her responsibilities and that she deserves a life of greater ease and <span class="pageBreak" page-number="11"></span>independence. But with personal revelation, she can prioritize correctly and navigate this life confidently.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.p5" pid="y8c6Dw60oUSnbDsqtx1MZQ" hash="l9q9eA">The ability to qualify for, receive, and act on personal revelation is the single most important skill that can be acquired in this life. Qualifying for the Lord’s Spirit begins with a desire for that Spirit and implies a certain degree of worthiness. Keeping the commandments, repenting, and renewing covenants made at baptism lead to the blessing of always having the Lord’s Spirit with us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Making and keeping temple covenants also adds spiritual strength and power to a woman’s life. Many answers to difficult questions are found by reading the scriptures because the scriptures are an aid to revelation.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Insight found in scripture accumulates over time, so it is important to spend some time in the scriptures every day. Daily prayer is also essential to having the Lord’s Spirit with us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Those who earnestly seek help through prayer and scripture study often have a paper and pencil nearby to write questions and record impressions and ideas.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.p6" pid="hoaJSUC9t0Wqbx7-Ttji1A" hash="tcrYoQ">Revelation can come hour by hour and moment by moment as we do the right things. When women nurture as Christ nurtured, a power and peace can descend to guide when help is needed. For instance, mothers can feel help from the Spirit even when tired, noisy children are clamoring for attention, but they can be distanced from the Spirit if they lose their temper with children. Being in the right places allows us to receive guidance. It requires a conscious effort to diminish distractions, but having the Spirit of revelation makes it possible to prevail over opposition and persist in faith through difficult days and essential routine tasks. Personal revelation gives us the understanding of what to do every day to increase faith and personal righteousness, strengthen families and homes, and seek those who need our help. Because personal revelation is a constantly renewable source of strength, it is possible to feel bathed in help even during turbulent times.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.p7" pid="-wgz4muMrkWs4JsO0S8GJQ" hash="UqHTHQ">We are told to put our trust in that Spirit which leads us “to do justly, to walk humbly, to judge righteously.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> We are also told that this Spirit will enlighten our minds, fill our souls with joy, and help us know all things we should do.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> Promised personal revelation comes when we ask for it, prepare for it, and go forward in faith, trusting that it will be poured out upon us.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="_2KtqNwi40yLJcGU3XSZNA" hash="qGYF5A">Relief Society—Teaching, Inspiring, and Strengthening</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.p8" pid="OPsy5jfHrEiBv2nZ0Tj31w" hash="qhr65w">Additionally, the Lord in His wisdom has provided a Relief Society to help His daughters in these latter days. When Relief Society functions in an inspired way, it lifts women up and out of a troubled world and into a way of living that prepares them for the blessings of eternal life. This society has at its very core the responsibility to help sisters increase faith and personal righteousness, strengthen families and homes, and seek out and help others who are in need. Through Relief Society, sisters can receive answers to their questions and be blessed by the combined spiritual power of all the sisters. Relief Society validates the true and eternal nature of daughters of God. It is a sacred trust, a guiding light, and a system of watchcare that teaches and inspires women to be strong and immovable. Its motto, “Charity never faileth,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> is embodied in all good women.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.p9" pid="qO-vnJ6El0OC0CbEByDwdw" hash="4Q6CGA">When a girl advances into Relief Society or when a woman is baptized into the Church, she becomes part of a sisterhood that strengthens her in her preparation for eternal life. Entrance into Relief Society signifies <span class="pageBreak" page-number="12"></span>that a woman can be trusted and relied upon to make a significant contribution in the Church. She continues to progress as an individual without receiving much outward credit or praise.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.p10" pid="NiMFaWXHWUmKZmgi76_8TQ" hash="6vSF5g">The second general Relief Society president, Eliza R. Snow, said this to the sisters: “We want to be ladies in very deed, not according to the term of the word as the world judges, but fit companions of the Gods and Holy Ones. In an organized capacity we can assist each other in not only doing good but in refining ourselves, and whether few or many come forward and help to prosecute this great work, they will be those that will fill honorable positions in the Kingdom of God. … Women should be women and not babies that need petting and correction all the time. I know we like to be appreciated but if we do not get all the appreciation which we think is our due, what matters? We know the Lord has laid high responsibility upon us, and there is not a wish or desire that the Lord has implanted in our hearts in righteousness but will be realized, and the greatest good we can do to ourselves and each other is to refine and cultivate ourselves in everything that is good and ennobling to qualify us for those responsibilities.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="RNAfLwMJe0qbvRSaE9Filw" hash="ESyzuQ">Measuring Success</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.p11" pid="wIzIpC_plEKbb84F_OSwrg" hash="DafemA">Good women always have a desire to know if they are succeeding. In a world where the measures of success are often distorted, it is important to seek appreciation and affirmation from proper sources. To paraphrase a list found in <span class="emphasis">Preach My Gospel,</span> we are doing well when we develop attributes of Christ and strive to obey His gospel with exactness. We are doing well when we seek to improve ourselves and do our best. We are doing well when we increase faith and personal righteousness, strengthen families and homes, and seek out and help others who are in need. We know we are successful if we live so that we qualify for, receive, and know how to follow the Spirit. When we have done our very best, we may still experience disappointments, but we will not be disappointed in ourselves. We can feel certain that the Lord is pleased when we feel the Spirit working through us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Peace, joy, and hope are available to those who measure success properly.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.p12" pid="P6FtvVDWZ0OV3qj22jYuQg" hash="A4bQxQ">A revelation in the book of Joel states that in the last days, sons and daughters of God will prophesy and the Lord will pour out His Spirit upon His servants and His handmaids.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> President Spencer W. Kimball echoed this prophecy when he said:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.p13" pid="uBiD0SuzTkGM-J5L_QfQpA" hash="WKW9Ww">“Much of the major growth that is coming to the Church in the last days will come because many of the good women of the world (in whom there is often such an inner sense of spirituality) will be drawn to the Church in large numbers. This will happen to the degree that the women of the Church reflect righteousness and articulateness in their lives and to the degree that the women of the Church are seen as distinct and different—in happy ways—from the women of the world. …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.p14" pid="S9iyYynYS06wRdCaiDckQA" hash="y4L_Ag">“Thus it will be that female exemplars of the Church will be a significant force in both the numerical and spiritual growth of the Church in the last days.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit.p15" pid="iLifj9J4HUq-0tQowJQQ8g" hash="5KGcUw">I bear my witness that the gospel of Jesus Christ is true. The Lord depends on His daughters to do their part to strengthen the homes of Zion and build His kingdom on the earth. As they seek and qualify for personal revelation, the Lord will pour out His Spirit upon His handmaids in these latter days. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/04/and-upon-the-handmaids-in-those-days-will-i-pour-out-my-spirit</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2010-general-conference/2010-04-1030-julie-b-beck-64k-eng.mp3" length="5156254" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2010 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daughters in My Kingdom: The History and Work of Relief Society</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Studying the history of Relief Society gives definition and expression to who we are as disciples and followers of our Savior, Jesus Christ.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021411_000_0010" doc-version="1" hash="q4j9oA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="qDSRPg4yuU-ALPCF26daMg" hash="Dnis6A">“Daughters in My Kingdom”: The History and Work of Relief Society</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="rVL3LLztcUGPG2sk6THS3Q" hash="6A7qTw">Julie B. Beck</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="UNmsK3WgxEORm4QEBwc4hQ" hash="fQJ3Lg">Studying the history of Relief Society gives definition and expression to who we are as disciples and followers of our Savior, Jesus Christ.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p1" pid="K0bf4PEo6Ey0lYgtN3dHqA" hash="uYbDrQ">This meeting is a gift to all of Heavenly Father’s daughters who desire to learn His mind and will and understand their responsibilities in His plan. I have visited many of you this past year, and my heart has been touched as I have looked into your eyes, hugged you, laughed with you, cried with you, and listened to your grief, joy, and triumph. Each of you is precious beyond description and known by our Heavenly Father. As daughters of God, you are preparing for eternal designations, and each of you has a female identity, nature, and responsibility. The success of families, communities, this Church, and the precious plan of salvation is dependent on your faithfulness. Oh, dear sisters, how we love and pray for you!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p2" pid="_AFKiPkn5kaxcPD4jmY6uQ" hash="1kiPew">All of us are in the middle of a very personal mortal experience. Two sisters I have met recently represent how to live faithfully. One sister lives in central Brazil. Her lovely redbrick home, set in a yard of red soil, surrounded by a wall of red blocks, is a haven and refuge from the world outside. Her bright-eyed children know how to sing Primary songs, and on the walls of her home hang pictures of the Savior, temples, and prophets of God cut from the <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> magazine. She and her husband made personal sacrifices to be sealed in the temple so their children could be born in the covenant. She told me that she prays continually for the Lord to give her strength and inspiration sufficient to bring up her children in the light, truth, and strength of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p3" pid="Vc6Ka6pJr0iED7UwczekFg" hash="hWz_cQ">Another sister lives alone in a tiny apartment on the 80th floor of a building in Hong Kong. She has some physical difficulties, but she is cheerfully independent. She is the only member of the Church in her family. On a little shelf are her scriptures, her Relief Society manuals, and other Church books. She has created a Spirit-filled haven in her home, and she is a light to everyone in her branch.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="zkYYbVra9Ua1tI4GpcKV2w" hash="OtqUAA">Warnings</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p4" pid="vhJT4Fx8zUeR-BDCiRRHBw" hash="x5Gr2g">We know that many sisters live in oppressive or dangerous circumstances. Some are constantly hungry, and some must summon daily courage to continue in faith despite disappointments and being betrayed by others. Because we are living in the last days of this earth, there are signs of a great struggle everywhere. Myths and misperceptions regarding the strength, purpose, and position of Latter-day Saint women abound. Prevailing myths imply that we are of lower importance than men, that we are generally sweet but uninformed, and that no matter what we do, we will never be enough to be accepted by our Heavenly Father. As the Apostle Peter said, there are “false teachers among you, who privily shall bring in damnable heresies, even denying the Lord that bought them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p5" pid="gjPWQRifJ0OQ2-o8t25-kA" hash="bpVgVA">The Book of Mormon describes what is happening:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p6" pid="D0QhyDkHMEepU9SocWFT0A" hash="MVHYBA">“For behold, at that day shall [Satan] rage in the hearts of the children of men, and stir them up to anger against that which is good.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p7" pid="LmshXpS3QUm5HpWjn4NJTw" hash="6ONdOA">“And others will he pacify, and lull them away into carnal security, that they will say: All is well in Zion; yea, Zion prospereth, all is well—and thus the devil cheateth their souls, and leadeth them away carefully down to hell.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p8" pid="fa_YZKe-cUqkVrkqFXbE3Q" hash="qrUzqQ">“And behold, others he flattereth away, and telleth them there is no hell; and he saith unto them: I am no devil, for there is none—and thus he whispereth in their ears, until he grasps them with his awful chains.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p9" pid="nXEtmqT2mk67CWRPvv6icw" hash="B_8U6Q">In the growing climate of entitlement, excuse, apathy, and enticement, daughters of God who are not watchful, prayerful, and inspired are increasingly at risk of becoming what the scriptures describe as “silly women”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> who worship a variety of “strange gods.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Sadly, as a result of life’s difficulties and the world’s popular heresies, many sisters believe the myths more than the truth. Their misalignment with God’s plan is demonstrated in findings that many are not doing essential things such as praying and reading scriptures. The Lord Himself has said that “this is a day of warning, and not a day of many words.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="0W1QY5Y6P022c6cazSw-Ag" hash="COFuXQ">Relief Society Was Organized to Be a Defense and a Refuge</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p10" pid="xDVO36gD90Cbs7GSVWEhrA" hash="PbmlgQ">In order to watch over, teach, and inspire His daughters in these perilous times, God authorized the Prophet Joseph Smith to organize the women of the Church. This divinely appointed and priesthood-directed organization is called Relief Society.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p11" pid="da1cqsDFwEy4HkmxfSF64w" hash="ECf-LA">The purpose of Relief Society is to prepare daughters of God for the blessings of eternal life as they increase in faith and personal righteousness, strengthen families and homes, and seek out and help others who are in need.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p12" pid="ToeHKDTf4Um9CV7k0kkQ6A" hash="otrahw">Relief Society clarifies our work and unifies us as daughters of God in defense of His plan. In this day of mistaken identities, confusion, and distraction, Relief Society is meant to be a compass and guide to teach the truth to faithful women. Righteous women today seek an outpouring of revelation to resist distractions, fight evil and spiritual destruction, and rise above personal disasters by increasing their faith, strengthening their families, and providing relief to others.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="BKevuRhWuEa8E3qQpf-JZQ" hash="LqdgzQ">History and Work of Relief Society</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p13" pid="Fj5UsTJ9CUGPh8lXIUobWg" hash="MWPYwA">Our presidency has prayed, fasted, pondered, and counseled with prophets, seers, and revelators to learn what God would have us do to help His daughters be strong in the face of “the calamity which should come upon the inhabitants of the earth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> An answer has come that the sisters of the Church should know and learn from the history of Relief Society. Understanding the history of Relief Society strengthens the foundational identity and worth of faithful women.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p14" pid="OZPiEcotk0qXI-oH0_RCBg" hash="qAnUUA">In consequence of this, a history of Relief Society for the Church is being completed and will be available for our use next year. In anticipation of this, Relief Society history is receiving increased attention, such as on the visiting teaching page of the <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and the <span class="emphasis">Ensign</span>. The preparation of the history has been an inspired and revelatory experience.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p15" pid="gtgNJH8E7Uy5k6BLjC6GsQ" hash="KC2P1w">As we have studied the history of Relief Society, we have learned that the Lord’s vision and purpose for Relief Society was not of a sleepy meeting on Sunday. He had in mind something much, much bigger than a women’s club or special-interest entertainment group.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p16" pid="AsyUa6N-UUuQEloXq6t5KQ" hash="N9_N-A">He intended Relief Society to help build His people and prepare them for the blessings of the temple. He established this organization to align His daughters with His work and to enlist their help in building His kingdom and strengthening the homes of Zion.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="TLiayg392kiaiyMt9k51Xg" hash="xjIH2w">History Teaches Us Who We Are</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p17" pid="ATDYW2FxfkOSSBS-K45ZIA" hash="r1Gl2g">We study our history to learn who we are. There is a worldwide hunger among good women to know their identity, value, and importance. Studying and applying the history of Relief Society gives definition and expression to who we are as disciples and followers of our Savior, Jesus Christ. Our faithfulness and service are signs of our conversion and commitment to remember and follow Him. In July of 1830, at the beginning of the Restoration of His Church, the Lord selected His first female leader of this dispensation, and in a revelation to her, He said, “I speak unto you, Emma Smith, my daughter; for verily I say unto you, all those who receive my gospel are sons and daughters in my kingdom.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p18" pid="9Bcf_r7CHkSYlfgjO8mL0A" hash="pvygrg">The history of Relief Society teaches us that our Heavenly Father knows His daughters. He loves them, He has given them specific responsibilities, and He has spoken to and guided them during their mortal missions. Additionally, the history of Relief Society elevates and validates the standing of women and demonstrates how they work in companionship with faithful priesthood leaders.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.t6">
        <h3 class="title" pid="Puh5BpCs00yTW8bbNXBfgg" hash="CqZGeA">History Teaches Us What We Are to Do</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p19" pid="PljtqtHULUmslyTFpuBqyg" hash="m7IrpQ">We study our history to learn what we are to do. Through our history we learn how to prepare for the blessings of eternal life. The Relief Society as an organization has always had the responsibility to organize the energies of the sisters in the wards and branches of Zion. Through Relief Society meetings, the ministry of visiting teachers, and their combined service, daughters of God are taught, watched over, and inspired in their responsibility in the Lord’s work and kingdom. Ward and branch Relief Society presidents are set apart to direct that work.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p20" pid="fv29Z4btH0qKFJkgGSi1-w" hash="mNtT0g">One year ago at this meeting, policies regarding Relief Society meetings were announced. We are happy to report that in most wards and branches throughout the world, Relief Society presidencies and sisters have embraced those policies and the spirit behind them. It has been a joy to see a rejuvenation of the historical purpose and work of Relief Society. We have also seen an increase in the dignity, identity, and relevance of Relief Society as all meetings of the sisters are now simply named and announced what they are—Relief Society meetings. We are seeing an increase of faith and personal righteousness, a strengthening of families and homes, and more relief being offered by Relief Society sisters through the correct use of Relief Society meetings. All policies regarding Relief Society meetings, visiting teaching, and other Relief Society work have their foundation in the history of Relief Society and are approved by the First Presidency.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p21" pid="2xGDI6HoI0m3rAbcd7Z4ig" hash="qE3iJA">It has always been a responsibility of Relief Society to participate in the work of salvation. From the beginning of the restored Church, the sisters have been there first, last, and always in responding to the happenings of everyday life. From Relief Society, sisters go forth to serve in Primary, Young Women, Sunday School, and other efforts, and they are beacons of light and virtue to the rising generation. Personal service builds each individual sister, and the united service of millions of faithful women creates a formidable force of faith in the Lord’s work. History shows that since the beginning of the Restoration, sisters have been at the forefront in sharing the gospel, and they continue this effort as they serve missions, prepare young men and women to serve missions, and invite their friends, neighbors, and family members to share in the blessings of the gospel. We also learn from history that the Prophet Joseph Smith used Relief Society meetings to instruct the sisters in their preparation for the temple. Today, family history and temple work continue to be some of the primary obligations of Relief Society.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p22" pid="cVMoWHkfh0emkMS1SsGigA" hash="Frwn5A">Our understanding of our historical purpose helps women learn to prioritize properly so they will “not spend money for that which is of no worth, nor [their] labor for that which cannot satisfy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Relief Society has always had the responsibility to do as the Apostle Paul taught—to teach young women to be sober, discreet, and chaste and to teach those who are married to love their husbands, love their children, and strengthen their homes.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> The history of Relief Society teaches us to take care of the essential things which will save and sanctify us and the things which are necessary to make us personally self-reliant and useful in the Lord’s kingdom.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p23" pid="wPL0-KGY-kmtrMXROkvd3Q" hash="ca1drw">A constant theme through our history is that sisters who utilize the power of the Holy Ghost operate with the inspiration of the Lord in their lives and receive revelation for their responsibilities.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.t7">
        <h3 class="title" pid="GEuYENyEoEqwDelzTB9TYA" hash="xqsbLA">History Unites Faithful Women</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p24" pid="6xHoFkaj6kqj_8JTEdT5Kw" hash="aKZwCA">We study our history because it unites faithful women. The history of Relief Society is a Spirit-filled story of strong, faithful, purposeful women. As a part of the Lord’s restored Church, Relief Society can now be found in nearly 170 nations. Everywhere in the world adult women in the Lord’s Church can be given serious and important responsibilities.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p25" pid="V2Dw8suSRkaTRerQqLahoQ" hash="YriXYg">Young girls and young women in the Church learn to set goals through the Faith in God and Personal Progress programs, which focus them toward the temple and their future responsibilities. In Relief Society they continue to progress toward the blessings of the temple and eternal life by increasing their faith and personal righteousness, strengthening their families and homes, and seeking out and helping those who are in need. Faithful sisters learn to do this with very little applause or recognition for the work they do. That is because Relief Society thrives on the teaching of the Lord Jesus Christ, who said that when we give our alms (or offerings) in secret, our Father in Heaven, who sees in secret, will reward us openly.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p26" pid="adxadsYJr02Qf2M3sNPzog" hash="CrIA9g">Through the history and work of Relief Society, we are connected to a great worldwide sisterhood of young and old, rich and poor, educated and illiterate, single and married, strong and immovable daughters of God.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.t8">
        <h3 class="title" pid="dEcGEpyd-0irq4KsB1vksw" hash="UsGxEg">Knowledge of History Can Help Us Change</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p27" pid="O9G8KZ6WEku-Pt9SOmtk_g" hash="9QQamw">We study our history because it helps us change. Ultimately, the value of history is not so much in its dates, times, and places. It is valuable because it teaches us the principles, purposes, and patterns we are to follow, it helps us know who we are and what we are to do, and it unites us in strengthening the homes of Zion and building the kingdom of God on the earth. Relief Society, when it operates in an inspired way, can replace fear, doubt, and selfishness with faith, hope, and charity. As we move the Lord’s work forward, the history of Relief Society will continue to be written by faithful sisters throughout the world. The Lord is strengthening Relief Society in the living present and preparing a glorious future for His daughters.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society.p28" pid="WVt2dyeg7ECMhr5CiWb_Gw" hash="Dok2wA">I bear you my testimony of the reality of our Heavenly Father and His Son, Jesus Christ. Through the Prophet Joseph Smith, the gospel, the good news of our identity and purpose, was restored to the earth. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/10/daughters-in-my-kingdom-the-history-and-work-of-relief-society</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2010-general-relief-society-meeting/2010-09-0010-julie-b-beck-64k-eng.mp3" length="8107952" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2010 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Hope My Granddaughters (and Grandsons) Will Understand about Relief Society</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society?lang=eng</link>
      <description>From the day the gospel began to be restored in this dispensation, the Lord has needed faithful women to participate as His disciples.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50029123_000_0010" doc-version="2" hash="V741gA">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="WzIL6-u9KkCmwWT1U7XiFQ" hash="bnSlSg">What I Hope My Granddaughters (and Grandsons) Will Understand about Relief Society</h1>
		<p class="authorName" guid="6d9c1d63-34fd-4f70-a560-8d52351a12d5" pid="OX4D_ELj7kGfXyV1OxC53Q" hash="6A7qTw">Julie B. Beck</p>
		<p class="kicker" pid="-4GzgUTZCUyjtmjt_UsnDw" hash="G4XOHA">From the day the gospel began to be restored in this dispensation, the Lord has needed faithful women to participate as His disciples.</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" guid="0d97a6e5-16b2-4e10-94c6-e63a07f222c3">
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.t1">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p1" guid="ed5ecc33-d0b0-4f93-82f4-cc727f0c9375" pid="Ysf0fV90KUiDPrNw4KhInQ" hash="Zbg7FQ">
				<span class="pageBreak" page-number="109"></span>It is a privilege to address you at this historic meeting. It is a blessing for us to be together. During my service as Relief Society general president, I have developed a deep love for the Relief Society sisters of this Church, and the Lord has expanded my vision of how He feels about us and what He expects of us.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p2" guid="7e0053f6-6545-489f-8f2a-3d4cf05b7075" pid="XMofseYU40KS6Mf7SmDQ0A" hash="LQKCAw">I have titled this message “What I Hope My Granddaughters (and Grandsons) Will Understand about Relief Society.” My oldest granddaughters are busily working in Personal Progress and developing the habits and traits of righteous womanhood. Soon they and their peers will carry the responsibility for this great worldwide sisterhood.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p3" guid="5f95d2c6-612b-4fc7-a31d-ff86fc18984c" pid="NwCd3UpEQ0ulwk08vTbgPQ" hash="6-2S0w">I hope what I say in this message will give them and all who hear or read it a clear understanding of what the Lord had in mind for His daughters when Relief Society was organized.</p>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.t2" guid="e5056b8f-f3b6-43fe-958f-35e249edd276">
				<h3 class="title" guid="a0fca217-1372-400e-9a1c-c6229b68d414" pid="2OqosaDNl0iuMiWhmgEu4A" hash="UEABUw">An Ancient Pattern of Discipleship</h3>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p4" guid="5c49154b-9a5b-4e34-9ae2-9b4f25f49bc8" pid="UtVpCFKHhEOFF98OinVCFA" hash="tSzLxg">I hope my granddaughters will understand that Relief Society today is organized after a pattern of discipleship that existed in the ancient Church. When the Savior organized His Church in New Testament times, “women were vital participants in [His] ministry.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> He visited Martha and Mary, two of His most dedicated followers, in Martha’s <span class="pageBreak" page-number="110"></span>home. As Martha listened to Him and served Him according to the custom of their time, He helped her see that she could do more than that. He helped Martha and Mary understand that they could choose “that good part,” which would not be taken from them.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> This gentle comment served as an invitation to participate in the Lord’s ministry. And later in the New Testament, Martha’s strong testimony of the Savior’s divinity gives us some insight into her faith and discipleship.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p5" guid="7902eb00-ca4e-4e69-8620-9e0d3bf3ddfa" pid="_pd7AqBBFECQqIkL35GOtA" hash="bvT_IQ">As we read further in the New Testament, we learn that the Apostles continued to establish the Lord’s Church. We also learn about faithful women whose discipleship contributed to the growth of the Church. Paul spoke of female disciples in places such as Ephesus<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> and Philippi.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> But as the Lord’s Church was lost in apostasy, this pattern of discipleship was also lost.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p6" guid="ff460bc4-414e-4aea-8b7b-3d38ab649860" pid="uBYUoEzLj02Xi7Dmt00Yew" hash="5xtVww">As the Lord began restoring His Church through the Prophet Joseph Smith, He again included women in a pattern of discipleship. A few months after the Church was formally organized, the Lord revealed that Emma Smith was to be set apart as a leader and teacher in the Church and as an official helper to her husband, the Prophet.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> In her calling to help the Lord build His kingdom, she was given instructions about how to increase her faith and personal righteousness, how to strengthen her family and her home, and how to serve others.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p7" guid="ad4e7199-410e-4310-b9b3-12681fa75b56" pid="8dqukm7W7UK0TstYBwjSfA" hash="Ckre5g">I hope my granddaughters will understand that from the day the gospel began to be restored in this dispensation, the Lord has needed faithful women to participate as His disciples.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p8" guid="6abb9f78-8e33-4c22-97a6-e639a1d0c4b5" pid="d-FfzEJm-Uimey_e45NZew" hash="Ysg83w">Just one example of their extraordinary contribution was in missionary work. The great growth of the early Church was made possible because faithful men were willing to leave their families to travel to unknown places and suffer privations and hardship to teach the gospel. However, these men understood that their missions would not have been possible without the full faith and partnership of the women in their lives, who sustained homes and businesses and earned income for their families and the missionaries. The sisters also cared for the thousands of converts who gathered in their communities. They were deeply committed to a new way of life, helping build the Lord’s kingdom and participating in His work of salvation.</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.t3" guid="1190bee7-765c-4d91-8f0a-31fdf22ad7b1">
				<h3 class="title" guid="cf559ce8-7048-4b3c-84ab-18f7d27ca61f" pid="V2C4WueINEqc1HHMZBVVSw" hash="lEGRpQ">Connected with the Priesthood</h3>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p9" guid="bddf3638-a069-4efd-b0fa-8310be233476" pid="e3SFfqRM0EuuBMET9DhNSg" hash="l7FiYA">I hope my granddaughters will understand that the Lord inspired the Prophet Joseph Smith to organize the women of the Church “under the priesthood after the pattern of the priesthood”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> and to teach them “how [they] would come in possession of the privileges, blessings and gifts of the Priesthood.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p10" guid="cea14a2a-c757-43b8-b8d9-04a6136d2c98" pid="3hR47cPpRky16Fa5DHc-pw" hash="yzLwZg">When Relief Society was officially organized, Emma Smith continued in her calling as a leader. She was named as president of the organization, with two counselors to serve with her in a presidency. Rather than being selected by popular vote, as was common in organizations outside of the Church, this presidency was called by revelation, sustained by those they would lead, and set apart by priesthood leaders to serve in their callings, thus being “called of God, by prophecy, and by the laying on of hands by those who are in authority.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Being organized under the priesthood made it possible for the presidency to receive direction from the Lord and His prophet for a specific work. The organization of Relief Society enabled the Lord’s storehouse of talent, time, and means to be administered in wisdom and order.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p11" guid="2a125e85-c19a-4318-8c89-37a5edd434d5" pid="UFTLSz2tokSGTeDnQ2cRBQ" hash="YMRYPw">That first group of women understood that they had been given authority to teach, inspire, and organize the sisters as disciples to assist in the Lord’s work of salvation. In their first meetings the sisters were taught the guiding purposes of Relief Society: to increase faith and personal righteousness, strengthen families and homes, and seek out and help those in need.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p12" guid="5b78aa48-a661-4f8d-8877-5473d7dc7b78" pid="5IY7SSxNEEmoy5rvvzvgYg" hash="bnenxg">I hope my granddaughters will understand that the organization of Relief Society was an essential part of preparing the Saints for the privileges, blessings, and gifts found only in the temple. President Joseph Fielding Smith taught that Relief Society “is a vital part of the kingdom of God on earth” and “is so designed and operated that it helps its faithful members to gain eternal life in our Father’s <span class="pageBreak" page-number="111"></span>kingdom.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> We can imagine what it must have been like for the sisters to be in Joseph Smith’s Red Brick Store at those first Relief Society meetings, facing the hill where a temple was being built as the Prophet taught them that “there should be a select society, separate from all the evils of the world, choice, virtuous, and holy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p13" guid="6d0b37d6-f841-4ad8-b395-515d9ce5f061" pid="y_41Mo5pf0O4mcqeRZ0AJA" hash="K-k8Pg">I hope my granddaughters value the temple as did the sisters of the first Relief Society, who believed that temple blessings were the grand prize and great goal of every Latter-day Saint woman. I hope that, like early Relief Society sisters, my granddaughters will strive daily to become sufficiently mature to make and keep sacred temple covenants and that when they do go to the temple, they will pay attention to all that is said and done. Through the blessings of the temple, they will be armed with power<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> and blessed to receive “the key of the knowledge of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> Through the ordinances of the priesthood found only in temples, they will be blessed to fulfill their divine, eternal responsibilities, and they will promise to live as committed disciples. I am grateful that one of the Lord’s primary purposes in organizing Relief Society was to give the women the responsibility to help each other prepare “for the greater blessings of the priesthood found in the ordinances and covenants of the temple.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.t4" guid="847b5090-3c17-4845-98e7-f4afdffaa74e">
				<h3 class="title" guid="223bd1f2-1fb2-41ed-b4a1-3143f754aec8" pid="us0O4NT4Dk63d91b95cRrw" hash="MurN8w">The Refuge and Influence of a Worldwide Sisterhood</h3>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p14" guid="7357ef35-daa6-4bb1-97a6-09b4d53a5363" pid="_Ln4sz799E-vpPE3wG1lvQ" hash="hu_JZg">I hope my granddaughters will come to understand the important influence and capacity of the great worldwide sisterhood of Relief Society. Since 1842 the Church has spread well beyond Nauvoo, and Relief Society is now found in over 175 countries, where sisters speak more than 80 languages. Every week new wards and branches are organized, and new Relief Societies become part of an ever-expanding sisterhood, “spread across the continents.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> When Relief Society was relatively small in numbers and was organized mainly in Utah, its leaders could focus much of their organization and discipleship on local social programs and interconnected relief work. They developed home industries and carried out projects to build hospitals and store grain. Those early Relief Society efforts helped establish patterns of discipleship which are now applied globally. As the Church has grown, Relief Society is now able to fulfill its purposes in every ward and branch, in every stake and district, while adapting in an ever-changing world.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p15" guid="aecfa45d-8897-435d-ab11-a26a3e60f663" pid="Sh2e2tPFnEidzqxS3202TA" hash="IdxXiA">Every day, Relief Society sisters around the world experience the entire range of mortal challenges and experiences. Women and their families today live face to face with unrealized expectations; mental, physical, and spiritual illness; accidents; and death. Some sisters suffer loneliness and disappointment because they do not have families of their own, and others suffer from the consequences of poor choices made by family members. Some have experienced war or hunger or natural disasters, and others are learning about the strain of addictions, unemployment, or insufficient education and training. All of these difficulties have the potential to bleach the bones of <span class="pageBreak" page-number="112"></span>faith and exhaust the strength of individuals and families. One of the Lord’s purposes in organizing the sisters into a discipleship was to provide relief that would lift them above “all that hinders the joy and progress of woman.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> In every ward and branch, there is a Relief Society with sisters who can seek and receive revelation and counsel with priesthood leaders to strengthen each other and work on solutions that are applicable in their own homes and communities.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p16" guid="bd5582de-3c33-483e-9cff-f9c9dd713e8c" pid="dSiKjyKE80603Gxo_S6yQw" hash="_ZCo2g">I hope my granddaughters will understand that through Relief Society, their discipleship is extended and they can become engaged with others in the kind of impressive and heroic work the Savior has done. The kind of work the sisters of this Church are asked to do in our day has never been too modest in scope or inconsequential to the Lord. Through their faithfulness, they can feel His approval and be blessed with the companionship of His Spirit.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p17" guid="1aebbd62-7b09-4644-846e-d1986968923a" pid="eEiSpMfOM0CyXWDeuXoigQ" hash="Kt4Wnw">My granddaughters should also know that the sisterhood of Relief Society can provide a place of safety, refuge, and protection.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> As our times become ever more difficult, the faithful sisters of Relief Society will unite to protect the homes of Zion from the shrill voices of the world and the predatory and provocative influence of the adversary. And through Relief Society, they will be taught and strengthened and taught and strengthened more, and the influence of righteous women can bless many more of our Father’s children.</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.t5" guid="44d9bc89-789f-4974-be95-e3458c79f311">
				<h3 class="title" guid="53f5b672-87c4-4609-8018-dde55fe1bfd8" pid="mxl2SRHdXUSRD1sVZ2MMEg" hash="lTID2Q">A Discipleship of Watchcare and Ministering</h3>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p18" guid="c5516cde-8c82-4bb5-87b1-ce818e820f51" pid="u_nav9IUt0OgbBZaxxspJw" hash="O2GYMA">I hope my granddaughters will understand that visiting teaching is an expression of their discipleship and a significant way to honor their covenants. This element of our discipleship should closely resemble the ministry of our Savior. In the early days of Relief Society, a visiting committee from each ward received an assignment to assess needs and collect donations to be distributed to those in need. Throughout the years, Relief Society sisters and leaders have learned one step at a time and have improved in their ability to watch over others. There have been times when sisters have focused more on completing visits, teaching lessons, and leaving notices when they have stopped by their sisters’ homes. These practices have helped sisters learn patterns of watchcare. Just as people in the time of Moses concentrated on keeping long lists of rules, the sisters of Relief Society have at times imposed many written and unwritten rules upon themselves in their desire to understand how to strengthen one another.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p19" guid="3fa3aac2-0275-4ee3-b2e6-ab798a2ffe42" pid="oWYvYTXIHk6cBBLzpQvq5w" hash="H8CRPA">With so much need for relief and rescue in the lives of sisters and their families today, our Heavenly Father needs us to follow a higher path and demonstrate our discipleship by sincerely caring for His children. With this important purpose in mind, leaders are now taught to ask for reports about the spiritual and temporal well-being of sisters and their families and about service rendered.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> Now visiting teachers have the responsibility to “sincerely come to know and love each sister, help her strengthen her faith, and give service.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p20" guid="364994e3-97ce-43ac-8273-11580809f459" pid="nVVj40g2LkKnQVaAYvNYuA" hash="CN5crQ">As committed disciples of the Savior, we are improving in our ability to do the things He would do if He were here. We know that to Him it is our caring that counts, and so we are trying to concentrate on caring about our sisters rather than completing lists of things to do. True ministry is measured more by the depth of our charity than by the perfection of <span class="pageBreak" page-number="113"></span>our statistics. We will know we are successful in our ministry as visiting teachers when our sisters can say, “My visiting teacher helps me grow spiritually” and “I know that my visiting teacher cares deeply about me and my family” and “If I have problems, I know my visiting teacher will take action without waiting to be invited.” Leaders who understand the importance of ministering to others will counsel together to seek and receive revelation about how to edify visiting teachers and how to organize and carry out an inspired ministry.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p21" guid="fe4a9275-afa2-43db-ae54-9e0826260b5a" pid="qG09m9KZAUqEclc03v3aog" hash="HckBQw">Additionally, visiting teaching is an extension of the bishop’s charge to care for the Lord’s flock. The bishop and Relief Society president need the service of inspired visiting teachers to assist them in fulfilling their responsibilities. Through the ministry of visiting teachers, a Relief Society president can be aware of the well-being of each sister in the ward and report about their well-being when she visits with her bishop.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p22" guid="157646e6-1004-4fa3-9f58-6035b16f6e3b" pid="oZJD9gARNkmw88u5vrXoKg" hash="pb-o7g">President Thomas S. Monson has taught us that “when we strive with faith nothing wavering to fulfill the duties appointed to us, when we seek the inspiration of the Almighty in the performance of our responsibilities, we can achieve the miraculous.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> I hope my granddaughters will participate in miracles as they help visiting teaching become a pattern of discipleship that the Lord will recognize when He comes again.</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.t6" guid="122f01fe-d9a8-4a8d-bbb4-517ce612cbc8">
				<h3 class="title" guid="f4292659-023c-4e9d-a138-2b31ddfc6fc5" pid="3qrqkNN2_kC9HdEyeja7kA" hash="YUJIUQ">Fulfilling the Purposes of Relief Society</h3>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p23" guid="6c738c5a-54c8-478c-8eaa-62fb7faf42f2" pid="EpmwlcJkU0iF4LrUdIY8LA" hash="BEPdIA">These and other essential teachings about Relief Society are now available for my granddaughters to study in <span class="emphasis">Daughters in My Kingdom: The History and Work of Relief Society.</span> This book contains a record of the legacy of Relief Society and the women of this Church. It will unify and align a worldwide sisterhood with the purposes of Relief Society and the patterns and privileges of disciples. It is a witness of women’s essential role in our Father’s plan of happiness, and it provides an immovable standard of what we believe, what we do, and what we will defend. The First Presidency has encouraged us to “study this book and allow its timeless truths and inspiring examples to influence [our] lives.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society.p24" guid="1572861b-01a3-4f6e-afad-1154dd252c18" pid="ssyM8Kxfg0GRiO2w3JnGUQ" hash="5JJpDA">Knowing that the organization of Relief Society was divinely created, President Joseph F. Smith told Relief Society sisters: “It is for you to lead the world and to lead especially the women of the world. … You are the head,” he said, “not the tail.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> As the time of the Lord’s return grows closer, I hope my granddaughters will become strong, faithful women who apply the principles and patterns of Relief Society in their lives. As Relief Society becomes a way of life for them, I hope they will serve in unity with others to fulfill its divine purposes. I have a testimony of the true restored Church of Jesus Christ, and I am grateful for the pattern of discipleship that was restored when the Lord inspired the Prophet Joseph Smith to organize Relief Society. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/10/what-i-hope-my-granddaughters-and-grandsons-will-understand-about-relief-society</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2011-general-relief-society-meeting/2011-09-0010-julie-b-beck-64k-eng.mp3" length="8347628" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2011 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Vision of Prophets regarding Relief Society: Faith, Family, Relief</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Faith, family, and relief—these three simple words have come to express the vision of prophets for sisters in the Church.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10485_000_44beckj" doc-version="2" hash="0yulvg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="Z62jKAJ9eUWmR42nL3ULzg" hash="fEkd8w">The Vision of Prophets regarding Relief Society: Faith, Family, Relief</h1><p class="authorName" pid="2VMHlBCki0ub0acTnt9ZdQ" hash="I5G8Dw">By Julie B. Beck</p><p class="kicker" pid="fnR6qFXM7E-ZRTCv42QPYw" hash="-Bvmmw">Faith, family, and relief—these three simple words have come to express the vision of prophets for sisters in the Church.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.p5" pid="JziShMj50UOISpWsWxB0wg" hash="LDOk_g">
      <span class="pageBreak" page-number="83"></span>In recent years I have been impressed to speak often about Relief Society—its purposes and qualities,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> the value of its history,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> its work, and its partnership with bishops and Melchizedek Priesthood quorums.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> It seems important now to focus some attention on the vision of prophets regarding Relief Society.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.p6" pid="Y6qi-8vxtkyeJ6u5ha5U-Q" hash="sTgSjg">Just as the Lord’s prophets have continually taught elders and high priests their purposes and duties, they have shared their vision for the sisters of the Relief Society. From their counsel, it is clear that the purposes of Relief Society are to increase faith and personal righteousness, strengthen families and homes, and seek out and help those in need. <span class="emphasis">Faith, family,</span> and <span class="emphasis">relief</span>—these three simple words have come to express the vision of prophets for sisters in the Church.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.p7" pid="bgD9rkbgqEinAlP-dSM1Ag" hash="HnDvhA">Since the beginning of the Restoration, prophets have shared their vision of strong, faithful, purposeful women who understand their eternal value and purpose. When the Prophet Joseph Smith established Relief Society, he directed its first president to “preside over this society, in taking care of the poor—administering to their wants, and attending to the various affairs of this institution.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> He envisioned the organization as “a select society, separate from all the evils of the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.p8" pid="jnaqp6f-5EmDZW68k7GDNA" hash="9JSa_w">Brigham Young, the second President of the Church, instructed his counselors and the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles to direct bishops to “let [the sisters] organize Female Relief Societies in the various wards.” He added, “Some may think this is a trifling thing, but it is not.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.p9" pid="BY5kL5NjgkyUD1-yXlunrg" hash="w0csqw">Later, President Joseph F. Smith said that in contrast to worldly organizations, which “are men-made, or women-made,” the Relief Society “is divinely made, divinely authorized, divinely instituted, divinely ordained of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> President Joseph Fielding Smith told the sisters that they had “been given power and authority to do a great many things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> He said, “You are members of the greatest women’s organization in the world, an organization which is a vital part of the kingdom of God on [the] earth and which is so designed and operated that it helps its faithful members to gain eternal life in our Father’s kingdom.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.t1">
      <h2 class="title" pid="UuW-yh9zLkKGEHqN2u3BKQ" hash="zLhdmw">An Extensive Sphere of Influence</h2>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.p11" pid="X151iLU7OkiRL4IKoNsYpQ" hash="c_e0LA">Every year hundreds of thousands of women and young women become part of this ever-expanding “circle of sisters.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> Thereafter, wherever a sister lives and wherever she serves, she retains her membership and association in Relief Society.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Because of Relief Society’s important purposes, the First Presidency has expressed their desire that young women begin their preparation for Relief Society well before they are 18 years old.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.p12" pid="8YXuhNe-CUqk_tvlrza1LA" hash="7KIYwQ">Relief Society is not a program. It is an official part of the Lord’s Church that is “divinely ordained of God” to teach, strengthen, and inspire sisters in their purpose regarding faith, family, and relief. Relief Society is a way of life for Latter-day Saint women, and its influence extends far beyond a Sunday class or a social gathering. It follows the pattern of female disciples who served with the Lord Jesus Christ and His Apostles in His ancient Church.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> We have been taught that “it is as obligatory upon a woman to draw into her life the virtues that are fostered by the Relief Society as it is an obligation for the men to build into their lives the patterns of character fostered by the priesthood.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.p13" pid="cqzbFX2Y0kGeA5_zerjFIg" hash="sne1gg">When the Prophet Joseph Smith <span class="pageBreak" page-number="84"></span>organized the Relief Society, he taught the sisters that they were to “relieve the poor” and “save souls.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> In their charge to “save souls,” sisters were authorized to organize and participate in an extensive sphere of influence. The first Relief Society president was set apart to expound the scriptures, and Relief Society still carries an essential teaching responsibility in the Lord’s Church. When Joseph Smith told the sisters that the organization of Relief Society would prepare them for the “privileges, blessings and gifts of the Priesthood,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> the Lord’s work of salvation was opened to them. Saving souls includes sharing the gospel and participating in missionary work. It includes engaging in temple and family history work. It includes doing everything possible to become spiritually and temporally self-reliant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.p14" pid="-9txxNy__EiMh00a-jEcsA" hash="iRtYQg">Elder John A. Widtsoe declared that Relief Society offers “relief of poverty, relief of illness; relief of doubt, relief of ignorance—relief of all that hinders the joy and progress of woman. What a magnificent commission!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.p15" pid="42h0vs7R6Eqi06ZdMNCsig" hash="SJZ6kA">President Boyd K. Packer has likened Relief Society to “a protecting wall.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> The responsibility to protect sisters and their families increases the significance of the watchcare and ministering of visiting teachers, and it is a demonstration of our willingness to remember our covenants with the Lord. As “ministers to the needy and to the afflicted,” we work in harmony with bishops to look after the temporal and spiritual needs of the Saints.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.p16" pid="Pt1tUzb5PkSx3RHUObmIGw" hash="HVhluw">President Spencer W. Kimball said: “There are many sisters who are living in rags—spiritual rags. They are entitled to gorgeous robes, spiritual robes. … It is your privilege to go into homes and exchange robes for rags.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> President Harold B. Lee shared this vision. He said: “Cannot you see why the Lord has put it upon the … Relief Society to visit these homes? Because, next to the Master himself, there are none in [the] Church who have a more lovely touch, a more complete understanding of the hearts and the lives of these individuals.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.p17" pid="ABmbAIz9AE6_qfiJrLfGHw" hash="r_q2Gw">President Joseph F. Smith cautioned Relief Society sisters and their leaders, saying that he did not want “to see the time when our Relief Societies will follow, or commingle and lose their own identity by mixing up with … woman-made organizations.” He expected the sisters “to lead the world and … especially the women of the world, in everything that is praise-worthy, everything that is God-like, everything that is uplifting and that is purifying to the children of men.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> His counsel emphasizes the charge to eliminate traditions, themes, fads, and trends and incorporate practices that are consistent with Relief Society purposes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.p18" pid="-2fCmaAa9kmNIDGZrXVPyQ" hash="VwIU3Q">Leaders who seek revelation can ensure that every meeting, lesson, class, activity, and effort of the Relief Society fulfills the purposes for which it was organized. The sociality, friendship, and unity we desire will be the sweet results of serving together with the Lord in His work.</p>
    </div>
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.t2">
      <h2 class="title" pid="Nq0uffMQMUCjDjpJfrvNHA" hash="9PrhxA">Fulfilling the Vision of Prophets</h2>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.p20" pid="5lotjDNNZkmaIRTqfxGO-w" hash="AblCUA">President Thomas S. Monson and his counselors recently testified “that the Lord has restored the fulness of the gospel through the Prophet Joseph Smith and that Relief Society is an important part of that restoration.” As evidence of their desire that the “glorious heritage” of Relief Society be preserved, the First Presidency recently published and distributed worldwide <span class="emphasis">Daughters in My Kingdom: The History and Work of Relief Society.</span> Within the pages of this book, we can find patterns and examples of sisters and brothers working in partnership in families and the Church, and we can learn principles about who we are, what we believe, and what we should protect. We have been encouraged by the First Presidency to study this important book and “allow its timeless truths and inspiring examples to influence [our] lives.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.p21" pid="I1_qpH2lm0-_dk_mA5i2-w" hash="zC_aVw">As sisters become more aligned <span class="pageBreak" page-number="85"></span>with the purposes of Relief Society, the vision of the prophets will be fulfilled. President Kimball said, “There is a power in this organization [of Relief Society] that has not yet been fully exercised to strengthen the homes of Zion and build the Kingdom of God—nor will it until both the sisters and the priesthood catch the vision of Relief Society.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span> He prophesied that “much of the major growth that is coming to the Church in the last days will come because many of the good women of the world (in whom there is often … an inner sense of spirituality) will be drawn to the Church in large numbers. This will happen to the degree that the women of the Church … are seen as distinct and different—in happy ways—from the women of the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26">26</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.p22" pid="lE-EouRoYk-A3VUOpA3Z-w" hash="Z7uaOg">I am grateful for the vision of prophets regarding Relief Society. I, like President Gordon B. Hinckley, “am convinced there is no other organization anywhere to match the Relief Society of this Church.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_27">27</span> It is our responsibility now to align ourselves with the vision of the prophets regarding Relief Society as we seek to increase faith, strengthen families, and provide relief.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief.p23" pid="cFVIPzn_bUK8a8lSYQu4AA" hash="C9iJsA">I close with the words of President Lorenzo Snow: “The future of the [Relief] Society is full of promise. As the Church grows, its field of usefulness will be correspondingly enlarged, and it will be even more potent for good than it has been in the past.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_28">28</span> To sisters who help advance the kingdom of God, he said, “As you have shared in these labors, so you will most certainly share in the triumph of the work and in the exaltation and glory which the Lord will give to His faithful children.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_29">29</span> Of this vision I also bear testimony in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2012/04/the-vision-of-prophets-regarding-relief-society-faith-family-relief</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2012-general-conference/2012-04-4040-julie-b-beck-64k-eng.mp3" length="5028815" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
