<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Kazuhiko Yamashita</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Kazuhiko Yamashita.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Kazuhiko%20Yamashita.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Kazuhiko Yamashita.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2011 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Missionaries Are a Treasure of the Church</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I am thankful that missionaries are called by the Lord, that they respond to that call, and that they are serving throughout the world.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50029123_000_5040" doc-version="2" hash="XV-P6w"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="VLc5lZnhmkagO3CSkqe6jg" hash="uHkvEA">Missionaries Are a Treasure of the Church</h1><p class="authorName" guid="5aec69cd-3dc6-4aa9-b49d-3a9a4c2c3054" pid="vcrvEKrTIEieQ-_KXqrzqQ" hash="5TQ1NA">Kazuhiko Yamashita</p><p class="kicker" pid="OHgt8fB1QUqYCV7sXhdCyg" hash="nqX-Mg">I am thankful that missionaries are called by the Lord, that they respond to that call, and that they are serving throughout the world.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="bb98bd38-addf-4c92-a379-0653b5f77239">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.p1" guid="562b6bee-7429-48f2-b7f3-209046dfade0" pid="j7eeXHI61kOjiZzJnTW1Cg" hash="Eq8bQA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="96"></span>One night a number of years ago, a newly called missionary named Elder Swan and his Japanese senior companion came to visit our home. Fortunately I was home, so I invited them in. When I greeted them at the door, my eyes were drawn to the coat that Elder Swan was wearing. Without thinking, I said to him, “That sure is a nice coat you are wearing!” However, it wasn’t a new coat, and it was rather faded. I assumed that the coat was one that a previous missionary had left behind in the missionary apartment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.p2" guid="68266b86-e8c7-415a-ba6e-19273d1277c3" pid="Q5gAhKm9eEyPRY_HuaNAfQ" hash="pQ0GRw">Elder Swan immediately responded to my words, and it was completely the opposite of what I had been thinking. In halting Japanese he replied, “Yes, this is a good coat. My father wore this coat when he served as a missionary in Japan over 20 years ago.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.p3" guid="6ed4eeb0-f593-4588-a3dd-6b00fc31f2e8" pid="zuaPQFvXpUqwOwWgtGnwCQ" hash="PDd28Q">His father had served in the Japan Okayama Mission. And when his son was leaving to serve a mission in Japan, he had given his coat to him. This picture shows that coat that two generations of Elder Swans wore in Japan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.p4" guid="ae393c49-3a6a-4a60-8852-d04ea68fa05e" pid="yf2kzeCczEqojfUhyN_xtA" hash="WNhhOw">I was touched when I heard Elder Swan’s words. And I now understood why Elder Swan wore his father’s coat while he was proselyting. Elder Swan had embarked on his mission having inherited his father’s love for Japan and its people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.p5" guid="f20cc789-285b-4789-b512-3ed1b7902bd3" pid="VxOpqFRkn0u7ZN1O5gVzHA" hash="AbQrDA">I am sure that some of you have experienced something similar to this. A number of missionaries serving in Japan have told me that their fathers, their mothers, their grandfathers, or their uncles have also served missions in Japan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.p6" guid="073daad7-afd4-443c-970a-58c01d165081" pid="Iy4ul0Qq6U2nO_BRb16XcQ" hash="DA4H2A">I would like to express my sincere love, respect, and feeling of thankfulness for all the returned missionaries who have served around the world. I am sure that those you helped convert have not forgotten you. “How beautiful upon the mountains are the feet of him that bringeth good tidings … !”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.p7" guid="44bc713d-82aa-45ba-bd66-aa058c37a7d5" pid="3HR8IDqi5UGrPW1SZV4WWw" hash="ysvmYQ">I am one of those converts. I was converted at 17, when I was a high school student. The missionary who performed my baptism was an Elder Rupp from Idaho. He was recently released as a stake president in Idaho. I have not seen him since I was newly baptized, but I have exchanged e-mails with him and talked to him by telephone. I have never forgotten him. His <span class="pageBreak" page-number="97"></span>kind, smiling face is etched into my memory. He was so happy when he learned that I was doing well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.p8" guid="aa4bc941-85eb-4aa9-862b-f8fe7822a072" pid="MQFOOunSl0-4YEuNNK9PtA" hash="4LVdsQ">When I was 17, I didn’t really have a good understanding of the messages that the missionaries had been teaching me. However, I had a special feeling about the missionaries, and I wanted to become like them. And I felt their deep and abiding love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.p9" guid="50ae1a90-cd2d-4932-82ed-9373d4f6b128" pid="-b2NSXcnWUCo2HuLX-TkvA" hash="ddyUQg">Let me tell you about the day I was baptized. It was July 15, and it was a very hot day. A woman was also baptized that day. The baptismal font had been handmade by the missionaries, and it wasn’t much to look at.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.p10" guid="307a9086-67a9-45a7-8301-4fa508ca43d8" pid="tEFPV7QlNUSnY07WQA8B2A" hash="dibWqg">We were confirmed right after we were baptized. First, the sister was confirmed by Elder Lloyd. I sat down with the other members, closed my eyes, and quietly listened. Elder Lloyd confirmed her and then began to pronounce a blessing on her. However, Elder Lloyd stopped talking, so I opened my eyes and looked at him with an intent gaze.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.p11" guid="400b67df-d04e-4d9f-89fc-d00fada45566" pid="MWfpqcI8hECG9k8-9Qq29Q" hash="hQRLQw">Even today I can clearly remember that scene. Elder Lloyd’s eyes were overflowing with tears. And for the first time in my life, I experienced being enveloped in the Holy Spirit. And through the Holy Spirit I gained a sure knowledge that Elder Lloyd loved us and that God loved us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.p12" guid="dfd89a99-a63b-44b6-8835-6f64128db540" pid="FWy4vTc1nEOP0MXUWXcPKQ" hash="LsZQBw">Then it was my turn to be confirmed. Again it was Elder Lloyd. He placed his hands on top of my head and confirmed me a member of the Church, bestowed the gift of the Holy Ghost, and then began pronouncing a blessing. And again he stopped talking. However, I now understood what was happening. I truly knew through the Holy Ghost that the missionaries loved me and that God loved me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.p13" guid="1410355f-72eb-4aa1-93bf-27e1b381c936" pid="1zxdUqIjbEq4jYAopwX5YA" hash="jRl0_A">I would now like to say a few words to the missionaries currently serving missions around the world. Your attitudes and the love that you show toward others are very significant messages. Even though I didn’t immediately grasp all the doctrines that the missionaries taught me, I felt of their great love, and their many acts of kindness taught me important lessons. Your message is a message of love, a message of hope, and a message of faith. Your attitude and your actions invite the Spirit, and the Spirit enables us to understand the things that are important. What I want to convey to you is that through your love, you are imparting the love of God. You are a treasure of this Church. I am so very thankful to all of you for your sacrifice and your dedication.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.p14" guid="6e977bc1-c033-4274-9ddb-d45e812bef50" pid="BgUczeJJs0GiapENSD_Tiw" hash="XVttPw">I also would like to talk to you future missionaries. In my own family, four of our children have served missions, and our fifth missionary will enter the Provo Missionary Training Center at the end of this month. Next <span class="pageBreak" page-number="98"></span>year our youngest is planning to serve a mission after graduating from high school.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.p15" guid="31b668b1-1e0b-4b4b-ad76-316eccb76fa3" pid="Y5x3isHOEEK__M-kTLjJYQ" hash="qcLCMg">So I speak to my sons and to all of you preparing to serve missions. It is necessary to bring three things with you on your mission:</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.f1"><ol class="number" guid="35682733-7026-4df6-88e3-40c5b9197c91"><li guid="997e3a3e-39c8-4f90-8815-73cd0d26415f" pid="AYtIgIRgWEKzfKH762oGAQ" hash="1aeFbQ">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p guid="a60c835c-2ef7-40e1-b4ad-10c9b7cf35ea" pid="u2OMGIhyvkaBELmlNICHiA" hash="pyKvDg">A desire to preach the gospel. The Lord wants you to search for His sheep and seek them out.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> People all over the world are waiting for you. Please go quickly to where they are. No one strives harder than missionaries to go to the rescue of others. I am one of those rescued.</p>
        </li><li guid="8a65300f-7448-4d31-9079-c423ba4f1953" pid="EW2_HH84jE-j6mOoE7D7CA" hash="2O96vw">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p guid="e710f54e-1860-4183-bdf9-9ab8a98303fe" pid="rvu1LZ1nQUya4faMChTD5w" hash="ueiNcQ">Develop your testimony. The Lord requires your “heart and a willing mind.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
        </li><li guid="6d11e6e0-651e-4f53-90ac-84815ea71692" pid="yEtGTPx-AUucJFuF6Ck3cA" hash="laj07g">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p guid="09491a3c-c862-473a-b0fe-008e3135aadb" pid="JfAsKbijEEKyyCQ4xnMDlA" hash="RfYv7g">Love others, just like Elder Swan, who brought his father’s coat and his father’s love for Japan and its people with him on his mission.</p>
        </li></ol></div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.p16" guid="a31edd5a-9894-45f1-a7a6-19e5197ec776" pid="vjmEpD56dkOHQJCsJVG7ng" hash="5kp3mQ">And for those of you who don’t know how to prepare to serve a mission, please go and see your bishop. I know that he will help you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.p17" guid="98d15758-5ff3-467e-af5f-e30c20d11fb1" pid="ai_Zu3BM8E2AIasmNk0tOA" hash="qys8nA">I am thankful that missionaries are called by the Lord, that they respond to that call, and that they are serving throughout the world. Let me say to all of you beloved returned missionaries: I am truly thankful for all your efforts. You are a treasure of this Church. And may you always continue to be missionaries and act like disciples of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church.p18" guid="8a3e10d3-12a2-4f26-b57f-6ad9435b78ee" pid="5UxIDYaqBkCWV_eGudXNAQ" hash="eSNl6g">I testify that we are our Father in Heaven’s children, that He loves us, and that He sent His Beloved Son, Jesus Christ, so that we can again return to His presence. I say these things in the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/10/missionaries-are-a-treasure-of-the-church</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2011-general-conference/2011-10-5040-elder-kazuhiko-yamashita-64k-eng.mp3" length="4614799" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2011 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Ambitious for Christ</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Yamashita encourages us to be “ambitious for Christ” by serving faithfully and diligently without complaint and by enduring trials joyfully.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60001311_000_36yamashita" doc-version="1" hash="nxtOeg">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="REWE4nBpZEylXjSdVzwFUg" hash="5uRNmA">Be Ambitious for Christ</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p2" pid="prfwkTQheUGFThAiMUi4Iw" hash="GegNZA1">By Elder Kazuhiko Yamashita</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p3" pid="XnJSPYg3kEuFV-WC1H0W-Q" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="VGUhORF1IEKnzqve03nkEw" hash="ikWhIA">We are ambitious for Christ when we serve faithfully, accept humbly, endure nobly, pray fervently, and partake worthily.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="AJE5lMtadUK9F2Kd4o2G5Q" hash="GegNZA">By Elder Kazuhiko Yamashita</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p5" pid="BNSiFU7U00-Xf3TGY5Oeqg" hash="Licenw">My dear brothers and sisters, today I would like to speak to the young people of the Church, including our wonderful missionaries. Of course, brothers and sisters who are young at heart are warmly invited to listen.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p6" pid="Afu848gxkEW5pR63j4C1XA" hash="Y7wZfA">Last August 21, President Russell M. Nelson dedicated the beautiful Sapporo Temple—the third temple in Japan. The Sapporo Temple is built in northern Japan in a place called Hokkaido. Like Utah, Hokkaido was settled by industrious, hardworking pioneers.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p7" pid="q4tP-1CgCk2tCePPfi4T_w" hash="WhulOg">In 1876, a renowned educator named Dr. William Clark<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> was invited to come to Hokkaido to teach. He lived in Japan for just eight months, but his Christian spirit left a lasting impression on his young non-Christian students. Before leaving, he gave his students a parting message that has become immortalized in this bronze statue.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> He said, “Boys, be ambitious!”—“Be ambitious for Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> His injunction to “be ambitious for Christ” can help direct daily decisions for today’s Latter-day Saints.</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=xQIyZVmaWkW7JE6z9HKY8Q"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813878/7c5f5eb14eab4f7eb060353a6830abe1/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813878/7c5f5eb14eab4f7eb060353a6830abe1/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813878/7c5f5eb14eab4f7eb060353a6830abe1/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813878/7c5f5eb14eab4f7eb060353a6830abe1/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813878/7c5f5eb14eab4f7eb060353a6830abe1/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813878/7c5f5eb14eab4f7eb060353a6830abe1/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813878/7c5f5eb14eab4f7eb060353a6830abe1/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813878/7c5f5eb14eab4f7eb060353a6830abe1/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813878/7c5f5eb14eab4f7eb060353a6830abe1/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813878/7c5f5eb14eab4f7eb060353a6830abe1/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Dr. William Clark" pid="xQIyZVmaWkW7JE6z9HKY8Q" hash="K_gBrg"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p8" pid="M8q3nofVFkunBkp251gr5A" hash="PotaWw">What does it mean to “be ambitious for Christ”? Being ambitious for Christ means being motivated, focused, and dedicated to His work. Being ambitious for Christ will seldom mean that we are singled out for public honor. Being ambitious for Christ means that we serve faithfully and diligently in our wards and branches without complaint and with joyful hearts.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p9" pid="rUUhGB6JnUGx3Qoimfi4gw" hash="6AFOJg">Our missionaries serving throughout the world are beautiful examples of those who are truly ambitious for Christ. A few years ago, Sister Yamashita and I served in the Japan Nagoya Mission. Our missionaries were so ambitious for Christ. One of those missionaries was a young man named Elder Cowan.</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=dfeTjNDJXUekXomi9dH-Gg"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813879/aa30d4e20446465a81b1ed0fe6411c0d/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813879/aa30d4e20446465a81b1ed0fe6411c0d/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813879/aa30d4e20446465a81b1ed0fe6411c0d/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813879/aa30d4e20446465a81b1ed0fe6411c0d/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813879/aa30d4e20446465a81b1ed0fe6411c0d/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813879/aa30d4e20446465a81b1ed0fe6411c0d/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813879/aa30d4e20446465a81b1ed0fe6411c0d/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813879/aa30d4e20446465a81b1ed0fe6411c0d/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813879/aa30d4e20446465a81b1ed0fe6411c0d/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813879/aa30d4e20446465a81b1ed0fe6411c0d/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Elder Cowan with President and Sister Yamashita" pid="dfeTjNDJXUekXomi9dH-Gg" hash="LJkr9w"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p10" pid="kLg1h6IkBUiLd_8a7vaeLg" hash="Wu1a2w">Elder Cowan did not have a right leg because of a bicycle accident as a youth. A few weeks after he entered the mission, I received a phone call from his companion. Elder Cowan’s prosthetic leg had broken while he was riding his bike. We took him to a good repair facility, and there in a private room, I saw his leg for the first time. I realized how much pain he had been suffering. His prosthetic leg was repaired, and he returned to his area.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p11" pid="Md4G1pZ3Mk6MlpaJLvcBIw" hash="3VWfHg">However, as the weeks went by, the prosthesis continued to break again and again. The area medical adviser recommended that Elder Cowan return home for a possible mission reassignment. I resisted this advice because Elder Cowan was a great missionary and he had a strong desire to remain in Japan. Gradually, though, Elder Cowan began to approach his physical limit. In spite of this, he did not murmur or complain.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p12" pid="nMc0hPTgeE6CZI_SMJSMIA" hash="C8zyLA">Again, I was advised that Elder Cowan be allowed to serve in a place that did not require him to ride a bike. I pondered this situation. I thought about Elder Cowan and his future, and I prayed about the matter. I felt impressed that, yes, Elder Cowan should return home and await reassignment. I phoned him and expressed my love and concern and told him of my decision. He did not say anything in reply. I could only hear him weeping on the other end of the phone. I said, “Elder Cowan, you don’t have to answer me right now. I will call you tomorrow. Please consider my recommendation with sincere prayer.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p13" pid="bD3REPVYfk2LGegtMiGhJQ" hash="NJg9fg">When I called him the next morning, he humbly said he would follow my counsel.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p14" pid="coBg3ttpC02Nw0pTpzZQ4w" hash="I7kRDA">During my final interview with him, I asked him this question: “Elder Cowan, did you request on your missionary application to be sent to a mission where you would not have to ride a bike?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p15" pid="sRzvteii2EOfR9cbO0ZnaQ" hash="WP6vqA">He said, “Yes, President, I did.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p16" pid="LyRmSWO0l0eJszC-51R3pw" hash="atPWKg">I responded, “Elder Cowan, you were called to the Japan Nagoya Mission, where you would have to ride a bike. Did you tell this to your stake president?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p17" pid="rOIH5Ke7pkGyQ1YoEIA7Eg" hash="2ZYCWw">I was surprised by his answer. He said, “No, I didn’t. I determined that if <span class="emphasis">that</span> is where the Lord called me, I would go to the gym and train my body to be able to ride a bike.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p18" pid="BhVNG6Z9oEqQ9D2JsZqKrQ" hash="15zpag">At the conclusion of our interview, he asked me this question with tears in his eyes: “President Yamashita, why did I come to Japan? Why am I here?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p19" pid="8ZEREjKzaUi48d-MDrI2jw" hash="WMU_gQ">I answered him without hesitation: “Elder Cowan, I know one reason you came here. You came here for my benefit. I have come to understand what a great young man I have been serving with. I am blessed to know you.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p20" pid="w9f6Mgan2kabHCxf9vybtA" hash="gljUBA">I am happy to report that Elder Cowan returned to his loving home and was reassigned to serve in a mission where he could use a car for his travel. I am proud not only of Elder Cowan but also of all the missionaries throughout the world who serve willingly without murmuring or complaining. Thank you, elders and sisters, for your faith, your focus, and your strong ambition for Christ.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p21" pid="JGfLpsSbcEKfM1A3UH-hqg" hash="mqqiQw">The Book of Mormon contains many accounts of those who were ambitious for Christ. Alma the Younger, as a young man, persecuted the Church and its members. He later went through a dramatic change of heart and served as a powerful missionary. He sought the Lord’s direction, and he blessed his companions as he served with them. The Lord strengthened him, and he overcame the trials he faced.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p22" pid="IUOdFpuupUGMLUE90h0-ng" hash="wXyesg">This Alma gave his son Helaman the following counsel:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p23" pid="4WhwAS-OJUqlJ4XEQolVzA" hash="fFo4fg">“Whosoever shall put their trust in God shall be supported in their trials, and their troubles, and their afflictions. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p24" pid="WmcMhowf3EmjuevPYW2Xng" hash="FuTmkQ">“… Keep the commandments of God. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p25" pid="uEyjw7KghEaKvRTSXcgS1w" hash="gUy1yA">“Counsel with the Lord in all thy doings, and he will direct thee for good.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p26" pid="MjWGtPaop06GJjVSZ6ZEzw" hash="luSSUQ">Our second son lived much of his youth apart from the Church. When he turned 20, he had an experience that made him want to change his life. With love, prayers, and help from his family and members of the Church, and ultimately through the compassion and grace of the Lord, he returned to the Church.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p27" pid="Acu8KDCC8EGBf0wGlun3zw" hash="hEQ_mg">He was later called to serve in the Washington Seattle Mission. He initially suffered great discouragement. Every night for the first three months, he would go into the bathroom and cry. Like Elder Cowan, he sought to understand “Why am I here?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p28" pid="kK-mlxnZnUeBJgJlEEK4nw" hash="Hd9QPw">After he served for a year, we received an email that was an answer to our prayers. He wrote: “Right now I can really feel the love of God and of Jesus. I will work hard to become like the prophets of old. Though I am also experiencing a lot of difficulties, I am truly happy. Serving Jesus really is the best thing ever. There is nothing as wonderful as this. I am so happy.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p29" pid="i_TNpVlmR0CiT9FE1_I-TQ" hash="NTgIdA">He felt as Alma did: “And oh, what joy, and what marvelous light I did behold; yea, my soul was filled with joy as exceeding as was my pain!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p30" pid="Aw_zrBGhnkudeYkCkVxmMw" hash="8zt-cQ">In our lives we experience trials, but if we are ambitious for Christ, we can focus on Him and feel joy even in the midst of them. Our Redeemer is the ultimate example. He understood His holy mission and was obedient to the will of God the Father. What a choice blessing it is to bring His wonderful example to our remembrance each week as we partake of the sacrament.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p31" pid="f8dXm7j1X0OxFrGF21Lrsg" hash="ug0UAg">My dear brothers and sisters, we are ambitious for Christ when we serve faithfully, accept humbly, endure nobly, pray fervently, and partake worthily.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p32" pid="ZlhnyfrRG0S9rKtJmgzcbA" hash="Xluj1Q">May we be ambitious for Christ as we accept our difficulties and trials with patience and faith and find joy in our covenant path.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ.p33" pid="iXwXIKguHEqjx1xvcO0Cyw" hash="TRceZA">I testify that the Lord knows you. He knows your struggles and concerns. He knows of your desires to serve Him with devotion and, yes, even ambition. May He guide and bless you as you do so. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/10/be-ambitious-for-christ</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2016-general-conference/2016-10-2060-kazuhiko-yamashita-64k-eng.mp3" length="5448947" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
