<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Keith K. Hilbig</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Keith K. Hilbig.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Keith%20K.%20Hilbig.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Keith K. Hilbig.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2001 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Create or Continue Priesthood Links</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links?lang=eng</link>
      <description>When we serve righteously … , we are strengthening our priesthood link and connecting it ever more securely to those who have preceded and who will follow us.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029371_000_020" doc-version="2" hash="OIdyIA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="1hZZwB6ryUKWI3EU7mptOA" hash="FosCLQ">Create or Continue Priesthood Links</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="9aIQM70IpEiXRH7JcTSgUw" hash="mFT4Hg">Keith K. Hilbig</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="jeSERpaLG0e3rjaHOzPbjQ" hash="X7ieOg">When we serve righteously … , we are strengthening our priesthood link and connecting it ever more securely to those who have preceded and who will follow us.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1381.jpg" alt="Elder Keith K. Hilbig" pid="qEqO7hPolUWRcfqNIHwx6w" hash="5z77iw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.p1" pid="evI1M0AyLESaRcveYDEjMQ" hash="Z4xZCA">Within this vast congregation of priesthood bearers assembled here and throughout the world sit several generations—tens of thousands of sons, fathers, grandfathers, even great-grandfathers—all of whom have faith in Christ, seek to keep His commandments, and desire to serve Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.p2" pid="6qi5D0T8rUS1m6QutdhfHQ" hash="v1SDNQ">Some are part of a long tradition of priesthood men stretching back in time. Others are the very first men in their respective families to bear the priesthood of God. But all have the opportunity—and responsibility—either to create or to continue a chain of worthy men who honor the priesthood and render service in the kingdom, thereby linking families together from generation to generation. It is <span class="emphasis">your</span> individual link in that priesthood chain of which I would speak tonight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.p3" pid="Imk9ecGeiEyU4TRTsOCs7g" hash="e2jNRA">In each dispensation faithful men have been given the priesthood to further the Lord’s purposes. The scriptures recount the passing of priesthood authority from prophet to prophet, beginning with Adam.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.p4" pid="P7MfKu5LbEKmxOzPcZ7Yow" hash="T7s88g">We are figuratively part of that priesthood chain stretching back to the beginnings of the earth. However, each of us is now literally engaged in the critical task of creating our own strong priesthood link so as to be joined with our own forefathers and to our own posterity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.p5" pid="F18MPhKHNEm_KXfo8oMyTA" hash="u-we4Q">If one fails to obtain or to honor the Melchizedek Priesthood, his link will be missing, and eternal life will be unattainable (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.79" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:79</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.41-42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:41–42</a>). Hence, our great effort as a church to teach the message of the Restoration to all who are willing to listen and to prepare all who are desirous for the blessings of the priesthood and the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.p6" pid="MXjab18K2EmHsM4_2gUCiw" hash="dQs1pw">Our privilege to bear the priesthood of God tonight has its beginnings in our premortal existence. The prophet Alma explained that men ordained to the Melchizedek Priesthood on earth have been “called and prepared from the foundation of the world according to the foreknowledge of God, on account of their exceeding faith and good works; in the first place being left to choose good or evil; therefore they having chosen good, and exercising exceedingly great faith, are called with a holy calling” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/13.3" class="scriptureRef">Alma 13:3</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.p7" pid="fY5qtofiQkOir6iwGsHLVQ" hash="q1-dJQ">The Lord has long intended you to be a creator or a continuer of the chain of faithful bearers in your priesthood family. It was your faith and wise exercise of free agency—in the premortal existence and here in mortality—which permitted you to receive the “holy calling” of the priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.p8" pid="MhyxSpcNdE-1N686wNcHrw" hash="-qv5SQ">The Prophet Joseph Smith stated in 1844, “Every man who has a calling to minister to the inhabitants of the world was ordained to that very purpose in the Grand Council of heaven before this world was” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith,</span> sel. Joseph Fielding Smith [1976], 365).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.p9" pid="JInyJnmfAkCkgoNAukkoQg" hash="yt0UxA">Thus, whether as the first in your family or as the fifth generation to hold the priesthood, we have each come to earth with a personal heritage of faithfulness and foreordination. Such knowledge gives us a firm resolve to always honor the priesthood and thereby to create or continue a multigenerational family in the Church and in the celestial kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.p10" pid="qA6nyMUg6ketwtJ_kZQ6oA" hash="ysGgyA">We often define <span class="emphasis">priesthood</span> as the power and authority to act in the name of God upon the earth. But service to our Savior, our family, and our fellowman also defines our priesthood. The Savior intends that we exercise our priesthood primarily for the benefit of others. We cannot bless or baptize ourselves, nor provide the ordinances of the temple to ourselves. Rather, every priesthood bearer must rely upon others to lovingly exercise their priesthood authority and power to help each of us progress spiritually.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.p11" pid="q3NQYtldrkaDqO1jXj6rug" hash="BTrdgw">I was able to learn the importance of priesthood service not only by observing my grandfather, father, and brother magnify their callings but also from the brethren in my ward who were priesthood models to me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.p12" pid="tELTOhFkLUCn_B7wJVelCg" hash="nMv08Q">As a newly ordained teacher in the Aaronic Priesthood, my first home teaching companion was Henry Wilkening, a high priest nearly 60 years my senior. He was a German immigrant, a shoemaker by trade, small in stature, but an energetic and faithful shepherd to the families assigned to us. I trotted behind him (for he seemed to walk and to climb stairs much faster than I could) during our monthly visits, which took us into sobering environments new to my sheltered experience. He expected me to present part of each lesson and to make all the appointments, but mostly I listened and watched as he aided brothers and sisters with various spiritual and social, economic and emotional needs previously unknown to me as a 14-year-old.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.p13" pid="6i77Vy8U50Wxa14_JJ0grw" hash="j-OaTA">I began to realize how much good could be done by a single faithful priesthood bearer. I watched Brother Wilkening forging a strong priesthood link for himself through his loving service to those families in need—and to me in my youth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.p14" pid="OqNkvfUYEUC1tfo--cJsrg" hash="TCrkJg">The many priesthood men I observed while growing up taught me that providing priesthood service to others is not dependent upon a particular title or specific calling or formal position in the kingdom. Rather the opportunity arises from and is inherent within the fact that one has received the priesthood of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.p15" pid="TYFsEFYn0kKGyHpWb1kI1A" hash="XeU--Q">President J. Reuben Clark Jr. wisely taught at the April 1951 general conference: “In the service of the Lord, it is not where you serve but how. In [T]he Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, one takes the place to which one is duly called, which place one neither seeks nor declines” (in Conference Report, Apr. 1951, 154).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.p16" pid="S1tx1zuqfUyhjR1cjh4fUQ" hash="EeBP5Q">When we serve righteously with all our heart, whatever the responsibility apportioned to us, we are strengthening our priesthood link and connecting it ever more securely to those who have preceded and who will follow us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links.p17" pid="0XWQElHMkkyQ7Qq2OCne-A" hash="1l0bPQ">I bear solemn testimony of the Savior’s divinity and atoning sacrifice and of the restoration of His priesthood which we are privileged to bear—and pray that every son and father participating in this meeting will determine this night to serve the Lord by faithfully honoring the priesthood and firmly connecting his personal link to the priesthood chain which will bind him, his forefathers, and his posterity together throughout eternity. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2001/10/create-or-continue-priesthood-links</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2001-general-conference/2001-10-3040-elder-keith-k-hilbig-64k-eng.mp3" length="3743094" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2001 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quench Not the Spirit Which Quickens the Inner Man</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man?lang=eng</link>
      <description>When we invite the Holy Ghost to fill our minds with light and knowledge, He “quickens” us, that is to say, enlightens and enlivens the inner man or woman.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008332_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="sfPuqg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="CDS44N1qzUSCyVbWSe-Xlg" hash="tHCwNg">Quench Not the Spirit Which Quickens the Inner Man</h1><p class="authorName" guid="9892d2d1-4183-4bde-a6e8-5018ec20f3d3" pid="G7XIvsf0kUC3yFqh87TQew" hash="mFT4Hg">Keith K. Hilbig</p><p class="kicker" pid="3g6ZbtBZSU6oUYnCv7LGVg" hash="q_3T3g">When we invite the Holy Ghost to fill our minds with light and knowledge, He “quickens” us, that is to say, enlightens and enlivens the inner man or woman.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="4d53f5bd-ba61-4d08-8d46-c8d6531ee2b0">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/HILBIGKK_01.jpg" alt="Elder Keith K. Hilbig" guid="0bff7c46-16f2-408c-92c3-df042d9ed2e5" pid="0CyJWKxPv0etZkl1MviuHQ" hash="BbOJFg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="q0M3xeEzdkWPy7UKJ5SjIA" hash="mqE-eA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="37"></span>In 1 Thessalonians chapter 5, Paul admonished the members to act in a manner as becometh Saints. He proceeded to list appropriate attributes and behaviors. In verse <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-thes/5.19" class="scriptureRef">19</a> Paul counseled with these four simple words: “Quench not the Spirit.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="QXqnT_Kb6US1S6ZANEt4zg" hash="uBpuZw">Interestingly, some 500 years <span class="emphasis">before</span> Paul’s writings, a Book of Mormon prophet named Jacob sought to teach the gospel of Jesus Christ to a resistant people. He boldly inquired of them as follows: “Will ye reject the words of the prophets; and will ye … deny the good word of Christ, … and the gift of the Holy Ghost, and quench the Holy Spirit?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="-N82M3zDo0-NBaWsdMgawg" hash="P8fEEQ">In our day, so many centuries <span class="emphasis">after</span> both Paul and Jacob, we too must be careful <span class="emphasis">not</span> to hinder, disregard, or quench the Spirit in our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="1AHCtD83506Kh_MyNREkwA" hash="U8mPSg">The beckoning invitations of the world attempt to divert our attention from the strait and narrow path. The adversary labors to dull our sensitivity to the promptings of the Spirit, whether we are teenagers, young adults, or mature men and women. The role of the Spirit, the Holy Ghost, is essential in every season of our mortal lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="5UW9RmJUKUaQWUab299m_A" hash="k7yMVg">From the beginning the Father has promised each of His spirit sons and daughters that through the Atonement and Resurrection of His Beloved Son, we <span class="emphasis">all</span> might return to God’s presence and inherit the blessings of eternal life <span class="pageBreak" page-number="38"></span>in the highest degree of the celestial kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="Ua5JXavf6UWs6TmfMdiC6Q" hash="nHOwpg">Each of us knew that the journey to exaltation would be long, strenuous, and sometimes lonely, but we also knew that we would not travel alone. Heavenly Father provides all who fulfill the prerequisites of faith, repentance, and baptism with a companion and guide, the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="WKowQ8B1uU-adYOQwB8kTw" hash="qB33hQ">The path to eternal life is not on a plateau. Rather, it is an incline, ever onward and upward. Hence, ever-increasing spiritual understanding and energy are required to reach our destination. Because the pernicious opposition by Satan continues, the continuous enlightened guidance of the Holy Ghost is absolutely essential. We dare not hinder, disregard, or quench the promptings of the Holy Spirit. Yet when it comes to drawing upon the promptings and the blessings which flow from the Holy Ghost, we often “live far beneath our privileges.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="cEAWOUyFwkS9OgN-9TpEAw" hash="ceTOoA">In the Pearl of Great Price, Moses recorded that Adam, having been baptized and having received the Holy Ghost, “became quickened in the inner man.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="8mSh76foAEaM8j2L_hpSMA" hash="5pci7A">When we invite the Holy Ghost to fill our minds with light and knowledge, He “quickens” us, that is to say, enlightens and enlivens the inner man or woman.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> As a result we notice a measurable difference in our soul. We feel strengthened, filled with peace and joy. We possess spiritual energy and enthusiasm, both of which enhance our natural abilities. We can accomplish more than we otherwise could do on our own. We yearn to become a holier person.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="2YLVNIgVtkqCJ9WOeUyv-A" hash="k0Ygsg">Do you wish to know the price to be paid for the privileges that are offered after we have received the Holy Ghost? The price is not a predetermined or fixed amount; rather, it is determined by each of us individually.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="fTFVoXxru0m78Kdk42sviw" hash="CGAObA">If you set your payment, which is your personal effort, very low, you may not be able to avail yourself of <span class="emphasis">all</span> the Spirit has to offer. You may even quench the Spirit! However, if you set your personal contribution high, you will reap an abundant harvest from the Spirit. The payment I reference is, of course, not money; rather, it is a greater commitment to and involvement in personal spiritual endeavors and behaviors.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.f1"><p pid="Hsq5zix7ikOWWvJ6nrMfpg" hash="GI6IaQ">We determine the level of our current personal contribution by examining our present choices and priorities against questions such as these:</p><ol class="number" guid="68e5604f-e228-4925-9d8e-1fa974230a4c"><li guid="511bc99b-babf-494b-a6d9-735f01497373" pid="ttnDTJnB_0KnMW1-jybANQ" hash="hsk6vg">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p guid="b543d8cb-a467-4c51-bf16-0733d53bc320" pid="SXrEyIwkNE6GXwCyqf2WXw" hash="uj_5lw">Do I spend more time with sports than Church attendance or callings?</p>
        </li><li guid="76ee5294-3754-4069-9adc-f72cecdd665c" pid="ozvpJUCCFkWOreJ1M2QqLQ" hash="kxS90w">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p guid="20f3f94b-1594-404f-bb8d-8b27b3ffe324" pid="q3NNF3VvOkSlxP8b0jwgTg" hash="DKLAfA">If I have a free day, do I choose to attend the temple or to visit the mall?</p>
        </li><li guid="ca83337c-1fa8-4505-bb65-4659c9215bf4" pid="mKCDeR_E70-MalgCNIw5FA" hash="-03xLA">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p guid="b7524bbd-1360-47a4-81a6-a80054c75b4f" pid="NJkCi807w0iVjxgymTmP1g" hash="Gg0GxQ">Do I resort to computer games or surfing the Internet rather than offering meaningful service to others in my home and community?</p>
        </li><li guid="233c3a5b-2e07-4249-96c7-0247be91c6ab" pid="18egie1nDU22ZCS7kmWeKg" hash="D6eyfA">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p guid="d0dafa1c-c6cd-4202-bdc6-9cab7c483338" pid="xKPSwGn2TkqQjYHfZa07wA" hash="BhG7yg">Do I read the newspaper religiously but find it difficult to read the scriptures daily?</p>
        </li></ol></div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="NFMZxVzG8Ual-24bV4DH4w" hash="Z4AaUg">There are other questions you might formulate which will reveal the appropriateness of your current choices and priorities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="R8yTlNYdaEmSUqQUnZztXA" hash="2nSGYQ">Whatever level of spiritual development each of us may presently have, there always exists a higher level within our reach. Time is a most precious asset. Would you consider <span class="pageBreak" page-number="39"></span>investing more of your time in the things of eternity in order to merit the constant companionship of the Holy Ghost and to benefit more fully from His influence?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="Nokx13esZ06iij01PQxBlQ" hash="yJfGww">If your answer is yes, the initial offering in this pursuit of deeper spirituality is an intensified desire to receive greater inspiration and to become more holy. When these desires fill our hearts, we will eagerly increase the price we pay for heaven’s help.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="v6-h6EbfFkqZLvzTG44RtQ" hash="9GroTw">Our next contribution to this effort will be to immerse ourselves more consistently in the words of Christ and of the prophets. When our study efforts expand, so will the influence of the Holy Ghost in our lives increase. Let us search the scriptures with pen in hand, making note of new insights and recording spiritual promptings. Thereafter, let us strive to <span class="emphasis">apply</span> what has been learned to our personal lives. The Spirit will quicken our inner selves; new understanding will come precept upon precept.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="Zv0fqcEo40CyY5jZlUkM-w" hash="whEftA">To ensure we quench not the Spirit, but rather invite His presence, there is another step to take. Let us pray frequently and fervently. The Savior’s tender and comprehensive promise is recorded in the Doctrine and Covenants:</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.f2"><ul class="bullet" guid="229d3671-dbb8-4baa-9312-6bdd6bb0e3de"><li guid="4417c672-ed6a-4cce-809b-8ee3d30d1480" pid="NmkezGR5TES34UY90UKb8Q" hash="Uu68NQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p guid="b53b17e1-a09c-4d15-821c-803ce1162f52" pid="CRvV0wQOW02LyYBRFbenEA" hash="WIWH0Q">“Draw near unto me and I will draw near unto you.”</p>
        </li><li guid="6d0ad386-048d-4e43-a915-dbcc6bbd8949" pid="sA8oNfIN0kWGRVSVU_EBhA" hash="W6Cw5Q">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p guid="5ed6ecab-0c3a-42a5-9486-83193083df9b" pid="L9q4_JoiPkKcsGi2VBYngg" hash="5cwS8A">“Seek me diligently and ye shall find me.”</p>
        </li><li guid="28ac239b-f414-46ca-8ae0-0fdfbe57cf65" pid="DBqU6vZHa069QQ87cCcpTA" hash="IbJoYg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p guid="f04bc4d2-9a86-4061-8a5e-5d98bb66aa98" pid="XX5l7XJVAEiacohVthEmMw" hash="IntR8Q">“Ask, and ye shall receive.”</p>
        </li><li guid="b158d83a-fee7-4784-8f81-d6d011485455" pid="HGFAjsrTwE2uv8Fba4AoHA" hash="PyMMag">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p guid="4f207f72-1135-4eb7-8075-94e2c1490750" pid="_FCq2w_0PU2SoFtMdSVIIA" hash="BQSVSQ">“Knock, and it shall be opened unto you.”</p>
        </li><li guid="c0a5764b-07f5-436b-81ec-c4dff4b39009" pid="vNa5V0bYcUyNktbCbUVxWA" hash="xFStkQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p guid="ead9e7eb-7e7e-4151-a632-c8d492c98f1c" pid="FWNcWVUEUEqFx6iLs1h8EQ" hash="jSdm6Q">“Whatsoever ye ask the Father in my name it shall be given unto you, that is expedient for you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
        </li></ul></div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="-q28kL1BQ0GOgoIAX3Vbkw" hash="mP3y_A">Note that sequence, brothers and sisters. We draw nearer to the Savior as we keep His commandments with exactness. We earnestly petition the Father in the name of Christ. Then, through the promptings of the Holy Ghost, we receive divine direction and clear understanding.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="V355qYLVok6X8LS1cSpV4g" hash="dFRRiw">As we fast, renew our covenants during the sacrament, and attend the temple, we further access the Spirit. In these settings the Holy Ghost may manifest His influence with great impact.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="qXQzetazzkqOq1uCDJYI3g" hash="SF335A">The temple is a marvelous environment to seek personal revelation. When we attend as often as we can and listen thoughtfully, pondering the glorious promises and expectations pertaining to eternity, we depart with heightened understanding of our Heavenly Father’s plan for us. The Holy Ghost extends our vision and allows that eternal perspective to influence the decisions we make in our daily lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.p" pid="S2pD-WuUsUSAfzzOMwPGNw" hash="MAqgMw">If we undertake this effort and quench not the Spirit, our inner being is quickened. As we persevere, eternal life awaits us. Thus, we dare not quench the Spirit through disobedience or neglect. Rather, let us “live in the Spirit,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> enhancing the sacred and essential role of the Holy Ghost in our individual lives. I testify that as we truly seek the Spirit, we shall benefit more fully from the quiet, but essential, workings of the Holy Ghost. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man.f3"><title>Notes</title><ol class="number" guid=""><li guid="ce93c117-3e96-4570-aa07-9267ab277446" pid="nI1_JYCLi02zqL0Zjzsl5Q" hash="wggxMQ1">
        <span class="label">1.</span>
        <p guid="b7066a81-2def-422e-9379-f97d8ab4a158" pid="s_BHe6DpFEqhwHPF6EnKjw" hash="3a1mow">
          <a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/6.8" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 6:8</a>.</p>
      </li><li guid="4fe4dcf6-1a81-4f7d-a872-448e73a8e4f5" pid="WDn3w2bpBE-_vwuwWiQymQ" hash="X6S2rQ1">
        <span class="label">2.</span>
        <p guid="6cb471ce-3889-4567-9795-2254a30e8c2a" pid="H0KpuTKe5UqaaNBFxPH8jA" hash="tmEMoQ">Brigham Young, <span class="emphasis">Discourses of Brigham Young,</span> sel. John A. Widtsoe (1954), 32.</p>
      </li><li guid="a2b838fb-9f5d-45c6-baf6-62e614a9d3a8" pid="ZhiTh6N8D0m5dRfFY9qaCQ" hash="-UvTPA1">
        <span class="label">3.</span>
        <p guid="e3c9526c-6e6b-4574-b236-1af29b737983" pid="_f_uxDEO4EiC8yv24cC-gw" hash="jsLkpg">
          <a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/6.65" class="scriptureRef">Moses 6:65</a>.</p>
      </li><li guid="73c738f7-fdcf-4df6-8ec5-679eb2c778a7" pid="bYrXTH3EOkioLSerTe96lw" hash="eVdp_A1">
        <span class="label">4.</span>
        <p guid="1f2eafbc-d28d-4786-9bdc-fbee16dfd821" pid="-7JG8N2v6EK5W7PfsFNdoQ" hash="YLikmA">See Parley P. Pratt, <span class="emphasis">Key to the Science of Theology,</span> 9th ed. (1965), 101: “The gift of the Holy Ghost … quickens all the intellectual faculties, increases, enlarges, expands and purifies all the natural passions and affections; and adapts them, by the gift of wisdom, to their lawful use.”</p>
      </li><li guid="0af0037b-43e5-4db1-865d-489d4f5f30e8" pid="CFJ0PGW0GUe9dM4ecO-fag" hash="oDIbNw1">
        <span class="label">5.</span>
        <p guid="b68b0be4-e718-4e14-aa4b-19bd1b562a94" pid="rH0c7HE6kk6zH0AthBLvyg" hash="cCip_g">
          <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.63-64" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:63–64</a>.</p>
      </li><li guid="7fd65341-2213-42c3-806f-1c5c9ed4be93" pid="tOMXZzIQ0UKaMakwiWuMHQ" hash="pIMJYg1">
        <span class="label">6.</span>
        <p guid="48d9b5df-0c8e-4e1f-9435-2bbe2497176e" pid="jKxVYLgfTESdz2WM-Jn1Hw" hash="bj65gw">
          <a href="/scriptures/nt/gal/5.25" class="scriptureRef">Galatians 5:25</a>.</p>
      </li></ol></div>
    <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/HILBIGKK_01.jpg" alt="Elder Keith K. Hilbig" guid="0bff7c46-16f2-408c-92c3-df042d9ed2e5" pid="Fhy9Kx7Y3kW1n-QV67joEQ" hash="BbOJFg1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="0bff7c46-16f2-408c-92c3-df042d9ed2e5"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/10/quench-not-the-spirit-which-quickens-the-inner-man</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2007-general-conference/2007-10-2060-elder-keith-k-hilbig-64k-eng.mp3" length="4443170" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
