<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Keith B. McMullin</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Keith B. McMullin.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Keith%20B.%20McMullin.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Keith B. McMullin.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 1996 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 1996 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>“Ye May Know”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Humbly, gratefully, I stand before you to testify of God’s words and works. I come in the spirit of one going before to prepare the way. The commission to do so comes from the Lord. My desire is to help us prepare for His Second Coming and to dwell i</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_96905_000_004" doc-version="2" hash="Yp5y_Q">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="JADwvC5TQUCY78Zkh9x3cA" hash="RAp6Vw">“Ye May Know”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="WjpMfAYfJUmIK7iwTwG5ow" hash="bnTkHA">Keith B. McMullin</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1eee.jpg" alt="Bishop Keith B. McMullin" pid="rpVaTGETok2xXbtWk_bCuw" hash="y5UdTA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p1" pid="lhky9bjwHkm2EHRp1OFtkQ" hash="kGVn7w">Humbly, gratefully, I stand before you to testify of God’s words and works. I come in the spirit of one going before to prepare the way. The commission to do so comes from the Lord. My desire is to help us prepare for His Second Coming and to dwell in His presence, to enjoy the gifts and graces He alone can bestow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p2" pid="sIwefUYRs06uZXR2AINHZA" hash="6Zu4dQ">During the course of this general conference, much will be said concerning the Lord’s work and what Heavenly Father desires of His children. These are sacred things. May it be known that the speakers do not stand alone in their declarations. Accompanying their testimonies, I raise my voice as yet another witness. This process is referred to as the <span class="emphasis">law of witnesses.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p3" pid="-BV3LYO_TUmS8oo95miwYA" hash="VPIIaw">This law was established to introduce, affirm, and seal the truth upon the hearts of God’s children. One never stands alone in carrying the word of God to the world. Moses was called as a prophet to lead Israel, but he was not left alone. The Lord sent to him his brother, Aaron, not only as a voice, but as a witness with Moses that the God of Abraham had spoken.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p4" pid="tVTPwPLBy0O4zh0y_aXlFg" hash="2vXHlQ">This law of witnesses ushered in the birth, life, and mission of Christ Jesus. Holy angels, John the Baptist, prophets, apostles, the Holy Ghost, the Savior himself, and God our Father all declared His divinity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p5" pid="ywLTf34Oxk-Ge3KSkpqikg" hash="v6ZbWA">This same pattern prevailed at each step in the Restoration of the gospel of Jesus Christ in these latter days. Multiple witnesses, reliable beyond refute, have written and spoken of what their ears heard, their eyes beheld, their hearts understood. In every dispensation, two or more witnesses have joined their voices in such proclamations. It is the pattern of heaven. Said the Apostle Paul, “In the mouth of two or three witnesses shall every word be established” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-cor/13.1" class="scriptureRef">2 Cor. 13:1</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p6" pid="z6fDLdSAv0eW536qVGYCJQ" hash="HidYBQ">The essential nature of witnesses was brought forcibly to my mind some years ago while seeking permission from a man for his wife and children to be baptized. Our missionaries had taught the family of the divinity of Christ, the sacred appearance of God the Father and His Beloved Son to the Prophet Joseph Smith in 1820, and the Restoration of the true Church upon the earth. To each point, the missionaries bore fervent testimony, and the Holy Ghost confirmed to the mother and children that it was all true. They wished to be baptized.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p7" pid="i3OYwKxezEWTPWw_7h240g" hash="2E9A4g">The father, however, was skeptical. He felt no such spiritual confirmation. Long-held beliefs and traditions filled his mind with doubt. I met with him to discuss his misgivings and the desire of his wife and children to be baptized. Though he did not wish to keep them from making their own choices, he was deeply troubled by the conflict he felt between his beliefs and family traditions, and this message of the Restoration. As our conversation drew to a close, I bore my witness to him. It included my testimony of what the missionaries had taught. When explaining the divine nature of this Church, the Lord’s words from the Doctrine and Covenants came into my mind, and I testified that this is “the only true and living church upon the face of the whole earth” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.30" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:30</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p8" pid="EAvFTcrlxUe8lva_2Ojorw" hash="c0jYog">My friend was startled. This declaration troubled him, and in disbelief he said: “How can you possibly claim such a thing? My church has many more members than yours; my church is much larger and more influential than yours; and furthermore, the history and traditions of my church go back much further than Joseph Smith. How can you possibly claim that yours is the only true church?”</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.f2">
	<p pid="JoR2xBdXzEKA6xC4WTdeqA" hash="ou224w">His reaction is similar to that of many when first hearing such a testimony—one that could be experienced by some listening to this conference. During these proceedings, those who participate through prayer, the spoken word, and music will be testifying of what they know to be true. Their witnesses will include:</p>
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="DQz3kaaGCkunH1WOv1DlPg" hash="g6VZ9Q">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="mhU9OM4IoE25fjw1icdsEA" hash="jWghCQ">The reality of God, the divinity of His Beloved Son, and the doctrines of Christ.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="e3Gpaqi120uPFYxS6-y3Ew" hash="OaCjzw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="ZRuUBPMoQk2jwmpfn2umZg" hash="L_aqWg">The divine calling of prophets, seers, and revelators, with special emphasis given to the first prophet of this dispensation, Joseph Smith, and the Lord’s prophet today, President Gordon B. Hinckley.</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.f3">
	<p pid="uQkftt1HZEq2ABXGdFXPIw" hash="YPeXQA">These witnesses will point us to:</p>
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="rhJ803Nij0qMj5Bb_gsUOA" hash="9sBKyA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="bP8iIPzQYU6kLcfcxi_3tA" hash="T7ql5g">Revealed truths about the purposes of life, our origin and destiny, and</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="npcUtDEz5k-Ik4loFzrPcQ" hash="4huWBg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="aUrse1Q0h06Swh7fU0ff8Q" hash="C2URyA">The holy scriptures, often referencing the Book of Mormon as another testament of Jesus Christ.</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p9" pid="CZw1Pae2EUa-Ou3TQQxMqg" hash="XzVITw">To some, these testimonies will be troubling, at variance with what they think or believe. They may ask: “How can you possibly claim such a thing? How can you know?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p10" pid="FokfW6zdh0myc21yUn_kvA" hash="P_sfLg">To you with such questions, I say—Before reacting, before closing your mind, before finding fault because of a word—please listen and consider this inspired insight. I quote: “‘Words do not convey meanings; they call them forth.’ I speak out of the context of my experience, and you listen out of the context of yours, and that is why communication is difficult” (David O. McKay, as quoted by Lowell L. Bennion, in Conference Report, Apr. 1968, 94; or <span class="emphasis">Improvement Era,</span> June 1968, 90).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p11" pid="a-45-1bjbk6pje2g8FREZw" hash="Vz2eyQ">This is a phenomenon of mortality and lies at the heart of one’s skepticism. But amidst differing views on spiritual matters, there comes to us from scripture the wonderful and comforting promise <span class="emphasis">“Ye may know.”</span> Though our backgrounds are different, we are all children of the same Heavenly Father. He has provided a way to bridge our differences, a way <span class="emphasis">each of us may know.</span> This way is through the power and sure witness of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p12" pid="FiMfRg4lqE26ZBzNfrduSw" hash="o3wI4A">The Holy Ghost is the third member of the Godhead, sent forth by God to reveal all needful things. He teaches and testifies with divine power and clarity. His witness may go unheard or unheeded, forsaken or denied, but it is never misunderstood. “The Holy Ghost is a revelator” (Joseph Smith, <span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith,</span> sel. Joseph Fielding Smith [1976], 328). That which is received of him has a more powerful effect upon the soul than anything else received in any other way. A millennium of experience through sight, sound, touch, taste, smell, and all the powers of the universe combined cannot approach the sublime and complete experience of one brief moment under the influence of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p13" pid="eqnM7uNg1UygRnJz9trR8w" hash="sEgJcg">The Holy Ghost is a spirit personage. He has power to speak to the spirit of every man and woman, boy and girl. His message is conveyed with absolute certainty. This revealed knowledge constitutes a personal testimony and witness of the truth. (See Bruce R. McConkie, <span class="emphasis">Doctrinal New Testament Commentary,</span> 3 vols. [1966–73], 1:756.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p14" pid="4KMILFpMj0WvHVg8fQlFXw" hash="U8OkZw">Said the Lord through the Prophet Joseph Smith:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p15" pid="QG93jIhhOEa0q3luGQyO1A" hash="RQ9x-w">“Yea, behold, I will tell you in <span class="emphasis">your mind</span> and in <span class="emphasis">your heart,</span> by the Holy Ghost, which shall come upon <span class="emphasis">you</span> and which shall dwell in <span class="emphasis">your heart.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p16" pid="qbFPlvQXGUyjuUnVT6wTHQ" hash="NpR_ug">“Now, behold, this is the spirit of revelation” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/8.2-3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 8:2–3</a>; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p17" pid="Iw7DadZSqkOhawCQZqZzRg" hash="UHMbkA">How perfect and complete! How extraordinary! How wonderful!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p18" pid="N9yvAfAAYESGxrxzzkrh2A" hash="FZanMw">Different though our lives may be, there can come to each of us the same sure anchor—the <span class="emphasis">truth</span> from God. It is absolute, infinite, and available. As Jesus said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p19" pid="3KPIxQvfx0K0TAIozsQkCQ" hash="3lnUOA">“The word of the Lord is truth, and whatsoever is truth is light, and whatsoever is light is Spirit, even the Spirit of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p20" pid="xuYFvXskoEGtRiWT1wTpOg" hash="R9Md7w">“And the Spirit giveth light to every man that cometh into the world; and the Spirit enlighteneth every man through the world, that hearkeneth to the voice of the Spirit” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.45-46" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:45–46</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p21" pid="2wsUq8EJIEGGRzVfzoSl3A" hash="FvSD6w">He further explained: “Truth is knowledge of things as they are, and as they were, and as they are to come. … The Spirit of truth is of God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.24,26" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:24, 26</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p22" pid="l0HSFf5YlEmzF5I5u-_m-g" hash="kKhlmw">And finally the Lord urges, “Ask of God; ask, and it shall be given you” (JST, Matt. 7:12).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p23" pid="QG255vOt5EmIbZZ4-L4dPg" hash="wfZQmg">Now, for the rest of the story. You recall that my friend asked: “How can you possibly claim such a thing? How can you possibly claim that yours is the only true church?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p24" pid="jD9Z4l9JlE65tWpwOqwoCw" hash="TC1usQ">The answer came, not from me but through me: “I am not claiming it,” I said. “I am quoting it. Jesus Christ said it. Don’t argue with me. If you wish to take issue, pray and talk with Heavenly Father about it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p25" pid="yu6Np3H1cU27TN--vn505g" hash="xXAiMQ">The conversation came to a close, he gave permission for his family members to be baptized, and we parted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p26" pid="JuCFIw5RNEOukkIyKcqYaw" hash="ba8LYg">Some weeks later, as I was leaving a stake conference, I saw two men coming toward me, shouldering their way through the crowd. One of them was the same man of whom I have spoken. The first thought that crossed my mind was, “Oh no, here comes an argument!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p27" pid="pTNwhGKa6ki_NE2X_q8Zww" hash="GqDKLg">As he approached, he extended his hand and asked, “Do you remember me?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p28" pid="7LbKLGKuKk-1hgnAUQGvwQ" hash="4E5fqQ">“I certainly do,” I said, “and I want you to know that this is still the only true and living Church.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p29" pid="981aLbsGPECAzin4CiQg_w" hash="Q4r9aA">Before more could be said, his handshake tightened and he replied: “I know! I have prayed about it as you said. The Lord has told me by the power of His Spirit that it is all true. I was baptized last weekend and ordained a priest. Today, I am baptizing my friend here, for he also knows it is true.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p30" pid="vhqthgjFpUCFf3h4yLxyfg" hash="gtNQmw">Such is the purpose of witnesses, such is the power of the Holy Ghost, such is the anchor of truth. To the things which have been and will yet be testified of, I now add my witness that <span class="emphasis">“ye may know.”</span> God lives! We are His children, and He loves us. Jesus Christ is His Beloved Son, our Redeemer, and the Savior of the world. The Father and Son appeared to the Prophet Joseph Smith, answered his prayers, and gave him instructions. Other heavenly ministrants came to him thereafter, restoring what had been lost. They included Moroni bringing forth the Book of Mormon; John the Baptist restoring the priesthood of Aaron; Peter, James, and John conferring upon Joseph Smith and Oliver Cowdery the higher priesthood and holy apostleship; Moses with the keys of the gathering of Israel; Elias with the gospel of Abraham; and Elijah with the power to seal mothers, fathers, and children together as eternal families. The Lord’s gospel has been restored and His earthly kingdom reestablished, which He has named The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/115.3-4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 115:3–4</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.7-8" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 27:7–8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p31" pid="3irtqNGY1k-JDTS1Bn3eDw" hash="kaCpCw">If you find this or any other declaration of this conference unsettling, take up the matter with your Heavenly Father in prayer. “Ask in faith, nothing wavering” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.6" class="scriptureRef">James 1:6</a>). For “if ye … ask with a sincere heart, with real intent, having faith in Christ, he will manifest the truth … unto you, by the power of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p32" pid="HbOm1n0lm0quiTlvxWhDew" hash="tZiZ9g">“And by the power of the Holy Ghost <span class="emphasis">ye may know</span> the <span class="emphasis">truth</span> of all things” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.4-5" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:4–5</a>; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know.p33" pid="lB0sF0plWkSbHb2x-R4l8Q" hash="dDBgrg">This is my witness—all of this is true! In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1996/04/ye-may-know</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1996-general-conference/1996-04-1020-bishop-keith-b-mcmullin-64k-eng.mp3" length="6041879" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 1996 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Behold the Man”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Our vision of you and your work looks beyond the outward appearance of a boy and sees instead a bearer of the holy priesthood outfitted with its attendant powers, duties, and blessings.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_97911_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="sUhQDg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="l5-Jn78jMEqbdafHNXrxkA" hash="L0xnjw">“Behold the Man”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="_QpqvTv47USjsvN2FIuXvA" hash="bnTkHA">Keith B. McMullin</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="rfGpv2BmlUeq-zCSlyvV6g" hash="4pRs3w">Our vision of you and your work looks beyond the outward appearance of a boy and sees instead a bearer of the holy priesthood outfitted with its attendant powers, duties, and blessings.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1eee.jpg" alt="Bishop Keith B. McMullin" pid="O9BsyFwMmEaGornSXqJAdQ" hash="y5UdTA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p1" pid="iyQ34Ls1Wkinkcru9PzGbw" hash="8DjWdw">This vast assembly of brethren reminds us that the purposes and destiny of the Church rest in large measure on the shoulders of those who bear the Aaronic and Melchizedek Priesthoods. Though the Aaronic is the lesser and an appendage to the greater, or Melchizedek, each is everlasting and essential to the Lord’s work. Said President John Taylor: “When both of these Priesthoods are carried out and united in their purity, the glory of the Lord will be manifested upon Mount Zion, in the Lord’s house, both operating according to their callings, position and authority.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p2" pid="A4Od7EPqTUuIz9SqAfphkg" hash="Ft74Rg">With this aim in view, there lies before us the duty to hold fast all those who are newly converted and baptized, rekindle the faith of those who have drifted away, and protect the budding devotion of our youth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p3" pid="tghfwLVtr02RfnJOzcl8wg" hash="f0dq2Q">Newly baptized converts make an abrupt departure from past habits and ways. They are frequently alone in the Church, without the support of family and familiar faces. They stand on a path that is strait, narrow, and true. It is also new and can be a bit baffling.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p4" pid="L54vcvYrl0WNMf197MnK3A" hash="I_Xy-g">There are those who were once on this same path who have wandered away. Their faith has grown dim. To them, the prospect of full fellowship seems remote and perhaps unwanted. They “hide” from the Church and feel hidden from God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p5" pid="NWeSYp6WSkyKd0EqSTa_eg" hash="3tQs2w">We love and admire you young men of the Aaronic Priesthood. Your vitality is infectious, your abilities astounding, your association invigorating. But we know of other forces interested in you. They are dark and ominous. Wicked men and women parade before you ferocious temptations and deceptions. Their intent is to destroy you. They can exact a terrible toll.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p6" pid="DAj3Iq5KZk6fW5VvagFcUA" hash="UzDqiA">To escape these perils, Heavenly Father provided a Savior.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> The atoning sacrifice of our Lord is the most important single event in the history of all created things. This, then, is the gospel—that God lives and is our Father, Christ is the beloved Son of God, His Atonement is real, His earthly kingdom is established, and a celestial inheritance awaits those who embrace and abide by the everlasting principles upon which it rests.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p7" pid="_bBN_Ebae0eXN1Pm1p_Niw" hash="00LfUQ">The gospel is imparted and received in two ways—one comes before the other. The first contains a lesser portion which prepares; thereafter comes the greater portion which fulfills. The substance of each is found in the ordinances and workings of the holy priesthood—beginning in the Aaronic, culminating in the Melchizedek. Those who are “faithful unto the obtaining these two priesthoods … and the magnifying their calling … become … the church and kingdom, and the elect of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p8" pid="V7c3bnawskivjdEYqzY6ow" hash="rNpmUQ">The lesser portion of the gospel encompasses vital, saving truths and rests on the cornerstones of obedience and sacrifice. These truths school men and women, boys and girls in the fundamentals of righteousness. They consist of repentance, baptism, and observance of the law of carnal commandments unto the remission of sins. Carnal commandments are those that enable us to overcome the lusts, passions, and desires of our natural, or mortal, bodies and minds. Principal among these are the Ten Commandments.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> This lesser portion of the gospel will nourish those who are new in the Church, lead back those who have strayed, help young people recognize and overcome the temptations and deceptions of the world. Without this preparation, the fulness of gospel blessings cannot be realized or enjoyed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p9" pid="FPfOCmX510iRnc6oIbS7fA" hash="9Zl-bA">The responsibility for administering this preparatory portion of the gospel is entrusted to the Aaronic Priesthood:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p10" pid="cmxQsI5qZUGlYWyH-_AOpg" hash="00VNqQ">“And the lesser [or Aaronic] priesthood … holdeth the key of the … preparatory gospel;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p11" pid="Y7hD748oz0i-CEJoV0WvLA" hash="Qt-Eqg">“Which gospel is the gospel of repentance and of baptism, and the remission of sins, and the law of carnal commandments.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p12" pid="CIuXJs9ld067GOboPntRpQ" hash="V9vnvw">Blessed is the man so called and ordained, for his devoted service in the Aaronic Priesthood will not only save others but himself as well.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> It is the same whether the man is new in the Church, returning after a long absence, or of younger years. As he administers these principles, ordinances, and commandments, he himself is schooled. Aaronic Priesthood service readies men for the fulness of the everlasting gospel, for the oath and covenant and spiritual blessings “which belongeth to the [Melchizedek] priesthood.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> In every sense, the Aaronic Priesthood is truly preparatory. And for you younger men, there are additional opportunities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p13" pid="Yp8hT4DyNEufALNlzwPakA" hash="YfcmDA">The world uses age as a means of defining one’s readiness for manhood. For example, age is used to determine when a young person is sufficiently mature and responsible to drive an automobile. To youth, the long-awaited time arrives. To their parents, it is a time of sheer terror.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p14" pid="_LxxjkZS90Sr7_iUvtg74g" hash="nzt2NA">The world also uses age to establish when a man is sufficiently wise and responsible to vote, to make contracts, to be held fully and legally accountable. We call this the age of majority, the time when one ceases to be a minor.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p15" pid="z73ZxQOCjEyKj3u1DNjAbA" hash="jnrpAg">Because youth and age are so visible in the Aaronic Priesthood, we could mistakenly assume they somehow determine the powers and effectiveness of this priesthood.<span class="emphasis"> Remember, please remember: In the Church, it is worthiness and the power of God that qualify men for the work. Expectation, opportunity, and service contribute more to one’s growth than do birthdays. In the kingdom of God, the age of majority begins with ordination.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p16" pid="meMahNKmGE-Sa8z4J0xscA" hash="7J8yXg">Think about the mighty works of Samuel, John the Baptist, Mormon, and Joseph Smith. Each was called while in his youth; each was qualified by God for the great tasks at hand; each performed his duties to the everlasting blessing of us all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p17" pid="mjsKmvwagEuCSl3KpSsnAg" hash="KcuwRw">Such works can be the hallmark of the Aaronic Priesthood today. It is, in some measure, a matter of perspective. As we look upon a young Aaronic Priesthood bearer, do we see a boy, or a man “called of God, by prophecy, and by the laying on of hands”?<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> How we view him has a bearing on how he views himself. Let me illustrate.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p18" pid="s_ffx8_ipUi5x1LTWhg4Pg" hash="yzKVig">Pretend for a moment that my hand represents Aaronic Priesthood authority. These four fingers represent its four offices: deacon, teacher, priest, and bishop. Select one of these offices, say that of a deacon. Next to the others, he stands a little shorter, a little less robust. But as the hand is seriously impaired by the loss of its little finger, so the priesthood is impaired if we view a deacon as merely a boy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p19" pid="C8C5SDBomkWD4mebtbwI1w" hash="FY37jw">In the eyes of God, there is more power and authority in the hand of an Aaronic Priesthood bearer than there is among all of the world’s rich, famous, and influential people. Their works will end; his will not. They can do nothing in the name of the Lord; he can do whatever the Lord requires of him, for he is on the Lord’s errand. He can strengthen the new convert, bring a change of heart to those who seem lost, and bolster other young people in their faith.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.f2">
	<p pid="WhENrhDE0UyGJGRzglXY7g" hash="AwFUBA">Acting in his Aaronic Priesthood office, he:</p>
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="6IXonQaE20izzCcN0HBSNw" hash="lSya6Q">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="JcPoS0v6Wkef4AoS8dT11A" hash="bE9OYw">Extends the hand of fellowship and friendliness.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="wn7k8jDeYkyDKiK0_fw99Q" hash="3eyw_Q">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="G6i_DV7CFEe08w4ocYZZsA" hash="VX_iUA">Teaches, declares, and bears witness of the truth.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="XbIyo7XmIUWCoTdnxCEXIA" hash="dCNcrQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="9jCbcRB88kadC4TVuW74Gw" hash="MMe4sQ">Sees that members meet together often and that none are overlooked.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Q2VT3CITXEmLB_apAd8emg" hash="Dhf3KQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="6bfOxtEOi0qkyTH13ax3MA" hash="J6ksIw">Collects fast offerings to care for the poor.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="puYyKsvKrE2M1y8J_Mc33w" hash="ADHoyQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="tVd2irb80UerFmDDWA46AQ" hash="EGTkvQ">Administers the holy sacrament.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="22V80fS09EWpLhEiEgaP_Q" hash="fojF3Q">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="of7E5T-ZwkqVR1uyCWe5SA" hash="OwBycg">Visits members in their homes and enfolds them in the safety of the Church.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="ECCPvjmW2UeHtHQg50ksJA" hash="Z9MZyQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="KEeEmUJwjEChEVsbEdsc-A" hash="wBoRZg">Searches out his ancestors, submits their names to the family file, and presents himself at the temple to be baptized and confirmed for those who did not receive these ordinances while on earth.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="FMwCJmQZ7UeyCHUsqStxhg" hash="t41MSg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="wwgo-YerG0yhWofCAHJXjw" hash="bQIz_w">As a priest, performs baptisms and ordains, by the laying on of hands, other priests, teachers, and deacons.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="GRQMi9hoF0eOkQrjepVAeg" hash="RxoGLA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="cdH2IE3Bm0udiZA06g4vIA" hash="Yiux_w">Is an example of virtue, moral courage, and wholesome manhood in his family, among his friends, and in the community and nation where he dwells.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p20" pid="NPpp8OgDoUiIdKLOsj_7rw" hash="rhfYgw">In my mind I can hear you of the Aaronic Priesthood saying, with a fervor and conviction characteristic of men like Mormon and Joseph Smith:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p21" pid="VGD-Smz07USu0DXGhTfc0A" hash="FVuoIw">“We are sons of our Heavenly Father and disciples of Jesus Christ. We act in ‘faith, hope, charity and love, with an eye single to the glory of God.’<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.f3">
	<p pid="fSkleCS6RU2ZwyTzON2sxw" hash="nYeHQg">“As a bearer of the Aaronic Priesthood:</p>
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="aKAEWEhroUireN5G9Lm3EQ" hash="0IHmFw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="gEWUpvetJkyYLBVC4WR-Qg" hash="GM6noQ">I will live the gospel of Jesus Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="p1trR-ZgbkiCkhkELzuiug" hash="UrNJFg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="tN2QrtMmM0WiCBCw3jphMw" hash="cWGzFA">I will magnify priesthood callings.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="S12mDJq1hUS75S343UNtow" hash="86tgVQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="rdYTg3b6jka5_xI_TdTnjQ" hash="8oYKpg">I will give meaningful service.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="n47JPcKZ8U24msospLJCcA" hash="EtMkSg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="irPCrT5pFUGEZDtGCtpatw" hash="1asdOA">I will prepare to receive the Melchizedek Priesthood.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="DAr9v0rz_0GG54nn6LPfgg" hash="Hrmb3Q">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="I6jPJszI_U-Z3lSQMbKzcQ" hash="Gh0wBQ">I will commit to, prepare for, and serve an honorable full-time mission.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="BQX9VUOgWEyp3lDviZ-eHQ" hash="cCYtiA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="YluWsGcMvEaAei5Q968Ebg" hash="paylrQ">I will live worthy to receive temple covenants and prepare to become a worthy husband and father.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p22" pid="VXZqQxrgdUGOmjjsX8LHjA" hash="4pRs3w1">Our vision of you and your work looks beyond the outward appearance of a boy and sees instead a bearer of the holy priesthood outfitted with its attendant powers, duties, and blessings.</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.f4">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="wGJSTfBCOEeqlUDcLC2ovQ" hash="KWJ1sA">
            <span class="emphasis">To men of old there came in time</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="sSE2-DfWgkmRJokaNRZbtw" hash="8TzWVA">
            <span class="emphasis">The priesthood named for Aaron.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="dP-e2gdJwkizKPAJWOAQZA" hash="HgzUFA">
            <span class="emphasis">Through Levites, priests, and prophets too,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="pou3igCGF020JstTJ4pq8Q" hash="R6b8yQ">
            <span class="emphasis">It served to bless God’s children.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="chTcgqPTG06ZpFikmkfV5Q" hash="4BiC0A">
            <span class="emphasis">Then came the Savior of the world</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="_lto-dTJNUe9KhaGOrhxkw" hash="sUbTlw">
            <span class="emphasis">And sought out one named John,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="_T8dbi5AbEWtzNyWgRrTfw" hash="KIiZjA">
            <span class="emphasis">To be baptized by this same power</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Pe0TR2RjO0-PCNdW1NhuLQ" hash="EHKaEw">
            <span class="emphasis">And mark salvation’s dawn.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="sk_03M6OEkysxVPasDpvkQ" hash="ESr6FA">
            <span class="emphasis">In latter days this selfsame power</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="V8ih1uIpr0SnFVCZCcGyvw" hash="mF5X5g">
            <span class="emphasis">Was again restored to earth,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="2xrBEc5g3EC-eEx3bUudCg" hash="vTFtGw">
            <span class="emphasis">That gospel truths from first to last</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="ZXeR4C-AVUWDjS47nfAloQ" hash="4_epkw">
            <span class="emphasis">Might in one’s soul find birth.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="J0g7Z7nUZEqrfboQCExNWA" hash="9ZU7zw">
            <span class="emphasis">Aaronic Priesthood, truth sublime,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="7l_TLCeiHkqDR-CPFElUtw" hash="8V0tXw">
            <span class="emphasis">In preparation come—</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="mmGM167n0EukXgvw8ndejw" hash="bUdY2g">
            <span class="emphasis">That redemption might be had</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="bwXcUTAZ-kSrnRE7lrUEIA" hash="QbhEIg">
            <span class="emphasis">Through God’s Beloved Son!</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="EiOu05qxLEmZqDSeoKFhQA" hash="PBICcw">
            <span class="emphasis">And he who ministers these powers—</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="THQdgJpE7k-BfhyZ_pZVPw" hash="kToFzg">
            <span class="emphasis">’Tis not a boy that can.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="gU7-oRWUB0iz0pXJgcGdBw" hash="go8NRw">
            <span class="emphasis">With priesthood mantle on him fixed</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="v8CQZZFb70Gpfa-gvxSHXw" hash="V6awNQ">
            <span class="emphasis">We say, “Behold the man!”</span>
            <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man.p23" pid="rQYjqHUQt0marfkrZ9uTUQ" hash="ZbX1XQ">God bless you, noble men of the Aaronic Priesthood, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1997/10/behold-the-man</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1997-general-conference/1997-10-3020-bishop-keith-b-mcmullin-64k-eng.mp3" length="5011311" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1997 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Home</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Have faith in Christ, trust Him, come unto Him, follow Him. … Step by step the way will unfold before you until … you are back where you belong.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_99260_000_033" doc-version="2" hash="v_c0vQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="mHmpbPpf_ka3Nm2pJYj-dA" hash="4L--EA">Welcome Home</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="utyXo31Q2EapD53k82kIIA" hash="bnTkHA">Keith B. McMullin</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="icSNqBMAl0SBweNF6ASfzw" hash="BVUiJw">Have faith in Christ, trust Him, come unto Him, follow Him. … Step by step the way will unfold before you until … you are back where you belong.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-183.jpg" alt="Bishop Keith B. McMullin" pid="-RtnJ3Ul6kWiB0qxtfo3pA" hash="HRPyCA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p1" pid="Mu0QwTtfwkCFE8E8nhB6GQ" hash="ZvhliA">My dear brothers and sisters, as this general conference draws to a close, my thoughts turn to those who feel lonely, afraid, or who have lost their way. If you or someone you know is “out there … in the shadows” (Gordon B. Hinckley, “Converts and Young Men,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1997, 48), please listen!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p2" pid="SemiCnXSN0ORDuYKLi-j4Q" hash="rw_KyQ">Mortal life is like unto the traveler on a homeward journey. The miles seem long, the minutes slow, the events of the day protracted and tedious. Eventually, however, familiar scenes come into view. They may be hills or valleys, country landscapes or towering buildings, a teeming thoroughfare or a quiet neighborhood street. Whatever the scene, its familiarity quickens the traveler’s step, invigorates his wearied soul, and restores sweet feelings of anticipation and peace. At long last, he is home again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p3" pid="ZWkl959mPkupv9K22KXfOA" hash="_nFRdA">In our mobile, bustling world, this experience of the homeward journey is repeated daily in the lives of millions of people. If we look closely, we can learn much about mortality from such a common occurrence. One thing is certain—we make a colossal mistake if we approach this mortal journey frivolously or take whatever path presents itself without thought as to where it leads. As one beloved Apostle has observed: “Truly, of all the errors mortals could make, God’s plan of salvation is the wrong thing to be wrong about! No error could be more enormous or more everlasting in its consequences!” (Neal A. Maxwell, “The Great Plan of the Eternal God,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1984, 22).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p4" pid="Cu7h12ZFSkOZDJuFBMmeBw" hash="N2UMUQ">The successful traveler understands and acts correctly on four things: namely, the eternity of life, the nature of sin, the beauty of repentance, and the power of the Atonement.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p5" pid="Ay_133nd_U2CQEKE-EITPQ" hash="oju4Bg">Life is more than biology. Before we came to this earth, we lived in the presence of God. His heaven was our home. Each of us is His spirit offspring, and He is our Heavenly Father (see <a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.23-25" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:23–25</a>; <a href="/scriptures/ot/job/38.4-7" class="scriptureRef">Job 38:4–7</a>; <a href="/scriptures/ot/jer/1.5" class="scriptureRef">Jer. 1:5</a>). Because of the restoration of the gospel of Jesus Christ, we know that birth is divinely appointed and an essential step in our eternal journey. In the words of the Lord’s prophet, President Gordon B. Hinckley: <span class="emphasis">“The fact of all life is that it is eternal.</span> That’s the great salient truth. We have come into the world for a purpose under a divine plan and when we conclude this life we will go on to something that will be better, if we live worthy of it” (priesthood leadership session, Charlotte North Carolina regional conference, 24 Feb. 1996, 5; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p6" pid="9OSoNSavEEK9ZOBVuy4Ing" hash="3FiSyw">The nature of sin, however, makes this mortal journey anything but an easy task. Wrote the Apostle Paul:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p7" pid="tWqShBjv2EO6kAns7IyYzA" hash="-XI8RQ">“<span class="emphasis">This know also, that in the last days perilous times shall come.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p8" pid="s6ZZE2dXvUWROsQ0Zog1gg" hash="lyVErA">“For men shall be lovers of their own selves, covetous, boasters, proud, blasphemers, disobedient to parents, unthankful, unholy,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p9" pid="qcWfMCzYJkS4iv2fe8Syiw" hash="ydcVRg">“Without natural affection, trucebreakers, false accusers, incontinent, fierce, despisers of those that are good,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p10" pid="6XtkYcu1sEKPk18jbLeILw" hash="5CX5FQ">“Traitors, heady, highminded, lovers of pleasures more than lovers of God;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p11" pid="anvzEjDVnUiwyc8U8cY5NA" hash="IbkzuQ">“Having a form of godliness; but denying the power thereof: <span class="emphasis">from such turn away</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/3.1-5" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 3:1–5</a>; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p12" pid="bjA4vUnC9EK-eOEEIvFHQg" hash="hjSekA">Because of our frailties and vulnerabilities, sin becomes a part of every traveler’s journey. It is the consequence of being in the crucible of law, opposition, and agency (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/42.17-24" class="scriptureRef">Alma 42:17–24</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/12.31-34" class="scriptureRef">Alma 12:31–34</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.11,15-16,25-27" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:11, 15–16, 25–27</a>). “To him that knoweth to do good, and doeth it not, to him it is sin” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/4.17" class="scriptureRef">James 4:17</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p13" pid="Xn7l3G5WlUulxzMANBC-9A" hash="t8KdWQ">Furthermore, no matter how well-intentioned or watchful we are, the journey causes us to suffer temptation. Not even the Savior escaped it, and the temptations He suffered at the outset of His ministry typify those that beset us. Speaking of these temptations—to turn stones into bread, to cast Himself from the temple’s pinnacle, and to sell His soul for earth’s treasures (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/4.2-10" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 4:2–10</a>)—President David O. McKay said, “Classify them, and you will find that under one of those three nearly every given temptation that makes you and me spotted … comes to us as (1) a temptation of appetite; (2) a yielding to the pride and fashion and vanity of those alienated from the things of God; or (3) a gratifying of the … desire for the riches of the world, or power among men” (in Conference Report, Apr. 1911, 59).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p14" pid="aVKLnU64Sk6cS44bZ-yrCA" hash="HiEbWg">When temptation besets us, we experience pain of conscience. A sensitive conscience is the evidence of a healthy spirit. The pain or guilt we feel is the spirit’s reaction to temptation, imperfection, or sin. Conscience is the companion of every traveler (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.16-19" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:16–19</a>); it can also make the trip very uncomfortable, since “all have sinned” and “the Lord cannot look upon sin with the least degree of allowance” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/3.23" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 3:23</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.31" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:31</a>). Thanks be to God for this supernal gift, for it can lead us to repentance and peace of conscience (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.1-3" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:1–3</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p15" pid="PyJydzyo402nUiZ5ZX5OrA" hash="F4ET-w">Heavenly Father knew the grave dangers we would face on our journey through life, but He remains resolute in His desire to have each and every one of His children return home. Therefore, He gave us time—time to work out our mistakes, time to overcome our sins, time to prepare for reunion. “There was a space granted unto man in which he might repent; therefore this life became a probationary state; a time to prepare to meet God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/12.24" class="scriptureRef">Alma 12:24</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p16" pid="hOsDz7WwPU-SBqNSDhXvtw" hash="XmuBng">But Heavenly Father knew that even if we exerted every ounce of energy, we could not make it home without divine help. Therefore, He promised, “We will provide a savior for you!” (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/10.4" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 10:4</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/13.40" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 13:40</a>; <a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.6" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:6</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/25.23" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 25:23</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p17" pid="JX4chPSHA0eaSv3KUUjd0A" hash="CiSGXQ">In fulfillment of this promise, Jesus Christ came during the meridian of time, the Only Begotten Son of God, the Eternal Father, in the flesh. He walked the paths and byways of mortality so He could “know according to the flesh how to succor his people according to their infirmities” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/7.12" class="scriptureRef">Alma 7:12</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/7.11" class="scriptureRef">Alma 7:11</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.27" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:27</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:22</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/62.1" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 62:1</a>). There is not one vexation, anxiety, or suffering unfamiliar to Him. Though He is without sin yet knows He each and every one of our griefs that He might be able to help us (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/53.3-6" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 53:3–6</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p18" pid="hcaKQJ_DJE-YhrsIV3rHww" hash="miU3IA">Christ bridged the gulf between the mortal and immortal. The grave no longer holds its captives; justice can be satisfied through mercy; the wondrous Atonement, infinite and eternal in scope, is in place (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/34.8-10,14-16" class="scriptureRef">Alma 34:8–10, 14–16</a>). Christ is the resurrected Lord, our Savior and Redeemer. Therefore, do not wait any longer (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/13.27" class="scriptureRef">Alma 13:27</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/34.33-35" class="scriptureRef">Alma 34:33–35</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p19" pid="yoIPU80Bm0uI5gk-K_b5sA" hash="H5fsMg">Have faith in Christ, trust Him, come unto Him, follow Him (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.13-16" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 27:13–16</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.32-33" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:32–33</a>). Make a mental list of those things you know you ought not to be doing. Stop doing today at least one such thing, and replace it with what you ought to do. Pray to Heavenly Father for forgiveness and for the strength to complete this journey. As you overcome one obstacle and move on to another, I promise that step by step the way will unfold before you until, as the wearied traveler, you are back where you belong.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p20" pid="38VqqXoubk6Tw_qNQwswAw" hash="oHKgrg">Thomas (that is not his real name) was one who had lost his way. We became acquainted at a special fireside attended by members one doesn’t normally see on Sunday. He was then 35 years old and had not been active in the Church for some 20 years. The day before, Thomas’s father had invited him to attend the fireside. Thomas said, “I’ll think about it.” I quote now from a letter written by his father:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p21" pid="n82xuvx230uM4sL1Qb2w5g" hash="VZ5sXg">“Thirty minutes before the fireside, [Thomas] called and asked me to pick him up. I can’t explain the anticipation I felt as we walked into the room [to join] you and about 40 others. There was a special feeling and spirit there that touched [Tom’s] heart and he went home determined to read again the passages in the Book of Mormon that you had outlined.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p22" pid="GJCrxf36G0OLdkM1MDeNGA" hash="X1fFkQ">“This led to a reading of the whole book and the beginning of his payment of tithing. He began to see his life in a different light. … He stopped using drugs and caffeine. He continued to read, not only the Book of Mormon, but also the Doctrine and Covenants. He started to attend sacrament meetings and … literally began to be a different person. In fact, we jokingly asked him, ‘What have you done with our son?’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p23" pid="0HIVQAzfH02bbXcXHrcQNw" hash="a9LAHg">“The great blessing to us was when he was interviewed by the bishop … to receive the Melchizedek Priesthood. This has truly been an answer to prayers which have been offered in his behalf for almost 20 years” (personal letter, 1 Aug. 1997).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p24" pid="miULJZKpXUWbEwuiSvVrHA" hash="wcdCyA">This account recalls to our minds the words of another parent: “For this my son was dead, and is alive again; he was lost, and is found” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15.24" class="scriptureRef">Luke 15:24</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p25" pid="1ZbtXppPckWGdilcdV9d_Q" hash="JUw0rA">Said President Brigham Young: “There is no spirit but what was pure and holy when it came here from the celestial world. … He is the Father of our spirits; and if we could know, understand, and do His will, every soul would be prepared to return back into His presence. And when they get there, they would see that they had formerly lived there for ages, that they had previously been acquainted with every nook and corner, with the palaces, walks, and gardens; and they would embrace their Father, and He would embrace them and say, ‘My son, my daughter, I have you again;’ and the child would say, ‘O my Father, my Father, I am here again’” (in <span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses,</span> 4:268).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p26" pid="l1M9CylvgUKrDPiebrt6Pg" hash="o2EkMQ">With all the power of which I am capable, I bear witness to the truthfulness of these things. Come in out of the shadows! Step fully into the light of the gospel. Enjoy the sweet fruits of repentance, the peace of conscience, and the comfort of the Holy Ghost. Let this journey take you back where you belong. Recalling a familiar phrase, I leave with you this testimonial:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="7det94etBUazAjw58DitYw" hash="cwVjYA">
            <span class="emphasis">“O my Father, thou that dwellest</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="IYD39ov0uEifuoXwo5_epA" hash="IuTLbg">
            <span class="emphasis">In the high and glorious place,”</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="dKzYwCxQUkKT4VsYuhrPOA" hash="Jp6PGA">
            <span class="emphasis">I do yearn to once again be</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="onJV8ODrwEe5SsUKXoQfqA" hash="eDIBjA">
            <span class="emphasis">With Thee, and behold Thy face.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="1OwHY0Kj1EKVCYhGNS_qtg" hash="4mqqAA">
            <span class="emphasis">Then shall I, in adoration,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="yRrvBgZynE6WzqnJh7FAhQ" hash="lxpPTg">
            <span class="emphasis">Bow before my Savior dear,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="xpxj__jeTUy16uhuSpu2_A" hash="UJZZWA">
            <span class="emphasis">Thank Him for His great Atonement,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="knUiH85iMEqhKid1X_zs7w" hash="cyBk4g">
            <span class="emphasis">Wash His feet with many tears.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="5L1AqXVe50-HKH6NBCJz2A" hash="E7Cw_g">
            <span class="emphasis">And with grateful heart a-swelling,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="l-Clveeci0SRfMLDbnf5Fw" hash="Ae1BPw">
            <span class="emphasis">Seeing I am not alone,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="PzyeYTafAEWYCFJTqjtgKA" hash="Le944g">
            <span class="emphasis">Will feel Thy love and hear Thy greeting—</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="R1HAdrgs0EOUfmlox-4Rsw" hash="DozHDg">
            <span class="emphasis">“Sons and daughters, welcome home!”</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home.p27" pid="eoaWUDf6u0qQhtnJV9ZT0w" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1999/04/welcome-home</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1999-general-conference/1999-04-5030-bishop-keith-b-mcmullin-64k-eng.mp3" length="5028273" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1999 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Invitation with Promise</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Just being a member of this Church is not enough. Nor is merely going through the motions of membership sufficient.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029247_000_026" doc-version="2" hash="XRUhKg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="4FyB4iLjM0aFrpFt0_QAtw" hash="OqKbwg">An Invitation with Promise</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="xzphJwKCZECKYBLvhPDA7g" hash="bnTkHA">Keith B. McMullin</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="uXs5AghvJ0eZH4S4H3fQbw" hash="8NT9fA">Just being a member of this Church is not enough. Nor is merely going through the motions of membership sufficient.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-183.jpg" alt="Bishop Keith B. McMullin" pid="N7HOKgSQl0e0KDEG_1ceVg" hash="HRPyCA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p1" pid="bZAPVAr9BkKxKfFEAac1Cg" hash="wCmriA">To those who yearn for spiritual truth, some things become self-evident. I bear my witness of these things. God is in His heavens. We mortals are His spirit offspring. Jesus is our Redeemer. Joseph Smith was God’s prophet, and Gordon B. Hinckley is His prophet today. Revelations are pouring forth as in days of old. The kingdom of God, which is The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, is once more upon the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p2" pid="WvYRPehlw0il_4Dk5kvdVA" hash="5gGnEw">Satan is real and is on the earth as well. He and his legions are wreaking havoc among the children of men. He speaks no truth, feels no love, promotes no good, and avows nothing but mayhem and destruction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p3" pid="FTJzx54pfEidXr9hMp7wAw" hash="9yfpRw">Therefore, I raise this day a “voice of warning.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> It is an urgent, sobering reminder and invitation to good men and women everywhere. Listen to these words of revelation received on November 1, 1831:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p4" pid="6PUn4_X_TkyDaILjCOa-7w" hash="yDzHNA">“Wherefore, I the Lord, knowing the calamity which should come upon the inhabitants of the earth, called upon my servant Joseph Smith, Jun., and spake unto him from heaven, and gave him commandments; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p5" pid="qwMwmCcOi0SLpdrPQ7opaQ" hash="5-BLcg">“For I am no respecter of persons, and will that all men shall know that the day speedily cometh; the hour is not yet, but is nigh at hand, when peace shall be taken from the earth, and the devil shall have power over his own dominion.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p6" pid="atPD7CkfOUWEMGoUXK_m9g" hash="mIZ67Q">The Lord speaks of calamity to befall the inhabitants of the earth. Calamities come in different forms. From time to time the forces of nature convulse, and we are wrenched by their destructive powers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p7" pid="eRTMKROF7kGkvfe6ztjjOQ" hash="7lx5Ow">Even more devastating, however, are the calamitous forces of evil which surfeit us continually. In accordance with the prophecy of 1831, peace has now been taken from the earth, and the devil has power over his dominion. His beguiling ways are mesmerizing the people. Temptation is on every hand. Crassness and wrangling have become a way of life. What was once considered awful is now considered tame; what at first titillates, soon captivates and then destroys.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p8" pid="XpvkZYik6kC7HHlSxLvZNw" hash="nuEGgA">This calamity of evil will continue to spread until “the whole world … groaneth … under the bondage of sin.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.f2">
	<p pid="bpiC2BT9gU6CV9EZTfjwrQ" hash="Nb0_yA">Therefore, this “voice of warning”:</p>
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="sfWM4FRg80KZ4B5umt1w6Q" hash="nWIkqw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="_E10QTDeqUqK2S0ffz7-bA" hash="WknFRg">
            <span class="emphasis">Beware of worldly lusts.</span> They stimulate the senses but enslave the soul. Those caught in the web of sensuality find that it is not easily broken.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="2R-xUZCb90CE4g_jMeGg-g" hash="OtWLpg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="xhXrNofRwEm4EvC_YdeeeA" hash="gA1lww">
            <span class="emphasis">Beware of worldly wealth.</span> Its promises are enticing, but its happiness is a mirage. Wrote the Apostle Paul, “The love of money is the root of all evil.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="KmJqnvrEi0mv3q5gaeTNiw" hash="_lLPCA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="ZDk9z1kw5UaYLuFcxy60Hw" hash="q_5i9w">
            <span class="emphasis">Beware of worldly preoccupation with self.</span> The highs are counterfeit; the lows are despairing. Love, kindness, personal fulfillment, and genuine self-worth are found in service to God and others, not in service to oneself.</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p9" pid="Uvo_WubAhU2Ct7hqey5ZiQ" hash="eZuulQ">In the midst of these perils, there is a safe harbor. From the revelation cited earlier comes this assurance:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p10" pid="z34BRRuu30K3f7nWM_zwPw" hash="XtstTw">“And also the Lord shall have power over his saints, and shall reign in their midst, and shall come down in judgment upon Idumea, or the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p11" pid="ogv3HukPqkm0xgix1_EK2w" hash="b7w_MA">There is safety in being a Saint. Members of the Church of Jesus Christ today are known as Latter-day Saints. In addition to being the Lord’s designation of those who belong to His Church, this appellation also serves as His invitation to a better way of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p12" pid="kSGuYp81AESh-sU9ycmESw" hash="IgIwAw">This became clear to me some years ago when, as a young father, I needed to purchase some temple clothing. Upon entering the store, my attention was drawn to a sign on the counter that read “For Latter-day Saints Only.” The message jolted me. In my mind, an argument ensued. <span class="emphasis">Why does it say “For Latter-day Saints Only”?</span> I asked myself. <span class="emphasis">Why doesn’t it say something like “For Endowed Church Members”? Why does it raise this issue of being a “Latter-day Saint”?</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p13" pid="zy-Xitz8rUu8dt1EbFmKdQ" hash="WbrGVw">The years since have tempered my impetuous nature. That argumentative encounter of long ago has become a treasured, defining moment. The experience taught me that just being a member of this Church is not enough. Nor is merely going through the motions of membership sufficient in this day of cynicism and unbelief. The spirituality and vigilance of a saint are required.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p14" pid="g3qTsQ7yZUexwV3LVo3xnA" hash="Lq5iRg">Being saintly is to be good, pure, and upright. For such persons, virtues are not only declared but lived. For Latter-day Saints, the kingdom of God, or the Church, is not a byline; rather, it is the center and the substance of their lives. Home is “a bit of heaven,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> not a hotel. The family is not merely a societal or biological entity. It is the basic eternal unit in God’s kingdom wherein the gospel of Jesus Christ is taught and lived. Indeed, Latter-day Saints diligently strive to become a little better, a little kinder, a little nobler in the daily affairs of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p15" pid="2bbwAEa6zkOD6gtF6phOyg" hash="IeV7Qg">The Lord sets forth the way in which such progress is made. Said He, “Wherefore, seek not the things of this world but seek ye first to build up the kingdom of God, and to establish his righteousness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p16" pid="2QXVIHaoMECznwXMO2eGhQ" hash="IRc2Lw">Holding to this course provides Latter-day Saints the means for avoiding the treacherous shoals of worldliness. Living this way enables members of the Church to become the covenant people of the Lord. For our time, we have the following prophetic guidance from President Hinckley on how this can be done. I quote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p17" pid="-uRpeeL-WE-eoeiGay4Wkw" hash="VBlPEA">“We are a covenant people. I have had the feeling that if we could just encourage our people to live by three or four covenants everything else would take care of itself. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p18" pid="XIksVE_xqUK2LaQFhHD-bg" hash="l-FwKA">“<span class="emphasis">The first of these is the covenant of the sacrament,</span> in which we take upon ourselves the name of the Savior and agree to keep His commandments with the promise in His covenant that He will bless us with His spirit. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p19" pid="cA8mE91mrUuyIKPDoRDU6Q" hash="_YE9Hw">“<span class="emphasis">Second, the covenant of tithing.</span> … The promise … is that He will stay the destroyer and open the windows of heaven and pour down blessings that there will not be room enough to receive them. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p20" pid="HntjyDrCSkm5XH-jhC3IKg" hash="6uw_uw">“<span class="emphasis">Three, the covenants of the temple:</span> Sacrifice, the willingness to sacrifice for this the Lord’s work—and inherent in that law of sacrifice is the very essence of the Atonement. … Consecration, which is associated with it, a willingness to give everything, if need be, to help in the on-rolling of this great work. And a covenant of love and loyalty one to another in the bonds of marriage, fidelity, chastity, morality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p21" pid="5KLe40CU702NVCEtl7yJ_Q" hash="SUgaDQ">“<span class="emphasis">If our people could only learn to live by these covenants, everything else would take care of itself, I am satisfied.”</span><span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p22" pid="8KIva7Cp4kytfkqeF-K6cQ" hash="dAQWNQ">
        <span class="emphasis">Worldly lusts</span> lose their allure as the holy sacrament assumes its proper place in our lives. This covenant enables the faithful to keep themselves “unspotted from the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p23" pid="U5hYW7IK3EWd7gPLGiPxlQ" hash="i2H40Q">
        <span class="emphasis">Worldly wealth</span> loses its peril through conscientious adherence to the Lord’s tithe. Returning to Him a tithe of all He provides engenders in the giver a love of God above all else. It introduces the obedient to the higher law of giving without command. The fast and fast offerings are embraced and power comes to loose the bands of wickedness, lift heavy burdens, bless the less fortunate, and strengthen family ties.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> The covenant of tithing weans the faithful from the love of money and its attendant trappings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p24" pid="9VLUrEygqku-SptkYBbvEg" hash="ufzQUw">
        <span class="emphasis">Worldly preoccupation with self</span> surrenders to sacrifice, consecration, and the other holy covenants of the temple. As the Redeemer of the world gave all that we might be saved, these covenants allow us to give our all in the accomplishment of Heavenly Father’s purposes for His children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise.p25" pid="dfFWTA_nuk-l0-Oopn9ktQ" hash="NK0EiQ">And so, fear not. The things deemed weak by the world overthrow evils that appear so mighty and strong. Righteous men speak in the name of God the Lord. Faith increases in the earth. The everlasting covenants blossom in the lives of Latter-day Saints. The fulness of Christ’s gospel is proclaimed by precept and example unto the ends of the world. And the Lord’s covenant people prepare this earth for His Second Coming.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> This is our duty. May the Lord sustain us in it is my prayer, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2001/04/an-invitation-with-promise</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2001-general-conference/2001-04-4030-bishop-keith-b-mcmullin-64k-eng.mp3" length="4505232" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Come to Zion! Come to Zion!</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Principles of love, work, self-reliance, and consecration are God given. Those who embrace them and govern themselves accordingly become pure in heart.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029898_000_031" doc-version="2" hash="UZqBaQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="vTLUk5ou1kOva-_omnNPnA" hash="sNulew">Come to Zion!</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="pds3D7wS3UOsORa7oSt1LQ" hash="sNulew1">Come to Zion!</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="FjB79f-QO0urQ6-2E-RDfw" hash="bnTkHA">Keith B. McMullin</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="hugvL73EkEq3C4-9MtXljA" hash="AsPyRQ">Principles of love, work, self-reliance, and consecration are God given. Those who embrace them and govern themselves accordingly become pure in heart.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-183.jpg" alt="Bishop Keith B. McMullin" pid="QPMsMjWv9UWtRxlGQsEuAQ" hash="HRPyCA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p1" pid="11mdzSDExUaJkFlR4rOtwg" hash="8C0SKQ">As we meet with Church members around the world, one challenge seems universal: having enough time to do everything that needs doing. Among those who have few resources, the need is for more time to secure the necessities of life. Among those who have sufficient, the need is for more time to attend to the niceties of life. The challenge is daunting because time is fixed; man can neither lengthen out the day nor extend the year.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p2" pid="llZUwQzmD0mKXMMCchuvJg" hash="eKWEKQ">The world is the culprit. As the world grapples with more efficient ways of managing time, it lures us into more and more earthly pursuits. But life is not a struggle with time—it is a struggle between good and evil.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p3" pid="WALD9FGWnEaObk9RALlJZA" hash="tH2OSQ">What to do about all this can be one of the more vexing decisions in life. In 1872, the prophet Brigham Young counseled the Saints on this very subject. Said he: “Stop! Wait! When you get up in the morning, before you suffer yourselves to eat one mouthful of food, … bow down before the Lord, ask him to forgive your sins, and protect you through the day, to preserve you from temptation and all evil, to guide your steps aright, that <span class="emphasis">you may do something that day that shall be beneficial to the kingdom of God on the earth.</span> Have you time to do this? … This is the counsel I have for the Latter-day Saints to day. Stop, do not be in a hurry. … You are in too much of a hurry; you do not go to meeting enough, you do not pray enough, you do not read the Scriptures enough, you do not meditate enough, <span class="emphasis">you are all the time on the wing, and in such a hurry that you do not know what to do first.</span> … Let me reduce this to a simple saying—one of the most simple and homely that can be used—‘Keep your dish right side up,’ so that when the shower of porridge does come you can catch your dish full.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p4" pid="mg2qdkxI00eqGocXanC_6A" hash="HFSI8A">Use the gospel plan to set proper priorities. The Lord instructed, “Wherefore, seek not the things of this world but seek ye first to build up the kingdom of God [or Zion], and to establish his righteousness, and all these things shall be added unto you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p5" pid="mMUNDzObmU-S44PTk4A27w" hash="Tryz6A">As a young boy growing up in southern Utah, the concepts of Zion were much less clear to me than they are today. We lived in a small town not far from Zion National Park. In church we often sang the familiar words:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="tKqhA4VuZECkpctiJ2-oNA" hash="S3TXkA">
            <span class="emphasis">Israel, Israel, God is calling,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="fIfU8A_y8kWprhNjSOh2MA" hash="NnhQGQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Calling thee from lands of woe.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="fTU3S1YjAkuGx6dnX-bHwQ" hash="uAmj1g">
            <span class="emphasis">Babylon the great is falling;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="WKZDaQ2ed0qJvUmkJOuDOw" hash="bMqZSw">
            <span class="emphasis">God shall all her tow’rs o’erthrow.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="6Rp23AIeZk67kMI6RegHKQ" hash="KUlccA">
            <span class="emphasis">Come to Zion, come to Zion</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="AdyseEbWA0-qy0CG7dicBQ" hash="PaSFpw">
            <span class="emphasis">Ere his floods of anger flow.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="1jDqqOQhjU-rIO1HEP3BMQ" hash="KUlccA1">
            <span class="emphasis">Come to Zion, come to Zion</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="5tZSIYjObEWGD-ShmJoccw" hash="BTwkGA">
            <span class="emphasis">Ere his floods of anger flow.</span>
            <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p6" pid="aOl2kiGmXUe4fv8Gl_PX2A" hash="WDPsQA">In my little-boy mind, I saw the magnificent cliffs and towering stone pinnacles of that national park. Meandering through the high-walled canyons flowed a river of water—sometimes placid, sometimes a raging torrent. You can probably imagine the confusion experienced as this little boy tried to put together the words of the hymn with the familiar surroundings of that beautiful park. Though it was not a perfect fit, lodged in my mind was the impression that Zion was something majestic and divine. Over the years, a grander understanding has emerged. In the scriptures we read, “Therefore, verily, thus saith the Lord, let Zion rejoice, for this is Zion—the pure in heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p7" pid="AgGQW4c0Zki05D9_93A3qQ" hash="NknN0w">The establishment of Zion should be the aim of every member of this Church. It can be safely said: <span class="emphasis">As we seek with all our hearts to bring forth and establish Zion, the vexations of too little time will disappear.</span> There are joys and blessings by enlisting in this noble cause. One’s personal life is transformed. The home is no longer a hotel but a place of peace, security, and love. Society itself changes. In Zion, contentions and disputations cease, class distinctions and hatreds disappear, no one is poor—spiritually or temporally, and all manner of wickedness is no more. As many have attested, “Surely there could not be a happier people among all the people … created by the hand of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p8" pid="19Qo72dQBkmCHjcu0jVT4g" hash="ovDhAg">The ancient prophet Enoch labored many years to bring his people to this state of righteousness. Like our day, they also lived in a time of wickedness, wars, and bloodshed. But the righteous people responded. “And the Lord called his people Zion, <span class="emphasis">because</span> they were of one heart and one mind, and dwelt in righteousness; and there was no poor among them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p9" pid="nxAFuhyqC0Gw3LRenDLmjg" hash="b-B6jQ">Take special note of the word <span class="emphasis">because</span> in this scripture. Zion is established and flourishes <span class="emphasis">because</span> of the God-inspired lives and labors of its citizens. Zion comes not as a gift but because virtuous covenant people are drawn together and build it. President Spencer W. Kimball observed, “As we sing together ‘Come to Zion,’ we mean … come to the ward, the branch, the mission, the stake, and give assistance to build up Zion.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> Thus gathered in the Lord’s appointed way, Latter-day Saints conscientiously strive to bring forth Zion as the “kingdom of our God and his Christ,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> preparatory to the Lord’s Second Coming.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p10" pid="-_gCBSZ6YkyCgzThiz1hzg" hash="x0E04w">President Hinckley has reminded us that “this cause in which we are engaged is not an ordinary cause. It is the cause of Christ. It is the kingdom of God our Eternal Father. It is the building of Zion on the earth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p11" pid="LaGlUG5djk2ZF77DL_IUTA" hash="7Muw7g">“If we are to build that Zion of which the prophets have spoken and of which the Lord has given mighty promise, we must set aside our consuming selfishness. We must rise above our love for comfort and ease, and in the very process of effort and struggle, even in our extremity, we shall become better acquainted with our God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p12" pid="ucxz26Q-s0-7vg_OSYHG-A" hash="1RgZIw">Among the doctrines that give rise to this highest order of priesthood society are <span class="emphasis">love, service, work, self-reliance, consecration,</span> and <span class="emphasis">stewardship.</span><span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> To better understand how we can build Zion on these foundational truths, let us consider four of them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p13" pid="TNAXIRRdH0an10J7Gv_UaQ" hash="TMGOTg">The first is <span class="emphasis">love.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p14" pid="nPWfMNm3YkyNhwQlqMr6FQ" hash="CU3Gfw">“Jesus said … Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p15" pid="9NQjRwoZK0OnCnzuI1Uh5w" hash="pLnaTg">“This is the first and great commandment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p16" pid="h9TLUV9PYkioMgbfKwTpLQ" hash="9pnSeg">“And the second is like unto it, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p17" pid="2FkzvXuDX0-i8xSrbWukxA" hash="jivN6A">“On these two commandments hang all the law and the prophets.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p18" pid="kmHAILcgT0-mRoTwSNy9jw" hash="el5QxA">To love God more than anything else impels us to take control of our priorities and order our lives so as to be in accord with Him. We come to love all of God’s creations, including our fellowman. Placing God first in all things kindles greater love and devotion between husband and wife, parents and children. In Zion, we find “every man seeking the interest of his neighbor, and doing all things with an eye single to the glory of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p19" pid="5Fkoovi9akWAIEF_MfRS9g" hash="-Y-4gQ">Next is <span class="emphasis">work.</span> Work is physical, mental, or spiritual effort. The Lord commanded, “By the sweat of thy face shalt thou eat bread.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> Work is the source of happiness, self-esteem, and prosperity. In the economy of God, there is no room for chicanery and greed. Work is to be honest toil with this overarching, divine purpose: “The laborer in Zion shall labor for Zion; for if they labor for money they shall perish.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p20" pid="aYXh7_hnZU2sCnKfm_AaUQ" hash="jwO5Kw">
        <span class="emphasis">Self-reliance</span> comes next. It is the harbinger of personal agency and security. This Church and its people are commanded by the Lord to be prepared, self-reliant, and independent.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> Times of plenty are times to live providently and lay up in store. Times of scarcity are times to live frugally and draw on those stores.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p21" pid="AxkSK-vDxkiWWmrWjgBL9g" hash="XazPZA">“No true Latter-day Saint, while physically or emotionally able will voluntarily shift the burden of his own or his family’s well-being to someone else. So long as he can, under the inspiration of the Lord and with his own labors, he will supply himself and his family with the spiritual and temporal necessities of life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p22" pid="AR-CoJujrE6ywAVodoxWNQ" hash="fHLfCQ">We are sons and daughters of God and are truly dependent upon Him for all that we have. If we keep His commandments, He will never forsake us. But Heavenly Father does not do for us what we can and should do for ourselves. He expects us to use the means we receive of Him to care for ourselves and our families. When we do so, we are self-reliant.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p23" pid="zJ0SIMFHf0KIPDA_-DIN1A" hash="pJ06ng">Lastly, <span class="emphasis">consecration.</span> The covenant of consecration encompasses sacrifice; circumscribes <span class="emphasis">love, work,</span> and <span class="emphasis">self-reliance;</span> and is fundamental to the establishment of God’s kingdom. “Zion cannot be built up,” the Lord said, “unless it is by the principles of the law of the celestial kingdom.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> The covenant of consecration is central to this law. We shall one day apply it in its fulness. This covenant embraces the “giving of one’s time, talents, and means to care for those in need—whether spiritually or temporally—and in building the Lord’s kingdom.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p24" pid="lPeVu1w1UEar6GsdHBAZzw" hash="sS7tIw">These principles of <span class="emphasis">love, work, self-reliance,</span> and <span class="emphasis">consecration</span> are God given. Those who embrace them and govern themselves accordingly become pure in heart. Righteous unity is the hallmark of their society. Their peace and harmony become an ensign to the nations. Said the Prophet Joseph Smith:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p25" pid="C256z9RkFEyntSMLiwkoJw" hash="T3ci2Q">“The building up of Zion is a cause that has interested the people of God in every age; it is a theme upon which prophets, priests and kings have dwelt with peculiar delight; … it is left for us to see, participate in and help to roll forward the Latter-day glory [of Zion] … <span class="emphasis">a work that is destined to bring about the destruction of the powers of darkness, the renovation of the earth, the glory of God, and the salvation of the human family.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion.p26" pid="E_nMwrUGX06ihKCVQJbYOA" hash="QWr4tA">I bear witness that these things are true. President Gordon B. Hinckley is God’s prophet on the earth, as was Joseph Smith Jr. The kingdom of God is The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and will become Zion in all her beauty. Christ is the Savior of the world, the Beloved Son of the living God, the Holy One. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2002/10/come-to-zion-come-to-zion</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2002-general-conference/2002-10-5050-bishop-keith-b-mcmullin-64k-eng.mp3" length="5527752" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2002 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jesus, the Very Thought of Thee</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Jesus, the very thought of Thee fills my heart with inexpressible joy. It controls every part of my being.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10031248_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="XIF6Fg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ff5bZzIegkCF4_nYjHLiQQ" hash="VUlxMw">Jesus, the Very Thought of Thee</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="UhbI44Xff0SbwG0nUmpALA" hash="bnTkHA">Keith B. McMullin</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="ktI0clA4Vkayj01Y7smJuA" hash="lvKKDw">Jesus, the very thought of Thee fills my heart with inexpressible joy. It controls every part of my being.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-183.jpg" alt="Bishop Keith B. McMullin" pid="4AwVqqzoF0S_QGv035vlbA" hash="HRPyCA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p1" pid="mqahT4lXxE2V9g9WtF4YOw" hash="fkVhvA">Recently President Hinckley was overheard saying to a young couple newly married in the temple, “What a wonderful time to be alive and to be in love.” His optimistic outlook and nature are reassuring. They foster hope in an otherwise gloomy world. These are, however, more than mere expressions of a positive personality. A glimpse into the past will help illustrate what I mean.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p2" pid="qSljtsKVdUKuOt8FEKmFHQ" hash="Wa5bqw">In the early 12th century, the cleric Saint Bernard of Clairvaux, “a man of intense … faith,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> penned the following words:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="R_nPTq4yyUCBq_sS-WxeCA" hash="VUlxMw1">
            <span class="emphasis">Jesus, the very thought of thee</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="8c2l3WVYwEaRskGwvJspnQ" hash="7YfgPA">
            <span class="emphasis">With sweetness fills my breast;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="ebrlrjrCnUa5Q4E7Y8Hv6g" hash="vFis8w">
            <span class="emphasis">But sweeter far thy face to see</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="bfFCf5t1rE6MJT28q8aUQQ" hash="9A4ztQ">
            <span class="emphasis">And in thy presence rest.</span>
            <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p3" pid="PSl_RqayCkq17rt1bJ7v_A" hash="5tnPfw">These lines speak of hope and joy and peace, though written in a time when much of the world lay blanketed in ignorance, impoverishment, and despair. These words capture the calm assurance that always accompanies the testimony of Jesus. This same assurance gives buoyancy and optimism to our beloved prophet and to all the faithful followers of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p4" pid="kwBxkfXkMkym5mbisnLQqQ" hash="L0jhcQ">What, then, is this testimony of Jesus, how can it be acquired, and what will it do for those who receive it? The testimony of Jesus is the sure and certain knowledge, revealed to the spirit of a person through the Holy Ghost, that Jesus is the living Son of the living God.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p5" pid="UINSQR6ZNk2ZP3Dx_t8zyA" hash="GIxmgA">Because the testimony of Jesus is God-given, it stands preeminent and is essential to a happy life. It is the fundamental principle of our religion, and all other things pertaining to our faith are appendages to it.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> President Hinckley reminds us:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p6" pid="yliNQRIzBUuKKkuov6XBYA" hash="Vxmk7w">“It is the privilege, it is the opportunity, it is the obligation of every Latter-day Saint to gain for himself or herself a certain knowledge … that Jesus is the Christ, the Son of God, the Redeemer of all mankind. … That testimony … is the most precious possession that any of us can hold. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p7" pid="VncRk-gdWEqhNBcUKyh4Eg" hash="NHY1hw">“… I am satisfied … that whenever a man has a true witness in his heart of the living reality of the Lord Jesus Christ all else will come together as it should.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p8" pid="iIcJgVAxm0OeV8yI3B-KhQ" hash="WWayww">Nurtured through righteous living, this testimony of Jesus becomes the governing force in all that a person does. Furthermore, it is available to everyone, for “God is no respecter of persons.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p9" pid="E9EkkB5C-UeZXY2RoOSF1A" hash="NS2eJw">Acquiring such a testimony does not, however, come without personal effort. One must <span class="emphasis">desire to know, study to learn, live to merit, </span>and<span class="emphasis"> pray to receive.</span> When so pursued in humility and faith, the knowledge comes, and with this knowledge comes both the sweet assurance that all will be well and the inner strength to make it so.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="syeguYxAsUOGpO_VMJisGw" hash="n0c6jQ">Desire to Know</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p10" pid="8EOntlk1vUmVq_VDSI7ZYA" hash="ihOWOA">The <span class="emphasis">desire to know </span>is the first step in one’s quest for a testimony of Jesus. The scriptures counsel, “If ye will awake and arouse your faculties, even to an experiment upon my words, and exercise a particle of faith, yea, even if ye can no more than <span class="emphasis">desire to believe, </span>let this <span class="emphasis">desire work in you,</span> even until ye believe in a manner that ye can give place for a portion of my words.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="qIPHnAOQLEmz46Oh5oP0OA" hash="vaXvwA">Study to Learn</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p11" pid="kkXtl_gv50-flcBnjSiqjA" hash="tJSfKg">A testimony of Jesus requires that the honest seeker <span class="emphasis">study to learn.</span> Said the Lord, “Search the scriptures; for in them ye think ye have eternal life: and they are they which testify of me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p12" pid="_Ja9kXpUFUSFG3KdFcK3GA" hash="HB9znQ">From cover to cover, the Holy Bible teaches and testifies of Christ. He is Jehovah of the Old Testament, Messiah of the New.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> The Book of Mormon, another testament of Him, was compiled, preserved, and brought forth for the express purpose of “convincing … Jew and Gentile that J<small>ESUS</small> is the C<small>HRIST</small>, the E<small>TERNAL</small> G<small>OD</small>, manifesting himself unto all nations.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="B8VLrAqn-EOdDnr57CLFcQ" hash="XYTTMQ">Live to Merit</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p13" pid="VqtT3UfRB0mNw82_c3My3w" hash="H_FQCQ">Concurrent with one’s <span class="emphasis">desire</span> and <span class="emphasis">study,</span> one must <span class="emphasis">live to merit</span> such a testimony. The person who does what Jesus says comes to know who Jesus is. Said He:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p14" pid="XFV53xBGBES1XfgoGIsMSQ" hash="PvjNRg">“My doctrine is not mine, but his that sent me.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p15" pid="UpbrFkhhik6pOLhQI-am3w" hash="cLST0Q">“If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it be of God, or whether I speak of myself.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="wq096KG4g0WmtU0IU2msZg" hash="I2R9Ig">Pray to Receive</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p16" pid="A68HmN_A3k6ujpqENC0vOA" hash="VzCtqQ">Finally, the testimony of Jesus comes to those who <span class="emphasis">pray to receive </span>it. “Ask, and it shall be given you”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> is the invitation that leads the humble and penitent to such knowledge. With this knowledge, the seeker also gains an understanding of the origin and purposes of life, opening vistas that would otherwise remain hidden.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p17" pid="dPvOPLWQJE6rSQAG4UvnpA" hash="0g98dA">For example, the Lord’s life did not begin in Bethlehem,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> and ours did not begin at birth. In the premortal world, He stood as the stalwart, unwavering advocate of God’s eternal plan for His children,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> and we were there. In the great War in Heaven, it was by the power of the Firstborn that Lucifer was cast out,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> and we helped champion the cause. Through God’s Only Begotten Son “the worlds are and were created,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> and we can therefore achieve our divine potential. As President J. Reuben Clark has said:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p18" pid="hqFY5VYtq0yzWRUCpx5C-w" hash="t2HXrw">“It was not a novice, not an amateur, not a Being making a first trial, that came down in the beginning … and … made this world. …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p19" pid="wAwd-7AmlEOCDAd3qdQeBg" hash="evrukA">“And if you think of this galaxy of ours having within it from the beginning perhaps … one million worlds, and multiply that by the number of millions of galaxies … that surround us, you will then get some view of who [Jesus Christ] is.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p20" pid="giT_q5WE6E2bzjtjUbyhsA" hash="FjGupw">In awe, we exult with the ancient cleric: Jesus, the very thought of Thee with <span class="emphasis">wonder </span>fills my breast.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p21" pid="6AfK8bAqMEepjLNeEEqDJA" hash="Qx4_Ew">As the literal offspring of God and being born of a mortal mother, the premortal Christ became the Only Begotten of the Father in the flesh. Though the fulness of His majesty, messiahship, and godhood came not at first, He “continued from grace to grace, until he received a fulness,” and so can we.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p22" pid="tjcbqO3Po02kxA0x_LyiiQ" hash="fwV1Rg">Angels attended Him, the Holy Ghost descended upon Him, the woes of all mankind were carried by Him, and our sins can be forgiven through Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p23" pid="Dh7Zd3KnFke-_KVfqS0qtw" hash="5IrkGg">This Jesus, who is called Christ, wrought out a perfect atonement for all mankind by His incomparable life, His suffering in Gethsemane, the shedding of His blood, His death upon the cross, and His glorious Resurrection. He conquered the grave, and because of Him, so will we.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> “He is the greatest Being to be born on this earth. … He is Lord of lords, King of kings, … the Savior, … the Bright and Morning Star. … His name … is the only name under heaven [whereby] we can be saved.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> He is the Anointed One. Again we exclaim: Jesus, the very thought of Thee with <span class="emphasis">reverence </span>fills my breast.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p24" pid="jmmIpK0TXkywKWb5Rh2H_w" hash="0zlxew">As the world could not overcome Him in the meridian of time, so the world cannot do without Him in our time, and neither can we. His purpose is “to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> Hence, He came to the Prophet Joseph Smith, restored the priesthood, reestablished His Church, and again proclaimed the plan of redemption. Joseph saw Him, conversed with Him, and has left us this transcendent, poetic account of Him:</p>
        <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.f3">
          <div class="stanza">
            <p class="line" pid="Cl4TETrHlE-Nt8U4aXI6vA" hash="SifzAA">
              <span class="emphasis">I beheld round the throne holy angels and hosts,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="55uIQSq_KUanAiFPgmcUOQ" hash="IIiYBA">
              <span class="emphasis">And sanctified beings from worlds that have been,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="kkdKba9_80OPTXSg0zEo7A" hash="hanHQg">
              <span class="emphasis">In holiness worshipping God and the Lamb,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="0r33tbf6vEmS3PsGD1Vgmg" hash="spbg6Q">
              <span class="emphasis">For ever and ever. Amen and amen.</span>
            </p>
          </div>
          <div class="stanza">
            <p class="line" pid="slfM85O1gUmu_QUbLYtq3A" hash="t2iLQQ">
              <span class="emphasis">And now after all of the proofs made of him,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="P42-lj_H9UGugXS9hVV7jw" hash="7RyegQ">
              <span class="emphasis">By witnesses truly, by whom he was known,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="xOa47avcRUeYDnvi-BSQRQ" hash="dy7Zzw">
              <span class="emphasis">This is mine, last of all, that he lives; yea, he lives!</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="9KpwSSGO_UOP1bzW7bL8_A" hash="-hs3nA">
              <span class="emphasis">And sits at the right hand of God on his throne.</span>
            </p>
          </div>
          <div class="stanza">
            <p class="line" pid="3V3ugk5Fd0qYGvUWLdrlaw" hash="QV1wCA">
              <span class="emphasis">And I heard a great voice bearing record from heav’n,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="v22ruS8N7UKjsWwAEHZQVw" hash="jHvecA">
              <span class="emphasis">He’s the Saviour and only begotten of God;</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="9W6NFm7oNU-MrLNPuOTvLg" hash="okRmJg">
              <span class="emphasis">By him, of him, and through him, the worlds were all made,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="k66eFkwPu0-H_WCRbGKoHQ" hash="4brMzw">
              <span class="emphasis">Even all that [careen] in the heavens so broad.</span>
            </p>
          </div>
          <div class="stanza">
            <p class="line" pid="_t1OUDDepU2WanPrZm54Ig" hash="kgnYeA">
              <span class="emphasis">Whose inhabitants, too, from the first to the last,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="wU2lCMl5tESJwjOfyHzm1w" hash="BJB3mA">
              <span class="emphasis">Are sav’d by the very same Saviour of ours;</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="xH59GJF6fU6AcVQeTc5O3Q" hash="MmvY8w">
              <span class="emphasis">And, of course, are begotten God’s daughters and sons</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="DfVVAA6GkEKoUe4R8BcWtw" hash="ezZ0bA">
              <span class="emphasis">By the very same truths and the very same powers.</span>
              <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span>
            </p>
          </div>
        </div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p25" pid="H-G8ti2-3UWVrgv9Vdqpow" hash="5Kn6bw">We have with us today the Lord’s duly ordained Apostles. True to their sacred commission as “special witnesses of the name of Christ in all the world,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> they declare:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p26" pid="JPxDSQT0OEOnFfTi37AMyQ" hash="M5zQWQ">“Jesus is the Living Christ, the immortal Son of God. He is the great King Immanuel, who stands today on the right hand of His Father. He is the light, the life, and the hope of the world. His way is the path that leads to happiness in this life and eternal life in the world to come. God be thanked for the matchless gift of His divine Son.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p27" pid="Tlm_R3ROA0aVrHXuUGjJcA" hash="r0S1pg">Jesus, the very thought of Thee fills my heart with <span class="emphasis">inexpressible joy.</span> It controls every part of my being. My life, my loves, my ambitions are molded, enlivened, and given purpose because I know that Thou art the Christ, the Holy One.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee.p28" pid="4u7vO6C4QU6-8A0nzMYwEA" hash="0ZOcGw">I thank God for my testimony of Jesus and pray that all may be likewise blessed, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2004/04/jesus-the-very-thought-of-thee</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2004-general-conference/2004-04-2060-bishop-keith-b-mcmullin-64k-eng.mp3" length="4957302" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2004 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Prepared … Be Ye Strong from Henceforth</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Tragedies never triumph where personal righteousness prevails.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10033479_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="s6tAGw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="l_0yXGjC00C3hUGYTWVZLQ" hash="b-ZHSA">Be Prepared … Be Ye Strong from Henceforth</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="_MfOEdjxyUuIdasRTQ6yZA" hash="bnTkHA">Keith B. McMullin</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="l6SlTLiRyUmtMr0TQ3e7Zw" hash="2245bg">Tragedies never triumph where personal righteousness prevails.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-183.jpg" alt="Bishop Keith B. McMullin" pid="nrvWYogS9U2iV49dHF7ZiA" hash="HRPyCA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p1" pid="ar9-0mqzdkSvbbgq4VD_hw" hash="DvrndQ">Have you ever found yourself in a conversation where you were suddenly required to remain silent while your point of view was misconstrued and belittled? Such a thing happened to me almost 25 years ago, and the frustration of that unfinished conversation has remained to this day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p2" pid="QYN-RUGu8UKJVKUE4CU1qg" hash="0DulMg">As mission president, I had been invited, with others from the Church, to meet with the mayor of one of the cities in our mission. He was cordial as he welcomed us into his office. Our conversation touched upon concerns of the day. Eventually, he asked why the Church was doing missionary work in his city.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p3" pid="hyLpV36gmkerwaNwnGgP_g" hash="PkM68w">This was not unexpected. An impression had come to me some weeks before that he would ask this question and what my response should be. I replied: “The gospel of Jesus Christ provides answers and solutions to all of the world’s problems, including those confronting the good people of your city. This is why we are here.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p4" pid="onjVqy40w06CDX1u1vi7UA" hash="LW3KvA">I fully expected the mayor would want to know more. Instead, his mood changed. Skepticism then disdain took control of his countenance. He blustered about my naive approach to challenges in the world and brought our visit to an abrupt close. No further explanation was permitted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p5" pid="IsullMRCTke7hqilN8PC1w" hash="eof7PA">This morning, I should like to complete that conversation. I hope the good mayor is listening because what follows is vital to a troubled world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p6" pid="JedGx5yiRk2TPpw6Bqp0xQ" hash="kxtU_Q">We are sobered by the terrible calamities of recent years. They occur with increasing frequency and intensity. Natural forces are ferocious in their scope, human assaults are merciless in their carnage, and unchecked appetites are leading to licentiousness, crime, and family decay approaching epic proportions. The tsunami in southern Asia and hurricanes in the United States, with their terrible tolls, are the most recent calamities capturing our attention. Hearts and hands from around the world reach out to those so profoundly affected. For a brief period differences yield to compassion and love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p7" pid="ucdDoU7lg0ixslm3_93xGA" hash="Ke9LXQ">We are indebted to those who, when buffeted by calamities, remind us of man’s dependence upon God. A widow in a refugee camp, anguishing over the brutal slaying of her sons, weeps the words, “I must not lose my faith.” Survivors, overwhelmed by Katrina’s fury, send out the plea, “Pray for us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p8" pid="HwANY5LAFEip7OCXIJ1eFQ" hash="dr2I5Q">Causes of such calamities are the subject of seemingly endless debate. Commentators, politicians, scientists, and many others have opinions as to the causes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p9" pid="X4EzNQQDqUquPhAVleWCUQ" hash="TwTfmw">The Lord Jesus Christ said, concerning the Restoration of His gospel:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p10" pid="7-qk84Pds02kgA3Kqfdp6w" hash="yDzHNA">“Wherefore, I the Lord, knowing the calamity which should come upon the inhabitants of the earth, called upon my servant Joseph Smith, Jun., and spake unto him from heaven, and gave him commandments; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p11" pid="lUCr5LdUjkWNgr8LLe4juQ" hash="1F3Rvw">“Search these commandments, for they are true and faithful, and the prophecies and promises which are in them shall all be fulfilled.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p12" pid="KK6WGp5h70S3hsaVJygwEA" hash="NZKC8Q">Let us turn our attention to the reasons or purposes for such calamities. Fortunately, debate is not needed here because we have the fulness of Christ’s gospel on which we can rely. Search the words of the prophets in the Book of Mormon and the Bible; read the teachings of Jesus Christ in the 24th chapter of Matthew;<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> study the Lord’s latter-day revelations in the Doctrine and Covenants.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Herein we learn the purposes of God in such matters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p13" pid="bUbgZ0j8L0-vfrr3F8muow" hash="jTJaxA">Calamities are a form of adversity, and adversity is a necessary part of Heavenly Father’s plan for the happiness of His children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p14" pid="W_ZVIUGYdUmxcTQ7pkqrMg" hash="kKij6Q">If our hearts are right before God, adversity will school us, help us overcome our carnal nature, and nurture the divine spark within us. Were it not for adversity, we would not know to “choose the better part.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Adversity helps us see where we need to repent, to bring into subjection baser instincts, to embrace righteousness and enjoy “peace of conscience.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p15" pid="VoZkTmQ_kE2E2hBSvwlytQ" hash="i0kqAg">The more we cleave unto righteousness, the more we enjoy the protecting care of our Savior. He is the Creator and Lord of the universe. He will calm the winds and the waves.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> His teachings and Atonement will heal the repentant soul. He is the Messiah or Deliverer, and because of Him, each of us can be in charge of his or her personal world, even as tragedies beset us. Listen to these truths:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p16" pid="t4Cmlvt32kCNHnIvgiTiBw" hash="chFyKQ">“The Messiah cometh in the fulness of time, that he may redeem the children of men from the fall. And because that <span class="emphasis">they are redeemed</span> from the fall they have become free forever, knowing good from evil; <span class="emphasis">to act for themselves and not to be acted upon, save it be by the punishment of the law at the great and last day, according to the commandments which God hath given.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p17" pid="Pi0I5CIjNUW4t_reoktPQg" hash="_wtQHA">“Wherefore, <span class="emphasis">men are free according to the flesh;</span> and all things are given them which are expedient unto man. And they are free to choose liberty and eternal life, through the great Mediator of all men, or to choose captivity and death, according to the captivity and power of the devil; for [the devil] seeketh that all men might be miserable like unto himself.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p18" pid="p0mWFhn7KkqsXF1SYYaNZQ" hash="8ZBBbA">We will do well to remember that the devil is the destroyer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p19" pid="AV1g59T_kEatoISrMtLdLw" hash="bKETog">It is true that in this life we are only as free as our mortal circumstances allow. We may not be able to stay the course of war in distant lands or with our puny arm hold back the tempests that rage or run freely when our body is imprisoned by failing health. <span class="emphasis">But it is verily true that such things do not ultimately control our personal world. We do!</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p20" pid="-3OaSRvgoUSHvdfc8Y-Big" hash="mM2PMg">The Prophet Joseph Smith declared: “Happiness is the object and design of our existence; and will be the end thereof, if we pursue the path that leads to it; and this path is virtue, uprightness, faithfulness, holiness, and keeping all the commandments of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p21" pid="sZJQvyi96EudIk9E4CxAuw" hash="XbkkMQ">And so, most honorable mayor, the gospel of Jesus Christ does provide answers to all of the world’s problems, <span class="emphasis">precisely because it provides solutions to the ills of every living soul.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p22" pid="V7XT78bEeEKdkXL79WKWKw" hash="xTm1Xw">Every time calamity strikes, there is a corresponding sacred obligation that falls upon each of us to become better. We should ask ourselves, “What part of my life needs to change so that the weight of chastisement need not be felt?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p23" pid="R8O9XC9pf0-NXnCzRiORQg" hash="PS4uEA">In the scriptures the Lord makes clear what He expects of us as such judgments descend. He says: “Gird up your loins and be prepared. Behold, the kingdom is yours, and the enemy shall not overcome.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p24" pid="3ZjkHgv1-UqSWqzUIZAOuQ" hash="BI19qg">The Church and its members are commanded to be self-reliant and independent.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> Preparation begins with faith, which enables us to weather vicissitudes as they come. We see earth life as a preparatory journey. Faith in the Lord and His gospel conquers fear and begets spirituality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p25" pid="ynvM1ePod0KCQuuSrdxtsA" hash="r9An1A">Spirituality grows as we “pray, and … walk uprightly before the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> It is “the consciousness of victory over self and of communion with the Infinite.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p26" pid="7-PrNdDVO0Wpq3d6X_v-VA" hash="nfgjzA">Faith, spirituality, and obedience produce a prepared and self-reliant people. As we obey the covenant of tithing, we are shielded from want and the power of the destroyer. As we obey the fast and give generously to care for others, our prayers are heard and family fidelity increases. Similar blessings come as we obey the counsel of the prophets and live within our means, avoid unnecessary debt, and set aside sufficient of life’s necessities to sustain ourselves and our families for at least a year. This may not always be easy, but let us do our “very best,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> and our stores shall not fail—there shall be “enough and to spare.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p27" pid="scRY5kX32EiBzE-y1d389A" hash="7RsZnQ">And again the Lord says, “Be ye strong from henceforth; fear not, for the kingdom is yours.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p28" pid="R6zYxAhAj0yC1r_WVekztg" hash="Oh0aYA">Strength and resiliency come by righteous living. One is not righteous who is a saint on Sunday and a slacker the remainder of the week. Unchecked appetites are destructive and cause men to “trifle … with sacred things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> President Brigham Young taught, “The sin that will cleave to all the posterity of Adam and Eve is, that they have not done as well as they knew how.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p29" pid="ICkLZ8TMMU2Q-LgrRrY20w" hash="N19Tpg">The gospel of Jesus Christ is the pathway to righteousness. Tragedies never triumph where personal righteousness prevails. Let us, therefore, heed the counsel of the Apostle Paul:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p30" pid="QigihPx9SUyW1hx2Hlzx2Q" hash="bjK26g">“The night is far spent, the day is at hand: let us therefore cast off the works of darkness, and let us put on the armour of light.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p31" pid="NuWpGOZb606x_to4IpDTHA" hash="IuCrLg">“Let us walk honestly, as in the day; not in rioting and drunkenness, not in chambering and wantonness, not in strife and envying.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p32" pid="9vm1H3k0LUS2W1tf8g5aJw" hash="hV-JPg">“But put ye on the Lord Jesus Christ, and make not provision for the flesh, to fulfil the lusts thereof.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p33" pid="_oynXwwyzkOWy1xfi4MXgQ" hash="nTajyg">Our duty as Latter-day Saints is to prepare ourselves, this earth, and its inhabitants for the Second Coming of the Lord Jesus Christ. Being prepared and being strong as the gospel teaches ensure happiness here and hereafter and make this “grand millennial mission” possible.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p34" pid="yJClSQKookugEVKn3Ro84g" hash="XgtorQ">Our beloved President Hinckley has admonished: “Now, my brethren and sisters, the time has come for us to stand a little taller, to lift our eyes and stretch our minds to a greater comprehension and understanding of the grand millennial mission of this The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. This is a season to be strong. It is a time to move forward without hesitation, knowing well the meaning, the breadth, and the importance of our mission. It is a time to do what is right regardless of the consequences that might follow. It is a time to be found keeping the commandments. It is a season to reach out with kindness and love to those in distress and to those who are wandering in darkness and pain. It is a time to be considerate and good, decent and courteous toward one another in all of our relationships. In other words, to become more Christlike.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p35" pid="11qCVZ21W0Sufg9NQAiXXg" hash="EaXiNQ">This admonition by the Lord’s prophet points our way through these turbulent times. To all who suffer, our hearts reach out to you. May Heavenly Father, in His infinite mercy, make light your burdens and fill your lives with that peace which “passeth all understanding.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> You are not alone. Our love and faith and prayers are joined with yours. Press forward in righteousness and all will be well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth.p36" pid="tZr1-FGELEuGrdThLwXkvA" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2005/10/be-prepared-be-ye-strong-from-henceforth</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2005-general-conference/2005-10-1030-bishop-keith-b-mcmullin-64k-eng.mp3" length="6064274" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lay Up in Store</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We call upon priesthood bearers to store sufficient so that you and your family can weather the vicissitudes of life.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008333_000_022" doc-version="2" hash="K9XVHQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="mdWQyhxXzU--CTTR0-B9rQ" hash="fOMdSg">Lay Up in Store</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Y6uQGAslpkK6b9CrV6xstA" hash="bnTkHA">Keith B. McMullin</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="7E8at3VZ-kSLKaf-JF2Y6A" hash="n4RMXQ">We call upon priesthood bearers to store sufficient so that you and your family can weather the vicissitudes of life.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.t1">
      <img src="McMullinKB_all.ob.jpg" alt="Bishop Keith B. McMullin" pid="uIFJOnBHxkq_aYCeQriwag" hash="IR0Vsw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p1" pid="defpIeQhxkmAFNWKG5cF5g" hash="8neoYQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="51"></span>My dear brethren, how blessed we are to be assembled together with the First Presidency and the Twelve Apostles. Each priesthood bearer present, be he 12 or 112, can, because of our Savior Jesus Christ, inherit the celestial order of life “by obedience to the laws and ordinances of the Gospel.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> This is wonderful to contemplate, and I know it is true. You are in charge of your world!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p2" pid="rL8FUqGHDUKCPpwuCJYXvA" hash="mHS4zQ">With this prospect before us, consider the following story. A young man, full of ambition and energy, enrolled in a fine university. At the time, he was a priest in the Aaronic Priesthood. His goal was lofty—he wanted to become a doctor. His aim was ambitious—he wanted to be rich. He wanted to play football, so he sought out the coaches and eventually made the team. Now he could have the recognition and bragging rights unique in the world of university sports. Such were the notions in his head.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p3" pid="27LAJFIQIUKpkdVtTcreEQ" hash="i_T_TQ">But he had given little thought to something that would ultimately dismantle his lofty and vain ambitions—he had failed to lay up in store. He had overlooked the importance of adequate preparation, the requirements of regular attendance and disciplined study, and the college chemistry class. The consequence was swift and merciless. It took less than 90 days. It happened this way:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p4" pid="Zx74w9qsfEy-AxZApAS7Gw" hash="itKJ6g">The day he found his 5-foot 8-inch, 170-pound body on the line of scrimmage opposite a mammoth lineman from the varsity squad, he knew he was in the wrong sport.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p5" pid="SuA1j-nkBEaJ558mXLx0oQ" hash="EzkZAA">Unaccustomed to rigorous study, his eyes and mind refused to function after a brief time in the books.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p6" pid="m6lVLlePAEOTWFpScCl-Hw" hash="G4pE-Q">The capstone of defeat was the final chemistry exam. Suffice it to say that his random answers to multiple-choice questions did not even approximate the law of averages. He failed miserably.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p7" pid="Na5TouulGEmN7ZCVhx1LCw" hash="fOG-ig">Hard work, a mission that awakened in him a correct vision of life’s purposes, and unrelenting preparation eventually overcame the consequence of this brief period of foolishness. Even today, however, I still have nightmares about that chemistry class.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p8" pid="xOrazdut30SpIZnhX4G9_g" hash="m-SchA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="52"></span>Fortunately, the Lord has shown us how to avoid similar foolishness. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p9" pid="2vB8T1Z8_065BBXMl60gWA" hash="vbZuag">“Hearken, O ye people of my church. … Hearken ye people from afar; and ye that are upon the islands of the sea, listen together. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p10" pid="Tnt7rzAonkuRLa6Pe0MIhQ" hash="q4bZug">“Prepare ye, prepare ye for that which is to come, for the Lord is nigh.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p11" pid="adS0Hn2j9EyoVxR8Hj9mfQ" hash="yafWBA">The doctrine of the Second Coming of the Messiah provides one of the great incentives to prepare and live right. Heavenly Father knows that promised rewards encourage His children to do works of righteousness and promised penalties create a dread of doing evil. Such are the revelations pertaining to the Second Coming of our Lord.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p12" pid="jIlmDlzyVUSZoR5UsentEQ" hash="PYeQZA">These revelations speak of signs and wonders on earth and in the heavens. They point to troublesome times and pending events vast in scope and duration. And most important, we receive these supernal promises:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p13" pid="kEkFtLW2QE6P2Q55Gd5wlw" hash="PeimhA">“The Lord shall have power over his saints, and shall reign in their midst.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p14" pid="kbq9Q5sVCUyKmrzmq8eSSw" hash="IPYsSQ">“Through my providence, notwithstanding the tribulation which shall descend upon you, … the church may stand independent above all other creatures beneath the celestial world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p15" pid="48HKJoAxgES7iwxnQuWGEQ" hash="1SPbNQ">And “if ye are prepared ye shall not fear.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p16" pid="fjBArPnyb0e8PEFDYyGpvg" hash="6S3jsw">Priesthood bearers are led by these promises to prepare themselves and their families for the Lord’s appearing.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> There is no need to be anxious about events leading up to the Second Coming. Let us instead be filled with gratitude for our understanding of what lies ahead. Let us appreciate that we are in charge of our own world, being the Lord’s agents over that which He has entrusted to us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> The formula is simple: Be faithful. Unencumber your life. Lay up in store.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p17" pid="IQ7Cglddz0K-dFCL0ofXAA" hash="_XEIIg">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">Be faithful.</span>
</span> As priesthood bearers, we cultivate a gentle touch and kindly word. We are men who pray, who keep the Sabbath day holy, and who know the word of God. We tithe, fast, and give a generous fast offering. We keep our covenants and consecrate our lives to the building up of God’s kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p18" pid="XcXpTZF_Z0Wyb5r0Y0T5UA" hash="DNS2Yw">And, brethren, we <span class="emphasis">lay up in store!</span> By doing these things, “the Lord shall have power over his saints, and shall reign in [our] midst.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p19" pid="GnnL6j-XFEOL_jKrWB4lgQ" hash="LlkFwA">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">Unencumber your life.</span>
</span> As men of God, we turn from excess to that which edifies, for “that which doth not edify is not of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> If dealings or involvements or pursuits or schedules detract from putting God first, we must pare back and unencumber our lives.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> If we have debts, we pay them and live debt free to the extent possible.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p20" pid="iIt4D9O_lUCsdsCmLPAMfw" hash="Jyq-Gw">And, brethren, we <span class="emphasis">lay up in store!</span> Then, “through [the Lord’s] providence, notwithstanding the tribulation … the church [and its people will] stand independent.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p21" pid="kjH4_4oKC0GqwDf-He2phQ" hash="SRmczg">
        <span class="strong">
  <span class="emphasis">Lay up in store.</span>
</span> Wives are instrumental in this work, but they need husbands who lead out in family preparedness. Children need parents who instill in them this righteous tradition. They will then do likewise with their children, and their stores will not fail.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p22" pid="bikWfn7Luk2bu0vZvADKQQ" hash="bk1FpQ">A cardinal principle of the gospel is to prepare for the day of scarcity. Work, industry, frugality are part of the royal order of life. Remember these words from Paul: “If any provide not for his own, and specially for those of his own house, he hath denied the faith, and is worse than an infidel.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p23" pid="9_32F2rHBk2cmCX2SANonQ" hash="2-hhJA">Seated before us are the three presiding high priests who constitute the First Presidency of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p24" pid="pcXnMZ7z2UKaceOQp2rpkA" hash="X8a6EA">From President James E. Faust, Second Counselor, we hear: “Every father and mother are the family’s storekeepers. They should store whatever their own family would like to have in the case of an emergency … [and] God will sustain us through our trials.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p25" pid="ydEc7JbD2Em3TbF5q5jXCg" hash="WJjgbg">From President Thomas S. Monson, First Counselor, we hear: “Many more people could ride out the storm-tossed waves in their economic lives if they had their year’s supply of food … and were debt-free. Today we find that many have followed this counsel in reverse: they have at least a year’s supply of debt and are food-free.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p26" pid="i5q0ohjjXUqYedXCaJ_13g" hash="g3zicA">From President Gordon B. Hinckley, the Lord’s prophet, we hear:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p27" pid="gsVeZq7JMUSpCEPmaP9-Wg" hash="A1DB3Q">“The best place to have some food set aside is within our homes. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p28" pid="Wpo9ZpVCPk-bYf4sbY4cbA" hash="vc-UVA">“We can begin ever so modestly. We can begin with a one week’s food supply and gradually build it to a month, and then to three months. … I fear that so many feel that a long-term food supply is so far beyond their reach that they make no effort at all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p29" pid="Qiy-xmi4I0eiTbcBPwKJUQ" hash="e00pTA">“Begin in a small way, … and gradually build toward a reasonable objective.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p30" pid="VDTE6mqS8Em7u7B-TbIOIA" hash="BGFqOw">Inspired preparation rests on the foundation of faith in Jesus Christ, obedience, and a provident lifestyle. Members should not go to extremes, but they should begin.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p31" pid="cOJMKx661UuFzCFtRgOmcA" hash="3zCbQQ">We call upon priesthood bearers to store sufficient so that you and your family can weather the vicissitudes of life. Please see to it that <span class="pageBreak" page-number="53"></span>those entrusted to your watchcare receive these two pamphlets entitled <span class="emphasis">All Is Safely Gathered In.</span> Exhort them to prepare now for rainy days ahead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p32" pid="Daf8cd5UOUuPZelzb5PjqA" hash="W2kdmg">Priesthood leaders, enlist the Relief Society in promoting family preparedness and homemaking. The women of the Church need your backing and will respond to your leadership.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p33" pid="eq3fYEHgc06mNcKKwX0g_w" hash="GmtMVg">Encourage our members to regularly put into their home storage a few wholesome, basic food items and some water that is safe to drink. They should save some money, if only a few coins each week. This modest approach will soon enable them to have several months’ reserve. Over time they can expand these modest efforts into a longer-term supply by adding such essentials as grains, legumes, and other staples that will keep them alive in case they do not have anything else to eat.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p34" pid="7z-v3QZeSU63RmVFdf0f7Q" hash="1BHU2w">As we do our very best, we can be confident that “the barrel of meal shall not waste, neither shall the cruse of oil fail.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> We shall enjoy greater wisdom, security, peace of mind, and personal well-being. We shall be prepared, and because we are prepared, we “shall not fear.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p35" pid="8kTVaJ8oLUeEwhAeunIBog" hash="1bAoRg">In closing, I introduce to you the Luca and Patrizia Vaccarono family. They live in a small town near Rome, Italy. In a recent letter, they wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p36" pid="DCyIhNCujkG0rHMONGkNaA" hash="AJGdaQ">“We decided after some experience that it is important to store the items we use. Sometimes we have to modify our habits in eating certain kinds of foods. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p37" pid="s6JwyFN2Xkq5rR_89OE9KA" hash="bEKk-g">“The feeling of peace and the desire to be faithful to the commandment given by the Lord through the modern prophet helps us feel the Holy Spirit, … to not be afraid, and to see that the signs of the time for the Second Coming of the Lord is a blessing and not something to fear. We rejoice in it. … It gives us the motivation to be faithful and endure to the end and to be saved and obtain eternal life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store.p38" pid="2JLZx_XdLE6xB9cuO2jr1g" hash="VHEwWg">As a final thought, Brother Vaccarono writes: “I’m sorry for my English. I hope you understand what I tried to explain to you.” Brother and Sister Vaccarono, we understand, for it is written in scripture: “Trust in the Lord with all thine heart; and lean not unto thine own understanding. In all thy ways acknowledge him, and he shall direct thy paths.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/04/lay-up-in-store</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2007-general-conference/2007-04-3030-bishop-keith-b-mcmullin-64k-eng.mp3" length="5200641" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2007 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>God Loves and Helps All of His Children</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We need Heavenly Father’s help. Important sources of this help come through man’s service to his fellowman, through prayer, and through focus on Christ.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00009501_000_025" doc-version="2" hash="V4xgLw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="c5BQPLLjVkqexHH8t3iZwQ" hash="jziTUg">God Loves and Helps All of His Children</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="uhjT2iu9K0O6HnNIsyRsnA" hash="0uTYLw">Bishop Keith B. McMullin</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="NELLJffS90Cw5CzpnISp9w" hash="heiFqQ">We need Heavenly Father’s help. Important sources of this help come through man’s service to his fellowman, through prayer, and through focus on Christ.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p1" pid="3GlO-p-PSkOpt2a1Zeo3HQ" hash="1oF5pQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="75"></span>One of the overarching truths of the Restoration is that God lives and dwells in His heavens, that He is an exalted man with “a body of flesh and bones,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> and that He is yesterday, today, and forever the same unchangeable God,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> the fountain of all virtue and truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p2" pid="umTy3Cdu6U-qBG_aXKdAjQ" hash="GmxUOQ">Adam and Eve were the first of His mortal children upon this earth. Of their advent, He said: “And I, God, created man in mine own image, in the image of mine Only Begotten created I him; male and female created I them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p3" pid="3gdLI2nZgk2SoxW24V4Tgw" hash="zOneXg">This truth elevates the human family. Men and women are wondrous creations endowed with divine attributes. At the time of Creation, God placed in Adam and Eve the supernal capacity to bear children in their likeness. We are all, therefore, in His image.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p4" pid="akSPrZm5Ikit5bDABL6ZWQ" hash="eKtktA">We do, however, contend with serious mortal frailties and hazards. Sickness, aging, and death are inescapable. Hardships and heartaches are part of life’s journey. Personal dispositions, appetites, and passions clamor for gratification.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p5" pid="JvdpCjI3RE-Jx-tpDf2DTg" hash="KXIakQ">For all these reasons and more, we need Heavenly Father’s help. An important source of this help comes through man’s service to his fellowman.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> The commandment is to “love thy neighbour as thyself.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Because we are all brothers and sisters, we are all “neighbors,” though separated at times by distance, culture, religion, or race. Said the Prophet Joseph, “A man filled with the love of God, is not content with blessing his family alone, but ranges through the whole world, anxious to bless the whole human race.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> The Lord sets the example, <span class="pageBreak" page-number="76"></span>“for he doeth that which is good among the children of men; … and he denieth none that come unto him, black and white, bond and free, male and female; and he remembereth the heathen; and all are alike unto God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p6" pid="qwg4qkUqvkGDYLx-OVULIA" hash="JmVUUA">To provide for others in the Lord’s way, we strive to care for ourselves and sacrifice to help those in need. The poor labor for what they receive and seek the betterment of others as well.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> This pattern has been with us from the beginning.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p7" pid="sKb5r_Nv-UyTNaVjLTTzmA" hash="lGnugA">The Church welfare plan embodies this divine pattern, and faithful Church members follow it. Their offerings provide succor to the widow, care to the orphan, and refuge to the suffering.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p8" pid="swenMFS2zUS8J98g0LRMRA" hash="lQPbEg">A few years ago a high-ranking official from China visited Salt Lake City, toured Church sites, and spoke at Brigham Young University. Learning about the Church welfare program, he said, “If we all loved each other like this, the world would be a more peaceful place.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p9" pid="l-IczOL2Q0OjC983Qu2acQ" hash="HAGR-A">Fasting and giving the value of the meals not eaten to help the poor captured his attention. At the conclusion of his visit to Welfare Square, he handed the manager a small red envelope—a “red pocket.” In China a “red pocket” is given as a gesture of love, blessing, and a wish for good fortune. “It does not contain much,” the visitor said, “but it represents the money I have saved from missing breakfast the last two mornings. I would like to give my fast offering to the Welfare program of the Church.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p10" pid="_S7i_H2vSUKHLhSmxNri_g" hash="8uTAsA">The Church welfare plan is God-inspired. Its tenets are fundamental to the salvation of man.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> It is an ensign for service, a witness to the world that the Church of Jesus Christ has been restored. It is heaven’s help in practical ways. President Thomas S. Monson has said: “Welfare principles … do not change. They will not change. They are revealed truths.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p11" pid="aZnfzo3Tnk21RsFqzMqekg" hash="AeAyNg">Another essential way to receive God’s help is through prayer. We are commanded to pray to God, our Father, in the name of Jesus Christ. The admonition is, “Ask, and it shall be given you; seek, and ye shall find; knock, and it shall be opened.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> Heavenly Father answers all sincere prayers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p12" pid="zgFAItlpNUa4vHiXPnjOsw" hash="2Nq9Uw">As the Lord’s prophet, President Monson counsels: “At times there appears to be no light at the tunnel’s end—no dawn to break the night’s darkness. … We feel abandoned, heartbroken, alone. If you find yourself in such a situation, I plead with you to turn to our Heavenly Father in faith. He will lift you and guide you. He will not always take your afflictions from you, but He will comfort and lead you with love through <span class="pageBreak" page-number="77"></span>whatever storm you face.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p13" pid="nb28G44h1EGVFJoj_lbFTA" hash="i9tvCA">In the face of some needs, we turn to a form of prayer available only under the hands of those authorized to minister for God. Jesus Christ went forth “healing the sick, raising the dead”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> and lifting up desperate souls. With the Restoration of the gospel came priesthood power and authority to continue this aspect of God’s work.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p14" pid="Hv_fNLc-ukyCjmtOp1UFKw" hash="buWkQw">When one is sick or deeply troubled, “call for the elders of the church; and let them pray over him, anointing him with oil in the name of the Lord: and the prayer of faith shall save the sick, and the Lord shall raise him up.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> Faithful elders are commissioned to do what the Lord would do if He were present.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p15" pid="v-bs309qVEm_nNEJU6XHDw" hash="n7DPcg">If records had been kept of prayers answered, the world could not contain the many volumes. From Elder Glen L. Rudd, an emeritus General Authority and beloved associate, comes this treasured testimonial:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p16" pid="Lg6h8oyOTECBWtubpUC4og" hash="gHHUDQ">“I received a phone call informing me that a family member, a 12-year-old girl named Janice, was in the hospital with critical injuries. Her mother wanted her to receive a priesthood blessing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p17" pid="OdOHS3uWRU-xyI8O07GAew" hash="5ySEYg">“Elder Cowley and I went to the hospital. There we learned details of the accident. Janice had been hit by a city bus. The double rear wheels had passed over her head and body.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p18" pid="Bd__dHatUUu_F0YJnsq6hA" hash="Zet9NQ">“Elder Cowley and I entered the room where Janice lay. She had a broken pelvis, a badly injured shoulder, multiple broken bones, and severe head injuries that were beyond repair. Nonetheless, it was our feeling that we should administer to her and bless her. I anointed her with oil, and Elder Cowley sealed the anointing. In a strong and resolute manner he blessed her to become well and whole and to live a normal life. He blessed her that she would recover with no lasting effects from her many injuries. It was a great blessing and a truly magnificent moment.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p19" pid="lAi6Mcsb0EyC-CWdN_M4gw" hash="aP-dJA">Elder Rudd goes on to say: “Janice didn’t move a muscle for more than a month. We never lost faith. A blessing had been pronounced that she would get well and have no lasting impairments.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p20" pid="3BqAP80hQEOhMnv64bWgbg" hash="cW6GeQ">Elder Rudd concluded: “Many years have now passed since that hospital visit. I spoke with Janice recently. She is now 70 years of age, the mother of 3 children, the grandmother of 11 grandchildren. To this day, she has not suffered a single negative effect from her accident.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p21" pid="05F0lNqeaEabAEM9HO6-1A" hash="hFrlBg">Hers is but one of many such healings. But none stands as a greater witness of how Heavenly Father helps His children through prayer than the one that took place in a hospital room, with 12-year-old Janice and two humble servants of God, some 58 years ago.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p22" pid="uQaUEmygsEel8B_1q8Wc0g" hash="Gp980g">The ultimate help from Heavenly Father comes to us through His Son, “for God so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son, that whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p23" pid="6NGkaGnSw0iTlqz6dY2mig" hash="eaVpIg">It is with great reverence and awe that I bear witness of the Lord Jesus Christ. In doing so, I am reminded how careful we must be in the use of His name. While His influence, teachings, and deliverance endear Him to us, we would do well not to speak of Him as though He were the friend next door.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p24" pid="UWJkcSXGUEmvMfG5bFquyA" hash="IouN4w">He is the Firstborn of our Father’s spirit children. He did all that was ordained for Him to do—hence all things give Him reverence and bear witness of Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> He told the ancient prophets what to write and reveals His will to His prophets today—and He fulfills their every word.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p25" pid="MZBruJehx02c3UTFW8AxXQ" hash="z6w0IA">Begotten of God, He was born of the virgin Mary, conquered death, atoned for the sins of the world, and <span class="pageBreak" page-number="78"></span>brought salvation to both the living and dead. As our resurrected Lord, He ate fish and honeycomb with the Apostles and invited multitudes on both hemispheres to feel the wounds in His hands, feet, and side that all might know He is the God of Israel—He is the living Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p26" pid="iCCIJd55hEKyRuS8wbiZDQ" hash="x61tZg">To all He declares:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p27" pid="gnZWKU_QaU-uio1l-eMq1Q" hash="iSy8UA">“I am the resurrection, and the life: he that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p28" pid="owV7FWPnKECy7UnMEY4hog" hash="gQra-w">“And whosoever liveth and believeth in me shall never die.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children.p29" pid="iGEsHPJbUkGG9cU3olr2tw" hash="zfT2ww">He is our Lawgiver and Judge, the Redeemer of the world. At His Second Coming, “the government shall be upon his shoulder; and his name shall be called, Wonderful, Counselor, The Mighty God, The Everlasting Father, The Prince of Peace.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> Of this I bear witness in the most sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2008/10/god-loves-and-helps-all-of-his-children</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2008-general-conference/2008-10-4030-bishop-keith-b-mcmullin-64k-eng.mp3" length="5013913" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Path of Duty</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Duty does not require perfection, but it does require diligence. It is not simply what is legal; it is what is virtuous.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021388_000_007" doc-version="2" hash="mkw3kQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="8v6o6Wl6D0yjuLWnm3AxHg" hash="-AjEvA">Our Path of Duty</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="2XVtijTycEuluDuE_1htjw" hash="bnTkHA">Keith B. McMullin</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="h9qlHxcNPEWs8uljGlbMHQ" hash="Igq9jg">Duty does not require perfection, but it does require diligence. It is not simply what is legal; it is what is virtuous.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p1" pid="2sAcEIFBOUWCrGYXFs0XHw" hash="cRcKvQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="13"></span>This is a troubled world. Discord and disaster are everywhere. It sometimes feels as though mankind itself may be hanging in the balance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p2" pid="jxrSIN4jX0S9c-aL5GKE1A" hash="LDnahQ">Foreshadowing our day, the Lord said, “The heavens shall shake, and also the earth; and great tribulations shall be among the children of men, <span class="emphasis">but my people will I preserve.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> We should take great comfort in this promise.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p3" pid="jZTGR_nbDkyGB9cGZ-Fc2w" hash="ctepCg">Though disasters completely disrupt “the even tenor of [our ways],”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> they do not have to leave our lives forever shattered. They can “stir [us] up in remembrance,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> “awaken [us] to a sense of [our] duty to God,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> and keep us “in the path of [our] duty.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p4" pid="2GxPS3xqq0uH5McAfPWbWA" hash="x8DxDA">In Holland during World War II, the Casper ten Boom family used their home as a hiding place for those hunted by the Nazis. This was their way of living out their Christian faith. Four members of the family lost their lives for providing this refuge. Corrie ten Boom and her sister Betsie spent horrific months in the infamous Ravensbrück concentration camp. Betsie died there—Corrie survived.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p5" pid="xHoCBH-jWUOYfSpkft6UgQ" hash="YDWq9A">In Ravensbrück, Corrie and Betsie learned that God helps us to forgive. Following the war, Corrie was determined to share this message. On one occasion, she had just spoken to a group of people in Germany suffering from the ravages of war. Her message was “God forgives.” It was then that Corrie ten Boom’s faithfulness brought forth its blessing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p6" pid="9aAQeI5Hu0iyU5MRW6lAWQ" hash="W2JztQ">A man approached her. She recognized him as one of the cruelest guards in the camp. “You mentioned Ravensbrück in your talk,” he said. “I was a guard there. … But since that time, … I have become a Christian.” He explained that he had sought God’s forgiveness for the cruel things he had done. He extended his hand and asked, “Will you forgive me?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p7" pid="POAjhcM31EWIP1KAIRqHJQ" hash="ljjESg">Corrie ten Boom then said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p8" pid="ODJp2ti9qU-tjvE-MIYKLg" hash="6ru3wg">“It could not have been many seconds that he stood there—hand held out—but to me it seemed hours as I wrestled with the most difficult thing I had ever had to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p9" pid="Gi-nddGkukydj5ISCjrCHA" hash="J10PKQ">“… The message that God forgives has a … condition: that we forgive those who have injured us. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p10" pid="NIH5gQIc7UCyE4QZ690jzw" hash="1KkdaA">“… ‘Help me!’ I prayed silently. ‘I can lift my hand. I can do that much. You supply the feeling.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p11" pid="XDK7R8QBckKh7Yp_3pzvUA" hash="-7864Q">“… Woodenly, mechanically, I thrust my hand into the one stretched out to me. As I did, an incredible thing took place. The current started in my shoulder, raced down my arm, sprang into our joined hands. And then this healing warmth seemed to flood my whole being, bringing tears to my eyes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p12" pid="PbHy6E-rp0i5teUGXHbpMA" hash="wfqB5A">“‘I forgive you, brother!’ I cried. ‘With all my heart.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p13" pid="tI4YTm4Kf0O5I6uNrKGOJw" hash="M1eKWw">“For a long moment we grasped each other’s hands, the former guard and the former prisoner. I had never known God’s love so intensely, as I did then.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p14" pid="N90RjoesZEeqhCBdvxD0vQ" hash="Ga35YA">For those who eschew evil and live good lives, who strive for a brighter day and keep the commandments of God, things can get better and better even in the face of tragedy. The Savior showed us the way. From Gethsemane, the cross, and the tomb, He rose triumphant, bringing life and hope to us all. He bids us, “Come, follow me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p15" pid="7_A8XMfc8EyrT59SucJMSg" hash="sX7Veg">President Thomas S. Monson has counseled: “If we are to walk with head held high, we must make our contribution to life. If we are to fulfill our destiny and return to live with our Father in Heaven, we must keep His commandments and pattern our lives after the Savior. By so doing, we will not only achieve our goal of eternal life, but we will also leave the world richer and better than it would have been had we not <span class="emphasis">lived and performed our duties.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p16" pid="F7tXCQrCRkW0yDNPQQtcIg" hash="DGbxzw">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="14"></span>In the Holy Bible are these inspired words: “Let us hear the conclusion of the whole matter: Fear God, and keep his commandments: for <span class="emphasis">this is the whole duty of man.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="C7AAOspcKkeqLToUwLTV5Q" hash="2X9pQA">What Is This Thing Called Duty?</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p17" pid="c2pT2YRJl0m3HDTRQnLjQA" hash="HC4qMA">The <span class="emphasis">duty</span> of which I speak is what we are expected to do and to be. It is a moral imperative summoning forth from individuals and communities that which is right, true, and honorable. Duty does not require perfection, but it does require diligence. It is not simply what is legal; it is what is virtuous. It is not reserved to the mighty or high in station but instead rests on a foundation of personal responsibility, integrity, and courage. Doing one’s duty is a manifestation of one’s faith.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p18" pid="i4wrxgWQWUCZ084_5GF2aQ" hash="Wn0EkA">President Monson said of it: “I love and cherish the noble word <span class="emphasis">duty.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> For members of the Church of Jesus Christ, our path of duty is keeping our covenants in daily life.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="_ahqtxakLUuMo_M6OcoMHQ" hash="dTaZdQ">To Whom and to What Are We Duty Bound?</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p19" pid="rwFUx7EBzUG344nKeFxInw" hash="NHhrfQ">First, our path of duty is to God, our Eternal Father. He is the author of the plan of salvation, “the framer of heaven and earth,” the creator of Adam and Eve.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> He is the fountain of truth,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> the embodiment of love,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> and the reason there is redemption through Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p20" pid="UcKmUBTq2Uqig7IwSDa7Lw" hash="c5MQdw">Said President Joseph F. Smith: “All that we have comes from [God]. … In and of ourselves we are but a lifeless lump of clay. Life, intelligence, wisdom, judgment, power to reason, all are the gifts of God to the children of men. He gives us our physical strength as well as our mental powers. … We should honor God with our intelligence, with our strength, with our understanding, with our wisdom, and with all the power that we possess. We should seek to do good in the world. <span class="emphasis">This is our duty.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p21" pid="Wmtt_txad0uncbaNabRCFg" hash="adCWeg">One cannot do his or her duty to God the Father without doing likewise to the Son of God, the Lord Jesus Christ. To revere one requires reverence for the other, for the Father has appointed that it is only in and through the name of Christ that one can completely fulfill this dutiful charge.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> He is our Exemplar, our Redeemer, and our King.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p22" pid="UXSt4anlT0mYtAzE0VuIvg" hash="3yUv4g">As men and women and boys and girls do their duty to God, they feel impelled to do their duty to one another, to their family, to their church and nation, to all things entrusted to their care. They are duty bound to magnify their talents and to be a law-abiding, good people. They become humble, submissive, and easily entreated. Temperance conquers indulgence; obedience guides their diligence. Peace distills upon them. Citizens become loyal, communities become benevolent, and neighbors become friends. The God of heaven is pleased, the earth is pacified, and this world becomes a better place.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="LancIQVIJEWjP2RGFMeo7g" hash="zAWDAg">How Do We Know Our Path of Duty in the Midst of Crisis?</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p23" pid="uDporRbo_Emn7sLWK_xgxA" hash="47nezg">
          <span class="pageBreak" page-number="15"></span>We pray! It is everyone’s sure way to know; it is everyone’s lifeline to heaven. Said the Apostle Peter, “The eyes of the Lord are over the righteous, and his ears are open unto their prayers.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p24" pid="79C9stZNRUmav4yi_F2TkA" hash="rC1xeA">Humble, sincere, inspired prayer makes available to each of us the divine guidance we so desperately need. Brigham Young counseled, “At times, men are perplexed and full of care and trouble … ; yet our judgment teaches us that <span class="emphasis">it is our duty to pray.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p25" pid="vkg2-_wNG0uk_mRfnLlsng" hash="jozTww">Jesus taught:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p26" pid="PcBJ132TnE2wqsssuLT4UQ" hash="pD1AfQ">“Ye must watch and pray always lest ye enter into temptation; …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p27" pid="awsQFfHpZEyfjogPsR7h_g" hash="JQC7Zw">“Therefore ye must always pray unto the Father in my name; …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p28" pid="leSry_hXl0S0e2xgBI9p8Q" hash="iDcGdA">“Pray in your families unto the Father, always in my name, that your wives and your children may be blessed.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p29" pid="4vFX_DzZKEOXPr9e9HLC0A" hash="-QIk2w">For prayers to be efficacious, they must be in harmony with the plan of heaven. The prayer of faith bears fruit when such harmony exists, and this harmony exists when prayers are inspired by the Holy Spirit. The Spirit manifests what our petitions should be.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> Absent this inspired guidance, we are inclined to “ask amiss,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> to seek only our will and not “Thy will.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> It is as important to be guided by the Holy Spirit while praying as it is to be enlightened by that same Spirit while receiving an answer to prayer. Such prayer brings forth the blessings of heaven because our Father “knoweth what things [we] have need of, before [we] ask him,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> and He answers every sincere prayer. Ultimately, it is the Father and the Son who promise, “Ask, and it shall be given you; seek, and ye shall find; knock, and it shall be opened unto you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty.p30" pid="MyICuFf7B0O2VuLq9in2KQ" hash="VtQgnw">I bear my witness that our path of duty is clearly marked by an undivided faith and belief in God, the Eternal Father, and in His Son, Jesus Christ, and in the power of prayer. This path is to be traveled by all of God’s children who love Him and desire to keep His commandments. For the young, it leads to personal achievement and preparation; for adults, it leads to renewed faith and resolve; for the older generation, it leads to perspective and endurance in righteousness to the end. It equips every faithful traveler with the strength of the Lord, protects him from the evils of the day, and endows him with the knowledge that “the conclusion of the whole matter [is to] Fear God, and keep his commandments: for <span class="emphasis">this is the whole duty of man.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26">26</span> In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/04/our-path-of-duty</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2010-general-conference/2010-04-1040-bishop-keith-b-mcmullin-64k-eng.mp3" length="5347461" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2010 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of the Aaronic Priesthood</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood?lang=eng</link>
      <description>You and the Aaronic Priesthood office you hold are essential to Heavenly Father’s work with His children and the preparation of this earth for the Second Coming.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50029123_000_3020" doc-version="2" hash="nSB_Ug"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="ctCC7Af9jUyXLftO1TBlkA" hash="T6VjqQ">The Power of the Aaronic Priesthood</h1><p class="authorName" guid="36264044-f9a1-4914-be89-bf7832872366" pid="asdvbKivrka-2QmZ09Pt5Q" hash="bnTkHA">Keith B. McMullin</p><p class="kicker" pid="Xt_--XEogkq_96jhOD_8Zg" hash="NF84ng">You and the Aaronic Priesthood office you hold are essential to Heavenly Father’s work with His children and the preparation of this earth for the Second Coming.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="2b86fde8-55d2-4562-8fef-2bcd25bc46e6">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p1" guid="836e6d76-7652-4cab-9308-ddf205b775b0" pid="zmLd8L27nUa2ZrrLqBMhFg" hash="Cu9HHw">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="47"></span>In a recent training session for General Authorities, President Thomas S. Monson emphasized anew the duties and opportunities for Aaronic Priesthood bearers.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> It is in the spirit of that instruction that I address you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p2" guid="9ab416cc-2fdd-4cde-94a8-a8d81e74e852" pid="uqu28WwmgEWlVDQYhxDN6Q" hash="FY6Kcg">Duty, properly carried out, determines the destiny of peoples and nations. So fundamental is the principle of duty that priesthood bearers are admonished, “Wherefore, now let every man learn his duty, and to act in the office in which he is appointed, in all diligence.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p3" guid="ac8f131f-0114-4e1e-a8f2-4ee3223c08d1" pid="qeHEY3i_Dki6nvHQtKGgmA" hash="kPsAtQ">President Monson explains, “The call of duty can come quietly as we who hold the priesthood respond to the assignments we receive.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> President Monson quoted George Albert Smith: “It is your duty first of all to learn what the Lord wants and then by the power and strength of His holy Priesthood to magnify your calling in the presence of your fellows in such a way that the people will be glad to follow you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p4" guid="ea79316b-316c-4a49-83bf-dbdfafee00d0" pid="Z2N-QN_WmkOdgnturQ1buQ" hash="6qzvdg">Speaking of His duty, our Lord said: “I seek not mine own will, but the will of the Father.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> “I came down from heaven, not to do mine own will, but the will of him that sent me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> Because Jesus Christ performed His duty, “all mankind may be saved, by obedience to the laws and ordinances of the Gospel.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> Brethren, this is the standard we are to follow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p5" guid="da5081cc-6951-47fb-b4a3-ab32cca8b663" pid="OyD3LwMG40ajCy8XooaIOQ" hash="uJK99w">It has been my experience that you who serve as deacons, teachers, and priests are as willing, reliable, and capable in doing your duty as we expect you to be. We admire you. Your vitality is infectious, your abilities astounding, your association invigorating. You and the Aaronic Priesthood office you hold are essential to Heavenly Father’s work with His children and the preparation of this earth for the Second Coming of His holy Son. Our vision of you and your duty looks beyond your age. Paul spoke of you, saying, “Let no man despise thy youth; but be thou an example of the believers, in word, in conversation, in charity, in spirit, in faith, in purity.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.f1" guid="a9c27bde-1860-44a4-95ae-9108fbf868d8">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="zNfWNXGcNEKTzm2HOSrYZA" hash="KWJ1sA">
            <span class="emphasis">To men of old there came in time</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="tBU7DoDIF0KUAc47vqKvwA" hash="8TzWVA">
            <span class="emphasis">The priesthood named for Aaron.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="X5eqk2szvkC5JGqeOLHOOg" hash="HgzUFA">
            <span class="emphasis">Through Levites, priests, and prophets too,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="0Uxs3Q4yZUa0wTNeXaCAWQ" hash="R6b8yQ">
            <span class="emphasis">It served to bless God’s children.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="kBRLdzvw5Uuce7Q65WhVcw" hash="4BiC0A">
            <span class="emphasis">
  <span class="pageBreak" page-number="48"></span>Then came the Savior of the world</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="haDwFKbyq0K_VmDmX1dXyQ" hash="sUbTlw">
            <span class="emphasis">And sought out one named John,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="_Wf1l2SP3k6aSnM6JtVn4A" hash="KIiZjA">
            <span class="emphasis">To be baptized by this same power</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="8-gJrEvVLE2NVqZC6456wA" hash="EHKaEw">
            <span class="emphasis">And mark salvation’s dawn.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="TFKSax0M20quYHtnqHohRQ" hash="ESr6FA">
            <span class="emphasis">In latter days this selfsame power</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="9INrPH78xkuMov19Q8kgJg" hash="mF5X5g">
            <span class="emphasis">Was again restored to earth,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="g4WLHA8WAkuCrBqX0Hx8tg" hash="vTFtGw">
            <span class="emphasis">That gospel truths from first to last</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="0aFPgha42k-4kDDBSdUfuQ" hash="4_epkw">
            <span class="emphasis">Might in one’s soul find birth.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="Z0ZUrnCO8ky5p-6AI2jRBw" hash="9ZU7zw">
            <span class="emphasis">Aaronic Priesthood, truth sublime,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="mpW4QWCV0kK_vFk54gq1_A" hash="8V0tXw">
            <span class="emphasis">In preparation come—</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="iRCGE6lPFUCsWD9xc859Jg" hash="bUdY2g">
            <span class="emphasis">That redemption might be had</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="rG0vuMK-90q_jQXRALnFpA" hash="QbhEIg">
            <span class="emphasis">Through God’s Beloved Son!</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="Fc8HK-11E0epEI_6ARNUVA" hash="PBICcw">
            <span class="emphasis">And he who ministers these powers—</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="jY3w2FiKTE2NLhWjJWA12w" hash="Y1Rr2Q">
            <span class="emphasis">’Tis not a mere boy that can.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="WAyy7SPaakmmDnJytazMBw" hash="go8NRw">
            <span class="emphasis">With priesthood mantle on him fixed</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="HtmOIFIHcESSXjTW9iIq-A" hash="f3hY8g">
            <span class="emphasis">We say, “Behold the man!”</span>
            <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p6" guid="851951ea-b658-4f0f-bd21-b55e150c5815" pid="HKLp6CNMfUCNy4V4YJDUvA" hash="ssvrMg">“The power and authority of the … Aaronic Priesthood, is to hold the keys of the ministering of angels, and to administer in outward ordinances, the letter of the gospel, the baptism of repentance for the remission of sins, agreeable to the covenants and commandments.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> President Boyd K. Packer has observed: “We have done very well at distributing the <span class="emphasis">authority</span> of the priesthood. We have priesthood authority planted nearly everywhere. … But distributing the <span class="emphasis">authority</span> of the priesthood has raced, I think, ahead of distributing the <span class="emphasis">power</span> of the priesthood.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> For the everlasting welfare of God’s children, this must be remedied.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p7" guid="a3e27732-83fc-4023-ba2b-ac3085281675" pid="y66HfwtyREGmJ84ynaWh-Q" hash="Y_Y0xQ">Our prophet has told us how this can be done. Quoting George Q. Cannon, President Monson said: “I want to see the power of the Priesthood strengthened. … I want to see this strength and power diffused through the entire body of the Priesthood, reaching from the head down to the least and most humble deacon in the Church. Every man should seek for and enjoy the revelations of God, the light of heaven shining in his soul and giving unto him knowledge concerning his duties, concerning that portion of the work … that devolves upon him in his Priesthood.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p8" guid="aecb091a-1b2d-4dc4-8674-cf7d41cd4fbc" pid="GPq2RyNXdkejCDshFuBYcA" hash="yljijQ">What can a deacon, teacher, or priest do to receive the spirit of revelation and magnify his calling? He can live so as to enjoy the cleansing, sanctifying, and illuminating power of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p9" guid="4ecd5a51-fe6b-4963-a340-ee82ca7e0572" pid="6arBQzmjcUSatfL_m3aTYA" hash="vixFLQ">The importance of this is found in these words from Alma: “Now I say unto you that this is the order after which I am called, … to preach unto … the rising generation … that they must repent and be <span class="emphasis">born again.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> When one is born again, his heart is changed. He has no appetite for things evil or unclean. He feels a deep and abiding love for God. He wants to be good, to serve others, and to keep the commandments.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p10" guid="6da51977-2231-4937-bf66-09ced62cb146" pid="zGTrj2B980mdlHTg6wukGg" hash="kXyVLA">President Joseph F. Smith described his experience with this mighty change: “The feeling that came upon me was that of pure peace, of love and of light. I felt in my soul that if I had sinned … it had been forgiven me; that I was indeed cleansed from sin; my heart was touched and I felt that I would not injure the smallest insect beneath my feet. I felt as though I wanted to do good everywhere to everybody and to everything. I felt a newness of life, a newness of desire to do that which was right. There was not one particle of desire for evil left in my soul. I was but a little boy, it is true, … but this was the influence that came upon me, and I know that it was from God, and was and ever has been a living witness to me of my acceptance of the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p11" guid="ed2f2347-5924-459b-956f-701f7c8dac45" pid="WfH3Xcc_zUS_WL9xrGT5GA" hash="Fqcxuw">So we call upon you wonderful young brethren to diligently strive <span class="pageBreak" page-number="49"></span>to be “born again.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> Pray for this mighty change in your life. Study the scriptures. Desire more than all else to know God and to become like His holy Son. Enjoy your youth but “put away childish things”:<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p12" guid="be8f6ff9-5abe-4f25-a6b1-3d4a95385783" pid="giBCV7IHV0Suf1V5-YEe9A" hash="5rU5Ng">Shun profane and foolish chatter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p13" guid="ba807255-c10d-4e08-9d86-38799e819207" pid="c3ECyorwT06nyTs6bzkK2Q" hash="oOL1NA">Flee all evil.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p14" guid="fa8a5d8a-9269-40f6-bd5c-e77b6e3184dc" pid="If-K3EpaMkOGiCstmAaUMQ" hash="JhBDfA">Avoid contention.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p15" guid="e6a539ba-9f48-4a05-8d07-18e3c4ad7aee" pid="3uTTMQkZ10afIspWE9uyMA" hash="8mZaCg">Repent where needed.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p16" guid="88fbcf84-3a8d-4f33-9e30-73cb27f35a0e" pid="w0p9hY548kWmL69HXILywQ" hash="TjSTqw">This will help you rise to the noble stature of your manhood. The qualities of courage, trustworthiness, humility, faith, and goodness will be yours. Friends will admire you, parents will praise you, brethren in the priesthood will depend on you, and the young women will adore you and become even better because of you. God will honor you and endow your priesthood service with <span class="emphasis">power from on high.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p17" guid="0c36e82a-73ff-4d9d-9c30-f7ae94ca47f8" pid="XqJI6vY-rkmLW3GloN4duQ" hash="J-j4vA">The rest of us will do our part. As parents and grandparents, we will prepare you for more valiant service in the kingdom of God. As your brethren, we will be examples for you to emulate. We will increase the strength of your quorums. We will sustain your quorum presidencies as they exercise their presiding keys. We will provide you opportunity to fully shoulder the duties of the Aaronic Priesthood and to magnify your calling therein.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p18" guid="9a3382a2-e153-49ea-abcb-dc0756d5891b" pid="D4SvXLhQ6U2zrCfFTyxiJw" hash="6knatg">Through your ministry, great blessings will come to the Church. “Angels speak by the power of the Holy Ghost.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> You can do so as well. As you speak by the power of the Holy Ghost and administer the sacred emblems of the sacrament, men and women, boys and girls will strive to repent, to increase their faith in Christ, and to have the Holy Spirit with them always.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p19" guid="431d0665-da1a-45ca-adf5-966694d414d6" pid="g2uHbaUX3UaAKTKhnDmypg" hash="RHVp1Q">As you fast and collect fast offerings, members will be moved to pattern their works after the Savior. The Lord cared for the poor and the downtrodden, and He beckoned, “Come, follow me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> Your service in caring for the less fortunate engages us in His holy work and helps us to retain the forgiveness for our own past sins.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p20" guid="3b987c4b-7ac9-4788-b5fe-b3d22573a893" pid="4fc0JGQFgUu0SaM3WfNFng" hash="wuChaA">As you “visit the house of each member,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> be not fearful or bashful. The Holy Ghost will supply you in the very moment the words to say, the testimony to bear, the service to render.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p21" guid="b8b55420-4047-4235-a2c5-9bb29dc4622d" pid="7k8jKjps1EGBl6l_mhuC2w" hash="CgKxIA">Your diligent efforts to “watch over the church always”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> will be fruitful. Your unpretentious manner will disarm the most unbelieving heart and loosen the adversary’s grip. Your invitation for others to come to church with you, to partake of the sacrament with you, and to serve with you will become a welcoming balm for those lost in the shadows where the gospel light is but a dim ember or glows not at all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p22" guid="8c7440dd-523b-4600-999f-b26e79848897" pid="NEjyaMzYjk6NnQC_IloHNQ" hash="aXmdtQ">Oh, my beloved young brethren, “neglect not the gift that is in thee,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> which you received when the Aaronic Priesthood was conferred and you were ordained.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p23" guid="eae202ae-34da-4cee-959f-363377d4d46b" pid="49LJRElpMEKu3ZPIXo0nCA" hash="ZjjVIA">“God hath not given us the spirit of fear; but of power, and of love, and of a sound mind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p24" guid="fb501b5b-9a11-4e48-a9e1-4a26917883a3" pid="OHeOemn840CrcO8HY_Ng1A" hash="pGQG9w">“Be not thou therefore ashamed of the testimony of our Lord. … Be thou partaker of the … gospel according to the power of God;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p25" guid="63ad7698-8b16-4c92-be17-63c19b25acb9" pid="NT7JB8rbBkWuXvcFRlXRcA" hash="cohRxQ">“Who hath … called us with an holy calling, … which was given us in Christ Jesus before the world began.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p26" guid="f5e537a9-1060-4fc4-ac3b-035f3d5c8ed8" pid="2xKTLR3iL0CEzwlNad2ztw" hash="DcHYBg">Our beloved prophet has “called you to the colors.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26">26</span> We salute you, pray for you, rejoice in serving with you, and give thanks to God for the power of your saving ministry.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p27" guid="c3f4c5af-44c4-4a68-84ed-ef9b0004f22e" pid="UBtons1md020g3v-o_Btvg" hash="s2UQWg">I bear witness, God is our Eternal Father and dwells in yonder heavens. Jesus the Christ is God’s holy Son, the Redeemer of the world, and you faithful bearers of the Aaronic Priesthood are His emissaries on the earth, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/10/the-power-of-the-aaronic-priesthood</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2011-general-conference/2011-10-3020-bishop-keith-b-mcmullin-64k-eng.mp3" length="5513480" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
