<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Kent F. Richards</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Kent F. Richards.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Kent%20F.%20Richards.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Kent F. Richards.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Atonement Covers All Pain</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Our great personal challenge in mortality is to become “a saint through the atonement of Christ.”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50028768_000_1050" doc-version="2" hash="Ahu5IA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.head1">
    <h1 class="title" pid="sVvLkwC2fUevDds9M5YsDA" hash="YBrGsw">The Atonement Covers All Pain</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="uASWBthkskqF0AzRtqDAGw" hash="r-wNrA">Kent F. Richards</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="9gVVvNZYREWfemE-PGYWiA" hash="mEUC6A">Our great personal challenge in mortality is to become “a saint through the atonement of Christ.”</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p1" pid="Y1Om_OSJKUuotEa37qpxXQ" hash="w5U9OQ">As a surgeon, I found that a significant portion of my professional time was taken up with the subject of pain. Of necessity I surgically inflicted it almost daily—and much of my effort was then spent trying to control and alleviate pain.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p2" pid="pV56BdmXuUWXeEOI5-AnKg" hash="Qwne8g">I have pondered about the purpose of pain. None of us is immune from experiencing pain. I have seen people cope with it very differently. Some turn away from God in anger, and others allow their suffering to bring them closer to God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p3" pid="P_osKo-UBke5DGWYdrh1QQ" hash="19WK6A">Like you, I have experienced pain myself. Pain is a gauge of the healing process. It often teaches us patience. Perhaps that is why we use the term <span class="emphasis">patient</span> in referring to the sick.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p4" pid="hs1mSq-7CUmI01bqN7F1Ag" hash="0fxIwA">Elder Orson F. Whitney wrote: “No pain that we suffer, no trial that we experience is wasted. It ministers to our education, to the development of such qualities as patience, faith, fortitude, and humility. … It is through sorrow and suffering, toil and tribulation, that we gain the education that we come here to acquire.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p5" pid="KQ_TeTPcMkC-I02S7NNBGw" hash="-Zcsag">Similarly, Elder Robert D. Hales has said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p6" pid="8YEsYjk3q0eDRVCHqxaMyQ" hash="qnAelQ">“Pain brings you to a humility that allows you to ponder. It is an experience I am grateful to have endured. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p7" pid="BJstR8TZZU6b6N8iIA14vw" hash="GINgVQ">“I learned that the physical pain and the healing of the body after major surgery are remarkably similar to the spiritual pain and the healing of the soul in the process of repentance.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p8" pid="dqn814iG6Ei_kj_dMaJW_A" hash="sLVoDg">Much of our suffering is not necessarily our fault. Unexpected events, contradicting or disappointing circumstances, interrupting illness, and even death surround us and penetrate our mortal experience. Additionally, we may suffer afflictions because of the actions of others.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Lehi noted that Jacob had “suffered … much sorrow, because of the rudeness of [his] brethren.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Opposition is part of Heavenly Father’s plan of happiness. We all encounter enough to bring us to an awareness of our Father’s love and of our need for the Savior’s help.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p9" pid="r1bu6z8x_k-0Zicx_T59nA" hash="O9xAhw">The Savior is not a silent observer. He Himself knows personally and infinitely the pain we face.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p10" pid="Q-XlJIAaP0epKKipjtTeow" hash="pZ-8Wg">“He suffereth the pains of all men, yea, the pains of every living creature, both men, women, and children.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p11" pid="RTSay-O8cEKzKmKKPGMjZQ" hash="y7ymvg">“Let us therefore come boldly unto the throne of grace, that we may obtain mercy, and find grace to help in time of need.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p12" pid="mXV3Mn5DXUGxO2fYMW8ERg" hash="nZMbxQ">Sometimes in the depth of pain, we are tempted to ask, “Is there no balm in Gilead; is there no physician there?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> I testify the answer is yes, there is a physician. The Atonement of Jesus Christ covers all these conditions and purposes of mortality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p13" pid="ma2dFBItZUiZWGD2Ki7L7Q" hash="25tjSg">There is another kind of pain for which we <span class="emphasis">are</span> responsible. Spiritual pain lies deep within our souls and can feel unquenchable, even as being racked with an“inexpressible horror,” as Alma described.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> It comes from our sinful actions and lack of repentance. For this pain too there is a cure that is universal and absolute. It is from the Father, through the Son, and it is for each of us who is willing to do all that is necessary to repent. Christ said, “Will ye not now return unto me … and be converted, that I may heal you?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p14" pid="F5AM9KShi0iRosDTuJbuLQ" hash="MKDZ6A">Christ Himself taught:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p15" pid="kQc7KaJfXkqqsOorMxDMvg" hash="oDKAxw">“And my Father sent me that I might be lifted up upon the cross; and <span class="emphasis">after</span> that I had been lifted up upon the cross, that I might draw all men unto me. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p16" pid="URifjsg990WogvLLX27lDQ" hash="n5f7Bw">“Therefore, according to the <span class="emphasis">power</span> of the Father I will draw all men unto me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p17" pid="4aatWylVxEKLHjE2P5rDwQ" hash="XVu_Xg">Perhaps His most significant work is in the ongoing labor with each of us individually to lift, to bless, to strengthen, to sustain, to guide, and to forgive us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p18" pid="kou0bxYgnkSyvja5RqDKbQ" hash="5xMYUw">As Nephi saw in vision, much of Christ’s mortal ministry was devoted to blessing and healing the sick with all kinds of maladies—physical, emotional, and spiritual. “And I beheld multitudes of people who were sick, and who were afflicted with all manner of diseases. … And they were healed by the power of the Lamb of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p19" pid="RTzxQ3CDPEiVYHIvBtoyGQ" hash="j0xVoQ">Alma also prophesied that “he shall go forth, suffering pains and afflictions and temptations of every kind; and … he will take upon him the pains and the sicknesses of his people. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p20" pid="1kA5QOkcE0GrY0wTYnoGMQ" hash="mQvTsQ">“That <span class="emphasis">his</span> bowels may be filled with mercy, … that <span class="emphasis">he </span>may know according to the flesh how to succor his people according to their infirmities.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p21" pid="yMNQGSRqfUi-qZSz-cQMXw" hash="sT8yJA">Late one night lying in a hospital bed, this time as a patient and not as a physician, I read those verses over and over again. I pondered: “How is it done? For whom? What is required to qualify? Is it like forgiveness of sin? Do we have to earn His love and help?” As I pondered, I came to understand that during His mortal life Christ <span class="emphasis">chose</span> to experience pains and afflictions in order to understand us. Perhaps we also need to experience the depths of mortality in order to understand Him and our eternal purposes.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p22" pid="UzFFNvo4c0GLT_RZx3oGgg" hash="8i-BwQ">President Henry B. Eyring taught: “It will comfort us when we must wait in distress for the Savior’s promised relief that He knows, from experience, how to heal and help us. … And faith in that power will give us patience as we pray and work and wait for help. He could have known how to succor us simply by revelation, but He <span class="emphasis">chose to learn by His own personal experience.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p23" pid="OVKeH0HRS0iSwN4GkbZ1mQ" hash="rsbZsw">I felt the encircling arms of His love that night.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> Tears watered my pillow in gratitude. Later, as I was reading in Matthew about Christ’s mortal ministry, I made another discovery: “When the even was come, they brought unto him many … and he … healed <span class="emphasis">all </span>that were sick.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> He healed <span class="emphasis">all</span> that came to Him. None were turned away.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p24" pid="bpJ2PqdepkGMwmVlCcbDjg" hash="eJJVsg">As Elder Dallin H. Oaks has taught: “Healing blessings come in many ways, each suited to our individual needs, as known to Him who loves us best. Sometimes a ‘healing’ cures our illness or lifts our burden. But sometimes we are ‘healed’ by being given strength or understanding or patience to bear the burdens placed upon us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> All that will come may be “clasped in the arms of Jesus.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> All souls can be healed by His power. All pain can be soothed. In Him, we can “find rest unto [our] souls.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> Our mortal circumstances may not immediately change, but our pain, worry, suffering, and fear can be swallowed up in His peace and healing balm.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p25" pid="ynWkyHKv4kiyMcGuV-GDlA" hash="hWpzcA">I have noted that children are often more naturally accepting of pain and suffering. They quietly endure with humility and meekness. I have felt a beautiful, sweet spirit surrounding these little ones.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p26" pid="QAqFU11NA0qJzbypcBui4Q" hash="aNIUzw">Thirteen-year-old Sherrie underwent a 14-hour operation for a tumor on her spinal cord. As she regained consciousness in the intensive care unit, she said: “Daddy, Aunt Cheryl is here, … and … Grandpa Norman … and Grandma Brown … are here. And Daddy, who is that standing beside you? … He looks like you, only taller. … He says he’s your brother, Jimmy.” Her uncle Jimmy had died at age 13 of cystic fibrosis.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p27" pid="XlmRRY2DyUaQvJeLHK0jCQ" hash="ptJ-Qw">“For nearly an hour, Sherrie … described her visitors, all deceased family members. Exhausted, she then fell asleep.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p28" pid="uHALY0VVG0Kpsi6R-6wdvw" hash="kqzP0Q">Later she told her father, “Daddy, all of the children here in the intensive care unit have angels helping them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p29" pid="LcCGkNYVq0CEbucUzHFjcQ" hash="8JSDLw">To all of us the Savior said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p30" pid="t2p7ncigIUaweSUOFIlfrA" hash="BJ8Cjw">“Behold, ye are little children and ye cannot bear all things now; ye must grow in grace and in the knowledge of the truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p31" pid="BjNb0emp_02_P3xcwA5OEg" hash="qgcDXA">“Fear not, little children, for you are mine. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p32" pid="EnLw3lliy0iHncXX1kxDxQ" hash="NcK4IA">“Wherefore, I am in your midst, and I am the good shepherd.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p33" pid="DBzpG38Kp0GGsQ4pMSTn-g" hash="F22SGA">Our great personal challenge in mortality is to become “a saint through the atonement of Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> The pain you and I experience may be where this process is most measured. In extremity, we can become as children in our hearts, humble ourselves, and “pray and work and wait”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> patiently for the healing of our bodies and our souls. As Job, after being refined through our trials, we “shall come forth as gold.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain.p34" pid="1CK3Dp36k0eEbFjblrqqOg" hash="QJQr2A">I bear testimony that He is our Redeemer, our Friend, our Advocate, the Great Physician, the Great Healer. In Him we can find peace and solace in and from our pain and our sins if we will but come unto Him with humble hearts. His “grace is sufficient.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span> In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/04/the-atonement-covers-all-pain</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2011-general-conference/2011-04-1050-elder-kent-f-richards-64k-eng.mp3" length="4892922" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Godliness</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13285_000_65richards" doc-version="2" hash="RojcUA"&gt;
	
	&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.head1"&gt;
		&lt;h1 class="title" pid="AFEjffpi9EOKJenh3iaQfQ" hash="o-shhg"&gt;The Power of Godliness&lt;/h1&gt;
		&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p2" pid="R0QdTK-aXU6-acEExyhLkA" hash="1lzpnQ1"&gt;By Elder Kent F. Richards&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p3" pid="8wsc4Mc3MU6oCq96KySlHw" hash="sSmk3g"&gt;Of the Seventy&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=4zsXRqwiEUa2QpNncxCEMw"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" altText="Elder Kent F. Richards" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255573/7c17e869bf8b4ca087566d809292efb1/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255573/7c17e869bf8b4ca087566d809292efb1/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255573/7c17e869bf8b4ca087566d809292efb1/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x279="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255573/7c17e869bf8b4ca087566d809292efb1/200x279.jpg" data-src-320x447="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255573/7c17e869bf8b4ca087566d809292efb1/320x447.jpg" data-src-460x643="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255573/7c17e869bf8b4ca087566d809292efb1/460x643.jpg" data-src-640x894="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255573/7c17e869bf8b4ca087566d809292efb1/640x894.jpg" data-src-1024x1431="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255573/7c17e869bf8b4ca087566d809292efb1/1024x1431.jpg" data-src-2048x2863="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255573/7c17e869bf8b4ca087566d809292efb1/2048x2863.jpg" data-src-4041x5650="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255573/7c17e869bf8b4ca087566d809292efb1/4041x5650.jpg" webURL="kent-richards-second-quorum-seventy_1255573.jpg" pid="4zsXRqwiEUa2QpNncxCEMw" hash="AAAAAA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="kicker" pid="0zhtsrFZSU-okxBTo6ijNw" hash="O5-bgQ"&gt;Each temple is God’s holy, sacred house, and therein each of us may learn and know the powers of godliness.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="authorName" pid="b43KGLjuqEmaXxUMq_euyg" hash="1lzpnQ"&gt;By Elder Kent F. Richards&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class="bodyBlock"&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p5" pid="GsuPAWAXPUOiIT3ohuWzpg" hash="q7lDwA"&gt;Just a few months before the death of the Prophet Joseph Smith, he met with the Twelve Apostles to talk about the greatest needs the Church was facing in that very difficult time. He told them, &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;“We need the temple more than anything else.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; Surely, today in these trying times, each of us and our families need the temple more than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p6" pid="Sb58qrXas0Khv-_d69AMOg" hash="4uNsSQ"&gt;During a recent temple dedication, I was thrilled with the entire experience. I loved the open house, greeting many of the visitors who came to see the temple; the cultural celebration with the vibrancy and excitement of the youth; followed by the wonderful dedicatory sessions. The Spirit was sweet. Many people were blessed. And then the next morning, my wife and I entered the baptismal font to participate in baptisms for some of our own ancestors. As I raised my arm to begin the ordinance, I was nearly overcome by the power of the Spirit. I realized again that the real power of the temple is in the ordinances.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p7" pid="vyOU_pMA6E68JOVOcrQVVQ" hash="diuWYA"&gt;As the Lord has revealed, the fulness of the Melchizedek Priesthood is found in the temple and its ordinances, “for therein are the keys of the holy priesthood ordained, that you may receive honor and glory.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; “Therefore, in the ordinances thereof, the power of godliness is manifest.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; This promise is for you and for your family.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p8" pid="_4i_NbKBUUqeJ1qklP4dzQ" hash="h3j1XQ"&gt;Our responsibility is to “receive” that which our Father offers.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; “For unto him that receiveth it shall be given more abundantly, even power”:&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; power to receive &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;all&lt;/span&gt; that He can and will give us—now and eternally;&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; power to become sons and daughters of God,&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt; to know “the powers of heaven,”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8"&gt;8&lt;/span&gt; to speak in His name,&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9"&gt;9&lt;/span&gt; and to receive “the power of [His] Spirit.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt; These powers become available personally to each one of us through the ordinances and the covenants of the temple.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p9" pid="GSCYQ7C0K0WqIEGmE6BOBg" hash="JImaOg"&gt;Nephi saw our day in his great vision: “I, Nephi, beheld the &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;power&lt;/span&gt; of the Lamb of God, that it descended upon the saints of the church of the Lamb, and upon the &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;covenant people&lt;/span&gt; of the Lord, who were scattered upon all the face of the earth; and they were &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;armed with righteousness and with the power of God in great glory.&lt;/span&gt;”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11"&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p10" pid="VrYLLdo6pkms8jTf5f22XQ" hash="4hkjOw"&gt;I had the privilege recently of being in a temple open house with President Russell M. Nelson and his family as he gathered them around the sealing altar and explained to them that everything we do in the Church—every meeting, activity, lesson, and service—is to prepare each of us to come to the temple and kneel at the altar to receive all the Father’s promised blessings for eternity.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12"&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p11" pid="UZaDXlN9h0S6hoPHUIRCYg" hash="MJ8ueA"&gt;As we feel the blessings of the temple in our own lives, our hearts turn to our families, both living and dead.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p12" pid="Trkt2Yp6cUOkLJPo8WbYpQ" hash="dL6wXQ"&gt;Recently, I witnessed a three-generation family participate in baptisms together for their ancestors. Even the grandmother participated—though she had some trepidation about going under the water herself. As she emerged from the water and hugged her husband, she had tears of joy. The grandfather and father then baptized each other and many of the grandchildren. What greater joy could a family experience together? Each temple has a family priority time to allow you as a family to schedule time in the baptistry.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p13" pid="h9aQlZGugEuSErbjDpU5rA" hash="fGTaLQ"&gt;Shortly before his death, President Joseph F. Smith received the vision of the redemption of the dead. He taught that those who are in the spirit world are fully dependent upon the ordinances that we receive on their behalf. The scripture reads, “The dead who repent will be redeemed, through obedience to the ordinances of the house of God.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt; We receive the ordinances in their behalf, but they make and are held accountable for each covenant associated with each ordinance. Surely, the veil is thin for us and parts completely for them in the temple.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p14" pid="J3CUj1YrKUGLOvDI3Ycyeg" hash="Jh2qug"&gt;What then is our personal responsibility to be engaged in this work, both as patrons and as workers? The Prophet Joseph Smith taught the Saints in 1840 that “considerable exertion must be made, and means will be required—and as the work [to build the temple] must be hastened in righteousness, it behooves the Saints to weigh the importance of these things, in their minds, … and then take such steps as are necessary to carry them into operation; and arming themselves with courage, resolve to do all they can, and feel themselves as much interested as though the whole labor depended on themselves alone.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14"&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p15" pid="G4RtXUi4wUWNq3pd_J8YAw" hash="5P7_LA"&gt;In the book of Revelation we read:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p16" pid="myTCGCMOhkG_zfaA5O6P1w" hash="5w8KlQ"&gt;“What are these which are arrayed in white robes? and whence came they?&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p17" pid="U4RRO_ejj0GFVAajEp7OYA" hash="nn2PcA"&gt;“… These are they which came out of great tribulation, and have washed their robes, and made them white in the blood of the Lamb.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p18" pid="bDJQVCcKjUeg9CtVU1BbBg" hash="iJ2u4Q"&gt;“Therefore are they before the throne of God, and serve him day and night in his temple: and he that sitteth on the throne shall dwell among them.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15"&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p19" pid="o5BAEXN5gkWnI7OYT6P0vw" hash="_Uh9sQ"&gt;Can’t you just see in your mind’s eye those who serve in the temple today?&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p20" pid="pN27qaEk5U2I8oZHQh-KHQ" hash="bvmUGg"&gt;There are more than 120,000 ordinance workers in the 150 operating temples around the world. Yet there is opportunity for even more to have this sweet experience. When President Gordon B. Hinckley announced the concept of many smaller temples throughout the world, he taught that “all ordinance workers would be local people who would serve in other capacities in their wards and stakes.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16"&gt;16&lt;/span&gt; Normally, workers are called to serve for two to three years, with the possibility of extending beyond. It is not intended that once you are called, you will stay as long as you are able. Many long-serving workers carry their love for the temple with them as they are released and allow other, new workers to serve.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p21" pid="hmlEnXdJbEWiFGZ6b5BlTQ" hash="9u97zQ"&gt;Nearly 100 years ago, Apostle John A. Widtsoe taught: “We need more workers to accomplish [this] wonderful work. … We need more converts to temple work, drawn from all ages. … The time has come, … in this new temple movement, to bring into active service all the people, of all ages. … Temple work is … of as much benefit to the young and the active, as it is to the aged, who have laid behind them many of the burdens of life. The young man needs his place in the temple even more than his father and his grandfather, who are steadied by a life of experience; and the young girl just entering life, needs the spirit, influence and direction that come from participation in the temple ordinances.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17"&gt;17&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p22" pid="SLeM9y6js0Klw7sGT8gbNg" hash="adxIRw"&gt;In many temples, temple presidents are welcoming newly called and endowed missionaries, young men and women, to serve for just a short time as ordinance workers before going to the MTC. These young people are not only blessed to serve, but “they enhance the beauty and spirit for all serving in the temple.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18"&gt;18&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p23" pid="9rgn9SOXiEe6Ams4NcTbyg" hash="4UT5OA"&gt;I asked a number of young men and women who have served as ordinance workers before and after their missions to share their feelings. They used phrases like the following to describe their experience in the temple:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p24" pid="GdYhoJXVT06cj_YEND98-A" hash="oUB6Ng"&gt;When I serve in the temple—&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;ul class="bullet"&gt;
			&lt;li pid="0uWPWLUJakKNGW7XNdafmg" hash="s0MeQA"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p25" pid="CQntnANOj0y0jVZBmq94DA" hash="Rg9Uxg"&gt;I feel “a sense of being closer to my Father and the Savior”;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="9E0oiHpvzkWF3kcX9OjQIA" hash="j5P2-g"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p26" pid="aop9R4zdP02MRTKbov9foA" hash="jmpnPg"&gt;I feel “complete peace and happiness”;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="Y4Xv2eR7jk6jvZwDS2tNsA" hash="RnQ1ng"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p27" pid="94yngnWjXEOQxQxsZsTTow" hash="7bBkcQ"&gt;I have a feeling of “being home”;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="5G-fmwcsZUid5f7fe9D3tQ" hash="5xsB9Q"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p28" pid="_1hs9WkWtEm4u4PTDUaHaQ" hash="Fb7vbw"&gt;I receive “sacredness, power, and strength”;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="syEVvoOu8kmgN81KETuX9w" hash="tjIkGw"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p29" pid="LcPyLmwrHEaQ0h6mKfwXSA" hash="Eka8Ew"&gt;I feel “the importance of my sacred covenants”;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="Bc3bH3WfBE6MTgbkjlea7w" hash="zerBOA"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p30" pid="WRuN6Z3xBECJlpTXIRUv0Q" hash="vY483w"&gt;“The temple has become a part of me”;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="7nsiP_GTrEK13WG9sY7sxA" hash="YQLc5w"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p31" pid="e4Zhns8ZcUeo8OAdNBpuDQ" hash="bMxRFg"&gt;“Those whom we serve are close during the ordinances”;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="iz8aL2b-BU20ZL8_QV_WPw" hash="NMYWmA"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p32" pid="gLRfz_8K70qnK_H6CPUz6A" hash="bDEQrA"&gt;“It gives me the strength to overcome temptations”; and&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li pid="UbBjfPWVqUeXFgI0mefflA" hash="h_I8jA"&gt;
				&lt;span class="label"&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p33" pid="rBCqV37zCU6oK4Re0DEx2g" hash="aZCRRQ"&gt;“The temple has changed my life forever.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19"&gt;19&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p34" pid="tUs9rBEsJEChwkCz-Mvhog" hash="EMArBA"&gt;Serving in the temple is a rich and powerful experience for people of all ages. Even some newly married couples are serving together. President Nelson has taught, “Service in the temple … is a sublime activity for a family.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20"&gt;20&lt;/span&gt; As ordinance workers, in addition to receiving ordinances for your ancestors, you can also &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;officiate&lt;/span&gt; in ordinances for them.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p35" pid="UTwYCIRSQkSs6xap_hHZ9g" hash="KxjLVg"&gt;As President Wilford Woodruff said:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p36" pid="ac-nfM_IvUSDe-pJWIok4Q" hash="LwqqbA"&gt;“What greater calling can any man [or woman] have on the face of the earth than to hold in his [or her] hands power and authority to go forth and administer in the ordinances of salvation? …&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p37" pid="Esgfd8bVqUeB_G5MWH4iNQ" hash="lnWPIw"&gt;“… You become an instrument in the hands of God in the salvation of that soul. There is nothing given to the children of men that is equal to it.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21"&gt;21&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p38" pid="QxlOYM41IkixgLflnXBuKQ" hash="xNZU1w"&gt;He also said:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p39" pid="qz0q0z8FNEGCqo_hYyhPSw" hash="sUVsPA"&gt;“The sweet whisperings of the Holy Spirit will be given to [you] and the treasures of Heaven, the communion of angels, will be added from time to time.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22"&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p40" pid="87tg7_Q9Dk26NVwZhIpqkg" hash="8JaQMQ"&gt;“This is worth all you or I can sacrifice [during] the few years we have to spend here in the flesh.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23"&gt;23&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p41" pid="X2z34bR1MEiFFcLcvH2CdA" hash="tqgewg"&gt;President Thomas S. Monson recently reminded us that “the blessings of the temple are priceless.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24"&gt;24&lt;/span&gt; “No sacrifice is too great.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25"&gt;25&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p42" pid="PWXv5QXQSkKn0ZfLEjxf3A" hash="bZDfnQ"&gt;Come to the temple. Come often. Come with and for your family. Come, and help others to come too.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness.p43" pid="ibzvWJX_ZEKuvaAke_McjA" hash="rN1lWw"&gt;“What are these which are arrayed in white?” My brothers and sisters, &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;you&lt;/span&gt; are they—you who have received the ordinances of the temple, who have kept your covenants even by sacrifice; you who are helping your families find the blessings of temple service and who have helped others along the way. Thank you for your service. I testify that each temple is God’s holy, sacred house and that therein each of us may learn and know the powers of godliness, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/04/the-power-of-godliness</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2016-general-conference/2016-04-5050-kent-f-richards-64k-eng.mp3" length="5056329" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
