<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Kevin W. Pearson</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Kevin W. Pearson.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Kevin%20W.%20Pearson.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Kevin W. Pearson.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2009 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2009 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Faith in the Lord Jesus Christ</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In a household of faith, there is no need to fear or doubt. Choose to live by faith and not fear.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50015887_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="woopFg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="WHI5ZI0tIUCOfCDFTx7LgA" hash="uww0PA">Faith in the Lord Jesus Christ</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="pS8sCRk3M0a5rssXbzB8og" hash="F9haHA">Elder Kevin W. Pearson</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="n_0DOC1mvk6pFLPG8yj4VQ" hash="w9RYLQ">In a household of faith, there is no need to fear or doubt. Choose to live by faith and not fear.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p1" pid="6AInONQzx0yFPSZEp5VC9w" hash="qR3WLg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="38"></span>I humbly invite the companionship of the Holy Ghost as we discuss a vital principle of the gospel: faith in the Lord Jesus Christ. I acknowledge with deep appreciation and love great examples of true faith and faithfulness in my own life. To goodly parents, family, priesthood leaders, beloved missionaries, wonderful children, and a precious eternal companion, I express my deepest love and gratitude. I acknowledge my own need and desire for greater faith as a disciple and witness of Christ. There has never been a greater need for faith in my own life than now.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p2" pid="-DuqX7Iet0KG7bEpRS-3jQ" hash="GkutLg">As parents, we have been commanded to teach our children “to understand the doctrine of … faith in Christ the Son of the living God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.25" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:25</a>). This requires more than merely recognizing faith as a gospel principle. “To have faith is to have confidence in something or someone” (Bible Dictionary, “Faith,” 669). True faith must be centered in Jesus Christ. “Faith is a principle of action and of power” (Bible Dictionary, 670). It requires us to do, not merely to believe. Faith is a spiritual gift from God that comes through the Holy Ghost. It requires a correct understanding and knowledge of Jesus Christ, His divine attributes and perfect character, His teachings, Atonement, Resurrection, and priesthood power. Obedience to these principles develops complete trust in Him and His ordained servants and assurance of His promised blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p3" pid="vBYMr5RjkEGx01Mec7UuUQ" hash="bFdgZQ">There is no other thing in which we can have absolute assurance. There is no other foundation in life that can bring the same peace, joy, and hope. In uncertain and difficult times, faith is truly a spiritual gift worthy of our utmost efforts. We can give our children education, lessons, athletics, the arts, and material possessions, but if we do not give them faith in Christ, we have given little.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p4" pid="Hi5UxzpxX0SudzBLcsuAhg" hash="e86CLA">“Faith is kindled by hearing the testimony of those who have faith” <span class="pageBreak" page-number="39"></span>(Bible Dictionary, 669; see also <a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/10.14-17" class="scriptureRef">Romans 10:14–17</a>). Do your children know that you know? Do they see and feel your conviction? “Strong faith is developed by obedience to the gospel of Jesus Christ” (Bible Dictionary, 669).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p5" pid="iepILG-oiEWfeNtiEs8xdw" hash="9wvyvg">Elder Bruce R. McConkie taught: “<span class="emphasis">Faith is a gift of God bestowed as a reward for personal righteousness. </span>It is always given when righteousness is present, and the greater the measure of obedience to God’s laws the greater will be the endowment of faith” (<span class="emphasis">Mormon Doctrine,</span> 2nd ed. [1966], 264). If we desire more faith, we must be more obedient. When we teach our children by example or precept to be casual or situational in obeying God’s commandments, we prevent them from receiving this vital spiritual gift. Faith requires an attitude of exact obedience, even in the small, simple things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p6" pid="k96bN9xkqUqAaiVFcorXXA" hash="5GK0rw">Desire is a particle of faith that develops within us as we experience divine truth. It is like spiritual photosynthesis. The influence of the Holy Ghost, acting on the Light of Christ within every human being, produces the spiritual equivalent of a chemical reaction—a stirring, a change of heart, or a desire to know. Hope develops as particles of faith become molecules and as simple efforts to live true principles occur.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p7" pid="HYef9buxh0ivPpA2my3EdQ" hash="brkmLg">As patterns of obedience develop, the specific blessings associated with obedience are realized and belief emerges. Desire, hope, and belief are forms of faith, but faith as a principle of power comes from a consistent pattern of obedient behavior and attitudes. Personal righteousness is a choice. Faith is a gift from God, and one possessed of it can receive enormous spiritual power.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p8" pid="FDPSZevjE0-5ipHKiYtUgQ" hash="bhvJ_Q">There is a quality of faith which develops as we focus all of our heart, might, mind, and strength. It is seen and felt in the eyes of a great missionary, a valiant and virtuous young woman, and righteous mothers, fathers, and grandparents. It can be seen in the lives of individuals young and old, in every land and culture, speaking every language, in every circumstance and station in life. It is the “eye of faith” spoken of by the prophet Alma (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.15-26" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:15–26</a>)—the ability to focus and be steadfast, continually holding fast to true principles, nothing wavering, even when the mist of darkness confronting us is exceedingly great. This quality of faith is exceedingly powerful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p9" pid="E6NPE_OfqUy9hvligq7y8A" hash="4vZqrQ">However, “it must needs be, that there is an opposition in all things. … The Lord God gave unto man that he should act for himself. Wherefore, man could not act for himself save it <span class="pageBreak" page-number="40"></span>should be that he was enticed by the one or the other” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.11,16" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 2:11, 16</a>). And so it is with faith. It can be enticing to choose doubt and disbelief over faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p10" pid="Co-noce3LUCOu1yY-w6zOw" hash="eehUOQ">As Jesus returned from the transcendent spiritual experience on the Mount of Transfiguration, He was approached by a desperate father whose son needed help. The father pleaded, “If thou canst do any thing, have compassion on us, and help us.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p11" pid="82f29Pb5cU2a1O7m5FxGfg" hash="cCQnjg">Jesus replied, “If thou canst believe, all things are possible to him that believeth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p12" pid="j-Gr84ghREykgV5_0iAbvQ" hash="X3YbDQ">“And straightway the father … cried out, and said with tears, Lord, I believe; help thou mine unbelief” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/9.22-24" class="scriptureRef">Mark 9:22–24</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p13" pid="4sW-htL9dkSxWHK40MejkQ" hash="z0jNvA">Faith and fear cannot coexist. One gives way to the other. The simple fact is we all need to constantly build faith and overcome sources of destructive disbelief. The Savior’s teaching comparing faith to a grain of mustard seed recognizes this reality (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/13.31-32" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 13:31–32</a>). Consider it this way: our net usable faith is what we have left to exercise after we subtract our sources of doubt and disbelief. You might ask yourself this question: “Is my own net faith positive or negative?” If your faith exceeds your doubt and disbelief, the answer is likely positive. If you allow doubt and disbelief to control you, the answer might be negative.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p14" pid="h4a306ph0Emyj8f7RDzmeg" hash="kFQwUA">We do have a choice. We get what we focus on consistently. Because there is an opposition in all things, there are forces that erode our faith. Some are the result of Satan’s direct influence. But for others, we have no one but ourselves to blame. These stem from personal tendencies, attitudes, and habits we can learn to change. I will refer to these influences as the “Six Destructive Ds.” As I do, consider their influence on you or your children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p15" pid="7tG8PLigik2zuqPo4AnzuA" hash="LCp6IQ">First is <span class="emphasis">doubt.</span> Doubt is not a principle of the gospel. It does not come from the Light of Christ or the influence of the Holy Ghost. Doubt is a negative emotion related to fear. It comes from a lack of confidence in one’s self or abilities. It is inconsistent with our divine identity as children of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p16" pid="_3BAVST3e0egNkTC7edZWg" hash="N5AwSA">Doubt leads to <span class="emphasis">discouragement.</span> Discouragement comes from missed expectations. Chronic discouragement leads to lower expectations, decreased effort, weakened desire, and greater difficulty feeling and following the Spirit (see <span class="emphasis">Preach My Gospel</span> [2004], 10). Discouragement and despair are the very antithesis of faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p17" pid="5M6A5BIMPUKPPE8MVyUgEQ" hash="HcMFmw">Discouragement leads to <span class="emphasis">distraction,</span> a lack of focus. Distraction eliminates the very focus the eye of faith requires. Discouragement and distraction are two of Satan’s most effective tools, but they are also bad habits.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p18" pid="oMasIWIv1EiRWuKaRgyiQw" hash="SS81yg">Distraction leads to a <span class="emphasis">lack of diligence,</span> a reduced commitment to remain true and faithful and to carry on through despite hardship and disappointment. Disappointment is an inevitable part of life, but it need not lead to doubt, discouragement, distraction, or lack of diligence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p19" pid="yM4L_yvRVE66TV7aVwqGTw" hash="IPeTKg">If not reversed, this path ultimately leads to <span class="emphasis">disobedience,</span> which undermines the very basis of faith. So often the result is disbelief, the conscious or unconscious refusal to believe.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p20" pid="a_LRS3LAgkSBDib2KuVNpg" hash="jRRvJA">The scriptures describe <span class="emphasis">disbelief</span> as the state of having chosen to harden one’s heart. It is to be past feeling.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p21" pid="PzT2ayhzr0KIcwnkdnwOFA" hash="A_vLRA">These Six Destructive Ds—<span class="emphasis">doubt, discouragement, distraction, lack of diligence, disobedience,</span> and <span class="emphasis">disbelief</span>—all erode and destroy our faith. We can choose to avoid and overcome them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p22" pid="3FLTbMHOUk6-TrgKaOeptQ" hash="WnF8uQ">Challenging times require greater spiritual power. Consider carefully the Savior’s promise: “If ye will have faith in me ye shall have power to do whatsoever thing is expedient in me” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.33" class="scriptureRef">Moroni 7:33</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ.p23" pid="ZS_8ArXHTEWlGJHId9O-sQ" hash="56f7qA">I humbly declare that God, our Heavenly Father, lives and loves each of us, His children. Jesus Christ is our Savior and Redeemer. He lives and personally leads His Church through President Monson, His anointed prophet. Because He lives, there is always hope smiling brightly before us. In a household of faith, there is no need to fear or doubt. Choose to live by faith and not fear. In the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2009/04/faith-in-the-lord-jesus-christ</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2009-general-conference/2009-04-2060-elder-kevin-w-pearson-64k-eng.mp3" length="5320289" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2009 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stay by the Tree</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Kevin W. Pearson explains how Lehi’s vision of the tree of life teaches us what we must do to endure to the end.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_12565_000_52pearson" doc-version="5" hash="3oFCUg">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="sT2HrL4WL0aS656unXX9sg" hash="vgAIVA">Stay by the Tree</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p2" pid="ScTFby_jT0mGONWkMbgYQg" hash="ZW5Fng">By Elder Kevin W. Pearson</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p3" pid="Fz-VOHBRXUi8z8o1i4EyVQ" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=V4YZZzNBH0yTxiSi7qroLg"><img xmlns="" type="jpg" uri="kevin-w-pearson-10.jpg" translate="no" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255565/0874d2b0b358456797db5ca2a8c19083/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255565/0874d2b0b358456797db5ca2a8c19083/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255565/0874d2b0b358456797db5ca2a8c19083/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x278="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255565/0874d2b0b358456797db5ca2a8c19083/200x278.jpg" data-src-320x446="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255565/0874d2b0b358456797db5ca2a8c19083/320x446.jpg" data-src-460x641="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255565/0874d2b0b358456797db5ca2a8c19083/460x641.jpg" data-src-640x892="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255565/0874d2b0b358456797db5ca2a8c19083/640x892.jpg" data-src-1024x1427="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255565/0874d2b0b358456797db5ca2a8c19083/1024x1427.jpg" data-src-2048x2855="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255565/0874d2b0b358456797db5ca2a8c19083/2048x2855.jpg" pid="V4YZZzNBH0yTxiSi7qroLg" hash="7d4hvw"></img></a>
		</div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="4EOyJUVGvkSosNd7YVhXWg" hash="Ec5YHQ">Lehi’s vision of the tree of life is a powerful parable on enduring to the end.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="GCMHH2_X_EWccqMqwDtllw" hash="ZW5Fng1">By Elder Kevin W. Pearson</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="vMD9SnmG1k6uo1NwVNH13Q" hash="v2R97A">
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p5" pid="H1XbMzp9EUGI4FUi5ywvPw" hash="1sTukA">Shortly before President Heber J. Grant passed away, one of the Brethren visited his home. Before he left, President Grant prayed, “O God, bless me that I shall not lose my testimony and keep faithful to the end!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> After nearly 27 years as President of the Church, this was his fervent prayer. His example is a striking reminder that no one, at any age, is immune from Satan’s influence. Two of Satan’s most powerful tools are distraction and deception.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p6" pid="7ePVfcH5z0m5E7TkICa7xQ" hash="sx6BEQ">Enduring to the end is a hallmark of true discipleship and is essential to eternal life. But when trials and challenges come our way, we are often told to simply “hang in there.” Let me be clear: to “hang in there” is not a principle of the gospel. Enduring to the end means constantly coming unto Christ and being perfected in Him.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p7" pid="wCtydq2fs0Cdd-5m2kIEzw" hash="gQTfaA">If enduring to the end is essential to eternal life, why do we struggle to be faithful? We struggle when we are caught between competing priorities. Casual obedience and lukewarm commitment weaken faith. Enduring to the end requires total commitment to the Savior and to our covenants.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p8" pid="fOn0gIDJg0KFJQAw8BL2sw" hash="jPvc8g">Lehi’s vision of the tree of life is a powerful parable on enduring to the end. Please prayerfully study and ponder Lehi’s dream; then liken it unto yourself. As you do, carefully consider six important principles that help us endure to the end.</p>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.t1">
			<h2 pid="DOKzYWkn50mQp5tfIwf1Nw" hash="QpzZug">1. Don’t Forget to Pray</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p10" pid="7HMvkdzfdEmyBc6_rFGW1Q" hash="pYDRxQ">We begin with Lehi alone “in a dark and dreary waste.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Each of us experiences periods of darkness and loneliness. “When life gets dark and dreary, don’t forget to pray.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Follow President Heber J. Grant’s example. Pray for strength to endure to the end. Ask Heavenly Father, “What more would You have me do?”</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.t2">
			<h2 pid="puIQi8f63E-ev4tlTtIGYQ" hash="7a49Yg">2. Come unto Christ and Be Perfected in Him</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p12" pid="jmtmV_zZaEegIvNX3Mnycg" hash="736F-w">The tree of life is the central focus in Lehi’s dream. Everything points to the tree of life. The tree represents Christ, who is the clear manifestation of the love of God. The fruit is His infinite Atonement and is great evidence of God’s love. Eternal life with our loved ones is sweeter and more desirable than any other thing. To realize this gift, we must “come unto Christ, and be perfected in him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> He is “the way, the truth, and the life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> We can fill our lives with accomplishment and well-doing, but in the end, if we do not enter into sacred covenants to follow Christ and faithfully keep them, we will have utterly and completely missed the mark.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.t3">
			<h2 pid="Oa6OR7pC7UiFq8jYwX_HCA" hash="tvTTRg">3. Press Forward with Faith</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p14" pid="IkPwBOD8fEaXdl_mUrdl9A" hash="vetDMA">There is a path that leads to the tree of life, to Christ. It is strait and narrow, strict and exact. God’s commandments are strict but not restrictive. They protect us from spiritual and physical danger and prevent us from getting lost.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p15" pid="EEgSuRHhAkmlo9LiQxXEaA" hash="CxCd9w">Obedience builds faith in Christ. Faith is a principle of action and power. Consistently following the Savior’s example produces spiritual power and capacity. Without the strengthening and enabling power of the Atonement, it’s impossible to stay on the path and endure.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p16" pid="dN5PyUbFhEGiX5JYGd8dyw" hash="dqy03Q">“Press forward with a steadfastness in Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.t4">
			<h2 pid="VbSJR4Uud0G2fL20u-swJA" hash="be7m1Q">4. The Book of Mormon Is Key to Spiritual Survival</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p18" pid="PFL0ZrTz-EyDhrUIF18rSw" hash="q1lLMw">Life’s journey is challenging. It’s easy to be distracted, wander off the path, and get lost. Tribulation is an inevitable and indispensable part of our eternal progression. When adversity comes, don’t let something you don’t fully understand unravel everything you do know. Be patient, cling to truth; understanding will come. Trials are like great mists of darkness that can blind our eyes and harden our hearts. Unless we are “continually holding fast”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> to the word of God and living it, we will become spiritually blinded rather than spiritually minded. Search the Book of Mormon and the words of the living prophets every day, every day, every day! It’s the key to spiritual survival and avoiding deception. Without it, we are spiritually lost.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.t5">
			<h2 pid="piwNBrWYUkqwbfcBQGB_zw" hash="lWm3OQ">5. Don’t Be Distracted and Deceived</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p20" pid="Q9aDrlqackKkkiN7fN5Dsg" hash="HxfZmw">To heed is to give careful attention. Heeding those who do not believe in Christ will not help you find Him. Searching #spaciousbuilding for knowledge will not lead you to truth. It’s not posted there. Only the Savior has “the words of eternal life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Everything else is just words. The large and spacious building symbolizes the “vain imaginations and the pride”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> of the world—in other words, distraction and deception. It’s filled with well-dressed people who seem to have everything. But they mock the Savior and those who follow Him. They are “ever learning, and never able to come to the knowledge of the truth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> They may be politically correct, but they are spiritually lost.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.t6" pid="qjiifxAPXEiOF8XrE3g2Sw" hash="tHhyjA">
			<h2 pid="b0iRr551XUO7esp8NI5OfA" hash="KSrBjw">6. Stay by the Tree</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p22" pid="lYrXIorLBkiJ_x9DLQFtwA" hash="CleM4Q">Lehi’s message is to stay by the tree. We stay because we are converted unto the Lord. Alma taught, “Behold, he changed their hearts; yea, he awakened them out of a deep sleep, and they awoke unto God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> As we yield our hearts to God, the Holy Ghost changes our very natures, we become deeply converted unto the Lord, and we no longer seek the spacious building. If we stop doing those things that bring about deepening conversion, we regress spiritually. Apostasy is the reverse of conversion.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p23" pid="GYDrWNW3AUarCsoxjItLWw" hash="uWJ8wA">To all missionaries past and present: Elders and sisters, you simply cannot return from your mission, do a swan dive back into Babylon, and spend endless hours scoring meaningless points on pointless video games without falling into a deep spiritual sleep. Nor can you indulge in online pornography and ignore virtue and chastity without dire spiritual consequences. If you lose the Spirit, you are lost. Don’t be distracted and deceived.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p24" pid="7YZdm2PloUmxCGo15otxog" hash="WWU9WA">True disciples continue to awaken unto God each day in meaningful personal prayer, earnest scripture study, personal obedience, and selfless service. Stay by the tree and stay awake.</p>
			<span class="story">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p25" pid="aIApFU0G_E6wJmcRvTnCdw" hash="jx24vg">Several years ago, Sister Pearson and I were called to preside over the Washington Tacoma Mission. The call was a complete surprise. With some trepidation I met with the chairman and the CEO of the company where I was employed and informed them of my mission call. They were visibly upset with my decision to leave the firm. “When did you make this decision, and why didn’t you discuss it with us earlier?” they demanded.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p26" pid="iotflBgBME6Fcugpu54EMA" hash="EaHECw">In a moment of clarity, a profound answer came into my mind. I said, “I made this decision as a 19-year-old boy, when I made sacred covenants with God in the temple to follow the Savior. I’ve built my entire life on those covenants, and I fully intend to keep them now.”</p>
			</span>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p27" pid="YyFnB3TurU68XqP7AZr_Fg" hash="sRQN4g">Once we enter into covenants with God, there is no going back. Giving in, giving up, and giving out are not options. In the kingdom of God, there is a standard of excellence for exaltation. It requires valiant discipleship! There is no room for average or complacent disciples. Average is the enemy of excellence, and average commitment will prevent you from enduring to the end.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p28" pid="DQZMZlZZnU60Gwi0NXCLNw" hash="BVg3DA">If you are struggling, confused, or spiritually lost, I urge you to do the one thing I know will get you back on track. Begin again to prayerfully study the Book of Mormon and live its teachings every day, every day, every day! I testify of the profound power in the Book of Mormon that will change your life and strengthen your resolve to follow Christ. The Holy Ghost will change your heart and help you see “things as they really are.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> He will show you what you need to do next. This is Nephi’s promise to you:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p29" pid="c7t3FMeXiUOSd4Q5S_kvtA" hash="Kzlc3Q">“And I said unto them … whoso would hearken unto the word of God, and would hold fast unto it, they would never perish; neither could the temptations and the fiery darts of the adversary overpower them unto blindness, to lead them away to destruction.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p30" pid="Ky_3EPwz4UiK3Ii-zO_WQQ" hash="xv32bQ">“Wherefore, I … did exhort them … that they would give heed to the word of God and remember to keep his commandments always in all things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p31" pid="zAdvVXnjt0K9Bu13DHV0EQ" hash="5rVU4Q">Brothers and sisters, enduring to the end is the great test of discipleship. Our daily discipleship will determine our eternal destiny. Awaken unto God, cling to truth, keep your sacred temple covenants, and stay by the tree!</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree.p32" pid="gjn_IibPy0KP3Wh-yIjKyQ" hash="ND9TIg">I bear witness of the resurrected, living Christ. I know that He lives. My greatest desire is that I will be true and faithful to the very end in following His magnificent example. In the sacred name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/04/stay-by-the-tree</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2015-general-conference/2015-04-5020-elder-kevin-w-pearson-64k-eng.mp3" length="4963294" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
