<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Kevin R. Duncan</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Kevin R. Duncan.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Kevin%20R.%20Duncan.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Kevin R. Duncan.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Our Very Survival</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival?lang=eng</link>
      <description>May we have the wisdom to trust in and follow the counsel of the living prophets and apostles.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021411_000_2050" doc-version="2" hash="PkI8ew">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="1XWxDhVET0Wc8Dzv4UbgCg" hash="MpZ-sA">Our Very Survival</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="UGGIXIqkUkeeDXdcZ1ix5A" hash="lIroIw">Kevin R. Duncan</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="vc8PJD5d9keQBBZq7tZuyA" hash="3FnG8A">May we have the wisdom to trust in and follow the counsel of the living prophets and apostles.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p1" pid="0HXIaA64cU-yMU3xiUnILQ" hash="ivAMHw">The winter of 1848 was difficult and challenging for the pioneer settlers in the Salt Lake Valley. During the summer of 1847 Brigham Young had declared that the Saints had finally reached their destination. “This is the right place,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> said Brigham Young, who had been shown in a vision where the Saints were to be established. The early members of the Church had endured tremendous adversity as the Restoration of the gospel unfurled. They had been driven from their homes, persecuted, and hounded. They had suffered untold hardships as they crossed the plains. But now they were at last in “the right place.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p2" pid="UolmQ28jHk6GElBWU777Wg" hash="pUiN7A">And yet, the winter of 1848 had been extremely harsh. The winter had been so cold that some people’s feet had been badly frozen. A spirit of uneasiness began to descend upon the Saints. Some Church members declared that they would not build their homes in the valley. They wanted to remain in their wagons, for they were sure that Church leadership would herald them on to some better location. They had brought seeds and fruit plants, but they dared not waste them by planting in the barren desert wasteland. Jim Bridger, a well-known explorer of the time, told Brigham Young he would give a thousand dollars for the first bushel of corn raised in the Salt Lake Valley because, he said, it could not be done.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p3" pid="A1iSElgnLkq3Vc6qCEpH8w" hash="-9xerw">To complicate matters, gold had just been discovered in California. Some Church members envisioned that life would be simpler and more abundant if they were to move on to California in search of riches and a better climate.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p4" pid="lY9WlLCApEWtZYIybUxzbg" hash="_LsI5Q">Under this cloud of discontent, Brigham Young addressed the members of the Church. He declared:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p5" pid="V7u5OAAQkkyMCVk14oTefg" hash="XjFVXA">“[This valley] is the place God has appointed for His people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p6" pid="2_2GGM_sBUi5ENFwESHWwg" hash="T3Od-A">“We have been kicked out of the frying-pan into the fire, out of the fire into the middle of the floor, and here we are and here we will stay. God has shown me that this is the spot to locate His people, and here is where they will prosper; He will temper the elements for the good of His Saints; He will rebuke the frost and the sterility of the soil, and the land shall become fruitful. Brethren, go, now, and plant … your … seeds.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p7" pid="CFusmay_kEaBeQdqekD_Uw" hash="37qJtw">In addition to promising these blessings, President Young declared that the Salt Lake Valley would become known as a highway to the nations. Kings and emperors would visit the land. Best of all, a temple to the Lord would be erected.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p8" pid="0kOdmB0Zqk6Fcftx5Thctw" hash="TA8b5g">These were remarkable promises. Many Church members had faith in Brigham Young’s prophecies, while others remained skeptical and left for what they assumed would be a better life. Yet history has shown that every prophecy Brigham Young declared has come to pass. The valley did blossom and produce. The Saints prospered. The winter of 1848 was a great catalyst for the Lord to teach His people a valuable lesson. They learned—as we all must learn—that the only sure and secure road to protection in this life comes through trusting in and obeying the counsel from the prophets of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p9" pid="9BMfAjIvWk61w04uaSk9Mg" hash="rxNlCw">Surely one of the crowning blessings of membership in this Church is the blessing of being led by living prophets of God. The Lord declared, “There is never but one on the earth at a time on whom this power and the keys of this priesthood are conferred.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> The prophet and President of the Church today, Thomas S. Monson, receives God’s word for the entire membership of the Church and for the world. In addition, we sustain as prophets, seers, and revelators the counselors in the First Presidency and the members of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p10" pid="4F88-w7daUy7kbDPPdk0bQ" hash="5tO2oA">With frozen feet and a barren wasteland, those early Saints surely needed faith to trust their prophet. Their very survival and lives were at stake. Yet the Lord rewarded their obedience and blessed and prospered those who followed His mouthpiece.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p11" pid="RParF27FmkmBTtLfV7LwdA" hash="nzrwQA">And the Lord does the same today for you and me. This world is full of so many self-help books, so many self-proclaimed experts, so many theorists, educators, and philosophers who have advice and counsel to give on any and all subjects. With technology today, information on a myriad of subjects is available with the click of a keystroke. It is easy to get caught in the trap of looking to the “arm of flesh”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> for advice on everything from how to raise children to how to find happiness. While some information has merit, as members of the Church we have access to the source of pure truth, even God Himself. We would do well to search out answers to our problems and questions by investigating what the Lord has revealed through His prophets. With that same technology today, we have at our fingertips access to the words of the prophets on nearly any subject. What has God taught us about marriage and the family through His prophets? What has He taught us about education and provident living through His prophets? What has He taught us about personal happiness and fulfillment through His prophets?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p12" pid="GYPlMCKSTEim78AePNdlPQ" hash="4l-x-A">What the prophets teach may to some seem outdated, unpopular, or even impossible. But God is a God of order and has established a system whereby we may know His will. “Surely the Lord God will do nothing, but he revealeth his secret unto his servants the prophets.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> At the opening of this, the dispensation of the fulness of times, the Lord reaffirmed that He would communicate with us through His prophets. He stated, “My word … shall all be fulfilled, whether by mine own voice or by the voice of my servants, it is the same.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p13" pid="rkzzGswdg0ec5BqE7CCscg" hash="dF_h6g">Trusting in and following the prophets is more than a blessing and a privilege. President Ezra Taft Benson declared that “our [very] salvation hangs on” following the prophet. He described what he called “Fourteen Fundamentals in Following the Prophet.” In the session this morning, Elder Claudio Costa of the Presidency of the Seventy so eloquently instructed us on these 14 fundamentals. Because they are of such great importance to our very salvation, I will repeat them again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p14" pid="pdTPg7palkKjiAtfwfT-vQ" hash="UKlm9g"> “First: The prophet is the only man who speaks for the Lord in everything.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p15" pid="piBiPyhXxEGey-fLHeXASQ" hash="7M9IBQ"> “Second: The living prophet is more vital to us than the standard works.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p16" pid="jvLvwFSpjUuTbs5AX9VYfg" hash="7bbM3w">“Third: The living prophet is more important to us than a dead prophet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p17" pid="x1QoiNurJkOEawGrD24K6A" hash="H-ORaA">“Fourth: The prophet will never lead the Church astray.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p18" pid="cTKI5b39HU6T1L6iIhjvlA" hash="nGG0hw"> “Fifth: The prophet is not required to have any particular earthly training or credentials to speak on any subject or act on any matter at any time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p19" pid="6IMtkIGu5kih6unOQn95Ig" hash="mpy3fg"> “Sixth: The prophet does not have to say ‘Thus saith the Lord’ to give us scripture.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p20" pid="FWY2MC-2Xkq8cwVxFUqMEQ" hash="PDJA2A"> “Seventh: The prophet tells us what we need to know, not always what we want to know.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p21" pid="0NZhZaaKJU6hgBjX8nWoVg" hash="_jHgSg"> “Eighth: The prophet is not limited by men’s reasoning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p22" pid="Zakqj29duUyxguZL3WfKFQ" hash="ULEgUg"> “Ninth: The prophet can receive revelation on any matter, temporal or spiritual.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p23" pid="UrH_lkR4hUKi1-EorpVfCg" hash="jEWNUg"> “Tenth: The prophet may be involved in civic matters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p24" pid="7bmLQsCHGEykEIjYX0uSWQ" hash="c07wAA"> “Eleventh: The two groups who have the greatest difficulty in following the prophet are the proud who are learned and the proud who are rich.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p25" pid="i6DqS085m0yJfOeFWfTMAg" hash="A52PiQ"> “Twelfth: The prophet will not necessarily be popular with the world or the worldly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p26" pid="jfyjPOhTCkalRB9141Vk6A" hash="Z6Fddw"> “Thirteenth: The prophet and his counselors make up the First Presidency—the highest quorum in the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p27" pid="lfBI4cawX06ZzOZlCZ7rtQ" hash="olhvsg"> “Fourteenth: [Follow] … the living prophet and the First Presidency … and be blessed; reject them and suffer.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival.p28" pid="tEGgtdtuYkuIuazjMxa0yQ" hash="sl-p3g">Brothers and sisters, like the Saints of 1848, we can choose to follow the prophet, or we can look to the arm of flesh. May we have the wisdom to trust in and follow the counsel of the living prophets and apostles. I am a witness of their goodness. I testify that they are called of God. I also testify that there is no safer way to approach life, find answers to our problems, gain peace and happiness in this world, and protect our very salvation than by obeying their words. I bear this witness in the sacred name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/10/our-very-survival</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2010-general-conference/2010-10-2050-elder-kevin-r-duncan-64k-eng.mp3" length="4347088" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Healing Ointment of Forgiveness</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13285_000_25duncan" doc-version="2" hash="p-2ohg"&gt;
	
	&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.head1"&gt;
		&lt;h1 class="title" pid="80pbax6pIEW6TaUkHBEidg" hash="EDuNsg"&gt;The Healing Ointment of Forgiveness&lt;/h1&gt;
		&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p2" pid="PlCt3l2oNE-l_Hg51o1FxQ" hash="1aXgwg1"&gt;By Elder Kevin R. Duncan&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p3" pid="fDorWqLlbUqv3xE17PfTeA" hash="sSmk3g"&gt;Of the Seventy&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=FGWzpOPxD0i_IfZD6xx2iQ"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" altText="Elder Kevin R. Duncan" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255519/fa9817f48fc04c5caf3406229abf2b7c/100x140.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x70="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255519/fa9817f48fc04c5caf3406229abf2b7c/50x70.jpg" data-src-100x140="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255519/fa9817f48fc04c5caf3406229abf2b7c/100x140.jpg" data-src-200x280="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255519/fa9817f48fc04c5caf3406229abf2b7c/200x280.jpg" data-src-320x448="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255519/fa9817f48fc04c5caf3406229abf2b7c/320x448.jpg" data-src-460x644="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255519/fa9817f48fc04c5caf3406229abf2b7c/460x644.jpg" data-src-640x896="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255519/fa9817f48fc04c5caf3406229abf2b7c/640x896.jpg" data-src-1024x1434="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255519/fa9817f48fc04c5caf3406229abf2b7c/1024x1434.jpg" data-src-2048x2869="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255519/fa9817f48fc04c5caf3406229abf2b7c/2048x2869.jpg" data-src-3828x5363="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255519/fa9817f48fc04c5caf3406229abf2b7c/3828x5363.jpg" webURL="kevin-r-duncan-first-quorum-seventy_1255519.jpg" pid="FGWzpOPxD0i_IfZD6xx2iQ" hash="AAAAAA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="kicker" pid="z79OpzeGJU6I9MozSuYV0A" hash="Pf10yQ"&gt;Forgiveness is a glorious, healing principle. We do not need to be a victim twice. We can forgive.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="authorName" pid="ufUHDsJwbkOmxSB22RUpow" hash="1aXgwg"&gt;By Elder Kevin R. Duncan&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class="bodyBlock"&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p5" pid="JTidkYWTL0-UjYGkGGgD9w" hash="_Y8F7A"&gt;All that is of God encompasses love, light, and truth. Yet as human beings we live in a fallen world, sometimes full of darkness and confusion. It comes as no surprise that mistakes will be made, injustices will occur, and sins will be committed. As a result, there is not a soul alive who will not, at one time or another, be the victim to someone else’s careless actions, hurtful conduct, or even sinful behavior. That is one thing we all have in common.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p6" pid="yQRHwnBJ006mB08lvpEVwg" hash="4ODtcQ"&gt;Gratefully, God, in His love and mercy for His children, has prepared a way to help us navigate these sometimes turbulent experiences of life. He has provided an escape for all who fall victim to the misdeeds of others. He has taught us that we can forgive! Even though we may be a victim once, we need not be a victim twice by carrying the burden of hate, bitterness, pain, resentment, or even revenge. We can forgive, and we can be free!&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p7" pid="mPG2t5leDEaQTknaOWR_Wg" hash="Ndx0XQ"&gt;Many years ago, while I was mending a fence, a small sliver of wood entered into my finger. I made a meager attempt to remove the sliver and thought I had done so, but apparently I had not. As time went on, skin grew over the sliver, creating a lump on my finger. It was annoying and sometimes painful.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p8" pid="9I6dTpJzD06kvDUmHIS9rA" hash="zy__Ow"&gt;Years later I decided to finally take action. All I did was simply apply ointment to the lump and cover it with a bandage. I repeated this process frequently. You cannot imagine my surprise when one day, as I removed the bandage, the sliver had emerged from my finger.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p9" pid="v2xYfeAb-kS4VzEB5ww6qw" hash="jj1d-Q"&gt;The ointment had softened the skin and created an escape for the very thing that had caused pain for so many years. Once the sliver was removed, the finger quickly healed, and to this day, there remains no evidence of any injury.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p10" pid="7DG9VOU6Z06RM-8pR7WBPg" hash="RSSdfQ"&gt;In a similar way, an unforgiving heart harbors so much needless pain. When we apply the healing ointment of the Savior’s Atonement, He will soften our heart and help us to change. He can &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;heal&lt;/span&gt; the wounded soul (see &lt;a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/2.8" class="scriptureRef"&gt;Jacob 2:8&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p11" pid="s3VHQYXcOUaHe5ovypiH3g" hash="kVz90w"&gt;I am convinced that most of us want to forgive, but we find it very hard to do. When we have experienced an injustice, we may be quick to say, “That person did wrong. They deserve punishment. Where is the justice?” We mistakenly think that &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;if &lt;/span&gt;we forgive, somehow justice will not be served and punishments will be avoided.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p12" pid="79QdZ7YquUqAYdbIzrcJHg" hash="IgYXhg"&gt;This simply is not the case. God will mete out a punishment that is fair, for mercy cannot rob justice (see &lt;a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/42.25" class="scriptureRef"&gt;Alma 42:25&lt;/a&gt;). God lovingly assures you and me: “Leave judgment alone with me, for it is mine and I will repay. [But let] peace be with you” (&lt;a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/82.23" class="scriptureRef"&gt;D&amp;amp;C 82:23&lt;/a&gt;). The Book of Mormon prophet Jacob also promised that God “will console you in your afflictions, and he will plead your cause, and send down justice upon those who seek your destruction” (&lt;a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/3.1" class="scriptureRef"&gt;Jacob 3:1&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p13" pid="eCqXRikZx0u9DQhlFsayRQ" hash="wC43yQ"&gt;As victims, if we are &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;faithful,&lt;/span&gt; we can take great comfort in knowing that God will compensate us for every injustice we experience. Elder Joseph B. Wirthlin stated: “The Lord compensates the faithful for every loss. … Every tear today will eventually be returned a hundredfold with tears of rejoicing and gratitude.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p14" pid="vGm65v9zCEC2WMTTkvJGJA" hash="YDP49Q"&gt;As we strive to forgive others, let us also try to remember that we are all growing spiritually, but we are all at different levels. While it is easy to observe the changes and growth in the physical body, it is difficult to see the growth in our spirits.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p15" pid="CjM3KQYHxUW2mmGppzYVCw" hash="ayZ8wQ"&gt;One key to forgiving others is to try to see them as God sees them. At times, God may part the curtain and bless us with the gift to see into the heart, soul, and spirit of another person who has offended us. This insight may even lead to an overwhelming love for that person.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p16" pid="m3cRhE8WIE2krL3ODRv6vA" hash="-kcoJA"&gt;The scriptures teach us that God’s love for His children is perfect. He knows their potential for good, regardless of their past. By all accounts, there could not have been a more aggressive or harsh enemy of the followers of Jesus Christ than Saul of Tarsus. Yet once God showed Saul light and truth, there was never a more devoted, enthusiastic, or fearless disciple of the Savior. Saul became the Apostle Paul. His life offers a wonderful example of how God sees people not only as they currently are but also as they may become. We all have, in our own lives, Saul-like individuals with Paul-like potential. Can you imagine how our families, our communities, and the world at large might change if we all tried to see each other as God sees us?&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p17" pid="FAC2YSgmck-qcXrkJlt2dA" hash="2yOXBw"&gt;Too often we look at the offender the way we would look at an iceberg—we see only the tip and not beneath the surface. We do not know all that is going on in a person’s life. We do not know their past; we do not know their struggles; we do not know the pains they carry. Brothers and sisters, please do not misunderstand. To forgive is not to condone. We do not rationalize bad behavior or allow others to mistreat us &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;because&lt;/span&gt; of their struggles, pains, or weaknesses. But we &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;can&lt;/span&gt; gain greater understanding and peace when we see with a broader perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p18" pid="NipU75F6X0evsz9gTdixLQ" hash="d10wtA"&gt;Certainly those who are less spiritually mature may indeed make serious mistakes—yet none of us should be &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;defined&lt;/span&gt; only by the worst thing we have ever done. God is the perfect judge. He sees beneath the surface. He knows all and sees all (see &lt;a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.24" class="scriptureRef"&gt;2 Nephi 2:24&lt;/a&gt;). He has said, “I, the Lord, will forgive whom I will forgive, but of you it is required to forgive all men” (&lt;a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.10" class="scriptureRef"&gt;D&amp;amp;C 64:10&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p19" pid="VAmjlvrGdEWhaNViAyiUYg" hash="Z_AEnw"&gt;Christ Himself, when He was unjustly accused, then savagely assaulted, beaten, and left suffering upon the cross, in that very moment said, “Father, forgive them; for they know not what they do” (&lt;a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/23.34" class="scriptureRef"&gt;Luke 23:34&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p20" pid="jyYnFymcfEm8_BFrWyKwIA" hash="wSJMZA"&gt;In our shortsightedness, we may sometimes find it easy to develop resentments toward others who do not act or think the way we do. We may form intolerant attitudes based on such things as rooting for opposing sports teams, holding different political views, or having different religious beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p21" pid="Av3_heeuD0GqIJ10KW9NLA" hash="CBN5xg"&gt;President Russell M. Nelson gave wise counsel when he said, “Opportunities to listen to those of diverse religious or political persuasion can promote tolerance and learning.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p22" pid="8aRtg_SezkaavAQ5BJG1PQ" hash="cZSZZA"&gt;The Book of Mormon speaks of a time when “the people of the church began to be lifted up in the pride of their eyes, and … began to be scornful, one towards another, and … began to persecute those that did not believe according to their own will and pleasure” (&lt;a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/4.8" class="scriptureRef"&gt;Alma 4:8&lt;/a&gt;). Let us all remember that God looketh not upon the color of the jersey or the political party. Instead, as Ammon declared, “[God] looketh down upon all the children of men; and he knows all the thoughts and intents of the heart” (&lt;a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/18.32" class="scriptureRef"&gt;Alma 18:32&lt;/a&gt;). Brothers and sisters, in the competitions of life, if we win, let us win with grace. If we lose, let us lose with grace. For if we live with grace toward one another, grace shall be our reward at the last day.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p23" pid="NLOTgCNF20asn5gWFr-ELw" hash="KS-5Tg"&gt;Just as we are all victims to the misdeeds of others at one time or another, we are also sometimes the offender. We all fall short and have need of grace, mercy, and forgiveness. We must remember that forgiveness of our own sins and offenses is conditioned upon our forgiving others. The Savior said:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p24" pid="17oU7XrLmkesOmYo6ELe3w" hash="-6mZjg"&gt;“For if ye forgive men their trespasses, your heavenly Father will also forgive you:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p25" pid="_mmDV0a3_kOeDGnhy_Nqew" hash="VIEpRA"&gt;“But if ye forgive not men their trespasses, neither will your Father forgive your trespasses” (&lt;a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.14-15" class="scriptureRef"&gt;Matthew 6:14–15&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p26" pid="Jopj7Yo5YEWe_0O3ua2Dvg" hash="WZQ77Q"&gt;Of all the things the Savior could have said in the Lord’s Prayer, which is remarkably short, it is interesting that He chose to include “And forgive us our debts, as we forgive our debtors” (&lt;a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.12" class="scriptureRef"&gt;Matthew 6:12&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/13.11" class="scriptureRef"&gt;3 Nephi 13:11&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p27" pid="iR4dNYtbgke09wZDhCSLgQ" hash="U7S10w"&gt;Forgiveness is the very reason God sent His Son, so let us rejoice in His offering to heal us all. The Savior’s Atonement is not just for those who need to repent; it is also for those who need to forgive. If you are having trouble forgiving another person or even yourself, ask God to help you. Forgiveness is a glorious, healing principle. We do not need to be a victim twice. We can forgive.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness.p28" pid="jC7kk5Guh02yFpEo9iv2SA" hash="xmflNA"&gt;I witness of God’s enduring love and patience for all of His children and of His desire that we love one another as He loves us (see &lt;a href="/scriptures/nt/john/15.9,12" class="scriptureRef"&gt;John 15:9, 12&lt;/a&gt;). As we do so, we will break through the darkness of this world into the glory and majesty of His kingdom in heaven. We will be free. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/04/the-healing-ointment-of-forgiveness</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2016-general-conference/2016-04-1050-kevin-r-duncan-64k-eng.mp3" length="4712768" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
