<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Koichi Aoyagi</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Koichi Aoyagi.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Koichi%20Aoyagi.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Koichi Aoyagi.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2010 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2010 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Helping Hands, Saving Hands</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands?lang=eng</link>
      <description>May we follow the counsel and example of the prophet and each day seek out those in need.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021388_000_017" doc-version="2" hash="3cBBWQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="U4jV8qDMC0qMeW3f74KkDA" hash="mh5OBA">Helping Hands, Saving Hands</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="CMWOhHzp-ESfGOy8EgFdNQ" hash="KOCbEw">Koichi Aoyagi</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="OFYT1J-ld02SK93taSmR0A" hash="D72Vmg">May we follow the counsel and example of the prophet and each day seek out those in need.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands.p1" pid="9-4DufpcJk6TK9gO8oxAOw" hash="ggeIEg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="36"></span>My brothers and sisters, I am deeply grateful for the opportunity to speak at this conference. I am grateful for President Thomas S. Monson, and I testify that he is a prophet of the living God. I am deeply impressed by the wonderful example of President Monson, who has spent his life using his hands to help and save others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands.p2" pid="vMxudKEZ_0awK2pJFPx44g" hash="7aVmfw">We live in a day when many people are faced with calamities and are in need of help due to the devastating effects of earthquakes, tsunamis, hurricanes, and other natural disasters. The Church is reaching out to these people through humanitarian aid. Church members faithfully give generous fast offerings each month and perform service in a spirit of love. They literally offer helping hands in the Lord’s way. They follow the commandment of the Lord to “remember in all things the poor and the needy, the sick and the afflicted, for he that doeth not these things, the same is not my disciple” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/52.40" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 52:40</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands.p3" pid="6bXQ9mCLUE6uP17T59h8Cw" hash="JwmsQw">Today I would like to focus on hands that help and save spiritually. The Lord’s work and glory truly is “to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>). Many around us need spiritual help. As we offer a saving hand to less-active members, to part-member families, and to those not of our faith, we invite all to “come unto Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands.p4" pid="7Mouv4Skg0qMubXVV5rR9g" hash="1joxXw">As a new convert to the Church, I experienced a spiritual rescue through the saving hands of a faithful member of the Church. I grew up in Matsumoto, Japan, close to where the Nagano Winter Olympics were held. My hometown looks very much like Salt Lake City, a valley surrounded by beautiful mountains. When I was 17 years old, I met two American missionaries, Elder Carter and Elder Hayashi. Though our ages were only two or three years apart, the elders had something wonderful that I had never felt before. They were diligent, cheerful, and filled with love and light. I was deeply impressed by their qualities, and I wanted to become like them. I listened to their message and decided to be baptized. My parents, who were Buddhist, strongly opposed my baptism. Through the help of the missionaries and the Lord, I received permission and miraculously was baptized.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands.p5" pid="2SwTB4EPg0iyZUh5Jjikvw" hash="dOaD-w">The next year I entered the university in Yokohama. Living alone, far from my hometown and the people I knew, I became lonely and strayed from the Church. One day I received a postcard from a Church member back home. She wrote that she had heard I was not attending Church meetings. She quoted a scripture and invited me to return to church. I was overwhelmed by the words of the scripture. This helped me realize that maybe I had lost something important, and I pondered and struggled for many days. This also caused me to remember a promise the missionaries had made to me: “If you read the Book of Mormon and ask in fervent prayer if the promise found in Moroni is true, you will know the truth through the power of the Holy Ghost.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands.p6" pid="hwZpBjvhkEOIIzW0P1XTzQ" hash="FoVASQ">I realized that I was not praying with all of my heart and decided to do so. One morning I woke up early, knelt in my small apartment, and prayed sincerely. To my surprise, the confirmation of the Holy Ghost came upon me as promised. My heart burned, my body shook, and I was filled with joy. Through the power of the Holy Ghost, I learned that God the Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, live and that They <span class="pageBreak" page-number="37"></span>truly appeared to Joseph Smith. I made a commitment in my heart to repent and faithfully follow Jesus Christ for the rest of my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands.p7" pid="0GoR11RlKEaji3fmkKyKKw" hash="uwsjSg">This spiritual experience changed my life completely! I decided to serve a mission out of gratitude to the Lord and to the Church member who rescued me. Following my mission, I was sealed in the temple to a wonderful girl, and we have been blessed with four children. Not coincidentally, this is the same girl who saved me by sending a postcard to that lonely apartment in Yokohama many years ago. I remain ever grateful for the mercy of the Lord and the help of this Church member, who invited me to once again come unto Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands.p8" pid="7nnltd42f0aqkgs219woxg" hash="USVt0g">I know many of you privately extend your loving and saving hands each day. This includes a faithful Relief Society sister who cares not only for the sisters whom she is assigned to visit teach but also any sisters who are sick or otherwise in need of help. She visits often and for years has strengthened the faith of many. I reflect on a bishop who often visited the widows and widowers in his ward. This pattern of help continued for many years after his release.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands.p9" pid="jxsefEgfDkCh-6fDzZAHXQ" hash="Id6JFg">I know a priesthood leader who takes time with a young man who has lost his father. He joins with him in activities, teaches him the gospel, and gives advice the way his father would. Another family rejoices in sharing the gospel. The parents and children each testify of the gospel to those around them and are loved by many.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands.p10" pid="wkJDPeilbkWsHYlcI-1oog" hash="kLSccw">As part of a Primary activity, my five-year-old granddaughter places a popcorn seed in a large glass bottle each time she does a good turn. She sings this Primary song in a loud voice as she looks for good things to do each day: “Follow the prophet, follow the prophet, Follow the prophet; he knows the way.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands.p11" pid="rhgPn0aXQUSX40oDQL784g" hash="KB7fEQ">I do not have time to tell you about all the good things I see Church members do. They follow the counsel of the prophet—not out of duty or responsibility but of their own free will, anonymously and joyfully.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands.p12" pid="cS6fABSvpECpfVYgfvbAvA" hash="2h0Dpw">Sometimes we feel that we are weak and lack the strength to rescue others, but the Lord reminds us, “Verily I say unto you, Inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.40" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 25:40</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands.p13" pid="KdIyqsGmeUKamGB8C6XwUg" hash="dTCCPA">I close with a quote by President Thomas S. Monson: “My brothers and sisters, we are surrounded by those in need of our attention, our encouragement, our support, our comfort, our kindness—be they family members, friends, acquaintances, or strangers. We are the Lord’s hands here upon the earth, with the mandate to serve and to lift His children. He is dependent upon each of us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands.p14" pid="-jymb0S3aUiYJTyX-P6aJA" hash="db7qWg">May we follow the counsel and example of the prophet and each day seek out those in need, that we might be the hands of the Lord in helping and saving His children, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/04/helping-hands-saving-hands</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2010-general-conference/2010-04-2060-elder-koichi-aoyagi-64k-eng.mp3" length="4416359" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2010 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hold on Thy Way</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Koichi Aoyagi counsels us to turn our hearts to God in our trials so that we can endure them well and pass the test of this life.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13768_000_67aoyagi" doc-version="3" hash="IiCyKA">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="ooAtmwJhmEaxLRYDyt8VOQ" hash="nh8D4w">Hold on Thy Way</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p2" pid="IBH_-CpvwEKK7C-fEWugyg" hash="G_BXeA">By Elder Koichi Aoyagi</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p3" pid="CHJDm971AEKJ38Og6THOzQ" hash="pc2mbA">Emeritus Member of the Seventy</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=oDcCHRt3G0WxTTc_RIIn2Q"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" alt="Elder Koichi Aoyagi" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255491/0df40916e3504454a827bf8f0c94074d/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255491/0df40916e3504454a827bf8f0c94074d/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255491/0df40916e3504454a827bf8f0c94074d/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x279="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255491/0df40916e3504454a827bf8f0c94074d/200x279.jpg" data-src-320x447="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255491/0df40916e3504454a827bf8f0c94074d/320x447.jpg" data-src-460x643="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255491/0df40916e3504454a827bf8f0c94074d/460x643.jpg" data-src-640x895="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255491/0df40916e3504454a827bf8f0c94074d/640x895.jpg" data-src-1024x1433="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255491/0df40916e3504454a827bf8f0c94074d/1024x1433.jpg" data-src-2048x2866="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255491/0df40916e3504454a827bf8f0c94074d/2048x2866.jpg" data-src-4096x5733="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255491/0df40916e3504454a827bf8f0c94074d/4096x5733.jpg" pid="oDcCHRt3G0WxTTc_RIIn2Q" hash="LJgPKw"></img></a></div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="64n57v0BQEa0iciJ9zYMLQ" hash="y6gCSg">Put God first, regardless of the trials you face. Love God. Have faith in Christ, and entrust yourself to Him in all things.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="edUEvnBROEqk2FQgtKvXrw" hash="KOCbEw">Koichi Aoyagi</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p5" pid="6Mrqiaoo606wURcFGvL4sg" hash="53KUAA">On March 11, 2011, I was standing on a platform in the Tokyo Shinagawa train station to visit the Japan Kobe Mission. At approximately 2:46 p.m., a 9.0-magnitude massive earthquake struck. I was not able to stand because of the intense shaking, and I held tightly to a stair rail. Lights on nearby ceilings began falling to the floor. All of Tokyo was in a panic.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p6" pid="bsvYm67jV0ehFAmt3ICKjg" hash="55X4vQ">Fortunately, I was not injured, and four hours later, I was relieved to learn that my entire family was safe.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p7" pid="YZeiO0HYEkyMRhT2cVSLgw" hash="Vwo3Bw">On television there was a stream of terrifying, shocking footage. A massive tsunami surged into the Sendai mission area—sweeping away everything in its path: cars, houses, factories, and fields. I was stunned by the tragic images, and I wept. And I fervently prayed that our Heavenly Father’s protection and assistance would be upon all the people living in this region that I so dearly love.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p8" pid="HYVtUzJHjU2ZJLaMVEbFbA" hash="WSK52g">Later, it was confirmed that all the missionaries and Church members were safe. However, many members were affected, losing their family members, homes, and household possessions. Nearly 20,000 people perished, communities were destroyed, and many people were forced to leave their homes as a result of a nuclear power plant accident.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p9" pid="wayC-GY8q0GDyJKTKgybpg" hash="U7iStg">Disasters such as this are wreaking havoc in many parts of the world today, causing much loss of life. We are warned that disasters, wars, and countless difficulties in the world will occur.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p10" pid="M2FY6UuT106yHOawhWm94Q" hash="85PT_A">When trials such as these suddenly come upon us, we may question, “Why do these things happen to me?” or “Why do I have to suffer?”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p11" pid="gEyt7XwqIUmsR9rEfFQwYQ" hash="xwC4Zg">For a long period after I converted to the gospel, I didn’t have a clear answer to the question “Why am I given trials?” I understood the part of the plan of salvation that says we will be tested. However, in reality, when it came to this question, I did not have a conviction that was powerful enough to adequately answer it. But there came a time in my life when I too experienced a major trial.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p12" pid="j0NFVoKjSU2zp_y7_6-16g" hash="1pGS8w">When I was 30 years old, I was visiting the Nagoya mission as part of my work. After the meeting, the mission president kindly arranged for the elders to drive me to the airport. However, as we reached the intersection at the bottom of a long hill, a large truck came barreling down from behind us at great speed. It rammed into the rear of our car and propelled it forward more than 70 feet (20 m). The terrifying part of all of this was there was no driver. The rear of our car was compacted to half its original size. Fortunately, both the elders and I survived.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p13" pid="0QGOy8GtfU2DVbR32Cp__w" hash="V_ceuA">However, on the following day, I began experiencing pain in my neck and shoulders and developed a severe headache. From that day, I couldn’t sleep and I was forced to live each day with both physical and mental pain. I prayed to God to please heal my pain, but these symptoms lingered on for about 10 years.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p14" pid="TWypoCvEYEGLWmdkqqqLkQ" hash="t7R03Q">At this time, feelings of doubt also began creeping into my mind, and I wondered, “Why do I have to suffer this much pain?” However, even though the kind of healing I sought was not granted, I strove to be faithful in keeping God’s commandments. I continued to pray that I would be able to resolve the questions I had about my trials.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p15" pid="7fXajbFRJkSmqcCDDdEYug" hash="25riDw">There came a time when I found myself struggling with a few additional personal issues, and I was agitated because I did not know how to cope with this new trial. I was praying for an answer. But I didn’t receive an answer right away. So I went and talked with a trusted Church leader.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p16" pid="Cq3mbhxfHESsV7gpcMJiDg" hash="LRR6bA">As we were talking, with love in his voice, he said, “Brother Aoyagi, isn’t your purpose for being on this earth to experience this trial? Isn’t it to accept all the trials of this life for what they are and then leave the rest up to the Lord? Don’t you think that this problem will be resolved when we are resurrected?”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p17" pid="VOKL4UxOrUSgRi5eQox5_g" hash="ZpXosA">When I heard these words, I felt the Spirit of the Lord very strongly. I had heard this doctrine countless times, but the eyes of my understanding had never been opened to the extent they were at this time. I understood this was the answer that I had been seeking from the Lord in my prayers. I was able to clearly comprehend our Heavenly Father’s plan of salvation and understand anew this important principle.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p18" pid="ianmvUHIbEioLR8SYF9wBA" hash="jSC7KQ">In Abraham, the Lord God declared, “And we will prove them herewith, to see if they will do all things whatsoever the Lord their God shall command them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p19" pid="hiDD7tmtOEmWl6RU388KkQ" hash="6VeiWA">The principle is that the God who created the heavens and the earth knows the grand design of this earth, that He has dominion over all things in the heavens and the earth, and that in order to bring to pass the plan of salvation, He provides us with many different experiences—including some trials—while we are on this earth.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p20" pid="xyk6ekvvpkKM5KSlde4iEw" hash="Cd9QYg">And the Lord said the following to Joseph Smith:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p21" pid="Dz0XqkRLIES7MoygWZIB6Q" hash="qj8uVw">“Know thou, my son, that all these things shall give thee experience, and shall be for thy good. …</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p22" pid="rtjOlLsxcEu5k5H7l1_sOw" hash="y0gTrg">“Therefore, <span class="emphasis">hold on thy way … ,</span> for God shall be with you forever and ever.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p23" pid="IcG0riVRI0qfLYUdYjGOCQ" hash="52EdPA">The trials of this earth—including illness and death—are a part of the plan of salvation and are inevitable experiences. It is necessary for us to “hold on [our] way” and accept our trials with faith.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p24" pid="4WKWIJz6hEu2MQ2mN_SwFA" hash="MkcHuw">However, the purpose of our lives is not merely to endure trials. Heavenly Father sent His Beloved Son, Jesus Christ, as our Savior and Redeemer so we could overcome the trials we face on this earth; in other words, He makes our weak things become strong,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> He atones for our sins and our imperfections, and He makes it possible for us to obtain immortality and eternal life.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p25" pid="4d-joU0NNUG3pPw5eXWHUw" hash="B6tJdw">President Henry B. Eyring stated: “The test a loving God has set before us is not to see if we can endure difficulty. It is to see if we can endure it well. We pass the test by showing that we remembered Him and the commandments He gave us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p26" pid="Vn7OaETciE6ejLWjJe23TQ" hash="kNZdHg">“Hold on thy way” is a key choice during times of trial. Turn your heart to God, especially when you face trials. Humbly obey the commandments of God. Show faith to reconcile your wishes with the will of God.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p27" pid="NmmREMa56kmGBs4jPjEXbw" hash="IjFi9Q">Let’s now consider that rear-end collision in Nagoya. I could have died in that accident. Nevertheless, through the Lord’s grace, I miraculously survived. And I know that my sufferings were for my learning and for my growth.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Heavenly Father schooled me to temper my impatience, to develop empathy, and to comfort those who are suffering. When I realized this, my heart was filled with feelings of thankfulness toward my Heavenly Father for this trial.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p28" pid="hsyNIXpxyUinPQbcq-nB_w" hash="6v9SkQ">Put God first, regardless of the trials you face. Love God. Have faith in Christ, and entrust yourself to Him in all things. Moroni makes the following promise to such people: “And if ye shall deny yourselves of all ungodliness, and love God with all your might, mind and strength, then is his grace sufficient for you, that by his grace ye may be perfect in Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way.p29" pid="g7B-uUj6KEGoE5mHDA47Zw" hash="e9OXJw">I sincerely testify that God the Father and His Beloved Son, Jesus Christ, live and that God’s promises to those who “hold on [their] way” and love Him will be fulfilled even in the midst of trials, in the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/10/hold-on-thy-way</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2015-general-conference/2015-10-5070-elder-koichi-aoyagi-64k-eng.mp3" length="5131110" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
