<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By L. Aldin Porter</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by L. Aldin Porter.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/L.%20Aldin%20Porter.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by L. Aldin Porter.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Oct 1987 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 1987 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Brethren</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Shortly after this call came to me, I was traveling by plane from Baton Rouge, Louisiana, to Salt Lake City. A young businessman stepped to my seat in the plane and introduced himself as a Latter-day Saint. He asked if I was traveling to attend meeti</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03219_000_026" doc-version="2" hash="HrPRNQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="zRGCB522DEOcFuu1XBpNqg" hash="lZRKvQ">Follow the Brethren</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="L9FQTf1diUWJRSCgyA9Byg" hash="kkWTWg">L. Aldin Porter</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2010.jpg" alt="Elder L. Aldin Porter" pid="yT0_m2cQZEKWD9UPa6fXmQ" hash="UxfvRg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p1" pid="15BMeHw0wEe2q3ZW6mxe0w" hash="6OjbBw">Shortly after this call came to me, I was traveling by plane from Baton Rouge, Louisiana, to Salt Lake City. A young businessman stepped to my seat in the plane and introduced himself as a Latter-day Saint. He asked if I was traveling to attend meetings, and I answered, “Yes.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p2" pid="b8ox7lFC2kOUHkQJDxFZtQ" hash="vIyLmQ">“Will you see President Benson?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p3" pid="66fwv2Vx3UmWFrFkG0doyA" hash="6seT8g">“I think that is unlikely in view of the nature of the meetings.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p4" pid="ysrcAAnqs0-XzFdjOmph1A" hash="wLj9sw">“When you see him, will you tell him that though we have never met, I have a deep love for him?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p5" pid="LPhQ0MmSiEOft-ETn_Jyhg" hash="Mq_sJA">He returned to his seat.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p6" pid="CkP3ryztikWg4g0_9GWHnw" hash="zmxUwA">It was late in the day; soon the lights were dimmed, giving me ample opportunity to think about that experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p7" pid="mO9bRXxsXEK9B8XCPBejEw" hash="oLSC3A">Brothers and sisters, there is great safety in having a love for the Brethren. As we traveled through the night, I remembered an experience that had come to me in this tabernacle some years ago. It was, I believe, the last time that President Joseph Fielding Smith spoke in a general priesthood meeting. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p8" pid="66xWwn_9tESo7zMy3oi8Sg" hash="_oETpA">“Now, brethren, I think there is one thing which we should have exceedingly clear in our minds. Neither the President of the Church, nor the First Presidency, nor the united voice of the First Presidency and the Twelve will ever lead the Saints astray or send forth counsel to the world that is contrary to the mind and will of the Lord” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> July 1972, p. 88).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p9" pid="JA3ipCtQU0-U0IChavDssw" hash="o7Fdzg">When President Smith made that statement, the Spirit bore witness to me that it was true. That same Spirit bears witness anew today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p10" pid="ixrNZGSEl0GoFDpj2Cv1zg" hash="GwrPpQ">President Spencer W. Kimball told the experience of a man who “rebelled against the call of Brigham Young to go to southern valleys, saying: ‘Nobody is going to tell me where to go and what to do!’ Through his personal rebellion, he took his entire family out of the Church. How little he retarded the colonization program! The valleys were settled in spite of him. How little his disaffection injured the Church! It has grown steadily without him. But how he has suffered in his eternal progression! In contrast, there were many who pulled up stakes, moved to new worlds, and reared families of faith and devotion” (in Conference Report, Apr. 1955, p. 94).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p11" pid="-0nRyOl2oUm-1OhL8sqUKg" hash="B1SqQQ">What can we do to help develop a love for the prophets, seers, and revelators? Permit me to make three suggestions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p12" pid="g5VtdslzP0G8wGlAkiz1BQ" hash="l1jN1Q">First, read the scriptures, especially the Book of Mormon. Speaking of the scriptures, the Prophet Joseph Smith said, “He who reads it oftenest will like it best, and he who is acquainted with it, will know the hand wherever he can see it” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 2:14).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p13" pid="kRi6WPBbVkC9G9kbG8r10w" hash="tP-eZQ">Let us read the scriptures, and we “will know the hand.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p14" pid="rWfvC55olUGIwgGCDQ3b7w" hash="LqO0ZQ">The same spirit that is felt while we read the word of the Lord in the scriptures accompanies the pronouncements of the Lord’s prophets. As we learn to love the word of the Lord as written in the scriptures, we will love the word of the Lord as given through his prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p15" pid="YvaV22YitkWzKNd-UuV-eg" hash="YPfS-A">Second, let us do as the prophets request. Note the words of the Savior:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p16" pid="fWOZq9Np-UGzz8x9lKc9oQ" hash="GiA66Q">“And the Jews marvelled, saying, How knoweth this man letters, having never learned?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p17" pid="Lo3nzGDPDEWEivc61TZQOg" hash="1eBe9w">“Jesus answered them, and said, My doctrine is not mine, but his that sent me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p18" pid="6qP1KguPtE6EmUBeZF54uw" hash="F4twWg">“If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it be of God, or whether I speak of myself” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/7.15-17" class="scriptureRef">John 7:15–17</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p19" pid="Wg3HI7xGuEa6s5ADoacMRw" hash="s4Lz1w">President Benson, in April Conference, 1986, said, “The Book of Mormon has not been, nor is it yet, the center of our personal study, family teaching, preaching, and missionary work. Of this we must repent” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1986, pp. 5–6).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p20" pid="LvypaRE7nU2kVb1Dhhw4lQ" hash="9lpM-g">Brothers and sisters, let us do as the prophet asks, and in a little time we will know that he speaks the word of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p21" pid="fiVMIGH5gk2QQlBPlXX7lQ" hash="qfNo6Q">Third, pray for them. Call down the blessings of heaven upon the heads of the prophets, seers, and revelators. Know that the Lord responds to the sustaining prayers of the Saints. In addition, as our hearts go out to the brethren in sincere prayer, our hearts will be filled with love for them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p22" pid="1VwiqnrkK0-YuwyofXxC1w" hash="oqwmSA">There is safety in loving the Brethren. What kind of safety? The Master concluded the Sermon on the Mount as recorded in both Matthew and 3 Nephi with the following statement:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p23" pid="1LNi24Y2bUyFB92TvUwRyQ" hash="Y_ioIA">“Whoso heareth these sayings of mine and doeth them, I will liken him unto a wise man, who built his house upon a rock—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p24" pid="jCQaH3FE8E6T4Ersv3vyuw" hash="boT1ww">“And the rain descended, and the floods came, and the winds blew, and beat upon that house; and it fell not, for it was founded upon a rock.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p25" pid="Hlbk2ucm1kqYMzZsSwS-5g" hash="P440Ew">“And every one that heareth these sayings of mine and doeth them not shall be likened unto a foolish man, who built his house upon the sand—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p26" pid="7ReM-P_MUE-QDMmybR0xHA" hash="__hz3w">“And the rain descended, and the floods came, and the winds blew, and beat upon that house; and it fell, and great was the fall of it” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/14.24-27" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 14:24–27</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p27" pid="dlxwYqGPi0ySO_ch7ZKh6w" hash="0Ke_Hg">Did you note, brothers and sisters, that the rain descended and the floods came and the winds blew upon <span class="emphasis">both</span> houses? Just because we follow the word of the Lord does not mean we will suffer no ill winds; it does mean that we will spiritually survive them!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p28" pid="bamnVJEv_USJeubDvrJhwQ" hash="AphuYw">The prophet Mormon counseled us in great power on the subject of prophets when he said, “Wo unto him that shall deny the revelations of the Lord, and that shall say the Lord no longer worketh by revelation, or by prophecy, or by gifts, or by tongues, or by healings, or by the power of the Holy Ghost!” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/29.6" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 29:6</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p29" pid="2Td1xSeC_E6WMx9YmNdH5g" hash="OvFD9g">Priesthood leaders, do you want to raise the spiritual level of your stewardship? Follow the Brethren.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p30" pid="TaHYx51BkE-yjkzpA4onfw" hash="k2DrRA">Husbands, do you want your wives to have more confidence in you and your leadership? Follow the Brethren.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p31" pid="IScckc7Hg0yDdpuRK1H_Pg" hash="rjU0HA">Parents, do you want your children to feel your love and more willingly accept your direction? Love the Brethren.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p32" pid="JxwGoDRsFk6N4VceU_GJ-w" hash="hY76gQ">We have in this conference heard what the Lord would have us know. What has been said and what will yet be said should be studied and pondered and prayed over, and followed. Leave no question in anyone’s mind where you stand. Declare in quiet tones that you love the Brethren and that you are going to follow them. Add exclamation marks to your words as you quietly and faithfully follow the Brethren.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren.p33" pid="EaSlfu1Es0CclUJO5k9Dig" hash="V1wZCA">You will find that you will “enjoy the words of eternal life in this world, and eternal life in the world to come” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/6.59" class="scriptureRef">Moses 6:59</a>). I am a witness that this is the work of God. There is a prophet in our midst, even President Ezra Taft Benson, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1987/10/follow-the-brethren</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1987-general-conference/1987-10-5020-elder-l-aldin-porter-64k-eng.mp3" length="3912887" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 1987 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“A Disciple of Jesus Christ”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder L. Tom Perry made reference this afternoon to additional millions and millions of people who now may hear the glorious message of the restored gospel. The Lord has, in the recent past, opened the doors of nations long denied the blessings of go</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_92905_000_022" doc-version="2" hash="8Z_U2w">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="EPf3cWjnbUqwik_y5smvKw" hash="4OJktw">“A Disciple of Jesus Christ”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="G2RFYSPMcUWqgTFb7zlNoQ" hash="kkWTWg">L. Aldin Porter</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2010.jpg" alt="Elder L. Aldin Porter" pid="-jf9VqnVKk-KzAYC3euK8A" hash="UxfvRg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p1" pid="NFPO_6MHu0iFaygdKHoI_g" hash="ctBJWQ">Elder L. Tom Perry made reference this afternoon to additional millions and millions of people who now may hear the glorious message of the restored gospel. The Lord has, in the recent past, opened the doors of nations long denied the blessings of gospel covenants. Elder Perry reissued the Lord’s clarion call for every worthy young man to serve a mission. With a deep desire to in no way detract from his clear and urgent message, I would like to ask the question, What kind of missionaries must they be?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p2" pid="iGkBQp9VLEGUjpe6l8ewmQ" hash="eOEu6w">The Church was less than eighteen months old when the Lord encouraged the early Saints by saying: “Wherefore, be not weary in well-doing, for ye are laying the foundation of a great work. And out of small things proceedeth that which is great.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p3" pid="EJBoR17y0UqSA7lDf9rLTg" hash="X6rgKw">“Behold, the Lord requireth the heart and a willing mind” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.33-34" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:33–34</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p4" pid="zS6ObKCUA0u5mNmOCEZbZQ" hash="1SMI0Q">Missionaries who have willing minds are needed in the field.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p5" pid="631TZoQmbkeBabZM4L_cdg" hash="IqhFXQ">Let me share with you the recorded feelings of one who had a willing mind. Elder Heber C. Kimball recorded: “The Prophet Joseph came to me … and … said, ‘Brother Heber, the Spirit of the Lord has whispered to me: “Let my servant Heber go to England and proclaim my Gospel, and open the door of salvation to that nation.”’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p6" pid="MbL1F8F8k0SvvosvVcfl8w" hash="EL-gTQ">The thought was overpowering. “O, Lord,” wrote Elder Kimball, “I am a man of stammering tongue, and altogether unfit for such a work; how can I go to preach in that land, which is so famed throughout Christendom for learning, knowledge and piety; the nursery of religion; and to a people whose intelligence is proverbial!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p7" pid="_V0jxQ3zu0SOtE4N6WtOOw" hash="CuAL-Q">Note this: “However, all these considerations did not deter me from the path of duty; the moment I understood the will of my Heavenly Father, I felt a determination to go at all hazards, believing that He would support me by His almighty power, and endow me with every qualification that I needed.” (In Orson F. Whitney, <span class="emphasis">Life of Heber C. Kimball, </span>3d ed., Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1967, pp. 103–4.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p8" pid="lA2cBokKgUiqpr6KD_Vqiw" hash="hT-zdQ">Many months passed; this man of strong determination to duty had completed his mission and was about to return to his home:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p9" pid="Vran6pdaYEyVkPw_gX3WCQ" hash="wDj1_g">“On the morning when I left Chatburn many were in tears, thinking they should see my face no more. When I left them, my feelings were such as I cannot describe. As I walked down the street I was followed by numbers; the doors were crowded by the inmates of the houses to bid me farewell, who could only give vent to their grief in sobs. … While contemplating this scene I was constrained to take off my hat, for I felt as if the place was holy ground. The Spirit of the Lord rested down upon me and I was constrained to bless that whole region of country. … My heart was like unto theirs, and I thought my head was a fountain of tears, for I wept for several miles after I bid them adieu.” (Ibid., p. 187.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p10" pid="LlooNs_wN0a73aZmeUbzBw" hash="c4B6eA">The Lord needs missionaries with a willing heart and mind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p11" pid="kRbDr882FUu6RsStjpZW8Q" hash="p6cIUg">Truly effective missionaries have many talents, varied and beautiful, but one quality they all seem to have is the ability to stick with their commitments—that is, the power to <span class="emphasis">do</span> what they agree to do. They tell themselves to get up in the morning, on time, and do it. They don’t depend on companions, district leaders, or anyone else. They commit to the mission president that they will follow the gospel study program every morning and not run out of steam in a few days. They understand that the Lord has called them to teach and testify, baptize and build the kingdom in His name, and they are happily at their work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p12" pid="uXppCdKlZEST3tBARDATDA" hash="asqbbQ">From whence came this power to make a decision and stay with it? I would suggest to you it came, in most cases, long before they arrive in the mission field.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p13" pid="NB6sysTrHUWr9Qb6XbK6wg" hash="OcT1LQ">Eighteen months ago, President Thomas S. Monson spoke at the general priesthood meeting concerning a very important message. It has been published for all of us in a pamphlet called <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth. </span>Permit me to read a short paragraph: “Some people knowingly break God’s commandments. They plan to repent before they go on a mission or receive the sacred covenants and ordinances of the temple. Repentance for such behavior is difficult and painful and may take a long time. It is better to not commit the sin. Certain sins are of such gravity that they can put your membership in the Church and your eternal life at risk. Sexual sins are among those of such seriousness.” (<span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth,</span> Salt Lake City: The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, 1990, p. 17.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p14" pid="Z2KyrRtC-0yjKPt9hAeQjQ" hash="1lcsXQ">It is my judgment that some of our youth <span class="emphasis">do not believe </span>that repentance for serious transgression “is difficult and painful and may take a long time.” Where has this grave misunderstanding come from?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p15" pid="JvhHCGyrhUmXFXn3FSBcUQ" hash="QtXl0w">To you young people, if any of us who are older have given you the impression that it isn’t too serious to disobey the commandments of God, forgive us. Listen carefully to the words of the Lord through a prophet, even King Benjamin:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p16" pid="K7LRUqDJdkuiFVE7cfWRfg" hash="DlTCbQ">“And now, I say unto you, my brethren, that after ye have known and have been taught all these things, if ye should transgress and go contrary to that which has been spoken, that ye do withdraw yourselves from the Spirit of the Lord, that it may have no place in you to guide you in wisdom’s paths that ye may be blessed, prospered, and preserved—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p17" pid="AqZ-PtHTQ0CZYtwtdyLRkA" hash="BwJSlg">“I say unto you, that the man that doeth this, the same cometh out in open rebellion against God; therefore he listeth to obey the evil spirit, and becometh an enemy to all righteousness; therefore, the Lord has no place in him, for he dwelleth not in unholy temples.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.36-37" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2:36–37</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p18" pid="r6GNbsjb80Kh3L6x7MltKg" hash="AFSoIA">Far better that we diligently strive to keep ourselves clean of these serious transgressions. Some have not done so, and gratefully there is a way of escape. But it “is difficult and painful and may take a long time.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p19" pid="fqdYP8mnVUWLn6DoobvY0Q" hash="OKCceA">Note the words of the Lord Himself as He remembers the cost of our transgressions and points us to that deliverance:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p20" pid="qlCG7K-mGkW11yvTOBFFxg" hash="f58XPA">“Therefore I command you to repent—repent, lest I smite you by the rod of my mouth, and by my wrath, and by my anger, and your sufferings be sore—how sore you know not, how exquisite you know not, yea, how hard to bear you know not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p21" pid="OqddMQ5W00a9VdK40QphAQ" hash="1zQS0w">“For behold, I, God, have suffered these things for all, that they might not suffer if they would repent;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p22" pid="bKhm8Eh-9EWXHmsRuN6uOA" hash="lQavKQ">“But if they would not repent they must suffer even as I;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p23" pid="BgPstPZjHU-KObmUKu9Qkw" hash="0WGrkA">“Which suffering caused myself, even God, the greatest of all, to tremble because of pain, and to bleed at every pore, and to suffer both body and spirit.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/19.15-18" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 19:15–18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p24" pid="CZ1Hv89BXk2KyW2IJayclQ" hash="q37eCw">Young men, you must live righteously for many reasons. One of them is that you must be accompanied by the Spirit of the Lord as you labor in the mission field. The association of the Spirit of the Lord is dependent upon personal righteousness. If you do not strive diligently for the assistance of the Spirit, you will find your missionary work extremely difficult and your results very disappointing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p25" pid="qmajyxRbTE-FFGDqHi-SUQ" hash="kqm_hg">President Benson’s counsel is very clear: “Our preaching and our teaching must be by the power of the Holy Ghost. We must ever remember that in this glorious work, the most essential element is the Spirit” (<span class="emphasis">The Teachings of Ezra Taft Benson, </span>Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1988, p. 313.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p26" pid="AJSKliYET0eSNOkDvTS6jg" hash="7FSIkg">Listen also to the words of the Lord as He speaks of His emissaries: “Wherefore, I call upon the weak things of the world, those who are unlearned and despised, to thrash the nations by the power of my Spirit;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p27" pid="5Gof6UTxfUaj67N03snFRg" hash="X9LUOA">“And their arm shall be my arm, and I will be their shield and their buckler; and I will gird up their loins, and they shall fight manfully for me.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/35.13-14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 35:13–14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p28" pid="GddAhFyIwUmhcDT_IVp__Q" hash="9LHGng">Let your desire be to join this magnificent army marching arm in arm with companions to “fight manfully” for Him, accompanied by the Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p29" pid="-vI2isqd5E6WrWJheJ90ng" hash="NGR-Og">Priesthood leaders, let us be careful that we do not permit young missionaries to go into the mission field with unresolved transgression. It is literally like going into battle without helmet, sword, or shield. Let us remember that it takes time to develop the power to resist the fires of temptation. It takes time to receive the sweet comfort that always comes to the heart of the truly penitent. Allow them sufficient time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p30" pid="gT3QHV2T2E2JkBUpKe24DA" hash="VIMqiA">In addition, there is a broader issue. Time will permit just a reference to it. But our success in this endeavor will have eternal consequences for more than the missionary and the convert.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p31" pid="CxRr4GbCdUyXPYWb0JMTjg" hash="6CpCDw">Elder Boyd K. Packer has reminded us that “the safety of the Church in generations ahead rests on our success in calling missionaries. If we have concern for the future of this work, we will not rest until every able-bodied young man is made worthy and desires to receive a call to a mission.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign, </span>Mar. 1985, p. 10.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p32" pid="Giwk-gAatUmVoousrg1BYQ" hash="yoNtpw">The Lord is calling for worthy, willing workers to labor in His harvest fields.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p33" pid="uwTMlpQ8IUqHKadHPm7-2g" hash="c_-gJA">My beloved young men, will you consider what it would mean to you if you could join the prophet Mormon in saying: “Behold, I am a disciple of Jesus Christ, the Son of God. I have been called of him to declare his word among his people, that they might have everlasting life” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/5.13" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 5:13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ.p34" pid="Ph9yC2dV4kyoOFbJoGgL8w" hash="0Pii4w">I am a witness that the Lord Jesus Christ is the Son of God and the Savior of the world. It is my deep conviction that He has called us to teach and testify in His name before the world. And to you young brethren, my sincere prayer is that you will respond to His call with a willing mind and worthy heart, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1992/04/a-disciple-of-jesus-christ</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1992-general-conference/1992-04-3040-elder-l-aldin-porter-64k-eng.mp3" length="5703763" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 1992 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Revelations of Heaven</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven?lang=eng</link>
      <description>A few years ago I was in a Salt Lake hospital emergency room with my sons and a neighbor boy—the result of a backyard touch football game.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_94911_000_025" doc-version="2" hash="JxJaHw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="mFS7qRvFWkyDjOOnDLcp0w" hash="bKp7vw">The Revelations of Heaven</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="r15lW2DmekmlzN8CvnXAzA" hash="kkWTWg">L. Aldin Porter</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2010.jpg" alt="Elder L. Aldin Porter" pid="Lr2kmHiCBkmhYIQM09d4yg" hash="UxfvRg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p1" pid="uPIiG3guokeFCfopmpccCA" hash="IqNStg">A few years ago I was in a Salt Lake hospital emergency room with my sons and a neighbor boy—the result of a backyard touch football game.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p2" pid="bdLA5h8zA0CmwAl6EvzLSg" hash="koWY0Q">While we waited in the emergency room for the doctor to put one of the participants back together, we saw a young lady brought into the hospital. She may have been seventeen—tall, willowy, well dressed, and having a wild reaction to an overdose of drugs. While we watched, she collapsed, and I thought, There is no way this child can survive this experience. I wondered how she had come to this sad situation in her life. Had she not heard the words of the prophets? Had she heard them and laughed as if they were the warnings of men out of touch with the realities of a modern world? Had one of us been negligent in our opportunities to teach her? Had her parents known the truth but not been willing or able to help her understand?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p3" pid="waGX0NdKg0Om1nehfeWDDA" hash="Bl01AQ">While waiting in that hospital thinking, pondering, and praying for her, I recalled a principle the Lord teaches us in the 89th section of the Doctrine and Covenants. It is found in the fourth verse:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p4" pid="sNDBi5Kmz02RgQgf8wh8fQ" hash="08NS0w">“Behold, verily, thus saith the Lord unto you: In consequence of evils and designs which do and will exist in the hearts of conspiring men in the last days, I have warned you, and forewarn you, by giving unto you this word of wisdom by revelation.” [<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/89.4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 89:4</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p5" pid="euQFim38VEadlFhP37Q-dg" hash="g0VlVA">Consider carefully the principle: “I have warned you, and forewarn you, … by revelation.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p6" pid="nAz-ofMJVEq45qPHhoe50A" hash="ooCJdA">We in this church stand before the world, in all humility and sincerity, and declare that Joseph Smith, Jr., was raised up by the Lord Jesus Christ and appointed to be the mortal instrument through which the doctrines, powers, keys, priesthood, and ordinances were restored to the earth. Since that day there has been a continual flow of revelation through those who have followed as the Lord’s appointed Apostles and prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p7" pid="sT-FsAkgSkyA485pzKXcJQ" hash="7eGeAA">Yesterday we sustained Howard W. Hunter as the President of the Church and as the prophet, seer, and revelator. I wonder if we have any concept of the importance of that event. It is worth some pondering and some praying. But let me point out that President Hunter has sat as one of those men who hold this sacred revelatory power for thirty-five years. He whom the Lord has called and we have sustained is not a novice in the principles, process, and practice of receiving divine direction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p8" pid="nTUXtX02m0aVPLk3BNgunA" hash="XSCW5A">There is a question that each of us must deal with in a most solemn and serious way if our lives are to be what the Father of us all would have them be: “What is our response when the living prophets declare the mind and the will of the Lord?” This is the test of mankind in every dispensation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p9" pid="hbd3706Ot0SgyGJsO0rYiw" hash="xM1OVg">I sat in this tabernacle some years ago as President Joseph Fielding Smith stood at this pulpit. It was the general priesthood meeting of April 1972, the last general conference before President Smith passed away. He said: “There is one thing which we should have exceedingly clear in our minds. Neither the President of the Church, nor the First Presidency, nor the united voice of the First Presidency and the Twelve will ever lead the Saints astray or send forth counsel to the world that is contrary to the mind and will of the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p10" pid="_G-uCblPCkymd99DO7_G-Q" hash="Nfx-vQ">There came to me that evening a witness of the Spirit that he spoke the truth. I felt an overwhelming sense of peace and assurance that the Lord loved us and would not leave us without direction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p11" pid="8D1Ga5iKfUe0RkF2fRkkvw" hash="Wd18yw">President J. Reuben Clark, Jr., drew a very important distinction concerning revelation from the Lord:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p12" pid="W9yUAA9-5EeoIAedwL3W2Q" hash="wM8tuw">“Some of the General Authorities have had assigned to them a special calling; they possess a special gift; they are sustained as prophets, seers, and revelators, which gives them a special spiritual endowment in connection with their teaching of the people. They have the right, the power, and authority to declare the mind and will of God to his people, subject to the over-all power and authority of the President of the Church.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p13" pid="ByVHxiDVK0agfhmobaarIQ" hash="dmazXQ">President Clark continues: “Others of the General Authorities are not given this special spiritual endowment and authority covering their teaching; they have a resulting limitation, and the resulting limitation upon their power and authority in teaching applies to every other officer and member of the Church, for none of them is spiritually endowed as a prophet, seer, and revelator.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p14" pid="SuAp9gOfKEaM4NE0jprXEg" hash="SrvQjw">I emphasize that the rest of us do not have that specific power and authority. The Seventy have an endowment that is uniquely theirs; temple presidents and matrons, stake presidents and bishops, as well as fathers and mothers, have an endowment that is uniquely theirs; but none of us has the power, authority, or responsibility that is given to the First Presidency and the Twelve.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p15" pid="10mSR4FtfkqC_J0ikAlzVA" hash="VRZKDQ">You may wonder why I stress this point so strongly. It is because a misunderstanding here can cause us deep pain and can be the means of misleading many others. Those who claim similar powers often declare that they are doing it with purity of heart and with total sincerity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p16" pid="KE0m7JT3FkeD5YA9nOVJng" hash="2MZxyw">One’s intentions may be of the purest kind. The sincerity may be total and complete. Nevertheless, pure intentions and heartfelt sincerity do not give members of the Church authority to declare doctrine which is not sustained by the living prophets. While we are members of the Church, we are not authorized to <span class="emphasis">publicly declare</span> our speculations as doctrine nor to extend doctrinal positions to other conclusions based upon the reasoning of men and women, even by the brightest and most well-read among us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p17" pid="z-Els18hwEWigPJeYaUyLA" hash="_HQuHw">The prophets are not only called to receive the doctrine and direct the ordinances through the keys they hold. They are also responsible to keep the saving doctrine pure so that people can hear and feel that doctrine in its sure and certain form.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p18" pid="bOc6VT1u-069xamAo6735g" hash="QlW3ZQ">Occasionally we have those who become a law unto themselves in these matters. Sadly, their pride leads them down a road which President Spencer W. Kimball warned us about: “Apostasy usually begins with question and doubt and criticism. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p19" pid="EeahLQNsREqR-N2lSA2jiQ" hash="aK9TvQ">“They who garnish the sepulchres of the dead prophets begin now by stoning the living ones. They return to the pronouncements of the dead leaders and interpret them to be incompatible with present programs. They convince themselves that there are discrepancies between the practices of the deceased and the leaders of the present. … They allege love for the gospel and the Church but charge that leaders are a little ‘off the beam’! … Next they say that while the gospel and the Church are divine, the leaders are fallen. Up to this time it may be a passive thing, but now it becomes an active resistance, and frequently the blooming apostate begins to air his views and to crusade. … He now begins to expect persecution and adopts a martyr complex, and when finally excommunication comes he associates himself with other apostates to develop and strengthen cults. At this stage he is likely to claim revelation for himself, revelations from the Lord directing him in his interpretations and his actions. These manifestations are superior to anything from living leaders, he claims.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p20" pid="BFm1aBeDA0q_ezliTcZQlA" hash="VGB3cg">Almost without exception, as one finds himself or herself walking the road President Kimball just outlined, there will be priesthood leaders who will counsel and advise and even admonish the person. Many heed the counsel, but some do not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p21" pid="DkZS-PjB8UOXpnrO15t1Iw" hash="rF2kag">Counseling comes not just for our own benefit but for the blessing of those who might be misled by something we might say or do. I have been deeply grateful to my brethren that they have cared enough to speak to me, on occasion, in plain words.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p22" pid="Evdjnhv570yPrUC0Y-889g" hash="nwMiqw">Surrounded as we are by worldly influences, how can we maintain a sweetness of spirit and a humility that will make us receptive to such counsel? I fear that we have become so enamored with recreation, with fame and fortune, with videos, with television, and with what money can buy that we have little time for eternal things. We cannot take the time to obtain a knowledge of the doctrines of eternity—for that requires sacrifice, effort, and struggle. Furthermore, we have learned to live in a world of clamor and noise and haste and hurry to the extent that we have often become immune to the Spirit of the Lord and the “peaceable things of the kingdom.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p23" pid="ZvMDW2bT70OkYr8iCRy63A" hash="0f9eQQ">How do we prepare ourselves to be in harmony with the First Presidency and the Council of the Twelve?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p24" pid="Blv91qkYI0--ONrymc1SlQ" hash="9knX7Q">On one occasion during the Savior’s mortal ministry, he was challenged by those who were opposing him. They wondered how a person could speak with such certainty without the education of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p25" pid="ELw0tyufjUGvEVVUfJQDig" hash="1eBe9w">“Jesus answered them, and said, My doctrine is not mine, but his that sent me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p26" pid="l-MRu6GHtkCGLK0GzZvuCQ" hash="bRP9Ug">“If any man will <span class="emphasis">do</span> his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it be of God, or whether I speak of myself.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p27" pid="Jy-BnI7kqECXVQ2zo_3OMQ" hash="WzbUIQ">We must learn the will of our Father in Heaven by earnest study. Next, we must act upon it. Study alone is not sufficient; we must act upon the words of revelation before we know of a surety of the truthfulness of the doctrines. On the day the Church was organized in 1830, the Lord gave a wonderful promise to those <span class="emphasis">who labor in the vineyard:</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p28" pid="HM2q0nbxlU6m7eu0shTGTw" hash="QgFTfw">“For, behold, I will bless all those <span class="emphasis">who labor in my vineyard</span> with a mighty blessing, and <span class="emphasis">they shall</span><span class="emphasis">believe on his [Joseph Smith’s] words,</span> which are given him through me by the Comforter, which manifesteth that Jesus was crucified by sinful men for the sins of the world, yea, for the remission of sins unto the contrite heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p29" pid="7j4CLeztaEK-8nCeXG1omQ" hash="rbxYCA">If we will follow, with diligence, the counsel and instruction that is the united voice of these Brethren, we will know of the doctrine, whether it be of God or whether they speak of themselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p30" pid="bIgVXRAtL0y-dCjRRcEJiA" hash="9sN7yQ">In all solemnity and soberness—with a clear understanding of the consequences of a testimony borne in this setting—may I state that God has made known to me in an unmistakable way that he has called and he sustains those who are the living prophets, seers, and revelators. The Lord God of Israel will direct them, and they will not lead us astray. When you see any document, any address, any letter, any instruction that is issued by the Council of the First Presidency and the Quorum of the Twelve, it should be recognized for what it surely is—the mind and the will of the Lord to his people in this day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p31" pid="ehxnp1HMk06C3kdGXOsKkw" hash="0MqnuA">We do not need greater prophets. We need listening ears. We need hearts that are sufficiently pure that we can <span class="emphasis">feel</span> their words. We need souls that will commit to the keeping of our covenants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p32" pid="m0jH_UW2eEaLSd8zc2OLHg" hash="iA_Ynw">My prayer is that each of us may have that watershed experience of life of having the Spirit carry with power—even fire—to our souls the assurance that we are being directed by His appointed servants. I pray that there will enter our hearts the peace that comes from knowing by a power beyond all human ability to transmit that God is aware of us and has raised up servants in our day to lead us under the power and inspiration of his close attention.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven.p33" pid="Pa5o-XHfjkG3guRiifLftQ" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1994/10/the-revelations-of-heaven</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1994-general-conference/1994-10-4030-elder-l-aldin-porter-64k-eng.mp3" length="6201238" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 1994 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Spirit of Prophecy</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy?lang=eng</link>
      <description>One hundred seventy-six years ago, an event occurred which lies at the very foundation of the Restoration of the gospel in these latter days. It is, in my judgment, the most significant event that has occurred in this world since the Son of God walke</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_96911_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="xwiHjA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="PvDmzNBwWE2o3BB1-BSLBg" hash="WBAVsw">The Spirit of Prophecy</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="pIhdTSe4jUOrgXoX1gcWnw" hash="kkWTWg">L. Aldin Porter</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2010.jpg" alt="Elder L. Aldin Porter" pid="qDRvIpZN0Uu6yU1nVZJ6eQ" hash="UxfvRg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p1" pid="nRlk0a3zO0669_aDOpg_Rg" hash="tmAIyA">One hundred seventy-six years ago, an event occurred which lies at the very foundation of the Restoration of the gospel in these latter days. It is, in my judgment, the most significant event that has occurred in this world since the Son of God walked forth from the tomb a resurrected being. I refer to that first heavenly vision that came to the Prophet Joseph Smith. Let me read his words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p2" pid="s-sW49acnkmehnWtMSrSOA" hash="-7b7gA">“It was on the morning of a beautiful, clear day, early in the spring of eighteen hundred and twenty. It was the first time in my life that I had made such an attempt, for amidst all my anxieties I had never as yet made the attempt to pray vocally.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p3" pid="EO58zLY6lE-T_sQc6b9b0w" hash="LpWv_A">“After I had retired to the place where I had previously designed to go, having looked around me, and finding myself alone, I kneeled down and began to offer up the desires of my heart to God.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p4" pid="G27YdtslbUSffpCWR_50Lg" hash="cO7Naw">He then described a few moments of severe spiritual anguish, convincing him that the forces of evil were real and powerful. Then he continued:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p5" pid="A4KqJM3rsEyozMnVqJzVBQ" hash="U_btDw">“I saw a pillar of light exactly over my head, above the brightness of the sun, which descended gradually until it fell upon me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p6" pid="uwR01gygUkiE7iZA8iBQLg" hash="-dFjAA">“It no sooner appeared than I found myself delivered from the enemy which held me bound. When the light rested upon me I saw two Personages, whose brightness and glory defy all description, standing above me in the air. One of them spake unto me, calling me by name and said, pointing to the other—<span class="emphasis">This is My Beloved Son. Hear Him!”</span><span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p7" pid="nh8HN-k2fkyH27z_RH4PMQ" hash="YEZLZQ">That single event changed the future of the world. The appearance of the Father and the Son to the young prophet ushered in the dispensation of the fulness of times. It exemplified God’s love for His children and changed the world forever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p8" pid="ljTB_uA-o0K_t1xC4tZ90w" hash="uFiM-Q">How can one know of a surety that Joseph Smith actually saw and conversed with the Father and the Son? How can one ascertain the truthfulness of our bold assertion that God speaks to the world today through His prophets? God has provided a way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p9" pid="7QjluldaXUOXsvvyw2X9Ug" hash="pDvQlA">Speaking of the supernal glory of that First Vision, President Gordon B. Hinckley has said: “Much has been written, much will be written, in an effort to explain it away. The finite mind cannot comprehend it. But the testimony of the Holy Spirit, experienced by countless numbers of people all through the years since it happened, bears witness that it is true, that it happened as Joseph Smith said it happened, that it was as real as the sunrise over Palmyra, that it is an essential foundation stone, a cornerstone, without which the Church could not be ‘fitly framed together.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p10" pid="I2dm3G8ib0K2GNAkVgZReA" hash="4vwPhw">I repeat: the testimony of the Holy Spirit bears witness that it is true. That testimony is the means, in most instances, by which God reveals truth to mankind. It is not a new or strange phenomenon but is as old as the human race. The scriptures are replete with examples of God communicating with man. By revelation Adam and Enoch and Noah and Abraham and Moses and all of the faithful former-day Saints came to know of sacred things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p11" pid="vOsEF3NS7kO-xYJ7K5bd9w" hash="pd9D3w">Nephi of ancient days taught this principle to his people. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p12" pid="y9l6OOOhDEGQuB-b0X-WpQ" hash="SONGUQ">“And now I, Nephi, cannot write all the things which were taught among my people; neither am I mighty in writing, like unto speaking; for when a man speaketh by the power of the Holy Ghost the power of the Holy Ghost carrieth it unto the hearts of the children of men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p13" pid="n2uv5FH4X0CGvshyHR8hJA" hash="RbSN1w">“But behold, there are many that harden their hearts against the Holy Spirit, that it hath no place in them; wherefore, they cast many things away which are written and esteem them as things of naught.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p14" pid="bO8CATD81kudAn8ZOV2YvA" hash="6bZMfA">The Holy Spirit does not teach the proud, the unteachable, the indolent, or the doubter. A deep desire for truth and faith in the Lord Jesus Christ will prepare one’s heart to be taught spiritual things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p15" pid="M-sT7886xkyLEOcFdOHP-g" hash="7vfFkw">The Lord Jesus Christ directs His work on the earth by revelation through the Holy Spirit. The power of this revelatory Spirit moves and motivates an army of more than 52,000 missionaries who take the gospel message to the four corners of the earth. When they are successful in their work, it is because of the witness they bear, a witness accompanied and confirmed by the power of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p16" pid="fVvy1tISqUWUIgG6kR_tow" hash="vHiixQ">The Lord describes His emissaries as weak, unlearned, and despised. But He promises that through their efforts He will “thrash the nations by the power of [His] Spirit.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p17" pid="NyoIm1z4WU2QE7b91KeaYA" hash="AwxKIQ">When President Hinckley returned from the British Isles last fall, he told us of an interview he had with a member of the British Broadcasting Company Radio Services. The reporter asked President Hinckley, “How do you expect people to listen to these callow youth?” President Hinckley had to explain to some of us that <span class="emphasis">callow</span> meant immature, inexperienced, and lacking sophistication. Then he pointed out to this reporter that “people do receive them and listen to them. They are wholesome. They are bright, they are alert, they are … clean.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p18" pid="amyTOOstnUmXsAfW1Whmww" hash="wtbF-w">And then at the general conference priesthood session held in October of last year, he said, speaking of the missionaries: “They are a miracle. … They speak out of their hearts, with personal conviction. Each is … an ambassador of the Lord Jesus Christ. Their power comes not of their learning in the things of the world. Their power comes of faith, and prayer, and humility.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p19" pid="3Yilmawctkq6yubkIteydw" hash="QyENjw">Jesus’ commandment to preach the gospel to all nations is obeyed as the servants of God bear testimony, in humility, across the earth. And the Lord responds to their sacrifices and bears witness of their words by revelation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p20" pid="5K3pn5Bt2kuph4JyC6OMHQ" hash="Fmk4Sg">Some years ago I enjoyed a stake conference assignment as a junior companion to Elder LeGrand Richards, who had, under the influence of this directing Spirit, reorganized a stake presidency. We were driving home; he was very pensive. After a rather long period of silence, I asked him if there was something he would like to teach me. Quietly he said, “We have too many in the Church who deny the spirit of prophecy and of revelation.” That was it—he said no more about it. As I reminisced about the calling of the new stake president that day, it occurred to me then that this Church could not function for even one day without the spirit of prophecy and revelation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p21" pid="ytKiYv2n2Ey9U8ehLcM6bA" hash="rpCOlw">But ours is a day of dwindling faith and increasing skepticism about sacred things. Our time reminds me of the period just prior to the coming of the resurrected Savior to this continent. They were very dark days.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p22" pid="aY2vU29Dl0GNHjigdIvNmg" hash="AFgu_g">Mormon recorded the roots of the problems that beset Nephite society when he said, “And it was because of the pride of their hearts, because of their exceeding riches, yea, it was because of their oppression to the poor, withholding their food from the hungry, withholding their clothing from the naked, and smiting their humble brethren upon the cheek, making a mock of that which was sacred, denying the spirit of prophecy and of revelation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p23" pid="O52GyBibUUGrFymAuL6epQ" hash="Z8MDUA">Later Mormon continues: “And because of their iniquity the church had begun to dwindle; and they began to disbelieve in the spirit of prophecy and in the spirit of revelation; and the judgments of God did stare them in the face.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p24" pid="Z7XpSftKbECRHaTkviJbNQ" hash="_p_XFA">We boldly assert that the spirit of revelation rests upon the Lord’s living prophets, seers, and revelators.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p25" pid="S85e20aPuk-WTmUwmFS5Qw" hash="G_GzMQ">President Spencer W. Kimball from this very pulpit bore his testimony when he said: “I say, in the deepest of humility, but also by the power and force of a burning testimony in my soul, that from the prophet of the Restoration to the prophet of our own year, the communication line is unbroken, the authority is continuous, and light, brilliant and penetrating, continues to shine. The sound of the voice of the Lord is a continuous melody and a thunderous appeal.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p26" pid="bdSHCI_4QEeMkjFNSdZ6Vw" hash="x1WpsA">When the appointed servants of this Church speak under the influence of the Holy Ghost as ambassadors of the Lord Jesus Christ, their words are carried by the power of the Spirit to those whose hearts are open to revelation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p27" pid="7cAZvvtrY0yWAc7iT65sYA" hash="zvlNWw">When, with heavenly power, that witness comes to a person, he or she will soon understand that personal sacrifice is its constant companion. The spiritual witness of these sacred things and the demands of sacrifice inevitably walk the road together. In time, one comes to understand the necessity of this and is filled with gratitude that it is so.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p28" pid="N4VsdWiGzEC05jkRjEDdkw" hash="TUONfw">The most important knowledge to be gained in this life is that which comes by revelation through the Holy Spirit. This is not to belittle in any way information available in a multitude of disciplines or fields of study. But any of it individually or all of it together can never equal the importance of receiving the personal witness, borne on the wings of the Spirit, of sacred things. That witness brings light and certainty and peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p29" pid="sl7QMXpfr0iqjINbR35BEg" hash="2jTDMQ">I raise my voice and state again that Joseph Smith saw the Father and the Son. This certain knowledge is independent of all mortal men, for this conviction has come to me by the Holy Spirit, as promised.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p30" pid="NlLGekUJeUypr8cEOei2fw" hash="nvrWoA">The kingdom of God on earth continues to move forward with dedicated missionary and member alike having the conviction confirmed by the Holy Ghost that Joseph Smith saw God our Father and His Son Jesus Christ. It moves forward empowered by the assurance in the heart of each faithful member, individually, that those who lead us do so with the spirit of prophecy and revelation. We must never lose this precious gift. We must pay whatever price of faith and obedience is required to retain this great blessing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy.p31" pid="BQdp8hjZrEaoG9Qedl32tw" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1996/10/the-spirit-of-prophecy</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1996-general-conference/1996-10-1030-elder-l-aldin-porter-64k-eng.mp3" length="5762177" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 1996 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Destiny</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The center of the plan is the Lord Jesus Christ. Reject or ignore Him, and the great plan of happiness cannot function in your behalf.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_99265_000_026" doc-version="2" hash="VDVqBg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="5M0gS5U-AEee-DbY8DeHBw" hash="-nDptg">Our Destiny</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="8EslCY7H_0OtNdLRarc5gQ" hash="kkWTWg">L. Aldin Porter</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="fe9nIHZarUm1yXztzmZ6bQ" hash="L1LCag">The center of the plan is the Lord Jesus Christ. Reject or ignore Him, and the great plan of happiness cannot function in your behalf.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-ebb.jpg" alt="Elder L. Aldin Porter" pid="NUO-LdyKNU-5ws_oEVliOg" hash="ouDyvw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p1" pid="2IcJxPBAVE2tor5Aqxiksg" hash="WwKPZg">Some months ago, following a session of stake conference, a lovely young lady in her late teens spoke with me expressing concern over some aspects of the proclamation on the family. Her attitude was not one of rejection but of a sincere desire to understand. I have given her concern a great deal of thought.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p2" pid="ttkZChtqD0Ck6-_rpfVj4A" hash="AvMr0w">The God of creation spoke to Moses in an effort to help him understand the destiny of this world: “And worlds without number have I created; and I also created them for mine own purpose; and by the Son I created them, which is mine Only Begotten” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.33" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:33</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p3" pid="acHej7r5qUOTvod2PRHFoQ" hash="hBNg1w">Note the Lord’s words: “I created them for mine own purpose.” The Lord had a purpose in establishing worlds, and in just a few verses, He explained what it was: “For behold, this is my work and my glory—to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p4" pid="3gR4k2INmUeE-t1CqTcmlw" hash="8-bQlw">It is clear that the Lord had a plan laid out for the accomplishment of His purposes. In the scriptures we read of the many names of the plan: “the great plan of happiness,” “the plan of redemption,” “the merciful plan of the great Creator,” “the plan of salvation,” “the plan of justice,” and “the great plan of the Eternal God.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p5" pid="p_HX3CUR5kGqMOv7xJdqpA" hash="j53JGw">Each name emphasizes one aspect or another of the plan. But in reality there is only one plan called by many names through which God means to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p6" pid="sRtsIOtN_ECAVejOn5cq6w" hash="vsGmXw">Think of an airplane leaving the airport with the complete journey mapped out. The pilots and crew know where they are going, and they won’t get off course and fail to reach their destination once in 50,000 times, unless weather or mechanical troubles interfere. Now, imagine another airplane with a captain and crew but no flight plan. The engines are started, and the plane moves down the runway. Yet as it begins to climb, the crew doesn’t know whether to turn east or to turn west. If you are on that airplane, you will have almost no chance of arriving at your destination. It is clear to each of us that an airplane crew needs a flight plan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p7" pid="zcubu4d9DUSx7XqkYWX79Q" hash="3KQbSw">So it is with our lives. One cannot make wise long-range decisions unless one understands that there is purpose here and recognizes that he must understand at least some aspects of the merciful plan of the great Creator.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p8" pid="hCDvfJ96g0GrqdQKvOis5w" hash="7WXwpQ">The Lord has given us instructions and commandments to help us fulfill the destiny which He envisions for us. Commandments are best understood after one knows something of the plan. Alma taught this principle when he said, “Therefore God gave unto them commandments, <span class="emphasis">after having made known unto them the plan of redemption,</span> that they should not do evil, the penalty thereof being a second death, which was an everlasting death as to things pertaining unto righteousness; for on such the plan of redemption could have no power, for the works of justice could not be destroyed, according to the supreme goodness of God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/12.32" class="scriptureRef">Alma 12:32</a>; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p9" pid="R_NMr8AFukyxfzWWm6egyQ" hash="QkJGcA">A very important part of the plan is the right of personal choice. The Lord calls it moral agency. We may choose as we desire, but we may not avoid the consequences of our choices. Think on that. We are permitted to make our choices in life, but we ought not then call the plan unfair because we must accept the results of our choices.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p10" pid="BXVTu-UY5UGoHaB136MaRA" hash="hxWiUw">The center of the plan is the Lord Jesus Christ. Reject or ignore Him, and the great plan of happiness cannot function in your behalf. His life was dedicated in His premortal existence, through mortality, and even on into the eternal worlds to establishing the Father’s plan to our blessing and benefit. The cost to the Master was monumental. Think of the pain of Gethsemane and of His suffering on Calvary. This should give us some concept of the enormous importance of the plan of redemption.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p11" pid="P3UxynWoFEeQuEZSs42tOg" hash="7Z9iGg">Pride, pursuing the vain things of the world, unchastity, misunderstanding gender roles, greed, and a disregard for the sacredness of human life are just a few of the obstacles in mortality. They can hinder us or prevent us from reaching our destination. The plan allows for repentance, but it does not allow for acceptance of self-destructive behavior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p12" pid="Li-QLoQN7UCcujfK-70gHg" hash="5FZKwg">“For I the Lord cannot look upon sin with the least degree of allowance;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p13" pid="_XKoa7P50kKVCLM-ys_deA" hash="nvCfrw">“Nevertheless, he that repents and does the commandments of the Lord shall be forgiven” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.31-32" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:31–32</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p14" pid="OUjbXH8zI0u9r7DqjbnY8A" hash="mtNXPw">Understanding the plan can give us great consolation in the severe tests that come to humankind. Further, that understanding will strengthen our faith. One of the most difficult tests is separation from loved ones through death. The plan is a great comfort if we understand the following words of scripture:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p15" pid="6ROQkk4kEECzcwu8qlcEhw" hash="2B_sdQ">“For as death hath passed upon all men, to fulfil the merciful plan of the great Creator, there must needs be a power of resurrection, and the resurrection must needs come unto man by reason of the fall; and the fall came by reason of transgression; and because man became fallen they were cut off from the presence of the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/9.6" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 9:6</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p16" pid="MhbNt49-SkSniNUwTNKV3A" hash="dlBdgw">We are literally sons and daughters of God. That reality should permeate every fiber of our beings. Knowing this one truth will greatly influence the decisions of life that can bring us either great joy or bitter regret.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p17" pid="J-PONI-FUk2BkrBCPtFTzQ" hash="EHNu4Q">Many who design the philosophies of men know little or nothing of the purposes of God. Their secular concepts are often woefully inadequate for eternal purposes. If, for instance, one believes that man’s existence on earth is an accident of nature—one’s judgment will be flawed. These modern-day philosophers do not know of the premortal life of mankind, nor are they aware of the eternal destiny of man. How could they possibly build principles that will endure the tests of centuries?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p18" pid="gOZsNRxUwki04Cj6LmdgEQ" hash="ImrlaQ">President Gordon B. Hinckley announced the proclamation on the family, saying: “With so much of sophistry that is passed off as truth, with so much of deception concerning standards and values, with so much of allurement and enticement to take on the slow stain of the world, we have felt to warn and forewarn. In furtherance of this we of the First Presidency and the Council of the Twelve Apostles now issue a proclamation to the Church and to the world as a declaration and reaffirmation of standards, doctrines, and practices relative to the family which the prophets, seers, and revelators of this church have repeatedly stated throughout its history” (“Stand Strong against the Wiles of the World,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1995, 100).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p19" pid="1cWKNNfq4E2-uvX_5JBm2w" hash="xQjbGw">Some complain that when the prophets speak with clarity and firmness that they are taking our agency away. We are still free to choose. But we must accept the consequences of those decisions. The prophets do not take away our agency. They simply warn us of what the consequences of our choices will be. How foolish to fault the prophets for their warnings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p20" pid="kXAGM_I37kG4xwdOPXbQlA" hash="xSuU3A">Develop faith in the prophets and their admonitions. Seek the confirmation of the Spirit that they are inspired. Then when they speak and you respond positively to their counsel, you will find comfort, peace, and even joy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p21" pid="vs6g29p-y0egbvVlG7yf0Q" hash="eDRSNA">Alma, an ancient prophet, felt very strong feelings of concern for his fellowmen when he said, “Yea, I would declare unto every soul, as with the voice of thunder, repentance and the plan of redemption, that they should repent and come unto our God, that there might not be more sorrow upon all the face of the earth” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/29.2" class="scriptureRef">Alma 29:2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p22" pid="FszuNhswX0Ga5vMAyNIFmQ" hash="3h8Waw">When we understand the great plan of the Eternal God, the proclamation on the family brings peace and certainty. The very work bears witness of itself, for the Spirit of God attends it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny.p23" pid="0eEgjwoocUSoIjDjdIhEtg" hash="HkTeQQ">The message of the proclamation will comfort parents who may be questioning their roles in the home. It will bring security to children as they are raised by parents who love them and understand their divine destiny. And it will bring lasting happiness to the young woman who spoke to me as she understands and fulfills the role designed for her by an all-wise and loving Father in Heaven. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1999/10/our-destiny</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1999-general-conference/1999-10-4030-elder-l-aldin-porter-64k-eng.mp3" length="5218598" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 1999 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“To Bear Testimony of Mine Only Begotten”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten?lang=eng</link>
      <description>A spiritual witness of the Nephite scripture will always bring the certainty of the Savior’s existence.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029247_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="ur5HnQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="s47aXadfU0OFp8W7RFZ-6g" hash="yHcNCw">“To Bear Testimony of Mine Only Begotten”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="AO4JGtK4vUWein90UnTgZw" hash="kkWTWg">L. Aldin Porter</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="HGUEvALhBU-YTFweh1ULJA" hash="Qohd8g">A spiritual witness of the Nephite scripture will always bring the certainty of the Savior’s existence.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-ebb.jpg" alt="Elder L. Aldin Porter" pid="GJoo49MRfEu1KNKFDOn-jA" hash="ouDyvw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p1" pid="oTmnmojyNU6OSI7xhD1HwA" hash="Eu9hfg">We of the Seventy would like to extend a hearty welcome to the brethren who this day were sustained to the five quorums of Seventy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p2" pid="PdOboPO6rkqPhtZ9569sEQ" hash="ellbXw">We are blessed, brothers and sisters, to live in a world filled with almost daily announcements of progress against disease and other threats to mankind. There seems to be a never-ending march of man’s accomplishments in overcoming impediments to a long and healthy life. Most of us have become accustomed to a constant flow of wonders.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p3" pid="H7SB2FmidUWm2ABSJJK9dg" hash="ZOh7eQ">Yet, with it all, we are also faced with a relentless onslaught of soul-destroying distractions such as pornography, illegal drug use, and abuse of spouse and children. There is a parade of false philosophies which are trumpeted as new and modern answers to the problems of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p4" pid="nx-9bEEi9EuvoJ2UfB4OlA" hash="h1-Y6g">The extensive communication resources which the Lord has revealed for our day have, to a large degree, been appropriated for evil purposes. The print media, television and videos, and now the Internet constantly bring into our homes material that will pollute our souls and destroy our lives. Our homes in times past have generally been peaceful havens against the world. To retain that peace now takes an almost unrelenting vigilance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p5" pid="-LXWyqGU_UOTFaql8VaTWw" hash="UczVGw">Yet we have great reason for optimism. We are not left without defense against these wicked elements that would bring us sorrow and despair here and would deny us the joys of eternity hereafter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p6" pid="BoK6dziiLUqTAUhyj6p_FA" hash="3EF65g">“And Jesus said unto them, I am the bread of life: he that cometh to me shall never hunger; and he that believeth on me shall never thirst” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/6.35" class="scriptureRef">John 6:35</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p7" pid="DOlcp-ywk0SglyyKQPjxMA" hash="r4VPmw">“This is the bread which cometh down from heaven, that a man may eat thereof, and not die.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p8" pid="PC9mMa_86Emk2hlRWzBE0Q" hash="g2cprA">“I am the living bread which came down from heaven: if any man eat of this bread, he shall live for ever: and the bread that I will give is my flesh, which I will give for the life of the world” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/6.50-51" class="scriptureRef">John 6:50–51</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p9" pid="iEV-WZEr2U--WeIqebmlbw" hash="bSVR_Q">He is the answer to the longings of the human heart for certainty. He is the answer to our individual sins and to our sorrows.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p10" pid="OVAgF0l34Eeky5zG4d2riw" hash="-hkidg">He is our protector in a world constantly seeking to solve problems through violence. He is our protector in a world where the minds of so many are filled with evil continually. We, of all people, should look to the future with enthusiasm and optimism. We have His word to direct us, to comfort us, and to give us hope for the future. There is so much that lies ahead of light and purity and virtue; and, in time, violence will disappear, for surely the lamb will lie down with the lion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p11" pid="LerXHbtorE6P__EHXFuklQ" hash="JQIUmA">The Lord, of course, saw our day. He saw the devastating effects of transgression. And He prophesied that He would provide protection for His people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p12" pid="4DUmJ18NpEe8gCn_6S9WHw" hash="emxl8w">He spoke to Enoch of the last days—the days of wickedness and vengeance—and He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p13" pid="8XD-Ak1_hE6IFLK_S1eRyQ" hash="ZMoSLg">“And the day shall come that the earth shall rest, but before that day the heavens shall be darkened, and a veil of darkness shall cover the earth; and the heavens shall shake, and also the earth; and great tribulations shall be among the children of men, but my people will I preserve;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p14" pid="8YXOgMKyE0WMbGVG8Sve5g" hash="KRGE0Q">“And righteousness will I send down out of heaven; and truth will I send forth out of the earth, to bear testimony of mine Only Begotten; his resurrection from the dead; yea, and also the resurrection of all men; and righteousness and truth will I cause to sweep the earth as with a flood, to gather out mine elect from the four quarters of the earth” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/7.61-62" class="scriptureRef">Moses 7:61–62</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p15" pid="yaIDkbFHVEm0OFTNY2pnFg" hash="YVjx5g">Did you note that He said, “Truth will I send forth out of the earth”? To do what? “To bear testimony of mine Only Begotten.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p16" pid="S_KbklhBKUWJAaC8CU3TDQ" hash="7MiKpQ">The Book of Mormon was compiled and translated for our day. It came forth out of the earth as was prophesied to bless and guide the lives of the people of this day. It came in a day and time as the Lord knew it would when the dislocations caused by wickedness would be very intense.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p17" pid="sSIPzGHvIUuv6_WpkvRj0g" hash="fhjidw">As Moroni concluded the immense work of his father and others, he made a promise that has been shared widely in a multitude of languages. But I fear it has become too commonplace among us. We learn about it in Sunday School, in seminary, in family home evenings, and we even memorize it as missionaries. But today I would ask that you listen as I read this promise as if you had never heard of it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p18" pid="Ivo24tXllUWaikC6VACVtg" hash="4uZzdQ">“And when ye shall receive these things, I would exhort you that ye would ask God, the Eternal Father, in the name of Christ, if these things are not true; and if ye shall ask with a sincere heart, with real intent, having faith in Christ, he will manifest the truth of it unto you, by the power of the Holy Ghost” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.4" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:4</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p19" pid="V1lhIZcO_0ayATcnYP1I_A" hash="fLi9Ng">This is the promise, that our Eternal Father will give us a manifestation of truth—a personal revelation of eternal consequence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p20" pid="X7DBdvPeDEi5ATku2fmefA" hash="hgotFA">The Book of Mormon was given to the convincing of the Jew and Gentile that Jesus is the Christ, manifesting Himself unto all nations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p21" pid="1KAfkcFmIkivE__crab-7Q" hash="LU1PKA">Do not treat lightly the revelations of God. Do not treat lightly this astonishing promise. I bear a solemn testimony to you that this promise has been fulfilled not only in my life but in the lives of hundreds of thousands, even millions, of people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p22" pid="EGRcRICUk0CT06lhYljVxA" hash="9NXfNw">You will find that when Moroni’s promise is fulfilled and you are given the knowledge that the Book of Mormon is truly the word of God, there will come with it a witness that Jesus is the Christ, the Redeemer and Savior of the world. I have never known an instance where this did not occur. Moreover, I do not believe a violation of this principle will ever take place. A spiritual witness of the Nephite scripture will always bring the certainty of the Savior’s existence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p23" pid="HBG2HrikPkWgFF9IXSL1HA" hash="ZDtGYw">With that witness borne of the Holy Ghost will come a sure knowledge that Joseph Smith told the truth when he said that he had seen the Father and the Son on that spring morning of 1820.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p24" pid="pIeenVg27USdw5Y834e67g" hash="vXDavQ">A knowledge that Jesus Christ lives and is our Redeemer and Savior is worth whatever the cost may be. This is the fulfillment of Moroni’s promise in our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p25" pid="o1QVYcDpyEaabhnNEKM9fg" hash="h-nQ1A">After that, we then through study and prayer can come to know that He has given us life through the Resurrection. We will come to know that He has promised us a quality of life hereafter beyond our capacity to comprehend. We must understand that this testimony comes only through obedience to the principles and ordinances of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p26" pid="m7VxvkZU40uPzUdgwoyD6w" hash="OcbFMA">Read the Book of Mormon. “With a sincere heart [and] real intent,” begin to read. Ponder the words. Often pause and ask your Heavenly Father “if these things are not true.” Continue to read, to ponder, and to ask. It will not be easy reading. There will be roadblocks along the way. Persist.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p27" pid="RM6cOvZ86UCyI1dSVL4YwA" hash="GuvlQg">Approach your Father in Heaven having expelled your prejudices and biases. Leave your heart open to receive the impressions that come from eternal sources. Many inspiring treasures will be revealed to you. There will, in time, come into your heart and mind an assurance that Jesus Christ is the living Son of the living Father. With it will come a knowledge that Joseph Smith is the prophet of the Restoration and that there are apostles and prophets on the earth today. You will come to know with a sure knowledge that President Gordon B. Hinckley is the prophet to the world as well as the President of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p28" pid="LTcuOrkJr0iybBy4-GUNoA" hash="FnzyKw">Now I make this promise to those who are investigating the Church, to those who are members but who have lost enthusiasm for the work and are, therefore, in a state of confusion in a world that is in moral chaos. I make this promise to those who through transgression and faithless living are in despair over eternal things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p29" pid="s_9tTl-d00eKUJZcW81vmg" hash="Kni9xA">When this sacred witness comes, our love for Him will increase without bounds; our desire to know of Him will increase. We will sorrow as we read such words as King Benjamin’s prophecy of Him:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p30" pid="YSpI0dZgU0iqtcYEMiVQdw" hash="AZYfug">“And lo, he shall suffer temptations, and pain of body, hunger, thirst, and fatigue, even more than man can suffer, except it be unto death; for behold, blood cometh from every pore, so great shall be his anguish for the wickedness and the abominations of his people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p31" pid="9BWA0Pvxz06ejfkJbVvBrw" hash="mXFHNg">“And he shall be called Jesus Christ, the Son of God, the Father of heaven and earth, the Creator of all things from the beginning” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/3.7-8" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 3:7–8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p32" pid="eaWD3zEavUybsVryhPXM9w" hash="ud5RCQ">Our hearts will overflow with gratitude for His sacrifice in our behalf. This doctrine of personal revelation is not new. This eternal principle has been taught in ages past:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p33" pid="7Nm1JHEjUEq7Tl760OnY3w" hash="GODJ8g">“When Jesus came into the coasts of Caesarea Philippi, he asked his disciples, saying, Whom do men say that I the Son of man am?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p34" pid="099pOh-k7Uqr81vu4PVGgw" hash="j7ecPg">“And they said, Some say that thou art John the Baptist: some, Elias; and others, Jeremias, or one of the prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p35" pid="zvqSrjv-1EOI_U3GjL-xPg" hash="zYTRdg">“He saith unto them, But whom say ye that I am?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p36" pid="hn-qGvGteUyZWH8hG7kqzw" hash="3d-4RA">“And Simon Peter answered and said, Thou art the Christ, the Son of the living God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p37" pid="nsU9qsH0p06tQPQoqnD89w" hash="jGUOJw">“And Jesus answered and said unto him, Blessed art thou, Simon Bar-jona: for flesh and blood hath not revealed it unto thee, but my Father which is in heaven” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/16.13-17" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 16:13–17</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p38" pid="UnozhBSo1kCKJ99TY8DPog" hash="iL6WGw">After this sacred witness comes, you will see His hand in a thousand things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p39" pid="3ivi98XK40WeDY814UG9Rw" hash="qmHm8Q">“And behold, all things have their likeness, and all things are created and made to bear record of me, both things which are temporal, and things which are spiritual; things which are in the heavens above, and things which are on the earth, and things which are in the earth, and things which are under the earth, both above and beneath: all things bear record of me” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/6.63" class="scriptureRef">Moses 6:63</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p40" pid="Gy3ucvRpZkGcgBoskpVfSw" hash="41OThQ">We will find great joy in contemplating His life, and we will shortly realize that in truth all things do bear witness of Him. Furthermore, in the midst of our trials and challenges, we will find peace, knowing that in the end it will be all right. We will find serenity in the face of affliction. We will find this serenity in life even as chaos swirls around us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p41" pid="aRuSBkOu3UCFlMfFSZ7TbQ" hash="Xd6I-Q">Such is the power of a testimony and witness that Jesus is the Christ, the Redeemer, our Advocate with the Father, the Only Begotten of the Father in the flesh, the very Savior of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p42" pid="xiiMnTJY60-TRdeVMKEOuA" hash="5G-VtA">I bear witness of Him. I witness that He lived, He died, He came forth from the tomb a resurrected being, and He has gifted us with resurrection and a promise of an eternal life of joy and fulfillment through obedience to the laws and ordinances of the gospel as revealed anew in our day through living prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten.p43" pid="4i7Y7hnMXESiZF_uACkbXA" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2001/04/to-bear-testimony-of-mine-only-begotten</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2001-general-conference/2001-04-2070-elder-l-aldin-porter-64k-eng.mp3" length="5941865" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2001 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
