<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By L. Whitney Clayton</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by L. Whitney Clayton.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/L.%20Whitney%20Clayton.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by L. Whitney Clayton.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2001 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>“Help Thou Mine Unbelief”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We promote the process of strengthening our faith when we do what is right—increased faith always follows.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029371_000_012" doc-version="2" hash="5dgYmg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="-ureR3d8nUCf15Rf4F8OpA" hash="XuDIrw">“Help Thou Mine Unbelief”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="QFz3qOC1GEqswst5m2zbyQ" hash="Kn78eg">L. Whitney Clayton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="yFucnnXQFkuJd82gUtJnVQ" hash="FkkHRg">We promote the process of strengthening our faith when we do what is right—increased faith always follows.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-137d.jpg" alt="Elder L. Whitney Clayton" pid="hpJ1BMCMh0Sj6SjX0QbC4w" hash="8ZvonQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p1" pid="YsGzxJrx60e-62geFudcEA" hash="3htK2A">On one occasion, the Savior encountered a great multitude of people who were listening to a discussion between His disciples and the scribes. He then asked the scribes, “What question ye with them?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p2" pid="_26VZ5OiRE-YtUHRB8gLFQ" hash="Gb3VhQ">A certain man, kneeling down to Him, answered that he had asked the disciples to cast an evil spirit out of his son, but “they could not.” The father begged Him, saying, “But if thou canst do any thing, have compassion on us, and help us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p3" pid="TJvzagSnBEyT5pVAvgvWYw" hash="lttwyw">“Jesus said unto him, If thou canst believe, all things are possible to him that believeth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p4" pid="6GUS0DsdiEG2VF6O9EniIw" hash="TXAJ8A">“And straightway the father of the child cried out, and said with tears, Lord, I believe; help thou mine unbelief.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p5" pid="odY4O1TEPUKDLc4cAhHGTA" hash="8jvKmQ">The Savior then rebuked the evil spirit and charged it to “come out of him, and enter no more into him. And the spirit cried, and rent him sore, and came out of him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p6" pid="q9PEWhbhdkCrHEghC2wiUw" hash="rDY9_A">All of us have come face-to-face with difficult, even desperate hours, when with tears we have fallen on our knees and pled as did this father, “Lord, I believe; help thou mine unbelief.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p7" pid="gpJ90H7uYkiT2emAlGKUhw" hash="p4afJQ">Just as the Savior stood ready to help this father whose son was “sore vexed,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> so is He ready to help our unbelief today so that with faith we can survive our mortal struggles and “come off conqueror.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p8" pid="WBRNpkaXBEOntWv35YFKEA" hash="0BnvEA">Faith in the Lord Jesus Christ is the first principle of the gospel and is more than mere belief.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Faith is a “hope for things which are not seen, which are true.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> “Faith always moves its possessor to … physical and mental action.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> “To have faith in Jesus Christ means to have such trust in him that we obey whatever he commands. There is no faith where there is no obedience.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p9" pid="2gL9XJymLEe7_iQqiS-H5w" hash="FCdHUw">Faith comes from hearing the word of God and is a spiritual gift.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Faith increases when we not only hear, but act on the word of God as well, in obedience to the truths we have been taught.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p10" pid="Jq3l18aceUOANhx0q0LDqw" hash="uAAa6Q">Mary’s reply to the angel’s announcement provides an excellent example. Mary was told by the angel Gabriel: “Thou shalt conceive in thy womb, and bring forth a son, and shalt call his name JESUS. He shall be great, and shall be called the Son of the Highest.” Mary then obediently said to Gabriel, “Behold the handmaid of the Lord; be it unto me according to thy word.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p11" pid="nsaLr4Ye4EOxZFgg1xzToA" hash="h-11DA">On another occasion, “Jesus, walking by the sea of Galilee, saw two brethren, Simon called Peter, and Andrew his brother, casting a net into the sea: for they were fishers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p12" pid="rAm_Q-VIrEaifhoRfiCn1w" hash="6-uLQA">“And he saith unto them, Follow me, and I will make you fishers of men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p13" pid="0LR3eWqQU065ktWUema_DA" hash="H6eS4Q">“And they straightway left their nets, and followed him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p14" pid="HgsukEUikEOUxTL1rhVvsA" hash="QwHAuQ">After the Savior’s Resurrection, Peter and other disciples went “a fishing.” However, “that night they caught nothing. But when the morning was now come, Jesus stood on the shore: but the disciples knew not that it was Jesus.” He told them to “cast the net on the right side of the ship, and ye shall find. They cast therefore, and now they were not able to draw it for the multitude of fishes.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p15" pid="IJsAQq2oCUOMayUswv1Fgg" hash="N1R1NQ">We find similar faith-developing obedience in the life of the Prophet Joseph Smith. Following the angel Moroni’s all-night-long visits with him in September 1823, Joseph went to work in the morning with his father. Having been awake nearly all night, he “found [his] strength so exhausted as to render [him] entirely unable” to perform “the necessary labors of the day.” His father told him to return home, and he “started with the intention of going to the house; but … [his] strength entirely failed [him], and [he] fell helpless on the ground, and for a time was quite unconscious of anything.” When he awoke, he “looked up, and beheld the same messenger standing over [his] head, surrounded by light as before.” Joseph was commanded to “go to [his] father and tell him of the vision and commandments which [he] had received.” Although understandably weary, he obediently “returned to [his] father in the field, and rehearsed the whole matter to him.” His father replied “that it was of God, and told [him] to go and do as commanded.” Exhausted but obedient, Joseph then “left the field, and went to the place where the messenger had told [him] the plates were deposited, a journey of several miles.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p16" pid="FFgT_Fi0nUuGIx1vU2T5JA" hash="pOjkcQ">Each day we decide what we will do and what we will not do, among myriad alternatives. When we choose to obey the commandments cheerfully as our first priority, neither murmuring about nor measuring the things He commands, we become the handmaids of the Lord and fishers of men and cast our nets on the right side of our own ships. We simply go and do the things the Lord has commanded, even when we are weary, trusting that He will help us to do exactly as He asks.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> As we do so, the Lord helps our unbelief, and our faith becomes powerful, vibrant, and unshakable. The Prophet Joseph wrote from Liberty Jail, “Therefore, dearly beloved brethren, let us cheerfully do all things that lie in our power; and then may we stand still, with the utmost assurance [or faith], to see the salvation of God, and for his arm to be revealed.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p17" pid="TKrAN2VJy0mVw2JAo0G-og" hash="hGM2Dg">No matter who we are or where we live, there is much about our daily lives that is routine and repetitive. As we go about this dailiness, we must be deliberate about doing the things that matter most. These must-do things include making room first for the minimum daily requirements of faithful behavior: true obedience, humble prayer, serious scripture study, and selfless service to others. No other daily vitamins strengthen the muscles of our faith as fast as these actions. We also must remember that genuine fasting fosters strong faith. This is especially important as we faithfully seek to fix deeply embedded character flaws which go “not out but by prayer and fasting.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p18" pid="FBuQUDez9kK6aKPsankzHg" hash="bZnU3w">Developing faith in the Lord Jesus Christ is a step-by-step, line-upon-line, and precept-upon-precept process. We promote the process of strengthening our faith when we do what is right—increased faith always follows as a consequence.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> If we exercise our faith daily with prayer, study, and obedience, the Savior helps our unbelief, and our faith becomes a shield to “quench all the fiery darts of the wicked.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> Alma taught that we may “withstand every temptation of the devil, with [our] faith on the Lord Jesus Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> However, we can neither ignore nor reject the essential ingredients of faith and then expect to reap a rich harvest.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p19" pid="nt4Gbgumw0qbn6K_t_aMqA" hash="6T-jiQ">We see countless examples of faith developing in Church members today. As young men, young women, and mature couples accept calls to serve missions, as couples prepare themselves in virtue to be married in the holy temple, as parents train up children in the way they should go,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> they strengthen their faith in the Lord Jesus Christ. As we keep the Sabbath day holy, magnify callings, pay tithes and offerings, welcome new members into Church circles, and invite friends and neighbors to learn gospel truths, we strengthen our faith. When we choose to abandon our sins and repent willingly, and when we fall to our knees in prayer in good times as well as in turbulent times, we develop strong faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p20" pid="Kyn80WcCmEqj-T6vygpsJw" hash="HLMMkg">We then find occurring in our own lives an experience described in the Book of Mormon: “Nevertheless they did fast and pray oft, and did wax stronger and stronger in their humility, and firmer and firmer in the faith of Christ, unto the filling their souls with joy and consolation, yea, even to the purifying and the sanctification of their hearts, which sanctification cometh because of their yielding their hearts unto God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief.p21" pid="rhwUo_GiTEi4fKUDE6UC7w" hash="xUrYHQ">I know that the Savior lives and that He helps our unbelief. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2001/10/help-thou-mine-unbelief</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2001-general-conference/2001-10-2040-elder-l-whitney-clayton-64k-eng.mp3" length="4043670" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2001 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blessed Are All the Pure in Heart</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart?lang=eng</link>
      <description>May God bless our genuine efforts to be pure of heart and mind, that “virtue [may] garnish [our] thoughts unceasingly.”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008332_000_020" doc-version="2" hash="k1iXuQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="1cVJqx9EhUCYdgCuno80wA" hash="9lbMog">Blessed Are All the Pure in Heart</h1><p class="authorName" guid="18c0dfd9-dde4-4558-8070-b6b6285858bf" pid="H7A-pdiatE-GVnan4Cineg" hash="Kn78eg">L. Whitney Clayton</p><p class="kicker" pid="vjrRSqjHkUiR6yZb-H3IzA" hash="TRKn9A">May God bless our genuine efforts to be pure of heart and mind, that “virtue [may] garnish [our] thoughts unceasingly.”</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="e4d66a65-3b83-4c43-93eb-0a958e40556b">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/CLAYTONLW_01.jpg" alt="Elder L. Whitney Clayton" guid="55af5130-78d8-4f02-9b50-25d9994bec3d" pid="SzHcZpEFME-HVIyiWJQhKQ" hash="9XdQEQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.p" pid="AHM0ncAiRkqEWHcyaRyR7g" hash="C1mz3g">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="51"></span>Walking down a beach in the Caribbean one sunny morning some years ago, my wife and I saw several small fishing boats that had been pulled up onto the sand. When we stopped to look at the boats, I learned something about fishing that I have never forgotten. Instead of using nets, lines, or hooks, the local fishermen used simple traps made of wire mesh. Each trap was shaped like a box. The fishermen cut vertical openings about eight inches long on each side of the trap and then bent the cut wires inward, creating narrow slots through which fish could enter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.p" pid="Rbt0Z0lz1ESGYcRQd2f3uA" hash="GzHteg">You can probably guess how a trap worked. The fishermen took a baited trap out to sea and lowered it to the bottom. When a dinner-sized fish came near the trap and sensed the bait, it would find an opening on the side of the trap and swim in, just squeezing between the cut wires. Then, when a trapped fish tried to swim out, it would discover that it was one thing to squeeze past the cut wires to get into the trap, but it was an entirely different thing to swim against those sharp ends to get out—it was caught. When the fishermen returned, they hauled the trap out of the water, and the trapped fish soon became a fresh seafood dinner.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.p" pid="tHDFsoWDsEmof7xZZu4GPA" hash="UDELQQ">There’s an account in the Old Testament about someone who fell prey to a similar trap. That man was mighty King David, and what happened is one of the saddest stories in the scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.p" pid="zr1IRXyrSkidMNgHpjWj_g" hash="GMKNvA">“And it came to pass … at the time when kings go forth to battle, that David sent Joab, and his servants with him, and all Israel; and they [fought against Ammon]. But David tarried still at Jerusalem.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.p" pid="VzWds-TEaUuwMo7LZvJHrA" hash="oIM5QQ">“And it came to pass in an evening-tide, that David arose from off his bed, and walked upon the roof of the king’s house: and from the roof he saw a woman washing herself; and the woman was very beautiful to look upon” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/2-sam/11.1-2" class="scriptureRef">2 Samuel 11:1–2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.p" pid="KH5EaHxhIUOtJ2uYptgKig" hash="6JGI5Q">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="52"></span>David learned the woman’s name was Bathsheba. Her husband, Uriah, a soldier, was away fighting the Ammonites with the rest of the army, where David, their king, should have been. David had Bathsheba brought to the palace. They committed adultery, she became pregnant, and David began to fear that their adultery would be discovered. Hoping to cover his sin, David ordered that Uriah be sent back to Jerusalem. Uriah returned, but refused on principle to go to his home to visit Bathsheba. David then arranged for Uriah to be slain in battle (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/2-sam/11.3-17" class="scriptureRef">2 Samuel 11:3–17</a>). This series of dreadful decisions brought death to Uriah and misery to David, Bathsheba, and eventually the entire kingdom. With rich understatement, the Bible says, “The thing that David had done displeased the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/2-sam/11.27" class="scriptureRef">2 Samuel 11:27</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.p" pid="BK6Ee-LzTUuyMXPuZeKkbg" hash="jbYrHQ">Do you see how David got caught in this trap? He was on a rooftop courtyard of his palace, and looking below in a neighboring yard, he saw something he never should have seen. That was the adversary’s bait. Modesty, chastity, and good judgment required that David turn away immediately and not watch, but he didn’t do either thing. Instead, he allowed his mind to turn to forbidden fantasies, those thoughts led to actions, and things quickly spiraled downward from bad to worse to fatal. David was trapped, and for him the consequences were eternal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.p" pid="xhLErAILj0e7jT1VyAmjLg" hash="ACMFBA">There’s a spiritual snare today called pornography, and many, allured by its provocative messages, enter this deadly trap. Like any trap, it is easy to enter but difficult to escape. Some rationalize that they can casually view pornography without suffering its adverse effects. They say initially, “This isn’t so bad,” or, “Who cares? It won’t make any difference,” or, “I’m just curious.” But they are mistaken. The Lord has warned, “And he that looketh upon a woman to lust after her shall deny the faith, and shall not have the Spirit; and if he repents not he shall be cast out” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:23</a>). That’s exactly what happened to David: he looked at Bathsheba, lusted after her, and lost the Spirit. How different the rest of David’s life might have been if he had just looked away.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.p" pid="oTwhLJWde0mxegaQGMBVsQ" hash="0NWIlw">Along with losing the Spirit, pornography users also lose perspective and proportion. Like King David, they try to conceal their sin, forgetting that nothing is hidden from the Lord (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/27.27" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 27:27</a>). Real consequences start to accumulate as self-respect ebbs away, sweet relationships sour, marriages wither, and innocent victims begin to pile up. Finding that what they have been viewing no longer satisfies, they experiment with more extreme images. They slowly grow addicted even if they don’t know it or they deny it, and like David’s, their behavior deteriorates as their moral standards disintegrate.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.p" pid="y5DHXpk11EiLmethxS62cQ" hash="Hh-KpQ">As popular culture across the world degenerates, sleaze increasingly saturates the media, entertainment, advertising, and the Internet. But popularity according to the world’s prevailing norms is a very perilous scale to use to measure what’s right or even what’s not dangerous. A movie or television show may be well known and well liked by millions of viewers and nevertheless portray images and conduct that are pornographic. If something in a movie “isn’t too bad,” that automatically means that it isn’t too good either. Thus, the fact that others watch movies or open Web sites that aren’t appropriate is no excuse for us. Priesthood holders’ lives should emulate the standards of the Savior and His Church, not the standards of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.p" pid="WQGyO3thdkyO8Lfyi23xHA" hash="q4Ht-A">The Savior taught, “And blessed are all the pure in heart, for they shall see God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/12.8" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 12:8</a>). The promises of the gospel are uplifting and ennobling, even exalting. We receive those promises by covenants which are conditioned on our living lives of purity and morality. When we live right and seek to purify our hearts, we draw closer to God and the Spirit. The condition of our heart determines how much evidence of divinity we see in the world now and qualifies <span class="pageBreak" page-number="53"></span>us for the eventual realization of the promise that the pure “shall see God.” Ours is a quest for purity. Thus, the Apostle John wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.p" pid="tTcbe0ZgikuLJXxKL9TOUw" hash="u496nQ">“Beloved, now are we the sons of God, and it doth not yet appear what we shall be: but we know that, when he shall appear, we shall be like him; for we shall see him as he is.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.p" pid="6Yj1UzDnM06fDW-1OhwvWw" hash="e2BHvA">“And every man that hath this hope in him purifieth himself, even as he is pure” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-jn/3.2-3" class="scriptureRef">1 John 3:2–3</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.p" pid="EUCo4f858EKTFiRsgSMCdA" hash="ps8Qgg">If you are already caught in the pornography trap, now is the time to free yourself with the help of the Savior. There is a way out, but you will need His help to escape. Your complete recovery will depend upon your complete repentance. Go to your bishop immediately. Seek his inspired guidance. He will help you put in place a plan of repentance that will restore your self-esteem and bring the Spirit back into your life. The healing power of the Atonement of the Lord Jesus Christ reaches all afflictions, even this one. If you will turn to the Savior with all of your heart and follow the counsel of your bishop, you will find the healing you need. The Savior will help you find the strength to resist temptation and the power to overcome addiction. As Moroni taught:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.p" pid="1ySjiGh4cUy7v8P8JExm4g" hash="-G09jw">“Come unto Christ, and lay hold upon every good gift, and touch not the evil gift, nor the unclean thing. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.p" pid="CUwcMN3f7k-BdWQHOMQnKQ" hash="aj5rgQ">“Yea, come unto Christ, and be perfected in him, and deny yourselves of all ungodliness; and if ye shall deny yourselves of all ungodliness, and love God with all your might, mind and strength, then is his grace sufficient for you, that by his grace ye may be perfect in Christ” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.30,32" class="scriptureRef">Moroni 10:30, 32</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart.p" pid="4G6Yy8c8I02QquWq1ulRhQ" hash="DCV6xw">May God bless our genuine efforts to be pure of heart and mind, that “virtue [may] garnish [our] thoughts unceasingly” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.45" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:45</a>). I testify of the redeeming love of the Savior and of the purifying power of His Atonement in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/CLAYTONLW_01.jpg" alt="Elder L. Whitney Clayton" guid="55af5130-78d8-4f02-9b50-25d9994bec3d" pid="RHdoYf4vIEaJjm0j0Krz4A" hash="9XdQEQ1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="55af5130-78d8-4f02-9b50-25d9994bec3d"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/10/blessed-are-all-the-pure-in-heart</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2007-general-conference/2007-10-3030-elder-l-whitney-clayton-64k-eng.mp3" length="4374541" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>That Your Burdens May Be Light</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Burdens provide opportunities to practice virtues that contribute to eventual perfection.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50019113_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="mCaxLA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="S7hqyDaoRkm5GXDQWQNS4g" hash="7wkwUA">That Your Burdens May Be Light</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="z7v8_ZeJF0-hTENvb14nQg" hash="Kn78eg">L. Whitney Clayton</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="n5KVXjM96keraFgjb5yxgw" hash="ZgpisA">Burdens provide opportunities to practice virtues that contribute to eventual perfection.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p1" pid="HJFrlg8LU0CYl5r2quI0Nw" hash="50scZA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="12"></span>Many years ago I walked at dawn through the narrow cobblestone streets of Cusco, Peru, high in the Andes Mountains. I saw a man from a local indigenous group walking down one of the streets. He was not a big man physically, but he carried an immense load of firewood in a huge burlap sack on his back. The sack seemed to be as big as he was. The load must have weighed as much as he did. He steadied it with a rope that looped under the bottom of the sack and circled up around his forehead. He gripped the rope tightly on both sides of his head. He kept a rag on his forehead underneath the rope to keep it from cutting into his skin. He leaned forward under his burden and walked with deliberate, difficult steps.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p2" pid="OIIz5bLP60KGF-j4PQFjTA" hash="lVl7jQ">The man was carrying the firewood to the marketplace, where it would be sold. In an average day he might make just two or three round-trips across the town to deliver similarly awkward, heavy loads.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p3" pid="e-8Kl2iiJkOup7Bg6ARIEg" hash="oRsEDw">The memory of him bent forward, struggling down the street has become increasingly meaningful for me with the passage of years. How long could he continue to carry such burdens?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p4" pid="Mw9-ND_7s0CvX-p6adfcVA" hash="ZzwP-A">Life presses all kinds of burdens on each of us, some light but others relentless and heavy. People struggle every day under burdens that tax their souls. Many of <span class="emphasis">us</span> struggle under such burdens. They can be emotionally or physically ponderous. They can be worrisome, oppressive, and exhausting. And they can continue for years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p5" pid="pzD_6g97_0erqmEIvNS16Q" hash="EjGsCw">In a general sense, our burdens come from three sources. Some burdens are the natural product of the conditions of the world in which we live. Illness, physical disability, hurricanes, and earthquakes come from time to time through no fault of our own. We can prepare for these risks and sometimes we can predict them, but in the natural pattern of life we will all confront some of these challenges.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p6" pid="2bUc8KMHNkq3UKhx1sacpg" hash="XehmAg">Other burdens are imposed on us <span class="pageBreak" page-number="13"></span>by the misconduct of others. Abuse and addictions can make home anything but a heaven on earth for innocent family members. Sin, incorrect traditions, repression, and crime scatter burdened victims along the pathways of life. Even less-serious misdeeds such as gossip and unkindness can cause others genuine suffering.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p7" pid="RFCM0ZCyW0exLB4R4zyzYw" hash="UfCpUQ">Our own mistakes and shortcomings produce many of our problems and can place heavy burdens on our own shoulders. The most onerous burden we impose upon ourselves is the burden of sin. We have all known the remorse and pain which inevitably follow our failure to keep the commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p8" pid="g_BVr4mrNkap6_gu7EVsVQ" hash="mCQssg">No matter the burdens we face in life as a consequence of natural conditions, the misconduct of others, or our own mistakes and shortcomings, we are all children of a loving Heavenly Father, who sent us to earth as part of His eternal plan for our growth and progress. Our unique individual experiences can help us prepare to return to Him. The adversity and afflictions that are ours, however difficult to bear, last, from heaven’s perspective, for “but a small moment; and then, if [we] endure it well, God shall exalt [us] on high.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> We must do everything we can to bear our burdens “well” for however long our “small moment” carrying them lasts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p9" pid="5Z3cpoEORUi0nKxGWcqWnA" hash="M3HYFg">Burdens provide opportunities to practice virtues that contribute to eventual perfection. They invite us to yield “to the enticings of the Holy Spirit, and [put] off the natural man and [become] a saint through the atonement of Christ the Lord, and [become] as a child, submissive, meek, humble, patient, full of love, willing to submit to all things which the Lord seeth fit to inflict upon [us], even as a child doth submit to his father.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Thus burdens become blessings, though often such blessings are well disguised and may require time, effort, and faith to accept and understand. Four examples may help explain this:</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.f2">
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="hGLnUjjLW0mO-7yhIUSB6w" hash="b-0ZIg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="VOfF7sKlPEucJ_69_xj5kQ" hash="U4MgYw">First, Adam was told, “Cursed shall be the ground for thy sake,” which meant for his benefit, and “by the sweat of thy face shalt thou eat bread.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Work is a continual burden, but it is also a continual blessing “for [our] sake,” for it teaches lessons <span class="emphasis">we</span> can learn only “by the sweat of [our] face.”</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="5SMQ1ei13EOqTkuf58Tu3g" hash="CXHvjg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="X-kIDWn8PUqhXTY8if4ewg" hash="oUfSjA">Second, Alma observed that the poverty and “afflictions [of the poor among the Zoramites] had truly humbled them, and that they were in a preparation to hear the word.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> He added, “Because ye are compelled to be humble blessed are ye.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Our economic challenges may help prepare us to hear the word of the Lord.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="9k2GK_vq0kikKaqYKkH6zA" hash="pbTzjA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="IqGW8rZItk2R-kP511sMTw" hash="YflTjw">Third, because of the “exceedingly great length of [their] war,” many Nephites and Lamanites “were softened because of their afflictions, insomuch that they did humble themselves before God, even in the depth of humility.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> Political unrest, social disorder, and, in some areas of the world, modern Gadianton robbers may humble us and motivate us to seek heavenly shelter from societal storms.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="i8Oo6xq8qEyNgA33Z7qiqA" hash="MX1GCg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="Die4DmnsdkesRzTZHZCOrw" hash="1XyaiQ">Fourth, Joseph Smith was told that <span class="pageBreak" page-number="14"></span>the terrible things he suffered for years at the hands of his enemies would “give [him] experience, and … be for [his] good.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> The suffering we experience through the offenses of others is a valuable, though painful, school for improving our own behavior.</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p10" pid="EU_OHdCZoE-IjVttCACLrw" hash="WGvXbA">Further, bearing up under our own burdens can help us develop a reservoir of empathy for the problems others face. The Apostle Paul taught that we should “bear … one another’s burdens, and so fulfil the law of Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Accordingly, our baptismal covenants require that we should be “willing to bear one another’s burdens, that they may be light; yea, and [be] willing to mourn with those that mourn; yea, and comfort those that stand in need of comfort.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p11" pid="D-rBI0H0KkGndhUMHsE7hw" hash="nWMZRw">Keeping our baptismal covenants helps relieve our <span class="emphasis">own</span> burdens as well as those of burdened souls we serve.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Those who offer such assistance to others stand on holy ground. In explaining this, the Savior taught:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p12" pid="_CGQVqwQgUeDpZalQfA5og" hash="2t0WvA">“When saw we thee an hungred, and fed thee? or thirsty, and gave thee drink?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p13" pid="ytEZrdUH_kSf4r98ONKFOw" hash="3nEFVQ">“When saw we thee a stranger, and took thee in? or naked, and clothed thee?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p14" pid="H8cVduOqL0eBDETt0vVonQ" hash="8EgWfQ">“Or when saw we thee sick, or in prison, and came unto thee?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p15" pid="pobi3MitFkaXFwqShYliUg" hash="jlVnVQ">“And the King shall answer and say unto them, Verily I say unto you, Inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p16" pid="rVyhPIPlb0-TLl0aYPmlvA" hash="IUAZSg">Through it all, the Savior offers us sustaining strength and support, and in His own time and way, He offers deliverance. When Alma and his followers escaped from the armies of King Noah, they established a community named Helam. They began to till the ground, build buildings, and prosper.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Without warning, an army of the Lamanites brought them into bondage, and “none could deliver them but the Lord their God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> That deliverance, however, did not come immediately.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p17" pid="cOo_lKchwkyWXOj-NxezVw" hash="8klc_A">Their enemies began to “put tasks upon them, and put taskmasters over them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> Although they were threatened with death for praying,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> Alma and his people “did pour out their hearts to [God]; and he did know the thoughts of their hearts.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> Because of their goodness and their obedience to their baptismal covenants,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> they were delivered in stages. The Lord said to them:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p18" pid="NSj_8ewRoEunag-5Vvqrhw" hash="Dx2iSQ">“I will … ease the burdens which are put upon your shoulders, that … you cannot feel them upon your backs, even while you are in bondage; and this will I do that ye may stand as witnesses for me hereafter, and that ye may know of a surety that I, the Lord God, do visit my people in their afflictions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p19" pid="6pBUY5Uho0KLeUZpO7eBKA" hash="I_Aj4g">“And now it came to pass that the burdens which were laid upon Alma and his brethren were made light; yea, the Lord did strengthen them that they could bear up their burdens with ease, and they did submit cheerfully and with patience to all the will of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p20" pid="3pWZwl09z0CX_1HIDArmQg" hash="CItteA">“And it came to pass that so great was their faith and their patience that the voice of the Lord came unto them again, saying: Be of good comfort, for on the morrow I will deliver you out of bondage.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p21" pid="fF30fp3xwEe-bERnZiuJ5A" hash="6IP2gQ">Mercifully, the Son of God offers us deliverance from the bondage of our sins, which are among the heaviest of all the burdens we bear. During His Atonement He suffered “according to the flesh that he might take upon him the sins of his people, that he might blot out their transgressions according to the power of his deliverance.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> Christ “suffered these things for all, that they might not suffer if they would repent.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> When we repent and keep the commandments, forgiveness and relief from our burdened conscience come with the help that only the Savior offers, for “surely, whosoever repenteth shall find mercy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light.p22" pid="rtgS7bBiz0ON1cCaFTMWJg" hash="Q_RVkQ">I remember that man in Peru, hunched over and struggling to carry that enormous sack of firewood on his back. For me, he is an image of us all as we struggle with the burdens of life. I know that as we keep the commandments of God and our covenants, He helps us with our burdens. He strengthens us. When we repent, He forgives us and blesses us with peace of conscience and joy.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> May we then submit cheerfully and with patience to all the will of the Lord, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2009/10/that-your-burdens-may-be-light</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2009-general-conference/2009-10-1040-elder-l-whitney-clayton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5534544" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2009 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Time Shall Come</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come?lang=eng</link>
      <description>With you, I stand in awe as this work moves forward miraculously, marvelously, and irresistibly.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50029123_000_1030" doc-version="2" hash="TRErQw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="TY8uT3u8j0-5u5bVV4dmFw" hash="_bZJ5g">The Time Shall Come</h1><p class="authorName" guid="18c0dfd9-dde4-4558-8070-b6b6285858bf" pid="iBIb3bSH10eFpSo9LfDg9A" hash="Kn78eg">L. Whitney Clayton</p><p class="kicker" pid="mIToHY3vxE2KZSYPZACDRw" hash="lc4A2A">With you, I stand in awe as this work moves forward miraculously, marvelously, and irresistibly.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="b54f2cc6-b8fd-4173-9c4b-e8db6a9282de">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p1" guid="dfd6d448-c37e-41d9-8e5f-e70a639ff2c2" pid="120vEZzZDkqQnGBZjzuXfw" hash="jxaTag">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="11"></span>I served as a young missionary for several months in the central areas of Lima, Peru. As a result, I crossed Lima’s Plaza de Armas many times. The Government Palace, the official residence and office of Peru’s president, faces the plaza. My companions and I invited people in the plaza to hear the restored gospel. I often wondered then what it would be like to enter the palace, but the thought of ever doing so seemed wildly remote.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p2" guid="ae5e2b8d-04da-44d7-b621-4e214f7be8cc" pid="djxCLwlahkOdW6bNZXipeg" hash="OTdGZQ">Last year, Elder D. Todd Christofferson of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles, a few others, and I met with Alan García, then the president of Peru, in the Government Palace. We were shown its beautiful rooms and cordially received by President García. My young missionary wonderings about the palace were fulfilled in a way that I would never have dreamed possible in 1970.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p3" guid="c85c9012-d4e9-4f8b-bc62-678f656eecd4" pid="weUzAv-7zki628VlOanZ3A" hash="0nBcUQ">Things have changed in Peru since I was a missionary, especially for the Church. There were about 11,000 members of the Church there then and just one stake. Today there are more than 500,000 members and almost 100 stakes. In towns where there were just little groups of members, vibrant stakes and attractive meetinghouses now grace the land. The same thing has happened in many other countries around the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p4" guid="12f39dfb-3b15-47f3-ba7c-56257880a7f5" pid="io2aWkHKQkW8psyTXwGrcA" hash="2SBuKA">This remarkable Church growth deserves explanation. We begin with a prophecy from the Old Testament.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p5" guid="09e595a1-9ca9-4734-a0a6-e372b4575d2d" pid="X7w8S5mCBECkhf-32fcBRQ" hash="3ctOhg">Daniel was a Hebrew slave in Babylon. He was given the opportunity to interpret King Nebuchadnezzar’s dream. Daniel asked God to reveal to him the dream and its interpretation, and his prayer was answered. He told Nebuchadnezzar, “There is a God in heaven that revealeth secrets, and maketh known to the king Nebuchadnezzar what shall be in the latter days. … The visions of thy head upon thy bed, are these.” Daniel said the king had seen a frightening image with a head, torso, arms, legs, and feet. A stone was cut out of a mountain without hands and rolled forth, gradually growing in size. That stone collided with the image, breaking it into pieces, “and the stone that smote the image became a great mountain, and filled the whole earth.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p6" guid="efbf53c3-9e88-4225-a3f9-a1c7f101ba46" pid="Jcr1VNhn0USVc7UKbgOfkg" hash="AmUrxg">Daniel explained that the image represented future political kingdoms and that “in the days of [those future] kings shall the God of heaven set up a kingdom, which shall never be destroyed: … but it shall break” these kingdoms into pieces and consume them. “And it shall stand for ever.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p7" guid="850a5d11-db8a-4596-8658-9b27d7a73c07" pid="nJxF0ZYZWEmvWqRODKmQNg" hash="mhoYZQ">We now go to more recent times. The angel Moroni first appeared to <span class="pageBreak" page-number="12"></span>Joseph Smith in 1823 and told him “that God had a work for [him] to do; and that [his] name should be had for good and evil among all nations, kindreds, and tongues.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Moroni’s message surely must have astonished Joseph, who was just 17.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p8" guid="df60107a-2b1b-4575-b2c1-541efcb14afa" pid="Yg9fyNASB0KxbPZVkZxqSA" hash="4nl-qA">In 1831, the Lord told Joseph that the keys of the kingdom of God had again been “committed unto man on the earth.” He said the “gospel [would] roll forth unto the ends of the earth, as the stone which is cut out of the mountain without hands … , until it has filled the whole earth,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> just as Daniel had told Nebuchadnezzar.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p9" guid="893ae799-9f5e-41ef-99b1-2054a6945c3f" pid="5lS_6MOORE-B2q9xiOfPiA" hash="ZLKBTw">In 1898, President Wilford Woodruff recounted an experience he had as a new member in 1834 at a priesthood meeting in Kirtland. He related: “The Prophet called on all who held the Priesthood to gather into the little log school house they had there. It was a small house, perhaps 14 feet [4.3 m] square. … When we got together the Prophet called upon the Elders of Israel … to bear testimony of this work. … When they got through the Prophet said, ‘Brethren I have been very much edified and instructed in your testimonies here tonight, but I want to say to you before the Lord, that you know no more concerning the destinies of this Church and kingdom than a babe upon its mother’s lap. You don’t comprehend it. … It is only a little handfull of Priesthood you see here tonight, but this Church will fill North and South America—it will fill the world.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.f1"><p pid="VEVswMZ_O02WrfVviV7mYQ" hash="IJVs3g">These prophecies that:</p><ul class="bullet" guid="e315386f-922a-4db7-ab58-25100f9eaef2"><li guid="0453f359-270e-4573-88b8-790fd5cbde0b" pid="xDzW8NUvJ0eVoHmKs3tiNQ" hash="ZinfSQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p guid="e69709c6-9d0c-45b1-b1ec-ed213ba1fa52" pid="wNs2GzhGO06kiJEWE8QPCw" hash="zZO6wg">the kingdom of God like a stone cut out of a mountain would fill the earth;</p>
        </li><li guid="a45ebfe8-217d-4a35-a560-2d730df9d013" pid="8mB619zMIkqTWstVCX2nGw" hash="GnqKQw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p guid="5c029a45-7900-4796-a44e-f214f448efa9" pid="Oi--SYDZ4kO2IG_WJaBFGA" hash="HiDnFw">the name of Joseph Smith would be known throughout the world; and</p>
        </li><li guid="02152d49-1501-4e29-b86a-5cacf2aba026" pid="58lnvVuYlUW77Hcwy5Yfbw" hash="kVfxhA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p guid="9c5ee5c1-0cb6-43ea-a789-9d9a8e87be6a" pid="Wwv6iRlo0k-oBbvyx7TdzA" hash="pn01JQ">the Church would fill the Americas and fill the world</p>
        </li></ul></div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p10" guid="78efb040-617e-422d-8aa3-076529bb9205" pid="vSJj7fAcLUqAiOTU0odxvw" hash="fQlUuA">might have seemed laughable 170 years ago. The little band of believers, eking out a living on the American frontier and moving to escape persecution, didn’t look like the foundation of a faith that would cross international borders and penetrate hearts everywhere.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p11" guid="efc6430c-075e-48d0-aa11-90f245b3aa5c" pid="k2Hi_0z-wUKprEcCZmsCUQ" hash="wVlvSw">But that is just what has happened. Let me give an example.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p12" guid="42dadf0c-037f-4d39-9204-7011454fe9ce" pid="WnzC1rgffkOQ1D-tBnC4Uw" hash="STA4Kw">On Christmas Day 1925 in Buenos Aires, Argentina, Elder Melvin J. Ballard dedicated the entire continent of South America for the preaching of the gospel. By August 1926 a handful of converts had been baptized. They were the first members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints baptized in all of South America. That was 85 years ago, within the life span of many who are listening to conference today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p13" guid="17d1c2b3-5974-4441-a8d3-1e27a2b11ca7" pid="2A_KZw_--kCf3DgjoabnTg" hash="FCvTyQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="13"></span>There are 23 stakes of Zion in Buenos Aires today, with dozens of stakes and tens of thousands of Church members in cities and towns across Argentina. Now there are well over 600 stakes and several million Church members throughout South America. While we watch, the kingdom of God is filling the continent, and the name of Joseph Smith is being published both by us and by his detractors in countries he may never even have heard of during his lifetime.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p14" guid="f7e0f1dd-0eed-467e-8435-10bf6dbb70dd" pid="kG25D55OnkGlbzxhkoQGfw" hash="CXMAIw">There are nearly 3,000 stakes in the worldwide Church today, from Boston to Bangkok and from Mexico City to Moscow. We are approaching 29,000 wards and branches. In many countries there are mature stakes, with members whose ancestors were converts. In others, small groups of new members meet as tiny Church branches in rented houses. Every year the Church spreads farther and farther across the globe.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p15" guid="6b45e2e7-0ec7-4399-9533-8690e28ff200" pid="is8TK0GwY06F1JVztQKUtw" hash="b8wdmA">These prophecies about filling the world and being known world over: Preposterous? Perhaps. Unlikely? Undoubtedly. Impossible? Emphatically no. It is happening before our eyes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p16" guid="ba74acde-d74d-4c09-b9b6-129c3faa5b66" pid="WoHIW4sIAU6iEu6Yy2IY9A" hash="Ztv21Q">President Gordon B. Hinckley observed:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p17" guid="500e628a-a3b7-4325-b7f9-efe227919961" pid="H1eq_kWUh0ikKbBX59NqCg" hash="tgsm3w">“It was said that at one time the sun never set on the British Empire. That empire has now been diminished. But it is true that the sun never sets on this work of the Lord as it is touching the lives of people across the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p18" guid="300f6636-8ec9-4f0e-8877-529fb716ead5" pid="7CWv1FmykkSG6muFvDFloA" hash="tANpeg">“And this is only the beginning. We have scarcely scratched the surface. … Our work knows no boundaries. … Those nations now closed to us will someday be open.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p19" guid="0cbde592-fac5-437c-af90-89caa6074617" pid="O6kggD1Dn0iTTxj9q6J-kw" hash="2gC-fw">Today we can see that the fulfillment of a Book of Mormon prophecy draws close:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p20" guid="f35d0fcb-fa2d-42b2-8518-28b68337e075" pid="SbZexD89K02LNDU7vCKFZg" hash="W6Emrg">“And … it shall come to pass that kings shall shut their mouths; for that which had not been told them shall they see; and that which they had not heard shall they consider.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p21" guid="49bb3744-b0e6-49bf-88ae-9ad23905730d" pid="jehvUaEG5EO-TjKjzQHr0Q" hash="enbmfA">“For in that day, for my sake shall the Father work a work, which shall be a great and a marvelous work among them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p22" guid="65812bf8-eaae-4304-ac6e-5af0ce7387af" pid="nv1-kkAQBUO4Vhdrsib8YA" hash="khHUuA">This work of the Lord is indeed great and marvelous, but it moves forward essentially unnoticed by many of mankind’s political, cultural, and academic leaders. It progresses one heart and one family at a time, silently and unobtrusively, its sacred message blessing people everywhere.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p23" guid="97e9affa-777d-4cf6-8757-ce58a3da7299" pid="OwdtB4fntUG91U7PmIdHLw" hash="5Ji1yA">A verse in the Book of Mormon provides a key to the miraculous growth of the Church today: “And moreover, I say unto you, that the time shall come when the knowledge of a Savior shall spread throughout every nation, kindred, tongue, and people.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p24" guid="5ad2e63c-f8e1-457a-b811-9e75bbad0285" pid="Y6G700GgyUioeplSHAzYoA" hash="brVYbw">Our most important message, which we are both divinely commissioned and commanded to take everywhere in the world, is that there is a Savior. He lived in the meridian of time. He atoned for our sins, was crucified, and was resurrected. That matchless message, which we proclaim with authority from God, is the real reason this Church grows as it does.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p25" guid="bc1c9019-b818-4506-ab43-a074d42ccdab" pid="7uG9xn_MpU65RZuWonMJbQ" hash="gwncug">I testify that He appeared with His Father to Joseph Smith. Under the direction of the Father, He established His gospel anew upon the earth. He sent apostles, prophets, and priesthood keys to the earth again. He leads His Church through a living prophet, President Thomas S. Monson. His Church is that stone cut out of the mountain without hands that rolls forward across the globe.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come.p26" guid="0b611d59-b489-4bbe-bcb9-8fb5770ea14a" pid="kiD3qf6ibUWO9NW_IrCXeQ" hash="UTmq_w">We are grateful for Joseph Smith and watch with wonder as his name is revered and, yes, even reviled ever more widely across the earth. But we recognize that this mighty latter-day work is not about him. It is the work of Almighty God and His Son, the Prince of Peace. I testify that Jesus Christ is the Savior, and with you, I stand in awe as this work moves forward miraculously, marvelously, and irresistibly. Indeed, “the time [has] come when the knowledge of a Savior … spread[s] throughout every nation, kindred, tongue, and people.” I bear testimony of Him, the Savior of all mankind, and of this work in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/10/the-time-shall-come</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2011-general-conference/2011-10-1030-elder-l-whitney-clayton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5435819" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marriage: Watch and Learn</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The promises of the Lord are extended to all those who follow the pattern of life that builds happy, holy marriage relationships.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10785_000_44clayton" doc-version="2" hash="gdJynA">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="NRB53M7MHk6GxFTemz1Iow" hash="iAhplQ">Marriage: Watch and Learn</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="_9cgC5BPEEuZDRq6Wf0Waw" hash="5RaOYQ">By Elder L. Whitney Clayton</p>
		<p class="kicker" pid="GZRqBx66qEevq5nsq0r3Iw" hash="ipkV4g">The promises of the Lord are extended to all those who follow the pattern of life that builds happy, holy marriage relationships.</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="xGMXvdS4DkmTHopE1QrK5w" hash="Qk9stw">
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn.p5" pid="XPUi-gZMgU6KmEd-QaPi-A" hash="A_Vqaw">
				<span class="pageBreak" page-number="83"></span>One evening several years ago, my wife and I were visiting the home of one of our sons and his wife and children for dinner. It was a typical event for a family with small children: there was much noise and even more fun. Shortly after dinner our four-year-old granddaughter, Anna, and I were still sitting at the table. Realizing that she had my full attention, she stood up straight on a bench and fixed her eyes on me. When she was sure that I was looking at her, she solemnly ordered me to “watch and learn.” She then danced and sang a song for me.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn.p6" pid="y9V63cbFxEyeBVit2TRpyA" hash="l_2blA">Anna’s instruction to “watch and learn” was wisdom from the mouth of a babe. We <span class="emphasis">can</span> learn so much by watching and then considering what we have seen and felt. In that spirit, let me share with you a few principles I have observed by watching and learning from wonderful, faithful marriages. These principles build strong, satisfying marriages that are compatible with heavenly principles. I invite you to watch and learn with me.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn.p7" pid="irUi9mIGB0GtvGlTPhXkWA" hash="JvdAIg">First, I have observed that in the happiest marriages both the husband and wife consider their relationship to be a pearl beyond price, a treasure of infinite worth. They both leave their fathers and mothers and set out together to build a marriage that will prosper for eternity. They understand that they walk a divinely ordained path. They know that no other relationship of any kind can bring as much joy, generate as much good, or produce as much personal refinement. Watch and learn: the best marriage partners regard their marriages as priceless.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn.p8" pid="H15WlX6blESspd3brY5c8Q" hash="dUcO3w">Next, faith. Successful eternal marriages are built on the foundation of faith in the Lord Jesus Christ and adherence to His teachings.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> I have observed that couples who have made their marriages priceless practice the patterns of faith: they attend sacrament and other meetings every week, hold family home evening, pray and study the scriptures together and as individuals, and pay an honest tithing. Their mutual quest is to be obedient and good. They do not consider the commandments to be a buffet from which they can pick and choose only the most appealing offerings.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn.p9" pid="avBZ8VYel06yzQlIgQY8hg" hash="yAdimw">
			<span class="pageBreak" page-number="84"></span>Faith is the foundation of every virtue that strengthens marriage. Strengthening faith strengthens marriage. Faith grows as we keep the commandments, and so do the harmony and joy in marriage. Thus, keeping the commandments is fundamental to establishing strong eternal marriages. Watch and learn: faith in the Lord Jesus Christ is the foundation of happy eternal marriages.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn.p10" pid="xsY-oQKaAUuOHTvmW5Y68A" hash="ygl9nQ">Third, repentance. I have learned that happy marriages rely on the gift of repentance. It is an essential element in every good marital relationship. Spouses who regularly conduct honest self-examination and promptly take needed steps to repent and improve experience a healing balm in their marriages. Repentance helps restore and maintain harmony and peace.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn.p11" pid="JctCDT5dDUK3XRa_q7iD8A" hash="4gYkVQ">Humility is the essence of repentance. Humility is selfless, not selfish. It doesn’t demand its own way or speak with moral superiority. Instead, humility answers softly<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> and listens kindly for understanding, not vindication. Humility recognizes that no one can change someone else, but with faith, effort, and the help of God, <span class="emphasis">we</span> can undergo <span class="emphasis">our own</span> mighty change of heart.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Experiencing the mighty change of heart causes us to treat others, especially our spouses, with meekness.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Humility means that both husbands and wives seek to bless, help, and lift each other, putting the other first in every decision. Watch and learn: repentance and humility build happy marriages.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn.p12" pid="2O4-WyUeoky6c1M7hn9Rhw" hash="YE9AIw">Fourth, respect. I have observed that in wonderful, happy marriages, husbands and wives treat each other as equal partners. Practices from any place or any time in which husbands have dominated wives or treated them in any way as second-class partners in marriage are not in keeping with divine law and should be replaced by correct principles and patterns of behavior.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn.p13" pid="oRMrOKvfiEOjgTcH9ppGmw" hash="AK31kQ">Husbands and wives in great marriages make decisions unanimously, with each of them acting as a full participant and entitled to an equal voice and vote.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> They focus first on the home and on helping each other with their shared responsibilities.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> Their marriages are based on cooperation, not negotiation. Their dinner hour and the family time that follows become the center of their day and the object of their best efforts. They turn off electronics and forgo personal entertainment in order to help with household duties. To the extent possible, they read with their children every night and both participate in putting the little ones to bed. They retire to their bed together. As their duties and circumstances permit, husbands and wives work side by side in doing the most important work there is—the work we do in our own homes.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn.p14" pid="bqfH2IqLa0CvPAGmEW3d0Q" hash="DYShWg">Where there is respect, there is also transparency, which is a key element of happy marriages. There are no secrets about relevant matters in marriages based on mutual respect and transparency. Husbands and wives make all decisions about finances together, and both have access to all information.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn.p15" pid="snOwREetoUS8qjcJ7pzchA" hash="XtUh-A">Loyalty is a form of respect. Prophets teach that successful marriage partners are “fiercely loyal” to each other.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> They keep their social media use fully worthy in every way. They permit themselves no secret Internet experiences. They freely share with each other their social network passwords. They do not look at the virtual profiles of anyone in any way that might betray the sacred trust of their spouse. They never do or say anything that approaches the appearance of impropriety, either virtually or physically. Watch and learn: terrific marriages are completely <span class="pageBreak" page-number="85"></span>respectful, transparent, and loyal.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn.p16" pid="VAl8RnDzN06z1g2jrU-pNQ" hash="z9zUpA">Fifth, love. The happiest marriages I have seen radiate obedience to one of the happiest commandments—that we “live together in love.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Speaking to husbands, the Lord commanded, “Thou shalt love thy wife with all thy heart, and shalt cleave unto her and none else.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> A Church handbook teaches: “The word <span class="emphasis">cleave</span> means to be completely devoted and faithful to someone. Married couples cleave to God and one another by serving and loving each other and by keeping covenants in complete fidelity to one another and to God.” Both the husband and wife “leave behind their single life and establish their marriage as [their] first priority. … They allow no other person or interest to have greater priority … than keeping the covenants they have made with God and each other.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Watch and learn: successful couples love each other with complete devotion.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn.p17" pid="cpE3XoYCnE-7K5Za01lLtg" hash="0K2nng">There are those whose marriages are not as happy as they would wish, as well as those who have never married, are divorced, are single parents, or for various reasons are not in a position to marry. These circumstances can be full of challenge and heartbreak, but they need not be eternal. To those of you in such situations who nevertheless “cheerfully do all things that lie in [your] power”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> to persevere, may heaven bless you richly. Seek after the ideal of forming an eternal marriage, including by striving or preparing to be a worthy spouse. Keep the commandments, and trust the Lord and His perfect love for you. One day every promised blessing concerning marriage will be yours.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn.p18" pid="3xcKxljN1EiQr21ApGXkjw" hash="H4bfDg">One of the sweetest verses in the Book of Mormon states simply, “And they were married, and given in marriage, and were blessed according to the multitude of the promises which the Lord had made unto them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> The promises of the Lord are extended to all those who follow the pattern of life that builds happy, holy marriage relationships. Such blessings come as the delightful, predictable consequences of faithfully living the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn.p19" pid="-9mRByDqn0-lbj_CugdxGg" hash="AUfwTg">I am grateful for my wonderful wife, Kathy, who is the love of my life.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn.p20" pid="dIRfma_xBkyYxwG_zeviHg" hash="RaUXaA">Marriage is a gift from God to us; the quality of our marriages is a gift from us to Him. I bear testimony of the marvelous plan of our loving Heavenly Father, which provides for eternal, wondrous marriage. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2013/04/marriage-watch-and-learn</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2013-general-conference/2013-04-4040-elder-l-whitney-clayton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5099510" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choose to Believe</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder L. Whitney Clayton of the Seventy teaches that we follow spiritual light in our lives when we choose to believe in the Savior and His gospel.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_12565_000_15clayton" doc-version="5" hash="FiWGHQ">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="IoOJGQ4AG0KnzuurE3lX4w" hash="_PY-MA">Choose to Believe</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p2" pid="4UBTUUplRkGlt5ONU_qoow" hash="5RaOYQ">By Elder L. Whitney Clayton</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p3" pid="E-jHHhXrl0aeMDTd43jW7Q" hash="hptprg">Of the Presidency of the Seventy</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=9iS9UcBHbU2zWcK1-dJt6Q"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" type="jpg" uri="l-whitney-clayton-10.jpg" translate="no" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255507/4bcd99db79f94d9fae34a93440274dc1/100x125.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x62="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255507/4bcd99db79f94d9fae34a93440274dc1/50x62.jpg" data-src-100x125="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255507/4bcd99db79f94d9fae34a93440274dc1/100x125.jpg" data-src-200x250="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255507/4bcd99db79f94d9fae34a93440274dc1/200x250.jpg" data-src-320x400="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255507/4bcd99db79f94d9fae34a93440274dc1/320x400.jpg" data-src-460x576="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255507/4bcd99db79f94d9fae34a93440274dc1/460x576.jpg" data-src-640x801="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255507/4bcd99db79f94d9fae34a93440274dc1/640x801.jpg" data-src-1024x1283="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255507/4bcd99db79f94d9fae34a93440274dc1/1024x1283.jpg" data-src-2048x2566="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255507/4bcd99db79f94d9fae34a93440274dc1/2048x2566.jpg" data-src-3874x4854="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255507/4bcd99db79f94d9fae34a93440274dc1/3874x4854.jpg" pid="9iS9UcBHbU2zWcK1-dJt6Q" hash="t4Zcnw"></img></a>
		</div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="xTCQFYlCnUeMBGlh8-DdaA" hash="BS44CQ">The Savior provides His gospel as a light to guide those who choose to believe in and follow Him.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="pe9V6wJ790KdSsDfZHxQ9A" hash="5RaOYQ1">By Elder L. Whitney Clayton</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="yYiVRD23CUypxioiBeDGKQ" hash="4a0xEg">
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p5" pid="b_HXXb-sx0G5qEmo0HEg1w" hash="JjVKDQ">Last January, seven-year-old Sailor Gutzler and her family were flying from Florida to Illinois in a private airplane. Sailor’s father was at the controls. Just after nightfall, the aircraft developed mechanical problems and crashed in the pitch-dark hills of Kentucky, upside down in very rough terrain. Everyone but Sailor died in the accident. Her wrist was broken in the crash. She suffered cuts and scrapes and had lost her shoes. The temperature was 38 degrees Fahrenheit (or 3 degrees Celsius)—it was a cold, rainy Kentucky winter’s night—and Sailor was wearing only shorts, a T-shirt, and one sock.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p6" pid="m_PfXjkJBESwN8kWGg_dSA" hash="FUBwhg">She cried out for her mother and father, but no one answered. Summoning every ounce of courage, she set off barefoot across the countryside in search of help, wading through creeks, crossing ditches, and braving blackberry briars. From the top of one small hill, Sailor spotted a light in the distance, about a mile away. Stumbling through the darkness and brush toward that light, she eventually arrived at the home of a kind man she had never met before who sprang to her care. Sailor was safe. She would soon be taken to a hospital and helped on her way to recovery.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p7" pid="rAO-gKZHH0SINF5sv82xtw" hash="QER1Kw">Sailor survived because she saw a light in the distance and fought her way to it—notwithstanding the wild countryside, the depth of the tragedy she faced, and the injuries she had sustained. It is hard to imagine how Sailor managed to do what she did that night. But what we do know is that she recognized in the light of that distant house a chance for rescue. There was hope. She took courage in the fact that no matter how bad things were, her rescue would be found in that light.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p8" pid="jOlJnLJK6UCUSBYP7bMmCg" hash="rhd96A">Few of us will ever endure an experience as harrowing as Sailor’s. But all of us will, at some time or another, have to traverse our own spiritual wilderness and undertake our own rugged emotional journeys. In those moments, however dark or seemingly hopeless they may be, if we search for it, there will <span class="emphasis">always</span> be a spiritual light that beckons to us, giving us the hope of rescue and relief. That light shines from the Savior of all mankind, who is the Light of the World.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p9" pid="XpQlpjhysU2OBf0xvR7Ltw" hash="2lFe5Q">Perceiving spiritual light is different from seeing physical light. Recognizing the Savior’s spiritual light begins with our willingness to believe. God requires that initially we at least desire to believe. “If ye will awake and arouse your faculties … and exercise a <span class="emphasis">particle</span> of faith,” the prophet Alma teaches, “yea, even if ye can no more than <span class="emphasis">desire</span> to believe, let this desire work in you, even until ye believe in a manner that ye can give place for a portion of [the Savior’s] words.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p10" pid="ha9MXIVWd0CFSlKDGH9rcA" hash="kMfcVA">Alma’s call for us to desire to believe and to “give place” in our hearts for the Savior’s words reminds us that belief and faith require our personal choice and action. We must “awake and arouse [our] faculties.” We ask before it is given unto us; we seek before we find; we knock before it is opened unto us. We are then given this promise: “For every one that asketh, receiveth; and he that seeketh, findeth; and to him that knocketh, it shall be opened.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p11" pid="ZM3OmFAeLE6M5T7Gl8ADjQ" hash="CBFgsg">No more impassioned plea for us to believe has come than from the Savior Himself, during His earthly ministry, when He appealed to His disbelieving listeners:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p12" pid="lRyV4U7WykKS2eHvJle1pg" hash="rzv-4Q">“If I do not the works of my Father, believe me not.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p13" pid="OSJqmSRfckqcjE95dpOJ0g" hash="spzj4w">“But if I do, though ye believe not me, believe the works: that ye may know, and believe, that the Father is in me, and I in him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p14" pid="Z_0RYAvzFUiqvSNNwUQF7Q" hash="9RFK-w">Every day each of us faces a test. It is the test of our lifetimes: will we choose to believe in Him and allow the light of His gospel to grow within us, or will we refuse to believe and insist on traveling alone in the dark? The Savior provides His gospel as a light to guide those who choose to believe in and follow Him.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p15" pid="HMF8-CkMhkSj6C2wCURaxw" hash="YpfdeA">After the crash, Sailor had a choice. She could have chosen to stay by the airplane in the dark, alone and afraid. But there was a long night ahead, and it was just going to get colder. She chose another way. Sailor climbed up a hill, and there she saw a light on the horizon.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p16" pid="BXFhYVXOHUub4pSR7UHIGg" hash="ykM7Ww">Gradually, as she made her way through the night toward the light, it grew brighter. Still, there must have been times when she could not see it. Perhaps it went out of view when she was in a ravine or behind trees or bushes, but she pressed on. Whenever she could see the light, Sailor had evidence that she was on the right path. She did not yet know precisely what that light was, but she kept walking toward it based on what she knew, trusting and hoping that she would see it again if she kept moving in the right direction. By so doing, she may have saved her life.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p17" pid="YuY3YJnoEkGrISn6rj2l1A" hash="SfYJ3g">Our lives can be like that too. There may be times when we have been hurt, when we are tired, and when our lives seem dark and cold. There may be times when we cannot see any light on the horizon, and we may feel like giving up. If we are willing to believe, if we desire to believe, if we choose to believe, then the Savior’s teachings and example will show us the pathway forward.</p>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.t1">
			<h2 pid="kSwwqy_0DkKOsDXm98K8VA" hash="_PY-MA1">Choose to Believe</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p19" pid="UvKAooF_QEe7jQpZoAs7jw" hash="kjpqcg">Just as Sailor had to believe that she would find safety in that distant light, so we too must choose to open our hearts to the divine reality of the Savior—to His eternal light and His healing mercy. Prophets across the ages have encouraged us and even implored us to believe in Christ. Their exhortations reflect a fundamental fact: God does not force us to believe. Instead He invites us to believe by sending living prophets and apostles to teach us, by providing scriptures, and by beckoning to us through His Spirit. We are the ones who must choose to embrace those spiritual invitations, electing to see with inward eyes the spiritual light with which He calls us. The decision to believe is the most important choice we ever make. It shapes all our other decisions.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p20" pid="HJMwIIlxw0ud3W1WYE2nwQ" hash="KuI-_Q">God does not compel us to believe any more than He compels us to keep any commandments, despite His perfect desire to bless us. Yet His call to us to believe in Him—to exercise that particle of faith and to give place for His words—remains in effect today. As the Savior said, “I bear record that the Father commandeth all men, everywhere, to repent and believe in me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p21" pid="AOtypYNLX022WizPGgzIRA" hash="OpqXMg">Belief and testimony and faith are not passive principles. They do not just happen to us. Belief is something we choose—we hope for it, we work for it, and we sacrifice for it. We will not accidentally come to believe in the Savior and His gospel any more than we will accidentally pray or pay tithing. We actively choose to believe, just like we choose to keep other commandments.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.t2">
			<h2 pid="h2UT-3VuWEi9vtxLh9yoqA" hash="bju0Pw">Put Belief into Action</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p23" pid="YQRq9A6Ag0WIIhAn6tJHxA" hash="lHTLOA">Sailor could not know at first if what she was doing as she pushed her way through the underbrush would actually work. She was lost and injured; it was dark and cold. But she left the crash site and ventured out in hope of rescue, crawling and scraping her way forward until she saw a light in the distance. Once she had seen it, she did her best to move toward it, remembering what she had seen.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p24" pid="MZBQe9H7A06BI0xPWudf1A" hash="5c9JTg">We likewise must give place for the hope that we will find spiritual light by embracing belief rather than choosing to doubt. Our actions are the evidence of our belief and become the substance of our faith. We are choosing to believe when we pray and when we read the scriptures. We are choosing to believe when we fast, when we keep the Sabbath day holy, and when we worship in the temple. We are choosing to believe when we are baptized and when we partake of the sacrament. We are choosing to believe when we repent and seek divine forgiveness and healing love.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.t3">
			<h2 pid="eL0S3B3G3E2j2gBStwHmBQ" hash="OZm-pw">Never Give Up</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p26" pid="R_dZ5JURlEi6dWJ_tEocng" hash="HeRleQ">Sometimes progress in spiritual things can seem slow or intermittent. Sometimes we may feel that we have lost ground, that we have made mistakes, or that our best efforts to find the Savior are not working. If you feel this way, please do not give up—ever. Go right on believing in Him and in His gospel and His Church. Align your actions with that belief. In those moments when the light of your faith has dimmed, let your hope for the Savior’s love and grace, found in His gospel and His Church, overcome your doubt. I promise that He stands ready to receive you. Over time you will come to see that you have made the best choice you could possibly have made. Your courageous decision to believe in Him will bless you immeasurably and forever.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.t4">
			<h2 pid="zQwldKEQuUaPtWOY-ET5kQ" hash="M5sxxg">The Blessings of Belief</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p28" pid="AHDWIokpzkS054vCb6G_Ew" hash="4FOQcQ">I have felt the merciful love of the Savior in my life. I have searched for Him in my own moments of darkness, and He has reached out to me with His healing light. One of the great joys of my life has been traveling with my wife, Kathy, to meet with members of the Church in many corners of the globe. These wonderful encounters have taught me and taught us about God’s love for His children. They have shown me the limitless potential for happiness that becomes the blessing of those who choose to follow the teachings of the Lord Jesus Christ. I have learned that believing in Him and in His redemptive power is the true path to “peace in this world, and eternal life in the world to come.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe.p29" pid="vwLSqlD8kE6DThqFrWarFQ" hash="z5BTpw">I testify that Jesus Christ is the source of light and hope for all of us. I pray that we may all choose to believe in Him. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/04/choose-to-believe</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2015-general-conference/2015-04-1050-elder-l-whitney-clayton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5495729" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whatsoever He Saith unto You, Do It</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Clayton teaches that as we obey God’s commandments, even in small ways, He will bless us with faith and strength.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60003501_000_55clayton" doc-version="1" hash="PIGQiw">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="BS5iXU3sN0KNAqv769UkFQ" hash="f3apQA1">Whatsoever He Saith unto You, Do It</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p2" pid="qtOGACZtSk2Y-1mYQnmWIw" hash="5RaOYQ1">By Elder L. Whitney Clayton</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p3" pid="gea6SJ-TME2A7LHZI4My6g" hash="hptprg">Of the Presidency of the Seventy</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="Bmtz_fCPIECOBgGnhExauQ" hash="XtY9Ng">When we decide to do “whatsoever [God] saith unto” us, we earnestly commit to align our everyday behavior with God’s will.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="FD3mGrO1hUqugq_sNxGWmw" hash="5RaOYQ">By Elder L. Whitney Clayton</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p5" pid="HmEYfioidUGmlScQNXJnKw" hash="TN8PxA">The Savior performed His first recorded miracle at a wedding feast in Cana of Galilee. Mary, His mother, and His disciples were there as well. Mary apparently felt some responsibility for the success of the feast. During the celebration, a problem arose—the wedding hosts ran out of wine. Mary was concerned and went to Jesus. They spoke briefly; then Mary turned to the servants and said:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p6" pid="2EHtgqb-wEaLxE4Nc3mJ_g" hash="f3apQA">“Whatsoever he saith unto you, do it.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p7" pid="QGXNxl8oHU64HbZFYIpsPg" hash="ZJlwvQ">“And there were set there six waterpots of stone. … [These waterpots weren’t used to store drinking water but were used for ceremonial washings under the law of Moses.]</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p8" pid="8qskWL03dUa819JTPF_qaA" hash="idRofw">“Jesus saith unto [the servants], Fill the waterpots with water. And they filled them up to the brim.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p9" pid="vfbZAPn7jUaY4e-Z-K6f9g" hash="F3hcXA">“And he saith unto them, Draw out now, and bear unto the governor of the feast. And they bare it.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p10" pid="Jd9wrcxVukC6imHpXY1tXg" hash="NMRRww">“[Then] the ruler of the feast … tasted the water that was made wine” and expressed surprise that the best wine was served so late in the feast.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p11" pid="l2VOe2x7Bkagtz481JMlgw" hash="15N7Bg">We usually remember this event because transforming water to wine was a demonstration of the power of God—it was a miracle. That is an important message, but there is another important message in John’s account. Mary was “a precious and chosen vessel,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> called by God to give birth to, nurture, and raise the very Son of God. She knew more about Him than anyone else on earth. She knew the truth of His miraculous birth. She knew that He was sinless and that He “spake not as other men, neither could he be taught; for he needed not that any man should teach him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Mary knew of His extraordinary capacity to solve problems, including one as personal as providing wine for a wedding feast. She had unshakable confidence in Him and in His divine power. Her simple, straightforward instruction to the servants had no caveats, no qualifications, no limitations: “Whatsoever he saith unto you, do it.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p12" pid="m_pcuZ9qA0-lMq2b79IkOg" hash="vqFkIQ">Mary had been a young woman when the angel Gabriel appeared unto her. At first she had been “troubled” by being called “highly favoured” and “blessed … among women … and cast in her mind what manner of salutation this should be.” Gabriel reassured her that she had nothing to fear—the news he brought was good. She would “conceive in [her] womb … the Son of the Highest” and “bring forth a son … [who] shall reign over the house of Jacob for ever.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p13" pid="9bU3cMc02E21RXO77aowmA" hash="C98GOg">Mary wondered aloud, “How shall this be, seeing I know not a man?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p14" pid="wwM8_ds2p0i8lO1EXQ3yBw" hash="ZVLKQw">The angel explained but only briefly, affirming to her that “with God nothing [is] impossible.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p15" pid="h0fwwyYWRkeD-o3_Bog9Hg" hash="A3belg">Mary humbly responded that she would do what God asked, without demanding to know specifics and undoubtedly in spite of having countless questions about the implications for her life. She committed herself without exactly understanding why He was asking that of her or how things would work out. She accepted God’s word unconditionally and in advance,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> with little knowledge of what lay ahead. With simple trust in God, Mary said, “Behold the handmaid of the Lord; be it unto me according to thy word.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p16" pid="2gh_hJuEqEyw2ms7mpnxVg" hash="tyBvvg">When we decide to do “whatsoever [God] saith unto” us, we earnestly commit to align our everyday behavior with God’s will. Such simple acts of faith as studying the scriptures daily, fasting regularly, and praying with real intent deepen our well of spiritual capacity to meet the demands of mortality. Over time, simple habits of belief lead to miraculous results. They transform our faith from a seedling into a dynamic power for good in our lives. Then, when challenges come our way, our rootedness in Christ provides steadfastness for our souls. God shores up our weaknesses, increases our joys, and causes “all things [to] work together for [our] good.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p17" pid="ovz_cmVt90uuIlfFcgZ7QA" hash="HG7Jxg">A few years ago, I spoke with a young bishop who was spending hours each week counseling with members of his ward. He made a striking observation. The problems that members of his ward faced, he said, were those faced by Church members everywhere—issues such as how to establish a happy marriage; struggles with balancing work, family, and Church duties; challenges with the Word of Wisdom, with employment, or with pornography; or trouble gaining peace about a Church policy or historical question they didn’t understand.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p18" pid="J06eVX9jLU-O2nqmcgGttg" hash="3ebgow">His counsel to ward members very often included getting back to simple practices of faith, such as studying the Book of Mormon—as we were counseled by President Thomas S. Monson to do—paying tithing, and serving in the Church with devotion. Frequently, however, their response to him was one of skepticism: “I don’t agree with you, Bishop. We <span class="emphasis">all </span>know those are good things to do. We talk about those things <span class="emphasis">all the time</span> in the Church. But I’m not sure you’re understanding me. What does doing any of <span class="emphasis">those</span> things have to do with the issues <span class="emphasis">I’m</span> facing?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p19" pid="ojppNS5CKUizU8XMTO9hzA" hash="egtLDA">It’s a fair question. Over time, that young bishop and I have observed that those who are deliberate about doing the “small and simple things”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span>—obeying in seemingly little ways—are blessed with faith and strength that go far beyond the actual acts of obedience themselves and, in fact, may seem totally unrelated to them. It may seem hard to draw a connection between the basic daily acts of obedience and solutions to the big, complicated problems we face. But they <span class="emphasis">are</span> related. In my experience, getting the little daily habits of faith right is the single best way to fortify ourselves against the troubles of life, whatever they may be. Small acts of faith, even when they seem insignificant or entirely disconnected from the specific problems that vex us, bless us in <span class="emphasis">all</span> we do.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p20" pid="hXytfaR8x0aK-gz3-FiuZg" hash="i48gvA">Consider Naaman, a “captain of the host of … Syria, … a mighty man in valour,” and a leper. A servant girl told of a prophet in Israel who could heal Naaman, and so he traveled with an escort of servants, soldiers, and gifts to Israel, eventually arriving at Elisha’s house. Elisha’s servant, not Elisha himself, informed Naaman that the Lord’s command was to “go and wash in [the river] Jordan seven times.” A simple thing. Perhaps this simple prescription struck the mighty warrior as so illogical, simplistic, or beneath his dignity that he found the mere suggestion offensive. At the very least, Elisha’s instruction didn’t make sense to Naaman, “so he turned and went away in a rage.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p21" pid="P5oeZ_wftUeS5wbt8KgXHg" hash="5zqQsg">But Naaman’s servants gently approached him and observed that he would have done “some great thing” if Elisha had asked it of him. They noted that since he was asked to do only a small task, shouldn’t he do it, even if he didn’t understand why? Naaman reconsidered his reaction and perhaps skeptically, but obediently, “went … down, and dipped himself seven times in Jordan” and was miraculously healed.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p22" pid="8r4xDjkykUuMoss-6g4Z8A" hash="0JI-7w">Some rewards of obedience do come quickly; others come only after we are tested. In the Pearl of Great Price, we read about Adam’s tireless diligence in keeping the commandment to offer sacrifices, apparently for years. When the angel asked Adam why he was offering sacrifices, he answered, “I know not, save the Lord commanded me.” The angel explained that his sacrifices were “a similitude of the sacrifice of the Only Begotten of the Father.” But that explanation came only after Adam had demonstrated his commitment to obeying the Lord for “many days” without knowing <span class="emphasis">why</span> he was supposed to offer those sacrifices.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p23" pid="0j0Gy9BkMkS8W7BXawkHmw" hash="_moZyQ">God will always bless us for our steadfast obedience to His gospel and loyalty to His Church, but He rarely shows us His timetable for doing so in advance. He doesn’t show us the whole picture from the outset. That is where faith, hope, and trusting in the Lord come in.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p24" pid="7MENrbcEyE6V26On7re55A" hash="VOsrqw">God asks us to bear with Him—to trust Him and to follow Him. He pleads with us to “dispute not because ye see not.” He cautions us that we shouldn’t expect easy answers or quick fixes from heaven. Things work out when we stand firm during the “trial of [our] faith,” however hard that test may be to endure or slow the answer may be in coming.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> I am not speaking of “blind obedience”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> but of thoughtful confidence in the perfect love and the perfect timing of the Lord.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p25" pid="rbfedmCrxkGGBhs_v1bFNQ" hash="5FQT8A">The trial of our faith will <span class="emphasis">always</span> involve staying true to simple, daily practices of faith. Then, and only then, does He promise that we will receive the divine response for which we long. Only once we have proven our willingness to do what He asks without demanding to know the whens, the whys, and the hows do we “reap the rewards of [our] faith, and [our] diligence, and patience, and long-suffering.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Real obedience accepts God’s commandments unconditionally and in advance.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it.p26" pid="rtx_Ypl_-0qRnXqBLvdwgQ" hash="bb1nog">Every day, consciously or otherwise, we all choose “whom [we] will serve.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> We demonstrate our determination to serve the Lord by faithfully engaging in daily acts of devotion. The Lord promises to direct our paths,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> but for Him to do that, we have to walk, trusting that He knows the way because He <span class="emphasis">is</span> “the way.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> We must fill our own waterpots up to the brim. When we trust and follow Him, our lives, like water to wine, are transformed. We become something more and better than we ever otherwise could be. Trust in the Lord, and “whatsoever he saith unto you, do it.” In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2017/04/whatsoever-he-saith-unto-you-do-it</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2017-general-conference/2017-04-4050-l-whitney-clayton-64k-eng.mp3" length="6094217" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
