<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Lance B. Wickman</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Lance B. Wickman.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Lance%20B.%20Wickman.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Lance B. Wickman.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 1994 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>“Stand Ye in Holy Places”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1994/10/stand-ye-in-holy-places?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I shall never forget one night almost three decades ago. My bride, Patricia, and I had been married for two years. We lived in a small duplex on Oahu’s north shore. I was an army infantry officer, a platoon leader, assigned to a unit at Schofield Bar</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/stand-ye-in-holy-places" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_94911_000_032" doc-version="2" hash="g0pZUg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/stand-ye-in-holy-places.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="hOLbkAZBFU2SIcJLtiS26g" hash="X0fkeA">“Stand Ye in Holy Places”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="xdOCqoh8dUy9kpEfWOGHWg" hash="1T1w9w">Lance B. Wickman</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/stand-ye-in-holy-places.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-21f4.jpg" alt="Elder Lance B. Wickman" pid="odWBF3OOk0OR15dBYrFpcA" hash="gu9ltg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/stand-ye-in-holy-places.p1" pid="Qzb8uLrXAE2fhYI_ScLnLQ" hash="GdWy1Q">I shall never forget one night almost three decades ago. My bride, Patricia, and I had been married for two years. We lived in a small duplex on Oahu’s north shore. I was an army infantry officer, a platoon leader, assigned to a unit at Schofield Barracks, Hawaii. Our brigade had been ordered to war in Vietnam. My plane was scheduled for departure after midnight, and a good Latter-day Saint friend had agreed to take me to the airfield at 11:00 <small>P.M.</small></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/stand-ye-in-holy-places.p2" pid="_ogx4DHgZ0KhVRR_fGClrA" hash="xKT4Jg">All through that long evening, Pat and I sat on the sofa in our tiny living room with our fingers intertwined, watching the hands of the clock approach the fateful hour and listening to the soft lapping of the surf against the shore. The ticking of the clock seemed a metronome of mortality in painful contrast to the muffled rushing of the eternal sea. At last the hour of parting arrived. Inside the doorway to our little home, I clutched my bride to my bosom and kissed her one last time, and then I was gone. As I closed the door, I wondered if I had seen my sweetheart for the last time in mortality. It was truly night.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/stand-ye-in-holy-places.p3" pid="iUwz73RbSUG1o4bblnkxdA" hash="QUFzXQ">My friend and I drove silently in the darkness through the sugarcane and pineapple fields of Oahu. My heart felt as though it would break. Then as we passed Schofield, an unseen infantry unit on night maneuvers fired a flare. Its brilliance momentarily lit the inky darkness and seemed to ignite a spiritual flame in the blackness that invested my soul. My thoughts were drawn away from this saddest of days to the very happiest: back to that beautiful December day when Pat and I had entered the holy temple and there were sealed to each other, not just for this life only but for all eternity. I thought of the eternal covenants we had made. Like the sunrise, it dawned on me that no matter what happened in the uncertain future just ahead, Pat would always be mine. When I reached the air base, I telephoned her. In the spirit of a renewed hope and peace born of faith and understanding, we talked and laughed softly before once more bidding each other good-bye. It was only midnight, but for me the sun was already rising.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/stand-ye-in-holy-places.p4" pid="91u0bBlrNkOB_0Gp4wINRw" hash="mEDb7w">On another day in another place, however, the sun was setting on the mortal ministry of the Messiah as he departed the temple at Jerusalem for the last time. Climbing atop the Mount of Olives with his disciples, the Savior prophesied the cataclysmic events that would precede the destruction of Jerusalem and his second coming. He then issued this portentous admonition to his disciples, ancient and modern: “Then you shall <span class="emphasis">stand in the holy place;</span> whoso readeth let him understand” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-m/1.12" class="scriptureRef">JS—M 1:12</a>; emphasis added; see also <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/24.15" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 24:15</a>). Latter-day revelations provide understanding. They teach that in our day, amidst strife and catastrophe and pestilence, there are two kingdoms locked in grim struggle for the souls of men—Zion and Babylon. More than once they repeat the injunction to “stand in holy places” for a refuge from these storms of latter-day life (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/45.32" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 45:32</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/87.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 87:8</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/101.16-23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 101:16–23</a>). Prominent among such holy places, and key to all the others, is the temple of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/stand-ye-in-holy-places.p5" pid="4tnRWQGsbUKKBlW3lTttYQ" hash="Z6U82A">The words <span class="emphasis">Zion</span> and <span class="emphasis">temple</span> belong in the same sentence together. In August 1833, as Saints attempted against much persecution to establish a geographic Zion in Jackson County, Missouri, the Prophet Joseph Smith was counseled in revelation to build a house unto the Lord “for the salvation of Zion” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/97.12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 97:12</a>). The temple is the key to salvation, it said, because it is a place of thanksgiving, a place of instruction, and a place of understanding “in all things” (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/97.12-14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 97:12–14</a>). Then comes this glorious promise: “Yea, and my presence shall be there, for I will come into it, and all the pure in heart that shall come into it <span class="emphasis">shall see God.</span> … Therefore, … let Zion rejoice, for this is Zion—<small>THE PURE IN HEART;</small> therefore, let Zion rejoice, while all the wicked shall mourn” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/97.16,21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 97:16, 21</a>; emphasis added). For Zion, the pure in heart, the temple holds the key that unlocks holy places—places of rejoicing—while those in Babylon’s byways are condemned to mourn.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/stand-ye-in-holy-places.p6" pid="vr3idI3A-E2vxjLXqFhBVA" hash="ddBDdA">I was to bid my dear wife good-bye twice more during the tumultuous years of the Vietnam War. In a later year we would stand together and say farewell as a five-year-old son slipped from this world across the veiled threshold into the next; and, later still, we would welcome a handicapped daughter into mortality. Life has brought us its challenges, as it does to all. But through the years I have come to appreciate the wisdom of a dear friend, a patriarch and temple sealer. “Lance,” he said, “the joy I receive is more than just being in the temple. <span class="emphasis">The temple is in me!</span> And when I leave the temple, its peace goes with me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/stand-ye-in-holy-places.p7" pid="Se-htNmlOUKLEDb-Vv3p0A" hash="SDbhBA">So it can be for every righteous soul. When we visit the temple as often as distance and individual circumstance permit, <span class="emphasis">the temple will be in us.</span> Then, despite the buffetings of life, we will always be in a holy place. The house of the Lord beckons to all who would be numbered with Zion: “Come ye, and let us go up to the mountain of the Lord, to the house of the God of Jacob; and he will teach us of his ways, and we will walk in his paths” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/2.3" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 2:3</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/stand-ye-in-holy-places.p8" pid="ABVCf5PpKUODG1O-K7jHQw" hash="KeHmdQ">The day of the San Diego California Temple dedication attended by our stake, I came into the celestial room a few minutes early, accompanied by my daughter and one of my sons. My dear Pat was directing the choir. As though joined by angels, they rehearsed these magnificent words from a beloved Latter-day Saint hymn—a hymn we sang only moments ago:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/stand-ye-in-holy-places.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="9wOJHM9wqEGL7JNpnLdW_Q" hash="IeNs0w">
            <span class="emphasis">High on the mountain top</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="CC4801CC7UOC9FmX4I8A9A" hash="skwF9g">
            <span class="emphasis">A banner is unfurled.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="KQNL8dWXOkOyARp_bloV7A" hash="5rJwOg">
            <span class="emphasis">Ye nations, now look up;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="7x17jm33DkGXd-9Ul5OdUA" hash="gb2FgA">
            <span class="emphasis">It waves to all the world.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="DwPC3eYpI0GcNiiw97OU1g" hash="MM0aUA">
            <span class="emphasis">In Deseret’s sweet, peaceful land,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="_e0d9kQhSUiaJGtgoJj0JA" hash="awrTEw">
            <span class="emphasis">On Zion’s mount behold it stand!</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/stand-ye-in-holy-places.p9" pid="isnouknPEUaZScl3r8DfwA" hash="7jendw">Pat’s eyes met mine. For a brief moment I was transported back across the years, past the challenges and the heartaches to that wonderful day when together we had entered the house of the Lord. I drew my children close. In that instant a wonderful, celestial feeling swelled my breast. I <span class="emphasis">knew</span> I was in a holy place. I felt a peace as I had on that dark night so many years ago—and again I rejoiced. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1994/10/stand-ye-in-holy-places</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1994-general-conference/1994-10-5050-elder-lance-b-wickman-64k-eng.mp3" length="3373961" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 1994 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>But If Not</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Mortality’s supreme test is to face the “why” and then let it go, trusting humbly in the Lord’s promise that “all things must come to pass in their time.”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029898_000_012" doc-version="2" hash="ATvz2w">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="VrY-5c6_akad-NUoUuMb8g" hash="jPTbfQ">But If Not</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="OmYeLaXRNUuklv_-eMqU4w" hash="1T1w9w">Lance B. Wickman</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="IIOAXr3VzkuZcmGR1RW6OQ" hash="q5qaew">Mortality’s supreme test is to face the “why” and then let it go, trusting humbly in the Lord’s promise that “all things must come to pass in their time.”</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-eff.jpg" alt="Elder Lance B. Wickman" pid="Zp22YE9A6EKc1UwwSDuZfQ" hash="zPCi7A" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not.p1" pid="M8fpd0lBXEiL7pCLcvMbJw" hash="FOblZg">Some of my richest memories are associated with weekend assignments to stake conferences as I have accompanied a stake president in visits to members of his stake wrestling with life’s challenges in courage and faith, especially those who have lost a child or who are struggling valiantly in nursing a sick or crippled or handicapped child. I know from poignant personal experience that there is no night quite so dark as the loss of a child. Neither is there any day quite so long and exhausting as the relentlessness of caring for a child crippled in form or faculty. All such parents can empathize exquisitely with the father of the child afflicted with a “dumb spirit,” who, when admonished by the Savior to believe, responded in anguish of soul, “Lord, I believe; help thou mine unbelief” (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/9.17,23-24" class="scriptureRef">Mark 9:17, 23–24</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not.p2" pid="ofZlvqMwe0O0inP6qY3AmA" hash="1yNBeg">And so today I wish to speak to all who are struggling in this laboratory of applied faith that is called mortality—and in particular to those bereaved, burdened, and grieving parents who beseechingly ask, “Why?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not.p3" pid="Thz4fBDslE-XarONN6Rj1Q" hash="O2NISQ">First, please know that grief is the natural by-product of love. One cannot selflessly love another person and not grieve at his suffering or eventual death. The only way to avoid the grief would be to not experience the love; and it is love that gives life its richness and meaning. Hence, what a grieving parent can expect to receive from the Lord in response to earnest supplication may not necessarily be an elimination of grief so much as a sweet reassurance that, whatever his or her circumstances, one’s child is in the tender care of a loving Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not.p4" pid="KeGgLcRh8Eu5vdF4hmPqtA" hash="fY2oPw">Next, do not ever doubt the goodness of God, even if you do not know “why.” The overarching question asked by the bereaved and the burdened is simply this: <span class="emphasis">Why? Why</span> did our daughter die, when we prayed so hard that she would live and when she received priesthood blessings? <span class="emphasis">Why</span> are we struggling with this misfortune, when others relate miraculous healing experiences for their loved ones? These are natural questions, understandable questions. But they are also questions that usually go begging in mortality. The Lord has said simply, “My ways [are] higher than your ways, and my thoughts than your thoughts” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/55.9" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 55:9</a>). As the Son’s will was “swallowed up in the will of the Father” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/15.7" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 15:7</a>), so must ours be.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not.p5" pid="zP-aPR36fUui30FlJk8Iwg" hash="4L10Rg">Still, we mortals quite naturally want to know the why. Yet, in pressing too earnestly for the answer, we may forget that mortality was designed, in a manner of speaking, as the season of unanswered questions. Mortality has a different, more narrowly defined purpose: It is a proving ground, a probationary state, a time to walk by faith, a time to prepare to meet God (see, for example, <a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.24-25" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:24–25</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.15-16,20" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:15–16, 20</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/12.24" class="scriptureRef">Alma 12:24</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/42.4-13" class="scriptureRef">Alma 42:4–13</a>). It is in nurturing humility (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.6-21" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:6–21</a>) and submissiveness (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/3.19" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 3:19</a>) that we may comprehend a fulness of the intended mortal experience and put ourselves in a frame of mind and heart to receive the promptings of the Spirit. Reduced to their essence, humility and submissiveness are an expression of complete willingness to let the “why” questions go unanswered for now, or perhaps even to ask, “Why not?” It is in enduring well to the end (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.15-16" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:15–16</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.15" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:15</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:8</a>) that we achieve this life’s purposes. I believe that mortality’s supreme test is to face the “why” and then let it go, trusting humbly in the Lord’s promise that “all things must come to pass in their time” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.32" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:32</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not.p6" pid="78NPWB-ydEegbwgx3e2hHQ" hash="KXUzgA">But the Lord has not left us comfortless or without any answers. As to the healing of the sick, He has clearly said: “And again, it shall come to pass that he that hath faith in me to be healed, <span class="emphasis">and is not appointed unto death,</span> shall be healed” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.48" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:48</a>; emphasis added). All too often we overlook the qualifying phrase “and is not appointed unto death” (“or,” we might add, “unto sickness or handicap”). Please do not despair when fervent prayers have been offered and priesthood blessings performed and your loved one makes no improvement or even passes from mortality. Take comfort in the knowledge that you did everything you could. Such faith, fasting, and blessing could not be in vain! That your child did not recover in spite of all that was done in his behalf can and should be the basis for peace and reassurance to all who love him! <span class="emphasis">The Lord—who inspires the blessings and who hears every earnest prayer—called him home nonetheless.</span> All the experiences of prayer, fasting, and faith may well have been more for <span class="emphasis">our</span> benefit than for his.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not.p7" pid="UcyItx1BAk2fq57ojm6Vxg" hash="BozriA">How, then, should we approach the throne of grace as we plead earnestly for a loved one and place hands upon her head to give a blessing by priesthood authority? How do we properly exercise our faith? The Prophet Joseph Smith defined that first principle of the gospel as “faith <span class="emphasis">in the Lord Jesus Christ</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/a-of-f/1.4" class="scriptureRef">A of F 1:4</a>; emphasis added). It is that defining phrase—“in the Lord Jesus Christ”—that we sometimes forget. Too often we offer our prayer or perform our administration and then wait nervously to see whether our request will be granted, as though approval would provide needed evidence of His existence. That is not faith! Faith is, quite simply, a <span class="emphasis">confidence</span> in the Lord. In Mormon’s words, it is “a <span class="emphasis">firm mind</span> in every form of godliness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.30" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:30</a>; emphasis added). The three Hebrew magistrates expressed trust that the Lord would deliver them from the fiery furnace, <span class="emphasis">“but if not,”</span> they said to the king, “we [still] will not serve thy gods” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/dan/3.18" class="scriptureRef">Dan. 3:18</a>; emphasis added). Significantly, not three but four men were seen in the midst of the flames, and “the form of the fourth [was] like the Son of God” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/dan/3.25" class="scriptureRef">Dan. 3:25</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not.p8" pid="-KQNA_DWgkK6vi8FiKXGpw" hash="sCB1vw">So with us. It is common in our secular world to say that “seeing is believing.” Whatever value this little maxim may have in the mundane affairs of life, it is an alien presence when we turn to the Lord in the dark hour of our extremity. The way of the Lord is best defined by a different maxim: “Believing is seeing.” Faith in the Lord is the premise, not the conclusion. We <span class="emphasis">know</span> He lives; <span class="emphasis">therefore,</span> we trust Him to bless us according to His divine will and wisdom. This childlike confidence in the Lord is known in scripture simply as the “sacrifice” of “a broken heart and a contrite spirit” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not.p9" pid="KCkQ07z1NEqnuFTJih9CXA" hash="vcwlpg">I offer this as profound conviction born in the fiery crucible of life’s experience. Our second son, Adam, entered our lives when I was far away in the jungles and rice paddies of Vietnam. I still have the joyful telegram announcing his birth. Adam was a blue-eyed, blond-haired little fellow with an impish personality. As he turned five years old, Adam eagerly looked forward to starting school. Then a common childhood illness blanketed our southern California community, and Adam contracted the disease. Aside from concern for his comfort, we were not worried. He even seemed to have a light case. Suddenly one morning he did not arise from his bed; he was in a deep coma. We rushed him to the hospital, where he was placed in intensive care. A constant cadre of devoted doctors and nurses attended him. His mother and I maintained a ceaseless vigil in the waiting room nearby.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not.p10" pid="YNrpJimQzEe8l0KU_xHbYw" hash="0Cwmsw">I telephoned our dear stake president, a childhood friend and now a beloved colleague in the Seventy, Elder Douglas L. Callister, and asked if he would come to the hospital and join me in giving Adam a priesthood blessing. Within minutes he was there. As we entered the small, cramped space where Adam’s lifeless little body lay, his bed surrounded by a bewildering maze of monitoring devices and other medical paraphernalia, the kind doctors and nurses reverently stepped back and folded their arms. As the familiar and comforting words of a priesthood blessing were spoken in faith and earnest pleading, I was overcome by a profound sense that Someone else was present. I was overwhelmed by the thought that if I should open my eyes I would see the Savior standing there! I was not the only one in that room who felt that Spirit. We learned quite by chance some months later that one of the nurses who was present that day was so touched that she sought out the missionaries and was baptized.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not.p11" pid="o1QTCe9HE0CIgWYF1UmmMQ" hash="QK-3uQ">But notwithstanding, Adam made no improvement. He lingered between this life and the next for several more days as we pleaded with the Lord to return him to us. Finally, one morning after a fitful night, I walked alone down a deserted hospital corridor. I spoke to the Lord and told Him that we wanted our little boy to return so very much, but nevertheless what we wanted most was for His will to be done and that we—Pat and I—would accept that. Adam crossed the threshold into the eternities a short time later.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not.p12" pid="yE_U3AVLi0SAF2B2Njs3Dg" hash="kmzA4w">Frankly, we still grieve for our little boy, although the tender ministering of the Spirit and the passage of the years have softened our sadness. His small picture graces the mantel of our living room beside a more current family portrait of children and grandchildren. But Pat and I know that his path through mortality was intended by a kind Heavenly Father to be shorter and easier than ours and that he has now hurried on ahead to be a welcoming presence when we likewise eventually cross that same fateful threshold.</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="a0O44R8GykKWmJmEpdAvIw" hash="F_EMQg">
            <span class="emphasis">When through the deep waters I call thee to go,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="fwsJljVJEkKIijqjdRQsqQ" hash="RJLy9A">
            <span class="emphasis">The rivers of sorrow shall not thee o’erflow,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Zefqlz9kQE-WNnvFAS77Xw" hash="Z0F0YQ">
            <span class="emphasis">For I will be with thee, thy troubles to bless, … </span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="z5bUltVTuE27H_hyJlW-_g" hash="rZtGqQ">
            <span class="emphasis">And sanctify to thee thy deepest distress.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="M-AMOU65zUG3N66AA15tvg" hash="bjD38w">
            <span class="emphasis">When through fiery trials thy pathway shall lie,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="oJyxFYw74kCqVBFZfWoGqQ" hash="mFaE3Q">
            <span class="emphasis">My grace, all sufficient, shall be thy supply.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="4eOMp1S2Nke9rbe7QjpNMg" hash="12NzYQ">
            <span class="emphasis">The flame shall not hurt thee; I only design … </span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="ggBBhOXLYkS2eLBZ1ebOFQ" hash="UNI_lQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Thy dross to consume and thy gold to refine. … </span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="nUL412-qgkeXSweh0JFwfg" hash="GXMgtQ">
            <span class="emphasis">The soul that on Jesus hath leaned for repose</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="GsG9pWAKRkKxfwUJIxB7dg" hash="S-taFQ">
            <span class="emphasis">I will not, I cannot, desert to his foes;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Ek_ceQ-q9U2vlcHkH3pZqw" hash="HklUbw">
            <span class="emphasis">That soul, though all hell should endeavor to shake, … </span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="TAOv0Ud50EurzOCESYYF6g" hash="zkrpdg">
            <span class="emphasis">I’ll never, no never, no never forsake!</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not.p13" pid="2CWa52ndQEWf72O8PYTymw" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2002/10/but-if-not</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2002-general-conference/2002-10-2040-elder-lance-b-wickman-64k-eng.mp3" length="5509948" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2002 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Today</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2008/04/today?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Provided we have so lived Today that we have claim on the Atonement’s cleansing grace, we will live forever with God.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00009475_000_037" doc-version="2" hash="oM2wDw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="bsMDFA_FhES9vqO-6K3l7Q" hash="0pPZ9A">Today</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="_x1QjWm5oESCJ2ajm_H_sA" hash="m9gKyQ">Elder Lance B. Wickman</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="iEG89e5rjk6tucFAYgFnuQ" hash="ks90RA">Provided we have so lived Today that we have claim on the Atonement’s cleansing grace, we will live forever with God.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.p1" pid="TYeKYOgysE-7q9lpXW1Cfg" hash="2PbqBg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="103"></span>Three weeks ago, I stepped into Yesterday. In that moment, I rediscovered Today. And it is about Today that I wish to speak.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.p2" pid="Dyh80KgSnEynNwI5MJQyog" hash="QiP3HA">A Church assignment had carried me across the vast reaches of the Pacific to the land of Vietnam. For me, this was more than a flight over an ocean. It was a step back in time. More than 40 years ago, I had served on the battlefields of that land as an infantry officer. Etched in my mind over those intervening decades were memories of that place, its people, and my comrades in arms with whom I had served. Jacob once wrote, “Our lives passed away like … unto us a dream” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/7.26" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 7:26</a>). So it had been for me. And now I was returning from my hall of memories to that place of memory after a near half-century. My Church business concluded, I determined to once again visit those fields of desperate struggle. Accompanied by my dear wife, I made the pilgrimage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.p3" pid="MDyMt2qHhkeulNJYWVwV9Q" hash="sSzhKg">I am not quite sure what I expected to find after so many years. What I did find was most unexpected. Instead of a war-ravaged people, I found a youthful, vibrant population. Instead of a countryside pockmarked by shell fire, I found peaceful, verdant fields. Even the jungle growth was new. I guess that I had half expected to find Yesterday, but what I found was Today and the promise of a bright Tomorrow. I was reminded that “weeping may endure for a night, but joy cometh in the morning” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/30.5" class="scriptureRef">Psalm 30:5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.p4" pid="7OdneuLZEEiqA0bkn1ZD1Q" hash="whhqlQ">As I once again set foot upon the field and walked once more a jungle path, in my mind I heard again the stutter of the machine gun, the whistle of shrapnel, and the clatter of small arms. I saw again the bronzed, youthful faces of friends who “gave the last full measure of devotion” (Abraham Lincoln, Gettysburg Address). And I thought of one in particular and one day—a single day, April 3, 1966, Palm Sunday, the Easter season—42 years ago almost to this very day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.p5" pid="R-bAjFzY4UCofI6gU1YGsw" hash="fIbFdA">Our infantry battalion had been in Vietnam for several months. I was a lieutenant, the leader of a rifle platoon. We were involved almost constantly in combat operations. That day dawned with our battalion deep in hostile territory. Very early we sent <span class="pageBreak" page-number="104"></span>out a reconnaissance patrol of about 10 men. One of them was Sergeant Arthur Morris. Several of the men were wounded in a firefight, including Sergeant Morris, who received a slight flesh wound. Eventually the men of the patrol limped back to our lines.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.p6" pid="xQiHIlRLOE-gVzvk6EglWw" hash="XOU8Cw">We radioed for a medical evacuation helicopter. Loading the wounded men on the chopper, I urged Sergeant Morris also to get aboard. He demurred. Again I urged him. Again he demurred. Once again I admonished him. Once again he refused. Finally I said, “Sergeant Morris, get on that chopper.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.p7" pid="uve1em7sD0qcWcsh3cb2Kg" hash="kEgm_A">He looked at me, his eyes earnest, pleading. “Please, sir,” he said, and then these words that will forever haunt me: <span class="emphasis">“They can’t kill a tough old bird like me.”</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.p8" pid="OLNReTcNiUCIi2D0KQxm0Q" hash="uN2NYw">The entire scene is etched in my mind like a battle tableau: the jungle clearing; the impatient, throbbing rotor blade of the helicopter; the pilot looking at me expectantly; and my friend begging to stay with his men. I relented. I waved away the chopper with its lifeline to Tomorrow. Before the sun had set that very day, my dear friend Sergeant Arthur Cyrus Morris lay dead upon the ground, felled by hostile fire. And echoing in my mind over and over again, I hear his exclamation, “They can’t kill, they can’t kill, they can’t kill …”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.p9" pid="w5XocrlieEKOnkjG4CY6pQ" hash="8pGSRg">Of course, in one sense he was dreadfully wrong. Mortality is so fragile. Only one heartbeat, the drawing of a single breath, separates this world from the next. One moment, my friend was a vital, living person; the next, his immortal spirit had fled, leaving the mortal tabernacle a lump of lifeless clay. Death is a curtain through which each must pass, and like Sergeant Arthur Morris, none of us knows when that passage will occur. Of all the challenges we face, perhaps the greatest is a <span class="emphasis">misguided sense that mortality goes on forever</span> and its corollary, that we can postpone until tomorrow the seeking and offering of forgiveness, which as the gospel of Jesus Christ teaches, are among mortality’s central purposes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.p10" pid="Z5wC4_qUC0-dymMXSI8s6Q" hash="zvu62Q">This profound truth is taught by Amulek in the Book of Mormon:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.p11" pid="gmyXDzbe-E6eUIU5r32WBA" hash="wa9P0g">“For behold, this life is the time for men to prepare to meet God; yea, behold <span class="emphasis">the day of this life</span> is the day for men to perform their labors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.p12" pid="7w_BS9UIcEi7XCky9RG2lA" hash="2oXx9Q">“… Therefore, I beseech of you that ye do not procrastinate the day of your repentance until the end; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.p13" pid="F249RB7XQE-aSZjY5saGLg" hash="4H0Yjg">“… For that same spirit which doth possess your bodies at the time that ye go out of this life, that same spirit will have power to possess your body in that eternal world” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/34.32-34" class="scriptureRef">Alma 34:32–34</a>; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.p14" pid="2RIj2b34hUGoVJIahj-ziA" hash="36LLWQ">What a pungent expression Amulek uses—“the <span class="emphasis">day</span> of this life”! The Apostle James put it this way: “Whereas ye know not what shall be on the morrow. For what is your life? It is even a vapour, that appeareth for a little time, and then vanisheth away” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/4.14" class="scriptureRef">James 4:14</a>). And <span class="pageBreak" page-number="105"></span>the person we are when we depart this life is the person we will be as we enter the next. Thankfully, we do have Today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.p15" pid="j5sQNBupgE6QGXJDHPI_Ew" hash="j7c_Fg">If Sergeant Morris was dreadfully wrong, he was also magnificently right! We really are immortal in the sense that Christ’s Atonement conquers death, both physical and spiritual. And <span class="emphasis">provided</span> we have so lived <span class="emphasis">Today </span>that we have claim on the Atonement’s cleansing grace, we will live forever with God. This life is not so much a time for getting and accumulating as it is a time for giving and becoming. Mortality is the battlefield upon which justice and mercy meet. But they need not meet as adversaries, for they are reconciled in the Atonement of Jesus Christ for all who wisely use Today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.p16" pid="T_yZAXmBAk2ek1bRlFWNHQ" hash="l0erdg">It remains only for you and me to both <span class="emphasis">seek</span> and <span class="emphasis">tender</span> that forgiveness—to both repent and to extend charity to others—which enables us to pass through the door the Savior holds open, thus to cross the threshold from this life into exaltation. <span class="emphasis">Today</span> is the day to forgive others their trespasses, secure in the knowledge that the Lord will thus forgive ours. As Luke significantly recorded, “Be ye therefore merciful” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/6.36" class="scriptureRef">Luke 6:36</a>; emphasis added). Perfection may elude us here, but we can be merciful. And in the end, repenting and forgiving are among God’s chief requirements of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/today.p17" pid="AoPEpfYeikCETBzigd76vw" hash="K8x5Zw">My pilgrimage back in time completed, I looked around upon those peaceful fields of Today and saw in their fertility the promise of Tomorrow. I thought of my friend Sergeant Arthur Cyrus Morris. I thought of that fateful Palm Sunday of Yesterday. And I was profoundly grateful for the Redeemer of Easter morning, who grants us life, whose descent below all things makes possible our rising above all things—Tomorrow, if we but seize Today. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2008/04/today</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2008-general-conference/2008-04-5060-elder-lance-b-wickman-64k-eng.mp3" length="4022748" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
