<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Larry R. Lawrence</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Larry R. Lawrence.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Larry%20R.%20Lawrence.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Larry R. Lawrence.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2010 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Courageous Parenting</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting?lang=eng</link>
      <description>What the world really needs is courageous parenting from mothers and fathers who are not afraid to speak up and take a stand.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021411_000_5030" doc-version="2" hash="dhLJKg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="8-MJ8FaozE68RbqCy2Q_jg" hash="YQ7lPg">Courageous Parenting</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="kRkNkuNlm0CdsREqbLV0GA" hash="gVjwqQ">Larry R. Lawrence</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="bnaEXnniS0WG_AiltVTkGw" hash="tqWo0g">What the world really needs is courageous parenting from mothers and fathers who are not afraid to speak up and take a stand.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p1" pid="__pyC-jx-EuVy_LYA5_KxA" hash="Dq9vdw">I would like to speak today to the parents of teenagers. Your bright and energetic youth are the future of the Church, and for that reason they are a prime target of the adversary. Many of you faithful mothers and fathers are listening to conference today, praying for answers to help you guide your children through these important years. My oldest grandchildren have recently become teens, so the subject is near to my heart. There are no perfect parents and no easy answers, but there are principles of truth that we can rely on.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p2" pid="zSfQ-I2cSEexjPztpsNFVg" hash="J-PyCw">The Young Men and Young Women Mutual theme for 2010 was taken from the book of Joshua. It begins, “Be strong and of a good courage; be not afraid” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/1.9" class="scriptureRef">Joshua 1:9</a>). This phrase from the scriptures would be a good theme for parents as well. In these last days, what the world really needs is courageous parenting from mothers and fathers who are not afraid to speak up and take a stand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p3" pid="M_whC4kAP0qkg_jJ1E2wrA" hash="kdfwvw">Imagine for a moment that your daughter was sitting on the railroad tracks and you heard the train whistle blowing. Would you warn her to get off the tracks? Or would you hesitate, worried that she might think you were being overprotective? If she ignored your warning, would you quickly move her to a safe place? Of course you would! Your love for your daughter would override all other considerations. You would value her life more than her temporary goodwill.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p4" pid="p_IPA5c3sEO7bkd9_UEGQw" hash="wwB7RA">Challenges and temptations are coming at our teenagers with the speed and power of a freight train. As we are reminded in the family proclamation, parents are responsible for the protection of their children.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> That means spiritually as well as physically.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p5" pid="0wOOrpLq-UOe6UuuzOmcfQ" hash="LC_VFw">In the Book of Mormon, we read about Alma the Younger counseling his wayward son. Corianton had made some serious mistakes while serving a mission among the Zoramites. Alma loved him enough to speak very directly to the problem. He expressed his deep disappointment that his son had been immoral and explained to him the serious consequences of sin.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p6" pid="cRbspWBICEWO4EYXWVlSog" hash="kIQTUA">I am inspired every time I read these courageous words from Alma: “And now the Spirit of the Lord doth say unto me: Command thy children to do good … ; therefore I command you, my son, in the fear of God, that ye refrain from your iniquities” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/39.12" class="scriptureRef">Alma 39:12</a>). This early intervention by his father became a turning point for Corianton. He repented and served faithfully thereafter (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/42.31" class="scriptureRef">Alma 42:31</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/43.1-2" class="scriptureRef">43:1–2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p7" pid="2yMT6Kzaj0O0WPuPVifDwQ" hash="9Tp42Q">Contrast Alma’s example with that of another father from the scriptures, Eli in the Old Testament. Eli served as the high priest in Israel during the childhood of Samuel the prophet. The scriptures explain that the Lord rebuked him severely “because his sons made themselves vile, and he restrained them not” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-sam/3.13" class="scriptureRef">1 Samuel 3:13</a>). Eli’s sons never did repent, and all of Israel suffered because of their folly. The story of Eli teaches us that parents who love their children cannot afford to be intimidated by them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p8" pid="XP9eIAoZiU63W_s9STShbw" hash="Ha42FQ">Several years ago at general conference, Elder Joe J. Christensen reminded us that “parenting is not a popularity contest.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> In the same spirit, Elder Robert D. Hales has observed, “Sometimes we are afraid of our children—afraid to counsel with them for fear of offending them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p9" pid="oB89S-dKi0GjfRO_wS6MZA" hash="LD7sbg">Years ago our 17-year-old son wanted to go on a weekend trip with his friends, who were all good boys. He asked for permission to go. I wanted to say yes, but for some reason I felt uncomfortable about the trip. I shared my feelings with my wife, who was very supportive. “We need to listen to that warning voice,” she said.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p10" pid="aPTp-0QaIkyxbcUL9sQgVA" hash="hpc9lg">Of course, our son was disappointed and asked why we didn’t want him to go. I answered honestly that I didn’t know why. “I just don’t feel good about it,” I explained, “and I love you too much to ignore these feelings inside.” I was quite surprised when he said, “That’s OK, Dad. I understand.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p11" pid="SzOvuQ6e3EmqY7re7BseWQ" hash="zg0iow">Young people understand more than we realize because they too have the gift of the Holy Ghost. They are trying to recognize the Spirit when He speaks, and they are watching our example. From us they learn to pay attention to their promptings—that if they “don’t feel good about something,” it’s best not to pursue it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p12" pid="qaU6lCVedkO7b9duutSQfQ" hash="L6GReA">It’s so important for husbands and wives to be united when making parenting decisions. If either parent doesn’t feel good about something, then permission should not be granted. If either feels uncomfortable about a movie, a television show, a video game, a party, a dress, a swimsuit, or an Internet activity, have the courage to support each other and say no.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p13" pid="V5bQAo1V4UCUg1jwxEEiWg" hash="mv6Y9Q">I would like to share with you a letter from a heartbroken mother. Her teenage son gradually lost the Spirit and drifted away from Church activity. She explained how this happened: “All throughout my son’s teenage years, I worried and tried to stop him from playing violent video games. I talked to my husband and showed him articles in the <span class="emphasis">Ensign</span> and in the newspaper that cautioned about these games. But my husband felt it was OK. He said that our son wasn’t out using drugs and that I should stop worrying. There were times that I would hide the controllers, and my husband would give them back. It began to be easier for me to give in … than to fight it. I really feel that gaming is just as addictive as drugs. I would do anything to prevent other parents from going through this experience.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p14" pid="vqyvudzWa0i94bysbFRsKg" hash="UTDarw">Brothers and sisters, if your spouse doesn’t feel good about something, show respect for those feelings. When you take the easy way out by saying and doing nothing, you may be enabling destructive behavior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p15" pid="D2Izz4XZmEuwG4UX9s6vMg" hash="zSMXQw">Parents can prevent a lot of heartache by teaching their children to postpone romantic relationships until the time comes when they are ready for marriage. Prematurely pairing off with a boyfriend or girlfriend is dangerous. Becoming a “couple” creates emotional intimacy, which too often leads to physical intimacy. Satan knows this sequence and uses it to his advantage. He will do whatever he can to keep young men from serving missions and to prevent temple marriages.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p16" pid="jBH0n1ER7kONeVg3IvZmdQ" hash="oNG8Jw">It is vital that parents have the courage to speak up and intervene before Satan succeeds. President Boyd K. Packer has taught that “when morality is involved, we have both the <span class="emphasis">right</span> and the <span class="emphasis">obligation</span> to raise a warning voice.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p17" pid="ZzwRjlRnHEKyf_C7ekyeww" hash="sgDdZw">I have always believed that nothing really good happens late at night and that young people need to know what time they are expected to come home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p18" pid="X0zT8IiWAkeZqKK0cMgYjg" hash="kizK1Q">There is a great deal of wisdom displayed when parents stay up and wait for their children to return home. Young men and women make far better choices when they know their parents are waiting up to hear about their evening and to kiss them good night.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p19" pid="eQCiaZU0DEih2bWXqp3uEg" hash="FArNdQ">May I express my personal warning about a practice that is common in many cultures. I am referring to sleepovers, or spending the night at the home of a friend. As a bishop I discovered that too many youth violated the Word of Wisdom or the law of chastity for the first time as part of a sleepover. Too often their first exposure to pornography and even their first encounter with the police occurred when they were spending the night away from home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p20" pid="4Via7wqmE0KKtDMAkRbSmw" hash="X0ZuxA">Peer pressure becomes more powerful when our children are away from our influence and when their defenses are weakened late at night. If you have ever felt uneasy about an overnight activity, don’t be afraid to respond to that warning voice inside. Always be prayerful when it comes to protecting your precious children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p21" pid="JmTHlXpIB0mSra-tqX1g_Q" hash="NH-xTw">Courageous parenting does not always involve saying no. Parents also need courage to say yes to the counsel of modern-day prophets. Our Church leaders have counseled us to establish righteous patterns in our homes. Consider five fundamental practices that have the power to fortify our youth: family prayer, family scripture study, family home evening, family dinner together, and regular one-on-one interviews with each child.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p22" pid="qsuu3NqHl0OaFkCxgv0ZTw" hash="ZPFNTw">It takes courage to gather children from whatever they’re doing and kneel together as a family. It takes courage to turn off the television and the computer and to guide your family through the pages of the scriptures every day. It takes courage to turn down other invitations on Monday night so that you can reserve that evening for your family. It takes courage and willpower to avoid overscheduling so that your family can be home for dinner.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p23" pid="IAvpQgc8hUiQfUEdeGIldA" hash="Z-lETQ">One of the most effective ways we can influence our sons and daughters is to counsel with them in private interviews. By listening closely, we can discover the desires of their hearts, help them set righteous goals, and also share with them the spiritual impressions that we have received about them. Counseling requires courage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p24" pid="LggfU9-2skWfz0k5RgBuLg" hash="ux_r-A">Try to imagine what the rising generation could become if these five righteous patterns were practiced consistently in every home. Our young people could be like Helaman’s army: invincible (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/57.25" class="scriptureRef">Alma 57:25</a>--26).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting.p25" pid="l8nXudydP0eP4BWNfzrf5A" hash="VmLgLQ">Parenting teenagers in the latter days is a very humbling assignment. Satan and his followers are striving to bring this generation down; the Lord is counting on valiant parents to bring them up. Parents, “Be strong and of a good courage; be not afraid” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/1.9" class="scriptureRef">Joshua 1:9</a>). I know that God hears and will answer your prayers. I testify that the Lord supports and blesses courageous parents. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/10/courageous-parenting</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2010-general-conference/2010-10-5030-elder-larry-r-lawrence-64k-eng.mp3" length="5083443" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2010 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Lack I Yet?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Lawrence teaches that the Holy Ghost can tell us through personalized revelation how we can improve.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13768_000_25lawrence" doc-version="2" hash="9Gg5ow">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="JSqhmQby3ESXx60rVYk2Bw" hash="S12k8w">What Lack I Yet?</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p2" pid="M9ywwvYu-kqKaSNaHKTOwg" hash="8BOikA">By Elder Larry R. Lawrence</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p3" pid="OTvh0LUtm02lv1jWzJCHvA" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=9tuuEps8302SULWXhqf4_g"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" alt="Elder Larry R. Lawrence" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255547/92181536e94e46bd92231aa4c0a10e57/100x134.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x67="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255547/92181536e94e46bd92231aa4c0a10e57/50x67.jpg" data-src-100x134="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255547/92181536e94e46bd92231aa4c0a10e57/100x134.jpg" data-src-200x269="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255547/92181536e94e46bd92231aa4c0a10e57/200x269.jpg" data-src-320x431="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255547/92181536e94e46bd92231aa4c0a10e57/320x431.jpg" data-src-460x620="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255547/92181536e94e46bd92231aa4c0a10e57/460x620.jpg" data-src-640x863="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255547/92181536e94e46bd92231aa4c0a10e57/640x863.jpg" data-src-1024x1381="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255547/92181536e94e46bd92231aa4c0a10e57/1024x1381.jpg" data-src-2048x2762="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255547/92181536e94e46bd92231aa4c0a10e57/2048x2762.jpg" pid="9tuuEps8302SULWXhqf4_g" hash="4GSmyw"></img></a></div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="40hK7brx1kOFJYxhAJifag" hash="NC2kTg">If we are humble and teachable, the Holy Ghost will prompt us to improve and lead us home, but we need to ask the Lord for directions along the way.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="JNufgfRLrkqNwznODtyCIQ" hash="gVjwqQ">Larry R. Lawrence</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p5" pid="qmxoWzC71k-LCRgIDe2WDA" hash="e3GFtQ">When I was a young adult, I began investigating the Church. At first I was drawn to the gospel by the examples of my Latter-day Saint friends, but eventually I was attracted to the unique doctrine. When I learned that faithful men and women could keep progressing and ultimately become like our heavenly parents, I was frankly amazed. I loved the concept; it rang true to me.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p6" pid="lNL9uIGkhEuInLrW7u78XA" hash="xV2z2A">Soon after my baptism, I was studying the Sermon on the Mount, and I recognized that Jesus taught this same truth about eternal progression in the Bible. He said, “Be ye therefore perfect, even as your Father which is in heaven is perfect.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p7" pid="-Q5rJLUkL0u8rdwJupXDCw" hash="2jOJnQ">I have been a member of the Church now for over 40 years, and whenever I read this verse of scripture, I am reminded of our purpose here on earth. We came to learn and improve until we gradually become sanctified or perfected in Christ.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p8" pid="RR0PmBwk10etXJvSRTpbBA" hash="j95DAg">The journey of discipleship is not an easy one. It has been called a “course of steady improvement.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> As we travel along that strait and narrow path, the Spirit continually challenges us to be better and to climb higher. The Holy Ghost makes an ideal traveling companion. If we are humble and teachable, He will take us by the hand and lead us home.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p9" pid="GTaD1b-OuEi7sWhzsPQ-4Q" hash="L9DMfA">However, we need to ask the Lord for directions along the way. We have to ask some difficult questions, like “What do I need to change?” “How can I improve?” “What weakness needs strengthening?”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p10" pid="dRor2EuD40SxQVekdae88w" hash="XdjpKw">Let’s consider the New Testament account of the rich young ruler. He was a righteous young man who was already keeping the Ten Commandments, but he wanted to become better. His goal was eternal life.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p11" pid="vabG1R7FaUGPOZu6QZxYRA" hash="fV-H1A">When he met the Savior, he asked, “What lack I yet?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p12" pid="9TFa219keEyk-dEs1cZ29w" hash="Lug2gw">Jesus answered immediately, giving counsel that was intended specifically for the rich young man. “Jesus said unto him, If thou wilt be perfect, go and sell that thou hast, and give to the poor, and … come and follow me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p13" pid="P6LDuy4Z5U-IrAeZN-Mg6w" hash="326rMA">The young man was stunned; he had never considered such a sacrifice. He was humble enough to ask the Lord but not faithful enough to follow the divine counsel he was given. We must be willing to act when we receive an answer.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p14" pid="2I2C9B5gQEqIiO8w5SOYgA" hash="pKW5vA">President Harold B. Lee taught, “Every one of us, if we would reach perfection, must [at] one time ask ourselves this question, ‘What lack I yet?’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p15" pid="PxTP3Jf_6kWj1MK0R-iKXA" hash="gdtH1w">I knew a faithful mother who humbled herself and asked, “What is keeping me from progressing?” In her case, the response from the Spirit came immediately: “Stop complaining.” This answer surprised her; she had never thought of herself as a complainer. However, the message from the Holy Ghost was very clear. In the days that followed, she became conscious of her habit of complaining. Grateful for the prompting to improve, she determined to count her blessings instead of her challenges. Within days, she felt the warm approval of the Spirit.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p16" pid="2pgEbiDgHEK2a2NbnurQyQ" hash="U-BePQ">A humble young man who couldn’t seem to find the right young woman went to the Lord for help: “What is keeping me from being the right man?” he asked. This answer came into his mind and heart: “Clean up your language.” At that moment, he realized that several crude expressions had become part of his vocabulary, and he committed to change.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p17" pid="P5Vqp42dlEO_GifxtJd_yA" hash="Y56i_g">A single sister bravely asked the question: “What do I need to change?” and the Spirit whispered to her, “Don’t interrupt people when they are talking.” The Holy Ghost really does give customized counsel. He is a completely honest companion and will tell us things that no one else knows or has the courage to say.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p18" pid="wKu0xjzR7EGp7voiCxzd6A" hash="KvibFg">One returned missionary found himself stressed with a very heavy schedule. He was trying to find time for work, studies, family, and a Church calling. He asked the Lord for counsel: “How can I feel at peace with all that I need to do?” The answer was not what he expected; he received the impression that he should more carefully observe the Sabbath day and keep it holy. He decided to dedicate Sunday to God’s service—to lay aside his school courses on that day and study the gospel instead. This small adjustment brought the peace and balance that he was seeking.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p19" pid="UNGZm98AR0GpUpEj5DUEeQ" hash="1BQQmg">Years ago I read in a Church magazine the story of a girl who was living away from home and going to college. She was behind in her classes, her social life was not what she had hoped for, and she was generally unhappy. Finally one day she fell to her knees and cried out, “What can I do to improve my life?” The Holy Ghost whispered, “Get up and clean your room.” This prompting came as a complete surprise, but it was just the start she needed. After taking time to organize and put things in order, she felt the Spirit fill her room and lift her heart.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p20" pid="zVhhnwNYzEmArlw2D2B6dw" hash="tun9cw">The Holy Ghost doesn’t tell us to improve everything at once. If He did, we would become discouraged and give up. The Spirit works with us at our own speed, one step at a time, or as the Lord has taught, “line upon line, precept upon precept, … and blessed are those who hearken unto my precepts, … for unto him that receiveth I will give more.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> For example, if the Holy Ghost has been prompting you to say “thank you” more often, and you respond to that prompting, then He may feel it’s time for you to move on to something more challenging—like learning to say, “I’m sorry; that was my fault.”</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=dqtZJEAwJUO-70KOZ1W6Tg"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579908/373841ccfd894f76b20fc6af3e17d059/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579908/373841ccfd894f76b20fc6af3e17d059/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579908/373841ccfd894f76b20fc6af3e17d059/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579908/373841ccfd894f76b20fc6af3e17d059/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579908/373841ccfd894f76b20fc6af3e17d059/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579908/373841ccfd894f76b20fc6af3e17d059/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579908/373841ccfd894f76b20fc6af3e17d059/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579908/373841ccfd894f76b20fc6af3e17d059/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579908/373841ccfd894f76b20fc6af3e17d059/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579908/373841ccfd894f76b20fc6af3e17d059/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Family partaking of the sacrament" pid="dqtZJEAwJUO-70KOZ1W6Tg" hash="fJR-Tg"></img></a>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p21" pid="0SjknSRW7kSio19dLDNF9A" hash="OCR20A">A perfect time to ask, “What lack I yet?” is when we take the sacrament. The Apostle Paul taught that this is a time for each of us to examine ourselves.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> In this reverent atmosphere, as our thoughts are turned heavenward, the Lord can gently tell us what we need to work on next.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p22" pid="jkDH5nQkuU67wPXHcSWcBw" hash="92j36w">Like you, I have received many messages from the Spirit over the years showing me how I could improve. Let me share a few personal examples of messages that I took to heart. These promptings have included:</p>
		<ul class="bullet">
			<li pid="Z9le-dgHKU6q2D5hviEaYA" hash="g2AM5w">
				<span class="label">•</span>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p23" pid="PNsv2hgzVUWT4cWwTOFCFg" hash="b7Xvew">Don’t raise your voice.</p>
			</li>
			<li pid="q5LIfCTBnkiE06NSVaI7OA" hash="9ff78Q">
				<span class="label">•</span>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p24" pid="b9NCEnTF8UKZHWp4XW_qxA" hash="PN_-kg">Organize yourself; create a daily list of things to do.</p>
			</li>
			<li pid="CI8HTX3V0k6mwJ2k9y7Y6g" hash="LS62Tg">
				<span class="label">•</span>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p25" pid="_qoe-aXXTk-zWWuRuJbT9g" hash="MOXFmA">Take better care of your body by eating more fruits and vegetables.</p>
			</li>
			<li pid="xQFpF90W7EKqnr6gxC3okQ" hash="745Vjg">
				<span class="label">•</span>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p26" pid="w-4isocxXk6Wih5WG5CYMA" hash="km3AJQ">Increase your temple attendance.</p>
			</li>
			<li pid="jlJqT3tir0i96oUXAh68vQ" hash="1Vm86w">
				<span class="label">•</span>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p27" pid="smHxhpq9bk6TOnMde-3pNQ" hash="XCpPRA">Take time to ponder before you pray.</p>
			</li>
			<li pid="v30EvpIQpkGUaTcrKHUllA" hash="8p_Wcw">
				<span class="label">•</span>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p28" pid="eDRd_RBD70Wf1WryF0Awjg" hash="VouMcg">Ask your wife for her counsel.</p>
			</li>
			<li pid="BIZzDI7tlUOp58MMfuQUfg" hash="joDgdw">
				<span class="label">•</span>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p29" pid="LX1STQduHE6LJT3wPPU8dA" hash="oHaWHA">And be patient when driving; don’t exceed the speed limit. (I’m still working on that last one.)</p>
			</li>
		</ul>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p30" pid="fOI0RgelJk-W3lPU9tHUgw" hash="VoGtGw">The atoning sacrifice of the Savior is what makes perfection or sanctification possible. We could never do it on our own, but God’s grace is sufficient to help us. As Elder David A. Bednar once observed: “Most of us clearly understand that the Atonement is for sinners. I am not so sure, however, that we know and understand that the Atonement is also for saints—for good men and women who are obedient, worthy, and conscientious and who are striving to become better.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=MYzWqb0nhUuVCkS2Py2WcA"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579902/646db945aaaf4959aab646310b4df9cd/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579902/646db945aaaf4959aab646310b4df9cd/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579902/646db945aaaf4959aab646310b4df9cd/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579902/646db945aaaf4959aab646310b4df9cd/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579902/646db945aaaf4959aab646310b4df9cd/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579902/646db945aaaf4959aab646310b4df9cd/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579902/646db945aaaf4959aab646310b4df9cd/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579902/646db945aaaf4959aab646310b4df9cd/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579902/646db945aaaf4959aab646310b4df9cd/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579902/646db945aaaf4959aab646310b4df9cd/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Woman praying" pid="MYzWqb0nhUuVCkS2Py2WcA" hash="gA55mg"></img></a>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p31" pid="KixGw4QdiUaOTQ1CSLT-Fw" hash="gtHGEQ">I would like to suggest that each of you participate in a spiritual exercise sometime soon, perhaps even tonight while saying your prayers. Humbly ask the Lord the following question: “What is keeping me from progressing?” In other words: “What lack I yet?” Then wait quietly for a response. If you are sincere, the answer will soon become clear. It will be revelation intended just for you.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p32" pid="4IdrTNyYo0y9PkshhBcV7A" hash="ix0sDg">Perhaps the Spirit will tell you that you need to forgive someone. Or you may receive a message to be more selective about the movies you watch or the music you listen to. You may feel impressed to be more honest in your business dealings or more generous in your fast offerings. The possibilities are endless.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p33" pid="787LbvuLDUC2CIEyC3C38Q" hash="VD-AYA">The Spirit can show us our weaknesses, but He is also able to show us our strengths. Sometimes we need to ask what we are doing right so that the Lord can lift and encourage us. When we read our patriarchal blessings, we are reminded that our Heavenly Father knows our divine potential. He rejoices every time we take a step forward. To Him, our direction is ever more important than our speed.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p34" pid="CsUfB2AvHEiszQBNB8Uu7A" hash="DQ3HYw">Be persistent, brothers and sisters, but never be discouraged. We will have to go beyond the grave before we actually reach perfection, but here in mortality we can lay the foundation. “It is our duty to be better today than we were yesterday, and better tomorrow than we are today.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p35" pid="EQrwouZkTE-Ec_QJpYiTvQ" hash="zO86Qg">If spiritual growth is not a priority in our lives, if we are not on a course of steady improvement, we will miss out on the important experiences that God wants to give us.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p36" pid="KosMDWL7YUaqxjOEhN6MaQ" hash="ttg7GQ">Years ago I read these words of President Spencer W. Kimball, which had a lasting impact on me. He said: “I have learned that where there is a prayerful heart, a hungering after righteousness, a forsaking of sins, and obedience to the commandments of God, the Lord pours out more and more light until there is finally power to pierce the heavenly veil. ... A person of such righteousness has the priceless promise that one day he shall see the Lord’s face and know that he is.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet.p37" pid="FBYdktdyOU-6NQe1OY77ew" hash="3aOP6g">It is my prayer that this ultimate experience can be ours someday as we allow the Holy Ghost to lead us home. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/10/what-lack-i-yet</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2015-general-conference/2015-10-1050-elder-larry-r-lawrence-64k-eng.mp3" length="4977450" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
