<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Larry M. Gibson</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Larry M. Gibson.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Larry%20M.%20Gibson.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Larry M. Gibson.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Sacred Keys of the Aaronic Priesthood</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Lord wants every Aaronic Priesthood holder to invite all to come unto Christ—beginning with his own family.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood" dup-mag="false" dup-conf="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50028768_000_3030" doc-version="2" hash="qovTAA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="4hvZwZYCNUqe_MdiHj63QQ" hash="Ybt2Bw">Sacred Keys of the Aaronic Priesthood</h1><p class="authorName" guid="5cc1bd86-55e2-48e5-a884-bffafc5c75d6" pid="YQcn0fcsek-v4r5bCJR9lA" hash="MYGyoA">Larry M. Gibson</p><p class="kicker" pid="491LpPKDD0uC9sNXYdEbEw" hash="aKjATg">The Lord wants every Aaronic Priesthood holder to invite all to come unto Christ—beginning with his own family.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="5cbeda22-a48d-4e27-8271-48a38d526bba">
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.t1">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p1" guid="4653371a-c279-4602-a16f-a52a60211308" pid="7C-zpwQA30mwxIGT3pqHkQ" hash="kw_4Eg">One of my sons, at age 12, decided to raise rabbits. We built cages and acquired one large male and two female rabbits from a neighbor. I had no idea what we were getting into. In a very short time, our shed was bursting with bunnies. Now that my son is grown, I must confess my amazement at how they were controlled—a neighbor’s dog occasionally got into the shed and thinned out the herd.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p2" guid="011c0644-f2ae-4a47-87a2-6c09081a6b3b" pid="SjznxdrPoUioQ-mieIKlMw" hash="8n3dYQ">But my heart was touched as I saw my son and his brothers watch over and protect those rabbits. And now, as husbands and fathers, they are worthy priesthood holders who love, strengthen, and watch over their own families.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p3" guid="08821bcf-6bc1-428a-adda-646d3d0c4b1c" pid="xL5BvPEq5kus6ibODi-8YQ" hash="Y5ucYA">My feelings are tender as I observe you young men of the Aaronic Priesthood watching over, supporting, and strengthening those around you, including your families, members of your quorum, and many others. How I love you.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p4" guid="b460ed07-9aa0-447d-9310-6ab96e9a3ea1" pid="6J-tjkxV10iG_fXKQkoq9g" hash="cqfPZA">Recently I watched as a 13-year-old young man was set apart as deacons quorum president. Afterward the bishop shook his hand and addressed him as “president,” explaining to the quorum members that he “addressed him as president to emphasize the sacredness of his calling. The deacons quorum president is one of only four people in the ward who hold keys of presidency. With those keys, he, with his counselors, will lead the quorum under the inspiration of the Lord.” This bishop understood the power of a presidency led by a president who holds and exercises sacred priesthood keys. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/124.142-143" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 124:142–43</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p5" guid="24f6df81-3259-49bd-940e-a96bf81f460f" pid="_Zh_0jc8dEOdIT4XuKIBFg" hash="NEdmuA">Later I asked this young man if he was ready to preside over this great quorum. His response was: “I’m nervous. I don’t know what a deacons quorum president does. Can you tell me?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p6" guid="066ec619-324a-4f2f-a271-9bc646e8883e" pid="4byijxR3qEmu7K-I0x0l3g" hash="Gdpx-w">I told him he had a wonderful bishopric and advisers who would help him become a successful and powerful priesthood leader. I knew they would respect the sacred keys of presidency he held.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p7" guid="bd3ae9d1-d32f-4618-8f50-b92daa71c358" pid="6_pcbXNKn0m3him0Py8ycA" hash="YznvCA">I then posed this question: “Do you suppose the Lord would call you to this important calling without giving you direction?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p8" guid="5223ab9f-02b8-4556-81e7-56ffcf2688b2" pid="OPvPxjiIQEqrJTH7J_9pkg" hash="j9KZfg">He thought, then responded, “Where do I find it?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p9" guid="c6f59bab-3bae-4945-bd09-e2f21ba7f6d9" pid="QWIn-Ji-xU-bkKIX01-zww" hash="0JeUdg">After some discussion, he realized that he would find direction from the scriptures, the words of the living prophets, and answers to prayer. We determined to find a scripture that would be a starting place for his search to learn the responsibilities of his new calling.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p10" guid="b3bf74ed-602d-43c0-b2a3-9a2dd26dc8a9" pid="zZPhlozItkqn58-ceJ2GFg" hash="hbLrXA">We turned to the 107th section of the Doctrine and Covenants, <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.85" class="scriptureRef">verse 85</a>. It mentions that a deacons quorum president is to sit in council with his quorum members and teach them their duties. We noted that his quorum is not only a class but also a council of young men, and they are to strengthen and edify one another under the president’s direction. I expressed confidence that he would be an outstanding president who would rely on the inspiration from the Lord and magnify his sacred calling as he taught his fellow deacons their duties.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p11" guid="54f4f427-9f79-41e0-87b8-5d28f89845f8" pid="poQw6UOHkEqvZeUYwdErZA" hash="z84rTg">Then I asked, “Knowing you are to teach the deacons their duties, do you know what those duties are?”</p>
			<div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.f1"><p pid="ZpDVqCFk8kC5cxbfZxRJWQ" hash="xdMxRQ">Again we turned to the scriptures and found:</p><ol class="number" guid="96983fb6-8933-4788-b339-0e10615b7571"><li guid="4687f831-1d51-4fee-8430-bcc6b7787593" pid="KvIBElbw50O1vy7luJ06og" hash="tAdqvQ">
					<span class="label">1.</span>
					<p guid="5f80f607-a21f-410d-bf7f-8972fc2d9942" pid="ylrfXuJw-0efclwYBAryFA" hash="QyiALg">A deacon is appointed to watch over and be a standing minister in the Church (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.111" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:111</a>).</p>
					<p guid="649d238b-bd0e-43df-8c8a-b4d523749714" pid="LMIX22GqIEuoexK8wIlmkg" hash="jwXssA">Because the family is the basic unit of the Church, the most important setting in which an Aaronic Priesthood holder can fulfill this duty is in his own home. He provides priesthood service to his father and mother as they lead the family. He also watches over his brothers and sisters, the young men of his quorum, and the other members of the ward.</p>
				</li><li guid="170a68cb-1e5d-4643-9dec-c4fad552c44b" pid="11pvKKR_W0mbylizGKYEWQ" hash="exTTew">
					<span class="label">2.</span>
					<p guid="00d7f06d-ad1b-4fb2-b419-3588e96709da" pid="OcizmWmKsUu4ojbFi1JxTQ" hash="a77ZNg">A deacon assists the teacher in all his duties in the Church if occasion requires (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.57" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:57</a>).</p>
					<p guid="32cd9ae1-4d67-4385-9d1e-721994abaf39" pid="ByD07sdFi0-H08l6RoNIqw" hash="ve7obA">We determined that if a deacon is to assist with the teachers’ duties, he needs to know their duties. We looked in the scriptures and quickly identified over a dozen duties for the office of teacher (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.53-59" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:53–59</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.111" class="scriptureRef">84:111</a>). What a powerful experience it would be for every young man—and his father, advisers, and all of us—to do exactly what this young man did: go to the scriptures and discover for ourselves what our duties are. I suspect that many of us will be surprised—and inspired—by what we find. Duty to God contains helpful summaries of Aaronic Priesthood duties and is a great resource for spiritual development. I urge you to consistently use it.</p>
				</li><li guid="17ed3c46-4ce2-49f9-a508-ccfd72077801" pid="rzLw3HYAwEiepYEZ64XSVg" hash="lzrCng">
					<span class="label">3.</span>
					<p guid="4cf46fa2-8479-402f-8cc1-a73df6268c9c" pid="hr6BiMuiRUiUqOIfBOlMNA" hash="DZDPJg">Deacons and teachers are also to “warn, expound, exhort, and teach, and invite all to come unto Christ” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.59" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:59</a>; see verses 46 and 68 for priests).</p>
					<p guid="261d0b37-80f6-4899-b1e3-02a066f80b7d" pid="EP7wRspji0-QevRSan8cdw" hash="Ct0MuA">Many young men think that their missionary experience starts when they turn 19 and enter the Missionary Training Center. We learn from the scriptures that it starts long before that. The Lord wants every Aaronic Priesthood holder to invite all to come unto Christ—beginning with his own family.</p>
				</li></ol></div>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p12" guid="39b183ba-9d36-45f8-b878-64b3dfdfb284" pid="4yiv1NDkM0e1QDnKH0Us0Q" hash="ZhkuqA">Next, to help this young president understand that he and he alone was the presiding officer in the quorum, I suggested he read three times the first duty listed in <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.85" class="scriptureRef">Doctrine and Covenants 107:85</a>. He read, “Preside over twelve deacons.” I asked, “What is the Lord telling you personally about your duty as president?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p13" guid="278ae764-40f0-4b2b-955d-be466753b556" pid="Bbn2q4CHhUyMj8xb49UpRQ" hash="ygsc8w">“Well,” he said, “several things have popped into my head as we have been talking. I think Heavenly Father wants me to be president of twelve deacons. There are only five of us who come, and one comes only sometimes. So how do we get twelve?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p14" guid="3f46afb1-2883-4e79-a537-b59a0f46e43b" pid="AN-DRMyyJ0uk6twjzmIhFQ" hash="3xGmWA">Now, I had never interpreted this scripture the way he did, but then, he held sacred keys that I did not have. I was being taught by a 13-year-old deacons quorum president about the revelatory power that comes to those with the sacred keys of presidency regardless of their intellect, stature, or age.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p15" guid="3a573607-4f64-4ddc-ab25-b84838b77a4b" pid="IQLcoSGMx0WnYBOJSWT7Yw" hash="IRE33g">I answered, “I don’t know. What do you think?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p16" guid="1ca0bb11-70f8-4ecd-9b36-add11d19db28" pid="fi3FefSiwEqMvIwllOQOBg" hash="FyL7GA">And he said, “We need to figure out how to keep him coming. I know there are two others who should be in our quorum, but they don’t come, and I don’t know them. Maybe I can become close friends with one and have my counselors work with the others. If they all came, we would have seven, but where do we get five more?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p17" guid="c6d03802-7228-423a-980f-8c3eb3310647" pid="ozMpHM_Eg0yzRfKeHOed-w" hash="eS-Taw">“I don’t know,” was my answer, “but if Heavenly Father wants them there, He knows.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p18" guid="df2c86e5-ee38-4fab-ae86-61d26bd3a9b4" pid="MDDISOkMBkiTL5CQ-ue4YQ" hash="uvd8Qw">“Then we need to pray as a presidency and quorum to find out what to do.” He then asked, “Am I responsible for all deacon-age boys in our ward, even those who are not members?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p19" guid="fa8ea99a-9613-460a-9367-3dcde2aed33e" pid="V-pdrR4DCEGMrAq5GWDEAw" hash="parxNA">In awe, I said, “In the Lord’s view, does your bishop have responsibility for only the members of the ward or for all who live within its boundaries?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p20" guid="73839383-410c-46ca-ad96-7255471e209a" pid="CND5eHhcr0yVvwVSnrga4A" hash="DMCQiA">This young “standing minister” got it. He recognized the role of every deacon, teacher, and priest in watching over the Church and inviting all to come unto Christ.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p21" guid="eda09786-9add-45db-acbc-ab82d636314b" pid="nqkN5Xwsl0qEuH-VqOBO-A" hash="F-GO5g">My thoughts turn to a scripture as I think of our wonderful young men and women of the Church—a scripture that Moroni quoted to Joseph Smith, saying that it had “not yet [been] fulfilled, but was soon to be” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.41" class="scriptureRef">Joseph Smith—History 1:41</a>)—“And it shall come to pass afterward, that I will pour out my spirit upon all flesh; and your sons and your daughters shall prophesy, … your young men shall see visions” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/joel/2.28" class="scriptureRef">Joel 2:28</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p22" guid="5b2d4949-38c3-4058-a2c1-3f6c22d68e47" pid="QrsKBWZPm0CZkXch1dAbWA" hash="6yzylQ">What “popped into” this young president’s head was a vision of what Heavenly Father wants his quorum to be. It was the revelation he needed to strengthen the active members of his quorum, to rescue those who were struggling, and to invite all to come unto Christ. Thus inspired, he made plans to carry out the Lord’s will.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p23" guid="7d7f6c32-96a1-4e6c-ad74-babe99974624" pid="3iqj33K7-Uexc-IzgF0hrA" hash="MGvTgA">The Lord taught this young president that <span class="emphasis">priesthood</span> means reaching out to serve others. As our beloved prophet, President Thomas S. Monson, explains: “The priesthood is not really so much a gift as it is a commission to serve, a privilege to lift, and an opportunity to bless the lives of others” (“Our Sacred Priesthood Trust,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 2006, 57).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p24" guid="89c31ace-6f5b-4da5-b3c4-91ee2286303c" pid="vC-owF0Z6EuS3L_cJQg7PA" hash="uGU1EQ">Service is the very foundation of the priesthood—service to others as exemplified by the Savior. I testify that it is His priesthood, we are on His errand, and He has shown all priesthood holders the way of faithful priesthood service.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p25" guid="a427566a-e86c-435f-9c33-b5ef9fecd1f6" pid="GbVYhMR5mEm-sPeOBRa5iw" hash="8jog8g">I invite each deacons, teachers, and priests quorum presidency to regularly counsel, study, and pray to learn what the Lord’s will is for your quorum and then go and do. Use Duty to God to help you teach your quorum members their duties. I invite each quorum member to sustain your quorum president and look to him for counsel as you learn and righteously fulfill all of your priesthood duties. And I invite each of us to see these remarkable young men as the Lord sees them—a powerful resource for building and strengthening His kingdom here and now.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p26" guid="3c2bb784-8374-46c7-97e9-a91436a1139f" pid="pwYb9HBSr0qnv4ODOtGzcQ" hash="4QjNhw">You wonderful young men hold the Aaronic Priesthood, restored by John the Baptist to Joseph Smith and Oliver Cowdery near Harmony, Pennsylvania. Your priesthood holds the sacred keys that open the door for all of Heavenly Father’s children to come unto His Son, Jesus Christ, and follow Him. This is provided through “the gospel of repentance, and of baptism by immersion for the remission of sins”; the weekly ordinance of the sacrament; and “the ministering of angels” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/13.1" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 13:1</a>; <a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.69" class="scriptureRef">Joseph Smith—History 1:69</a>). You truly are ministers who must be clean and worthy and faithful priesthood men at all times and in all places.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p27" guid="f864e163-0c17-4ea9-ab2a-6381c9d797a4" pid="3E9hHtTHI0yASqSrJBJtCg" hash="qZXP0A">Why? Listen to the words of our beloved First Presidency, given to each one of you in your Duty to God:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p28" guid="222d7bfe-9be7-44c7-baeb-f7f741609af5" pid="zbpu7dO9GkOVGEn8w4cdng" hash="4emTXA">“You have the authority to administer the ordinances of the Aaronic Priesthood. … You will greatly bless the lives of those around you. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p29" guid="65b258e2-f39d-4ffb-9d94-6189652c07d8" pid="BhTSUdg1_E6g4LoYblly-Q" hash="FWIhEQ">“Heavenly Father has great trust and confidence in you and has an important mission for you to fulfill” (<span class="emphasis">Fulfilling My Duty to God: For Aaronic Priesthood Holders </span>[2010], 5).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood.p30" guid="338802c8-924f-42a4-8e0a-4ed5002253c8" pid="ps0aND-4IkejTocIEKWgHQ" hash="R0F72w">I know these words are true, and I pray that each of us will have that same witness. And I say these things in the sacred name of Him whose priesthood we hold, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/04/sacred-keys-of-the-aaronic-priesthood</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2011-general-conference/2011-04-3030-larry-m-gibson-64k-eng.mp3" length="5819024" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fatherhood—Our Eternal Destiny</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Brother Larry M. Gibson teaches men of the Church about the central importance of their role as fathers, both now and in eternity.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_12565_000_33gibson" doc-version="5" hash="M8YSXg">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="7WqYELUfnUWsQF7YZ-VEsQ" hash="qE5Z9A">Fatherhood—Our Eternal Destiny</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p2" pid="RHIKhWigk0mx3d_SX_2xvQ" hash="V0s8pQ">By Larry M. Gibson</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p3" pid="dXwFt7p5w0qeO7Yk8idwrA" hash="HLaZiQ">Recently Released First Counselor in the Young Men General Presidency</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=yDGgfoZpvEKjynkY4zr-FQ"><img xmlns="" type="jpg" uri="larry-m-gibson-10.jpg" translate="no" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255531/dba4d933e2e4462393c7291fad0f7e11/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255531/dba4d933e2e4462393c7291fad0f7e11/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255531/dba4d933e2e4462393c7291fad0f7e11/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x278="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255531/dba4d933e2e4462393c7291fad0f7e11/200x278.jpg" data-src-320x445="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255531/dba4d933e2e4462393c7291fad0f7e11/320x445.jpg" data-src-460x640="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255531/dba4d933e2e4462393c7291fad0f7e11/460x640.jpg" data-src-640x891="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255531/dba4d933e2e4462393c7291fad0f7e11/640x891.jpg" data-src-1024x1426="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255531/dba4d933e2e4462393c7291fad0f7e11/1024x1426.jpg" data-src-2048x2852="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255531/dba4d933e2e4462393c7291fad0f7e11/2048x2852.jpg" data-src-3698x5150="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255531/dba4d933e2e4462393c7291fad0f7e11/3698x5150.jpg" pid="yDGgfoZpvEKjynkY4zr-FQ" hash="JyjNNQ"></img></a>
		</div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="Z1bHmi9PeUqe5bOjYhLkmw" hash="9hf8TA"> May we each enjoy the fulness of Father’s blessings in this life and the fulfillment of His work and His glory by becoming fathers to our families for eternity. </p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="ChDNYalrWk6ulqQVDaSAkA" hash="V0s8pQ1">By Larry M. Gibson</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="lK4q9gqzkkGQvVMuGebGxw" hash="wus_uw">
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p5" pid="_ra7Q3gZdEKI_Gk-OCQgmQ" hash="nW4tBA">My father taught me a significant lesson when I was young. He sensed that I was becoming too enamored with temporal things. When I had money, I immediately spent it—almost always on myself.</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=klcWIt4ghU2LVvViN10ISA"><img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448794/57397d23f56e412d9573fe386ff90d1d/200x156.png" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x39="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448794/57397d23f56e412d9573fe386ff90d1d/50x39.png" data-src-100x78="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448794/57397d23f56e412d9573fe386ff90d1d/100x78.png" data-src-200x156="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448794/57397d23f56e412d9573fe386ff90d1d/200x156.png" data-src-320x251="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448794/57397d23f56e412d9573fe386ff90d1d/320x251.png" data-src-460x360="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448794/57397d23f56e412d9573fe386ff90d1d/460x360.png" data-src-640x502="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448794/57397d23f56e412d9573fe386ff90d1d/640x502.png" data-src-1024x803="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448794/57397d23f56e412d9573fe386ff90d1d/1024x803.png" data-src-2048x1606="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448794/57397d23f56e412d9573fe386ff90d1d/2048x1606.png" data-src-2790x2189="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448794/57397d23f56e412d9573fe386ff90d1d/2790x2189.png" altText="" pid="klcWIt4ghU2LVvViN10ISA" hash="nqcFwA"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p6" pid="fmSynwlBvkKR1G5HAF9X_Q" hash="u0k7gQ">One afternoon he took me to purchase some new shoes. On the second floor of the department store, he invited me to look out the window with him.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p7" pid="eIZy0mFhwEKZXYlPvGjZhw" hash="v4gNoA">“What do you see?” he asked.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p8" pid="fKRUsO8Ez0GTvCVtPA1NwA" hash="gr_98A">“Buildings, sky, people” was my response.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p9" pid="AS3VIoGDaUW6N5-BDixDDQ" hash="palYdQ">“How many?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p10" pid="bx2bNYyt50WlBu1t_Asqiw" hash="D2rCcw">“A lot!”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p11" pid="eMICr23oFEWXgP7TzFfbAg" hash="FTqKHQ">He then pulled this coin from his pocket. As he handed it to me, he asked, “What is this?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p12" pid="fLrHYPp8NkSm8y8PrM7pZQ" hash="atUPeA">I immediately knew: “A silver dollar!”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p13" pid="Ml5_yIO6M0mCGhy8t8RieQ" hash="psR-0g">Drawing on his knowledge of chemistry, he said, “If you melt that silver dollar and mix it with the right ingredients, you would have silver nitrate. If we coated this window with silver nitrate, what would you see?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p14" pid="Xv0unGCyR0eMqjOSXl0VGw" hash="V7KmyQ">I had no idea, so he escorted me to a full-length mirror and asked, “Now what do you see?”</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=H2hAoPzpRE2MeAqh7wG3_A"><img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448795/b358ef21a6a340c7a9a0a3c4af9494e9/200x129.png" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448795/b358ef21a6a340c7a9a0a3c4af9494e9/50x32.png" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448795/b358ef21a6a340c7a9a0a3c4af9494e9/100x64.png" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448795/b358ef21a6a340c7a9a0a3c4af9494e9/200x129.png" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448795/b358ef21a6a340c7a9a0a3c4af9494e9/320x206.png" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448795/b358ef21a6a340c7a9a0a3c4af9494e9/460x296.png" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448795/b358ef21a6a340c7a9a0a3c4af9494e9/640x412.png" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448795/b358ef21a6a340c7a9a0a3c4af9494e9/1024x660.png" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448795/b358ef21a6a340c7a9a0a3c4af9494e9/2048x1321.png" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448795/b358ef21a6a340c7a9a0a3c4af9494e9/2790x1800.png" altText="" pid="H2hAoPzpRE2MeAqh7wG3_A" hash="oVDQ-Q"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p15" pid="Beuy5Zz4zkCgJwx3MNIUHA" hash="gpFpig">“I see me.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p16" pid="yqTLH_cmVEuIZOC2oZcNmA" hash="dqJPaw">“No,” he replied, “what you see is silver reflecting you. If you focus on the silver, all you will see is yourself, and like a veil, it will keep you from seeing clearly the eternal destiny Heavenly Father has prepared just for you.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p17" pid="nNESSGsx5ESDacnr98qwHg" hash="eFp31g">“Larry,” he continued, “‘seek not the things of this world but seek … first … the kingdom of God, and to establish [<span class="emphasis">His</span>] righteousness, and all these things shall be added unto you’” (Joseph Smith Translation, Matthew 6:38 [in <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.33" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 6:33</a>, footnote <span class="emphasis">a</span>]).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p18" pid="ZZp8QAHvUU-ztF1MQlDHKQ" hash="i1h5bw">He told me to keep the dollar and never lose it. Each time I looked at it, I was to think about the eternal destiny that Heavenly Father has for me.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p19" pid="WrRbpQQd00WgGcZTsI0HjA" hash="xiID9A">I loved my father and how he taught. I wanted to be like him. He planted in my heart the desire to be a good father, and my deepest hope is that I am living up to his example.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p20" pid="X-snXNQ6gESAbPWjCzll7w" hash="XgMjsg">Our beloved prophet, President Thomas S. Monson, has often said that our decisions determine our destiny and have eternal consequences (see “Decisions Determine Destiny” [Church Educational System fireside, Nov. 6, 2005], 2; <a href="https://www.lds.org/broadcasts/archive/ces-devotionals/2005/01?lang=eng">lds.org/broadcasts</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p21" pid="kEsqYoK8ZEmmNG2AX5HESw" hash="-c99dA">Should we not, then, develop a clear vision of our <span class="emphasis">eternal destiny,</span> particularly the one that Heavenly Father wants us to achieve—eternal fatherhood? Let our <span class="emphasis">eternal destiny</span> drive <span class="emphasis">all</span> of our decisions. Regardless of how difficult those decisions may be, Father will sustain us.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p22" pid="fjRNFCjcsUO3bBB1Lyl_DQ" hash="gCFOOA">I learned about the power of such a vision when I joined my 12- and 13-year-old sons for a 50/20 competition. A 50/20 consists of walking 50 miles (80 km) in less than 20 hours. We started at 9:00 p.m. and walked all that night and most of the next day. It was an excruciating 19 hours, but we succeeded.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p23" pid="x0fttLXIqEiy_GLcughG6A" hash="fTuEEg">Upon returning home, we literally crawled into the house, where a wonderful wife and mother had prepared a lovely dinner, which we didn’t touch. My younger son collapsed, totally exhausted, on the couch, while my older son crawled downstairs to his bedroom.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p24" pid="mW__lRWhwUaYvI4SYbgIoA" hash="OTpqBQ">After some painful rest of my own, I went to my younger son to make sure he was still alive.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p25" pid="gRlpgV6qF0SlEhigpRMMdw" hash="Lj8w6A">“Are you OK?” I asked.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p26" pid="5rAQk8w6RUKS01ayKfHMCA" hash="zXT1ag">“Dad, that was the hardest thing I have ever done, and I never want to do it again.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p27" pid="ObswCXbUNUi76j5CeSRGOA" hash="rUPV0g">I wasn’t about to tell him that I would never do it again either. Instead, I told him how proud I was that he had accomplished such a hard thing. I knew it would prepare him for other hard things he would face in his future. With that thought, I said, “Son, let me make you this promise. When you go on your mission, you will never have to walk 50 miles in one day.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p28" pid="RDbEIj44JE6AlLdvnsOuRQ" hash="Fq3_MA">“Good, Dad! Then I’m going.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p29" pid="1S-r9_nkj0G-rtk40o6lXw" hash="twK3zg">Those simple words filled my soul with gratitude and joy.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p30" pid="KesgAa75a0OLX0E1VU_Dvw" hash="9F_tGw">I then went downstairs to my oldest son. I lay by him—then touched him. “Son, are you all right?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p31" pid="zzl632bc-kSA2s_26WGxfw" hash="Jh2x_A">“Dad, that was the most difficult thing I have ever done in my life, and I will never, ever do it again.” His eyes closed—then opened—and he said, “Unless my son wants me to.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p32" pid="sMksIBbuCU6qn2fV2MeQyw" hash="qqt_cA">Tears came as I expressed how grateful I was for him. I told him I knew he was going to be a much better father than I was. My heart was full because at his young and tender age he already recognized that one of his most sacred priesthood duties was to be a father. He had no fear of that role and title—the very title that God Himself wants us to use when we speak to Him. I knew I had the responsibility to nurture the embers of fatherhood that were burning within my son.</p>
		</span>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p33" pid="tW7ExnRakEWbOpFhB_lk0Q" hash="btb5Bg">These words of the Savior took on a much deeper meaning to me as a father:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p34" pid="pA7TQfG4bkmiZtWdGcAaWA" hash="cBbu5w">“The Son can do nothing of himself, but what he seeth the Father do: for [whatsoever things He] doeth, these also doeth the Son likewise” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.19" class="scriptureRef">John 5:19</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p35" pid="qJQK1OgLfEm3v-5RhL2O6w" hash="2hHMNQ">“I do nothing of myself; but as my Father hath taught me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.28" class="scriptureRef">John 8:28</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p36" pid="ypIpNKPx2UarSI7Yk8OrQw" hash="HW0KFg">I love being a husband and father—married to a chosen daughter of heavenly parents. I love her. It is one of the most fulfilling parts of my life. My hope that night was that my five sons and their sister would always see in me the joy that comes from eternal marriage, fatherhood, and family.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p37" pid="QGxbW-a5SUu66WzTMV5Hkw" hash="UB0ukQ">Fathers, I am sure you have heard the saying “Preach the gospel at all times, and when necessary use words” (attributed to Francis of Assisi). Every day you are teaching your children what it means to be a father. You are laying a foundation for the next generation. Your sons will learn how to be husbands and fathers by observing the way you fulfill these roles. For example:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p38" pid="jJnNnGFOX0W5ZlDsVqu0EQ" hash="pbS5sA">Do they know how much you love and cherish their mother and how much you love being their father?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p39" pid="QUiYuMKq1kW08rVXmk1UCg" hash="jNI6Rw">They will learn how to treat their future wife and children as they watch you treat <span class="emphasis">each one of them</span> just as Heavenly Father would.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p40" pid="_XWMbl5N-Eer8SkzPCj7tg" hash="2nnPTQ">Through your example, they can learn how to respect, honor, and protect womanhood.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p41" pid="jNaA9O-u3UuzK6P0YF0N8g" hash="uswo9g">In your home, they can learn to preside over their family in love and righteousness. They can learn to provide the necessities of life and protection for their family—temporally and spiritually (see “The Family: A Proclamation to the World,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign</span> or <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> Nov. 2010, 129).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p42" pid="wNjME5LIT0mvSucGY3t2aA" hash="9GDvUw">Brethren, with all the energy of my soul, I ask you to consider this question: Do your sons see you striving to do what Heavenly Father would have <span class="emphasis">them</span> do?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p43" pid="D6hgNDHywECkFH0-HbnQ-g" hash="1juJxQ">I pray the answer is yes. If the answer is no, it’s not too late to change, but you must begin today. And I testify that Heavenly Father will help you.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p44" pid="yIl7CM5Gc0idpuHBamN0BQ" hash="_jUW3g">Now, you young men, whom I dearly love, you know you are preparing to receive the Melchizedek Priesthood, receive sacred temple ordinances, fulfill your <span class="emphasis">duty</span> and <span class="emphasis">obligation</span> to serve a full-time mission, and then, without waiting too long, get married in the temple to a daughter of God and have a family. You are then to lead your family in spiritual things as guided by the Holy Ghost (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.44" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:44</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/46.2" class="scriptureRef">46:2</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.12" class="scriptureRef">107:12</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p45" pid="X59RrYFCnEGkMSd58NE-wA" hash="O_Wj0g">I have asked many young men around the world, “Why are you here?”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p46" pid="d9i4nBcCeESSoFB7kEDWQA" hash="LOMNQA">So far, not one has responded, “To learn to be a father, that I might be prepared and qualified to receive all that Heavenly Father has.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p47" pid="YMQoI9vZR0qKJhRCjmUuZQ" hash="XcbcFg">Let’s examine <span class="emphasis">your</span> Aaronic Priesthood duties as described in <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20" class="scriptureRef">section 20</a> of the Doctrine and Covenants. Be sensitive to what <span class="emphasis">you</span> feel as I apply these duties to your service in your family.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p48" pid="f5Tlt7nlRka_KeHNjVIb0A" hash="nhTTJg">“Invite all [of your family] to come unto Christ” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.59" class="scriptureRef">verse 59</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p49" pid="6yhsHVAob06KVCyyPFXkOw" hash="Ce8o5g">“Watch over [them] always, and be with and strengthen them” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.53" class="scriptureRef">verse 53</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p50" pid="zAPuVVEQcE-quLVLqG6fWA" hash="Rmyz8A">“Preach, teach, expound, exhort, and baptize” members of your family (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.46" class="scriptureRef">verse 46</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p51" pid="OErD4-L7T0atP3ylLzHfag" hash="o5tlGw">“Exhort them to pray vocally and in secret and attend to all family duties” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.47" class="scriptureRef">verse 47</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p52" pid="_MeqlbAyHEKeNCLtTEWDvQ" hash="EPjj2g">“See that there is no iniquity in [your family], neither hardness with each other, neither lying, backbiting, nor evil speaking” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.54" class="scriptureRef">verse 54</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p53" pid="aIhMFX_iMkq7MhnF1ZL_-g" hash="IjRI8g">“See that [your family meets] together often” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.55" class="scriptureRef">verse 55</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p54" pid="aLHflF1SnUml-wy8YtOg2Q" hash="E9c_hg">Assist your father in his duties as patriarch. Support your mother with priesthood strength when a father is not present (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.52,56" class="scriptureRef">verses 52, 56</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p55" pid="6kgjDwLsFkagbWEJ4u_4bA" hash="bXAR0w">When asked, “ordain other priests, teachers, and deacons” in your family (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.48" class="scriptureRef">verse 48</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p56" pid="ezJ1ILlc30e7O_bxmoIWUA" hash="6-s4xA">Doesn’t this sound like <span class="emphasis">the work and role of a father</span> ?</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=OGRKdCOfR0yTqjo2FEd7hA"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448796/75e4e64a4f164af596b220de0d2adc56/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448796/75e4e64a4f164af596b220de0d2adc56/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448796/75e4e64a4f164af596b220de0d2adc56/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448796/75e4e64a4f164af596b220de0d2adc56/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448796/75e4e64a4f164af596b220de0d2adc56/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448796/75e4e64a4f164af596b220de0d2adc56/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448796/75e4e64a4f164af596b220de0d2adc56/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448796/75e4e64a4f164af596b220de0d2adc56/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448796/75e4e64a4f164af596b220de0d2adc56/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448796/75e4e64a4f164af596b220de0d2adc56/2790x1800.jpg" altText="" pid="OGRKdCOfR0yTqjo2FEd7hA" hash="ASNYpQ"></img></a>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p57" pid="NqqGHNQsNUGA9a6BEpI7mg" hash="-Vpifg">Fulfilling your Aaronic Priesthood duties is preparing you young men for <span class="emphasis">fatherhood</span>. The <span class="emphasis">Duty to God</span> resource can help you learn about and make specific plans to fulfill your duties. It can serve as a guide and assistance as you seek Heavenly Father’s will and set goals to accomplish it.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p58" pid="_MrLL2TmA0KkCMUYj3yTxA" hash="TlpTgA">Father in Heaven has brought you here at this particular time for a special work and eternal purpose. He wants you to see clearly and understand what that purpose is. He is your Father, and you can always turn to Him for guidance.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny.p59" pid="yfAN5O_r3EqNy10gvi_0lQ" hash="axmw7A">I know that Heavenly Father is concerned about each of us individually and has a personal plan for us to achieve our eternal destiny. He has sent His Only Begotten Son, Jesus Christ, to help us overcome our imperfections through the Atonement. He has blessed us with the Holy Ghost to be a witness, companion, and guide <span class="emphasis">to our eternal destination</span> if we will rely on Him. May we each enjoy the fulness of Father’s blessings in this life and the fulfillment of <span class="emphasis">His work</span> and <span class="emphasis">His glory</span> by becoming fathers to our families for eternity (see <a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>). In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/04/fatherhood-our-eternal-destiny</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2015-general-conference/2015-04-3030-larry-m-gibson-64k-eng.mp3" length="5029452" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
