<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Lawrence E. Corbridge</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Lawrence E. Corbridge.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Lawrence%20E.%20Corbridge.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Lawrence E. Corbridge.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Way</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2008/10/the-way?lang=eng</link>
      <description>There is only one way to happiness and fulfillment. Jesus Christ is the Way.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00009501_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="LNtAtg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="p0tyNxjnUU2GxRmX-1QBIA" hash="XwpE0w">The Way</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="0GBr1UGXj0y6JYVBuaJM5w" hash="_AVuXA">Elder Lawrence E. Corbridge</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="Z-gCx0GUwEK9cWnSS0O41w" hash="foyCfA">There is only one way to happiness and fulfillment. Jesus Christ is the Way.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.t1">
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="hIIaOH0-70CZYhM-WE8X0A" hash="mSDYxg">Jesus Christ, Alpha and Omega, the Beginning and the End</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p1" pid="MfA7D60c-0a7P02y0dHxsw" hash="JhDbcw">
          <span class="pageBreak" page-number="34"></span>“In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God. …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p2" pid="QahrkM1yxU2KBB7c4luicA" hash="EuIuow">“In him was life; and the life was the light of men.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p3" pid="Po78u1Hl2UKlkb0pT9siSg" hash="82OgSw">He said, “I am Alpha and Omega, Christ the Lord; yea, even I am he, the beginning and the end, the Redeemer of the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p4" pid="Rz-dQyuiMEqRsd7N6JRV2Q" hash="lwlk7Q">He said, “Whosoever drinketh of the water that I shall give him shall never thirst; but the water that I shall give him shall be in him a well of water springing up into everlasting life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p5" pid="zdcVojr3706bC-0fVfQtng" hash="89wl-w">He said, “I am the bread of life: he that cometh to me shall never hunger; and he that believeth on me shall never thirst.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p6" pid="NIVZzpn6EU2jtc7_kMSQYA" hash="RuWcUw">He said, “I am the light of the world: he that followeth me shall not walk in darkness, but shall have the light of life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p7" pid="FTLrA8TPkkOK8xCS5HDJqg" hash="EITtnA">He said, “I am the resurrection, and the life: he that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p8" pid="8-QsaW6W-06qT9gNg0VPhQ" hash="xaLXnw">“And whosoever liveth and believeth in me shall never die.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p9" pid="crMf45FfM0yBExRHPkRmjA" hash="hoURXA">He said, “I am the way, the truth, and the life: no man cometh unto the Father, but by me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p10" pid="FmfWpHWEtESwafk4gpeh4g" hash="WoeGWA">Jesus Christ is the Way. He is Light and Life, Bread and Water, the Beginning and the End, the Resurrection and the Life, the Savior of the world, the Truth, and the Way.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p11" pid="MS_WoW7yD0al9bP5tVhRwQ" hash="HtQdow">There is only one way to happiness and fulfillment. He is the Way. Every other way, any other way, whatever other way, is foolishness.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p12" pid="8qhBYyXlG0CUEb1n9OFtVg" hash="r5PrNw">He offers a well of living water. Either we drink and never thirst more, or we don’t and foolishly remain thirsty still.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p13" pid="MG32sJgIt0eBvTwGukP-Hg" hash="463RKQ">He is the Bread of Life. Either we eat and hunger no more, or we don’t and foolishly remain weak and hungry still.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p14" pid="dkmCx1KA202jP18yz8JJww" hash="gv97Cg">He is the Light of the World. Either we follow Him and see clearly, or we don’t and foolishly remain blind and in darkness still.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p15" pid="AI6CcRwKgUyy1kzYxfZBgA" hash="jBd_gw">He is the Resurrection and the Life. He said, “The words that I speak unto you, they are spirit, and they are life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Either we learn of Him and have life more abundantly,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> or we don’t and foolishly remain dead still.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p16" pid="9_3GTwEcsEa729Kr2AWHKQ" hash="YLZhDg">He is the Savior of the world. Either we accept the blessings of His <span class="pageBreak" page-number="35"></span>Atonement and are made clean and pure, worthy to have His Spirit, or we don’t and foolishly remain alone and filthy still.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p17" pid="SL-qOXzoVEemFBpMDVQmww" hash="5Ddm8A">He is the Way.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="r_DEtwIEyUKvevMCwVz2SQ" hash="wbR8lw">No Other God</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p18" pid="E8sO6NN7DUmQ4r5l0PG9bw" hash="HKpCeg">“We believe in God, the Eternal Father, and in His Son, Jesus Christ, and in the Holy Ghost.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> The plan of the Father was implemented by the Son that we may have the Spirit of the Holy Ghost. The way of the Father is the way of the Son. He said, “Thou shalt have no other gods before me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p19" pid="BfqfiMx_EkCq1VaJ9SB12Q" hash="WlBrJA">Only God can bless us. Only He can sustain us. Only He can cause our hearts to beat and give us breath. Only He can preserve and protect us. Only He can give us strength to bear up the burdens of life. Only He can give us power, knowledge, peace, and joy. Only He can forgive our sins. Only He can heal us. Only He can change us and forge a godly soul. Only He can bring us back into His presence. And He will do all of that and much more if we but remember Him to keep His commandments. What then shall we do? We will remember Him to keep His commandments. It is the only intelligent thing to do.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="sCNW0z5M9EqSVplRTMsNZA" hash="xPxsig">Jesus Baptizes with the Holy Ghost</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p20" pid="zhgG5Vf9mEG0B1CBMvt7MA" hash="XHF9qQ">John the Baptist said that while he baptized with water, Jesus baptized “with the Holy Ghost.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p21" pid="KWktHdsrtk-jmVbdnzwrCQ" hash="0KEnYQ">Nothing in this life is of greater worth than the supernal gift of the Holy Ghost. It is the source of joy, peace, knowledge, strength, love, and every other good thing. With the Atonement, it is the power by which we may be changed and made strong where we are weak. With the priesthood, it is the power by which marriages and families are sealed together eternally.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> It is the power by which the Lord makes Himself manifest unto those who believe in Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> Every good thing depends on getting and keeping the power of the Holy Ghost in our lives. Everything depends on that.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p22" pid="MUsZas3rH0SZO9ipHFEJrw" hash="z5Hw9A">To that end, Jesus Christ entered a garden called Gethsemane, where He overcame sin for us. He took upon Himself our sins. He suffered the penalty of our wrongs. He paid the price of our education. I don’t know how He did what He did. I only know that He did and that because He did, you and I may be forgiven of our sins that we may be endowed with His power. Everything depends on that. What then shall we do? We will “take upon [us] the name of [the] Son, and always remember him and keep his commandments which he has given [us]; that [we] may always have his Spirit to be with [us].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> Everything depends on that.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="gdhLUuEk706g0irgQ9zwFg" hash="5sc7YQ">“My Yoke Is Easy, and My Burden Is Light”</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p23" pid="9hSP81s1VkyWg0XwW-p3Fg" hash="TYQU6Q">One of the most popular and attractive philosophies of men is to live life your own way, do your own <span class="pageBreak" page-number="36"></span>thing, be yourself, don’t let others tell you what to do. But the Lord said, “I am the way.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> He said, “Follow me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> He said, “What manner of men ought ye to be? Verily I say unto you, even as I am.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p24" pid="g5hfuEEcTE63lAJSJPjmGw" hash="9RX3rA">Don’t think you can’t. We might think we can’t really follow Him because the standard of His life is so astonishingly high as to seem unreachable. We might think it is too hard, too high, too much, beyond our capacity, at least for now. Don’t ever believe that. While the standard of the Lord is the highest, don’t ever think it is only reachable by a select few who are most able.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p25" pid="k8EDLozYuUakw_jArHzx8w" hash="2GFeMw">In this singular instance life’s experience misleads us. In life we learn that the highest achievements in any human endeavor are always the most difficult and, therefore, achievable only by a select few who are most able. The higher the standard, the fewer can reach it.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p26" pid="txUtMmsjtkemP7gHdR7OmQ" hash="JEpKkQ">But that is not the case here because, unlike every other experience in this life, this is not a human endeavor. It is, rather, the work of God. It is God’s work and it is His “glory … to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> There is nothing else like it. Not anywhere. Not ever.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p27" pid="nFOzPvpap0G18hKA8eHqJA" hash="xSQ7AA">No institution, plan, program, or system ever conceived by men has access to the redeeming and transforming power of the Atonement of Jesus Christ and the gift of the Holy Ghost. Therefore, while the Lord’s invitation to follow Him is the highest of all, it is also achievable by everyone, not because we are able, but because He is, and because He can make us able too. “We believe that through the Atonement of Christ, all mankind [everyone, living and dead] may be saved, by obedience to the laws and ordinances of the Gospel.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p28" pid="87yuSwppV0SArkOoXUXbkg" hash="gNgiRA">The Lord’s way is not hard. Life is hard, not the gospel. “There is an opposition in all things,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> everywhere, for everyone. Life is hard for all of us, but life is also simple. We have only two choices.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> We can either follow the Lord and be endowed with His power and have peace, light, strength, knowledge, confidence, love, and joy, or we can go some other way, any other way, whatever other way, and go it alone—without His support, without His power, without guidance, in darkness, turmoil, doubt, grief, and despair. And I ask, which way is easier?</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p29" pid="YxXGQiDTkkymIOHMYJekeg" hash="s3p0zg">He said, “Come unto me, all ye that labour and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p30" pid="yaXSokfCR0CoVf3a2wX0Zw" hash="NNHjYg">“Take my yoke upon you, and learn of me; … and ye shall find rest unto your souls.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p31" pid="wEGwIRwGzUqd8cA6s_FrAw" hash="IwlcHA">“For my yoke is easy, and my burden is light.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p32" pid="trgxAEyPckeTGYHqyel5wg" hash="gwJtGA">Life is hard, but life is simple. Get on the path and never, ever give up. You never give up. You just keep on going. You don’t quit, and you will make it.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p33" pid="D-uYkzudaUqeaux6PZzhfQ" hash="3M-zjg">There is only one way to happiness and fulfillment. Jesus Christ is the Way. Every other way, any other way, whatever other way is foolishness.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p34" pid="gkeko9oMJ0WRRK89hr8_1Q" hash="4hbstA">I bear record of Him, even Jesus Christ, that He is the Son of the living God, He is the Bread of Life, He is the Truth, He is the Resurrection and the Life, He is the Savior and the Light of the World. He is the Way, the only Way.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/the-way.p35" pid="P5-F2M5nS0-RED_YrC_99Q" hash="JPJ8Qg">May we have the good sense to follow Him. In His holy name, even Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2008/10/the-way</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2008-general-conference/2008-10-2050-elder-lawrence-e-corbridge-64k-eng.mp3" length="5696092" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Prophet Joseph Smith</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Lawrence E. Corbridge testifies of the important doctrine restored by the Prophet Joseph Smith.
		</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10985_000_54corbridge" doc-version="2" hash="K5uViQ">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="r8YpaCNCOUOfBz2LCmgZhQ" hash="tzEIWw">The Prophet Joseph Smith</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p" pid="HLqfH3Xv6USj7Owcy0xEyA" hash="-txwnA">By Elder Lawrence E. Corbridge</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p" pid="YPKxY-WePk-ObtCyjxGaPA" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
		</div>
		<img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/leaders/lawrence-e-corbridge.jpg" altText="Elder Lawrence E. Corbridge" pid="J6RZwyBUV0GulY5b3ct6vw" hash="7mKt3w" />
		<p class="kicker" pid="DO1HEDZJQkOcSNa6NQlbxw" hash="DOdGQg">The revelations poured out upon Joseph Smith affirm that he was a prophet of God.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="Qy-aMwgifUu2uwMvAgr78g" hash="-txwnA1">By Elder Lawrence E. Corbridge</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.t1">
			<h2 class="title" pid="wp7E3GpOBEux8us1OndwZg" hash="SXy8bQ">The First Vision</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p6" pid="1M4vbxzTQEmn6zRg-1JZNg" hash="dvBHGg">A young boy reads the Bible, and his eyes pause on a singular passage of scripture. This is a moment that will change the world.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p7" pid="o7FGO2pxLkK0o3_q7PhWPA" hash="e_CBZg">He is anxious to know which church can lead him to truth and salvation. He has tried almost everything else, and now he turns to the Bible and reads these words: “If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask of God, that giveth to all men liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span>
			</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p8" pid="e3fGMs41UkaEOzpIuDBf2g" hash="-oGU0w">He reflects on them over and over again. The first glimmer of light penetrates the darkness. Is this the answer, the way out of confusion and darkness? Can it be this simple? Ask God and He will answer? At length he decides he must either ask God or ever remain in darkness and confusion.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p9" pid="ltq3qgTVYEibE16aRJE2eQ" hash="kHcJTw">And yet as anxious as he is, he doesn’t run to a quiet corner and rattle off a hurried prayer. He is only 14, but in his haste to know, he is not hasty. This is not to be just any prayer. He decides where to go and when to make the attempt. He prepares to talk to God.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p10" pid="bgccBEu7-U6_2YwNR-AT0w" hash="j4zELw">And then the day comes. It is “the morning of a beautiful, clear day, early in the spring of [1820].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> He walks alone into the stillness of the nearby woods, beneath the trees that tower above him. He reaches the place where he previously designed to go. He kneels and offers up the desires of his heart.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p11" pid="bibs8PKVrkaV_HwDIqAJBA" hash="8NRHUg">Describing what happens next, he says:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p12" pid="NTB1DfLeFk-n00oQBsWmiw" hash="U_btDw">
				<span class="pageBreak" page-number="104"></span>“I saw a pillar of light exactly over my head, above the brightness of the sun, which descended gradually until it fell upon me.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p13" pid="eGMRQ3VfZUWY0rDq-wFxng" hash="fqjMTA">“… When the light rested upon me I saw two Personages, whose brightness and glory defy all description, standing above me in the air. One of them spake unto me, calling me by name and said, pointing to the other—[Joseph,] <span class="emphasis">This is My Beloved Son. Hear Him!</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span>
			</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p14" pid="zInrM1ImBEisZfzEPnGqgg" hash="zzwRug">Only 24 years later, Joseph Smith and his brother Hyrum will die because of what began here.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.t2">
			<h2 class="title" pid="Xa3ZlEPwDEGxbezVc0EnRw" hash="IKcR1A">Opposition</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p16" pid="kzlu7aAqb06WCL1cbESr1A" hash="YZy3uQ">Joseph said that when he was 17, an angel told him that his “name [would] be had for good and evil among all nations, … among all people.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> This amazing prophecy is continuing to be fulfilled today as The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints has spread throughout the world.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p17" pid="0qTFdXRB3UKN67XHhCSYXA" hash="SMRv9g">Opposition, criticism, and antagonism are companions to the truth. Whenever the truth with regard to the purpose and destiny of man is revealed, there will always be a force to oppose it. Beginning with Adam and Eve in the Garden of Eden, down to the ministry of Christ, and on down to our day, there has always been and will ever be an effort to deceive, derail, oppose, and frustrate the plan of life.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p18" pid="Ll59NVABRUiIv9Ay8Ysc8Q" hash="oB7UCw">Look for the biggest dust cloud billowing above the most dirt that is kicked at One who was most opposed, challenged, and rejected, beaten, abandoned, and crucified, One who descended below all things, and there you will find the truth, the Son of God, the Savior of all mankind. Why did they not leave Him alone?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p19" pid="r9Ad2CCN9keXSzgyJVq5cA" hash="ZnbkLg">Why? Because He is the truth, and the truth will always be opposed.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p20" pid="mjLk_1APw0mpgIGOGi2RvQ" hash="mSVIoA">And then look for one who brought forth another testament of Jesus Christ and other scripture, look for one who was the instrument by which the fulness of the gospel and the Church of Jesus Christ were restored to the earth, look for him and expect to find the dirt flying. Why not leave him alone?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p21" pid="LmnFn6Wv80OWOyozldz1_w" hash="wSanJA">Why? Because he taught the truth, and the truth will always be opposed.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.t3">
			<h2 class="title" pid="6bXFBe5enkywwsJsEcXRsQ" hash="rAQWyA">The Flood of Revelation</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p23" pid="dEXwjjNu6US1Zly8W-XRsQ" hash="eQjGZg">The revelations poured out upon Joseph Smith affirm that he was a prophet of God. Let’s just look at some of them—just look at some of the light and truth revealed through him that shines in stark contrast to the common beliefs of his day and ours:</p>
			<div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.f1">
				<ul class="bullet" guid="">
					<li pid="Yp51TkAmOU-mniuEDd2j9Q" hash="HjY7Fw">
						<span class="label">• </span>
						<p pid="LB-zuFYasUycrxJrSqo3_A" hash="ROXQgw">God is a personal, exalted being, an Eternal Father. He is our Father.</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="j-NPn12GvEWmaoOdD6FIAA" hash="q8EP0g">
						<span class="label">• </span>
						<p pid="X466hZi_30KOo3U_enw6_A" hash="zDHDxg">God the Father, Jesus Christ, and the Holy Ghost are separate beings.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span>
						</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="Hf0ZR7e7i02oge_SEsN8Jg" hash="zknlJg">
						<span class="label">• </span>
						<p pid="43bcpWDHk0mvRcqYkYKaGg" hash="XIeHlw">You are more than human. You are a child of God the Eternal Father and may become like Him<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> if you will have faith in His Son, repent, receive ordinances, receive the Holy Ghost, and endure to the end.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span>
						</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="SIlPXRqZA0OnSV9OKtRlJg" hash="fmVv_Q">
						<span class="label">• </span>
						<p pid="8LUyW8oRjEOEg2rnmIagHw" hash="af4HWQ">The Church of Jesus Christ today is fundamentally the same Church He organized during His mortal ministry, with prophets and apostles, Melchizedek and Levitical <span class="pageBreak" page-number="105"></span>Priesthoods, elders, high priests, deacons, teachers, bishops, and the seventy, all as described in the Bible.</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="VBRAD7kQPEiL5ZnqS8aZbw" hash="5uTWPA">
						<span class="label">• </span>
						<p pid="6Htn2nSlOUWmFXnoh1uUuA" hash="pwfXDQ">Priesthood authority was withheld from the earth following the deaths of the Savior and His Apostles and was restored again in our day.</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="lIWCaerHgk-IsBmxO4Qh1w" hash="9igrgg">
						<span class="label">• </span>
						<p pid="uxZdJ_umwUe5ZqTpjTaZMg" hash="7dFs9A">Revelation has not ceased, and the heavens are not closed. God speaks to prophets today, and He will speak to you and me as well.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span>
						</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="k8kyIRx4gEyBFMd6nTApVQ" hash="B0ZrVw">
						<span class="label">• </span>
						<p pid="AgB6ERjYd02vAVNWOOMR0w" hash="TmmNsQ">There is more after this life than only heaven and hell. There are degrees of glory, and it matters a great deal what we do in this life.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span>
						</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="p2MUQGkqzkO3BKKApYMjhg" hash="aZADSA">
						<span class="label">• </span>
						<p pid="C5U8p5ey10OR7iWrf5bPpQ" hash="tgB9-A">More than having a mere passive belief in Christ, we should “look unto [Him] in every thought,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> “do all that [we do] in the name of the Son,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> and “always remember him and keep his commandments … that [we] may always have his Spirit to be with [us].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span>
						</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="NLndn9CZU0OBWBZkqDhTIQ" hash="MFRm0g">
						<span class="label">• </span>
						<p pid="lCdgv5AfAUSa0svlUZ1VkQ" hash="vIC8wg">The billions who live and die without the gospel and the ordinances necessary for salvation are not lost. “Through the Atonement of Christ, all mankind may be saved, by obedience to the laws and ordinances of the Gospel,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> administered for both the living and the dead.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span>
						</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="o8zekDNZK0iweoRZXBU9tg" hash="U0vn4w">
						<span class="label">• </span>
						<p pid="TDlojxC6uUi4cctncwirdw" hash="_lCsuQ">Everything did not begin at birth. You lived before in the presence of God as His son or daughter and prepared for this mortal life.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span>
						</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="pcv1O3OGg0iRuJSBd4E-Pg" hash="plnqCg">
						<span class="label">• </span>
						<p pid="UJ2NPp1Zu0W-RDdYoTEEqQ" hash="ZCSOjw">Marriage and family are not conventions of men until only death do us part. They are intended to be made eternal through covenants we make with God. The family is the pattern of heaven.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span>
						</p>
					</li>
				</ul>
			</div>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p35" pid="Jeo0iDNx5UmSANFVcu1Mxw" hash="bEVtxQ">And this is only a part of the flood of revelation poured out upon Joseph Smith. Where did it all come from, these revelations which give light to darkness, clarity to doubt, and which have inspired, blessed, and improved millions of people? Which is more likely, that he dreamed it all up on his own or that he had the help of heaven? Do the scriptures he produced sound like the words of man or the words of God?</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.t4">
			<h2 class="title" pid="qSpHnE1HjkG8aPZt1LK87w" hash="JZFLeA">Conclusion</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p37" pid="OWGDiY4ME0ufUIxDVtG7Qw" hash="bxh1Pw">There is no dispute about what Joseph Smith accomplished, only how he did what he did and why. And there are not many options. He was either pretender or prophet. Either he did what he did alone, or he had the help of heaven. Look at the evidence, but look at all of the evidence, the entire mosaic of his life, not any single piece. Most importantly, do as young Joseph and “ask … God, that giveth to all men liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given [you].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> This is not only how you may learn the truth about the Book of Mormon and Joseph Smith; it is also the pattern to know the truth of all things.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span>
			</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p38" pid="KA8G7zaIyUu2csZsvZSYiA" hash="zPM8Wg">Joseph Smith was a prophet of God, as is Thomas S. Monson today. Through Joseph Smith, “the keys of the kingdom of God are [again] committed unto man on the earth, and … the gospel [will] roll forth … as the stone which is cut out of the mountain without hands … , until it has filled the whole earth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span>
			</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith.p39" pid="9aLuHKVPUUy2GuGVUqq7FA" hash="rN_CAg">God is our Eternal Father, and Jesus is the Christ. We worship Them. Nothing compares with Their creations, the plan of salvation, and the atoning sacrifice of the Lamb of God. In this dispensation, we fulfill the plan of the Father and partake of the fruits of the Atonement only by obedience to the laws and ordinances of the gospel, restored through the Prophet Joseph Smith. I bear testimony of Them—God the Eternal Father and Jesus Christ, the Savior of the world. And I do so in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/04/the-prophet-joseph-smith</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2014-general-conference/2014-04-5040-elder-lawrence-e-corbridge-64k-eng.mp3" length="5191804" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
