<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Linda S. Reeves</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Linda S. Reeves.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Linda%20S.%20Reeves.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Linda S. Reeves.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Claim the Blessings of Your Covenants</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As we renew and honor our covenants, our burdens can be lightened and we can continually become purified and strengthened.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10791_000_63reeves" doc-version="5" hash="rH4KOg">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="4FiNkk2d_UqRcClQNPiqBw" hash="xfHMjQ">Claim the Blessings of Your Covenants</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="vO4zDsTRrUmjU5yA1SRyIQ" hash="WpePOw">By Linda S. Reeves</p>
		<p class="kicker" pid="hf0X8zg8fkqjpkt81yajFQ" hash="InyWLw">As we renew and honor our covenants, our burdens can be lightened and we can continually become purified and strengthened.</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="A6aegxBb7U-VVw1JVXGjHg" hash="fcscuQ">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p5" pid="6A6t-9-e10ivJ-Ca98fDYg" hash="8rsImQ"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="118"></span>Sisters, how wonderful it is to be with you again.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p6" pid="RoMFOU3l4kOFgGKLnJ5qCw" hash="5YPwug">I recently met a woman who was preparing to be baptized. This particular Sunday she arrived at church having walked two miles (3 km) in heavy mud. She immediately went into the restroom, removed her muddy clothes, washed, and put on clean Sunday clothes. In the Relief Society meeting she told of her conversion. I was touched by her overwhelming desire to be washed clean and pure through repentance and the atoning sacrifice of the Savior and her willingness to give up her “old life” in order to make sacred covenants with our Father in Heaven. She had separated from her boyfriend, was overcoming addictions in order to live the Word of Wisdom, quit her Sunday job, and lost the friendship of loved ones when she announced her plans to be baptized. She was so anxious to give away all of her sins that she might be washed clean and feel the redeeming love of the Savior. I was inspired that morning by her desire to become both physically and spiritually clean.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p7" pid="qhP68r8RzE2ZJNhv71Ifyw" hash="AoB_kQ">We know that many of you have made similar sacrifices as you have felt the witness of the Holy Ghost and have longed to repent, be baptized, and be made clean. Perhaps at no other time do we feel the divine love of the Savior as abundantly as we do when we repent and feel His loving arms outstretched to embrace us and assure us of His love and acceptance.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p8" pid="PDgRllKog06Q4TlPmodbxA" hash="8qfQ_Q">A few Sundays ago as I listened to the sacrament prayer, I was moved by the way that the priest pronounced each word with great feeling. Later I called that priest to thank him for helping make the sacrament a deep spiritual experience for me and the congregation. He was not at home, but his mother responded, “Oh, he will be so happy that you called! This was his first time giving the sacrament prayer, and we have been preparing together, talking about the importance of the sacrament and worthily renewing our baptismal covenants with the Savior.” How I love this dear mother for teaching her son about the power of baptismal covenants and how he can help the members of the ward feel that power.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p9" pid="QjOKn6DSYUaa-JLvSBlFzA" hash="ao8Dmw">Another mother I know of has sat alone at church for a number of years with her four young children. Seldom able to concentrate on the Savior during the sacrament, she formed a plan. Now she tries to spend time each Saturday reviewing her week and thinking about her covenants and what she needs to repent of. “Then,” she says, “no matter what kind of an experience I have with my children on Sunday, I am prepared to partake of the sacrament, renew my covenants, and feel of the cleansing power of the Atonement.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p10" pid="5zfzBCHhrUesjJtwhh4XUQ" hash="1-hxqg">Why does the Savior put so much importance upon the sacrament, dear sisters? What importance does this weekly renewal of our baptismal covenants play in our lives? Do we recognize the ability of the Savior to completely cleanse us every week as we worthily and thoughtfully partake of the sacrament? President Boyd K. Packer has testified, “That is the promise of the gospel of Jesus Christ and the Atonement: … that at the end of [our lives, we] can go through the veil having repented of [our] sins and having been washed clean through the blood of Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p11" pid="RTvNiWmVjkWgOJCMzEoh9A" hash="JjWl2g">Our presidency feels great joy as our sisters and their families make and keep covenants, but our hearts <span class="pageBreak" page-number="119"></span>ache for those of you who are experiencing great adversity in your lives because of the covenant-breaking of loved ones. The prophet Jacob, brother to Nephi, was charged by the Lord to speak to his brethren concerning the righteous women and children of his day. I testify that his words have been preserved specifically for our day. He speaks to us as if the Savior Himself were speaking. Jacob was “weighed down with much … anxiety” as he testified to husbands and fathers:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p12" pid="a4fph5jnok-sq1fPqcBlQw" hash="AEkDlw">“It grieveth me that I must use so much boldness of speech … before your wives and your children, many of whose feelings are exceedingly tender and chaste and delicate. …</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p13" pid="oVG0G0kz7E-SqE6x5FopdQ" hash="ASoQRg">“… The sobbings of their hearts ascend up to God. … Many hearts [have] died, pierced with deep wounds.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p14" pid="aaE2lpEYx0CDuOUv137XYQ" hash="AACSEQ">To the covenant-keeping women and children of his and our day, Jacob promises:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p15" pid="X7EwqCyyMUyFmr5CxL7dvg" hash="ikPsuA">“Look unto God with firmness of mind, and pray unto him with exceeding faith, and he will console you in your afflictions. …</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p16" pid="20ecnsahrE6GtUCadp4LxA" hash="13V3eA">“… Lift up your heads and receive the pleasing word of God, and feast upon his love.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p17" pid="D50_Btgds0OppUMIdFNZCA" hash="bgC0vg">Sisters, I testify of the strength and power of prayer as we express our deepest pains and desires to our Heavenly Father and of the answers that are received as we “feast upon” the scriptures and the words of the living prophets.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p18" pid="-_-YlVXEt0W3_WGRKeyAzA" hash="r2mjOA">Almost three years ago a devastating fire gutted the interior of the beloved, historic tabernacle in Provo, Utah. Its loss was deemed a great tragedy by both the community and Church members. Many wondered, “Why did the Lord let this happen? Surely He could have prevented the fire or stopped its destruction.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p19" pid="nwprpi0WMkuBLTrktEBuZg" hash="U99_6w">Ten months later, during the October 2011 general conference, there was an audible gasp when President Thomas S. Monson announced that the nearly destroyed tabernacle was to become a holy temple—a house of the Lord! Suddenly we could see what the Lord had always known! He didn’t cause the fire, but He allowed the fire to strip away the interior. He saw the tabernacle as a magnificent temple—a permanent home for making sacred, eternal covenants.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p20" pid="rnECocXU1kyfwflyWd6J5A" hash="6V7_HA">My dear sisters, the Lord allows us to be tried and tested, sometimes to our maximum capacity. We have seen the lives of loved ones—and maybe our own—figuratively burned to the ground and have wondered why a loving and caring Heavenly Father would allow such things to happen. But He does not leave us in the ashes; He stands with open arms, eagerly inviting us to come to Him. He is building our lives into magnificent temples where His Spirit can dwell eternally.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p21" pid="Ka6UMp41XEih-UlA9gMqCQ" hash="GktKpg">In <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.3-4" class="scriptureRef">Doctrine and Covenants 58:3–4</a>, the Lord tells us:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p22" pid="wCMbHphrxEqYosygHnTJ0A" hash="1c8MTg">“Ye cannot behold with your natural eyes, for the present time, the design of your God concerning those things which shall come hereafter, and the glory which shall follow after much tribulation.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p23" pid="6S04VzdNdkWUT_oc6hyd8g" hash="2Xx4FA">“For after much tribulation come the blessings. Wherefore the day cometh that ye shall be crowned with much glory.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p24" pid="i4xlrKAxNUSvs7x-gD7Xag" hash="tr0Z6g">Sisters, I testify that the Lord has a plan for each of our lives. Nothing that happens is a shock or a surprise <span class="pageBreak" page-number="120"></span>to Him. He is all-knowing and all-loving. He is eager to help us, to comfort us, and to ease our pain as we rely on the power of the Atonement and honor our covenants. The trials and tribulation that we experience may be the very things that guide us to come unto Him and cling to our covenants so that we might return to His presence and receive all that the Father hath.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p25" pid="I8jsqe8ns0mbhe8OzXwDww" hash="2ydUPA">This past year I have needed and wanted to feel the love of the Lord more deeply, to receive personal revelation, to better understand my temple covenants, and to have my burdens lightened. As I have prayed specifically for these blessings, I have felt the Spirit directing me to go to the temple and listen more closely to each word of the blessings pronounced upon me. I testify that as I have listened more intently and tried to exercise my faith, the Lord has been merciful to me and has helped make my burdens light. He has helped me to feel great peace about prayers that have not yet been answered. We bind the Lord to keep His promises when we keep our covenants and exercise our faith.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Come to the temple, dear sisters, and claim your blessings!</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p26" pid="KQWZyrhPBU6DE2FYnZzVwA" hash="ODtWSA">I want to touch upon another way that can instill us with confidence and faith. We sometimes, as women, have a tendency to be very critical of ourselves. During these times we need to seek the Spirit and ask, “Is this what the Lord wants me to think about myself, or is Satan trying to beat me down?” Remember the nature of our Heavenly Father, whose love is perfect and infinite.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> He wants to build us up, not tear us down.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p27" pid="V8ZATcLGFE2e1F4qJ0wWQg" hash="Kj5Y7Q">As members of the Church, we may sometimes feel that we need to be part of a “perfect LDS family” in order to be accepted by the Lord. We often feel “less-than” or like misfits in the kingdom if we feel we do not fit that picture. Dear sisters, when all is said and done, what will matter to our Father in Heaven will be how well we have kept our covenants and how much we have tried to follow the example of our Savior, Jesus Christ.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants.p28" pid="x0rQhOEIyEOTguWvX_OjOw" hash="_P1tGA">I testify that Jesus Christ is our Savior and Redeemer. Because of His atoning sacrifice, we can be washed clean weekly as we worthily partake of His sacrament. As we renew and honor our covenants, our burdens can be lightened and we can continually become purified and strengthened so that at the end of our lives we will be counted worthy to receive exaltation and eternal life. I testify of these things in the name of our beloved Savior, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2013/10/claim-the-blessings-of-your-covenants</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2013-general-relief-society-meeting/2013-09-0030-linda-s-reeves-64k-eng.mp3" length="5843157" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protection from Pornography—a Christ-Focused Home</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Linda S. Reeves warns families of the dangers of pornography and explains that the best filter is a strong testimony. </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10985_000_15reeves" doc-version="3" hash="cJ3eUg">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="kA5x76rBPkmdGJGiPSHUFA" hash="y8KH6g">Protection from Pornography—a Christ-Focused Home</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p" pid="iIOBIPRfikOQmc2ECVuKUA" hash="WpePOw">By Linda S. Reeves</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p" pid="LPsK5no8s0O1fI7vIeMFlA" hash="QIuFfA">Second Counselor in the Relief Society General Presidency</p>
		</div>
		<img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/leaders/linda-s-reeves.jpg" altText="Linda S. Reeves" pid="WYwdfTYowkeQgZOJ-yc8yw" hash="HS7vpg" />
		<p class="kicker" pid="OsvrmUkhDUK1nK52E8ggsQ" hash="ToOn-w">The greatest filter in the world … is the personal internal filter that comes from a deep and abiding testimony.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="Abu8KSqbhkOZnyHp6UOn2w" hash="WpePOw1">By Linda S. Reeves</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="_FiCJS3CvEm8y5opopi8Cw" hash="MpbvyQ">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p5" pid="jeCKbSwYdECwmwmlGr601g" hash="2KmMIA">
			<span class="pageBreak" page-number="15"></span>Dear brothers and sisters, today I am blessed to have my 13 oldest grandchildren in the congregation. This has caused me to ask, “What do I want my grandchildren to know?” This morning I would like to talk frankly to my family and to yours.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p6" pid="gmyWiVEX-ECEJHy0InOgVQ" hash="sg89TQ">We as leaders are increasingly concerned about the destruction that pornography is causing in the lives of Church members and their families. Satan is attacking with unprecedented fury.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p7" pid="9ac8_lCCYEi32RciJUrGEg" hash="SyLTRg">One reason we are here on earth is to learn to manage the passions and feelings of our mortal bodies. These God-given feelings help us want to marry and have children. The intimate marriage relationship between a man and a woman that brings children into mortality is also meant to be a beautiful, loving experience that binds together two devoted hearts, unites both spirit and body, and brings a fulness of joy and happiness as we learn to put each other first. President Spencer W. Kimball taught that in marriage, “the spouse … becomes preeminent in the life of the husband or wife, and … [no] other interest [or] person [or] thing shall ever take precedence over the companion spouse. …</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p8" pid="NeY5rWHUOEeQiPMVvCVhEA" hash="ouIKnA">“Marriage presupposes total allegiance and total fidelity.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span>
		</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p9" pid="g3yiOyuRnEKypBBqNjEjmw" hash="nyhqjw">Many years ago one of our children was noticeably distressed. I stepped into her bedroom, where she opened up her heart and explained to me that she had been at a friend’s home and had accidentally seen startling and disturbing images and actions on the television between a man and a woman without clothing. She began sobbing and expressed how horrible she felt about what she had seen and wished she could get it out of her mind. I was so grateful that she would confide in me, giving me a chance to soothe her innocent and aching heart and help her know how to get relief through our Savior’s Atonement. I remember the sacred feelings I had as we knelt together, as mother and daughter, and petitioned the help of our Heavenly Father.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p10" pid="O-t82XJqEkq_Xw-NJuN1Ig" hash="zP_LSg">Many children, youth, and adults are innocently exposed to pornography, but a growing number of both men and women are choosing to view it and are drawn back repeatedly until it becomes an addiction. These individuals may desire with all of their hearts to get out of this trap but often cannot overcome it on their own. How grateful we are when these loved ones choose to confide in us as parents or a Church leader. We would be wise not to react with shock, anger, or rejection, which may cause them to be silent again.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p11" pid="Nu_RBZrP0UmWwWLhLh6mdQ" hash="SjeoFg">We as parents and leaders need to counsel with our children and youth on an ongoing basis, listening with love and understanding. They need to know the dangers of pornography and how it overtakes lives, causing loss of the Spirit, distorted feelings, deceit, damaged relationships, loss of self-control, and nearly total consumption of time, thought, and energy.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p12" pid="152h1DystEGVTgBsIF7CnQ" hash="Wk-6sQ">Pornography is more vile, evil, and graphic than ever before. As we counsel with our children, together we can create a family plan with standards and boundaries, being proactive to protect our homes with filters on electronic devices. Parents, are we aware that mobile devices with Internet capacity, not computers, are the biggest culprit?<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p13" pid="MCqW40oVLEa-gThP0zH-3A" hash="srwaJQ">Young people and adults, if you are caught in Satan’s trap of pornography, remember how merciful our beloved Savior is. Do you realize how deeply the Lord loves and cherishes you, even now? Our Savior has the power to cleanse and heal you. He can remove the pain and sorrow you feel and make you clean again through the power of His Atonement.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p14" pid="U4stFNNkPUm-XQCZzeMMWA" hash="Di8_KQ">
			<span class="pageBreak" page-number="16"></span>We as leaders are also greatly concerned about the spouses and families of those suffering from pornography addiction. Elder Richard G. Scott has pleaded: “If you are free of serious sin yourself, don’t suffer needlessly the consequences of another’s sins. … You can feel compassion. … Yet you should not take upon yourself a feeling of responsibility for those acts.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Know that you are not alone. There is help. Addiction recovery meetings for spouses are available, including phone-in meetings, which allow spouses to call in to a meeting and participate from their own homes.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p15" pid="ckryLW3caEaPQzTyTY4Fvw" hash="Qf5Y-A">Brothers and sisters, how do we protect our children and youth? Filters are useful tools, but the greatest filter in the world, the only one that will ultimately work, is the personal internal filter that comes from a deep and abiding testimony of our Heavenly Father’s love and our Savior’s atoning sacrifice for each one of us.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p16" pid="sXLaMe3B0UWgmnnD-Huy-g" hash="FR_kuA">How do we lead our children to deep conversion and to access our Savior’s Atonement? I love the prophet Nephi’s declaration of what his people did to fortify the youth of his day: “We talk of Christ, we rejoice in Christ, we preach of Christ, [and] we prophesy of Christ … that our children may know to what source they may look for a remission of their sins.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span>
		</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p17" pid="4lckvgPmkkiv8UZzpUxmwg" hash="059uOg">How can we do this in our homes? Some of you have heard me tell how overwhelmed my husband, Mel, and I felt as the parents of four young children. As we faced the challenges of parenting and keeping up with the demands of life, we were desperate for help. We prayed and pleaded to know what to do. The answer that came was clear: “It is OK if the house is a mess and the children are still in their pajamas and some responsibilities are left undone. The only things that really need to be accomplished in the home are daily scripture study and prayer and weekly family home evening.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p18" pid="wUjrzvsQH0qz0XE3qBGOJQ" hash="ZCUIcQ">We were trying to do these things, but they were not always the priority and, amidst the chaos, were sometimes neglected. We changed our focus and tried not to worry about the less-important things. Our focus became to talk, rejoice, preach, and testify of Christ by striving to daily pray and study the scriptures and have weekly family home evening.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p19" pid="iFcbNXrxYUWceOLb5yzy9Q" hash="is3lkQ">A friend recently cautioned, “When you ask the sisters to read the scriptures and pray more, it stresses them out. They already feel like they have too much to do.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p20" pid="mA7E1AiS5UaWnaCj6cp4UQ" hash="d4NZWg">Brothers and sisters, because I know from my own experiences, and those of my husband, I must testify of the blessings of daily scripture study <span class="pageBreak" page-number="17"></span>and prayer and weekly family home evening. These are the very practices that help take away stress, give direction to our lives, and add protection to our homes. Then, if pornography or other challenges do strike our families, we can petition the Lord for help and expect great guidance from the Spirit, knowing that we have done what our Father has asked us to do.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p21" pid="XQ3OlwI9XkawwBBQ3pStRA" hash="HBMNJg">Brothers and sisters, if these have not been practices in our homes, we can all begin now. If our children are older and refuse to join us, we can start with ourselves. As we do, the influence of the Spirit will begin to fill our homes and our lives and, over time, children may respond.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p22" pid="RJ0i7d0iTUCesPhCxNPuXw" hash="kM3u8w">Remember that living Apostles have also promised that as we search out our ancestors and prepare our own family names for the temple, we will be protected now and throughout our lives as we keep ourselves worthy of a temple recommend.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> What promises!</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p23" pid="uDR8VhH4CEOqh7EB_DlvMw" hash="NYKhwQ">Youth, take responsibility for your own spiritual well-being. Turn off your phone if necessary, sing a Primary song, pray for help, think of a scripture, walk out of a movie, picture the Savior, take the sacrament worthily, study <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth,</span> be an example to your friends, confide in a parent, go see your bishop, ask for help, and seek professional counseling, if needed.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p24" pid="XfHXtLIPwUidfU5z4AB1Rg" hash="eTzKJg">What do I want my grandchildren to know? I want them and you to know that I know the Savior lives and loves us. He has paid the price for our sins, but we must kneel before our Father in Heaven, in deep humility, confessing our sins, and plead with Him for forgiveness. We must want to change our hearts and our desires and be humble enough to seek the help and forgiveness of those we may have hurt or forsaken.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p25" pid="2wQ0Rd0XD0uKAa5OUjan0w" hash="dlCLYA">I know that Joseph Smith saw God, our Heavenly Father, and our Savior, Jesus Christ. I testify that we have a living prophet upon the earth, President Thomas S. Monson. I also testify that we will never be led astray if we heed the counsel of the prophet of God. I testify of the power of our covenants and the blessings of the temple.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home.p26" pid="P_Ay-x_kAUapI7fyONakkQ" hash="jK39XQ">I know that the Book of Mormon is true! I cannot explain the power of this great book. I only know that, coupled with prayer, the Book of Mormon carries the power to protect families, strengthen relationships, and give personal confidence before the Lord. I testify of these things in the holy name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/04/protection-from-pornography-a-christ-focused-home</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2014-general-conference/2014-04-1050-linda-s-reeves-64k-eng.mp3" length="5916191" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2014 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Worthy of Our Promised Blessings</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Linda S. Reeves encourages sisters to remember the blessings that Heavenly Father has promised them for living the gospel.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13768_000_12reeves" doc-version="5" hash="RbYjHw">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="wGuiKMfeq0Oy8VrlfjmKxQ" hash="SKcZCQ">Worthy of Our Promised Blessings</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p2" pid="B_GpLLINoEm2jlf-eG6sYA" hash="WpePOw">By Linda S. Reeves</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p3" pid="05Tc9wAIVE2llGKUlHU32Q" hash="QIuFfA">Second Counselor in the Relief Society General Presidency</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=dtukPp4cg0C2gsFNMOVnNA"><img xmlns="" alt="Linda S. Reeves" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255571/090c567796da4986a11666a5635142d1/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255571/090c567796da4986a11666a5635142d1/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255571/090c567796da4986a11666a5635142d1/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x279="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255571/090c567796da4986a11666a5635142d1/200x279.jpg" data-src-320x447="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255571/090c567796da4986a11666a5635142d1/320x447.jpg" data-src-460x642="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255571/090c567796da4986a11666a5635142d1/460x642.jpg" data-src-640x894="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255571/090c567796da4986a11666a5635142d1/640x894.jpg" data-src-1024x1431="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255571/090c567796da4986a11666a5635142d1/1024x1431.jpg" data-src-2048x2862="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255571/090c567796da4986a11666a5635142d1/2048x2862.jpg" data-src-3513x4910="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255571/090c567796da4986a11666a5635142d1/3513x4910.jpg" pid="dtukPp4cg0C2gsFNMOVnNA" hash="91T7Uw"></img></a></div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="JIEJTiQ070u3g5U38Q7QzA" hash="FYTpEQ">A vision of our Father’s incredible promised blessings must be the central focus before our eyes every day.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="oa-_FSQGPkCh-djr_OKijQ" hash="RVnuiA">Linda S. Reeves</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p5" pid="7Xicv54ack6seW-AKVljpg" hash="r551TA">Don’t you love this sister in the video? We know that many of you who have not had the opportunity to bear children of your own have spent your lives loving, teaching, and blessing children. And, oh, how our Heavenly Father and we, your sisters, love you for it!</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=uA81C-uS60-yCBbm1ukOyg"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572881/8b7e6363ca154847a3f08c072a6a2e82/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572881/8b7e6363ca154847a3f08c072a6a2e82/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572881/8b7e6363ca154847a3f08c072a6a2e82/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572881/8b7e6363ca154847a3f08c072a6a2e82/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572881/8b7e6363ca154847a3f08c072a6a2e82/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572881/8b7e6363ca154847a3f08c072a6a2e82/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572881/8b7e6363ca154847a3f08c072a6a2e82/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572881/8b7e6363ca154847a3f08c072a6a2e82/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572881/8b7e6363ca154847a3f08c072a6a2e82/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572881/8b7e6363ca154847a3f08c072a6a2e82/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Young  woman  holding  newborn" pid="uA81C-uS60-yCBbm1ukOyg" hash="Ucow6g"></img></a>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p6" pid="x1mSQo3owkijlzAe2d2-Rg" hash="a96tow">Have we all, including you dear younger sisters in Primary and Young Women, had the opportunity to hold a newborn baby in our arms and have him or her look up into our eyes? Have we sensed the sacred and holy feeling surrounding this celestial spirit, so recently sent by our Father in Heaven to its newly created, pure little body? I have seldom experienced feelings quite so sweet, so tender, and so spiritual.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p7" pid="FkGQjJQEwEeYt_tPu9ddUw" hash="03UuCA">Our bodies are sacred gifts from our Heavenly Father. They are personal temples. As we keep them clean and pure, we can be worthy to help our Heavenly Father create bodies for His beloved spirit children.</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=JckfFcQWg02DytWu8CFl1w"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572931/a088b1f8185646239a56493d95d9c7c3/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572931/a088b1f8185646239a56493d95d9c7c3/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572931/a088b1f8185646239a56493d95d9c7c3/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572931/a088b1f8185646239a56493d95d9c7c3/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572931/a088b1f8185646239a56493d95d9c7c3/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572931/a088b1f8185646239a56493d95d9c7c3/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572931/a088b1f8185646239a56493d95d9c7c3/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572931/a088b1f8185646239a56493d95d9c7c3/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572931/a088b1f8185646239a56493d95d9c7c3/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572931/a088b1f8185646239a56493d95d9c7c3/2790x1800.jpg" altText="President  Packer  speaking" pid="JckfFcQWg02DytWu8CFl1w" hash="V04_qg"></img></a>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p8" pid="CE1T_-H-m0-5_ECC_h0v_g" hash="COP9pQ">In President Boyd K. Packer’s final general conference talk, which you may remember as “a cookie and a kiss,” he testified that “the commandment to multiply and replenish the earth … is essential … and is the source of human happiness. Through the righteous exercise of this [creative] power, we may come close to our Father in Heaven and experience a fulness of joy, even godhood. The power of procreation is not an incidental part of the plan; it is the plan.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p9" pid="I_Ntz4Z2zke-xA6J9b_2oA" hash="xQatOw">He continued:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p10" pid="4T--PS76UU6OwZhwBiVnJA" hash="MFBKMg">“True love requires reserving until after marriage the sharing of that affection which unlocks those sacred powers … [by] avoiding situations where physical desire might take control. …</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p11" pid="XJCo_VNizk-GgNHHIQqr9g" hash="6YcjAg">“… Our happiness in mortal life, our joy and exaltation are dependent upon how we respond to these persistent, compelling physical desires.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p12" pid="Mmxb3g_Nr0qkzHtOwWvFGw" hash="PTXZRg">My dear sisters, both young and not so young, I have felt a great anxiety as I have prepared this talk. As Alma the Younger expressed, “I wish from the inmost part of my heart … that ye would … call on his holy name, and watch and pray continually, that ye may not be tempted above that which ye can bear, … that ye may be lifted up at the last day.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p13" pid="-yAQjd5zlUucfz48hk8Amg" hash="CYO7Cg">Later, Mormon also testified that in Alma’s day, Korihor, the anti-Christ, “did preach … , leading away the hearts of … many women.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p14" pid="-VaQCn4hAki3GLNrI49fNw" hash="MhgqVg">Sisters, Satan has raised a Korihor-like banner in our day with increasing success. What are some of his tools? Seductive romance novels, TV soap operas, married women and old boyfriends connecting on social media, and pornography. We must be so careful, dear sisters! We cannot play with Satan’s fiery darts and not get burned. I know of nothing that will qualify us for the constant companionship of the Holy Ghost as much as virtue.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p15" pid="dYaeEOYMq0aIvAbfiWA5aQ" hash="eF8Wmw">Many in today’s world are looking for instant gratification and instant knowledge on the Internet. In contrast, we will be exceedingly blessed if we exercise faith and patience and go to our Heavenly Father, the source of all truth, with our concerns. So many answers and assurances can come through daily searching and studying the scriptures and with sincere and pleading prayer, but there are no such promises on the Internet. The prophet Jacob testifies: “For the Spirit speaketh the truth and lieth not. Wherefore, it speaketh of things as they really are, and of things as they really will be.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p16" pid="vnXkyhG01UauzyRQhmx6ww" hash="eX_L1A">When we are involved in watching, reading, or experiencing anything that is below our Heavenly Father’s standards, it weakens us. Regardless of our age, if what we look at, read, listen to, or choose to do does not meet the Lord’s standards in <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth,</span> turn it off, rip it up, throw it out, and slam the door.</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=PL0FtB1Aa0-XUZtDDf_sZg"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/821656/6b963b2dde634743a76b7a3483fb74d9/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/821656/6b963b2dde634743a76b7a3483fb74d9/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/821656/6b963b2dde634743a76b7a3483fb74d9/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/821656/6b963b2dde634743a76b7a3483fb74d9/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/821656/6b963b2dde634743a76b7a3483fb74d9/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/821656/6b963b2dde634743a76b7a3483fb74d9/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/821656/6b963b2dde634743a76b7a3483fb74d9/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/821656/6b963b2dde634743a76b7a3483fb74d9/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/821656/6b963b2dde634743a76b7a3483fb74d9/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/821656/6b963b2dde634743a76b7a3483fb74d9/2790x1800.jpg" altText="The  Savior  in  Gethsemane" pid="PL0FtB1Aa0-XUZtDDf_sZg" hash="NWWncg"></img></a>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p17" pid="Ih8wwVbPdkyyRtk17TNF0A" hash="VkpO0w">None of us is perfect, but when we have sinned, President Packer reminded us:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p18" pid="Y-kDKuoNd0qxYIZJXrnPPQ" hash="wzkgBg">“The promise is: ‘Behold, he who has repented of his sins, the same is forgiven, and I, the Lord, remember them no more’ (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:42</a>). …</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p19" pid="Dk6T5t0z4kKf8N0rLhWLXw" hash="F8kB3g">“… The Atonement, which can reclaim each one of us, bears no scars. That means that no matter what we have done or where we have been or how something happened, if we truly repent, He has promised that He would atone. And when He atoned, that settled that. There are so many of us who are thrashing around … with feelings of guilt, not knowing quite how to escape. You escape by accepting the Atonement of Christ, and all that was heartache can turn to beauty and love and eternity.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p20" pid="bKfX_Wk5ik64AI99HEAGdQ" hash="TAh7gg">Besides repentance, what helps or tools have we been given to help us stay clean and virtuous? Our Primary children and young women all know and sing the song “Scripture Power.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> Can we expand it to “Prayer Power,” “Temple Power,” “Covenants Power,” “Sabbath Day Power,” “Prophet Power,” and “Virtue Power”?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p21" pid="nOAEl-_YdE-a4tku9factg" hash="FXZKpg">There are also great blessings and protecting promises associated with the proper wearing of our temple garment. I have come to feel that I am symbolically putting on royal robes given me by my Heavenly Father. I testify, sisters, that when we strive to wear the garment properly, our Father recognizes it as a great sign of our love and devotion to Him. It is a sign of the covenants we have made with Him, and He has promised, “I, the Lord, am bound when ye do what I say; but when ye do not what I say, ye have no <span class="emphasis">promise.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p22" pid="yZzH46KQ_kCkZ88g6Q-YMA" hash="FVTYxQ">Recently I talked to an old friend who has gone through two divorces due to the addictions and unfaithfulness of her husbands. She and her three children have suffered greatly. She pleaded, “I have tried so hard to live righteously. Why have I had so many trials? What have I done wrong? What does Heavenly Father want me to do? I pray and read my scriptures, help my children, and go to the temple often.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p23" pid="HBqIHEiKj0KqCVbC7Z82rQ" hash="mF54mg">As I listened to this sister, I felt like shouting out, “You are doing it! You are doing all that Heavenly Father wants and hopes you will do!”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p24" pid="EV0pPmHXrk-WTZMulXxHBA" hash="lmyBgg">Understandably, many have expressed that our Father’s promised blessings are just “way too far away,” particularly when our lives are overflowing with challenges. But Amulek taught that “this life is the time … to prepare to meet God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> It is not the time to receive all of our blessings. President Packer explained, “‘And they all lived happily ever after’ is never written into the second act. That line belongs in the third act, when the mysteries are solved and everything is put right.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> However, a vision of our Father’s incredible promised blessings must be the central focus before our eyes every day—as well as an awareness “of the multitude of his tender mercies”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> that we experience on a daily basis.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p25" pid="4hAlZSs_10CiPHE9YAI80Q" hash="Spx1-w">Sisters, I do not know why we have the many trials that we have, but it is my personal feeling that the reward is so great, so eternal and everlasting, so joyful and beyond our understanding that in that day of reward, we may feel to say to our merciful, loving Father, “Was that <span class="emphasis">all</span> that was required?” I believe that if we could daily remember and recognize the depth of that love our Heavenly Father and our Savior have for us, we would be willing to do anything to be back in Their presence again, surrounded by Their love eternally. What will it matter, dear sisters, what we suffered here if, in the end, those trials are the very things which qualify us for eternal life and exaltation in the kingdom of God with our Father and Savior?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings.p26" pid="5CSCWvV6QUyKyRcXxzxx9Q" hash="j6rZZw">I testify that our bodies are sacred gifts from our Heavenly Father and that as we keep our lives pure and clean through the atoning sacrifice of our Savior and keep the vision of our Father’s promised rewards daily in front of us, we will one day receive “all that [our] Father hath.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> In the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/10/worthy-of-our-promised-blessings</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2015-general-conference/2015-09-0030-linda-s-reeves-64k-eng.mp3" length="5491521" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Great Plan of Redemption</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sister Reeves shares stories of individuals who feel the peace, joy, and blessings of sincerely repenting and parking of the Savior’s Atonement.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60001311_000_54reeves" doc-version="1" hash="kREjSQ">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="LGqHQ9zMh0S8h16UudWU3g" hash="FWfu2w">The Great Plan of Redemption</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p2" pid="QSrruYTYM0CvMi-hhJkL6g" hash="WpePOw1">By Linda S. Reeves</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p3" pid="5ziOrkakS0677J9oLiTMtg" hash="QIuFfA">Second Counselor in the Relief Society General Presidency</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="hfOyZyPheUm-mDnWRcx9Vg" hash="19ZAWw">I know that when we sincerely repent of our sins, they are truly gone—without a trace!</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="LdT_DQZa3ku-VeLY1g5JzQ" hash="WpePOw">By Linda S. Reeves</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p5" pid="duMi_bUn_UCUkmt1lIcpcw" hash="DCpLzg">A few months before President Boyd K. Packer passed away, general priesthood and auxiliary leaders had the precious opportunity of having him speak to us. I have not been able to quit thinking about what he said. He shared that he had searched backward throughout his lifetime, looking for evidence of the sins that he had committed and sincerely repented of, and he could find <span class="emphasis">no trace</span> of them. Because of the atoning sacrifice of our beloved Savior, Jesus Christ, and through sincere repentance, his sins were completely gone, as if they had never happened. President Packer then charged us as leaders that day to testify that this is true for each one of us who sincerely repents.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p6" pid="vEihShyXdUi0ThpxEYm8TA" hash="C6uVxA">I’m aware of a man who was involved in moral transgressions several years ago. For some time, this man felt too ashamed and too worried to approach his wife and his priesthood leaders. He wanted to fully repent but actually expressed that he was willing to give up his own eternal salvation rather than put his spouse and children through the sorrow, shame, or other consequences that might be caused by his confession.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p7" pid="xbn_KK4jmkGN0g3YxrfAXA" hash="Dm9yIg">When we have sinned, Satan often tries to convince us that the unselfish thing to do is to protect others from the devastation of the knowledge of our sins, including avoiding confessing to our bishop, who can bless our lives through his priesthood keys as a common judge in Israel. The truth, however, is that the unselfish and Christlike thing to do is to confess and repent. This is Heavenly Father’s great plan of redemption.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p8" pid="BqDv5fBp1UyUSHP_AICu6Q" hash="-Z9qjA">Finally, this dear man confessed to his faithful wife and his Church leaders, expressing deep remorse. Though it was the most difficult thing he had ever done, feelings of relief, peace, gratitude, love for our Savior, and a knowledge that the Lord was lifting his heavy burden and carrying him caused joy beyond expression, regardless of the outcome and his future.</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=IPlGv1LUGEyCfVOlwmC7oA"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813930/07ced5b72f8b42d2ad3a30d5458c2150/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813930/07ced5b72f8b42d2ad3a30d5458c2150/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813930/07ced5b72f8b42d2ad3a30d5458c2150/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813930/07ced5b72f8b42d2ad3a30d5458c2150/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813930/07ced5b72f8b42d2ad3a30d5458c2150/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813930/07ced5b72f8b42d2ad3a30d5458c2150/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813930/07ced5b72f8b42d2ad3a30d5458c2150/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813930/07ced5b72f8b42d2ad3a30d5458c2150/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813930/07ced5b72f8b42d2ad3a30d5458c2150/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813930/07ced5b72f8b42d2ad3a30d5458c2150/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Savior comforting" pid="IPlGv1LUGEyCfVOlwmC7oA" hash="mOMXCg"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p9" pid="DES9D0lCHka5aisD5Rw8UQ" hash="ZhZN4g">He had been certain that his wife and children would be devastated—and they were; and that there would be disciplinary action and a release from his calling—and there was. He was certain that his wife would be brokenhearted, hurt, and angry—and she was. And he was convinced that she would leave, taking the children with her—but she didn’t.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p10" pid="JfuuxVMIwECuKzRunDbIWw" hash="o6YnHw">Sometimes serious transgression leads to divorce, and depending on circumstances, that might be necessary. But to this man’s amazement, his wife embraced him and dedicated herself to helping him in any way that she could. Over time, she was able to fully forgive him. She had felt the healing power of the Savior’s Atonement for her. Years later, this couple and their three children are strong and faithful. The husband and wife serve in the temple and have a wonderful, loving marriage. The depth of this man’s testimony and his love and gratitude for the Savior are so evident in his life.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p11" pid="mXJgDW2XBU6EbGUpBhYL4w" hash="IvaZYQ">Amulek testified, “I would that ye would come forth and harden not your hearts any longer; … if ye will repent … , immediately shall the great plan of redemption be brought about unto you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p12" pid="QMWVucxpUkOOzU4dfPSUiA" hash="msj-ow">When I served with my husband as he presided over a mission, we went to the airport to pick up a large group of missionaries one morning. One particular young man caught our eye. He seemed sad, weighed down, almost distraught. We watched him carefully that afternoon. By evening, this young man made a belated confession, and his leaders determined that he needed to return home. Although we were very sad that he had been dishonest and had not repented before coming on his mission, on the way to the airport we sincerely and lovingly praised him for having the courage to come forward, and we pledged to stay in close contact with him.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p13" pid="BoiQZaGRrkqu5pYJf_MUJQ" hash="aeigog">This great young man was blessed to have wonderful parents, great priesthood leaders, and a supportive, loving ward. After a year of working hard to fully repent and partake of the Savior’s Atonement, he was able to return to our mission. It is difficult for me to describe the feelings of joy we felt as we picked up this young man from the airport. He was full of the Spirit, happy, confident before the Lord, and anxious to fulfill a faithful mission. He became an outstanding missionary, and later my husband and I had the privilege of attending his temple sealing.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p14" pid="Qf7Wlwecu0CsgBWEeP0Tvg" hash="WPHrXw">By contrast, I’m aware of another missionary who, knowing her unconfessed sin from before her mission would surely cause her to be sent home early, made her own plan to work extra hard during her mission and confess to the mission president just days before completing her mission. She lacked godly sorrow and tried to circumvent the plan that our loving Savior has offered each one of us.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p15" pid="wz_I5rGkLUm-vphm9BiKDg" hash="IHEPcg">During our mission, I once accompanied my husband when he went to interview a man for baptism. While my husband conducted the interview, I waited outside with the sister missionaries who had taught this man. When the interview was finished, my husband informed the missionaries that the man would be able to be baptized. This dear man wept and wept as he explained that he had been certain that the serious sins he had committed in his life would prevent him from being able to be baptized. I have seldom witnessed the joy and happiness of someone coming out of the darkness and into the light equal to what I witnessed that day.</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=5KLJH_FsMUebw6JXgpiXbw"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813929/d704ee3d655e4172b0d6f5d7bbd5273d/200x183.png" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x45="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813929/d704ee3d655e4172b0d6f5d7bbd5273d/50x45.png" data-src-100x91="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813929/d704ee3d655e4172b0d6f5d7bbd5273d/100x91.png" data-src-200x183="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813929/d704ee3d655e4172b0d6f5d7bbd5273d/200x183.png" data-src-320x294="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813929/d704ee3d655e4172b0d6f5d7bbd5273d/320x294.png" data-src-460x423="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813929/d704ee3d655e4172b0d6f5d7bbd5273d/460x423.png" data-src-640x588="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813929/d704ee3d655e4172b0d6f5d7bbd5273d/640x588.png" data-src-1024x941="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813929/d704ee3d655e4172b0d6f5d7bbd5273d/1024x941.png" data-src-1957x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813929/d704ee3d655e4172b0d6f5d7bbd5273d/1957x1800.png" altText="The Savior provides hope" pid="5KLJH_FsMUebw6JXgpiXbw" hash="Eg9tuQ"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p16" pid="acKFJ6gx10OeE0vezJ7c9g" hash="7dWAYQ">Elder D. Todd Christofferson testified:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p17" pid="CJb3mZ_qnUmra5AeYFkWNg" hash="GzaHfA">“With faith in [our] merciful Redeemer and His power, potential despair turns to hope. One’s very heart and desires change, and the once-appealing sin becomes increasingly abhorrent. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p18" pid="7pxr4Bnnb0uCcn6q6lOPqQ" hash="M1LYRg">“… Whatever the cost of repentance, it is swallowed up in the joy of forgiveness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p19" pid="Bk_9-WydrEKTLBchWX2s6w" hash="TWx2Gg">These experiences remind me of Enos in the Book of Mormon, who “cried unto [the Lord] in mighty prayer” and then heard a voice saying, “Enos, thy sins are forgiven thee. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p20" pid="jGiletaQ0Ui5axcMPgD2sw" hash="uEGJ-g">“And I, Enos, knew that God could not lie; wherefore, my guilt was swept away.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p21" pid="nKybiBdSQEmKWsG-T932dQ" hash="9CDJyQ">“And I said: Lord, how is it done?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p22" pid="s5C_RAhCDU-k63VwAIQKWA" hash="yB68Aw">“And he said unto me: Because of thy faith in Christ. … Go to, thy faith hath made thee whole.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p23" pid="PHJ3kCwcmUW6fF4RsXcTVg" hash="23zVSA">In preparing this talk, I wanted to get a feeling for how our grandchildren understand repentance and how they feel about the Savior, so I asked our children to ask them the following questions. I was touched by our grandchildren’s responses.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p24" pid="dtIYGuYJDEWmf6dmQG8a6A" hash="a6HQ8Q">What is repentance? “When you hit someone, you can say ‘sorry’ and help them up.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p25" pid="gKb8yyQgPUeTrKvnVqAEvw" hash="vTJm8w">How do you feel when you repent? “You can feel Him; you can feel His warmness, and the bad feeling goes away.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p26" pid="x-G3O2IlGU-HT1caoQciTA" hash="cWhs0Q">How do you feel about Jesus and Heavenly Father when you repent? “I feel that Jesus feels it was worth it to do the Atonement, and He’s happy that we can live with Him again.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p27" pid="rBkssJtX10CBvp5BnnOkHw" hash="1-U6Lg">Why do Jesus and Heavenly Father want me to repent? In the words of my teenage grandchild: “Because They love me! In order to progress and become like Them, I need to repent. I also want the Spirit to be with me, so I need to repent daily to have His wonderful companionship. I will never be able to thank Them enough.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p28" pid="eqUIRE8VykSTIx5QSVzz9Q" hash="dXfLuw">When four-year-old Brynlee heard these questions, she said, “I don’t know, Daddy. You teach me.”</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=Pa9KBqyHF02DgIuoN4UFJg"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813934/43fe834b7f39487b991dcdb43579299c/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813934/43fe834b7f39487b991dcdb43579299c/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813934/43fe834b7f39487b991dcdb43579299c/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813934/43fe834b7f39487b991dcdb43579299c/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813934/43fe834b7f39487b991dcdb43579299c/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813934/43fe834b7f39487b991dcdb43579299c/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813934/43fe834b7f39487b991dcdb43579299c/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813934/43fe834b7f39487b991dcdb43579299c/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813934/43fe834b7f39487b991dcdb43579299c/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813934/43fe834b7f39487b991dcdb43579299c/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Brynlee and her dad" pid="Pa9KBqyHF02DgIuoN4UFJg" hash="lLxmiw"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p29" pid="KnWvNzHFukieB-Jpd-h5Hw" hash="nI2TuQ">In a past general conference, Elder Jeffrey R. Holland declared: “However late you think you are, however many chances you think you have missed, however many mistakes you feel you have made … , or however far from home and family and God you feel you have traveled, I testify that you have <span class="emphasis">not</span> traveled beyond the reach of divine love. It is not possible for you to sink lower than the infinite light of Christ’s Atonement shines.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p30" pid="uJz-ZnilTkavDKtyXdOwXQ" hash="Aehgkw">Oh, how I want each of my children, grandchildren, and each of you, my brothers and sisters, to feel the joy and closeness to Heavenly Father and to our Savior as we daily repent of our sins and weaknesses. Each accountable child of Heavenly Father needs repentance. Consider what sins we need to repent of. What is holding us back? In what ways do we need to improve?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p31" pid="6E_dOOaya0OGdNi9bLdzKw" hash="yX2_BA">I know, as President Packer experienced and testified, that when we sincerely repent of our sins, they are truly gone—without a trace! I have personally felt the love, the joy, the relief, and the confidence before the Lord as I have sincerely repented.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption.p32" pid="dZpKclJNtkaHceZirP5DSQ" hash="YNidpw">To me, the greatest miracles in life are not the parting of the Red Sea, the moving of mountains, or even the healing of the body. The greatest miracle happens when we humbly approach our Father in Heaven in prayer, fervently plead to be forgiven, and then are cleansed of those sins through the atoning sacrifice of our Savior. In the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/10/the-great-plan-of-redemption</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2016-general-conference/2016-10-4040-linda-s-reeves-64k-eng.mp3" length="5384952" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
