<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Linda K. Burton</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Linda K. Burton.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Linda%20K.%20Burton.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Linda K. Burton.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>First Observe, Then Serve</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve?lang=eng</link>
      <description>With practice, each of us can become more like the Savior as we serve God’s children.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10491_000_43burton" doc-version="2" hash="ThgNNQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="NuohwlvmjEqmrgLE3YEdTg" hash="V3eoMA">First Observe, Then Serve</h1><p class="authorName" pid="mLseeQc8MUKTchI7j_kktw" hash="EolBAA">By Linda K. Burton</p><p class="kicker" pid="b9qbu6lHqESXa0R_81COaA" hash="Z8Z47A">With practice, each of us can become more like the Savior as we serve God’s children.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" pid="55Fh2vFrk0iXJMMkWGPZSg" hash="ok0tAA">
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p5" pid="nvBeIx0vOEaILA_tKKd3Tw" hash="U-FZ3w">
      <span class="pageBreak" page-number="78"></span>One of the greatest evidences we have that our beloved prophet, President Thomas S. Monson, is the Lord’s chosen servant is that he has learned to follow the Savior’s example—serving individually, one by one. Those of us who have entered the waters of baptism have covenanted to do the same. We have covenanted to “always remember [the Savior] and keep his commandments,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> and He has said, “This is my commandment, That ye love one another, as I have loved you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p6" pid="0KKl8OMbl0SMPyR2kxUGlw" hash="Z6kP-A">Notice how the following words from President Monson include the same invitation: “We are surrounded by those in need of our attention, our encouragement, our support, our comfort, our kindness. … We are the Lord’s hands here upon the earth, with the mandate to serve and to lift His children. He is dependent upon each of us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p7" pid="64F_QCIeTUC46QXxKASOsA" hash="IzjcRw">Did you hear it—the invitation to love one another? For some, serving or ministering one by one, following the Savior’s example, doesn’t come easily. But with practice, each of us can become more like the Savior as we serve God’s children. To help us better love one another, I would like to suggest four words to remember: “First observe, then serve.”</p>
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p8" pid="JqU6ZWPtC06AUkKrFHAXCg" hash="Ik6O9g">Almost 40 years ago my husband and I went to the temple for our Friday night date. We had been married only a short time, and I was nervous because this was only my second time as a newlywed. A sister sitting next to me must have noticed. She leaned over and whispered reverently, “Don’t worry. I’ll help you.” My fears were calmed, and I was able to enjoy the rest of the temple session. She first observed, then served.</p>
    </span>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p9" pid="1UR5oyE61UGN0JcsbWkyrQ" hash="7B2GGg">We are all invited to follow Jesus’s teachings and to minister to others. This invitation is not limited to angelic sisters. As I share a few everyday examples of members who have learned to first observe and then serve, listen for the teachings of Jesus they illustrate.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p10" pid="scR-dV6gw0q-ps2oml3XMg" hash="2z93fA">A six-year-old Primary child said: “When I was chosen to be a class helper, I could choose a friend to work with me. I picked [a boy in my class who bullied me] because he never gets chosen by others. I wanted to make him feel good.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p11" pid="PIbgGqKlWkynZchemrAukA" hash="YBtg2w">
      <span class="pageBreak" page-number="79"></span>What did this child observe? He noticed that the class bully never got chosen. What did he do to serve? He simply chose him to be his friend as a class helper. Jesus taught, “Love your enemies, bless them that curse you, do good to them that hate you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p12" pid="le4Bo0LpOkSUH6CMkSlklg" hash="meOTEw">In one ward, Aaronic Priesthood holders first observed and now serve in a meaningful way. Every week the young men arrive early and stand outside the meetinghouse in rain, snow, or blistering heat, awaiting the arrival of the many elderly members in their ward. They lift wheelchairs and walkers out of cars, provide sturdy arms to grasp, and patiently escort the silver-haired seniors into the building. They are truly doing their duty to God. As they observe and then serve, they are living examples of the Savior’s teaching: “Inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> As the new youth curriculum is implemented, the eyes of these young men will undoubtedly be opened to even more opportunities to serve in a Christlike way.</p>
    </span>
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p13" pid="fZAtFh1Bc0KF-IFHL4-EPQ" hash="DapJCA">Observing and serving sometimes requires great effort. An inspired young woman named Alexandria noticed that her cousin Madison was unable to complete her own Personal Progress requirements because she suffered from severe autism. Alexandria rallied the young women in her ward, counseled with her leaders, and determined to do something for Maddy that she could not do herself. Each of the young women completed a portion of the Personal Progress activities and projects vicariously to enable Maddy to receive her own medallion.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
    </span>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p14" pid="LBfwZ8cXJ0ypkbE6hyOp3w" hash="8kUKFg">These young women will progress well into roles of motherhood and Relief Society sisterhood because they are learning to first observe, then serve in charitable ways.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p15" pid="TbSP33hL0E21P-XQ3HhMTA" hash="i-O20Q">President Monson has reminded us that charity, “the pure love of Christ”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span>—or in other words, observing and serving—“is evident when an elderly widow is remembered and taken to ward functions” and “when the sister sitting alone in Relief Society receives the invitation, ‘Come—sit by us.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> The golden rule is applicable here: “Whatsoever ye would that men [or women] should do to you, do ye even so to them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p16" pid="rcMkoTszf0m1QYuDd_bM2w" hash="CqAw4A">An observant husband served in two important ways. He relates:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p17" pid="LqqxoZWUmUCPYWH_sgARmQ" hash="gkRE2g">“I was assisting my wife one Sunday with her Primary class full of energetic seven-year-olds. As Primary sharing time started, I noticed one of the class members huddled on her chair and obviously not feeling well. The Spirit whispered to me that she needed comfort, so I sat by her and quietly asked what was wrong. She didn’t answer … , so I began to sing softly to her.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p18" pid="tH0cRwE7IUm2pacos0QV_Q" hash="VWz0bQ">“The Primary was learning a new song, and when we sang, ‘If I listen with my heart I hear the Savior’s voice,’ I began to feel the most incredible light and warmth fill my soul. … I received a personal testimony of our Savior’s love for her … and for me. … I learned that we are [the Savior’s] hands when we serve the one.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p19" pid="i9EShMfVQE28gRYCwuj3nQ" hash="B3vh1Q">Not only did this Christlike brother notice the need to help his wife with a class full of energetic seven-year-olds; <span class="pageBreak" page-number="80"></span>he also gave individual service to a child in need. He followed the Savior, who taught, “The works which ye have seen me do that shall ye also do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
    </span>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p20" pid="lalmaIosmEqi9VgFXMHINw" hash="_AP3KQ">Recently a flood opened many opportunities for disciples of Jesus Christ to first observe and then serve. Men, women, teenagers, and children saw businesses and homes destroyed and dropped everything to help clean and repair damaged structures. Some observed the need to help with the overwhelming task of doing laundry. Others painstakingly wiped down photographs, legal documents, letters, and other important papers and then carefully hung them out to dry to preserve whatever they could. Observing and then serving is not always convenient and doesn’t always fit our own timetable.</p>
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p21" pid="ZNnMU74VcUujVnWPwS85Kw" hash="XdWgvw">What better place to first observe and then serve than in the home? An example from the life of Elder Richard G. Scott illustrates:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p22" pid="v-pNQEHeg021g594sezxyQ" hash="g_9HGg">“One night our little son Richard, who had a heart problem, awoke crying. … Normally my wife always got up to take care of a crying baby, but this time I said, ‘I’ll take care of him.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p23" pid="UET_7gS8Gk6f8ojvpq_ZEg" hash="60nj3g">“Because of his problem, when he began to cry, his little heart would pound very rapidly. He would throw up and soil the bed clothing. That night I held him very close to try to calm his racing heart and stop his crying as I changed his clothes and put on new bedsheets. I held him until he went to sleep. I didn’t know then that just a few months later he would pass away. I will always remember holding him in my arms in the middle of that night.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
    </span>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p24" pid="RmTwbTc9iEipcmIP6ZECRA" hash="afgcYA">Jesus said, “Whosoever will be great among you, let him be your minister.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p25" pid="q_Q_k32NBEiTzA-rWtYnIQ" hash="N4L5eA">Sometimes we are tempted to serve in a way that we want to serve and not necessarily in the way that is needed at the moment. When Elder Robert D. Hales taught the principle of provident living, he shared the example of buying a gift for his wife. She asked, “Are you buying this for me or for you?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> If we adapt that question to ourselves as we serve and ask, “Am I doing this for the Savior, or am I doing this for me?” our service will more likely resemble the ministry of the Savior. The Savior asked, and so should we, “What will ye that I shall do unto you?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p26" pid="8Et6hdd4yUuKaUSpXbt5QQ" hash="HSh4lw">A few weeks ago, I was hurried and frazzled, with too many to-dos on my list. I had hoped to go to the temple that day but felt I was just too busy. As soon as that thought of being too busy for temple service crossed my mind, it awakened me to what I most needed to do. I left my office to walk over to the Salt Lake Temple, wondering when I was going to recapture the time I was losing. Thankfully, the Lord is patient and merciful and taught me a beautiful lesson that day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p27" pid="3YtlnrZTVka9vGJ3QI7GmA" hash="f2JNpA">As I sat down in the session room, a young sister leaned over and reverently whispered, “I’m really nervous. This is only my second time in the temple. Could you please help me?” How could she ever have known that those words were exactly what I needed to hear? She didn’t know, but Heavenly Father knew. He had observed my greatest need. I needed to serve. He prompted this humble young sister to serve me by inviting me to serve her. I assure you that I was the one who benefited most.</p>
    </span>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p28" pid="05XwLznpcE6fRan4L8_AgA" hash="Cy5Ifg">I acknowledge with deep gratitude the many Christlike people who have served our family throughout the years. I express heartfelt appreciation to my beloved husband and family, who serve selflessly and with great love.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve.p29" pid="Q09cjGRkLUqQORXS98bvXA" hash="DY1E0A">May we all seek to first observe, then serve. As we do so, we are keeping covenants, and our service, like President Monson’s, will be evidence of our discipleship. I know the Savior lives. His Atonement enables us to live His teachings. I know President Monson is our prophet today. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2012/10/first-observe-then-serve</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2012-general-conference/2012-10-4030-linda-k-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="4806304" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power, Joy, and Love of Covenant Keeping</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I invite each of us to evaluate how much we love the Savior, using as a measure how joyfully we keep our covenants.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10791_000_61burton" doc-version="5" hash="yqEwkg">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="_lgBTHk-LEafgcw7V9P8Xw" hash="atHdCw">The Power, Joy, and Love of Covenant Keeping</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="KdT3lvj3Q0Kiax979BkBzw" hash="EolBAA">By Linda K. Burton</p>
		<p class="kicker" pid="haFdHQerJEGUnFvGrGVBJA" hash="t0T1Zw">I invite each of us to evaluate how much we love the Savior, using as a measure how joyfully we keep our covenants.</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="MfF-7a7xaE24T6KdKBWKZA" hash="HpKoxw">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p5" pid="9uQBIl9dlE--_g4ZtpJR2g" hash="qnEiXg"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="111"></span>I’d like to begin by sharing a story that touches my heart.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p6" pid="mqGKvP3d_ku2ULZPxdkYfg" hash="dKUtbA">One evening a man called his five sheep to come into the shelter for the night. His family watched with great interest as he simply called, “Come on,” and immediately all five heads lifted and turned in his direction. Four sheep broke into a run toward him. With loving-kindness he gently patted each of the four on the head. The sheep knew his voice and loved him.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p7" pid="whV_C8WoYEiskWmv3z8Iiw" hash="dfIjsA">But the fifth sheep didn’t come running. She was a large ewe that a few weeks earlier had been given away by her owner, who reported that she was wild, wayward, and always leading the other sheep astray. The new owner accepted the sheep and staked her in his own field for a few days so she would learn to stay put. He patiently taught her to love him and the other sheep until eventually she had only a short rope around her neck but was no longer staked down.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p8" pid="09nvxr23Kki3DylgbMZ8Lw" hash="lp3gRw">That evening as his family watched, the man approached the ewe, which stood at the edge of the field, and again he gently said, “Come on. You aren’t tied down anymore. You are free.” Then lovingly he reached out, placed his hand on her head, and walked back with her and the other sheep toward the shelter.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p9" pid="_tS4Fdeh2EeUQhitwkeINw" hash="iqWHMA">In the spirit of that story, I pray that the Holy Ghost will help us learn together tonight about covenant keeping. Making and keeping covenants means choosing to bind ourselves to our Father in Heaven and Jesus Christ. It is committing to follow the Savior. It is trusting Him and desiring to show our gratitude for the price He paid to set us free through the infinite gift of the Atonement.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p10" pid="D3aWQ6qqA0-IrmLnMechVw" hash="T6jqvQ">Elder Jeffrey R. Holland explained that “a covenant is a binding spiritual contract, a solemn promise to God our Father that we will live and think and act in a certain way—the way of His Son, the Lord Jesus Christ. In return, the Father, Son, and Holy Ghost promise us the full splendor of eternal life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> In that binding contract, the Lord sets the terms and we agree to keep them. Making and keeping our covenants is an expression of our commitment to become like the Savior.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> The ideal is to strive for the attitude best expressed in a few phrases of a favorite hymn: “I’ll go where <span class="emphasis">you</span> want me to go. … I’ll say what <span class="emphasis">you</span> want me to say. … I’ll be what <span class="emphasis">you</span> want me to be.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.t1">
			<h2 class="title" pid="F-EOVTJoW0iEgdF4-wC0oQ" hash="HnPD_g">Why Make and Keep Covenants?</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p12" pid="8L8aZYW1zky-ksBOIyQmeA" hash="mtCJlg">
				<span class="strong">1. Covenant keeping strengthens, empowers, and protects.</span>
			</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p13" pid="AHTTeL36KU2ozSpB_cpAHg" hash="gkygGg">Nephi saw in vision the significant blessings the Lord bestows upon covenant keepers: “And it came to pass that I, Nephi, beheld the power of the Lamb of God, that it descended … upon the covenant people of the Lord, … and they were armed with righteousness and with the power of God in great glory.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p14" pid="k6hcCPWZaEq8WP7sllIgLA" hash="ZTtQXA">I recently met a dear new friend. She testified that after she had received her temple endowment, she felt strengthened with the power to resist temptations she had previously struggled with.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p15" pid="VwJUhNQoXEmPLP3D4Kbn1g" hash="Fhx34g">As we keep our covenants, we also receive courage and strength to help us bear one another’s burdens. A heartbroken sister had a son who was experiencing a difficult mortal challenge. Because of her faith in her Relief Society sisters as covenant keepers, she courageously invited them to fast and pray for her son. Another sister expressed how she wished she had asked for similar prayers from her sisters. Years before, her own son was struggling. She wished she had invited them to help her family bear this burden. The Savior said, “By this shall all men know that ye are my disciples, if <span class="pageBreak" page-number="112"></span>ye have love one to another.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p16" pid="xedm2oorD0-Z4XgO03wvNw" hash="GjCXwQ">Oh, sisters, we all have burdens to bear and burdens to share. An invitation to bear one another’s burdens is an invitation to keep our covenants. Lucy Mack Smith’s counsel to the first Relief Society sisters is more relevant today than ever before: “We must cherish one another, watch over one another, comfort one another and gain instruction, that we may all sit down in heaven together.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> This is covenant keeping and visiting teaching at its finest!</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p17" pid="xArkBJiCU0mbIryWXFALow" hash="Eeo65A">The Book of Mormon reminds us that even the prophet Alma had to bear the burden of having a rebellious son. But Alma was blessed with covenant-keeping brothers and sisters in the gospel who were deeply converted unto the Lord and had learned what it meant to bear each other’s burdens. We are familiar with the verse in Mosiah that speaks of the great faith of Alma’s prayers in behalf of his son. But the record states that “the Lord … heard the prayers <span class="emphasis">of his people,</span> and also the prayers of his servant, Alma.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p18" pid="cdmvVSIUK0-_AquUCtgFng" hash="uStx4A">We know that the Lord always rejoices “in the soul that repenteth,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> but we desire above all to have our children follow the counsel of President Henry B. Eyring to “start early and be steady” in making and keeping covenants.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Not long ago a thought-provoking and sincere question was raised in a council of priesthood and auxiliary leaders: do we really expect eight-year-olds to keep their covenants? As we counseled together, it was suggested that one way to prepare children to make and keep sacred baptismal covenants is to help them learn to make and keep a simple promise.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p19" pid="nO_ninJsq0uBXl73Kz-D3Q" hash="FxhNpg">Faithful parents are entitled to know how to best teach to meet the needs of their children. As parents seek and act on personal revelation, counsel together, minister and teach the simple principles of the gospel, they will have power to strengthen and protect their families. Other family members can also help. My cute grandpa taught us the importance of keeping promises through a simple song. It went something like this: “Before you make a promise, consider well its importance. Then when made, engrave it upon your heart. Engrave it upon your heart.” That little song was taught with love, conviction, and power because Grandpa engraved his own promises on his heart.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p20" pid="blTg-9Xvkkq5Mj_lmZgz8A" hash="v8GlAA">A wise mother I know intentionally includes her children in her efforts to keep her covenants. She joyfully bears the burdens of neighbors, friends, and ward members—and comforts those who stand in need of comfort. It was not surprising when her young daughter recently came asking for help to know how to best comfort her friend whose father had just passed away. That was a perfect setting to teach that her desire to comfort her friend was one way to keep her baptismal covenant. How can we expect children to make and keep temple covenants if we don’t expect them to keep their first covenant—their baptismal covenant?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p21" pid="YcC6JlNsAEa4Gp-ZgohxBA" hash="US13jg">Elder Richard G. Scott observed, “One of the greatest blessings we can offer to the world is the power of a Christ-centered home where the <span class="pageBreak" page-number="113"></span>gospel is taught, covenants are kept, and love abounds.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> What are some ways we can create such a home to prepare our children to make and keep temple covenants?</p>
			<div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.f1">
				<ul class="bullet" guid="">
					<li pid="QWAf6tc090aIbY5TFDI-6w" hash="VRO_8g">
						<span class="label">•</span>
						<p pid="6aGw9YzBpk6B8cSYRnH36A" hash="R3LFIQ">We can discover together what it means to be worthy of a temple recommend.</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="1RZy_ViCb0yHkgJ4Vz3t9g" hash="K187cQ">
						<span class="label">•</span>
						<p pid="Qgs8shlw2kuyRSSrdIpNFw" hash="KBqzjQ">We can discover together how to listen to the Holy Ghost. Because the temple endowment is received by revelation, we need to learn that vital skill.</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="3h1ZBojoUk6vVouXgqQlVw" hash="xaBI6Q">
						<span class="label">•</span>
						<p pid="KTV4GTpbX0GLUnGxN6mbUA" hash="PG_04w">We can discover together how to learn through the use of symbols, beginning with the sacred symbols of baptism and the sacrament.</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="hhz5kYxsc0aOKWT0tdnwxA" hash="3tuAJw">
						<span class="label">•</span>
						<p pid="Psysq6fqu0qRNzcnHFWWow" hash="LtDWGQ">We can discover together why the body is sacred, why it is sometimes referred to as a temple, and how modest dress and grooming relates to the sacred nature of temple clothing.</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="qUSQfUb9iEiVKeUWJVod9A" hash="jhxgWQ">
						<span class="label">•</span>
						<p pid="1a5gMGUNg0OLqJUOQzmUxQ" hash="1Io6nw">We can discover the plan of happiness in the scriptures. The more familiar we are with Heavenly Father’s plan and the Atonement in the scriptures, the more meaningful temple worship will be.</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="5hMS_xPmVU2wJ_Wf70DrZg" hash="dAfOIA">
						<span class="label">•</span>
						<p pid="55fagHdkf0m0u5uX6vBd5w" hash="k99Fbw">We can learn the stories of our ancestors together, research family history, index, and perform vicarious temple work for deceased loved ones.</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="Eep2K3n7UEeeXwABA_O3yw" hash="_4ooKQ">
						<span class="label">•</span>
						<p pid="UQrS2UUklEOqi3Qy-uA5YA" hash="6QQVxQ">We can discover together the meaning of terms such as <span class="emphasis">endowment, ordinance, sealing, priesthood, keys,</span> and other words related to temple worship.</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="YoMqJ2jDQE-iAtid5lpzqA" hash="lon6Vg">
						<span class="label">•</span>
						<p pid="-aJauqbc20Gev0U4_0MnuQ" hash="MqAH_Q">We can teach that we go to the temple to make covenants with Heavenly Father—we return home to keep them!<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
					</li>
				</ul>
			</div>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p30" pid="gU9z7eBjZ0OiuX7d-c_CfQ" hash="zSWvrA">Let us remember the concept of “good, better, and best” as we teach.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> It is good to teach our children about the temple. It is better to prepare and expect them to make and keep covenants. It is best to show them by example that we cheerfully cleave to our own baptismal and temple covenants! Sisters, do we realize our vital role in the work of salvation as we nurture, teach, and prepare children to progress along the covenant path? The power to do so will come as we honor and keep our covenants.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p31" pid="JWx-otSHxUeIqsnVaDEodw" hash="Z8TbFQ">
				<span class="strong">2. Keeping covenants is essential for true happiness.</span>
			</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p32" pid="r2JVuPsM80CjvG-Z5foNGw" hash="pQoUng">President Thomas S. Monson taught, “Sacred covenants are to be revered by us, and faithfulness to them is a requirement for happiness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> In 2 Nephi we read, “And it came to pass that we lived after the manner of happiness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> Earlier in this same chapter we learn that Nephi and his people had just built a temple. Surely they were joyful covenant keepers! And in Alma we read, “But behold there never was a happier time among the people of Nephi, since the days of Nephi, than in the days of Moroni.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> Why? Again we learn in a previous verse that they “were faithful in keeping the commandments of the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> Covenant keepers are commandment keepers!</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p33" pid="wF7sbtqVF0Shd8HVQqI6Qw" hash="Z_N5EA">I love the scripture that reads: “And now when the people had heard these words [meaning the words describing the baptismal covenant], they clapped their hands for joy, and exclaimed: This is the desire of our hearts.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> I love the desire of their hearts. They cheerfully desired to make and keep their covenants!</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p34" pid="wBj1K2cOL0GqGH6pk30THA" hash="Vw_U2Q">One Sunday a young sister joyfully exclaimed, “I get to take the sacrament today!” When was the last time we rejoiced in that privilege? And how do we demonstrate it? We do this by <span class="emphasis">always</span> remembering the Savior and <span class="emphasis">always</span> keeping His commandments, which include keeping His Sabbath day holy. We do it by <span class="emphasis">always</span> remembering Him as we <span class="emphasis">always</span> have our personal and family prayers, daily scripture study, and weekly family home evenings. And when we get distracted or casual with these important things, we repent and begin again.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p35" pid="Cer-pmyv6kuyf_tViIT7uA" hash="e38oJw">Making and cheerfully keeping our covenants gives validity and life to the vital sacred and saving ordinances we need to receive in order to obtain “all that [the] Father hath.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> Ordinances and covenants are the “spiritual milestones” President Henry B. Eyring referred to when he taught: “The Latter-day Saints are a covenant people. From the day of baptism through the spiritual milestones of our lives, we make promises with God and He makes promises with us. He <span class="emphasis">always</span> keeps His promises offered through His authorized servants, but it is the crucial test of our lives to see if <span class="emphasis">we</span> will make and keep our covenants with Him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p36" pid="JJgsLnXP1UOcksgu6mZZxA" hash="_GeaSw">
				<span class="pageBreak" page-number="114"></span>
				<span class="strong">3. Keeping our covenants demonstrates our love for the Savior and our Father in Heaven.</span>
			</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p37" pid="zJ8LFe0SPEaxKJ496aCFwg" hash="ikMfUg">Of all the reasons we ought to be more diligent in our covenant keeping, this reason is more compelling than all—love. A verse in the Old Testament is one that touches my heart as we consider the principle of love. Who of us is not moved by Jacob and Rachel’s biblical love story as we read, “And Jacob served seven years for Rachel; and they seemed unto him but a few days, for the love he had to her”?<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> Sisters, do we keep our covenants with that kind of deep and devoted love?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p38" pid="_9pT7Iz1nUKvy3F3vjWExw" hash="AWcrFw">Why was the Savior willing to keep His covenant with the Father and fulfill His divine mission to atone for the sins of the world? It was His love for His Father and His love for us. Why was the Father willing to allow His Only Begotten and perfect Son to suffer pain beyond description to bear the sins, heartaches, sicknesses, and infirmities of the world and all that is unfair in this life? We find the answer in these words: “For God so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p39" pid="eognzw0bHUW_Z34ftDaI0Q" hash="zgD0mA">“If we fully appreciated the many blessings which are ours through the redemption made for us, there is nothing that the Lord could ask of us that we would not anxiously and willingly do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> According to this statement by President Joseph Fielding Smith, covenant keeping is one way to express our love for the incomprehensible, infinite Atonement of our Savior and Redeemer and the perfect love of our Father in Heaven.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p40" pid="TowAJmId0EidZRD05WioJg" hash="kcC0hA">Elder Holland movingly suggested, “I am not certain just what our experience will be on Judgment Day, but I will be very surprised if at some point in that conversation, God does not ask us exactly what Christ asked Peter: ‘Did you love me?’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> Tonight I invite each of us to evaluate how much we love the Savior, using as a measure how joyfully we keep our covenants. The Savior said, “He that hath my commandments, and keepeth them, he it is that loveth me: and he that loveth me shall be loved of my Father, and I will love him, and will manifest myself to him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span> How we all need a regular manifestation of the Savior in our daily lives!</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping.p41" pid="BNDKHusAu0Cg45PcUVA_QA" hash="mxzdgA">Let us remember that even those who have been wayward in the past or who are currently struggling can feel the touch of the Good Shepherd’s hand upon their heads and hear His voice saying: “Come on. You aren’t tied down anymore. You are free.” The Savior said, “I am the good shepherd: the good shepherd giveth his life for the sheep.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26">26</span> He can say that because He kept His covenants with love. The question then is, will we? May we go forth with faith, cheerful hearts, and a great desire to be covenant keepers. This is how we demonstrate our love for our Father in Heaven and our Savior, both of whom I testify with great love in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2013/10/the-power-joy-and-love-of-covenant-keeping</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/2013-general-relief-society-meeting/2013-09-0010-linda-k-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="7539302" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wanted: Hands and Hearts to Hasten the Work</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Linda K. Burton teaches that we can be devoted disciples of Jesus Christ by serving others and furthering the work of salvation.
		</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10985_000_63burton" doc-version="3" hash="Iua4qQ">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="cjALcuYOiEKbODOqj-4jSA" hash="oRvArA">Wanted: Hands and Hearts to Hasten the Work</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p" pid="87xAEFUBH0WiNC6uEl8e1Q" hash="EolBAA">By Linda K. Burton</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p" pid="q7owjawd2UuR-ETloSsDEA" hash="Wft9FQ">Relief Society General President</p>
		</div>
		<img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/leaders/linda-k-burton.jpg" altText="Linda K. Burton" pid="mDvmvnk7xUCO0qAKWKoTCA" hash="sQY7rA" />
		<p class="kicker" pid="_FxTya8aTUynb8QfWLw_mg" hash="RdNwzA">We can offer hands to help and hearts to hasten Heavenly Father’s wonderful work.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="1i5o4RvQaEWr7Ko24BEIFg" hash="EolBAA1">By Linda K. Burton</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="0j1kUlc920Sy5yettWPx4A" hash="aR-dwA">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p5" pid="63_IfxLfqEeyatbZ7alZAQ" hash="vpmCIQ">
			<span class="pageBreak" page-number="122"></span>Dear sisters, how we love you! As we watched that beautiful video, did you see your own hand reaching out to help someone along that covenant path? I was thinking about a young Primary girl named Brynn who has only one hand, and yet she uses that hand to reach out to bless her family and her friends—Latter-day Saints and those of other faiths. Isn’t she beautiful? And so are you! Sisters, we can offer hands to help and hearts to hasten Heavenly Father’s wonderful work.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p6" pid="tACoPqE6wkipJo29CJqFpQ" hash="o2qZWQ">Just as our faithful sisters in the scriptures, such as Eve, Sarah, Mary, and many others, knew their identity and purpose, Brynn knows that she is a daughter of God.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> We too can know of our own divine heritage as beloved daughters of God and the vital work He has for us to do.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p7" pid="MBbv8X52vUuRpW6flrM1qA" hash="RN6xFA">The Savior taught, “If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> What do we need to know and do “to live with him someday”?<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> We can learn from the story of the rich young man who asked Jesus what he needed to do in order to receive eternal life.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p8" pid="W5cyrwi65EyM1_tIhUqeoQ" hash="DE08hw">Jesus answered him, “If thou wilt enter into life, keep the commandments.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p9" pid="AXigFEVT60KQ3PtmhTMUuQ" hash="bZt-Rw">The young man asked Him which ones he should keep. Jesus then reminded him of several of the Ten Commandments we are all familiar with.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p10" pid="pGZ_4ZQg8EKe69FHPYVvVw" hash="UrRsNQ">The young man responded, “All these things have I kept from my youth up: what lack I yet?”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p11" pid="jxLZxdBGyEm1hmeR-WWTNQ" hash="nuEiBg">Jesus said, “If thou wilt be perfect, go and sell that thou hast, and give to the poor, and thou shalt have treasure in heaven: and come and follow me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p12" pid="Itscl541zUencOPumwvV7A" hash="xJDj_Q">Jesus called him to become a part of His work—the work of a disciple. Our work is the same. We are to “lay aside the things of [the] world, … cleave unto [our] covenants,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> and come unto Christ and follow Him. That’s what disciples do!</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p13" pid="A7toJMbYNk2fNeUKmjqDcg" hash="DUNrSQ">Now, sisters, let’s not start beating ourselves up because the Savior spoke to the rich young man about becoming perfect. The word <span class="emphasis">perfect</span> in this account was translated from a Greek word that means “complete.” As we try our best to move forward along the covenant path, we become more complete and perfect in this life.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p14" pid="Sz3nPZhFrEy2qkNf1vbSBA" hash="oURkGw">Like the rich young man in Jesus’s day, sometimes we are tempted to give up or turn back because maybe we think we can’t do it alone. And we are right! We cannot do the difficult things we have been asked to do without help. Help comes through the Atonement of Jesus Christ, the guidance of the Holy Ghost, and the helping hands of others.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p15" pid="R660mz3SP0OlORl8b6CuDw" hash="GFW7Eg">A faithful single sister recently testified that through the Atonement, she found strength to use her helping hands and willing heart to raise the four children her sister had left behind when she died of cancer. That reminded me of something Elder Neal A. Maxwell said: “All the easy things that the Church has had to do have been done. From now on, it’s high adventure, and followership is going to be tested in some interesting ways.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> You have been sent to earth in this dispensation of time because of who you are and what you have <span class="pageBreak" page-number="123"></span>been prepared to do! Regardless of what Satan would try to persuade us to think about who we are, our true identity is that of a disciple of Jesus Christ!</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p16" pid="ZieGMCt3YEudwQtlVVWR9A" hash="dicEZg">Mormon was a true disciple who lived in a day when “every heart was hardened, … and there never had been so great wickedness among all the children of Lehi.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> How would you like to have lived in that day? And yet Mormon boldly declared, “Behold, I am a disciple of Jesus Christ, the Son of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p17" pid="rlDusCE-OUe2F6A1SVfksQ" hash="msX2Qg">Don’t you love Mormon? He knew who he was and what his mission was and was not distracted by the evil that surrounded him. In fact, he considered his calling to be a gift.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p18" pid="W5RIo2_ti0y2cVBz6cxVdQ" hash="qFga3Q">Think what a blessing it is to be called to give our gift of daily discipleship to the Lord, declaring in word and deed, “Behold, I am a disciple of Jesus Christ!”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p19" pid="SUBKaOc06kKKcEnZ37UAsw" hash="0yyJFg">I love the story President Boyd K. Packer told of a dear sister who was ridiculed for following the prophet’s counsel to store food. The one who criticized suggested that if times became desperate, her leaders would ask her to share her food storage with others. Her simple and resolute response as a true disciple was, “At least I will have something to bring.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p20" pid="F3Uw0VpMP0yx2aGXge8Gtg" hash="wTJnfQ">I love the women of the Church, young and old. I have seen your strength. I have seen your faith. You have something to give and are willing to give it. You do this without fanfare or publicity, drawing attention to the God we worship, not yourselves, and with no thought of what you will receive.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> That’s what disciples do!</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p21" pid="IUQaUajVp0imTTe3zlX5Bg" hash="H4DYgw">I recently met a young woman in the Philippines whose family became less active in the Church when she was only 7 years old, leaving her alone to walk a dangerous road to church week after week. She told how at age 14 she decided that she would stay true to her covenants so she would be worthy to raise her future family in a home “blessed by the strength of priesthood pow’r.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> The best way to strengthen a home, current or future, is to keep covenants, promises we’ve made to each other and to God.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p22" pid="VG8dYBMMckisPgUgFmGkww" hash="tz772w">That’s what disciples do!</p>
		</span>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p23" pid="cm6OooapfUyF0KOCZuNM_A" hash="JayHdA">A faithful Japanese sister and her husband visited our mission in Korea. She didn’t speak Korean and was limited in her ability to speak English, but she had a willing heart to use her unique gifts and helping hands to do the Lord’s work. That’s what disciples do! She taught our missionaries how to do a simple piece of origami—a mouth that could open and shut. She then used the few English words she knew to teach the missionaries to “open their mouths” to share the gospel—a lesson they will never forget, nor will I.</p>
		</span>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p24" pid="XVQqsOXfGUqtoCQ35agY_A" hash="dRizBw">
				<span class="pageBreak" page-number="124"></span>Visualize for a minute you and me standing together with the other millions of sisters and brothers in His Church, going forth boldly, doing what disciples do—serving and loving like the Savior. What does it mean to you to be a disciple of Jesus Christ?</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p25" pid="nt6-D41rRUibnFoocy1FEA" hash="LAJ3ag">Mormon Helping Hands vests and shirts have been worn by hundreds of thousands of selfless disciples of Jesus Christ who have embraced the opportunity to provide temporal service. But there are other ways to serve as devoted disciples. Imagine with me some of the possible spiritual “help wanted” signs related to the work of salvation:</p>
		<div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.f1">
			<ul class="bullet" guid="">
				<li pid="OLH3yDztT0qvFr7jxUTOeg" hash="o_EOPA">
					<span class="label">• </span>
					<p pid="JX1gcllMo0ahlO1Arp-Sog" hash="TgxSRg">Help wanted: parents to bring up their children in light and truth</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="r4CCfkxXW0ihjYurT5mJYw" hash="Qi-wLg">
					<span class="label">• </span>
					<p pid="8ZADkTMmt0aohZV4WAvT6A" hash="JrJ6Sw">Help wanted: daughters and sons, sisters and brothers, aunts and uncles, cousins, grandparents, and true friends to serve as mentors and offer helping hands along the covenant path</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="zlQKrz-bUUyg4w-Gldc--Q" hash="r8fQAg">
					<span class="label">• </span>
					<p pid="_HcyJEe_lkGEOeiZnqr7OA" hash="9NDlWw">Help wanted: those who listen to the promptings of the Holy Ghost and act on impressions received</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="HocIZfBK4kurwT88iHZ7Kg" hash="KaBClw">
					<span class="label">• </span>
					<p pid="S1XlFpB5Wky7DMJrfDz_BQ" hash="5zLc3A">Help wanted: those who live the gospel daily in small and simple ways</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="2JH0gb3UM0qkUG5C1zNKtA" hash="E9DGWg">
					<span class="label">• </span>
					<p pid="cBq3iJ19fEiZIkkT2DSjJg" hash="ckH3Rw">Help wanted: family history and temple workers to link families eternally</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="R7wTO-CDZkG6ppspKq4A9g" hash="reyerA">
					<span class="label">• </span>
					<p pid="wbS1YGd_x0ys1T2mSJXVtw" hash="vOocCg">Help wanted: missionaries and members to spread the “good news”—the gospel of Jesus Christ</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="25SlPUXkA0inJ9IHHLtPEQ" hash="khOApQ">
					<span class="label">• </span>
					<p pid="hP5snDfSykGpC9RIWqp94Q" hash="uQanCQ">Help wanted: rescuers to find those who have lost their way</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="-xq8TJ03EEO0XHPL2ulyzg" hash="DDX4KA">
					<span class="label">• </span>
					<p pid="yCdlXN2LOkKPAUrW7KNwog" hash="eR0Ahw">Help wanted: covenant keepers to stand firm for truth and right</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="pgLTqXfLB0CGtqovFyfBgQ" hash="2ExYfw">
					<span class="label">• </span>
					<p pid="EC40gFPJFkWV5GrCAEoNZg" hash="2DbaBw">Help wanted: true disciples of the Lord Jesus Christ</p>
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p35" pid="PN2GRRnv60KDgPN7YIcZDw" hash="EcvXNg">Years ago, Elder M. Russell Ballard issued a clarion call to the sisters of the Church when he said:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p36" pid="eXMim-YebkWSwZcSG2rc2g" hash="jYjU5w">“Between now and the day the Lord comes again, He needs women in every family, in every ward, in every community, in every nation who will step forward in righteousness and say by their words and their actions, ‘Here am I, send me.’</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p37" pid="VeEjxrzKtkOk4Um5b2rRNQ" hash="SiktBQ">“My question is, ‘Will you be one of those women?’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p38" pid="mvy5aHsV-UqMEO9OjxGW1Q" hash="SJ8wuw">I hope each of us can answer with a resounding “Yes!” I close with the words of a Primary song:</p>
		<div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.f2">
			<div class="stanza">
				<p class="line" pid="NLsALCAjgU29q0wS7Q1SYA" hash="wldgwA">We are cov’nant [daughters] with a gift to give.</p>
				<p class="line" pid="ra5MjppCNUalu1DS-vDkTg" hash="JzbDIA">We will teach the gospel by the way we live.</p>
				<p class="line" pid="KIa9YlnM70OJJe6_Agj95w" hash="RM6cBw">With each word and action, we will testify:</p>
				<p class="line" pid="7msdk479QUS9_oNLvSACaA" hash="77rZIw">We believe, and we serve Jesus Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span>
				</p>
			</div>
		</div>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work.p43" pid="l1XPUVcK4UeqRwr-XxODhA" hash="i6pbGA">As true disciples, may we offer our willing hearts and our helping hands to hasten His work. It does not matter if, like Brynn, we have only one hand. It does not matter if we are not yet perfect and complete. We are devoted disciples who reach out and help each other along the way. Our sisterhood reaches across the generations to those faithful sisters who have walked before. Together, as sisters and in unity with living prophets, seers, and revelators with restored priesthood keys, we can walk as one, as disciples, as servants with willing hearts and hands to hasten the work of salvation. As we do so, we will become like the Savior. I so testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/04/wanted-hands-and-hearts-to-hasten-the-work</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/march-2014-general-womens-meeting/2014-03-0050-linda-k-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5088128" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prepared in a Manner That Never Had Been Known</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10991_000_61burton" doc-version="10" hash="eSm2oQ"&gt;
			
			&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.head1"&gt;
				&lt;h1 class="title" pid="cQWE2QyCdkOawF4wmS1SLw" hash="Qo88KA"&gt;Prepared in a Manner That Never Had Been Known&lt;/h1&gt;
				&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p2" pid="bjUXozS4G0SsH3-BGGQ-0w" hash="EolBAA"&gt;By Linda K. Burton&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p3" pid="tZT75BCLO0mcg5NsBhGnrQ" hash="Wft9FQ"&gt;Relief Society General President&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=wDFYktAWBUOBsf9rjQ5xXQ"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/100x136.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x68="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/50x68.jpg" data-src-100x136="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/100x136.jpg" data-src-200x273="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/200x273.jpg" data-src-320x437="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/320x437.jpg" data-src-460x628="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/460x628.jpg" data-src-640x875="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/640x875.jpg" data-src-1024x1400="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/1024x1400.jpg" data-src-2048x2800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/2048x2800.jpg" data-src-3550x4854="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/3550x4854.jpg" altText="Linda K. Burton" pid="wDFYktAWBUOBsf9rjQ5xXQ" hash="_b6Usg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;p class="kicker" pid="wj1F-t2bFUKAdiUhhJDQJA" hash="o9uudw"&gt;May we prepare to worthily receive saving ordinances drop by drop and keep the associated covenants wholeheartedly.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="authorName" pid="MM9nZLwqrUq1WnI2sNSu7g" hash="EolBAA1"&gt;By Linda K. Burton&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;div class="bodyBlock" pid="UvTLK4TBiUCX2KPcYRqVxA" hash="KzsYxw"&gt;
				&lt;span class="story"&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p5" pid="c5PhOjNzaEeCoxPgu_Pn9Q" hash="iJqwYw"&gt;When our youngest daughter returned home after her first day of school, I asked, “How did it go?”&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p6" pid="CGlpRNM9P0mwxKgACWx6tw" hash="M6C_sA"&gt;She answered, “It was good.”&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p7" pid="d1ta4XOf3UyiXCD9zbc0jA" hash="UBr-OQ"&gt;The next morning, however, when I woke her up for school, she folded her arms and firmly stated, “I already went to school!” Apparently I had not &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;prepared&lt;/span&gt; her or explained that going to school was not a onetime event but that she was expected to go to school five days a week for many, many years.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p8" pid="zZ6dSGjiM0m8z6Dwwyxipw" hash="6693Nw"&gt;As we consider the principle of being prepared, imagine with me the following scene. You are sitting in the celestial room of the temple and notice a number of brides and grooms being reverently ushered in and out as they wait to be married for time and all eternity. A bride enters the celestial room, hand in hand with her sweetheart. She is wearing a simple but beautiful temple dress and a calm, peaceful, warm smile on her face. She is well groomed but not distracting. She takes her seat, glances about, and then is suddenly overcome with emotion. It seems that her tears come because of the awe and reverence she has for both the place she is in and the sacred ordinance awaiting her and the love of her life. Her demeanor seems to say, “How grateful I am to be in the Lord’s house today, ready to begin an eternal journey with a beloved eternal companion.” She seems &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;prepared&lt;/span&gt; for much more than just an event.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p9" pid="XQoBDNIhn0OCE3aDbRZ9FQ" hash="hC3sLw"&gt;Our cute teenage granddaughter recently left a note for me on my pillow that in part said: “One thing that strikes me as I enter the temple is the peaceful, loving spirit that dwells there. … People can go to the temple to receive inspiration.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; She is right. We can receive inspiration and revelation in the temple—and also power to cope with the adversities of life. What she is learning about the temple as she consistently participates in taking her own family names to do temple baptisms and confirmations will prepare her to receive additional temple ordinances, covenants, and blessings, both for herself and those on the other side of the veil.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p10" pid="eoQK0XKZrUyMinfTGCyEoA" hash="dyuR8w"&gt;Elder Russell M. Nelson taught, “As temples are prepared for the people, the people need to prepare themselves for the temple.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p11" pid="PtH-dI7zC0W4cxy0usN1Lw" hash="cWzJ9g"&gt;As I am again reading about Captain Moroni in the Book of Mormon, I am reminded that one of Moroni’s greatest accomplishments was his careful preparation of the Nephites to withstand the frightening Lamanite army. He prepared his people so well that we read, “Behold, to [the Lamanites’] uttermost astonishment, [the Nephites] &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;were prepared for them, in a manner which never had been known.&lt;/span&gt;”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p12" pid="M5tNFxbinEeK5LUWaQHuKw" hash="FyP_dg"&gt;That phrase, “prepared … in a manner which never had been known,” really caught my attention.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p13" pid="sivrrfDmm0yqws3Hef2FKw" hash="4vwQ8A"&gt;How can we better prepare for sacred temple blessings? The Lord taught, “And again, I will give unto you a pattern in all things.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; Let’s consider a scriptural pattern to help us prepare well. Moroni’s preparation for the enemy took consistent and faithful diligence, and this pattern will require the same.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p14" pid="Pv1e6ZNmbEC8UNFcd9ftXw" hash="2eNdSg"&gt;I never seem to tire of the beautiful parable the Savior told of the five wise and five foolish virgins. Though this parable refers to being prepared for the Second Coming of our Savior, we could also liken it to being prepared for temple blessings, which can be like a spiritual feast for those who are well prepared.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p15" pid="cwKiWbN42Uq9FL9osUYneQ" hash="Ig3MGQ"&gt;In Matthew 25 we read:&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p16" pid="t68Sxp2AHUW4anGE-GpnZA" hash="d0V4PA"&gt;“Then shall the kingdom of heaven be likened unto ten virgins, which took their lamps, and went forth to meet the bridegroom.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p17" pid="8wtcvjC6q0uxU9_fwlQ3Sg" hash="auhNYA"&gt;“And five of them were wise, and five were foolish. …&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p18" pid="qbTqGJvCDECuzIu7oqh_Ng" hash="hctgDg"&gt;“[They that were] wise took oil in their vessels with their lamps.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p19" pid="FmhtQYGGFUuW-sUdxBeYAw" hash="OD0GGw"&gt;“While the bridegroom tarried, they all slumbered and slept.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p20" pid="oLclSM35rkWv5D4eSxHMzA" hash="mK23SQ"&gt;“And at midnight there was a cry made, Behold, the bridegroom cometh; go ye out to meet him.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p21" pid="vJQ1W18b1k6l_LWm-HYO_w" hash="lWevcQ"&gt;“Then all those virgins arose, and trimmed their lamps.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p22" pid="JwJrb8Qq6EG3B5wCE2vxPw" hash="CyFCeg"&gt;“And the foolish said unto the wise, Give us of your oil; for our lamps are gone out.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p23" pid="VczDPshZgUGqF1dnwa3I5g" hash="JXveig"&gt;“But the wise answered, saying, Not so; lest there be not enough for us and you: but go ye rather to them that sell, and buy for yourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p24" pid="94XRumWDe0OPMHGDIuEL7g" hash="tPptOQ"&gt;“And while they went to buy, the bridegroom came; and they that were ready went in with him to the marriage: and the door was shut.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p25" pid="Tl6E9LtqykyC3Cx-Ai_O4w" hash="0CJRoA"&gt;“Afterward came also the other virgins, saying, Lord, Lord, open to us.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p26" pid="AxQ24mkHokSy9RqE904Bgw" hash="xf8CaA"&gt;“But he answered and said, Verily I say unto you, Ye know me not.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p27" pid="2K7PqdQrg0SC8sUVLKkRzg" hash="xFkZqg"&gt;I don’t think there is anyone, especially among those with tender hearts, who doesn’t feel sad for the foolish young women. And some of us just want to say to the others, “Can’t you just share so everyone can be happy?” But think about it. This is a story the Savior told, and He is the one who calls five of them “wise” and five of them “foolish.”&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p28" pid="decJKaW1dUKrW1C7nqZKQw" hash="aFaWMQ"&gt;As we consider this parable as a pattern for temple preparation, consider the words of a latter-day prophet who taught that “the oil of spiritual preparedness cannot be shared.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; President Spencer W. Kimball helped clarify why the five “wise” young women could not share the oil in their lamps with those who were “foolish” when he said: “Attendance at sacrament meetings adds oil to our lamps, drop by drop over the years. Fasting, family prayer, home teaching, control of bodily appetites, preaching the gospel, studying the scriptures—each act of dedication and obedience is a drop added to our store. Deeds of kindness, payment of offerings and tithes, chaste thoughts and actions … —these, too, contribute importantly to the oil with which we can at midnight refuel our exhausted lamps.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p29" pid="IOut9SKx_ECrn19aZAsBxg" hash="1JcM5Q"&gt;Can you see the pattern of preparedness—drop by drop—that can help us as we think how we might be more diligent in our preparation to receive sacred ordinances for ourselves and others? What other small and simple things might we do to add precious spiritual drops of oil to our lamps of preparation?&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p30" pid="5J9dI0WWlEyiFIcmlu-1KA" hash="4Fp6Kw"&gt;We learn from Elder Richard G. Scott that “personal worthiness is an essential requirement to enjoy the blessings of the temple. … Worthy character is best forged from a life of consistent, correct choices centered in the teachings of the Master.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8"&gt;8&lt;/span&gt; I love the word &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;consistent.&lt;/span&gt; To be consistent is to be steady, constant, and dependable. What a great description of the principle of worthiness!&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;span class="story"&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p31" pid="UsrUqYt6Z0qWTHq6IW2pPQ" hash="V6gujw"&gt;We are reminded in the Bible Dictionary: “Only the home can compare with the temple in sacredness.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9"&gt;9&lt;/span&gt; Do our homes or apartments fit that description? A darling young woman in our ward came to our home recently. Knowing her brother had just returned from his mission, I asked her what it was like to have him back home. She said it was great, but he would occasionally ask if the music could be turned down. She said, “And it wasn’t even &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;bad&lt;/span&gt; music!” It may be worthwhile for us to check ourselves now and then to make sure our homes are places we are prepared to feel the Spirit. As we prepare our homes to be places where the Spirit is welcome, we will be prepared to feel more “at home” when we enter the house of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p32" pid="aQaaqeWH8U6nT7w9bPri4A" hash="K5avoQ"&gt;As we prepare ourselves to worthily enter the temple and are faithful to temple covenants, the Lord will bestow “a multiplicity of blessings”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt; upon us. My good friend Bonnie Oscarson recently turned a scripture inside out when she said, “Where much is required, much more will be given.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11"&gt;11&lt;/span&gt; I couldn’t agree more! Because we come to the temple to receive &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;eternal&lt;/span&gt; blessings, it should not surprise us that a higher standard is required to qualify for those blessings. Again Elder Nelson taught: “Because the temple is the house of the Lord, standards for admission are set by Him. One enters as His guest. To hold a temple recommend is a priceless privilege and a tangible sign of obedience to God and His prophets.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12"&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p33" pid="F43hkL4Wu06ZjdmbSPoLdA" hash="sdyJAQ"&gt;World-class athletes and university doctoral students spend hours and days and weeks and months and even years of preparation. Daily drops of preparation are required of them to come out on top. Likewise, those who wish to qualify for exaltation in the celestial kingdom are expected to live a higher standard of obedience that comes by practicing the virtue of obedience day by day and drop by drop.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p34" pid="Qg57N3mlc0ON1HtyTsuwiA" hash="1iy60g"&gt;As we consistently and diligently add oil, drop by drop, to our spiritual lamps, doing these small and simple things, we can have our lamps “trimmed and burning”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt; with astonishing preparation. My cute husband, who is a stake president, recently remarked that he can almost always tell when someone is prepared and worthy to enter the temple, because “they light up the room” when they come seeking a temple recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p35" pid="wMm7YckE30SdHXq10tgPcw" hash="3MzjiQ"&gt;In the dedicatory prayer of the Kirtland Temple, the Prophet Joseph Smith asked the Lord “that all people who shall enter upon the threshold of the Lord’s house may feel thy power, … that they may grow up in thee, and receive a fulness of the Holy Ghost, … and be prepared to obtain every needful thing.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14"&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known.p36" pid="ZffDhKWmREGYJmEynEUIVw" hash="J0ZT3w"&gt;It is my prayer that for us, going to the temple will be much more than a onetime event. May we prepare to worthily receive saving ordinances drop by drop and keep the associated covenants wholeheartedly. As we do so, I know we will qualify to receive the promised blessings of a fulness of the Holy Ghost and the power of the Lord in our homes and individual lives. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
			
		&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/10/prepared-in-a-manner-that-never-had-been-known</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-session/september-2014-general-womens-session/2014-09-0010-linda-k-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="4907821" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We’ll Ascend Together</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sister Burton teaches that as men and women keep their covenants and strengthen each other, all can reach their full potential.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_12565_000_13burton" doc-version="8" hash="n-N88w">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="eK-EwE5TNEW_sStrFy94UA" hash="U3l6LA">We’ll Ascend Together</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p2" pid="WezVt_79o0iEQLXizbY6JQ" hash="EolBAA">By Linda K. Burton</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p3" pid="2orGWcFO6UWtIL7N8C0mqw" hash="Wft9FQ">Relief Society General President</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=zkcUNhzViUylFn69S4HuJQ"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" type="jpg" uri="linda-k-burton-10.jpg" translate="no" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/100x136.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x68="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/50x68.jpg" data-src-100x136="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/100x136.jpg" data-src-200x273="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/200x273.jpg" data-src-320x437="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/320x437.jpg" data-src-460x628="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/460x628.jpg" data-src-640x875="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/640x875.jpg" data-src-1024x1400="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/1024x1400.jpg" data-src-2048x2800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/2048x2800.jpg" data-src-3550x4854="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/3550x4854.jpg" pid="zkcUNhzViUylFn69S4HuJQ" hash="_9hFFw"></img></a>
		</div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="pRcMHL6ZwUKnImIz5ibn0Q" hash="aYdIUw">As covenant-keeping women and men, we need to lift each other and help each other become the people the Lord would have us become.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="1O-zk7n3ykmbUtC4hUPSyQ" hash="EolBAA1">By Linda K. Burton</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p5" pid="oWf_GHmk1UWmgk2Aixbsfw" hash="Z5SpkA">Next to the inspiring talks, music, and prayers that always touch our hearts during general conference, I have been told by many sisters that what they love most is watching the First Presidency and Quorum of the Twelve as they exit this podium with their eternal companions. And don’t we all enjoy hearing the Brethren tenderly express their love for them?</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=gXY0fjfiK0uGLh9E6DGToA"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448778/ea90199d44d642ee9ac557734d679fbe/100x123.png" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x61="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448778/ea90199d44d642ee9ac557734d679fbe/50x61.png" data-src-100x123="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448778/ea90199d44d642ee9ac557734d679fbe/100x123.png" data-src-200x246="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448778/ea90199d44d642ee9ac557734d679fbe/200x246.png" data-src-320x394="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448778/ea90199d44d642ee9ac557734d679fbe/320x394.png" data-src-460x567="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448778/ea90199d44d642ee9ac557734d679fbe/460x567.png" data-src-640x789="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448778/ea90199d44d642ee9ac557734d679fbe/640x789.png" data-src-1024x1263="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448778/ea90199d44d642ee9ac557734d679fbe/1024x1263.png" data-src-1459x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448778/ea90199d44d642ee9ac557734d679fbe/1459x1800.png" altText="" pid="gXY0fjfiK0uGLh9E6DGToA" hash="d_IYdQ"></img></a>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p6" pid="6l96G4-9qU2Q2Thq2VJmXQ" hash="oVC2NA">Speaking about his wife, Donna, President Boyd K. Packer said, “Because of the office I hold, I have a solemn obligation to tell the truth: She’s perfect.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=dNhcJUKTEkW2Jf5xmWf21Q"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448779/1500148aaa654814a87a9c552558b3b6/200x112.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x28="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448779/1500148aaa654814a87a9c552558b3b6/50x28.jpg" data-src-100x56="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448779/1500148aaa654814a87a9c552558b3b6/100x56.jpg" data-src-200x112="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448779/1500148aaa654814a87a9c552558b3b6/200x112.jpg" data-src-320x179="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448779/1500148aaa654814a87a9c552558b3b6/320x179.jpg" data-src-460x258="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448779/1500148aaa654814a87a9c552558b3b6/460x258.jpg" data-src-640x359="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448779/1500148aaa654814a87a9c552558b3b6/640x359.jpg" data-src-1024x575="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448779/1500148aaa654814a87a9c552558b3b6/1024x575.jpg" data-src-2048x1151="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448779/1500148aaa654814a87a9c552558b3b6/2048x1151.jpg" data-src-2790x1569="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448779/1500148aaa654814a87a9c552558b3b6/2790x1569.jpg" altText="" pid="dNhcJUKTEkW2Jf5xmWf21Q" hash="ArHCXA"></img></a>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p7" pid="c0L2UmkpLU64KUwWaZ40hA" hash="_FxWEg">“She is the sunshine of my life,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> said President Dieter F. Uchtdorf of his wife, Harriet.</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=Mwjgzg05_0q7w2L2KgOthQ"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448782/1a3b8577cfd94ee4b55403769bf2f274/200x154.png" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x38="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448782/1a3b8577cfd94ee4b55403769bf2f274/50x38.png" data-src-100x77="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448782/1a3b8577cfd94ee4b55403769bf2f274/100x77.png" data-src-200x154="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448782/1a3b8577cfd94ee4b55403769bf2f274/200x154.png" data-src-320x247="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448782/1a3b8577cfd94ee4b55403769bf2f274/320x247.png" data-src-460x355="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448782/1a3b8577cfd94ee4b55403769bf2f274/460x355.png" data-src-640x495="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448782/1a3b8577cfd94ee4b55403769bf2f274/640x495.png" data-src-1024x792="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448782/1a3b8577cfd94ee4b55403769bf2f274/1024x792.png" data-src-2048x1584="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448782/1a3b8577cfd94ee4b55403769bf2f274/2048x1584.png" data-src-2790x2159="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448782/1a3b8577cfd94ee4b55403769bf2f274/2790x2159.png" altText="" pid="Mwjgzg05_0q7w2L2KgOthQ" hash="MT-eUw"></img></a>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p8" pid="Kj7FClip1U-sqFQ4nDmmaQ" hash="KVpBLA">President Henry B. Eyring, referring to his wife, Kathleen, said, “She [is] a person who has always made me want to be the very best that I can be.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=GMkrHbOfUUiUIp0i_wxl_A"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448783/36a257c841a846a195b1fb9e4ebeb9bf/200x112.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x28="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448783/36a257c841a846a195b1fb9e4ebeb9bf/50x28.jpg" data-src-100x56="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448783/36a257c841a846a195b1fb9e4ebeb9bf/100x56.jpg" data-src-200x112="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448783/36a257c841a846a195b1fb9e4ebeb9bf/200x112.jpg" data-src-320x179="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448783/36a257c841a846a195b1fb9e4ebeb9bf/320x179.jpg" data-src-460x258="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448783/36a257c841a846a195b1fb9e4ebeb9bf/460x258.jpg" data-src-640x359="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448783/36a257c841a846a195b1fb9e4ebeb9bf/640x359.jpg" data-src-1024x575="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448783/36a257c841a846a195b1fb9e4ebeb9bf/1024x575.jpg" data-src-2048x1151="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448783/36a257c841a846a195b1fb9e4ebeb9bf/2048x1151.jpg" data-src-2790x1569="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448783/36a257c841a846a195b1fb9e4ebeb9bf/2790x1569.jpg" altText="" pid="GMkrHbOfUUiUIp0i_wxl_A" hash="RUdJQg"></img></a>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p9" pid="rkWa3bYD1U6c5Bsb4eevag" hash="-_7xgA">And President Thomas S. Monson, speaking of his beloved Frances, said, “She was the love of my life, my trusted confidant, and my closest friend. To say that I miss her does not begin to convey the depth of my feelings.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p10" pid="sBaIXAg5tkiP0eJVP3wYFA" hash="0eh9XA">I too would like to express my love for my beloved companion, Craig. He is a precious gift to me! Referring to my husband, a cherished and sacred phrase in my patriarchal blessing promises that my life and the lives of my children will “be well in his keeping.” It is clear to me that Craig is the fulfillment of that promise. Borrowing from the words of Mark Twain, I say that “life without [Craig] would not be life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> I love him, heart and soul!</p>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.t1">
			<h2 pid="8eM9f3qPKEix-N3c9txbgg" hash="6m9eLg">Divine Roles and Responsibilities</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p12" pid="qKZlm935O02Mgdq6EPjsiw" hash="tFB93Q">Today I wish to honor husbands, fathers, brothers, sons, and uncles who know who they are and who are doing their best to fulfill their God-given roles as described in the family proclamation, including righteously presiding and providing for and protecting their families. Please know that I am painfully aware that the topics of fatherhood, motherhood, and marriage can be troubling for many. I know that some Church members feel that their homes will never reach what they perceive to be the ideal. Many are hurting because of neglect, abuse, addictions, and incorrect traditions and culture. I do not condone the actions of men or women who have willfully or even ignorantly caused pain, anguish, and despair in their homes. But today I am speaking of something else.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p13" pid="g9tYkVPtmkOsCU6oTl1Itw" hash="Rzl1dw">I am convinced that a husband is never more attractive to his wife than when he is serving in his God-given roles as a worthy priesthood holder—most important in the home. I love and believe these words from President Packer to worthy husbands and fathers: “You have the power of the priesthood directly from the Lord to protect your home. There will be times when all that stands as a shield between your family and the adversary’s mischief will be that power.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.t2" pid="RjJ-4kVS1EqmOMwmTYm3-A" hash="e5r-TQ">
			<h2 pid="10zvpy3kb0SaL0wvtgnkgg" hash="912JPA">Spiritual Leaders and Teachers in the Home</h2>
			<span class="story">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p15" pid="GJukGAEawU6N8Ue9Bj-yPA" hash="HhJFIw">Earlier this year I attended the funeral of an extraordinary ordinary man—my husband’s uncle Don. One of Uncle Don’s sons shared an experience he had as a small child, shortly after his parents had purchased their first home. Because there were five small children to feed and clothe, there was not enough money to fence the yard. Taking seriously one of his divine roles as the protector of his family, Uncle Don drove a few small wooden stakes into the ground, took some string, and tied the string from stake to stake all around the yard. He then called his children to him. He showed them the stakes and string and explained to them that if they would stay on the inside of that makeshift fence, they would be safe.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p16" pid="7ysVH6JBG0OoB5fXZD8lzA" hash="9YQxmA">One day the visiting teachers watched in disbelief as they approached the house and saw five little children standing obediently at the edge of the string, looking longingly at a ball that had bounced beyond their boundaries and out into the street. One little child ran to get their daddy, who, in response, ran and retrieved the ball.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p17" pid="rJMFwDFz_0iEIMbfGuElNg" hash="TQ0rng">Later in the funeral, the oldest son tearfully expressed that all he had ever hoped in this life was to be like his beloved father.</p>
			</span>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=XpSjt3PvwEe636imKURBig"><img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448787/a577993d956c4b51b10fd980696595c1/200x112.png" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x28="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448787/a577993d956c4b51b10fd980696595c1/50x28.png" data-src-100x56="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448787/a577993d956c4b51b10fd980696595c1/100x56.png" data-src-200x112="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448787/a577993d956c4b51b10fd980696595c1/200x112.png" data-src-320x179="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448787/a577993d956c4b51b10fd980696595c1/320x179.png" data-src-460x258="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448787/a577993d956c4b51b10fd980696595c1/460x258.png" data-src-640x359="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448787/a577993d956c4b51b10fd980696595c1/640x359.png" data-src-1024x575="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448787/a577993d956c4b51b10fd980696595c1/1024x575.png" data-src-2048x1151="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448787/a577993d956c4b51b10fd980696595c1/2048x1151.png" data-src-2790x1569="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448787/a577993d956c4b51b10fd980696595c1/2790x1569.png" altText="" pid="XpSjt3PvwEe636imKURBig" hash="CgU-OA"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p18" pid="67xX1aO7wk2VnQa5bakvNQ" hash="6aOWsg">President Ezra Taft Benson said:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p19" pid="AbVg9vGERkGyMTQBS_Qh7g" hash="pp4otw">“Oh, husbands and fathers in Israel, you can do so much for the salvation and exaltation of your families! …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p20" pid="xC5MMskNjE6b0uBxs9Wmew" hash="L0I8nQ">“Remember your sacred calling as a father in Israel—your most important calling in time and eternity—a calling from which you will never be released.”</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=A9e--b3NxEu-BHftEnMMJQ"><img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448788/15b006bcc10e472497792762810d0a5d/200x112.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x28="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448788/15b006bcc10e472497792762810d0a5d/50x28.jpg" data-src-100x56="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448788/15b006bcc10e472497792762810d0a5d/100x56.jpg" data-src-200x112="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448788/15b006bcc10e472497792762810d0a5d/200x112.jpg" data-src-320x179="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448788/15b006bcc10e472497792762810d0a5d/320x179.jpg" data-src-460x258="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448788/15b006bcc10e472497792762810d0a5d/460x258.jpg" data-src-640x359="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448788/15b006bcc10e472497792762810d0a5d/640x359.jpg" data-src-1024x575="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448788/15b006bcc10e472497792762810d0a5d/1024x575.jpg" data-src-2048x1151="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448788/15b006bcc10e472497792762810d0a5d/2048x1151.jpg" data-src-2790x1569="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1448788/15b006bcc10e472497792762810d0a5d/2790x1569.jpg" altText="" pid="A9e--b3NxEu-BHftEnMMJQ" hash="FAWN_w"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p21" pid="hQC5TL5fiU-fYUHWtu4B0Q" hash="VuQuJA">“You must help create a home where the Spirit of the Lord can abide.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p22" pid="QllwD5zck0OpM3ZFW6JS2g" hash="udBl0A">How applicable those prophetic words are today.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p23" pid="qXjnRBFu8UyQVqJbDtO4EQ" hash="QCEDCA">It must be difficult, at best, for covenant men to live in a world that not only demeans their divine roles and responsibilities but also sends false messages about what it means to be a “real man.” One false message is “It’s all about me.” On the other end of the scale is the degrading and mocking message that husbands and fathers are no longer needed. I plead with you not to listen to Satan’s lies! He has forfeited that sacred privilege of ever becoming a husband or father. Because he is jealous of those who have the sacred roles he will never fill, he is intent on making “all men … miserable like unto himself”!<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.t3">
			<h2 pid="kDG-uB-pv0uiO5aCqm1pwQ" hash="0F98bA">Lifting and Helping in Our Complementary Roles</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p25" pid="GZu5RPAYw0a8h7uUaUTasg" hash="NTGUig">Brothers and sisters, we need each other! As covenant-keeping women and men, we need to lift each other and help each other become the people the Lord would have us become. And we need to work together to lift the rising generation and help them reach their divine potential as heirs of eternal life. We could do as Elder Robert D. Hales and his wife, Mary, have done and follow the proverb “Thee lift me and I’ll lift thee, and we’ll ascend together.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p26" pid="pHlkSwm4M0eone2w-SyXPg" hash="-fhQcg">We know from the scriptures that “it is not good that … man should be alone.” That is why our Heavenly Father made “an help meet for him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> The phrase <span class="emphasis">help meet</span> means “a helper suited to, worthy of, or corresponding to him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> For example, our two hands are similar to each other but not exactly the same. In fact, they are exact opposites, but they complement each other and are suited to each other. Working together, they are stronger.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p27" pid="-lV7LWSOFUSLGeDlxbKYvQ" hash="RyGfoQ">In a chapter about families, the Church handbook contains this statement: “The nature of male and female spirits is such that they complete each other.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> Please note that it does not say “compete with each other” but “complete each other”! We are here to help, lift, and rejoice with each other as we try to become our very best selves. Sister Barbara B. Smith wisely taught, “There is so much more of happiness to be had when we can rejoice in another’s successes and not just in our own.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> When we seek to “complete” rather than “compete,” it is so much easier to cheer each other on!</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p28" pid="OoRYmTjNHkaea3R8F3TPkQ" hash="F0JPuA">When I was a young mother of several small children, at the end of days filled with diapering, dish washing, and disciplining, no one sang more emphatically the Primary song “I’m so glad when daddy comes home.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> I’m sad to admit, however, I was not always cheerful when Craig seemed to bounce through the door after a hard day of work. He always greeted each of us with a hug and kiss and turned many difficult and sometimes disastrous days into delightful daddy times. I wish I had been a little less preoccupied with the endless list of to-dos still to be done and had more wisely focused, like he did, on things that mattered most. I would have stopped more often and enjoyed sacred family time and would have thanked him more often for blessing our lives!</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.t4" pid="8apWwUjmokapdfYquup4jw" hash="IkD0Mg">
			<h2 pid="CmUOQQhKtk6EUJoEp-Ir7Q" hash="OgW-YQ">Let Us Oft Speak Kind Words to Each Other</h2>
			<span class="story">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p30" pid="dzhWx9NQLEOB_lPUYFHdfw" hash="lhhPzQ">Not long ago, a faithful sister in the Church shared with me a deep concern she had been praying about for some time. Her concern was for some of the sisters in her ward. She told me how it hurt her heart to observe that they sometimes spoke disrespectfully to their husbands and about their husbands, even in front of their children. She then told me how as a young woman she had earnestly desired and prayed to find and marry a worthy priesthood holder and build a happy home with him. She had grown up in a home where her mother had “ruled the roost” and her father had cowered to her mother’s demands in order to keep peace at home. She felt that there was a better way. She had not seen it modeled in the home she grew up in, but as she prayed fervently for guidance, the Lord blessed her to know how to create a home with her husband where the Spirit would be warmly welcomed. I have been in that home and can testify it is a holy place!</p>
			</span>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p31" pid="W6djY-X5rU-GLaTpc4TZJA" hash="Zz1Z_w">Sisters and brothers, how often do we intentionally “speak kind words to each other”?<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p32" pid="HdlrQv_BQU2v5tD6rLh07A" hash="d-PnzA">We might test ourselves by asking a few questions. With a little adaptation, these questions can apply to most of us, whether we are married or single, whatever our home situation might be.</p>
			<ol class="number">
				<li pid="dGYCDx84sUm7ZrcpCYRBNw" hash="2IeYjw">
					<span class="label">1.</span>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p33" pid="QSAfP6Cc5UCrneKatJVH4A" hash="SwEaYQ">When was the last time I sincerely praised my companion, either alone or in the presence of our children?</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="YRmXYud950--R2jd63836g" hash="vywUuw">
					<span class="label">2.</span>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p34" pid="zC5bq-6aAUuiC6tuxQf1sw" hash="9O33Aw">When was the last time I thanked, expressed love for, or earnestly pleaded in faith for him or her in prayer?</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="0qBgTygIrkGUmgSTKqlUSA" hash="8Y4iMQ">
					<span class="label">3.</span>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p35" pid="d5GivtDmkk-JB4v57JM9ZA" hash="0JQ7AQ">When was the last time I stopped myself from saying something I knew could be hurtful?</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="MYIxkhBYaEODxamKE_UrCQ" hash="GWCdzw">
					<span class="label">4.</span>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p36" pid="Ak0fVkXCZ0KpyluC2UZuKg" hash="_8r1Lg">When was the last time I apologized and humbly asked for forgiveness—without adding the words “but if only you had” or “but if only you hadn’t”?</p>
				</li>
				<li pid="b9EcAJbeGkediP4eCQ2tPA" hash="j8Alow">
					<span class="label">5.</span>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p37" pid="m-BnsjeFZE20zD8zzY7VdQ" hash="OD4LHA">When was the last time I chose to be happy rather than demanding to be “right”?</p>
				</li>
			</ol>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p38" pid="aonHeMfM7EuYbsHJepQV2A" hash="4X_VWg">Now, if any of these questions lead you to squirm or feel a tinge of guilt, remember that Elder David A. Bednar has taught that “guilt is to our spirit what pain is to our body—a warning of danger and a protection from additional damage.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p39" pid="3HXjhwuwS0WJC1KTCaPWDA" hash="Im4kdQ">I invite each of us to heed Elder Jeffrey R. Holland’s heartfelt plea: “Brothers and sisters, in this long eternal quest to be more like our Savior, may we try to be ‘perfect’ men and women in at least this one way now—by offending not in word, or more positively put, by speaking with a new tongue, the tongue of angels.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p40" pid="cC5sH74x1Uykxx5R4ymRjA" hash="K0K9Jw">As I have prepared for this opportunity today, the Spirit has taught me, and I have committed to speak words of kindness more often to my cherished companion and about him, to lift the men in my family and express gratitude for the ways they fulfill their divine and complementary roles. And I have committed to follow the proverb “Thee lift me and I’ll lift thee, and we’ll ascend together.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p41" pid="85iLUSlb4kiopzsE8GooVA" hash="QFn7NQ">Will you join me in seeking the help of the Holy Ghost to teach us how we can better lift each other in our complementary roles as covenant sons and daughters of our loving heavenly parents?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together.p42" pid="d3ViEOwK_Eal0BX3NIL0wA" hash="7U6Elg">I know that through the enabling power of the Atonement of Jesus Christ and our faith in Him, we can do it. I pray we will put our trust in Him to help us help each other live happily and eternally as we ascend together, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/04/well-ascend-together</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2015-general-conference/2015-04-1030-linda-k-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5423418" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“I Was a Stranger”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13285_000_13burton" doc-version="2" hash="dym4QQ"&gt;
	
	&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.head1"&gt;
		&lt;h1 class="title" pid="ciyKwLfHZUWoD8qdreFWGA" hash="jQkYTg"&gt;“I Was a Stranger”&lt;/h1&gt;
		&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p2" pid="2AEoiuC7Kky6XtBOjeg8vg" hash="EolBAA1"&gt;By Linda K. Burton&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p3" pid="EH_nIwMwmkWRHkKbWHe3fg" hash="Wft9FQ"&gt;Relief Society General President&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=tOSQ4svH20qRvUlektANgQ"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" altText="Linda K. Burton" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/100x136.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x68="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/50x68.jpg" data-src-100x136="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/100x136.jpg" data-src-200x273="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/200x273.jpg" data-src-320x437="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/320x437.jpg" data-src-460x628="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/460x628.jpg" data-src-640x875="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/640x875.jpg" data-src-1024x1400="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/1024x1400.jpg" data-src-2048x2800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/2048x2800.jpg" data-src-3550x4854="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255499/02312c356cf7496f99170ecd0098a209/3550x4854.jpg" webURL="linda-burton-relief-society-president-busath_1255499.jpg" pid="tOSQ4svH20qRvUlektANgQ" hash="AAAAAA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="kicker" pid="gB27kmlMx06WPrZiK-hHng" hash="UGG6eQ"&gt;Prayerfully determine what you can do—according to your own time and circumstance—to serve the refugees living in your neighborhoods and communities.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="authorName" pid="Nks3SBeMnUu3ZllL0LY8GQ" hash="EolBAA"&gt;By Linda K. Burton&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class="bodyBlock"&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p5" pid="1VJtsI5zlUKNjG9D_44l7w" hash="Q72BLA"&gt;On the day Relief Society was organized, Emma Smith declared: “We are going to do something extraordinary. … We expect extraordinary occasions and pressing calls.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; Those pressing calls and extraordinary occasions presented themselves frequently then—as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p6" pid="Zf0zn-TI1UOMInRU8_s92Q" hash="HbG_Ig"&gt;One came in the October 1856 general conference as President Brigham Young announced to the congregation that handcart pioneers were still on the trail and late in the season. He declared: “Your faith, religion, and profession of religion, will never save one soul of you in the celestial kingdom of our God, unless you carry out just such principles as I am now teaching you. Go and bring in those people now on the plains, and attend strictly to those things which we call temporal, … otherwise your faith will be in vain.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p7" pid="x4XUUEY_RU-pg-TylbuJfg" hash="ufzZsg"&gt;We remember with grateful admiration the men who headed off to rescue those suffering Saints. But what did the sisters do?&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p8" pid="BV5Weihg6E-7RcddP9Gg9Q" hash="poU3Yw"&gt;“Sister [Lucy Meserve] Smith recorded … that after President Young’s exhortation, those in attendance took action. … Women ‘[removed] their petticoats [large underskirts that were part of the fashion of the day and that also provided warmth], stockings, and every thing they could spare, right there in the [old] Tabernacle, and piled [them] into the wagons to send to the Saints in the mountains.’”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p9" pid="K-sn2f4QL0uAo_f-HtLEGg" hash="S8d2VQ"&gt;Several weeks later, President Brigham Young gathered the Saints again in the old Tabernacle as the rescuers and the handcart companies got closer to Salt Lake City. With great urgency, he pleaded with the Saints—especially the sisters—to nurse the sufferers and feed them and receive them, saying: “Some you will find with their feet frozen to their ankles; some are frozen to their knees and some have their hands frosted. … We want you to receive them as your own children, and to have the same feeling for them.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p10" pid="j1GpV4Sog06xbJKL0VIefQ" hash="Fk2KZg"&gt;Lucy Meserve Smith also recorded:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p11" pid="OqvOKiZsKk2332vS0InSdg" hash="zJ-Hqw"&gt;“We did all we could, with the aid of the good brethren and sisters, to comfort the needy. … They got their hands and feet badly frosted. … We did not cease our exertions [un]til all were made comfortable. …&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p12" pid="_Zn1jC6wMUG5eAXP9usOaQ" hash="wiTrgA"&gt;“I never took more satisfaction and, I might say, pleasure in any labor I ever performed in my life, such a unanimity of feeling prevailed. …&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p13" pid="3pNOqmvpMke_5xkZhEWEvQ" hash="twAY7Q"&gt;“What comes next for willing hands to do?”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p14" pid="7Htl4UajMkOZjmcxyrMYlQ" hash="9Jpw2A"&gt;My beloved sisters, this account might be likened to our day and those who are suffering throughout the world. Another “extraordinary occasion” touches our hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=P27mkI3WzU-XRArUb_XpbA"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705568/bf0a3e4f454c48c7a4e608f16fa552e7/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705568/bf0a3e4f454c48c7a4e608f16fa552e7/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705568/bf0a3e4f454c48c7a4e608f16fa552e7/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705568/bf0a3e4f454c48c7a4e608f16fa552e7/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705568/bf0a3e4f454c48c7a4e608f16fa552e7/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705568/bf0a3e4f454c48c7a4e608f16fa552e7/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x413="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705568/bf0a3e4f454c48c7a4e608f16fa552e7/640x413.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705568/bf0a3e4f454c48c7a4e608f16fa552e7/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705568/bf0a3e4f454c48c7a4e608f16fa552e7/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-3200x2065="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705568/bf0a3e4f454c48c7a4e608f16fa552e7/3200x2065.jpg" altText="Tents in a refugee camp" pid="P27mkI3WzU-XRArUb_XpbA" hash="1gDWPQ"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=cxFYcvbgnkSskzBxIBSZOg"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705569/b626819fc201463ab30c202393d2342c/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705569/b626819fc201463ab30c202393d2342c/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705569/b626819fc201463ab30c202393d2342c/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705569/b626819fc201463ab30c202393d2342c/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705569/b626819fc201463ab30c202393d2342c/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705569/b626819fc201463ab30c202393d2342c/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705569/b626819fc201463ab30c202393d2342c/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705569/b626819fc201463ab30c202393d2342c/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705569/b626819fc201463ab30c202393d2342c/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705569/b626819fc201463ab30c202393d2342c/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Children in a refugee camp" pid="cxFYcvbgnkSskzBxIBSZOg" hash="XPZrFA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=RRhXxDBPMU6dpbrb-L4Y4Q"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705570/905525964e8e4b4cbb4e5dd22e954403/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705570/905525964e8e4b4cbb4e5dd22e954403/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705570/905525964e8e4b4cbb4e5dd22e954403/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705570/905525964e8e4b4cbb4e5dd22e954403/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705570/905525964e8e4b4cbb4e5dd22e954403/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705570/905525964e8e4b4cbb4e5dd22e954403/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705570/905525964e8e4b4cbb4e5dd22e954403/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705570/905525964e8e4b4cbb4e5dd22e954403/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705570/905525964e8e4b4cbb4e5dd22e954403/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705570/905525964e8e4b4cbb4e5dd22e954403/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Woman in a refugee camp" pid="RRhXxDBPMU6dpbrb-L4Y4Q" hash="iRsqNQ"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=IH3ak4S-60umkCYU8xi2UQ"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705571/9d9b9650bbe246308cc3d8e2f76b6446/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705571/9d9b9650bbe246308cc3d8e2f76b6446/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705571/9d9b9650bbe246308cc3d8e2f76b6446/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705571/9d9b9650bbe246308cc3d8e2f76b6446/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705571/9d9b9650bbe246308cc3d8e2f76b6446/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705571/9d9b9650bbe246308cc3d8e2f76b6446/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705571/9d9b9650bbe246308cc3d8e2f76b6446/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705571/9d9b9650bbe246308cc3d8e2f76b6446/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705571/9d9b9650bbe246308cc3d8e2f76b6446/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705571/9d9b9650bbe246308cc3d8e2f76b6446/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Family in a refugee camp" pid="IH3ak4S-60umkCYU8xi2UQ" hash="AiziUA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=aajjfNmvlEqYg8-rdXLz_A"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705572/f950ae6f435c408bbd82b3098b3fc9ee/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705572/f950ae6f435c408bbd82b3098b3fc9ee/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705572/f950ae6f435c408bbd82b3098b3fc9ee/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705572/f950ae6f435c408bbd82b3098b3fc9ee/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705572/f950ae6f435c408bbd82b3098b3fc9ee/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705572/f950ae6f435c408bbd82b3098b3fc9ee/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705572/f950ae6f435c408bbd82b3098b3fc9ee/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705572/f950ae6f435c408bbd82b3098b3fc9ee/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705572/f950ae6f435c408bbd82b3098b3fc9ee/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705572/f950ae6f435c408bbd82b3098b3fc9ee/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Aid worker surrounded by children in a refugee camp" pid="aajjfNmvlEqYg8-rdXLz_A" hash="wKDB2g"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=DKxXOn0hokCTvOlTKZi2Ag"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705573/93c284e702b147beaf9c349aee9c9bcf/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705573/93c284e702b147beaf9c349aee9c9bcf/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705573/93c284e702b147beaf9c349aee9c9bcf/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705573/93c284e702b147beaf9c349aee9c9bcf/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705573/93c284e702b147beaf9c349aee9c9bcf/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705573/93c284e702b147beaf9c349aee9c9bcf/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705573/93c284e702b147beaf9c349aee9c9bcf/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705573/93c284e702b147beaf9c349aee9c9bcf/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705573/93c284e702b147beaf9c349aee9c9bcf/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705573/93c284e702b147beaf9c349aee9c9bcf/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Greeting a refugee family" pid="DKxXOn0hokCTvOlTKZi2Ag" hash="0pYKGw"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=_FU4ybs4S0GIuDA62Pez2A"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705574/a41822f0e23c4af682470da55ec12309/200x133.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x33="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705574/a41822f0e23c4af682470da55ec12309/50x33.jpg" data-src-100x66="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705574/a41822f0e23c4af682470da55ec12309/100x66.jpg" data-src-200x133="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705574/a41822f0e23c4af682470da55ec12309/200x133.jpg" data-src-320x213="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705574/a41822f0e23c4af682470da55ec12309/320x213.jpg" data-src-460x306="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705574/a41822f0e23c4af682470da55ec12309/460x306.jpg" data-src-640x426="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705574/a41822f0e23c4af682470da55ec12309/640x426.jpg" data-src-1024x682="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705574/a41822f0e23c4af682470da55ec12309/1024x682.jpg" data-src-2048x1365="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705574/a41822f0e23c4af682470da55ec12309/2048x1365.jpg" data-src-3456x2304="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705574/a41822f0e23c4af682470da55ec12309/3456x2304.jpg" altText="Aid worker embracing a refugee" pid="_FU4ybs4S0GIuDA62Pez2A" hash="z8bzpQ"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p15" pid="agD66wdZxkezNH8bVyAFhg" hash="pinSUA"&gt;There are more than 60 million refugees, including forcibly displaced people, worldwide. Half of those are children.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; “These individuals have undergone tremendous difficulties and are starting over in … new countr[ies] and culture[s]. While there are [sometimes] organizations that help them with a place to live and basic necessities, what they need is a friend and ally who can help them [adjust] to their new home, a person who can help them learn the language, understand the systems, and feel connected.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=9O_UBohi6E6nJ-4fdPlbxA"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705575/326e410137ad4158bf68857300c01cd9/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705575/326e410137ad4158bf68857300c01cd9/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705575/326e410137ad4158bf68857300c01cd9/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705575/326e410137ad4158bf68857300c01cd9/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705575/326e410137ad4158bf68857300c01cd9/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705575/326e410137ad4158bf68857300c01cd9/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705575/326e410137ad4158bf68857300c01cd9/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705575/326e410137ad4158bf68857300c01cd9/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705575/326e410137ad4158bf68857300c01cd9/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705575/326e410137ad4158bf68857300c01cd9/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Yvette Bugingo" pid="9O_UBohi6E6nJ-4fdPlbxA" hash="FXWsqA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p16" pid="NZjXD7G7w0auq1YqIsOVlQ" hash="3b-dHg"&gt;Last summer I met Sister Yvette Bugingo, who at age 11 fled from place to place after her father was killed and three of her brothers went missing in a war-torn part of the world. Yvette and the remaining family members eventually lived for six and a half years as refugees in a neighboring country until they were able to move to a permanent home, where they were blessed by a caring couple who helped with transportation, schools, and other things. She said they “were basically an answer to our prayers.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8"&gt;8&lt;/span&gt; Her beautiful mother and adorable little sister are with us tonight, singing in the choir. I have wondered many times since meeting these wonderful women, “What if &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; story were &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; story?”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p17" pid="QPP6ddp5K0-xmareUw-xsQ" hash="sPnxSQ"&gt;As sisters we make up more than half of the Lord’s storehouse to help Heavenly Father’s children. His storehouse is not composed just of goods but also of time, talents, skills, and our divine nature. Sister Rosemary M. Wixom has taught, “The divine nature within us ignites our desire to reach out to others and prompts us to act.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9"&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p18" pid="TSdV3V2ru0OT6qNmr4pRaA" hash="2CoYLQ"&gt;Recognizing our divine nature, President Russell M. Nelson urged:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p19" pid="rlJHIr7VuUO84D6LAlqdPA" hash="YaUcvQ"&gt;“We need women who know how to make important things happen by their faith and who are courageous defenders of morality and families in a sin-sick world … ; women who know how to call upon the powers of heaven to protect and strengthen children and families. …&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p20" pid="fG7kedsqi0Ce-Q7LPFT9Ow" hash="hD-PHQ"&gt;“… Married or single, you sisters possess distinctive capabilities and special intuition you have received as gifts from God. We brethren cannot duplicate your unique influence.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p21" pid="kQYsRLgtok-f-RWyTgFO2w" hash="tzbWAA"&gt;A First Presidency letter sent to the Church on October 27, 2015, expressed great concern and compassion for the millions of people who have fled their homes seeking relief from civil conflict and other hardships. The First Presidency invited individuals, families, and Church units to participate in Christlike service in local refugee relief projects and to contribute to the Church humanitarian fund, where practical.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p22" pid="6yjbpEGrAEqhj9xMLqPONg" hash="JPQWsQ"&gt;The general presidencies of the Relief Society, Young Women, and Primary have considered how to respond to the First Presidency’s invitation. We know that you, our beloved sisters of all ages, come from all walks of life and live in varied circumstances. Each member of this worldwide sisterhood has covenanted at baptism to “comfort those that stand in need of comfort.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11"&gt;11&lt;/span&gt; Yet we must remember that none of us should run faster than we have strength.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12"&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p23" pid="Nvn0Vev1Z0uUjHQ4_ZNJ3g" hash="g_pDuQ"&gt;With these truths in mind, we have organized a relief effort called “I Was a Stranger.” It is our hope that you will prayerfully determine what you can do—according to your own time and circumstance—to serve the refugees living in your neighborhoods and communities. This is an opportunity to serve one on one, in families, and by organization to offer friendship, mentoring, and other Christlike service and is one of many ways sisters can serve.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p24" pid="j-apwUpbh06UJ_XhJhGHig" hash="B0YBog"&gt;In all our prayerful efforts, we should apply the wise counsel of King Benjamin, given to his people after he exhorted them to care for those in need: “See that all these things are done in wisdom and order.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p25" pid="meo2Lx8jJEm3JLLiedkX2Q" hash="YmKQ9A"&gt;Sisters, we know that reaching out to others with love matters to the Lord. Consider these scriptural admonitions:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p26" pid="4eZYPjLlKUWlBlkIbtYy2w" hash="p10Pwg"&gt;“The stranger that dwelleth with you shall be unto you as one born among you, and thou shalt love him as thyself.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14"&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p27" pid="mKwxrmcq8U-T5ree2dqY6g" hash="wshKZw"&gt;“Be not forgetful to entertain strangers: for thereby some have entertained angels unawares.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15"&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p28" pid="KTBW0qfJ-ky-vNV-AEABdA" hash="1rX9Hw"&gt;And the Savior said:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p29" pid="Wg-dwoMwe0Kwz4BRsivsvQ" hash="ad-a6Q"&gt;“For I was an hungred, and ye gave me meat: I was thirsty, and ye gave me drink: I was a stranger, and ye took me in:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p30" pid="a7w5_AenqkeWMfb0KKrZVA" hash="1f3DoA"&gt;“Naked, and ye clothed me: I was sick, and ye visited me.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16"&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=zUejolLfi0K_Y_aXymceNw"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705576/0ad2c2ede7384bf885c70e261588d7ac/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705576/0ad2c2ede7384bf885c70e261588d7ac/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705576/0ad2c2ede7384bf885c70e261588d7ac/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705576/0ad2c2ede7384bf885c70e261588d7ac/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705576/0ad2c2ede7384bf885c70e261588d7ac/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705576/0ad2c2ede7384bf885c70e261588d7ac/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705576/0ad2c2ede7384bf885c70e261588d7ac/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705576/0ad2c2ede7384bf885c70e261588d7ac/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705576/0ad2c2ede7384bf885c70e261588d7ac/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1705576/0ad2c2ede7384bf885c70e261588d7ac/2790x1800.jpg" altText="The widow’s mites" pid="zUejolLfi0K_Y_aXymceNw" hash="gAYq0w"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p31" pid="GD88xMyTo0msUkX1YdZmyw" hash="CKTpxg"&gt;The Savior lovingly acknowledged the widow whose contribution was only two mites because she did what she could.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17"&gt;17&lt;/span&gt; He also told the parable of the good Samaritan, which He concluded saying, “Go, and do thou likewise.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18"&gt;18&lt;/span&gt; Sometimes reaching out is inconvenient. But when we work together in love and unity, we can expect heaven’s help.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p32" pid="PucODlH0EESLg3Le_91sDQ" hash="4tpJWA"&gt;At the funeral services for a remarkable daughter of God, someone shared that this sister, as stake Relief Society president, worked with others in her stake to contribute quilts to give warmth to suffering people in Kosovo during the 1990s. And like the good Samaritan, she went out of her way to do more as she and her daughter drove a truck filled with those quilts from London to Kosovo. On her journey home she received an unmistakable spiritual impression that sank deep into her heart. The impression was this: “What you have done is a very good thing. Now go home, walk across the street, and serve your neighbor!”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19"&gt;19&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p33" pid="V65jkTV9kkCF-OU7qxNR_A" hash="Qq_Vdw"&gt;The funeral was filled with additional inspiring accounts of how this faithful woman recognized and responded to the extraordinary and pressing calls—and also the ordinary occasions—of those within her sphere of influence. For example, she opened her home and her heart to help struggling young people at any hour—day or night.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p34" pid="06jD4mxX60O02VTZinRKSA" hash="P_wowg"&gt;My beloved sisters, we can be assured of Heavenly Father’s help as we get down on our knees and ask for divine guidance to bless His children. Heavenly Father; our Savior, Jesus Christ; and the Holy Ghost are ready to help.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p35" pid="eDbYZn42zk6kbzqJ30MUuQ" hash="5nQo1w"&gt;President Henry B. Eyring bore this powerful testimony to the women of the Church:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p36" pid="85KaouVYiUe-_ksl6ynanw" hash="uBLojQ"&gt;“Heavenly Father hears and answers your prayers of faith for guidance and for help to endure in your service for Him.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p37" pid="sFIkSpFQj0CEy5oaOiLS8w" hash="HpcRMw"&gt;“The Holy Ghost is sent to you and to those you care for. You will be strengthened and yet inspired to know the limits and extent of your ability to serve. The Spirit will comfort you when you may wonder, ‘Did I do enough?’”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20"&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger.p38" pid="Sa_e0-SzaU-ITOR_3NjiJg" hash="gx5elA"&gt;As we consider the “pressing calls” of those who need our help, let’s ask ourselves, “What if &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; story were &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; story?” May we then seek inspiration, act on impressions we receive, and reach out in unity to help those in need as we are able and inspired to do so. Perhaps then it might be said of us, as the Savior said of a loving sister who ministered to Him: “She hath wrought a good work. … She hath done what she could.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21"&gt;21&lt;/span&gt; I call that extraordinary! In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/04/i-was-a-stranger</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2016-general-conference/2016-03-0050-linda-k-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="4982855" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Certain Women</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sister Burton describes faithful women in the New Testament, in the early days of the Restoration, and in our day who have a firm and confident faith.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60003501_000_13burton" doc-version="2" hash="Amb3iA">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="XJ1A-T3fykqzPj7Q9b0jFw" hash="vKZEVg">Certain Women</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p2" pid="yT62Q70WykeD1-MYzjoq-Q" hash="EolBAA1">By Linda K. Burton</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p3" pid="OVs76NulsECljepX3z1Upg" hash="Wft9FQ">Relief Society General President</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="058haAljWkuquE0sYhDiBA" hash="GQUH6Q">Certain women are disciples centered in the Savior Jesus Christ and have hope through the promise of His atoning sacrifice.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="0P_8YRZav06SN7xl2WDNJg" hash="EolBAA">By Linda K. Burton</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p5" pid="n0Gc_7aw4Ua8n6XfVotEWw" hash="vSZabg">My beloved sisters, how we love you and thank you for your tenderhearted and enthusiastic response to the First Presidency’s invitation and the #IWasAStranger effort. Please keep praying, listening to the whisperings of the Spirit, and acting on the promptings you receive.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p6" pid="RwTrySI-7kakIO4nRwLJ8Q" hash="MUuXAg">Whether I travel locally or throughout the world, it is not unusual for someone to ask, “Do you remember me?” Because I am painfully imperfect, I must admit I often can’t remember names. However, I do remember the very real love Heavenly Father has allowed me to feel as I meet His precious daughters and sons.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p7" pid="_I8nBdT-G0KkU9SfUFnpVQ" hash="4AkjYQ">Recently I had the opportunity to visit some beloved women who are in prison. As we said our heartfelt goodbyes, one darling woman pleaded, “Sister Burton, please don’t forget us.” I hope she and others who want to be remembered will feel so as I share a few thoughts with you.</p>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.t1">
				<h2 pid="Yd_0UfpIeE25KG6aIG_ymQ" hash="DljF2Q">Certain Women in the Savior’s Day: Centered in the Savior Jesus Christ</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p9" pid="n-ucf8j5QEq6qNJkoRmQZQ" hash="mdo-Kw">Our sisters across the ages have demonstrated the faithful pattern of discipleship that we too strive for. “The New Testament includes accounts of [certain] women, named and unnamed, who exercised faith in Jesus Christ [and in His Atonement], learned and lived His teachings, and testified of His ministry, miracles, and majesty. These women became exemplary disciples and important witnesses in the work of salvation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
				<a href="gl://image/?pid=qPoFjp6p_kuS2SXSXgN_rQ"><img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908471/fbca5c1659c841c281596ef3b2cfa338/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908471/fbca5c1659c841c281596ef3b2cfa338/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908471/fbca5c1659c841c281596ef3b2cfa338/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908471/fbca5c1659c841c281596ef3b2cfa338/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908471/fbca5c1659c841c281596ef3b2cfa338/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908471/fbca5c1659c841c281596ef3b2cfa338/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908471/fbca5c1659c841c281596ef3b2cfa338/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908471/fbca5c1659c841c281596ef3b2cfa338/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908471/fbca5c1659c841c281596ef3b2cfa338/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908471/fbca5c1659c841c281596ef3b2cfa338/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Certain women" pid="qPoFjp6p_kuS2SXSXgN_rQ" hash="AAAAAA6"></img></a>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p10" pid="GzpJ1eEDek6s_hX0t64k3g" hash="g0RM2Q">Consider these accounts in the book of Luke. First, during the Savior’s ministry:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p11" pid="0k_OEoIc1kWgQv1BNxQT-w" hash="26pZXA">“And it came to pass … that [Jesus] went throughout every city and village, preaching and shewing the glad tidings of the kingdom of God: and the twelve were with him,</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p12" pid="mCiTgCKEAkuNt2AF_HeDnA" hash="OnGdnw">“And <span class="emphasis">certain women, </span>… Mary called Magdalene, … and Joanna … , and Susanna, and many others, which ministered unto him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p13" pid="OFArAJ6TrUuOsZksr6saoA" hash="AuHRcw">Next, following His Resurrection:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p14" pid="QhArk59BCkCKY0JxNLgv6Q" hash="8ULFbw">“And <span class="emphasis">certain women </span>… which were early at the sepulchre;</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p15" pid="InrH1g-XJUG2bL8gfj5Dww" hash="nOTanw">“… When they found not his body, they came, saying, that they had … seen a vision of angels, which said that he was alive.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p16" pid="Q_ylYIxkWE-Js2qC8YfQRg" hash="dvRXiQ">I have read and passed over the seemingly unremarkable expression “certain women” numerous times before, but recently as I pondered more carefully, those words seemed to jump off the page. Consider these synonyms of one meaning of the word <span class="emphasis">certain</span> as connected to faithful, <span class="emphasis">certain women</span><span class="emphasis">:</span> “convinced,” “positive,” “confident,” “firm,” “definite,” “assured,” and “dependable.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p17" pid="-ZkbNVyUZkCO3OhGoFgycA" hash="LCY-Vg">As I pondered those powerful descriptors, I remembered two of those New Testament <span class="emphasis">certain women</span> who bore positive, confident, firm, assured testimonies of the Savior. Though they, like us, were imperfect women, their witness is inspiring.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p18" pid="KnXdmKMr_EaCypgBX69bDw" hash="WD-jow">Remember the unnamed woman at the well who invited others to come and see what she had learned of the Savior? She bore her <span class="emphasis">certain </span>witness in the form of a question: “Is not this the Christ?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Her testimony and invitation were so compelling that “many … believed on him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
				<a href="gl://image/?pid=NcXmUvcP-Ee4TTot0rEF7A"><img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908465/fd72cf795a294529a7ba1676ee63b7bd/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908465/fd72cf795a294529a7ba1676ee63b7bd/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908465/fd72cf795a294529a7ba1676ee63b7bd/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908465/fd72cf795a294529a7ba1676ee63b7bd/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908465/fd72cf795a294529a7ba1676ee63b7bd/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908465/fd72cf795a294529a7ba1676ee63b7bd/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908465/fd72cf795a294529a7ba1676ee63b7bd/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908465/fd72cf795a294529a7ba1676ee63b7bd/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908465/fd72cf795a294529a7ba1676ee63b7bd/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908465/fd72cf795a294529a7ba1676ee63b7bd/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Martha bears testimony of the Savior" pid="NcXmUvcP-Ee4TTot0rEF7A" hash="AAAAAA5"></img></a>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p19" pid="noniKDNxF0a5-JqTlj3Ulw" hash="VPYsxQ">Following the death of her brother, Lazarus, Martha, the beloved disciple and friend of the Lord, declared with what must have been great emotion, “Lord, if thou hadst been here, my brother had not died.” Consider her certainty as she continued, “<span class="emphasis">But I know,</span> that even now, whatsoever thou wilt ask of God, God will give it thee.” She further testified, “I believe that thou art the Christ, the Son of God, which should come into the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p20" pid="HNWKz0mh8UWxRmLHHbV4XQ" hash="PDpPWQ">We learn from these sisters that <span class="emphasis">certain women</span> are disciples centered in the Savior Jesus Christ and have hope through the promise of His atoning sacrifice.</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.t2">
				<h2 pid="7QV2z1PEXkqUDXawMB5jNg" hash="OkevmQ">Certain Covenant-Keeping Women of the Restoration: Willing to Sacrifice</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p22" pid="AiqRNJaIfkOx35ieCaUjtA" hash="IIzlng">Anciently,<span class="emphasis"> certain women</span> sacrificed as they testified and lived the teachings of Jesus. <span class="emphasis">Certain women</span> in the early days of the Restoration did the same. Drusilla Hendricks and her family were among those who, as new converts, suffered during the persecution of the Saints in Clay County, Missouri. Her husband was permanently paralyzed during the Battle of Crooked River. She was left to care for him as well as provide for her family.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p23" pid="0NqEK4iTpEioDDd2FkiajA" hash="1WLDlQ">“At one particularly distressing time, when the family was out of food, she remembered that a voice told her, ‘Hold on, for the Lord will provide.’”</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p24" pid="Vg2p5OK7rUW25PM3ml2PPg" hash="8nnEYA">When her son was needed to volunteer for the Mormon Battalion, at first Drusilla resisted and wrestled in prayer with Heavenly Father until “it was as though a voice said to her, ‘Do you not want the highest glory?’ She answered naturally, ‘Yes,’ and the voice continued, ‘How do you think to gain it save by making the greatest sacrifices?’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p25" pid="ibwlxjb8YkqAIHHAgUjxnQ" hash="JIVuMA">We learn from this <span class="emphasis">certain woman</span> that covenant-keeping discipleship requires our willingness to sacrifice.</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.t3">
				<h2 pid="NHximnQJTUexHtrezvReOQ" hash="k6y29Q">Certain Women Today: Remembering and Preparing to Celebrate His Return</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p27" pid="T_qltoGKT0ShGGo-SJvEpQ" hash="FtCj7g">I have mentioned <span class="emphasis">certain women</span> in the Savior’s day and in the early days of the Restoration of the gospel, but what about examples of discipleship and testimonies of <span class="emphasis">certain women</span> in our own day?</p>
				<a href="gl://image/?pid=LxGuhTonHEi7AEfb2L3NmQ"><img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908453/6169a8c0a12c4234bcc2c1d1b27ac851/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908453/6169a8c0a12c4234bcc2c1d1b27ac851/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908453/6169a8c0a12c4234bcc2c1d1b27ac851/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908453/6169a8c0a12c4234bcc2c1d1b27ac851/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908453/6169a8c0a12c4234bcc2c1d1b27ac851/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908453/6169a8c0a12c4234bcc2c1d1b27ac851/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908453/6169a8c0a12c4234bcc2c1d1b27ac851/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908453/6169a8c0a12c4234bcc2c1d1b27ac851/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908453/6169a8c0a12c4234bcc2c1d1b27ac851/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908453/6169a8c0a12c4234bcc2c1d1b27ac851/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Sister Burton with sisters in Asia" pid="LxGuhTonHEi7AEfb2L3NmQ" hash="AAAAAA4"></img></a>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p28" pid="aPqoMFnJnkyadsPsAWIzIQ" hash="WSdiew">On my recent assignment to Asia, I was once again inspired by the many <span class="emphasis">certain women</span> I met. I was particularly impressed with first-generation members in India, Malaysia, and Indonesia who strive to live the gospel culture in their own homes, sometimes at great sacrifice, as gospel living often clashes with family and country cultures. The multigenerational <span class="emphasis">certain women</span> I met in Hong Kong and Taiwan continue to bless the lives of their families, Church members, and communities by remaining centered in the Savior and willingly sacrificing to keep covenants. Similar <span class="emphasis">certain women</span> are found throughout the Church.</p>
				<a href="gl://image/?pid=5emcuBKMn0aYrOQ4a2y6pA"><img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908454/6b76efcd53e94530b83167e2cf37a9ad/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908454/6b76efcd53e94530b83167e2cf37a9ad/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908454/6b76efcd53e94530b83167e2cf37a9ad/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908454/6b76efcd53e94530b83167e2cf37a9ad/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908454/6b76efcd53e94530b83167e2cf37a9ad/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908454/6b76efcd53e94530b83167e2cf37a9ad/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908454/6b76efcd53e94530b83167e2cf37a9ad/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908454/6b76efcd53e94530b83167e2cf37a9ad/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908454/6b76efcd53e94530b83167e2cf37a9ad/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908454/6b76efcd53e94530b83167e2cf37a9ad/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Sister Burton with sisters in Asia" pid="5emcuBKMn0aYrOQ4a2y6pA" hash="AAAAAA3"></img></a>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p29" pid="BFIUrVhM4U2ZS9_Wk-T9NA" hash="s5vx9g">A <span class="emphasis">certain woman </span>who has blessed my life for decades has battled for the past 15 years the debilitating, difficult, and progressive disease called inclusion body myositis. Though confined to her wheelchair, she strives to be grateful and keeps up her “Can Can List”: a running list of things she <span class="emphasis">can</span> do, such as I can breathe, I can swallow, I can pray, and I can feel my Savior’s love. She bears her Christ-centered <span class="emphasis">certain</span> witness almost daily to family and friends.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p30" pid="uBZ7RFjW0EOstECQFLdUJQ" hash="aWfpOQ">I recently heard Jenny’s story. She is a returned missionary whose parents divorced while she was serving her mission. She told how the thought of returning home “scared [her] to death.” But at the end of her mission to Italy, as she stopped in the mission home on her way home to the United States, a <span class="emphasis">certain woman,</span> the mission president’s wife, tenderly ministered to her simply by brushing her hair.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p31" pid="0ob9wt1maUGhJtJqT1b8WQ" hash="z6ritg">Years later, another <span class="emphasis">certain woman,</span> Terry—a stake Relief Society president and disciple of Jesus Christ—blessed Jenny’s life when Jenny was called as a ward Relief Society president. At that time, Jenny was working on her dissertation for her doctoral degree. Not only did Terry serve as a mentor to Jenny as a leader, but she also sat with her for 10 hours at the hospital when Jenny received the alarming diagnosis of leukemia. Terry visited the hospital and drove Jenny to appointments. Jenny confessed, “I think I may have thrown up several times in her car.”</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p32" pid="pS_-7jsFo0uEy2gEvkx_9A" hash="os-P0Q">Despite her illness, Jenny continued to serve valiantly as the ward Relief Society president. Even in her extremity, she made phone calls and sent texts and emails from her bed, and she invited sisters to come see her. She mailed cards and notes to people, loving her sisters from a distance. When her ward requested a photograph of her presidency for their ward history, this is what they got. Because Jenny is a <span class="emphasis">certain woman </span>herself, she invited all to share others’ burdens, including her own.</p>
				<a href="gl://image/?pid=lHvCMue2YUSkvy40yBZEIg"><img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908462/26130b8af32c4e378a268fb90c83d28b/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908462/26130b8af32c4e378a268fb90c83d28b/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908462/26130b8af32c4e378a268fb90c83d28b/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908462/26130b8af32c4e378a268fb90c83d28b/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908462/26130b8af32c4e378a268fb90c83d28b/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908462/26130b8af32c4e378a268fb90c83d28b/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908462/26130b8af32c4e378a268fb90c83d28b/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908462/26130b8af32c4e378a268fb90c83d28b/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908462/26130b8af32c4e378a268fb90c83d28b/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908462/26130b8af32c4e378a268fb90c83d28b/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Ward Relief Society presidency wearing hats" pid="lHvCMue2YUSkvy40yBZEIg" hash="AAAAAA2"></img></a>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p33" pid="_sZ-4On4zke4rixVtAWo9Q" hash="I45oyg">As a <span class="emphasis">certain woman,</span> Jenny testified: “Not only are we here to save others but to save ourselves. And that salvation comes from partnering with Jesus Christ, from understanding His grace and His Atonement and His feelings of love for the women of the Church. That happens through things as simple as brushing someone’s hair; sending a note with an inspired, clear, revelatory message of hope and grace; or allowing women to serve us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p34" pid="KPMLTU7shU2DIPUXJBcIXA" hash="AHIMeQ">Sisters, when we have become distracted, doubtful, discouraged, sinful, sorrowful, or soul-stretched, may we accept the Lord’s invitation to drink of His living water, as did the <span class="emphasis">certain </span>woman at the well, inviting others to do the same as we bear our own <span class="emphasis">certain </span>witness: “Is not this the Christ?”</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p35" pid="tEWBBKrBuU2ZVxz10LzGew" hash="9bJGHg">When life seems unfair, as it must have seemed to Martha at the death of her brother—when we experience the heartaches of loneliness, infertility, loss of loved ones, missing opportunities for marriage and family, broken homes, debilitating depression, physical or mental illness, stifling stress, anxiety, addiction, financial hardship, or a plethora of other possibilities—may we remember Martha and declare our similar <span class="emphasis">certain</span> witness: “<span class="emphasis">But I know … [and] I believe</span> that thou art the Christ, the Son of God.”</p>
				<a href="gl://image/?pid=g8535Gl8JUWYD9bpvR0IWg"><img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908466/0d8d349a464540388663195b2eb19bdc/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908466/0d8d349a464540388663195b2eb19bdc/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908466/0d8d349a464540388663195b2eb19bdc/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908466/0d8d349a464540388663195b2eb19bdc/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908466/0d8d349a464540388663195b2eb19bdc/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908466/0d8d349a464540388663195b2eb19bdc/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908466/0d8d349a464540388663195b2eb19bdc/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908466/0d8d349a464540388663195b2eb19bdc/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908466/0d8d349a464540388663195b2eb19bdc/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908466/0d8d349a464540388663195b2eb19bdc/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Women at the cross" pid="g8535Gl8JUWYD9bpvR0IWg" hash="AAAAAA1"></img></a>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p36" pid="ia4UImenVEut5OOatrFs7g" hash="tTt_Bw">May we remember the many <span class="emphasis">certain women</span> who refused to abandon our precious Savior during the excruciating experience He suffered on the cross and yet hours later were privileged to be among the <span class="emphasis">certain </span>witnesses of His glorious Resurrection. Let us be found staying close to Him in prayer and scripture study. Let us draw ourselves near to Him by preparing for and partaking of the sacred emblems of His atoning sacrifice weekly during the ordinance of the sacrament and as we keep covenants by serving others in their times of need. Perhaps then we might be part of the <span class="emphasis">certain women,</span> disciples of Jesus Christ, who will celebrate His glorious return when He comes again.</p>
				<a href="gl://image/?pid=fjwuPgd4KUCl5d_wi-CAtw"><img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908470/a5e99c0d742641358d6b279f708b8dce/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908470/a5e99c0d742641358d6b279f708b8dce/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908470/a5e99c0d742641358d6b279f708b8dce/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908470/a5e99c0d742641358d6b279f708b8dce/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908470/a5e99c0d742641358d6b279f708b8dce/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908470/a5e99c0d742641358d6b279f708b8dce/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908470/a5e99c0d742641358d6b279f708b8dce/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908470/a5e99c0d742641358d6b279f708b8dce/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908470/a5e99c0d742641358d6b279f708b8dce/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1908470/a5e99c0d742641358d6b279f708b8dce/2790x1800.jpg" altText="The Savior at the Second Coming" pid="fjwuPgd4KUCl5d_wi-CAtw" hash="AAAAAA"></img></a>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p37" pid="MKRO61E6CkORqd_BJbLwxQ" hash="fKbFXw">Sisters, I testify of loving Heavenly Parents; of our Savior, Jesus Christ; and of His infinite Atonement in our behalf. I know the Prophet Joseph Smith was foreordained as the prophet of the Restoration. I know the Book of Mormon is true and was translated by the power of God. We have been blessed with a living prophet in our own day, President Thomas S. Monson. Of these truths I am <span class="emphasis">certain</span>! In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women.p38" pid="bVnjdwv1l0yoE2hcOzd0aw" hash="FUGuYw"><span class="emphasis">Note: On April 1, 2017, Sister Burton was released as Relief Society General President.</span></p>
			</div>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2017/04/certain-women</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2017-general-conference/2017-03-0030-linda-k-burton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5698674" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
