<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Loren C. Dunn</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Loren C. Dunn.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Loren%20C.%20Dunn.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Loren C. Dunn.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Drink of the Pure Water</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Consider these words of the Savior as he spoke to the woman of Samaria at Jacob’s well: “Whosoever drinketh of this water shall thirst again:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03006_000_5050" doc-version="2" hash="OuMaKw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="QTjmEnh6aU22C0n3-ByuIw" hash="r62h0A">Drink of the Pure Water</h1><p class="authorName" guid="1a14b2cb-b5b2-48cb-a012-92bb04af8eeb" pid="pch_BKq4fUqGQcNQoT17lA" hash="osADdw">Loren C. Dunn</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="9a6fd871-eb3f-431a-8c7d-0c6a8c945387">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2b58.jpg" alt="President Loren C. Dunn" guid="e4de6f2b-6fe2-4eeb-87fd-2841c0a043d1" pid="QKbomheQJEmaCaMZ5CJVrQ" hash="kckzdw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p1" guid="7efabd71-3409-4426-8030-fb0c3d634003" pid="WcM0H3NeQk6QvoiIv-2rTQ" hash="yv5hiQ">Consider these words of the Savior as he spoke to the woman of Samaria at Jacob’s well: “Whosoever drinketh of this water shall thirst again:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p2" guid="1fb9b1e8-cb70-41c2-8b0b-9f574ac8b5cb" pid="xTFdVS6VQkiXQ9WsWtT8Uw" hash="41uxcw">“But whosoever drinketh of the water that I shall give him shall never thirst; but the water that I shall give him shall be in him a well of water springing up into everlasting life.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/4.13-14" class="scriptureRef">John 4:13–14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p3" guid="e47dc766-7571-4b20-af28-28b90bda3e82" pid="zlmiQmDpv0KzYx2q6h87Dg" hash="_pvKDg">What greater way to demonstrate the saving, healing principles of the gospel of Jesus Christ than to relate them to life-sustaining water—water that is essential for every human being in order to live.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p4" guid="599604a7-b064-4081-ba5a-140b54b80731" pid="-HuXrChwlEyxc2ucl4E5pA" hash="c-QbCw">The Savior was telling the woman that if she drank from her well she would thirst again, but if she drank from his well and partook of the principles that he taught, she would never thirst again, but her soul would be nourished and she would have eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p5" guid="5806503b-9c8b-4a85-a32a-62ea885d71c4" pid="PPXZD50t4EqVq4G5jTSVPQ" hash="Np8xBg">We live in a complex and challenging world. Young and old seem to be going to and fro and in their own way drinking from different wells, searching for that water that will begin to feed their souls, that will quench some inner thirst.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p6" guid="29854bf3-01c6-4a8e-b696-1378932d7f2d" pid="mSCfHh4UPUKemDQjADLHVg" hash="6P0vRQ">To youth who associate themselves with various causes, some popular, many designed to accomplish much good, and a few militant; to the adult who can find no satisfaction in his vocation and perhaps only frustration in his marriage and emptiness in his life; to the militant who spends his life bitterly denouncing what he is against but never quite certain what he is for; to the person who turns to drugs, perhaps even attempting to equate it with a spiritual experience, and then realizing that for every high there is some kind of dismal low—perhaps these people and many others seize upon special issues and act unpredictably more from an inner need to satisfy a yearning soul than because of the face value of that in which they are involved, however worthy it may be.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p7" guid="38881371-3a59-46f7-9ac6-3e0e476bafc9" pid="PSsBQlx_2UqOmDVx2gqZrQ" hash="auvXvA">Even in Russia, where its people have drunk at the well of socialist morality for fifty years, there is an indication of a desire for something more nourishing. In studying religion in Russia today, journalist Paul Wohl states that “socialist morality has been accepted as the official yardstick of good behavior, but whether Soviet man is more harmonious than his predecessor is a moot question. A scientific outlook is there,” says Wohl, “but so is religion. Its comeback,” he says, “is a phenomenon which the ideologists of communism cannot explain and about which they prefer to remain silent.” He states that the move toward religion is primarily sparked by young people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p8" guid="bf82c61c-3842-408f-b05f-b2ef76e0513c" pid="jpPqvJ0n4UGo7h-k6pTUcw" hash="19_Vow">The writer tells of a simple Russian woman who received the visit of her neighbor, a young engineer-physicist. “I know you are a believer,” said the engineer. “Can you tell me about God? The philosophy of dialectical materialism does not satisfy me. I would like to know the viewpoint of believers.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p9" guid="c30526b8-5328-4486-9e91-31fc030f7d7e" pid="MaEqoSxtTEq89I-sh2lb3g" hash="AHCTZA">It is most interesting to note that there is something fundamental and basic in the makeup of man that will sooner or later turn him to his Creator, provided he does not completely strangle this inclination through evil works on chronic unbelief, and provided he doesn’t condition himself to settle for less by insisting that what he doesn’t know or hasn’t experienced just isn’t so.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p10" guid="79654b93-b402-4a3f-91d1-e26eae7b2195" pid="hn8VCj-zoUuBK7IPEh9zlw" hash="L7jadw">Speaking of the Savior, the prophet Alma says:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p11" guid="e7a12340-5592-4ddc-bd80-056d4439ad25" pid="-E0GK3ozSUqZ6wDt6Pct3A" hash="5wTgCw">“Behold, he sendeth an invitation unto all men, for the arms of mercy are extended towards them, and he saith: Repent, and I will receive you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p12" guid="341ecf3b-f393-4361-bb9a-51e305bb6032" pid="knPb1ppj1UmKKPI3IsHmow" hash="G2XFIw">“Yea, he saith: Come unto me and ye shall partake of the fruit of the tree of life; yea, ye shall eat and drink of the bread and the waters of life freely;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p13" guid="48f628a3-5ef2-478e-a141-7a888d0bfccb" pid="0RcCVnC53Eu2lO1UYtMsIw" hash="zPvbnw">“Behold, I say unto you, that the good shepherd doth call you; yea, and in his own name he doth call you, which is the name of Christ. …” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.33-34,38" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:33–34, 38</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p14" guid="66f17469-bb7d-4cd6-b5a9-314c1da2be77" pid="U5G08Z91rky77iQ4bnrWFQ" hash="0bDEaQ">And after Alma teaches the people those things relative to the gospel of Jesus Christ and what they can do in order to nourish their souls, and find peace, and prepare for eternal life, he then says:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p15" guid="4f0189c2-d1e0-407b-8848-f36d02090ab4" pid="1oJgBN4KYkm_LvjAZeuyIw" hash="9Dl8Dw">“And now I, Alma, do command you in the language of him who hath commanded me, that ye observe to do the words which I have spoken unto you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p16" guid="f9d8b98d-8811-428d-a57b-ed99acab687e" pid="818FR1hQVkiGtzXkDZq_aQ" hash="4r67jg">“I speak by way of command unto you that belong to the church; and unto those who do not belong to the church I speak by way of invitation, saying: Come and be baptized unto repentance, that ye also may be partakers of the fruit of the tree of life.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.61-62" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:61–62</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p17" guid="589b1860-3bde-4174-8e4f-e97b1b648cd1" pid="Sgq6ioTgLEWiZI7TLWhfxA" hash="Veko3g">As this last scripture indicates, it is possible for a person to have the fruit of the tree of salvation readily available to him, but to no avail if he does not partake!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p18" guid="a483fced-0fc6-428c-9208-cbd6f9569b37" pid="fsznMS1bcUyZpUP6ndPpTw" hash="kvzo5A">I am reminded of two young men who came in to see me some months ago. They had been recommended by their priesthood leaders. From the moment they stepped into the office, they began in a very sincere way questioning certain doctrines and teachings and procedures of the Church. Their attitude, however, was not antagonistic, as they were sincerely looking for answers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p19" guid="c3b10f70-1ae2-4a60-90d8-216d2d3ebdd0" pid="K8TvGEOySE62FXOPkSBasg" hash="AAEQMQ">I asked them finally if their questions perhaps represented the symptoms of their problem and not the cause. Wasn’t their real question whether or not this church is true? Whether or not it is actually the Church of Jesus Christ? And whether or not it is led by divine revelation? The young men agreed that perhaps if they were sure of the answers to these questions, they could take care of the other questions that seemed to arise in their hearts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p20" guid="ad9a73fe-60ce-4937-81f5-ae384d486496" pid="CzugkxYu10WYkJsTxfI-FA" hash="nBN2qw">I asked them if they were willing to participate in an experiment. One of them appeared to be athletically inclined, and so I turned to him and asked, “If you wanted to learn about the chemical properties of water, would you go to the local sports stadium and run four laps around the track?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p21" guid="053a3b61-7541-4ef6-b1a0-2356204e92ac" pid="v3LNAc5HI0emx-N_Eviqrg" hash="C-hW0g">He said, “Of course not.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p22" guid="df6db273-3e0c-4e4e-b89f-fa8e1c03302a" pid="9Fue-lbNNkaQnXVcj2SYgw" hash="Nap_Vw">I asked, “Why not?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p23" guid="0d33b17c-67b9-4862-9fe5-93a46500540d" pid="oFhWLCEpM0qq78c69uQ27A" hash="ZfwSgA">He said, “The two are not related.” We then turned to John, chapter seven, and read: “If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it he of God, or whether I speak of myself.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/7.17" class="scriptureRef">John 7:17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p24" guid="2d4fb329-a70d-4496-a0d3-aa4ab352e0c4" pid="sXtLG4ZSskO53jbarhGveA" hash="uDAOCg">If we are going to experiment with the things of Christ, then we are going to have to put these things to a spiritual test—a test that the Savior himself has outlined for all those who wish to know, a test of doing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p25" guid="8f3bcdd8-94de-47d0-bd6e-d41720158ccb" pid="VAQwQbURnUS87dY16hn2cA" hash="r69LwQ">I asked them if they read the scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p26" guid="19a2e632-d22f-44d3-9fe6-dc7119a5ab1a" pid="0JtSorSMf0unQYROxIZckQ" hash="_Pn0ww">They said, “No.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p27" guid="12838243-0ce2-483f-9d42-9ac6c043fade" pid="Vw7x0xKodk2iVXA0KQ62sQ" hash="HaxQLg">I asked them if they prayed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p28" guid="4f0054bc-6731-4744-85af-ddab0ce573bc" pid="VCfL05ubkEqke3m_IskVEg" hash="oroE7A">They said, “Not often.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p29" guid="05d42a54-d508-42be-8a0a-0c9c0b58dd6b" pid="ERwaOpp5XE-taJ8A8Jd2qg" hash="c1pqRA">I asked them if they kept the Word of Wisdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p30" guid="78c0f9f8-51e4-4ba0-9b41-e1acb980baab" pid="PTq8RuFbMk-NR9LhnD7pqw" hash="GvvkLQ">They said, “Occasionally.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p31" guid="52b03ccf-e2fb-4bc0-81ca-b1b6905ecfda" pid="960p469PgEO2PI3coPbAIQ" hash="a5fLgg">I asked them if they went to church. They said they’d stopped.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p32" guid="e0d7fddb-26a6-442d-b0be-bd3533eb0c88" pid="NA6Z5j7vTkG6XLWVEogcUw" hash="xUxrFw">I asked them if they would be interested in a three-month experiment. They said they would try but were not anxious to commit themselves until they found out what I had in mind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p33" guid="b1310c01-41e8-4ee1-8ca2-a50712f46cc3" pid="JjliR8aaG0WyOKFn5ddcIg" hash="PhWmKg">“During the next three months will you attend all your church meetings and listen carefully to what is being said, even taking notes of the principal points being made by the teachers and how these points might apply to your lives?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p34" guid="63d6d0fa-42c2-479f-b3bc-030892f532b5" pid="Yj9xPt_oyUCCpS9Vct1BPQ" hash="Vt_BxA">They thought for a moment and said they would.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p35" guid="4795f964-cdb2-4930-bd92-b26aaa04c3f1" pid="4li8uqs4SkmwiTejKhloKg" hash="qQ6BBA">“During the next three months will you reinstitute in your personal life prayer, night and morning, thanking God for the blessings you enjoy and asking him to help you know if the Church is true and if the things you are doing are meaningful to your lives?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p36" guid="9b393973-af27-4cd5-bf08-15bcf46aa44c" pid="p8KX8f-dREy24tfezTIFmg" hash="GFJc3w">One of these young men, who considered himself an agnostic, balked at this, but then he finally agreed to do it on the basis that for the sake of the experiment he would accept the premise that there is a God and would appeal to this God for the light and knowledge which he was seeking.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p37" guid="b5da3143-6d89-4178-bb2b-75b2f8221b5f" pid="9zipY3k-6EiI9indYPHd6g" hash="Whp8UA">I asked them if in the next three months they would refrain from drinking, smoking, and drugs. Although this created some anxiety, they resolved to do it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p38" guid="882f4e19-7e7d-4ff8-a9c1-3c22630a6bac" pid="7erAK5rRrEKHzgsMnuSAVw" hash="V_dryA">I asked them if in the next three months they would resolve to keep themselves morally clean and in harmony with the principles of virtue which the Savior taught. They said they would. And then I suggested they establish a schedule, on their own, during the next three months to read the Book of Mormon from cover to cover—a few pages each day, with a prayer at each reading that the Lord would bless them to know if the book is true and actually from him. They agreed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p39" guid="fd99a57f-efaa-4d03-85d0-1a688b1e70e8" pid="aoyFnKWRmkGmzfWjhOa2hw" hash="yoknnA">Anticipating what might happen, I said, “Now, if you feel disposed to tell your friends about this, probably their first comment will be ‘Boy, has Brother Dunn snowed you.’ You may even feel that way a time or two during this experiment, but don’t let it keep you from doing what you have agreed to do. If you think that might be a problem, then keep it in the back of your mind, and go ahead and honestly experiment, and let this three-month experience speak for itself.” I added, “If things go properly, you’ll notice some by-products, such as a growing awareness and concern for your fellowman and greater appreciation and consideration for other people.” They accepted the challenge and left.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p40" guid="5f753e85-0bb6-499d-9b19-3f21a248f1ec" pid="vig3ant1XU2Oahii_ei5hA" hash="lSi_jw">Of course, what was really hoped for was the experience that every member has a right to enjoy and everyone else has the right to receive, and that is the knowledge of a personal testimony. I think Brigham Young described it best when he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p41" guid="d513a1b4-29d4-4c64-82fe-f6e6f0ce3bc0" pid="zmG29F-lvU-iYsSnFNeq5A" hash="69DOYw">“There is no other experience known to mortal man that can be compared with the testimony or witness of the Holy Ghost. It is as powerful as a two-edged sword and burns in the breast of man like a consuming fire. It destroys fear and doubt, leaving in their stead absolute unqualified, and incontrovertible knowledge that a principle or thing is true. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p42" guid="4dbb336f-4f38-482e-a7ec-94325ee804fa" pid="PlwoQySEKk-aPOE9Rae_RA" hash="7U_4yg">“This same testimony has sustained faithful saints to the present day and will be a lamp to their path forever. The effect of this testimony reaches above and beyond all physical or earthly things and makes relationship with God the Father a literal, pulsing fact. Every fiber of both body and spirit respond to the witness of that testimony and the soul knows and lives the truth.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p43" guid="dd380df7-0100-46b6-9f2b-46f49a7eb150" pid="1FT__qqtZUuwwsxByhodPw" hash="CXYY1g">And so to those who have tasted the water at many wells only to find that the unquenching thirst of the soul drives them on in search of that which will bring peace and nourishment to the heart—to you, whoever you are, member or nonmember—will you come and drink from this well, and taste and experiment and see if you have not found the waters of life where you can drink to your soul and thirst no more but be full with the joy of the true knowledge of Jesus Christ and his teachings and the purpose of your own life?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water.p44" guid="1d2f3b93-4bc3-46ec-85ac-f3c25e5f5d72" pid="yVaJTAyGs0iqAP02RbDFxA" hash="qtf4rQ">And to this invitation I bear you my witness that I know God lives. I know he lives and that Jesus Christ is our Redeemer and his Son. Joseph Smith saw what he said he saw, and we have a prophet of God sitting with us, presiding today. I bear you that witness in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/04/drink-of-the-pure-water</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1971-general-conference/1971-04-5050-elder-loren-c-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="6721151" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“This Is My Beloved Son”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son?lang=eng</link>
      <description>From the sixty-eighth section of the Doctrine and Covenants come these familiar words: “And again, inasmuch as parents have children in Zion, or in any of her stakes which are organized, that teach them not to understand the doctrine of repentance, f</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03012_000_1050" doc-version="2" hash="fD-4Hg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="S5nMdBY2A0isB18iRA_CNA" hash="t3FOwQ">“This Is My Beloved Son”</h1><p class="authorName" guid="1a14b2cb-b5b2-48cb-a012-92bb04af8eeb" pid="EtsFc0But0KiLzlA9N3pVw" hash="osADdw">Loren C. Dunn</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="9d8050ed-1709-45e8-95bb-237b48441e90">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2b58.jpg" alt="Conference photo" guid="5f1b7f19-999c-43b8-b6e2-7749a86d7db8" pid="-RU5JpCQPEiXZLyit_Co4Q" hash="kckzdw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p1" guid="a8196674-16b6-4989-92b4-d3c2e98cfc2f" pid="nUx2nVhcgkOoHDjEElZT-w" hash="IPo0NA">From the sixty-eighth section of the Doctrine and Covenants come these familiar words: “And again, inasmuch as parents have children in Zion, or in any of her stakes which are organized, that teach them not to understand the doctrine of repentance, faith in Christ the Son of the living God, and of baptism and the gift of the Holy Ghost by the laying on of the hands, when eight years old, the sin be upon the heads of the parents.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p2" guid="c912c5aa-8480-4626-be12-4124059a2fa3" pid="Ggs1WDCiuUS9nlOl4Fj1RQ" hash="NasFnQ">“For this shall be a law unto the inhabitants of Zion, or in any of her stakes which are organized.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p3" guid="3aa3e6e0-de2e-4d06-964b-672176eedb5e" pid="MWCwVrR9s0mPD7rxprMJjA" hash="6txZaA">“And their children shall be baptized for the remission of their sins when eight years old, and receive the laying on of the hands.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p4" guid="b4f8d1d9-4cba-4454-8c5f-568e8ae2f72e" pid="fLzl4NwueEyGS9uw3sJD8Q" hash="kZSaDw">“And they shall also teach their children to pray, and to walk uprightly before the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.25-28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:25–28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p5" guid="49d331f1-1e79-4de5-a2ea-3814172232c5" pid="nhfLACqsWku4yaIbCdX2VA" hash="tuYr6w">To help us with these sacred responsibilities, the Lord has given us the revelation of family home evening. But at the basis of the successful home evening there has to be the proper relationship between the parents and the other members of the family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p6" guid="6370281d-2bb7-4816-98d2-afef87cb065d" pid="dMEoFCXCuUWrGlmzCWJCuw" hash="mVlqgA">For instance, I believe there is no finer relationship in all the world than the special one that can exist between a father and his children—a relationship born of love and those deep abiding feelings which are initially there by instinct and later nurtured and developed by love and kindness and consideration.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p7" guid="aa7feea5-161e-4c7e-b70a-65c9fee1f2a6" pid="x5XUctq2Bk-G-u7XX4Tlaw" hash="9lyUlQ">I mention here the relationship of a father to his children—not to demean in any way the tremendous role of the mother, but having never been a mother, I feel that I am not qualified to speak from that point of view. Not only that, but I firmly believe that, generally speaking, the mothers of the Church are in need of a little more help from the fathers of the Church in building those special ties between parents and children that tend to make the family organization a little bit of heaven on earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p8" guid="1043a9ab-8d32-4e7d-9263-e543a9886ac1" pid="I_Ur1zBZ2UyXABuDlReceg" hash="bPPmaQ">I am impressed by the fact that the plan of redemption and salvation for all mankind was worked out between a father and his son, even God the Father and his Son Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p9" guid="ac50d50f-1a89-4db9-87e5-9d22de352cb5" pid="MHD70-UrMkWvaOtzA5m_gg" hash="OQWN5Q">I believe that one of the significant parts of the Joseph Smith story was when the angel Moroni told young Joseph to go to his father and relate to him everything that had happened.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p10" guid="24576921-9a0b-49f9-b8b6-2d1e98ed77f9" pid="UtL5gg5Sp06awuuxX3MTlg" hash="aii0_Q">Even in the restoration of the gospel of Jesus Christ, the Lord was careful to recognize the relationship of this young boy to his father, and he made sure that nothing would damage it. Yes, the association of a father with his children can and should be a very special one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p11" guid="e43ba3d1-708f-4029-b036-b49fc74c711f" pid="AH9a1FnsaUmaEO0Bf6BR6Q" hash="QVuN8Q">Certainly the outcome of children cannot always be predicted, and sometimes under the best circumstances something happens that will cause a member of the family to go astray. While these things are sometimes hard to understand, nevertheless, more than one life has been retrieved and altered, for the good, because of the undying love of a father for his son or daughter—a love that will tend to ease the frustrations that young people experience as they try to find themselves amid a conflict of ideals and standards.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p12" guid="a227f91a-8ad0-4c9d-8131-7f971c4b5775" pid="lemuZmb39UmFUSApfjLkDw" hash="Eo1q1A">One commentator described a typical youth of today as one who is “told he must be strong, beautiful, brave, and so on—a Boy Scout with jet set sophistication. He is swamped with plugs for beer, cigarettes, credit cards, and trips to Hawaii. It is suggested to the girl that she is a flat failure unless she looks like an oversized Hollywood queen. No wonder the poor child feels pain when he measures himself against what he is told is the ideal. How to ease the minds of the young is one of the hardest things. It is no good to say it doesn’t matter, because it does. It is no good to say that it only hurts for a little while, like hanging. But it might help if the youngster could be convinced that, in spite of the mismatch between himself and the false ideals held up before him, he possesses as much human worth as the next one and need not despair.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p13" guid="18e3a503-faea-4605-a0e7-d7834b9d4cb4" pid="PRQeeEO7G0OXRNXN6Jz1hA" hash="5FgGOg">This conflict of ideals and standards between what a young person is taught to do by the Church and what is expected by the world creates tremendous frustration, and certainly a father is in the best position to begin to bring these things into perspective, to help his son or daughter understand what is, and is not, important in life, to be there to reassure and to love and to make his children feel important, and to help them to be themselves and to stay close to their standards.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p14" guid="7da05ce6-d232-49cb-8286-2359038a1019" pid="7jcu8lHFjEqQtbpJTZYtig" hash="QG05wg">Someone once said that the middle-aged and the old forget how keenly the young are affected and by what. The young haven’t had any experience with this amazing process called youth, and we all need to realize that.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p15" guid="285a22ec-4869-4b42-b33c-527b1020e2b6" pid="GLQ-sJNiNEikJkCYCzH2IQ" hash="7rDh-g">As a father in the Church attempts to be a father to his children, there are occasionally some special conflicts. In the 75th section of the Doctrine and Covenants the Lord says: “And again, verily I say unto you, that every man who is obliged to provide for his own family, let him provide, and he shall in nowise lose his crown; and let him labor in the church.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/75.28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 75:28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p16" guid="ea7d4630-f64a-4a8c-9725-79100a84fb70" pid="WWYeBchfLE-YtyKM-UDOtA" hash="T3Azpg">This spells out two basic responsibilities: providing for our families and laboring in the Church. There arise questions sometimes as to a seeming conflict between a father’s duty to his family and the many church responsibilities that might be his.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p17" guid="af4ee39a-91bd-40d4-a47b-6f9b1e5a93ac" pid="KIPOCH6jq0CnHfPknr3WGA" hash="PQzAEg">In response to this, certainly all church leaders who have responsibility for organizing and calling administrative meetings should realize that a well-planned, well-organized meeting with the beginning and ending times determined, in advance, will not only make the maximum use of time but will make it easier for the brethren who attend these meetings to receive the support of their wives and children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p18" guid="4b446425-f0f2-439b-8923-b35aac88d8a0" pid="GAvH-sSn_U-8kJdDIPDdDQ" hash="YSg7GA">A well-planned meeting means that the family knows when they can expect the husband or father home. A well-planned meeting makes the maximum use of time and, therefore, cuts down on the number of intermediate meetings that might needlessly take the father away from the home. Certainly well-planned and well-scheduled meetings are as much a blessing to the families of the fathers of the Church as they are to those fathers who attend the meetings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p19" guid="e8a28de0-741f-412e-ade9-a8b717f1ca79" pid="yU7w-1p4s0qOmyq-Con94w" hash="WvnIuA">On the other hand, as the verse just read in the Doctrine and Covenants indicates, the Lord expects us to take care of our families and to also attend to our duties in the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p20" guid="ce30b592-9217-4bf8-9142-38ecb1176e19" pid="olTBuzH3DkCK-8Nwjml_yQ" hash="6vHtTg">It may not always be true that a heavy load of church responsibilities is the reason a father does not draw close to his family. My father was a stake president for twenty years. He was installed when I was six and released when I was twenty-six. I can hardly remember a time in my youth when he was not stake president. He had a very large stake, and it took a great deal of his time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p21" guid="60deff77-1587-425b-ba4a-8fd9fdf708f2" pid="P9UYsyNYOkSzw1rk-IQWzQ" hash="Z9oQCQ">In addition to this, he was a newspaper editor, and there were also great demands here as far as deadlines and other work that simply could not be put off. I can remember that a seventeen-, eighteen-, or nineteen-hour day was not unusual for him. While this could have created difficulties with us as children and our relationship with our father, surprisingly it did not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p22" guid="20203e18-1577-4025-98df-727623791510" pid="4edJz3i0eUmqW2zfaQ84zA" hash="3PGnow">In reflecting back to see what he did to keep us close to him, even though he had virtually no time to spend with us, I believe it was his ability to build us into his life. Even on the run, he knew what we were doing and was vitally interested and cared. The questions he would ask and the comments he would make let us know that he was proud of us and interested in us and followed us although he could not always be with us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p23" guid="4466a1c0-2594-42af-bbda-6dd21fbbb154" pid="N12Ltyyx302xF8FFu6l94Q" hash="pLHUdw">I also remember that no matter how tired he and Mother must have been, they never went to sleep until we were in. When I was the only one left at home, he was in the habit of not holding family prayer until I came home, even though he and Mother would be in bed. In situations like that he always called on me to pray. I want to tell you that that had quite an impact on how I conducted myself as a youth, when I knew that I was going to have to end my evening at the bedside of my parents in prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p24" guid="16ed117d-3aeb-47fb-a729-d76744fe8719" pid="KVD3kJ-lVUqsNhKFH0USqg" hash="Dg4Q7g">In addition to that, we would have some very profound discussions during those quiet, uninterrupted late night hours. He was always willing to talk if I wanted to talk, no matter what the hour. I would have to say that my father was the greatest man I ever knew, although he didn’t have a great deal of time to spend with me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p25" guid="63d1fbf8-2661-4eea-a3be-e7b7875467db" pid="NjFPfOc9XEmLtL3FwS4C-Q" hash="yEdxyw">As I look back on it, I realize that although the amount of time we spend is important, probably the more important thing is the ability to build our children into our lives. If we can express sincere interest in them and let them know that <span class="emphasis">we </span>know what is going on, even if we have to do it on the run sometimes, this seems to be far more important than a parent who has more time but somehow does not convey this interest.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p26" guid="c6376585-2d0f-444f-a2f6-c8047a71bfa2" pid="zpUoiVo4GU6PZtHo-swnNA" hash="vUZu0w">Finally, may I just state how preciously short the time is for a father to influence his children. In the United States and Canada, if your child is nine years old, he has spent approximately one-half the time he is going to spend in your home. By the time a young person is eighteen, he may be off to school or otherwise beginning his own life. By the time he is nineteen, he is on his mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p27" guid="3ac75fd8-cbb5-4776-ae0b-595b59e0e45c" pid="16mmK1YTpkSU9cXqspV_bg" hash="hU3sGw">In other countries around the world the time may be even shorter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p28" guid="83722fad-fc86-48b7-bcc4-ca3daafe5416" pid="0BCBXc7FD0SzlvFm35I0Vw" hash="jFag5w">I was with a bishop the other day who told me of how his eight-year-old daughter came in and woke him up in the middle of the night to ask him a question. The next morning the bishop explained to the girl that he was a very busy man and had a lot of work to do and needed his sleep. He would be most grateful if she didn’t wake him up in the middle of the night.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p29" guid="83113339-c4cc-48a4-b52a-16492124b4c2" pid="dxxNH9wQP06BvNUCR7mwXw" hash="f38BXg">The little girl waited patiently and finally in an almost exasperated manner she said, “Yes, Daddy, but you don’t understand. You see, you’re the bishop, and I had a problem.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p30" guid="2cdfe764-e7f8-433b-acf6-65a536ecf04b" pid="QRk8wRLxjkaMvDYEFO5Y7w" hash="qCZAEA">In this sense, oh, may each of us be the bishops of our own home just as the duly authorized bishop is the father of his ward. I would hope too that the bishop of the ward and the home teachers would be especially attentive to those families where the fathers are permanently or temporarily missing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p31" guid="872b2116-4ad5-4f4b-9969-287f2dc24c2c" pid="zMtjJPdewEOE5eiyqoKG9g" hash="d0mE0Q">May we take the time and do what we need to do and want to do with our children <span class="emphasis">now, </span>before it is too late, because the days have a way of escaping into months and then into years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p32" guid="33fc5705-7d93-4a04-a5aa-48cdcefb3c14" pid="v4sRvhq9J0Sbhj4Ho5u-OQ" hash="GrllGw">Like the words of the popular song:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.f1" guid="ebab643e-210e-48e7-a80a-a0ef34b7af20">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="T-AuglSXiUWc3z-51j9fvQ" hash="lJLyKQ">“Is this the little girl I carried?</p>
          <p class="line" pid="OotfabYjDE6KewpwIM7emA" hash="0cCFbw">Is this the little boy at play?</p>
          <p class="line" pid="jd5SG1YKQkC5KyepPJ08Pg" hash="ARXl9Q">I don’t remember growing older.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="qn4u48Z4R0GXXpBSGkpyyg" hash="glf1og">When did they?</p>
          <p class="line" pid="BmzriW7xU0ec686O-yi0gw" hash="zyS76Q">When did she get to be a beauty?</p>
          <p class="line" pid="l-8HQ-7ZYkKokYVAx3zF2g" hash="ZvAAiQ">When did he grow to be so tall?</p>
          <p class="line" pid="QH6gLh4A40Gb2ly7RoJUUA" hash="VDYfpQ">Wasn’t it yesterday when they were small?</p>
          <p class="line" pid="88H1ofRl5EGsivtQxOvQ4Q" hash="d7FA2Q">Sunrise, sunset,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="gKutpF1qm02XMxipI6VEuQ" hash="HaucKA">Swiftly fly the years.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="TMg9UJrigkqpJrl7daB1uA" hash="xonbTg">One season following another,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="ChNcR6gA_kiuqc2leLeWLw" hash="Vhdnzw">Laden with happiness and tears.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son.p33" guid="e2566d24-44ba-4285-8b50-f02eb9aad6e1" pid="16CfqCSnO0-Fc-fn9A_gZg" hash="CSbkoQ">May we strive to rededicate and strengthen our relationships with our children and to lend even greater help and leadership to the lovely mothers of this church as we work to bring the principles of righteousness and truth and joy and peace and happiness to the youth of our families, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/10/this-is-my-beloved-son</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1971-general-conference/1971-10-1050-elder-loren-c-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="6374540" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 1971 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Are Called of God</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My brothers and sisters, I am very grateful to be a part of this conference, and I pray that the Spirit of the Lord might bear me up and inspire me to say those things that will be of some contribution to this conference.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03020_000_1030" doc-version="2" hash="x_8JyA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="VmpcbRhzu0mVByY3HQbE7g" hash="uQQLLA">We Are Called of God</h1><p class="authorName" guid="1a14b2cb-b5b2-48cb-a012-92bb04af8eeb" pid="RL0SPdN7p02NRK0uHe8r7w" hash="osADdw">Loren C. Dunn</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="81d9cc82-ef56-4db8-8445-a81128cc8aae">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2b58.jpg" alt="President Loren C. Dunn" guid="aa214f5e-0547-4755-aa3b-ddbaf0568464" pid="l3MjaZw7C0CahgS3qjh9kw" hash="kckzdw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p1" guid="63a131ea-e028-4f6c-a67a-d5a0af977269" pid="uPa7jMoMg0WxC4k4MOa89A" hash="6_YTgg">My brothers and sisters, I am very grateful to be a part of this conference, and I pray that the Spirit of the Lord might bear me up and inspire me to say those things that will be of some contribution to this conference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p2" guid="d0d3ee30-e5c0-4d85-8662-0df6f511c689" pid="vlYEXrgpOkS56Xq9_aS_zA" hash="FAZ-RA">It has been our privilege this morning to once again sustain the general officers of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p3" guid="f377cfb7-26e3-4e95-ba93-eee91cd1e634" pid="nvI9iwAMWk65hI_0bAppNg" hash="aQar2A">This is part of the revealed procedure in the gospel of Jesus Christ, which takes place from the general to the ward or branch level and which allows every member the opportunity of sustaining a person who has been called to office.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p4" guid="68a0726d-f3cd-4652-8ea3-4a6511555d92" pid="zvl8jaEk9kCbdZ_bzjfLhg" hash="JoIUng">Sustaining, however, should not be confused with voting into office.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p5" guid="d1575a2a-002c-447b-8140-b2aee2288fbd" pid="kZpyUzN0cUOGY081xce0QA" hash="XqM0Vw">Joseph Smith made it clear how a person is called to a position in The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. In the fifth Article of Faith he says: “We believe that a man must be called of God, by prophecy, and by the laying on of hands, by those who are in authority to preach the Gospel and administer in the ordinances thereof.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p6" guid="f925ee1a-03cb-4ca2-a21a-978d1771d02d" pid="TM--Ei0hYUiej4_e3jVdiQ" hash="Mb0QDg">When we sustain officers, we are given the opportunity of sustaining those whom the Lord has already called by revelation. The dictionary tells us that the word <span class="emphasis">sustain </span>means “to bear up, to support, to furnish sustenance for, to aid effectually, to hold valid, to confirm or corroborate.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p7" guid="994f0a7c-8544-4276-b08e-6150550e547d" pid="BEcp2DozgE2a-g_OtgAcgg" hash="MVh-lA">The Lord, then, gives us the opportunity to sustain the action of a divine calling and in effect express ourselves if for any reason we may feel otherwise.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p8" guid="24153255-d331-47da-b2b1-778e970bcd03" pid="mAdbevyRzEqscZf-2Zqx_A" hash="AJfZAQ">To sustain is to make the action binding on ourselves and to commit ourselves to support those people whom we have sustained. When a person goes through the sacred act of raising his arm to the square, he should remember, with soberness, that which he has done and commence to act in harmony with his sustaining vote both in public and in private.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p9" guid="7cc61d7c-5bbf-4699-be59-59e4308438fc" pid="OMNXzAX7HkiXud1p9_AxNw" hash="gdyK3w">If for any reason we have a difficult time sustaining those in office, then we are to go to our local priesthood leaders and discuss the issue with them and seek their help.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p10" guid="18cdf598-0389-462c-9b89-20442b566f5f" pid="MsziXnBY6EGMPsqMsejHVw" hash="msQC-g">Brigham Young, when speaking of Joseph Smith, made the following statement:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p11" guid="02ca1225-b6c9-4bd7-b707-b538cf3066bf" pid="f3iHz6Dlf0ifnrFp6hY4vw" hash="Jvl8qA">“Who called Joseph Smith to be a prophet? Did the people or God? God, and not the people called him. Had the people gathered together and appointed one of their number to be a prophet, he would have been accountable to the people; but inasmuch as he was called by God, and not the people, he is accountable to God only and the angel who committed the gospel to him, and not to any man on earth. The Twelve are accountable to the prophet, and not the Church, for the course they pursue.” (<span class="emphasis">Documentary History of the Church, </span>vol. 5, p. 521.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p12" guid="dcd861f6-6757-44e3-9116-4345b63b06b2" pid="eZDTZtUIzEeZb0MNK6-O6Q" hash="RneYnw">And then, of course, it was added that all members are accountable to the principles and teachings of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p13" guid="6ecd1d58-9626-4c9d-8493-60d7736e309f" pid="japU2-FEV06M8iSA9sSD8A" hash="a8Qarg">If we are to take that same principle and apply it at the ward level, we can see that the bishop, who is considered the father of his ward and who leads his ward with judiciousness and love and patience and kindness, is nonetheless not answerable to the members of his ward, but instead is answerable to the Lord and to those priesthood leaders who preside over him. The bishop is answerable <span class="emphasis">for </span>the members of his ward but not necessarily answerable <span class="emphasis">to </span>the members of his ward.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p14" guid="09f50bb8-a20e-434a-ba07-514961e39398" pid="8JOwf7o1fEypF5BGdLZuLQ" hash="1JbQRg">The church of Jesus Christ, then, is organized from the top down.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p15" guid="3e39919a-588b-4806-abd0-8f428c5a0233" pid="vMYgpoMyoEuIGp7NYZIBmw" hash="NudCig">In contrast, the usual man-made organizations are organized from the bottom up.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p16" guid="7ace6e10-48fd-4c88-92ff-3ef628bc92ca" pid="WJjETT0Ti06Tpl9wEyNrbQ" hash="DS75tw">In this church the Lord raised up a prophet first, and then through the holy priesthood and through the power of revelation he revealed the organization and structure of his church from the highest to the least.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p17" guid="c635b94f-61b1-4779-a2df-aaf6b738e511" pid="2s9foRYm00KSQzaLqwPyGw" hash="LlMc0Q">While the Lord gives us the opportunity of sustaining that which he has revealed, this does not constitute voting someone into office; instead, it is properly referred to as the law of common consent.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p18" guid="19a4bab0-1d34-49f0-bebf-aaaf4caafb7c" pid="VM-a9OOCokesZzzzuIsLcw" hash="1eXBOg">A man-made organization will establish its own laws by the vote of its membership, and by virtue of that act it becomes an organization that is governed by man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p19" guid="6d6366ac-9645-4386-abc6-22503f91867a" pid="ng_yVWpNakSAu-IHvJMX9w" hash="uNhazQ">As we said previously, the church and kingdom of God is organized from the top down by the power of revelation so that Jesus Christ himself can stand at the head and lead his own church through his apostles and prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p20" guid="3813d2a4-6b8b-4208-9ed4-5f4ee47e453a" pid="vs4LKbNTFUOtb9m1vOX3kA" hash="kfEFvQ">There are many in the Church who may not be as attentive to their duties as they might be, not because they haven’t been called of God by revelation but because they did not fully realize that fact when they were called. Again, let me refer to the fifth Article of Faith: “We believe that a man must be called of God, by prophecy, and by the laying on of hands, by those who are in authority to preach the Gospel and administer in the ordinances thereof.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p21" guid="e8389f61-5d41-46e4-aa36-380d8f087d96" pid="y9V85_SgvUKpYYaLTmoxcw" hash="DyhYJw">A calling in the Church is both a personal and a sacred matter, and everyone is entitled to know he or she has been called to act in the name of God in that particular position. Every person in this church has the right to know that he has been called of God. If he does not have that assurance, then I would suggest he give his calling serious, prayerful consideration so that he can receive what he has a right to receive.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p22" guid="7a9bad68-1e7d-41bf-8466-3d122dbefd2a" pid="bB3Cp31ZSESUb4481vukug" hash="bhmWRw">Also, if a priesthood leader realizes that there are those under him who may not have this clear understanding, there is something he can do. He cannot call them again, but he can bring them in and reassure them of the divine nature of their callings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p23" guid="413ae32b-2fbc-4982-822e-8ec3c87db9b1" pid="ogdreZRqEUSlIo6eV_F9HQ" hash="EJCaxA">I am most grateful for the great leaders of the Church who have helped me to feel and understand the divine nature of the callings to which I have been called over the years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p24" guid="4ff6f6e9-da73-4243-a9fd-77171eb7cb83" pid="yc929unSTUuLksO6BhcDmg" hash="O7ju_Q">I can’t ever remember coming away from a personal audience with a priesthood leader who was delivering a call to me but what I felt in my heart the realization and assurance that I had been called of God and that that priesthood leader was a servant of the Lord and acting in his own office and calling.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p25" guid="40c2e4dc-14d1-4da3-8520-4ce4a71417b9" pid="0INQkJQO3kGf8awFIGUUWg" hash="Z__RbQ">It was four years ago at April conference that I was first sustained as a General Authority. The sustaining was preceded by a divine calling from a prophet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p26" guid="42fa3663-1549-4808-8762-d6b316112c81" pid="ihXBNHqIvEy5bvVm24DXbw" hash="AlDOXg">I can remember when I left President McKay’s office that morning, as inadequate as I felt, I knew that I had been called of God by revelation; and I had confirmed again to me something that I already knew, and that was, that President McKay was a prophet of God and that this the Lord’s church is led by apostles and prophets who are divinely guided.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p27" guid="4b98037c-0d6b-436a-85ec-220f82538484" pid="CXtHa72fR0ircdp8TowXUg" hash="4G1aNA">What a marvelous thing it would be if, throughout the Church, after the inspiration was received and worthiness determined, priesthood leaders would take the time to create the right atmosphere for a holy and divine calling, to be extended in keeping with the fifth Article of Faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p28" guid="10b5cc55-3430-4177-9748-5aa03bff6bfa" pid="Yhcq4lgbiEqsxiwb7pdZng" hash="0wXQ6A">Such a calling, I suspect, would concentrate on the fact that the priesthood leader was delivering the Lord’s call, so that if, in the future, we are asked, “Who called you?” our immediate response would be to say with conviction, “The Lord Jesus Christ,” and secondly to say, “The call was delivered through Bishop Jones, or Stake President Green.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p29" guid="925991e4-3177-4a91-9324-ea209988e9d4" pid="ToL_Fbv9mUWfHrROZJ_IwA" hash="RAyECw">Perhaps in too many cases that gets reversed, and when we answer the question “Who called you?” the name of Bishop Jones comes first.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p30" guid="bfd0369b-ba86-4af5-bad5-830613ed5525" pid="KLUFWLBDEk20qmimq0_PTg" hash="8CTh3w">In closing, I would like to quote these few words from the Prophet Joseph Smith: “All the ordinances, systems, and administrations on the earth are of no use to the children of men, unless they are ordained and authorized of God; for nothing will save a man but a legal administrator; for none others will be acknowledged either by God or angels.” (<span class="emphasis">DHC, </span>vol. 5, p. 259.) Let me repeat that last phrase: “for nothing will save a man but a legal administrator; for none others will be acknowledged either by God or angels.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p31" guid="2fa2a14f-d9b9-4c8a-b8cf-1b51f2b3496d" pid="Bx8rRiJW1E-igJqtbP2mLQ" hash="NSD7GA">It is my testimony that at this conference this day we have raised our hands to sustain not only a prophet, seer, and revelator but a legal administrator in the rites and ordinances of the gospel of Jesus Christ; and because we have a prophet standing at the head, that which is done under his direction throughout the Church is binding not only on earth but in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p32" guid="3fd17fda-435b-438b-8096-030bbb347b20" pid="efpLMCK6AUKvB_Rftmx_iQ" hash="z18MvA">The fact that we have apostles and prophets and that we have the opportunity to sustain apostles and prophets allows us to do those things which will reach into eternity and will guarantee us our eternal salvation, and will guarantee to any man who will listen and who will humble himself before the Lord the opportunity to receive those ordinances and blessings which will allow him entrance into the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p33" guid="16ecdec5-a74f-4a7b-a889-cba115a82723" pid="pUZRhTLlpkyoHRiFUjyxnw" hash="rsH1Bw">My brothers and sisters, I bear to you my witness as to the reality of the gospel of Jesus Christ. I know God lives and that Jesus the Christ is our Savior and is the leader of his own church. I testify that the apostles and prophets whom we have sustained receive revelation from God for the ongoing work of the kingdom in this day. I bear my witness that Joseph Smith was a prophet of God, and that he saw what he said he saw, and that he is a true prophet, and that we are led by a prophet of God today, even Joseph Fielding Smith, for in the last few years I have had the opportunity to see him stand and speak in the name of Christ the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god.p34" guid="1c062bd8-23e5-4af4-b72d-1743e7ff91b7" pid="rsWuIO8fH0GrwsVnvjwcng" hash="Y3eINw">May the Lord so bless us now that we may sustain those whom he has called and do that which is expected of us, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/04/we-are-called-of-god</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1972-general-conference/1972-04-1060-elder-loren-c-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="5547333" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 1972 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Gain a Testimony</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My brothers and sisters, I pray for the inspiration and strength and Spirit of the Lord during the few minutes that I am before you this afternoon.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03027_000_4060" doc-version="2" hash="-mAkbQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="svwM7GQ9HkmZW-BKiBunrg" hash="-5UzVw">How to Gain a Testimony</h1><p class="authorName" guid="1a14b2cb-b5b2-48cb-a012-92bb04af8eeb" pid="8TH2AlbI8ke9e3NEeRyYYw" hash="osADdw">Loren C. Dunn</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="1da7ada8-60b7-4d80-82c3-6ef7e415ec9d">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p1" guid="4b0e7ab2-5235-4a3c-bad6-c9ff2fbfdb91" pid="97Mm_caXnUCYIjIT7nBVhA" hash="_cwLlw">My brothers and sisters, I pray for the inspiration and strength and Spirit of the Lord during the few minutes that I am before you this afternoon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p2" guid="ee2c53ab-0158-4a84-939b-85eed79380e9" pid="V2ximXdFnEKKqXeTYo7-Kw" hash="gm67FA">In a recent area general conference held in Mexico, President Harold B. Lee made this statement:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p3" guid="ab0af7eb-34e7-43da-b905-d781b96256b9" pid="Crvd206vpkaOkct1YBDA2w" hash="CeoY2g">“The strength of the Church is not to be measured by the amount of money paid as tithing by faithful members, nor by the number of the total membership of the Church, or the number of Church chapels and temple buildings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p4" guid="3af4b00a-6b0c-4241-b169-4831ec3e88ad" pid="CkrTIgbQME64yXemLi3hzQ" hash="oZdFTg">“The real strength of the Church is to be measured by the individual testimonies to be found in the total membership of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p5" guid="7f085e66-f412-472b-9d3a-22233082499a" pid="PhXtrLwZA0-ABRbpq_Srkg" hash="ckyVvQ">No matter what position a person holds in this church, there is one thing to which he is entitled, and that is a testimony of its truthfulness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p6" guid="de0beba0-c169-48c1-9325-b114badc11e4" pid="0b_hKZO1AUC-gKE4svNhjQ" hash="dfo-wg">Not only is it the right of every member to know for himself, but every soul, whether member or nonmember, can if he desires receive a realization that God the Father actually lives; that Jesus Christ is his Son, and gave up his life on the cross that we might live, and was resurrected to ascend on high to take his place on the right hand of God; that Joseph Smith was a true prophet and that in reality he saw God the Father and his Son, Jesus Christ, and that he became the legal administrator to restore the kingdom of God to the earth; that The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is that kingdom of God on the earth, and anyone who makes himself worthy for baptism, by faith in the Lord Jesus Christ and repentance, can gain entrance to that kingdom; that the Book of Mormon is true and “a person can get closer to the Lord by following its precepts than by any other book”; and that we have today a living oracle, a prophet of God who stands at the head of this the Lord’s church upon the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p7" guid="5cf5d096-ea06-4da5-a5a1-d5de7b4a96bd" pid="gwPtlSKmYE2XSquFHvwfbg" hash="56i0fQ">It is not enough to enter into a scholarly discourse on the merits of this declaration or to accept or reject these claims with a wave of the hand. True strength, true peace of mind, true purpose in life comes when the individual, aside from what others may know, puts himself in a position so that the Lord can reveal to him the absolute truth of these things. It is an experience that defies description, at least to one who has not yet paid the price to receive it. It is the awakening of the mind and spirit to absolute truth. It is a revelation from God. It goes beyond what we can know and understand with our mortal senses. It is a testimony of the truthfulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p8" guid="9e182095-f344-47bb-9e86-67bbfc95fe56" pid="Ky4r2HJVzkGutjkKyphKGg" hash="wv2HuQ">Around the world literally hundreds of people are gaining this testimony daily. I heard one such person speak just a few days ago. He was a new convert to the Church. He was a young man and he had a young family. He told how his life had literally changed—how the life of his whole family had changed. For the first time he knew what his relationship to God was and what the Lord expected of him. Because of this, he said, he was a better husband and father. He knew where he was going and could lead his family in a better way. But mostly he was happy—happy with the quiet joy that fills the life of every truly converted person.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p9" guid="9e2c97ee-4903-4170-b12e-84162f7d88ed" pid="duz8e-J-lUej-f7b7ji4nQ" hash="LUwb9g">People who look at us from the outside can’t understand what makes this church so alive and its people so faithful and devoted. President Lee truly answered that question in Mexico when he said, as I mentioned, “The real strength of the Church is to be measured by the individual testimonies to be found in the total membership of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p10" guid="aec1ccfb-37e3-462b-ba26-42d25894ab70" pid="5unRXMESRUSEwJHmZcuiDg" hash="bG5Ahw">The way in which a person can gain such a testimony is clearly defined by the Lord. First let me read from the frontispiece of the Book of Mormon wherein the Lord gives the reasons for bringing forth this book to the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p11" guid="fcb65031-049d-4220-a25c-adedabd7dd64" pid="ieRIgJz20U-LMbmSIOE9lA" hash="UKQwaw">In the second paragraph we find this quote: “And also to the convincing of the Jew and Gentile that Jesus is the Christ, the Eternal God, manifesting himself unto all nations.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p12" guid="947c43b8-21d8-415d-a323-c68ae4230f2e" pid="8xRHZelcYUm5j2_r5UroAg" hash="yGVJXg">So the purpose of the book is to convince the world, both Jew and gentile, that Jesus is the Christ, the Eternal God, manifesting himself to all nations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p13" guid="a9c422d7-de49-415f-a094-835b0cba2f66" pid="jWTjwiFmQkul8v0ZTtqUoQ" hash="aO9XAA">Next we read in section 20 of the Doctrine and Covenants where the Lord, speaking of Joseph Smith and the Book of Mormon, says: “And gave him power from on high, by the means which were before prepared, to translate the Book of Mormon;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p14" guid="8aae3e7d-33c1-468f-9617-2274bc63aa81" pid="eZ-8Jrbz5U-MiGGJ5StSfQ" hash="4NuWFw">“Which contains a record of a fallen people, and the fulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ to the Gentiles and to the Jews also;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p15" guid="ac5bc0ab-bbf5-45d8-b6f0-f1b37f50639c" pid="40ri0hX2cEe8If9gVBFfLg" hash="_VGATw">“Proving to the world that the holy scriptures are true, and that God does inspire men and call them to his holy work in this age and generation, as well as in generations of old.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.8-9,11" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:8–9, 11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p16" guid="8951fdc8-c793-4435-b75a-6bf19964dddd" pid="KfRpYYyiNk63qqbfuL6qDQ" hash="MwyV3w">The Book of Mormon, then, has been brought forth to convince mankind that Jesus is the Christ and that the holy scriptures are true and that God is again speaking through prophets as he did in ancient times. The contents of the Book of Mormon then become the means whereby a person can put himself in harmony with the Spirit of the Lord so he can prove to himself and be convinced these things are true.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p17" guid="4f250ded-a69c-48bc-8cfd-2a38fa98de95" pid="XSHXWWeCEkq2VvHqAUy18g" hash="d-FcBw">How this should be accomplished is outlined by one of the last prophets to write in this ancient book of scripture. Some 421 years after the birth of Christ, the prophet Moroni, speaking to the people of this generation, gave the following guidelines:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p18" guid="c954db2f-d76d-447a-8d27-e5dcbabb6f0a" pid="D3_jUIgsHU6wpxjqoEqthw" hash="6UeLGg">“Behold, I would exhort you that when ye shall read these things, if it be wisdom in God that ye should read them, that ye would remember how merciful the Lord hath been unto the children of men, from the creation of Adam even down until the time that ye shall receive these things, and ponder it in your hearts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p19" guid="4a54910c-5947-450d-bd3b-55b7e0f7793b" pid="shgaYmX5r0qCmI8ICS26Gw" hash="-00-mQ">“And when ye shall receive these things, I would exhort you that ye would ask God, the Eternal Father, in the name of Christ, if these things are not true; and if ye shall ask with a sincere heart, with real intent, having faith in Christ, he will manifest the truth of it unto you, by the power of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p20" guid="4282aa4c-37d5-4e09-b063-990988f9a655" pid="fFCgtUoY3Eu7V1GjpIwMwg" hash="8sC22A">“And by the power of the Holy Ghost ye may know the truth of all things.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.3-5" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:3–5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p21" guid="44660915-25fe-4b25-9277-721ae5b27459" pid="tlXCGmjTfUWo5klccqlJ4A" hash="rzqR1A">The three steps, then, in seeking a testimony of the truthfulness of the gospel from the Lord himself are to read, ponder, and pray with real intent and sincerity of heart. If a person will prayerfully read the pages of this inspired book and carefully turn over in his mind what he has read and constantly ask the question, “Could any man have written this book?” the promise of the Lord is that he “will manifest the truth of it unto you, by the power of the Holy Ghost.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p22" guid="9e9babbf-3134-47c1-80a0-a6a917e75313" pid="0vmpIFAL0ki75DC6HSniDg" hash="5SraWQ">If the world would accept this invitation, then they would know for themselves the source of strength of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints—for like all of us, they would have gone to the source and received their own testimony.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p23" guid="df7f4f06-93d7-48cc-a3ee-98400dcef715" pid="CHMXSEOdRkWSJWwKQ9jGog" hash="llFcLA">And now to those who by heritage find themselves members of the Church but perhaps are not sure of their own testimony—to you I would suggest that it is no sin to admit to yourself that you do not know if, in fact, you don’t know. The error might be, however, in coming to the realization that you don’t know and then doing nothing about it. Any person, either member or nonmember, who wants to know <span class="emphasis">can </span>know. If at present you live by the faith and testimony of your parents and those around you, that is certainly all right. But seek to reach out and gain your own testimony so you can stand on the strength of your own personal relationship with the Lord. It will help you in solving many of your problems and bring peace to your heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p24" guid="86a4cb08-8b3a-4ba5-8ac2-4c0ea03d2947" pid="kNnBQ416Jk2A2XFOZj15zg" hash="nqiXog">I would hope that as Latter-day Saints we can strengthen each other in the way which the Lord provided, by bearing our testimonies often—at church meetings, at the end of gospel classes, even at fast and testimony meetings. We should renew our efforts to actually express our testimonies and give something more than a passing reference to the truthfulness of the gospel. With the bearing of testimony comes the spirit of testimony, and all are edified.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p25" guid="5287b2ea-f851-4cf8-b2ee-e10c9146e7e3" pid="KerNg5xGKEqPos408A1fKw" hash="654YoA">And finally, may Latter-day Saint parents bear their testimonies to their children in the home—actually express to your children exactly what it is about the Church you know to be true. If we think our children know these things just because they live in the same house with us, we are mistaken. We need to say the words so our families can feel the same spirit of testimony that we have felt. Family home evening is an ideal time for this to take place.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p26" guid="abed0b07-7bdb-4e9c-8f5d-0c95121f6503" pid="Gmp1fP6aH0K3CIuMm0XSFQ" hash="8RiXaQ">And may I add that the family setting is an ideal place to read the Book of Mormon. We as a family recently finished reading the Book of Mormon. Although two of our children are not old enough to read yet, we find that they understand more than we thought they would, for the spirit and truth of this great book enlighten all ages.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony.p27" guid="395830f2-1ea7-4281-8bca-be2401d1e54b" pid="9xPH6Yi9UEaPMS0g1QrLNA" hash="Mry1cQ">What greater inheritance can parents give their children than the spiritual heritage which the children have a right to receive! To all men, both member and nonmember, comes the invitation from the God of this earth to learn for themselves the truth. May all who have not received the knowledge accept the invitation of the Savior is my prayer in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/10/how-to-gain-a-testimony</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1972-general-conference/1972-10-4060-elder-loren-c-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="5356053" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Second Witness for Christ</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ?lang=eng</link>
      <description>During the few minutes that I am before you, I would like to address my remarks to those who are not of this faith; and since we are all the children of God, I would like to refer to you as my brothers and sisters.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03033_000_3030" doc-version="2" hash="gj9Wvw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="nhDzmN4K9kGn93KcXx81rQ" hash="ozllQw">A Second Witness for Christ</h1><p class="authorName" guid="1a14b2cb-b5b2-48cb-a012-92bb04af8eeb" pid="sVn9nDgWqUSh3VYQlzS-_g" hash="osADdw">Loren C. Dunn</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="9fa83c7e-bdce-4101-93b9-db789c5bea4d">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2b58.jpg" alt="President Loren C. Dunn, Of the First Council of the Seventy " guid="70809f35-a59d-400f-8b58-8ef74f0a1195" pid="XiJheGbj8EeXYsI58nYDAA" hash="kckzdw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p1" guid="c72d7072-2589-48c1-8dde-eca28e265f19" pid="_Ds8S1rslk6NivOzpEgqqQ" hash="zOdevg">During the few minutes that I am before you, I would like to address my remarks to those who are not of this faith; and since we are all the children of God, I would like to refer to you as my brothers and sisters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p2" guid="f9a7bc11-4ba8-4e19-9a51-46e81be33c19" pid="PuLlNnRa7kiOpkcpI_5sOw" hash="PKJ0yQ">With the approach of the Easter season, the world takes note of the greatest event known to mankind. The literalness of the death and burial and resurrection of Jesus Christ lifts him above the status of a great man or an inspired leader. To overcome death for all mankind, Jesus Christ had to be the Son of God and the Redeemer and Savior of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p3" guid="cd51d802-0d6f-4b4e-a191-089ccf8df54d" pid="PYX88K70aE6VYc4Qf4vYog" hash="raxEVw">To members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, this miraculous event has double meaning. For there are two sources to which we can look for an account of the resurrection. The one, of course, is the Holy Bible. Who can help but gain peace and reassurance from the words of John which say, “Jesus said unto her, I am the resurrection, and the life: he that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/11.25" class="scriptureRef">John 11:25</a>), or the words of Mark describing the experience of those going to the tomb after the death of the Savior: “And entering into the sepulchre, they saw a young man sitting on the right side, clothed in a long white garment; and they were affrighted. And he saith unto them, Be not affrighted: Ye seek Jesus of Nazareth, which was crucified: he is risen; he is not here: behold the place where they laid him” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/16.5-6" class="scriptureRef">Mark 16:5–6</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p4" guid="7cc6b66a-f330-4ff7-870c-08bbdf12aca3" pid="X4LAZSXCNky9_lCdRP5oWQ" hash="pFY9IA">Following these experiences in the land of the Bible, another people in a far-off land, a remnant of the house of Israel who also had prophets and kept their own scriptural record, recorded the following concerning the resurrected Lord:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p5" guid="f790f9f8-6def-4b75-9cf9-9e60df009991" pid="OEkeeuw5WEmRif9X36It4Q" hash="jjz6GA">“And it came to pass, as they understood they cast their eyes up again towards heaven; and behold, they saw a Man descending out of heaven; and he was clothed in a white robe; and he came down and stood in the midst of them; and the eyes of the whole multitude were turned upon him, and they durst not open their mouths, even one to another, and wist not what it meant, for they thought it was an angel that had appeared unto them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p6" guid="2d30a329-27fd-4b6a-ad37-20df9971b0f3" pid="-60NO8G87UW6gkFq9hBmdQ" hash="6K26LQ">“And it came to pass that he stretched forth his hand and spake unto the people, saying:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p7" guid="17970954-ec57-4ba2-9178-2f9ec450ba54" pid="alnsf9XcFEKrhVZUh7aJPA" hash="20pE4g">“Behold, I am Jesus Christ, whom the prophets testified shall come into the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p8" guid="255d2190-7a6b-404e-b3c7-fcc4d0a15736" pid="bEmMNvrnnUq6eenqup1Tuw" hash="k2SG6Q">“And behold, I am the light and the life of the world; and I have drunk out of that bitter cup which the Father hath given me, and have glorified the Father in taking upon me the sins of the world, in the which I have suffered the will of the Father in all things from the beginning.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.8-11" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:8–11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p9" guid="232bf15f-b724-48ff-bd63-1b448f458438" pid="HElYt7QQDECmQs6viu8tmw" hash="vkBmQg">A second evidence then is recorded to verify what was mentioned in the Holy Bible concerning the resurrection of the Savior. This second witness for Christ can be found in the volume of scripture known as the Book of Mormon. It is a compilation of the writings of the prophets of God who were part of the great civilization which lived anciently in the Americas. These prophets taught the gospel of Jesus Christ as did their counterparts in the Holy Land, and they spoke of the birth and life of the Savior and also of his death and resurrection—although these events would transpire in another part of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p10" guid="5dff3de1-e6c6-4b42-b204-d1644deaa373" pid="Pewtx_XKrUaAMCVUtXbTwg" hash="AnJl8w">The highlight of this great record was when the resurrected Savior appeared to these people and taught them the same gospel and the principles of salvation that he had presented to those who were his disciples in the Holy Land. It was only a matter of three generations from that time, however, when the people had almost entirely rejected the teachings of Jesus Christ. They had become warlike and even rejected the prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p11" guid="26512388-f9c5-4ab0-9439-6190eafa0ef6" pid="05vMIUnQ20y022Gq4S4kWQ" hash="DJPASQ">One of the last prophets to live was a man by the name of Mormon, who took all of the records and abridged them. For this reason the volume is known as the Book of Mormon. Mormon passed the sacred records to his son Moroni, who was one of the last followers of Christ in that generation, himself being a hunted man because of his beliefs. It was made known to Moroni and to other prophets that the Lord would bring this record forward in a later generation of time, to testify of the events that took place in Jerusalem and to convince mankind that Jesus Christ is the Son of God and that there is a plan whereby man can be saved and receive eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p12" guid="c042335b-145a-4f63-99e8-7eda5b24c8d9" pid="zgSDbQp5wUysqSKB1QKTGA" hash="XukJ1Q">Being commanded of the Lord, the prophet Moroni buried the record in a hill, and there it remained until the year 1827, when a young man by the name of Joseph Smith was shown by a divine messenger where the record was hidden and was given power to translate it so that the world might have a second evidence that the basic truths of the Bible are correct.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p13" guid="03b242c1-72c4-48c0-90e6-6d043f870b0a" pid="ypTkGJhFokyyIcWls4KHqA" hash="G2NHWA">There were witnesses to the translation of these plates. In a joint statement Oliver Cowdery, David Whitmer, and Martin Harris gave the following testimony: “B<small>E</small> I<small>T</small> K<small>NOWN</small> unto all nations, kindreds, tongues, and people, unto whom this work shall come: That we, through the grace of God the Father, and our Lord Jesus Christ, have seen the plates which contain this record, … And we also know that they have been translated by the gift and power of God, for his voice hath declared it unto us; wherefore we know of a surety that the work is true.” (Book of Mormon: The Testimony of the Three Witnesses.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p14" guid="43905095-54ff-4e6d-8f2c-d552c74eabae" pid="8k1UDydE-Eq6Z30d7J-uTQ" hash="5ZJq9g">The reason for the Book of Mormon coming forth in this generation of time can be found on the title page of the book, which is part of the translated record and which says in part, “And also to the convincing of the Jew and Gentile that JESUS is the CHRIST, the ETERNAL GOD, manifesting himself unto all nations.” The Book of Mormon, then, is a means whereby men can be convinced that God lives and that Jesus Christ is his Son and Savior of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p15" guid="ec946ace-e74d-4545-bb05-74104135df53" pid="_spjRgU-M0GchlDRS2dqIA" hash="PcnfeA">This book, then, bears record of the divine Sonship of Jesus Christ and recognizes him as Redeemer of the world. This passage from 3rd Nephi in the Book of Mormon is a good example:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p16" guid="f3250d06-edc0-4fdc-a1b1-f2e39353756a" pid="6qY4hBAY0U2TU8BgApqBPw" hash="vgPvBg">“Behold, I am Jesus Christ the Son of God. I created the heavens and the earth, and all things that in them are. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p17" guid="4af6b4c9-df2b-4eb4-9720-247b29d5221a" pid="4UbhwAy78k-B2qLUqN4zvA" hash="d_BxBw">“Behold, I have come unto the world to bring redemption unto the world, to save the world from sin.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p18" guid="e85e7c70-1f55-4815-bdcd-bf605ecf523b" pid="Z49Hg1zn5UaQUotPsv5zGA" hash="xqsKcA">“Therefore, whoso repenteth and cometh unto me as a little child, him will I receive, for of such is the kingdom of God. Behold, for such I have laid down my life, and have taken it up again; therefore repent, and come unto me ye ends of the earth, and be saved.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/9.15,21-22" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 9:15, 21–22</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p19" guid="986de79b-0429-4d76-af6e-9c08fac972a2" pid="97C6VMd18U2NP-b2NoYlBw" hash="y5e8Vw">A second message of the Book of Mormon is to teach mankind the plan of salvation in its pure and basic form so that we might know what the Lord expects of us in order to be saved. Again, an example of this can be found from the words of the Savior in 3rd Nephi, which are as follows:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p20" guid="c97435c9-0aa5-47bc-8210-24a4472542af" pid="jPqI7L_mNEmry7-sOYkrDg" hash="wt_AuQ">“And this is my doctrine, and it is the doctrine which the Father hath given unto me; … and I bear record that the Father commandeth all men, everywhere, to repent and believe in me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p21" guid="8c6c7e4e-48c2-4c2f-9dcc-ffc6b4e6a914" pid="DwAKiWkJn0y7XKpp8kP6Hg" hash="q6eVqg">“And whoso believeth in me, and is baptized, the same shall be saved; and they are they who shall inherit the kingdom of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.32-33" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:32–33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p22" guid="378c7f52-0bca-4de3-80ef-78a7b37b902a" pid="b3lDU3QqpUqcD7p8kxxABA" hash="vyu9BQ">At the same time the Savior spoke these words, he also commissioned certain disciples with specific authority to perform the baptism just spoken of. He also explained what he meant by repentance and what steps must be taken in order to gain this repentance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p23" guid="7c7e26c4-169a-473f-bc86-31a207fe72ba" pid="QYIVDQEz706hkudUYPHHZw" hash="I57fbg">And finally, if the Book of Mormon is true, then it must attest to the fact that Joseph Smith, the translator of this record, was a prophet of God and was divinely inspired to bring forth this work. In the revelation concerning the coming forth of the Book of Mormon the Lord referred to Joseph Smith in the following way: “… he has translated the book, even that part which I have commanded him, and as your Lord and your God liveth it is true.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/17.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 17:6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p24" guid="d9452edf-8733-47c6-8bb7-41b5d59fe870" pid="b30d1-cbu0qRKgyjDVQ00Q" hash="Ql6INA">Joseph Smith once made the statement that the Book of Mormon was the keystone of this religion, that a person could get closer to God by following its precepts than by any other book. Joseph Smith has long since passed away. But The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and the Book of Mormon live on as a sign and witness to all nations that Jesus Christ is the Son of God and that there is a way to return to the presence of God and that the basic truths of the Holy Bible are correct.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p25" guid="31c8d450-b6d9-4e28-adf4-0485cc4c695a" pid="QSfcJuxPrkK51zeGU-hmpg" hash="cBS8KA">Realizing that there would be those who might say, “Yes, but how can we know?”—the last prophet to write in the book gave this promise to all who want to know and in these words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p26" guid="8d817b78-737d-42fd-a46c-38ea32a8eadf" pid="goOMlScdikunvwhZ2Hgr3g" hash="6UeLGg">“Behold, I would exhort you that when ye shall read these things, if it be wisdom in God that ye should read them, that ye would remember how merciful the Lord hath been unto the children of men, from the creation of Adam even down until the time that ye shall receive these things, and ponder it in your hearts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p27" guid="44d0b692-5a7f-4ecc-af87-3ad322a9eb53" pid="_lXqgkVrbECbQFU7Cgs-gg" hash="-00-mQ">“And when ye shall receive these things, I would exhort you that ye would ask God, the Eternal Father, in the name of Christ, if these things are not true; and if ye shall ask with a sincere heart, with real intent, having faith in Christ, he will manifest the truth of it unto you, by the power of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p28" guid="0ce1c535-1348-47e6-9b1b-ae2fb58e2be8" pid="uYDa-NhxDkatY5nWwepAiw" hash="8sC22A">“And by the power of the Holy Ghost ye may know the truth of all things.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.3-5" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:3–5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p29" guid="48a87d30-e8a6-49bd-9871-6d9bb3d12a9a" pid="Kc0VlsiIaEyeaO4YPWKsaw" hash="K0xn9A">This promise is made, then, to all who want to know, that if they will read these things and ponder them in their hearts and do it prayerfully, the truth will be made known unto them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p30" guid="3d7ea7b8-8495-4ae0-88e7-26dc6cce5aee" pid="eiSA6Tsn9ECs6UqNA3UDcQ" hash="_b36xw">Today the Church is known as The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, to distinguish it from the church of Jesus Christ that existed at the time of the New Testament and the Book of Mormon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p31" guid="cefee948-94de-489c-889a-376e136b07f4" pid="24_sVKcjikic9P3qF88ssA" hash="KndXJw">As in the ancient church, it has apostles and prophets at the head, and it teaches that all mankind can be saved through obedience to the principles and ordinances of the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p32" guid="ab5f34f0-cfed-4ef2-8ca2-6a982a075076" pid="xQyeSs-zDE6OspeXQmu4Mg" hash="XtZfeA">We believe that the Savior literally leads his church through direct and continuous revelation to its leaders. We believe too that all mankind are the sons and daughters of God and that if they will prayerfully and honestly seek him, he will bless them with a realization of the truthfulness of these things. We believe that Jesus Christ will come again to the earth, and when he does, he will reign as King of kings, as the resurrected Lord and as the Prince of Peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ.p33" guid="438a4f54-ad11-4d3c-8a9a-15ee79413aad" pid="n9UKmYMLuEaS9o7lUD6T8w" hash="sBfP9w">To this I bear my humble witness that I know God lives and that Jesus the Christ is his Son, and that this work is true, for the Lord God has revealed it to me. And if we are the children of God, then all men can and should have this experience, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1973/04/a-second-witness-for-christ</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1973-general-conference/1973-04-3030-elder-loren-c-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="6138955" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 1973 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hanging On</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I should like to spend the few minutes I stand before you today to salute a group of people who have developed what I believe to be a Christlike characteristic, and that is the ability to “hang on.” At this very moment, there is a man, a good member </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03044_000_012" doc-version="2" hash="-OSZig">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="QZ7ZwmGYIk6GjJlRugJEMA" hash="Kuc_Hg">Hanging On</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Y7bVK85DZUSg-shGoAUrwA" hash="osADdw">Loren C. Dunn</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p1" pid="9x9NPik-5k-Sgfogciijmg" hash="Pr7a4w">I should like to spend the few minutes I stand before you today to salute a group of people who have developed what I believe to be a Christlike characteristic, and that is the ability to “hang on.” At this very moment, there is a man, a good member of the Church, who hovers between life and death in a nearby hospital. In the last few weeks he has withstood crisis after crisis; and yet to the amazement of all, he still hangs on. I know not whether the Lord will ordain that he should ultimately live or die at this time, but I do know there is something noble about his tenacious fight for life and the desire to hang on. In the lives of each of us come these trials—trials of all kinds which shake us to the very core and cause us to explore to the very depths our ability to hang on.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p2" pid="Jx234nhOu0icnJz1lH5-pg" hash="84HGIg">I think of the person who, in the quiet of night, could not be persuaded to compromise virtue and decides instead to hang on, though the temptation is great.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p3" pid="A38tDKIDiUOKW8yDdK39LA" hash="ehWCjg">I think of those who have withstood the test of many years, some of whom are confined and bedridden and who, in spite of the infirmities that age brings, will not give up. I see etched in the faces of these wonderful older people something of our pioneer heritage—lives so filled with determination and faith, lives so filled with the overcoming of adversity and trial that by their nature they simply can’t let go.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p4" pid="cJfmph2RQ0S3lA-Tg5G5gA" hash="pajX_A">It reminds me of two trees that were close to my home when I was growing up. The one was a Russian olive and grew right in our yard. It was watered every time the lawn was watered, and in that kind of protected environment it grew to be a beautiful tree. Yet one night a tremendous wind came up. Trees all over town were blown down, and with them went our Russian olive. We had watered it so well that the roots did not have to reach down into the soil; and because they were so close to the surface, the tree toppled over.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p5" pid="Xf8HYxT1YkqQGi94hKNl4w" hash="UWdmGw">The second tree withstood the gale. It was a tremendous cottonwood, which still stands in the lane just half a block from where I was born. This tree was in the fullness of its growth when I was a child. It has always stood by itself, completely exposed to the elements, with nothing but a ditch running by, which most of the time is dry. It is gnarled and tough, and its roots have had to sink deep in order to drink of the water of life; but because its roots were forced downward, it lives. I was out home the other day and noticed that most of the trees around this cottonwood are gone. But in all of its power and majesty, it still hangs on.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p6" pid="ELdcYsOWj0SaQON79bPdhw" hash="Uaf_4A">I see in many people this same kind of beauty. Adversity and trial have driven the roots of faith and testimony deep in order to tap the reservoir of spiritual strength that comes from such experiences. By nature they know how to stand and fight and hang on.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p7" pid="w0SpHv7qf0-2S93pxcbypQ" hash="5dlhxg">One person who has sunken deep the roots of faith and testimony because of the trials and affliction of years is the man whom we will sustain tomorrow as prophet, seer, and revelator. His branches can offer shade because his roots are deep.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p8" pid="654g-f1CS0auf8mpDS57Ug" hash="9WJgag">My own mother and mother-in-law are characteristic of these kinds of people. One suffered a broken hip and the other underwent a severe sickness. But they have both fought back and, like so many others, are enjoying active, useful lives. When we as a family are with them, we draw strength from them and their ability to hang on in severe crises.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p9" pid="o8PACg0AOk-aQfZRYQ3XFg" hash="QQHHmw">A few years ago, while on a mission tour in Europe, I was asked to interview a young man who was recently out and wanted to go home. He had not been away from home before in his life and he was homesick and in despair in a strange country. He had actually run away once, but had come back.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p10" pid="EXJ-3AndiE-aUpM_vwk86A" hash="gtGAJg">I had quite a conversation with this young man, and from my own missionary experience I knew something of the despair that can come into the life of a missionary when he first goes into the field and begins to make that initial adjustment. If he can just hang on through those early trials, then gradually he will get into the spirit of his mission and find the peace and joy that every missionary has a right to experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p11" pid="96B50V9elEeZ7J6sykSIvg" hash="EHm-uw">At first he was adamant in his desire to return home, but gradually the spirit of the conversation began to change. We talked about his call from a prophet. We talked about the love of his parents and their desire for him to stay and succeed. We talked about those he had been called among to teach, and finally I asked, “Elder, do your father and mother want you home?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p12" pid="jtN6SQ5Vu0CGTAaHyDOe9Q" hash="HB0OuA">His answer was, “No.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p13" pid="yrgMu6gyZkWO79-vYfsG8g" hash="QasF-g">“Well, do your brothers and sisters want you home?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p14" pid="gbxFVqNeI0W1xVQrSOTH6g" hash="zCMHHw">And he said, “No.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p15" pid="9wHoXp4G9ku6125zsUUBfg" hash="FRNQkw">Then I said, “Does your girl friend really want you home?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p16" pid="jL1CcQiacEyixzOdUSVXrw" hash="cOBvzQ">And he said, “I guess not.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p17" pid="C8KiHDbIdEqdAmxuuQG-sw" hash="fEctPA">I then said, “Elder, does anyone want you home right now?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p18" pid="HJxh_CybB0KtZxNxEIFaZg" hash="kf5dIg">He said, “I guess not,” and then he said with a new determination, “Brother Dunn, I think maybe I better try to stay.” He had made a vitally important decision in his life—he had decided to hang on.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p19" pid="dS5LWL-LYE6IZOF5uzoUrA" hash="-WJ4AA">The months passed and one day my secretary asked if I could take a minute to see a recently returned missionary. As I walked out of my office, there was this same missionary. I didn’t recognize him at first, he seemed taller because he was standing straight. Unlike the first time, he looked me right in the eye, and his whole countenance was smiling. I can’t remember what we talked about, but I shall never forget his image. He was going home now, a servant of the Lord, having completed an honorable mission. His roots were reaching downward; and although there will be the usual trials ahead, he knows something of what it means to hang on for a while longer when everything looks its darkest.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p20" pid="nUqvij40eUOodXD0d2rOiA" hash="fM5wgg">I don’t know all the reasons the Lord tries us in this life, but there are two or three that come to mind. First, I think he wants to know whom he can trust. The Lord found he could trust Abraham because he was willing to offer his own son as a sacrifice if that was what the Lord wanted. Many thought that Zion’s Camp was a tragic waste of time, until it was later demonstrated that the Lord used this ordeal to find whom he could trust. He wanted to know who had roots of faith and testimony that reached deep into the ground and who had such shallow roots that the first wind of adversity would blow them over.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p21" pid="aOwn49P-DEe1bl0g3iXHog" hash="4m_V5Q">Secondly, the Lord tells us in the Doctrine and Covenants section 122 that adversity came to Joseph Smith to give him experience. There is something about the eternal purpose of life that requires us to meet and experience trial and sorrow as we seek to overcome, for the Lord has told us also, “… for if they never should have bitter they could not know the sweet. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/29.39" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 29:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p22" pid="Y45rocftSEOn3jGYHMyz-Q" hash="VI30gQ">Thirdly, I believe that only through such experiences can a person develop true charity. And I mean by <span class="emphasis">charity</span> the pure love of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p23" pid="rQBKZ4_4sUCRJXQzm23TMg" hash="-XnQig">Let me read the following from Moroni in the Book of Mormon: “… if a man be meek and lowly in heart, and confesses by the power of the Holy Ghost that Jesus is the Christ, he must needs have charity; for if he have not charity he is nothing; wherefore he must needs have charity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p24" pid="ajRFWwfKDke7FMMms3PriQ" hash="LYtX6g">“And charity <span class="emphasis">suffereth long,</span> and is kind, and envieth not, and is not puffed up, seeketh not her own, is not easily provoked, thinketh no evil, and rejoiceth not in iniquity but rejoiceth in the truth, <span class="emphasis">beareth all things,</span> believeth all things, hopeth all things, <span class="emphasis">endureth all things.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p25" pid="j6-EpJSDMUSYbpXv7TFqsg" hash="N5T3iA">“Wherefore, my beloved brethren, if ye have not charity, ye are nothing, for charity never faileth. Wherefore, cleave unto charity, which is the greatest of all, for all things must fail—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p26" pid="Dbw2TWsIk02k05d5qHGFaw" hash="imIz9Q">“But charity is the pure love of Christ. …” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.44-47" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:44–47</a>. Italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p27" pid="h295RsllhUu-GXoXDY9ZTQ" hash="F4hk7g">May I say then to those who are now or will be facing deep trials: May the Lord bless you that you may continue to hang on. There is purpose in it all, and he has promised us that the severity of it all will not be greater than we can endure, for as the words of the song tell us:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="3NFxtK48v0O8VM8Zaa8EEw" hash="bjD38w">“When through fiery trials thy pathway shall lie,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="8CHtlzTzM06kOFv_fGxqNg" hash="mFaE3Q">My grace, all sufficient, shall be thy supply.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="MGXIMP2s_k-8KlQ3g7Fdrw" hash="4XYHWg">The flame shall not hurt thee; I only design</p>
          <p class="line" pid="jwcMLUltkki9pLSD8tVniQ" hash="ZsdLrg">Thy dross to consume and thy gold to refine.”</p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on.p28" pid="60Ie6X7unEiFRvl4njujWw" hash="Dc7QUw">And finally this promise from the Master: “And again, be patient in tribulation until I come; and, behold, I come quickly, and my reward is with me, and they who have sought me early shall find rest to their souls. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/54.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 54:10</a>.) In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/04/hanging-on</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1974-general-conference/1974-04-2050-elder-loren-c-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="10430206" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 1974 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Precious Families</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families?lang=eng</link>
      <description>What a beautiful spirit of peace this Tabernacle Choir has established for us in that last song. It is an honor to be at this conference this morning, my brothers and sisters, and to receive the instructions and direction from the prophet of God. I b</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03050_000_004" doc-version="2" hash="yH7yPw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="xBUFn4gNd0Gz4WIjvIRHsw" hash="3sKEBg">Our Precious Families</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="xqfE5nrH90u8Ki0JlkVQkg" hash="osADdw">Loren C. Dunn</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2b58.jpg" alt="President Loren C. Dunn" pid="asaF5H6MGkSBTfAu_EdRMQ" hash="kckzdw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p1" pid="qast4mmkU0G6UVQKvAVinA" hash="zN5GdA">What a beautiful spirit of peace this Tabernacle Choir has established for us in that last song. It is an honor to be at this conference this morning, my brothers and sisters, and to receive the instructions and direction from the prophet of God. I bear testimony to the fact that President Kimball is a prophet of God, that he is the Lord’s legal administrator upon the earth today, that those who will follow the instructions and advice that he has given us this morning will come to know, by practical experience, that what he has told us is true and is good for the strengthening and uplifting of mankind. President Spencer W. Kimball is a prophet of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p2" pid="Zy23gB59Yk2pofG7s02YDA" hash="9n1aKg">I would like to use as the key to my remarks a quote that President Kimball made on a previous occasion and a theme that he returned to this morning. He said, “The nation is built upon the foundation of its homes and the home upon its families.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p3" pid="SKxmZk4Yz0m18wIDME_QMA" hash="NHNdaA">The family—mother and father and the children—is the oldest of all our institutions and stands at the very foundation of our civilization. There can be nothing more precious or enduring than the family. It is obvious that the need exists, however, for the upgrading of the role of parents in the family setting.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p4" pid="KBZ25Za3PEG0N4b14FCyCw" hash="pfNKxA">I remember a few years ago going on a business trip to eastern Canada in company with a broad range of business and community leaders. After the business of the day, we had dinner together; and during the course of the evening, as everyone began to relax and get better acquainted, one of those present, for no apparent reason, began to tell about his son, a boy whom obviously he loved very much. Yet there was conflict and even some alienation and he wasn’t quite sure what to do, if indeed he should do anything.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p5" pid="TfvPTzEaoE627ceprzI-PA" hash="xvHjyg">That comment prompted a similar response from the others seated around the table. You could tell it was something they were not used to talking about, but each was personally concerned about some aspect of his family life, and this was primarily associated with his children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p6" pid="cOTww0uj906aZ7iU3qFB1g" hash="qZcwYg">Although we live in an era of transition and change, I believe parents are as anxious and concerned about their children as they have ever been. If the family, then, is the foundation unit in society, perhaps there is need to reaffirm some basic principles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p7" pid="JhGsjCcy3EelqYBeA5UgHg" hash="vsI_Zg">First is that parents recognize they have the right to structure the attitudes and conduct of their children—not only the right but the responsibility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p8" pid="pwtWkEyqWUiqLLXxZbtHIA" hash="moujuQ">Second, that the principle of work, the work ethic if you please, be taught by the parents in the family setting. Where else is the dignity of work to be taught if not in the home?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p9" pid="7hBrnBsWvUm8SAY1qSggww" hash="2-cHvQ">And, third, parents have a right to establish the moral and spiritual tone in the family to help family members to realize the importance of living divine principles as a means of accomplishment and of peace of mind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p10" pid="UKsmGd2ZFUS2ETvG9I7xZQ" hash="RyCdlg">First, then, the right of parents to structure the attitudes and conduct of their children. Fundamentally this is divine right. God says of Abraham that he “shall surely become a great and mighty nation, … for I know him, that he will command his children and his household after him, and they shall keep the way of the Lord, to do justice and judgment.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/18.18-19" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 18:18–19</a>.) God could make Abraham head of a numerous posterity because of his faithfulness in teaching his children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p11" pid="RQpK2Z2fEE6RNICAO4GH0A" hash="Nrm4mg">There are some in the world who might say that such parental influence is repressive and robs the child of its freedom, but quite the opposite is true. A group of young girls was overheard talking about the parents of one of their friends. Showing maturity beyond her years, one of the girls said, “Her parents don’t love her; they let her do anything she wants.” The others agreed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p12" pid="CoJEEMRIhkyqXe7kpnliYg" hash="xgiWXQ">In a <span class="emphasis">New York Times Magazine</span> article, later condensed in <span class="emphasis">Reader’s Digest,</span> William V. Shannon makes the following points: “American children … are suffering from widespread parent failure. By their words and actions [he says] many fathers and mothers make it clear that they are almost paralyzed by uncertainty. … Many parents are in conflict as to what their own values are. Others think they know, but lack the confidence to impose discipline in behalf of their values. …”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p13" pid="2nlWCCpmxUCik7egBeCOdg" hash="k_YsbA">What is lacking, he says, is not more information on child development, but <span class="emphasis">conviction.</span> Although heredity plays some role in the development of a child, the greater influence “depends on whether parents care enough about their children to assert and defend the necessary values.” The author also says that both mother and father need to put family and home responsibilities first. “Rearing our children is by far the most important task that most of us will ever undertake.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p14" pid="gsPfe7A27Ey6qAqYXqx9ig" hash="k62emw">He also states that “parents who do not persevere in rearing their children according to their own convictions are not leaving them ‘free’ to develop on their own. Instead, they are letting other children and the media, principally television and the movies, do the job.” (William V. Shannon, “What Code of Values Can We Teach Our Children?” <span class="emphasis">Reader’s Digest,</span> May 1972, pp. 187–88.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p15" pid="ovEH3QNYuEuQYZil4aiCWg" hash="xcIxbg">The greatest principle to be learned in the family setting is love. If parents will influence and direct and persevere with love, then members of the family will also make that principle a part of all they do. The principle of love can overcome many parental mistakes in the raising of their children. But love should not be confused with lack of conviction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p16" pid="5qhnjpaN5USz-Eeze0giig" hash="nxHF_w">Secondly, that the principle of work be taught in the family and home setting. There is evidence to support that at least in the United States the problems of stress and tension might be linked to a gradually decreasing average number of hours worked by the labor force. The suggestion is that free time, not work, might be a major cause of stress and tension in individuals.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p17" pid="U68xzYOomEa9RlWzCx__zA" hash="Vy4zIg">While we were growing up in a small community, my father saw the need for my brother and me to learn the principle of work. As a result, he put us to work on a small farm on the edge of town where he had been raised. He ran the local newspaper, so he could not spend much time with us except early in the morning and in the evening. That was quite a responsibility for two young teenagers, and sometimes we made mistakes. Our small farm was surrounded by other farms, and one of the farmers went in to see my father one day to tell him the things he thought we were doing wrong. My father listened to him carefully and then said, “Jim, you don’t understand. You see, I’m raising boys and not cows.” After my father’s death, Jim told us his story. How grateful I was for a father who decided to raise boys, and not cows. In spite of the mistakes, we learned how to work on that little farm, and I guess, although they didn’t say it in so many words, we always knew we were more important to Mother and Father than the cows or, for that matter, anything else.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p18" pid="wabs4I99A0eSbPcq1ozl4g" hash="7gSVig">Certainly in every home all family members can be given responsibilities that will fall within their ability to accomplish and, at the same time, teach them the satisfaction and dignity of work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p19" pid="8sA5inVs_0SxWPSQbEFDhg" hash="O4hUoQ">The third point is that parents have the right to teach moral and spiritual principles to their children. In that regard let me quote the following from modern scripture:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p20" pid="KTW6GleJS0ODu48GkTPY0A" hash="4E5QBw">“And again, inasmuch as parents have children in Zion, or in any of her stakes which are organized, that teach them not to understand the doctrine of repentance, faith in Christ the Son of the living God, and of baptism and the gift of the Holy Ghost by the laying on of the hands, when eight years old, the sin be upon the heads of the parents.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.25" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p21" pid="UDH9j3XdnUeq62Zl8BaE8w" hash="Ygv0MQ">In his first address to the United States Congress, President Gerald Ford stated this universal truth: “If we can make effective … use of the moral and ethical wisdom of the centuries in today’s complex society, we will prevent more crime and corruption than all the policemen and prosecutors … can ever deter.” And he added: “This is a job that must begin at home, not in Washington.” (<span class="emphasis">Christian Science Monitor,</span> 28 Aug. 1974.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p22" pid="cPhF_yWDx0mLk6mAyYEthg" hash="p3L4XQ">In the article previously mentioned, Mr. Shannon says, “Nothing has invalidated the hard-earned moral wisdom that mankind has accumulated since Biblical times. To kill, to steal, to lie, or to covet another person’s possessions still leads to varying degrees of misery for the victim and the perpetrator. … ‘Thou shalt not commit adultery’ may sound old-fashioned, but restated in contemporary terms—‘Do not smash up another person’s family life’—still carries a worthwhile message.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p23" pid="pidyz8qvZkqb1dMBgKPX8w" hash="tvdzMA">He also points out the virtues of self-denial and anticipation. As older teenagers learn the facts about sex, it would do no harm, he says, to use self-control.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p24" pid="9LKNGoGtAkC9_EgTd_LlnQ" hash="RSQt6w">“A certain amount of frustration and tension can be endured—and with good effect. Only modern Americans,” he says, “regard frustration as ranking higher than cholera in the scale of human afflictions.” (<span class="emphasis">Reader’s Digest,</span> May 1972, pp. 189–90.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p25" pid="wfuN1UYFd0i3H21-31T13A" hash="-GDulg">These are but three of many principles that should be emphasized in the setting of family and home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p26" pid="Dl30skpGtE2Ie3OaDDLMsw" hash="hA_ghA">The next question is, How do parents get this accomplished? For members of the Church, the point at which training and communication begin in the family is family home evening. Monday night is set aside for the family and nothing interferes. The father takes the lead but also has other members of the family make preparation and participate. What is said and done depends on the needs of that particular family. The Church publishes some guidelines to help parents teach moral and religious principles to the family and to make them apply in everyday life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p27" pid="tsKpydLsok26GdYW8wJshg" hash="d820ig">To the nonmember parent who is interested in establishing some kind of similar activity the Church also offers some special help. Living near you are both full-time and part-time missionaries who have been trained in how to hold a family home evening. They will be happy to demonstrate this program in your home at no obligation. This is a service of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints which it is prepared to offer families everywhere. The only thing we ask is that the whole family is present, especially the father or head of the home, since he is the key to the program.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p28" pid="xNplfAuvZEGHrdt66xnRdw" hash="a-TvTw">Of course, these young missionaries are also prepared to teach your family the principles of the gospel of Jesus Christ in subsequent visits. But if you do not want to continue, that will be your decision. At least you will be left with a program that many outside this Church have already adopted as being beneficial for the family and the home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p29" pid="SCGeS52nuUaZ6Z1cLOj0bw" hash="WjkHkg">Some business leaders have also looked at the family home evening program and recommended it to their employees. Employees do better work when things are going well at home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families.p30" pid="GAQNHdDUek6jp0ecoPw7BA" hash="6y7YIQ">May the Lord bless us as parents to realize our right to help formulate the lives of our children, to teach the dignity of work, and to establish moral and religious principles in our homes, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/10/our-precious-families</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1974-general-conference/1974-10-1020-president-loren-c-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="6285008" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 1974 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faithful Laborers</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, in the last few months President Spencer W. Kimball has recommitted us as a church to reach out to our Father’s other children.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03057_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="kTJGGg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="UjZiFQzkfESLg0kLrRjeLQ" hash="3_1z-A">Faithful Laborers</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="zFuHFzCcFkOwHz6dDDPVlw" hash="osADdw">Loren C. Dunn</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2b58.jpg" alt="Elder Loren C. Dunn" pid="Uq5mouwP6EuBj6UCHU4mzw" hash="kckzdw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p1" pid="IC3QiOu08kqGPaDTLeYXyg" hash="pngYcQ">My dear brothers and sisters, in the last few months President Spencer W. Kimball has recommitted us as a church to reach out to our Father’s other children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p2" pid="XVOAsvf8FketlhTsOl7UZA" hash="5vZoQw">We have been asked to lengthen our stride in two general areas. First is the need for every member of the Church to let his light so shine that others will see the gospel of Jesus Christ by example. The Lord tells us in the Doctrine and Covenants:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p3" pid="Sa_1lIJErkSCEyM-6ltixg" hash="WvUG5g">“And again, I say unto you, I give unto you a commandment, that every man, both elder, priest, teacher, and also member, go to with his might, with the labor of his hands, to prepare and accomplish the things which I have commanded.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p4" pid="qIQDlFB5GEiaWrGpqeqo6g" hash="PizRnQ">“And let your preaching be the warning voice, every man to his neighbor, in mildness and in meekness.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.40-41" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:40–41</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p5" pid="7REOAH0dxUWEqiUNy71oLQ" hash="1Zxs9g">Every family in the Church is asked to friendship a nonmember family on a family-to-family basis.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p6" pid="PF3GPY6Y4EG5IXO4CR6DrQ" hash="JjYTVw">Second, every able young man has been asked to prepare himself to serve a full-time mission. And again from the Doctrine and Covenants:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p7" pid="z6ceqN_-mUei_ap8ePF8_g" hash="W6aTFg">“Wherefore lay to with your might and call <span class="emphasis">faithful</span> laborers into my vineyard, that it may be pruned for the last time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p8" pid="-vcukEgmGEq3KRsECHpEWg" hash="GHC3iA">“And inasmuch as they do repent and receive the fulness of my gospel, and become sanctified, I will stay mine hand in judgment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p9" pid="LSe11qMX3kiIEkjPWImTIQ" hash="LrqAgQ">“Wherefore, go forth, crying with a loud voice, saying: The kingdom of heaven is at hand; crying: Hosanna! blessed be the name of the Most High God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p10" pid="VtGo-x9suU61q_PWYFPa7A" hash="hh62iA">“Go forth baptizing with water, preparing the way before my face for the time of my coming;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p11" pid="3hXJeLQBjki40_Mxoz2KIg" hash="jCh_Ug">“For the time is at hand; the day or the hour no man knoweth; but it surely shall come.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/39.17-21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 39:17–21</a>. Italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p12" pid="K-fK7oqIrEmhruDnQQjCUw" hash="6_5Nmw">It is this last point I would like to enlarge upon. I had the honor recently of being assigned to visit the Samoa Apia Mission and attend some stake conferences in that country. I found the missionaries all well and the work progressing. One afternoon following our meeting, the mission president, Patrick Peters—who is a native Samoan—said, “Elder Dunn, there is something I’d like to show you.” We drove a few miles from the mission home and climbed the brow of a small hill to a place that was isolated by palm trees and other tropical vegetation. I suddenly realized that we were in a very old graveyard. At the center of this graveyard was a plot that was surrounded by a cement wall low enough to step over. President and Sister Peters told me this was where some of the first missionaries in Samoa were buried. There were eight graves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p13" pid="nAMEwtdZIE-45rzHh5Ltdw" hash="CVm2PQ">The thing that struck my interest was that out of the eight graves, four represented children under the age of two and one was a twenty-one-year-old wife and mother. What role could these have possibly played in missionary work in Samoa?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p14" pid="8ZbvXzx5pEOLhSX4jKXfwA" hash="cxtDBg">During the next two days, when time would permit, I searched the history of the mission for an answer. While I was unable to gather information on all of the eight, I did discover the following.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p15" pid="1I-lRmrdlEinCRxXQaeIJA" hash="GF0X4g">In the early days of the Church it was common for young married couples to be called on missions and some of these young couples were called to Samoa. The first person to be buried in that plot was Sister Katie Eliza Hale Merrill. She and her husband had only been on a mission for three months when she took sick and gave birth to a premature child. The child died the next day. The history says the following: “An hour after the death of the child, the mother called Sister Lee (wife of the mission president) to her bedside and, after thanking her for waiting on her during the sickness, said that she was ‘going to die’ that she ‘could not stay because they had come for her.’ She then talked with her husband, kissed him goodbye, and all was over. The mother and baby boy were buried in one coffin.” After his mission, Brother Merrill took the remains of his wife and infant son back to Utah for burial.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p16" pid="BeXMbz0_vUaZmlqokxg4wg" hash="oiSR2Q">Elder Thomas H. Hilton and Sister Sarah M. Hilton were serving on a mission in Samoa, where they lost three of their children, between 1891 and 1894. Little Jeanette lived less than a year, George Emmett for only seven days, and Thomas Harold for a year and a half.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p17" pid="rJGzB6kw9EK-KWKzFXRYvQ" hash="3TyExA">Of the death of Thomas Harold the record says: “On Sunday the 11th, he was not feeling very well. … For two days following he appeared to be improving, but on the morning of the 14th, his mother again became concerned about his welfare. From then until his death, on March 17, 1894, everything that loving hands could do was done for his recovery, but he grew rapidly worse. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p18" pid="CqEFfPsd5EaXnTVHKCtlPg" hash="NpdoHg">“Oh how loath we all were to believe that it was so! How sad to see our dear sister <span class="emphasis">again</span> bereft, and her so far from dear parents and friends who she has left for the gospel’s sake.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p19" pid="UkVMoYhyrEe6eDxuAOSpXg" hash="TeFpWQ">“Thomas Harold Hilton was about one and a half years old, a beautiful little boy and very dearly beloved by all the missionaries, as well as the natives who knew him. Much sympathy is felt for the bereaved parents and the blessings of the Lord are invoked upon them.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p20" pid="nceB7Nxdt0m3coz3nWZLlw" hash="5W9LjA">At twenty-nine, Ransom Stevens was president of the Samoa Mission when stricken with typhoid fever, which was complicated by a heart problem. He died on April 23, 1894.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p21" pid="lMjMmpld706tynJEf_8cow" hash="HcgxUg">His widow, Sister Annie D. Stevens, started for home by steamer on May 23. She reached Ogden on Sunday, June 10, where she was met by President Joseph F. Smith and Elder Franklin D. Richards. On June 11, she had an interview with the First Presidency in Salt Lake City and then went on to her home in Fairview, Sanpete County, arriving at 6:00 <small>P.M.</small></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p22" pid="kXAwSnIKi0uW-dYOKPS6ew" hash="AXR9SA">The history states, “The greetings by her friends were necessarily brief for Sister Stevens was ill and had to retire to bed early, and at 11 <small>P.M.</small>, five hours after her arrival home, she gave birth to a nice boy.” She had gone through the whole ordeal in the advance stages of pregnancy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p23" pid="9sKHQLyCuEqb7PRL1SdrSw" hash="fLcEQQ">Another entry was Friday, March 2, 1900, “Little Loi Roberts was given up to die by Dr. Stuttaford at the sanatorium [in Apia]. The patient little sufferer was administered to daily, and each time he would get relief. … His parents [Elder and Sister E. T. Roberts] were untiring in their efforts to allay pain and sufferings.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p24" pid="9vVCE-rzBEiMUNtZe1umbA" hash="LdJpiw">Saturday, March 3, “Little Loi died at the sanatorium in Apia in the morning, making another sad day in the history of the mission.” Small wonder that the tombstone contained the words, “Rest sweet Loi, rest.” He was one and a half years old.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p25" pid="8CLFhkLU7keH-N53Kbp1Cw" hash="I5R5PA">And that brings us to Elder William A. Moody and his bride, Adelia Moody. They were called on a mission from Thatcher, Graham County, Arizona, arriving in Samoa in November 1894. They must have had the same hopes and aspirations of any young couple just starting out. She gave birth to an eight-pound daughter on May 3, 1895. Three weeks later she passed away. The daughter, little Hazel Moody, was taken care of by local Saints while her father continued his mission. Finally, one year later we read the following about a steamer leaving for the United States, whose passengers included four returning elders and “also Elder Moody’s daughter, Hazel, one-year-old, who will be delivered to loving relatives in Zion.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p26" pid="JPErLbg5y0G5wLD1TpPD2w" hash="olNiog">A price has been paid for the establishment of the gospel of Jesus Christ in the land of Samoa. It is interesting to note that much of that price was paid by little children. I suspect that there are many obscure cemeteries in many of the nations of the world similar to that little plot in Samoa. They are a mute witness to the trials and suffering that went into the beginnings of missionary work in this dispensation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p27" pid="v-8WVM6ZCUipc4ctlQF0Xw" hash="aVxU1A">Because of advancements in the standard of living and medical technology, these kinds of trials are almost a thing of the past. In Samoa, for instance, I found the missionaries well. There are even health missionaries, including a young couple and their two children who are helping to improve the health standards of the members and looking after the health of the missionaries where needed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p28" pid="J7WQfb_JHUiPPE5_1qEb8w" hash="yt2iyg">The sacrifice today is mostly a sacrifice of time and money. A sacrifice of 24 months for a worthy young man to help move the cause of the Lord forward. Others gave their lives to get the work started, but the Lord only requires that we sacrifice some time and our means to keep his work moving throughout the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p29" pid="kKeBQCxjZU2fxOHZ7LcxAg" hash="B8Vhpw">The story is told that toward the end of World War II an allied general came to the front lines one night to inspect his troops. As he walked along he would point out into no-man’s-land and say, “Can you see them? Can you see them?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p30" pid="EcXg-dCPTEKhVgU3g9MS6Q" hash="T7_-9w">Finally, someone said, “General, we can see nothing. What do you mean?” He said, “Can’t you see them? They’re your buddies; they are the ones who gave their lives today, yesterday, and the day before. They’re out there alright, watching you, wondering what you are going to do; wondering if they have died in vain.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p31" pid="CcFkoGnLVkeSc3DXVxe6CA" hash="Wj-Ipg">My dear brothers and sisters, as members of this Church we can ask ourselves the same question, “Can you see them?” They are the ones who paid, and some with their lives, that the gospel of the kingdom might be established in these, the last, days. They are the Hiltons, and the Robertses, and the Stevens, and the Moodys, and many others—people like you and me, who answered a call from God. I am sure they are allowed to look in on us from time to time to see how the work is going, to see what we are doing with their spiritual heritage, to see if they have died in vain.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p32" pid="OCQGEqSrokaaC-q8y9N6eQ" hash="LeH2uA">I wonder, young man, how successful you would be in convincing a young father who had buried three of his babies in an obscure graveyard halfway around the world because of the gospel of Jesus Christ that a mission is too much of a sacrifice because you want to buy that car or that stereo, or you don’t want to interrupt your schooling, or for some other reason.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p33" pid="_OSZpWPqnUWD0q0b9egwMA" hash="SOM_xQ">As members of the Church, I wonder how convincing we would be in telling someone that we are just too busy and maybe just a little embarrassed to share the gospel with our neighbor, especially if that someone were a young father who had buried his bride while on his mission and sent his little girl home to be taken care of by relatives while he finished his service to the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers.p34" pid="KXZZrqBG_EaLIqYafqm4wQ" hash="sAmmtg">Is it not time that we listen to a prophet’s voice? Is it not time that we lengthen our stride? Is it not time that we teach the gospel of the kingdom to the world, to our neighbor? In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/04/faithful-laborers</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1975-general-conference/1975-04-2060-elder-loren-c-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="5751311" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Living Prophet</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Out of curiosity, I went back in the records of the Church to look in on the April general conference of 1876 to see what kind of attention the centennial of the nation would receive at that conference. Not much was said, but I did come across what w</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03070_000_030" doc-version="2" hash="F8D7GA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="bKAUN92g6kSGkiDtNPofFg" hash="GgtSwQ">A Living Prophet</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="c6WluluSlkC1DfCZJflnxg" hash="osADdw">Loren C. Dunn</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2b58.jpg" alt="Elder Loren C. Dunn" pid="Nv1mmET0I0ygihcA9RX0Bg" hash="kckzdw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p1" pid="q5UdxPU9JkehkkTamvu1bw" hash="_x4UAw">Out of curiosity, I went back in the records of the Church to look in on the April general conference of 1876 to see what kind of attention the centennial of the nation would receive at that conference. Not much was said, but I did come across what would have to be considered the most spectacular unscheduled centennial event of the year.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p2" pid="7sB9rlQYVkuXlU4SZbCfwA" hash="_2bKTQ">It seems that on April 5, 1876, just one day before the general conference started, four powder magazines located on Arsenal Hill exploded. The hill was located one mile north and east of the temple block and the explosion of an estimated forty tons of powder scattered bits of stone and concrete all over the city and could be heard for miles around. It was reported that some thought the “day of judgment” had come. And I suspect this had some impact on the number of people who attended the opening session of general conference the following day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p3" pid="QBui_E4PeUG7_rpbcWlZ2w" hash="cR6oxA">The conference itself was very interesting. I think the theme more than anything was the payment of tithing, temple work, and sacrifice. You see, a hundred years ago the Church was only forty-six years old and the Salt Lake Temple had not yet been finished and the St. George Temple was nearing completion. So the Brethren were urging the efforts of the Saints in this direction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p4" pid="u4k2pgDZFEWf71a6cswyEw" hash="OOawtQ">President Brigham Young, of course, was President of the Church, and four members of the Twelve who were in attendance at that conference were to be future presidents of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p5" pid="NDxJxivfKkWF3VTU6zUJoA" hash="juN0UQ">Among the teachings that caught my eye at that April 1876 conference were these words from Wilford Woodruff, and I quote, “It may be asked—What are the commandments of the Lord? Many of them are contained in these records, the Bible, Book of Mormon and the Book of Doctrine and Covenants; and we have the living oracles with us, and have had from the commencement. The Lord will never leave his kingdom without a lawgiver, leader, president … to direct the affairs of his Church on the earth, for the reason that it is the dispensation of the fullness of times, in which God has set up a kingdom which is to be an everlasting kingdom, and to whose dominion there will be no end.” (<span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses,</span> 18:189).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p6" pid="JZ7DuXegSEKvGvr9M0HTQQ" hash="p2qC7A">That caused me to reflect on the absolute importance of a living oracle, and also on the words of Elder Orson F. Whitney of the Council of the Twelve, who said: “The Latter-day Saints do not do things because they happen to be printed in a book. They do not do things because God told the Jews to do them; nor do they do or leave undone anything because of instructions that Christ gave to the Nephites. Whatever is done by this Church is because God speaking from heaven in our day has commanded this Church to do it. No book presides over this Church and no books lie at its foundation. You cannot pile up books enough to take the place of God’s priesthood inspired by the power of the Holy Ghost.” (<span class="emphasis">Conference Reports,</span> Oct. 1916.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p7" pid="BATteQ3uJU-i7yRVkiT_Rg" hash="xSTHpA">Elder Whitney was not taking away from the power and majesty of the scriptures—he was just putting them into perspective. He also said, “No man ought to contend for what is in the books in the face of God’s mouthpiece who speaks for him and interprets his word. To so contend is to defer to the dead letter in preference to the living oracles, which is always a false position.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p8" pid="TNr7I-o_DEWihkr4pm8mNA" hash="gBSmCQ">What is the Lord’s oracle saying to us today? The general theme, of course, is to lengthen our stride in a variety of areas. A few weeks ago Sister Dunn and I had the opportunity to accompany President and Sister Kimball, President and Sister Tanner, and some other of the General Authorities and their wives to the area conferences in the South Pacific. May I share with you some of what I recorded President Kimball saying at these gatherings regarding missionary work?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p9" pid="Z326e-P49Uy-eMGNx0iLVw" hash="yfiywQ">In Apia, Samoa, he promised that if the Saints would hold family home evening, and see that baptisms and ordinations to the priesthood, and missions, and temple marriages were carried out, the Lord would truly bless the people and that very few would be lost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p10" pid="P3uDGv7LyE6jtoVbb8T7Bg" hash="gX2b-w">In Hamilton, New Zealand, he said, let us start a new effort to reach the sons of men all over the world. We are all called to our neighbors, and we should not go back to our maker without having properly warned our neighbors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p11" pid="vPMEl3O_UUeCrr5jfk1j3g" hash="hafdig">In Tonga, President Kimball asked that we pray to the Lord to open up the nations of the world so that we can teach the gospel everywhere. He said that he was of the belief that if we as a Church petitioned the Lord, night and morning, to change the hearts of men and open the nations of the world, the Lord would intervene and open the way whereby we can teach the gospel to all nations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p12" pid="_v-V0C4pCEm3UdeFv8aY4g" hash="CqlutA">In Sydney, Australia, he told of the operation on his throat and how they left a portion of the vocal cords, which allowed him to preach the gospel all over the world. He said he wants to continue and work very hard at doing this, but he does not want to do it alone. He then invited all the members of the Church to stand with him, and preach the gospel just as the Lord has commanded us to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p13" pid="DN8NOKUSHEyRg0qXtyTWAA" hash="5HEj-Q">Concerning missionary work, he said many young men who thought they didn’t have to go, or couldn’t go, are now finding that they can go if they plan and prepare; and then he said, certainly they should go.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p14" pid="FRvIyfUE20enkoFb2GbNTg" hash="NRElHQ">In Brisbane, Australia, President Kimball said that as a Church we must go forward, month in and month out, until we have brought the gospel to everyone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p15" pid="-58bm2sTYE6jcCkzHvrnHQ" hash="n3_c5A">In the Tahiti area conference he urged us to do missionary work and to send our boys on missions. He said that we must be serious about the missionaries going out.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p16" pid="Fu1v_G0x90elm20sMLQijA" hash="KAcmCg">I think we all recognize these messages for he has repeated them from this pulpit many times. The only thing left to be done is to follow the prophet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p17" pid="6BVcLmURd06IbALMmqZ-bg" hash="ogzLyA">President Kimball’s visit to Australia was the second official visit of a president of the Church. The first was President David O. McKay in 1955. When President McKay was in Brisbane, Australia, the mission president one day took him out to see the city. During the course of the day they were looking across the Brisbane River into a new suburb which was known as Chermside. President McKay said to the mission president, “Do we have any missionaries in that area?” The mission president said, “No.” President McKay said, “Send the missionaries in, for the people are ready.” Missionaries were sent into the area and they enjoyed tremendous success. Today Chermside is part of the Brisbane Fourth Ward of the Brisbane Australia Stake.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p18" pid="v2VzLs4zAUiJHD4XTRJxsA" hash="64rYdQ">These are the kinds of blessings that come when people not only listen to the living oracle, but do what he says. The blessings are found in doing the word and not just in hearing the word. The Church today is also responding to a prophet. President Kimball has asked every young man who is worthy and able to go into the mission field, and because of this we now have more missionaries in the field than ever before in the history of this dispensation. But many more are still needed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p19" pid="lFHCVRcD0EqBAAY15wErEg" hash="nvh3Pw">Because he has asked every family in the Church to prayerfully friendship a nonmember family and to otherwise help the missionary effort, there is a noticeable increase in the number of converts coming into the Church, but still President Kimball says we are just scratching the surface and much more needs to be done.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p20" pid="hegThllcJEeJLDTPN-ggMw" hash="KHllBA">Thank God for the scriptures which help us to grow in the gospel of Jesus Christ and to understand the nature of the Lord and the will of the Lord. But most of all, thank God for a living oracle, a legal administrator, so that we can know what the Lord wants us to do today. Under his direction we have the legal right to act in the name of God and the gospel of Jesus Christ is a living, viable influence built on current revelation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p21" pid="nPYfXA9wLEWnxYhGvPl4hA" hash="pgUySQ">Oh, truly we thank thee, oh God, for a prophet, to lead us in these latter days.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet.p22" pid="cbnBRLs_sUWwUfsT6hRT3w" hash="uPX00A">I bear you my witness that that prophet today is Spencer W. Kimball. I know that God our Father lives, and that Jesus the Christ is his son. I know this. I bear you that witness. In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/04/a-living-prophet</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1976-general-conference/1976-04-5020-elder-loren-c-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="9290514" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1976 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did Not Our Heart Burn Within Us?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, it is an honor to he at this conference. And it is an honor to serve as a missionary in Australia.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03083_000_015" doc-version="3" hash="oZdUAg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="tSd9L1zHAUuy2_AcsZv9WQ" hash="9-RzZA">Did Not Our Heart Burn Within Us?</h1><p class="authorName" pid="uCUyhu5Rs0-HJyWO_CgFww" hash="osADdw">Loren C. Dunn</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2b58.jpg" alt="Elder Loren C. Dunn" pid="4x0ZWoYH0Ui_pvHUgW8eiQ" hash="kckzdw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p1" pid="26WDte3ODEush7dZZ4kW4Q" hash="GOsJiA">My dear brothers and sisters, it is an honor to he at this conference. And it is an honor to serve as a missionary in Australia.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p2" pid="j61xMJThD0GXTIBuZOq_0g" hash="r4Yy3Q">This marks the 126th year that the Church has been in Australia.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p3" pid="heWnKnH-e0Kx5XB7gsq47g" hash="b0jRog">The two missionaries who introduced the gospel to Australia were John Murdock and Charles Wandell, who arrived in Sydney on October 30, 1851. Brother Murdock was fifty-nine years of age at the time and was one of the early stalwarts of the Church. He was in the first group to be ordained high priests by Joseph Smith. He was called on two of his missions by revelations which are in the Doctrine and Covenants. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/52.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 52:8</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/99.1" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 99:1</a>.) His wife died, leaving him twins only six hours old. These were the twins that the Prophet Joseph Smith received into his home to raise.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p4" pid="Ld8iqPHq9UOgPyijZALFqQ" hash="LxMf9Q">For a time he lived in the home of Joseph Smith and relates this incident: “During the winter that I boarded with Brother Joseph … we had a number of prayer meetings, in the Prophet’s chamber. … In one of those meetings the Prophet told us, ‘If we would humble ourselves before God, and exercise strong faith, we should see the face of the Lord.’ And about midday the visions of my mind were opened, and the eyes of my understanding were enlightened, and I saw the form of a man, most lovely, the visage of his face was sound and fair as the sun. His hair a bright silver grey, curled in a most majestic form; His eyes a keen penetrating blue, and the skin of his neck a most beautiful white and he was covered from the neck to the feet with a loose garment, pure white: Whiter than any garment I have ever before seen. His countenance was most penetrating, and yet most lovely. And while I was endeavoring to comprehend the whole personage from head to feet it slipped from me, and the vision was closed up. But it left on my mind the impression of love, for months, that I never before felt to that degree.” (John Murdock, <span class="emphasis">An Abridged Record of the Life of John Murdock,</span> p. 26.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p5" pid="QmdVch9dhEmyYsMuLrS3pg" hash="4GBmaw">Such was the man who opened the work of the gospel of Jesus Christ in Australia in this dispensation. Through the early years of the Church in Australia many joined the Church and then immigrated to either Canada or the United States. In 1955 President David O. McKay toured the country and advised the Saints to stay and build Zion in their land.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p6" pid="_izUc_QnXkWGWu886RGYtw" hash="zA-n9w">The next visit of a prophet in Australia came in February 1976 when President Spencer W. Kimball held the first area conferences. President Kimball’s message was “Grow!” And the Church is growing in Australia as well as elsewhere in the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p7" pid="qRjyO1Kdy06ZSvFU6ss41A" hash="WwZG5g">The reason for that growth is because of that which happens within any individual who looks into the Church or examines its doctrines. Perhaps I can explain it in this way. In Matthew, chapter sixteen, the Savior asked his disciples: “Whom do men say that I the Son of man am?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p8" pid="uACtXoesaUWQQFlOnGQjqw" hash="j7ecPg">“And they said, Some say that thou art John the Baptist: some, Elias; and others, Jeremias, or one of the prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p9" pid="LMhvFL-y0k62-tpeC6k3_A" hash="zYTRdg">“He saith unto them, But whom say ye that I am?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p10" pid="0XmATth0DkGKdCIrYU3jvQ" hash="3d-4RA">“And Simon Peter answered and said, Thou art the Christ, the Son of the living God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p11" pid="xPMfv3u95UW5iU949S_FDw" hash="tNK7fg">“And Jesus answered and said unto him, Blessed art thou, Simon Bar-jona: for flesh and blood hath not revealed it unto thee, but my Father which is in heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/16.13-17" class="scriptureRef">Matt 16:13–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p12" pid="FVR98YIscUuupYq2BBpdvg" hash="2cxS_Q">Although Peter walked and talked with the Savior and had observed many of his miracles, yet when he said, “Thou art the Christ, the Son of the living God,” the Savior pointed out that it wasn’t flesh and blood that revealed this to Peter, but his Father in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p13" pid="uQsU_dWC20miecsLy-WtcQ" hash="njz2FA">This tells us that there is a more certain way of knowing than actually seeing with our eyes; for there were many who saw Jesus Christ but knew him not as the Son of God. Those that did know him knew him because it was revealed to them by our Father in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p14" pid="zOdmFo0zJU6C-sXaluUI3w" hash="LZpPuA">This witness of the Spirit is mentioned in Luke, chapter twenty-four, as two of the disciples were walking along the road to a village called Emmaus. The Savior himself came and walked and talked with them, but they did “not know him” until right at the very end when their eyes were opened and they knew him. Verse 32 says: “And they said one to another, did not our heart burn within us, while he talked with us by the way, and while he opened to us the scriptures?” [<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/24.32" class="scriptureRef">Luke 24:32</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p15" pid="Y9yxNp7mGEqj3dgNTdwTSA" hash="pLCMJQ">With all the logic and outward evidences of the truthfulness of the gospel, it still comes down to the witness of the Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p16" pid="Y9lNkiopO0i0prhBS2kKdA" hash="ZBoHiQ">“Did not our heart burn within us?” is as applicable today to a person seeking the gospel of Jesus Christ as it was during the time of Christ or in John Murdock’s day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p17" pid="BI2RYO76002pHKpP-7Kdkw" hash="Blhndg">In modern revelation the Lord has established a spiritual test to find truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p18" pid="WF5X4xUiJEigDVcrYWGfdA" hash="2n3F2A">He says in the ninth section of the Doctrine and Covenants simply: “But, behold, I say unto you, that you must study it out in your mind; then you must ask me if it be right, and if it is right I will cause that your bosom shall burn within you; therefore, you shall feel that it is right.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/9.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 9:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p19" pid="aTJiN3uJiketb4Ou6c6Pdw" hash="G6GNEw">The words “you shall feel that it is right” refer to a feeling of peace and warmth, a feeling that touches the soul. For an investigator of the truth, this feeling begins to come when the missionaries come and leave their message. They can feel it in the home after the missionaries leave. They can feel it in the congregations of the Saints; and they can feel it as they read and study and pray about the message. It is a feeling that is unique in its peace and joy because it emanates from Jesus Christ. It is that feeling which brings a greater knowledge and a more sure witness than even flesh and bones.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p20" pid="r2W8WofdZk217Ha3iI394Q" hash="dTlr7Q">A recent convert from Canberra, Australia, says the following: “I was born into a religious family where religion was taken seriously. I had a strict Christian upbringing. However, I drifted away from the church at about twenty years of age when I left home to attend teachers college.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p21" pid="LXu8r6dZ_U60TQY9Oiofew" hash="f_oYug">“From that time on I felt an emptiness of purpose in some way, and each year or so would find me searching out and studying a new spiritual creed. I studied yoga and practiced meditation, read about Hinduism, Buddhism, Zen Buddhism, and most of the Protestant religions and Judaism. Somehow none of these held out anything I was seeking. Then I stopped searching, and when the elders came calling, I had mixed feelings about letting them in. I did not want yet another fruitless search, but I thought it only reasonable to hear the message and then decide. For a few lessons I was not convinced that there was anything different in the lessons from what I had already heard elsewhere. Then slowly, through the patience of the elders, I began to get the feeling that all they were saying was really true. They urged me to pray frequently, which I did; but still I was not sure. They explained how the Holy Ghost could come into one’s heart, and one could perhaps feel a warm glow inside. This was rather hard for me to imagine, but I believed them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p22" pid="mHN_qO15uE6BMj-VzWMeuA" hash="0CnALA">“One night the elders challenged me to take baptism the very next Saturday. I was surprised and felt I wasn’t ready, but I did agree to be baptized a week later, giving myself more time for questions and prayer. Then Elder Hurd asked Elder Nelson if he would bear his testimony to me. He did it so fervently that about halfway through I felt a warm spot in my heart which seemed to be coming from Elder Nelson; and as he spoke, it increased in size and intensity like a small cloud inside of me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p23" pid="oQEJ__OZ10iDb9VLkcbCJA" hash="NjrsuQ">“When he had finished, both elders assured me that they had felt the presence of the Holy Ghost, but I didn’t tell them of my experience until a few days later. I felt too overcome to speak of it. Before they left they asked me to read Third Nephi, chapters 11 to 26, in the Book of Mormon before going to bed that night. As soon as they went out the door, I read avidly, and as I did, the warm glow returned to me and I needed no more convincing.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p24" pid="QQC-dzaKRUieI7aJRgLpXg" hash="XL7x7Q">Not every experience will be just like this; but to greater or lesser degree, that same Spirit will come into the life of every soul who desires to know the truth. Each member of the Church and each soul who sincerely investigates the teachings by study, prayer, and attending church will receive his answer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p25" pid="SETmEq9Gk0O660hArtcw-w" hash="GfAdqQ">It is as simple as that. Flesh and blood do not reveal it, but our Father which is in heaven. At some time in the investigation process, this confirming spirit will come into the soul, and truth will be the result. Should there be someone watching or listening at this time who is thinking of looking into the Church or studying its doctrines, we offer this to you. There is nothing complicated or difficult about it. It requires only a person who desires to know the truth and who is willing to turn to the Lord with all his heart and ask about that which he reads and hears.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us.p26" pid="QXfKD561sk672FJiGUyOfg" hash="bspGmQ">I, too, have felt that Spirit; I, too, know that God lives and that Jesus the Christ is his Son. This is not my philosophy; this is not my belief. This is a knowledge borne by the Spirit. This Church is true. Joseph Smith was a prophet of God. Spencer W. Kimball is a prophet of God today. We are in the Lord’s service. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1977/04/did-not-our-heart-burn-within-us</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1977-general-conference/1977-04-2070-elder-loren-c-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="5037038" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 1977 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Spirit Giveth Life</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The most unique feature of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is that it is governed by the Savior, through the promptings and direction of the Spirit.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03109_000_027" doc-version="2" hash="PDMdVw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="CbgUWgfrhE6sD1fVYv2LxQ" hash="-Wlq_g">The Spirit Giveth Life</h1><p class="authorName" guid="1a14b2cb-b5b2-48cb-a012-92bb04af8eeb" pid="taiHcsdd6Ealwn-T4bqeuQ" hash="osADdw">Loren C. Dunn</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="ced7f946-8543-4b68-9b3d-dc11bc866165">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2b58.jpg" alt="Elder Loren C. Dunn" guid="ecc69534-7e07-437f-aecd-46e4682a254a" pid="238W2qUGQk-huy7mGa1REA" hash="kckzdw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="IsNmI4q1h0yb5YJ6BsczVg" hash="eznihQ">The most unique feature of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is that it is governed by the Savior, through the promptings and direction of the Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="VuRMr_KQf0-EK7uW4d9kyw" hash="9sqE5w">Those called to serve will prayerfully seek the inspiration of the Spirit to supplement and even go before their own natural abilities. Whenever the Church is upon the earth, there is always this reference to the Spirit as a guide. This is true, no matter what the background of the leaders might be.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="m-H5UATATEyteDMvyv3bxg" hash="Yf-vwQ">Two classic examples of this are Paul, the great New Testament prophet, and Brigham Young, the second president of the Church. Paul was a Pharisee and a pupil of Gamaliel. In addition to this, he was a member of the Sanhedrin. If anyone could approach his work with the credentials of an intellectual and a scholar, he could. Yet after his conversion, he was very careful to draw a distinction between these two approaches. In his letter to the Corinthians, he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="c04UCvmZgEur3hpHCp3R6w" hash="Aa6cGA">“Now we have received, not the spirit of the world, but the spirit which is of God; that we might know the things that are freely given to us of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="7CFcCMQVzUWPgWg43D38yA" hash="GLjOhw">“Which things also we speak, not in the words which man’s wisdom teacheth, but which the Holy Ghost teacheth; comparing spiritual things with spiritual.” (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/2.11-14" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 2:11–14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="KVAKO9puvke3SP2QOz7SBg" hash="vEAPzg">Brigham Young was a pragmatist, level-headed and down-to-earth. A glazier by trade, he became the second president of the Church after the death of the Prophet Joseph Smith. He led the Saints into a trackless waste and kept them from perishing until they forged a new life by making the desert blossom as the rose (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/35.1" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 35:1</a>). He recognized the practical and sensible aspects of religious life and service to God; yet from this down-to-earth, practical prophet come these words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="HC5nhZe3oE6sBz5Yyc-w0A" hash="Wpp5zg">“The eye, the ear, the hand, all the senses may be deceived, but the Spirit of God cannot be deceived; and when inspired with that Spirit, the whole man is filled with knowledge, he can see with a spiritual eye, and he knows that which is beyond the power of man to controvert” (<span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses,</span> 16:46).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="yY3JUA6ZSkWH7d-qcgdJ8Q" hash="e_mU2Q">We learn from these two great prophets that there is need to go beyond the word and find the power and strength that can come from the Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="PG0zxwhseEqV3B77ZfS4iQ" hash="_il2Tg">When we speak of the Spirit, we refer to the gift of the Holy Ghost. While the light of Christ enlightens all who come into the world, the spirit of the Holy Ghost is something more. The Holy Ghost is the third member of the Godhead; a personage of spirit, he speaks not for himself, but testifies to all that Jesus is the Christ, the Son of God, and conveys to man the mind and will of the Lord (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/16.13-15" class="scriptureRef">John 16:13–15</a>). He has a sanctifying and cleansing influence upon the souls of men and is the source of spiritual gifts. Just as Ephesians tells us that there is one Lord, one faith, and one baptism (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/4.5" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 4:5</a>), so this gift of the Holy Ghost can only come in one way. Only the right authority is acceptable for baptism and conferring the gift of the Holy Ghost, and this was made clear when Paul traveled to Ephesus and rebaptized some who had not been baptized with the right authority and then conferred upon them the Holy Ghost (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/19.title" class="scriptureRef">Acts 19</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="4cDle6TijkmT4nwV-QbQWg" hash="gdsSYQ">While the Spirit of the Holy Ghost will witness to a person that this is the gospel of Jesus Christ, the gift of the Holy Ghost comes only after a person has been baptized into the Church. It can be identified with feelings of peace and assurance to the prayerful and honest seeker for truth, and thus the scripture:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="L1Ry-rpskUyDq-l2Dpsedg" hash="C5DZzg">“Yea, behold, I will tell you in your mind and in your heart, by the Holy Ghost, which shall come upon you and which shall dwell in your heart” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/8.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 8:2</a>). “Therefore, you shall feel that it is right” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/9.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 9:8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="sS-I9irgrUSaTy7wsQJ8Mw" hash="Ys6bXQ">Some think that our ultimate judgment and reward will be based on how many laws and commandments we keep and how many we do not keep. While in a sense this is true, it misses the broader and spiritual purpose for keeping the commandments. When I was younger, I lived to play basketball. It was on my mind constantly. I spent countless hours practicing. Gradually I began to go through the moves automatically, without thinking about them. Physically and mentally I had become conditioned to do certain things by instinct. I had practiced them until they became natural to me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="_JU5fEFffEu6hnoHTpxO7A" hash="22fdCg">In like manner, we keep the commandments and teachings of the gospel in order to condition us spiritually. It is not a matter of how many laws we keep and how many we do not keep. We keep the commandments because they are the laws that govern the Spirit. The Spirit in turn will sanctify us, condition us spiritually, and eventually prepare us to live in the kingdom where God is. Hence the scripture: “They who are not sanctified through the law which I have given unto you, even the law of Christ, must inherit another kingdom” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:21</a>). The laws that govern the Spirit are nothing more nor less than the laws that govern the Church. In addition, there is also an outpouring of the Spirit for those loyal to and willing to uphold the prophet and others who have been called to preside.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="wXkUjykY1UmQKKoMAD8KZw" hash="UIGIxA">That the Spirit can and should have power in our lives and that we can have definite and measurable experiences associated with the Spirit is quite clear. One need only refer to the great variety of gifts of the Spirit promised to all who live the laws and commandments of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="faGBzHoNEU-Lgt3ZONkMjg" hash="2XZEiQ">We should seek the Spirit through the prayer of faith and through keeping the commandments, including partaking of the sacrament worthily, so that we might “have his Spirit to be with [us]” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.79" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:79</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="SRkl0V4mukOuedcC6KWUTQ" hash="aaYZBw">The sons of Mosiah, for instance, were fasting and praying in preparation for their mission to the Lamanites; they wanted a portion of the Spirit of the Lord to go with them and abide with them. The answer is recorded in this verse: “And it came to pass that the Lord did visit them with his Spirit, and said unto them: Be comforted. And they were comforted” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/17.10" class="scriptureRef">Alma 17:10</a>). Would you not be comforted if the Lord, by his Spirit, gave you the same experience?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="t2BkN82MWkWvPtT30Btd2w" hash="uH3IbQ">The prophet Alma says: “And now behold, I ask of you, my brethren of the church, have ye spiritually been born of God? Have ye received his image in your countenances? Have ye experienced this mighty change in your hearts?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.14" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="A1alo-guEU6F6zNTfCEqhg" hash="7xV2NA">Alma was making sure that the members of the Church had not just received the gift of the Holy Ghost, but also had truly received the sanctifying and cleansing power of that great Spirit. He said the way you can tell is when you become refreshed spiritually, as if you had been born anew. He said that the feelings and attitudes of your heart will be truly changed for the good. That your very appearance will begin to take upon itself the image of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="iGIQpei6ZkGrCrWfAUZDIA" hash="9RuIFQ">What a great and powerful friend is this gift of the Holy Ghost! Certainly all who will turn to the Savior and abide by his laws will be healed by this Spirit (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/9.13" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 9:13</a>). They will have the mind of Christ (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/2.16" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 2:16</a>), they will be “partakers of the divine nature” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-pet/1.4" class="scriptureRef">2 Pet. 1:4</a>), they will begin to have the image of Christ in their countenances (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.14" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:14</a>). Truly the gospel comes, as Paul said, not only in word, “but also in power,” the sanctifying, cleansing, soul-enlarging power of the Holy Spirit (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-thes/1.5" class="scriptureRef">1 Thes. 1:5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="yi2-Uix1G0-qrI9gk0DBHw" hash="iGM1cA">After the death of the Prophet Joseph Smith, Brigham Young had a dream in which Joseph Smith appeared to him with the following advice: “Tell the brethren to keep their hearts open to conviction, so that when the Holy Ghost comes to them, their hearts will be ready to receive it. They can tell the Spirit of the Lord from all other spirits; it will whisper peace and joy to their souls; it will take malice, hatred, strife and all evil from their hearts; and their whole desire will be to do good, bring forth righteousness and build up the kingdom of God. Tell the brethren if they will follow the spirit of the Lord they will go right. Be sure to tell the people to keep the Spirit,” he said. (Elden J. Watson, comp., <span class="emphasis">Manuscript History of Brigham Young 1846–1847,</span> Salt Lake City, 1971, pp. 529–30.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="9dvgudLhak2W2eAHCqcuAg" hash="ru8F7Q">And these final words from the Doctrine and Covenants: “Therefore, sanctify yourselves that your minds become single to God, and the days will come that you shall see him; for he will unveil his face unto you, and it shall be in his own time, and in his own way, and according to his own will” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.68" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:68</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="-eYVNmfPsEaTM64mBVnpbg" hash="X5LhTA">And thus we have the end result of the workings of the Spirit, to bring us face to face with Jesus Christ, our Savior and Redeemer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="JrIQNmHNpUmSLN10Y6uvMg" hash="bHPB9Q">Loyalty to the prophets and prayerful obedience to the word of God will bring the power of the Spirit. The enlarging influence of the Spirit will sanctify us, will condition us spiritually, and prepare us to see Him face to face and converse as one speaketh to another, and to live in his kingdom, even the celestial kingdom.</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.f1" guid="c99947ec-c8fc-4130-9e22-85d292700f82">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="bLLxydBBc0CKxl3wBpbR_g" hash="3txmQQ">
            <span class="emphasis">The witness of the Holy Ghost</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="mUc2GYLyVkOEYeDRgx1zrw" hash="8UO1xw">
            <span class="emphasis">As borne by those who know</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="6ZiFfTNZCEGSNU3E7gkg4w" hash="F7p12g">
            <span class="emphasis">Has lifted me again to thee,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="qucj8AO1HUeW4gEQ9Q2Yuw" hash="1XbPjg">
            <span class="emphasis">O Father of my soul.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="eH9nRQfWhkK5cEkUIriPgw" hash="_ctLzQ">
            <span class="emphasis">While listening to them testify,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="lwjkj8reVE2X2clSLHy7fA" hash="OHDYiA">
            <span class="emphasis">The Spirit fills my heart,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="wxSau63kLEe4u8TTTx2KhA" hash="Wsph3Q">
            <span class="emphasis">Dispels the gloom, Confirms the right.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="gbM6-WnwkU6WCmrO1yqYfw" hash="giE-ng">
            <span class="emphasis">Pure truth it does impart.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="2XhFciRHjEuqQxyc0-3IMQ" hash="M2n24g">
            <span class="emphasis">I know that thou are in thy heav’n,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="N6DtAMl5nE-t_fAEFbF3Vw" hash="KmFEfA">
            <span class="emphasis">I know the Savior reigns;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="y__T7XieckqivBPtSBZu9A" hash="TpkbJw">
            <span class="emphasis">I know a prophet speaks to us</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="elSV-ywPk0SjBvVjmx6ptg" hash="bbRvXw">
            <span class="emphasis">For our eternal gain.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="7qscwQrYjEOTBr8CnxvksA" hash="62oUmw">
            <span class="emphasis">The Holy Spirit moves all doubt</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="NaRMrvdikEGvtyjsc8uGUg" hash="afscAQ">
            <span class="emphasis">It lights the heart of man.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="fvYGPUNl8EW9uRlxSDpLdg" hash="HMR7OA">
            <span class="emphasis">It says to all, “return to me,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="f9y0lhCidEukO5fyDZfUjw" hash="3u4DLw">
            <span class="emphasis">Come follow my great plan.”</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="O6xg-ZmGc0ml-HX2lNB9dw" hash="8qFVug">
            <span class="emphasis">My eyes are wet, my heart is full,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="3-c0fEcbLkGpEDcaws92hQ" hash="dGYdFw">
            <span class="emphasis">The Spirit speaks today.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="kMgmEW2hDUODsWTT7MXgBw" hash="W3Z2VA">
            <span class="emphasis">Oh Lord, wilt thou my life renew</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="XkDNt_MpXUuhYCgre2O1xw" hash="YPE4qA">
            <span class="emphasis">And in my bosom stay.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="sysAwmeqy0elBRa9_Ks9WA" hash="7wxo4A">
            <span class="emphasis">As testimony fills my heart,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="dNZjVDG8lkSQUjt1z9_bZw" hash="_kQbZw">
            <span class="emphasis">It dulls the pain of days;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="9ItOVvlvnECSiNA1Aijmww" hash="8RUNeA">
            <span class="emphasis">For one brief moment heaven’s view</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="bpxvZfh9H06aj_2vNUI2jQ" hash="BCs1Eg">
            <span class="emphasis">Is fixed before my gaze.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life.p" pid="4CWXheLPuUCtTejB2OUKug" hash="YUqVfw">May the Lord help us to reach beyond the words of life and to capture this great spirit, I pray. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2b58.jpg" alt="Elder Loren C. Dunn" guid="ecc69534-7e07-437f-aecd-46e4682a254a" pid="rwcdw6vZ4kmtt1M0sdacPQ" hash="kckzdw1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="ecc69534-7e07-437f-aecd-46e4682a254a"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1979/04/the-spirit-giveth-life</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1979-general-conference/1979-04-5020-elder-loren-c-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="5205884" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 1979 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Bridges to Faith</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I have been inspired, as I know you have, with the singing of this lovely choir, and I think especially of their song at the beginning of this meeting, “True to the Faith.” It is faith that I would like to speak about this afternoon.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03135_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="-EdeNg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="eIF0GFnxU0iND43rNRUkuw" hash="cpwr2g">Building Bridges to Faith</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="BCbinnHg0EKrDOFIfH41pw" hash="osADdw">Loren C. Dunn</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2b58.jpg" alt="Elder Loren C. Dunn" pid="FiqgOVRa8keAurseXMarMw" hash="kckzdw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p1" pid="93lQ45IF90KL7E3f46v0GA" hash="gkQddw">I have been inspired, as I know you have, with the singing of this lovely choir, and I think especially of their song at the beginning of this meeting, “True to the Faith.” It is faith that I would like to speak about this afternoon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p2" pid="jVP6fqmJtkCg_4doufSeuw" hash="uGY9EQ">We have been referred to as a believing people. Certainly individual faith is the foundation stone of the gospel and the quality which is most important to us as individuals.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p3" pid="QLkYMa7gCEaAOpzfcWKQ_Q" hash="cxr_bw">Joseph Smith said, “Faith is the assurance which men have of the existence of things which they have not seen, and the principle of action in all intelligent beings. … [It] is the first great governing principle.” (<span class="emphasis">Lectures on Faith,</span> comp. N. B. Lundwall, Salt Lake City: N. B. Lundwall, n.d., pp. 7, 10.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p4" pid="02CCLQZyzE-sdeH87NmfBA" hash="YDbT6w">And Jacob teaches that the Lord commands all men that they must have “perfect faith in the Holy One of Israel, or they cannot be saved in the Kingdom of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/9.23" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 9:23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p5" pid="aNPdaRVGakKHqE8K2t9VIw" hash="hhEJYg">As a principle of power and of action, and as the key to our salvation, our individual faith, then, becomes of absolute importance to us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p6" pid="_h1KJzcjkUq4roE6py6IwQ" hash="YkkhSQ">Paul admonished us to “be thou an example of the believers, in word, in conversation, in charity, in spirit, in faith, in purity.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-tim/4.12" class="scriptureRef">1 Tim. 4:12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p7" pid="eF3KTNDd8kmpXv48f4WTTQ" hash="4Su32g">“If ye can no more than desire to believe,” said Alma, “let this desire work in you, even until ye believe in a manner that ye can give place for a portion of my words.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.27" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p8" pid="AQZ-vy1lyEewUjChn4nsmg" hash="3js_6A">Moroni says, “Dispute not because ye see not, for ye receive no witness until after the trial of your faith.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.6" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p9" pid="sfYQ37Ilb0OesliKazqvIw" hash="TW8zIA">There are many steps a person can take to develop the gift and power of faith. In the next few minutes I would like to suggest six of these steps.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p10" pid="95F4UgmJAk-mU1oLbLT2tA" hash="FnqTnA">Number one: Faith is the ability to recognize the Lord as all-powerful and the giver of all blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p11" pid="3XPFadG6oESyYHF0aCEu8Q" hash="eb_14w">As King Benjamin put it:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p12" pid="ro1Hb5ZuM0asEpmbtxmG_g" hash="Sp_jxA">“Believe in God; believe that he is, and that he created all things, both in heaven and in earth; believe that he has all wisdom, and all power, both in heaven and in earth; believe that man doth not comprehend all things which the Lord can comprehend.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p13" pid="a3h8eaXGFUi0y3VbkG32og" hash="0Ilz6g">Sometimes we compartmentalize. We pray about one thing and worry about something else. We seem to limit the ability of the Lord to help us in every aspect of our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p14" pid="n_ZcrNLKRESbXw5UFLUCSQ" hash="03eZmQ">John A. Widtsoe tells us the following:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p15" pid="ldZMWrwSUE6lsLQclxYB0w" hash="mMo0OA">“For several years, under a Federal grant with my staff of workers we had gathered thousands of data in the field of soil moisture; but I could not extract any general law running through them. I gave up at last. My wife and I went to the temple that day to forget the failure. In the third endowment room, out of the unseen, came the solution, which has long since gone into print.” (<span class="emphasis">In A Sunlit Land: The Autobiography of John A. Widtsoe,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret News Press, 1952, p. 177.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p16" pid="ZRa8IIGRtkWpqnIHm-Hi0A" hash="fPcpNg">Faith, then, is the realization that the Lord can help us with all things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p17" pid="dv3-Z2vZcEqyFKw2Pcut7Q" hash="CG8WOw">Number two: Faith is the ability to do what we are prompted to do, and when we are prompted to do it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p18" pid="lqInVqlqfkaRnpy-oGTSuw" hash="euYTDQ">A few years ago when we were presiding over the Sydney Mission, I was earnestly seeking a blessing from the Lord. The mission had done well but was pausing on a plateau, and we needed to move ahead once again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p19" pid="lyWUQ4aYOkyYxWYWzStiKg" hash="P6grKw">On one particular day I was fasting and praying that the Lord would lead us to a new level of achievement. In the midst of my prayers came the clear impression to seek out my son and give him a blessing. I followed the prompting and found my son, whom I am close to, in another part of the house, attending to his high school studies.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p20" pid="a1_sr9Keg0mHJbIzsg4jpg" hash="uCyXcw">I said, “How are things going?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p21" pid="6iDRADcQY0mnm-pjm2XHrA" hash="OmnwYA">He answered, in typical teenage fashion, “Why?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p22" pid="4qwYhX37mUKK65l9N1mosQ" hash="VW3WfQ">Not knowing what else to say, I asked, “Do you want a blessing?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p23" pid="b8U2IzLuNkmTxPSWW7PTew" hash="j7L37g">He looked at me in stunned silence for a few seconds and then said, “Yes.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p24" pid="wyVdf--REEO8uDON4pYsBA" hash="_cmo_w">The inspiration that followed from that blessing proved to be of great importance to both my son and me. It was an experience that neither of us will forget.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p25" pid="QBJcvpGzYUep_4soaz50nw" hash="9WCUxw">Yet this would have been lost had I stopped to question why the Lord was turning me to my first responsibility, my family, when I was seeking a blessing for the mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p26" pid="32j3AyTSA0yRoJOWyXbzdg" hash="peZV1g">Number three: Faith is the ability to live the laws of God that control the blessings we are in need of. While we should not keep the commandments just to receive blessings, nevertheless, the blessings are there.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p27" pid="bSSG4N0xtkGCNeJBkQYa6g" hash="CkYUmw">Harold B. Lee tells the experience of praying very hard for a material blessing he needed badly. He states that one day while he was praying for this blessing, he remembered that he had recently received some income that he had not yet tithed. It was as if, he said, the accusing voice of the Lord was saying: You want a blessing from me but you have not been obedient to the laws upon which such blessings are based. (“Faith,” address delivered at Brigham Young University, 28 Jun 1955, tape in Historical Department Archives.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p28" pid="syndsSvokUeJf0r8R8j-9A" hash="_YGDPQ">He said that he went and paid the tithing on that income, and then he again sought that particular blessing of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p29" pid="eD-49M2bx02a9ssB3S1Lvg" hash="KLiGeQ">Number four: Faith is the ability to act “as if.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p30" pid="SlpHZgVYEU-zRjfslxTTPA" hash="ssBO8w">In his teachings, Paul said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p31" pid="0RmeVfk7MEy78NMXnXgCIQ" hash="MyRgdw">“By faith Noah, being warned of God of things not seen … prepared an ark to the saving of his house.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/11.7" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 11:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p32" pid="kOujpBzYn0iPT9Pa1lWj1Q" hash="GsR2xg">President Kimball gives us this insight to Noah and the ark:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p33" pid="kYw8NjMLg0KMFLDXNckVJA" hash="1wgOpA">“As yet there was no evidence of rain and flood. … His warnings were considered irrational. … How foolish to build an ark on dry ground with the sun shining and life moving forward as usual! But time ran out. … The floods came. The disobedient … were drowned. The miracle of the ark followed the faith manifested in its building.” (<span class="emphasis">Faith Precedes the Miracle,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret Book, 1972, pp. 5–6.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p34" pid="Y8gQYJmnQEuDTTnPIzF9rA" hash="9G0kdw">Many years ago during the dark days of World War II, Elvon W. Orme, the president of the Australia Mission was invited to a faithful widow’s house for Sunday dinner. Rationing had taken its toll, and many of the good foods had long since disappeared from the shelves of the local stores.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p35" pid="R-ytZphcd0q46w-xiIyzJA" hash="1vllNQ">When the president arrived, he was shocked to find a table filled with foods that were in short supply and had not been seen for months.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p36" pid="yxb224n8sUGMyYpbMuun9A" hash="CnMBGA">“I can’t eat this,” he said, almost embarrassed that he was taking it out of the mouth of a widow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p37" pid="htIiBIy-_0OAugQgeteRCQ" hash="X83fIA">“I’m afraid you’ll have to,” she said. “You see, I listened to the Brethren years ago and put in my year’s supply, and this is the only kind of food I have.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p38" pid="qwatRaH_tUic18L3iPGZLA" hash="BxM48Q">She showed the faith to act “as if” by storing food, and the faith produced a miracle in the time of need.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p39" pid="0D0JcBJc1k6NK1ahyMQRHA" hash="f2luTw">I wonder how many Saints will be able to withstand the disaster of their own personal flood by showing faith in the advice of modern prophets and building an ark of family preparedness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p40" pid="MpXuKrF6j0qVq1Lm2Xt_Wg" hash="P3Wnyw">Number five: Faith is the ability to be charitable and to believe in people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p41" pid="SBtG6cKWYk-VzUF6-6Jrnw" hash="OqnnlA">The Savior of the world is the foremost example of this love. After having been rejected and despised, he asked his Father to forgive those who crucified him because “they know not what they do.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/23.34" class="scriptureRef">Luke 23:34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p42" pid="pRCk0RTRlEid5onMoXomjQ" hash="tkJhqg">Joseph Smith is another example. After living a life filled with trials and betrayals, he said as he was going to Carthage:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p43" pid="UpoUjWvRYEOEJ8qRuLrvVA" hash="0pFk4g">“I am going like a lamb to the slaughter, but … I have a conscience void of offense toward … all men.” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 6:555; italics omitted.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p44" pid="zhPolzzX9U2PveHUl48oDA" hash="KdrQ3w">I knew a man once whom I respected very much and who had this quality. On one occasion, a beggar came from out of town and appeared at his door and asked for money. My friend said, “I have an old barn that needs painting. If you want to paint it, I’ll pay you for it.” They went out to look at the barn, and then the man was sent to England’s paint store and arrangements were made for him to pick up the paint he needed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p45" pid="qF9rvVuCkkaTa3Pt4Hytcg" hash="D9qxjQ">The barn was painted, and the man was paid and left town. Shortly after, Mr. England called my friend and said that the man had picked up far more paint than was needed to paint the barn. In short, my friend had been taken.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p46" pid="aQYgEKr1I0GuTLtUrJf2Zg" hash="s8a6xA">Yet, he took the opportunity to teach his sons a lesson.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p47" pid="RenS-vBz4EKoKQyaAKtB-g" hash="IXJUXQ">“Had I known what he did, I would have stopped him,” he said. “But we have our painted barn, and the painter, whatever his problems, will always know that there was someone willing to believe in him.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p48" pid="wIIL3bk0WU24c_s2_xnjtA" hash="xZOF8g">Faith cannot be nourished in a heart that has been made hard by continued cynicism, skepticism, and unforgiveness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p49" pid="IdJlND-UdUOslnfkIWPUHg" hash="bw9iiw">A person who cannot see the good in people not only destroys his own faith, but also becomes a basically unhappy person.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p50" pid="bV98AhaKmkaeXVOKAPEW9w" hash="13IGgg">Number six: Faith is the ability to allow ourselves to be guided by the priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p51" pid="DB6I72zv-EaqSMLgBWSxmw" hash="7aQySQ">Paul teaches us this important truth:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p52" pid="13FG9UVNDEG5evVFHU7FDA" hash="tmBB_w">“And he [the Lord] gave some, apostles; and some, prophets; and some, evangelists; and some, pastors and teachers.” And here he tells us why these priesthood leaders have been given to the Saints: “till we all come in the unity of the faith, and of the knowledge of the Son of God, unto a perfect man, unto the measure of the stature of the fulness of Christ.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/4.11,13" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 4:11, 13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p53" pid="XgMz9b2Fn0OIK4BnBRJhrQ" hash="0iS6Dg">Priesthood leaders, all leaders who have been called by revelation under the hands of the priesthood, have been given to us so we can come to a unity of the faith, to the end that we might know the Savior and have his image in our countenance and become like him, “that every man might speak in the name of God the Lord, even the Savior of the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.20" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p54" pid="wTXC-jmp-ECprDUESY_SqQ" hash="G_no_Q">Years ago, President Joseph Fielding Smith, then a member of the Quorum of the Twelve, attended a stake conference where a relatively new stake president had been called. A man repeatedly came up to President Smith and asked him for counsel concerning a personal matter. Finally, President Smith said he would see the man, provided the new stake president could be there. As the man unfolded his situation, the stake president was prompted with what the person needed to do. Yet President Smith listened to the brother and surprised everyone by saying, “I have no counsel for you.” The man was surprised, and he left. After he had gone, President Smith turned to the stake president and said, “I knew how to counsel that man, but I was also prompted to know that he would go against the counsel. So rather than condemn him for going against the counsel of the priesthood, I told him nothing.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p55" pid="Q7shUupQUUu7YbClhJPbUA" hash="mM4Byg">From this we learn that it is not enough to seek the direction of those whom God has called to lead us—but we must come with a willingness to follow the counsel of inspired leaders in order to develop our faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p56" pid="hWsLF9JlNE6c-GLOQcg-6w" hash="Tu2LAg">Latter-day Saints need to believe. They need to take every opportunity to develop faith, both in their own lives and in the lives of others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p57" pid="Q21O66tIeUClSGlosCiygg" hash="2oPYew">Faith is a part of our heritage. Those who embrace the gospel of Jesus Christ are the blood of Israel, and characteristic of the house of Israel is the ability to believe. Some have referred to it as “believing blood.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p58" pid="FGxxwqlQb0-66l9DEZLApA" hash="odpBlg">My faith is both a beacon and a foundation stone. It is born of the Spirit and enriched by a multitude of prayers and promptings. It lifts my soul upwards. It opens my heart to peace and joy. It nourishes and reaffirms those things that I fully know. My faith is such that I know God lives. I know he lives and Jesus is the Christ and Joseph Smith was a true prophet and we sit in the midst of apostles and prophets today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith.p59" pid="VvyH1INoNECzGu9Oj5k3CA" hash="GzvWUQ">May the Lord bless us with faith as we go forward in our lives, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1981/04/building-bridges-to-faith</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1981-general-conference/1981-04-2050-elder-loren-c-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="6414773" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 1981 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Receiving a Prophet</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1983/04/receiving-a-prophet?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My brothers and sisters, I’m very grateful to be here this afternoon, and I want to begin my talk by bearing testimony to you of the truthfulness of this work. I know that God lives and that Jesus is the Christ and that this is their work. I know tha</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/receiving-a-prophet" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03161_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="03AxDQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/receiving-a-prophet.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="nd9xT71n70Wjf_EMJaQMng" hash="cccTlA">Receiving a Prophet</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="sTKmsMS_7UOfNKthnjhBBA" hash="osADdw">Loren C. Dunn</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/receiving-a-prophet.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2b58.jpg" alt="Elder Loren C. Dunn" pid="GObxw6K0LUWhWxliqQfVqg" hash="kckzdw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/receiving-a-prophet.p1" pid="CJVTU_NK3ki4r3L492b0bw" hash="qfL2pg">My brothers and sisters, I’m very grateful to be here this afternoon, and I want to begin my talk by bearing testimony to you of the truthfulness of this work. I know that God lives and that Jesus is the Christ and that this is their work. I know that Joseph Smith was a prophet of God, and that Spencer W. Kimball is a prophet of God today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/receiving-a-prophet.p2" pid="_8iAvWRv80WVzMvSeIC_Kw" hash="XIf9Ag">I would like to share an experience or two with you. When I was growing up, Heber J. Grant was the President of the Church. My father always prayed for President Grant. And he had great personal feeling for him because President Grant at one time was president of the Tooele Stake, and my father at that time was president of the Tooele Stake. President Grant became ill and passed away, and I can remember after the funeral kneeling in family prayer as a young boy and hearing my father praying with the same love and devotion and feeling for the next prophet, the next President of the Church, George Albert Smith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/receiving-a-prophet.p3" pid="humO13BHKUanBcFr03DIVg" hash="O-yzqQ">As a youth, I was surprised because I had never heard anybody pray for any prophet other than Heber J. Grant. And I felt almost cheated—like my father was turning away from a good friend. But as the time went on, through that experience and other experiences, he taught me a very valuable lesson—you see, he had great love and appreciation for President Grant, and that would never change, but in his heart I realized that he had saved his greatest love and his greatest loyalty for his God, and whomever God would send he would sustain and uphold and pray for and embrace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/receiving-a-prophet.p4" pid="6LdsgKMQ7UG2nmRB2YY-Eg" hash="6Cpxig">Not very long ago, my family and I had the opportunity to preside over the Australia Sydney Mission. I had come out of the Missionary Department, and I suppose my missionary views were very conservative. At any rate, as we began our work in the Australia Sydney Mission, we had some modest, but good, successes, and I felt comfortable about what we were doing—until President Kimball spoke to us. In his own manner and in his own way, he said, “Brother Dunn, Loren, we must all lengthen our stride.” And I got the message.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/receiving-a-prophet.p5" pid="R_XTx67jVkWk5RYUALnggA" hash="9A_22w">The message was that although we had made progress, yet before the Lord and before the prophet, it wasn’t enough. We went back, we redoubled our efforts; we found increased growth, but also we found increased strength and new stakes evolved because of those efforts. I don’t think the progress was so much because of us, but because of our desire to follow the prophet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/receiving-a-prophet.p6" pid="Iw_T2T7sKEOdBC7ybnKr5g" hash="f8OnbA">I was talking to a priesthood leader just last weekend. We had finished our Saturday night leadership meeting, which was on missionary work, and he said to me, “You know, you are really a missionary General Authority.” And I said, “No, I don’t consider myself a missionary General Authority. If I can be remembered for anything (and I hope that somehow, somewhere I can), I would settle for that which my father taught me and for which I feel he was known, and that is one who is willing to give allegiance to and follow a prophet of God. And if that can be my lot, then I feel I will have accomplished the thing the Lord has sent me to do.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/receiving-a-prophet.p7" pid="_h2mJ1o5V0-BFsJLVaBiww" hash="ZwwWXw">It’s not the program, it’s not the activities, but in the final analysis it is our loyalty to him whom God has called and the offering of our prayers on his behalf.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/receiving-a-prophet.p8" pid="u6xMoVHZG02qRUJ58ItnjQ" hash="CFZ64w">There is a scripture that goes this way: “He that receiveth a prophet in the name of a prophet shall receive a prophet’s reward.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/10.41" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 10:41</a>.) I have come to realize the literalness of that promise. I have seen those blessings in the life of my father because of his loyalty. I would like those blessings for my family and myself, and I would like to see those blessings in the life of every Latter-day Saint.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/receiving-a-prophet.p9" pid="7o7WoYl-AEu70h9PuDG0aA" hash="XpMzQQ">May I end where I began. God does live. Jesus is the Christ. Joseph Smith is a true prophet, and we are led by a prophet of God today. The prophet has my loyalty and he has my love, because how can I uphold the Lord unless I uphold him? In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1983/04/receiving-a-prophet</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1983-general-conference/1983-04-2070-elder-loren-c-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="3387991" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 1983 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gospel of Love</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love?lang=eng</link>
      <description>There is a hymn, which is a favorite hymn among Latter-day Saints, and comes to us from pioneer days. It was also reported to be among the favorite hymns of the Prophet Joseph Smith and was sung in those fateful hours prior to his martyrdom.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03193_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="6LXQRg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="_Ne2baM7UUiyowxz3aMjKg" hash="PXmM-w">The Gospel of Love</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="vKnS-AY5N0ee-qZJof71TA" hash="osADdw">Loren C. Dunn</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-213c.jpg" alt="Elder Loren C. Dunn" pid="2C6G6HuLj0ef2AgSkAcrVw" hash="GbmNXw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p1" pid="vYsT886SdkW7iRu7Cb3NYA" hash="_aa2HQ">There is a hymn, which is a favorite hymn among Latter-day Saints, and comes to us from pioneer days. It was also reported to be among the favorite hymns of the Prophet Joseph Smith and was sung in those fateful hours prior to his martyrdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p2" pid="GW21M8CCdEK1wR3c9Av4WA" hash="HMApHQ">The words of the first verse go this way:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="FPAhQ_OsvUCTRgl3AnRykg" hash="W6SW8A">
            <span class="emphasis">A poor wayfaring Man of grief</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="xy7JuHSBPkS3QCLJolqifw" hash="JdN_4g">
            <span class="emphasis">Hath often crossed me on my way,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="ZuybEgU790u-aK_CmpFk-A" hash="5c0-ww">
            <span class="emphasis">Who sued so humbly for relief</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="cN1HfLfYj0C-LDfEGiBtRw" hash="_omeZQ">
            <span class="emphasis">That I could never answer nay.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="qt3DtM9UfUabzFJSdKYDqQ" hash="CnSfnQ">
            <span class="emphasis">I had not pow’r to ask his name,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="9wVsQjOpaEWXHEjrarkgSg" hash="Za1iXQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Where-to he went, or whence he came;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="iT4muBtFWUaOk6_E4mD83g" hash="EyzkVw">
            <span class="emphasis">Yet there was something in his eye</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="-v45NRLXN0mUV4ofWPKKIA" hash="UuJclw">
            <span class="emphasis">That won my love; I knew not why.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p3" pid="8ZJh3ZPn8kmlyQps1pRp_Q" hash="K2RZ_Q">The other verses of this hymn show that our love toward our fellow men is indeed an expression of our love toward our God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p4" pid="q3uvqnNzkU-Odiyex5ob8g" hash="9GLCaA">The greatest expression of love from our Father in Heaven to the human family is probably the infinite atonement of the Savior. “For God so loved the world,” said John, “that he gave his only begotten Son, that whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.16" class="scriptureRef">John 3:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p5" pid="saamFwzZT0OPu-TAfGzVkA" hash="NacepA">The most noble expression of love by man is to “love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p6" pid="QX7zKJpAW0m9QFRkZUTHdQ" hash="ZtTJog">“And the second is like unto it, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.37,39" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:37, 39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p7" pid="XjGVdCtLWUm4j1FhTymrBQ" hash="hFopVg">To love our neighbor is a godlike trait and can take many forms.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p8" pid="5f67IYoIl0OJ1HPT4V1lXw" hash="m49KyQ">On the day that no one in the neighborhood saw “Hanse,” as she was called, concerned neighbors rang her doorbell, but to no avail. They were anxious for this gentle and gracious widow who found a place in their hearts. They looked on her as one of their own.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p9" pid="2owOvg-MR0quoVFW95YqCw" hash="bT5Z4A">Finally, a member of the bishopric forced open the door and there, in the bedroom, was Marie Woodruff Hansen, as if she had fallen asleep, but never again to awaken in this life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p10" pid="DT6tP-CgrkuFK-R5KXMQSg" hash="YZON2A">As the bishopric member paused to take in this sad but peaceful scene, he was startled, when from behind him he heard the words, “I love you.” Knowing that Marie lived alone, he turned; and there in the corner was a bird cage. A second time the bird said, “I love you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p11" pid="UATQdlJOhkuEVNOV2rz4BA" hash="mHdTyQ">It was as if Marie, herself, had paused at the portals that mark the point between life and death to send back one final message before moving on to that new day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p12" pid="_8LiFZsKKEicacf7Oy7tXA" hash="zIbfkA">Behind her was a neighborhood of friends, both young and old. She knew them all. They were like family to her; Marie’s baked goodies found their way into their homes, and they looked after her like a favorite aunt or a grandmother. Home teaching and visiting teaching were only the beginning as the whole neighborhood was caught up in this love affair. Children were welcomed into her home. They always knew there would be fresh-baked cookies. There was a warmth about that little home that was a reflection of Marie’s whole life. Many prayers had been offered here: prayers of gratitude, prayers of thanksgiving.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p13" pid="S0aI36xKoEyFg3VCCDgHMw" hash="t_si2g">The words she taught her pet bird were the words she lived by. Even in death they echoed in the ears of those she left behind. Ahead of Marie was a husband who had gone first, too many years ago. She had lived a full life and left one final message of good-bye in the words she knew best: “I love you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p14" pid="0Psfq79_JkqpgsU_zgXyxg" hash="Zk5Rcw">Marie Hansen left a great legacy, probably greater than she realized. For did not the Savior say, “A new commandment I give unto you, That ye love one another; as I have loved you, that ye also love one another”? (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/13.34" class="scriptureRef">John 13:34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p15" pid="j-ZIsvDUqkadrTqi3JgZ9g" hash="laHWQw">There are those who wish to know us better, to understand us better as a religion, as a church. There are those who write about us and study us. But may I suggest that until they take into account this spirit of love, they will never really understand. At the heart of it all is a genuine love of God and of fellowman.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p16" pid="WnpwCVBn3UWNIMnDJD9jCQ" hash="JvEy3w">Today, for instance, there are scores of Latter-day Saint missionaries in many countries throughout the world. They are easily identified by their dress and manner. They come on their missions for many reasons: duty, service, the testimony they have of their message. But after serving honorably for eighteen months or two years, virtually all of them develop a deep and profound love for the people they serve among. One missionary put it this way: “Although it was hard, I am thankful for all the experiences I’ve had here. They were right about the mission field; it’s the best place to practice true christianity, and it’s the best time of your life.” Another says: “I thank the Lord with all my heart for giving me the opportunity to serve him. I love this great land, and I love these people.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p17" pid="2sPrcv_EjE2Rcq3WycAfGA" hash="zLi08w">In Cali, Colombia, a few days ago, the mission president visited one of our Church meetings. At the start of the meeting a seven-year-old boy came up on the stand and sat next to him. He was not on the program; he just wanted to be there. When the meeting was nearly over he strode to the pulpit and bore his testimony.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p18" pid="OG1UIfKlnEaDW81bCkFvGQ" hash="i-1f3Q">When he finished, he went back and sat next to the president. The two exchanged glances. The mission president smiled approval. The young boy smiled back. In those dark eyes was a message of love and security. Here was someone who knew he belonged.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p19" pid="bhKaMOIEv0e7JK4jhX413A" hash="dL1W7Q">Later it was learned the boy had spent his earlier life as an orphan. A couple in the ward had taken him in and were raising him as their own. The whole ward was his home, and he was blossoming in this atmosphere of acceptance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p20" pid="sWnt5k9FuEeA0dcExW-4dA" hash="yR8sPQ">“Inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.40" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:40</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p21" pid="-X43NvbgG0a_L466R798AA" hash="UWDTGg">A few years ago, when President Kimball was a member of the Quorum of the Twelve, he and Sister Kimball were touring missions overseas.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p22" pid="8XxLGw4sU0ej8VqPKwninQ" hash="xtOvrQ">A change in the airline schedule found them, along with a mission president and his wife, in a cold and drafty airport, late at night, with no place to go but wait for an early morning flight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p23" pid="4OcQt3LwG0Cl_lB8UTxRLg" hash="cEM1dw">Sister Kimball had her coat, but the mission president’s wife did not. President Kimball tried to give her his coat, but she would not take it. As they began to fall asleep on those hard benches, President Kimball got up and gently put his coat over the sleeping wife of the mission president. This kind of selfless concern for others is how President Kimball has lived his life. This is the same leader we sustain today as prophet, seer, and revelator. This is the man whom God has called to lead nearly six million Latter-day Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p24" pid="mzvfbbl9n0GdBl6F7sUyag" hash="F129Dw">He has literally spent his life in taking off his coat, so to speak, and putting it around the shoulders of those he judged to be in greater need: people of all colors and creeds; men, women, and children. It has never made any difference to him. All are his brothers. All are his sisters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p25" pid="_oP6Z0Oux0Kg4FZlPJAD7Q" hash="bknDQA">“And charity suffereth long, and is kind, and envieth not, and is not puffed up, seeketh not her own, is not easily provoked, thinketh no evil, and rejoiceth not in iniquity but rejoiceth in the truth, beareth all things, believeth all things, hopeth all things, endureth all things. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p26" pid="kiR6aNxfiUOC_p14EE1ZGg" hash="lR9NBg">“[For] charity is the pure love of Christ, and it endureth forever.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.45,47" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:45, 47</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/13.title" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p27" pid="jFMsWRGm_0qUynQAVCt7PA" hash="Us3v1Q">Not long ago Sister Dunn and I attended a stake conference in Marilia, Brazil. Marilia is a beautiful city of 100,000 in the southeast interior of the country. The Sunday session had just concluded. The theme was the atonement of Christ and how he is the Savior of the whole world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p28" pid="pziF8Eg31U-l0gZGuWfc-A" hash="OmLI9Q">Some had traveled by bus for more than three hours to be at this meeting. As we were shaking hands, a young lady came up. She first stopped in front of the mission president and asked how to say “I love you” in English. She then stood in front of Sister Dunn and me and with a broad smile and great sincerity said “I love you.” It seemed a little thing, but it touched our hearts. It was the effort of a humble follower of Christ to express herself. The message could have been said in any language and been understood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p29" pid="eeIZBjlhX0qXEO2g887MLQ" hash="thCpvg">The spirit of love reaches across language barriers. There is a purity about it that lifts the soul and causes us all to realize that we are the children of the same God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p30" pid="avJfislLNkK7PMENXKJy3A" hash="PjrOvA">There is a thread running through it all: Marie Hansen; an orphan boy in Colombia; the young lady in Brazil; and our revered President, Spencer W. Kimball.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p31" pid="JpjjydX-z0CSlsimg35ZJw" hash="GAzs4Q">No one professes to be perfect, but there is a spirit in this work and among this people that makes them better than they would otherwise be. It is the spirit of love borne on the wings of the restored gospel of Jesus Christ. It comes from a God of love. It causes the Church to reach out to the lives of men and women everywhere.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p32" pid="Zoq0spmUPUC9RXIbRXkLCg" hash="a-IkwA">We claim no corner on love of others. We know the world is filled with many good, decent people. We respect and admire them and the righteous things they stand for. We teach the gospel of Jesus Christ. It is a gospel of salvation and exaltation. It is a gospel of love—love of God and love of fellowmen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p33" pid="9OF0nMxhukG8O9TDp9gaAw" hash="ZEHgcg">The final verse of the hymn that we mentioned in the beginning goes like this:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.f3">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="YER0Po9eYkuXntc3TCO-rA" hash="f-uL4w">
            <span class="emphasis">Then in a moment to my view</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="onBEna9h1kG59VYOwmM3pQ" hash="CGpBog">
            <span class="emphasis">The stranger started from disguise;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="kCiQx5uLhUyQOOWcfoFfGA" hash="fV_gWg">
            <span class="emphasis">The tokens in his hands I knew;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="mApVc-Yc0ECsTnSZoSWgXA" hash="asqN5Q">
            <span class="emphasis">The Savior stood before my eyes.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="sjwDzoRiZUWLsZlOpdIY-Q" hash="FzI-7Q">
            <span class="emphasis">He spake, and my poor name he named,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="EP3whKvQu0qqUiz7iFchRg" hash="kv1RUw">
            <span class="emphasis">“Of me thou hast not been ashamed;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="c5jZWrqysUW3AmLkNzIY6A" hash="Jx2vrQ">
            <span class="emphasis">These deeds shall thy memorial be,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="HWtlydNvrEyTciIqmi-C9w" hash="L6kQqw">
            <span class="emphasis">Fear not, thou didst them unto me.”</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love.p34" pid="LHj0azUQyk6ChQ6xjFwL6A" hash="hwNv9A">By way of testimony, I wish to express my love for my Father in Heaven, for his son Jesus Christ, for each one of you wherever you are, and for these my brethren and associates of the General Authorities. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1985/10/the-gospel-of-love</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1985-general-conference/1985-10-1040-elder-loren-c-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="6752964" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 1985 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Before I Build a Wall</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall?lang=eng</link>
      <description>There is a quality that can be seen in the lives of most Christians and good men and women everywhere. It is not only demonstrated in their actions but also seems to be a part of their nature. It is a blend of charity, forgiveness, and respect; and i</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_91905_000_032" doc-version="2" hash="W4ePPQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Uvsass71ZEyuRTE2FeLV2A" hash="5_qIrg">Before I Build a Wall</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="vS-ixlIaYEqkNGal-vCqIw" hash="osADdw">Loren C. Dunn</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-213c.jpg" alt="Elder Loren C. Dunn" pid="mzBnnKWRFUaWclucL1oMJQ" hash="GbmNXw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p1" pid="F5bIUcWglEmG25SzkJeKPg" hash="b_OPFA">There is a quality that can be seen in the lives of most Christians and good men and women everywhere. It is not only demonstrated in their actions but also seems to be a part of their nature. It is a blend of charity, forgiveness, and respect; and it takes into account the realization that God stands at the helm and we are all His children. As a result of this, we have certain obligations to one another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p2" pid="BXKRrEtbQUK8IyeALKZb7w" hash="tFkNcw">“Wherefore, the Lord God hath given a commandment that all men should have charity, which charity is love.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/26.30" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 26:30</a>.) And the scriptures also teach us, “And ye shall also forgive one another your trespasses.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/26.31" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 26:31</a>.) This quality can be a part of a person’s life without compromising principle or commitment to truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p3" pid="jY_0quJva0qVmnwXyLJX3g" hash="6CZgew">Not long ago, Father Paul Showalter of Nauvoo shared with us an interesting insight on the Prophet Joseph Smith that came from the early Catholic history of that area.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p4" pid="iWvR53la2kqG_BPEDgJSIA" hash="RVWSRg">When the Saints began to settle in Nauvoo and surrounding areas, a French Catholic priest by the name of Father John Alleman, who lived in neighboring McDonough County, needed transportation to visit a sick parishioner. Joseph provided him with ferry service to cross the river and a carriage to his destination.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p5" pid="KI4X_ClLSkeu2o-FAh7c0Q" hash="89s4ZQ">As an expression of respect, Joseph commented, “The priests attend to their people faithfully and mind their own business, whereas others are continually bothering the Latter-day Saints.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p6" pid="wYLBEbJaZUCgZLVbea9DPg" hash="q5KLhA">This quality of respect for others, no matter what their belief or religious affiliation, seems to have been a part of the life of the Prophet Joseph Smith. He stood for truth and the restored gospel to his dying day, and he had no patience with those who were deliberately wicked or who tried to exercise unrighteous dominion over the Latter-day Saints or, for that matter, anyone else. Still he showed a respect and brotherly concern for others, no matter what their beliefs or their backgrounds, which, in many ways, was remarkable, when one considers the persecution that both he and the early Saints underwent.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p7" pid="BxKJu8tdN0O5TIRs4W5E_g" hash="K_BMjQ">He said at one time that he was in possession of the quality of love, and we also read that if he could get the ear of his enemies, he was usually able to win them over. In his dealings with members and nonmembers, he was committed to a principle which can be found in the 121st section of the Doctrine and Covenants: “No power or influence can or ought to be maintained by virtue of the priesthood, only by persuasion, by long-suffering, by gentleness and meekness, and by love unfeigned; By kindness, and pure knowledge, which shall greatly enlarge the soul without hypocrisy, and without guile” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.41-42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:41–42</a>), and “Let thy bowels also be full of charity towards all men, and to the household of faith” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.45" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:45</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p8" pid="IRVkSaURTE6_2J8A-WaDUg" hash="6ndNgg">Joseph Smith declared the doctrine of the Restoration with great power and force. And never once did he back away from an opportunity to proclaim the truth of this work. He was the forerunner of literally legions of missionaries who have gone throughout the world to proclaim the same truths. Nevertheless, he also said, “I never feel to force my doctrine upon any person; I rejoice to see prejudice give way to truth, and the traditions of men dispersed by the pure principles of the Gospel of Jesus Christ.” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 6:213.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p9" pid="wpHTAbRPr0yK_r9ZeIY_kw" hash="7I_8Pw">In the closing days of his life, when Nauvoo was besieged with mobs and challenges both from within and without, he and Hyrum still took the time to write to a Mr. Tewkesbury in Boston, who had become disaffiliated with the Church, inviting him to be restored once again to fellowship. The letter says, in part, “Feeling an ardent desire for the salvation of the souls of men, we … would, in the sincerity of men of God, advise you to be rebaptized by Elder Nickerson, one of the servants of God, that you may again receive the sweet influences of the Holy Ghost, and enjoy the fellowship of the Saints.” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 6:427.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p10" pid="GKU6QuIk3EuHOakbQhJ1Og" hash="efrrTg">This same spirit can be found in the First Presidency letter of 1985, which said in part, “We are aware of some who are inactive, of others who have become critical and are prone to find fault, and of those who have been disfellowshipped or excommunicated because of serious transgressions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p11" pid="FCB5TfZ-tUigU_KmvECslQ" hash="oymvsg">“To all such we reach out in love. We are anxious to forgive in the spirit of Him who said: ‘I, the Lord, will forgive whom I will forgive, but of you it is required to forgive all men.’ (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:10</a>.)” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Mar. 1986, p. 88.) This letter is referred to as the invitation to “come back.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p12" pid="P-9vWmp_wkGljQuGsSDHHw" hash="8xK7pQ">Today we live in times of conflict, dissent, differences of opinion, charges, countercharges, disagreements. There is a need for us, perhaps more than ever before, to reach within ourselves and allow the qualities of mutual respect, mingled with charity and forgiveness; to influence our actions with one another; to be able to disagree without becoming disagreeable; to lower our voices and build on common ground with the realization that once the storm has passed, we will still have to live with one another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p13" pid="zRU8VCPOQ0e75G5wvSeU5g" hash="mdEwFA">While living in the East some years ago, I read of an experience that took place on the floor of the United States Senate. As I recall, a debate was taking place. The leader of the debate in one party was Senator Hubert Humphrey of Minnesota. The floor leader for the other party was Senator Margaret Chase Smith of Maine. As time went on, it was clear that Senator Humphrey’s party would win.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p14" pid="oC_tRv_G7EqVI_0ULYhDNA" hash="vA-OBw">On the morning of the vote, Senator Humphrey went out to his garden and cut some red roses. When Margaret Chase Smith arrived at her desk on the senate floor that morning, there was the bouquet of roses. This, of course, did not change Senator Smith’s mind concerning the issues, but it was a gesture of respect and appreciation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p15" pid="oWv3fPZyvUm7x_uaB9NlFg" hash="DQgZCQ">In our dealings with one another, no matter what our position might be, we need more roses—and, after Elder Faust’s talk this morning, I suppose, roses without thorns.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p16" pid="f5rOYVazCEmzn50blsoNsg" hash="Qk97Eg">I was raised in a community in the western valleys of Utah. The town, Tooele, was settled by pioneers; when precious ore deposits were discovered in the nearby mountains, people came in from southern and eastern Europe who had a different culture and different religious preferences. They came to work in the mines and at the smelter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p17" pid="TRB5ozd4H0GJY6OhC5aAoA" hash="A1885A">They settled just east of town and called their community “New Town.” From almost the beginning, there was division and suspicion and misunderstanding between the new residents, who brought with them their old-country customs, and the people of the more established community, who were mostly of pioneer stock. The two groups seldom mixed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p18" pid="w1NpjUDUP0WVjPwzJaTvwA" hash="GjNFIA">One year the high school hired a football coach fresh out of Utah State by the name of Sterling Harris. Coach Harris, as he came to be known, was outgoing and just a little irreverent. He went throughout the old town and the new town and made sure he got all the boys in school and then out for football. He had a nickname for everyone, and after a while it became a sort of status symbol to carry a Sterling Harris nickname.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p19" pid="O18jwPJpoEm9j1po3b8A7w" hash="s8Msog">It wasn’t long after that before he had the Gowns and the Whitehouses lined up next to the Savages and the Stepics and the Ormes and the Melinkoviches running from the same backfield. He was tough but impartial, and he had about him a presence that made people feel important and want to do their best.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p20" pid="eAGNUDsQa0aJUA5cmzCoMQ" hash="1jQA0Q">The team came together, and Coach Harris even took them to more than one state championship. But what was more important, in bringing the team together, he brought the whole community together. Walls were broken down. People from diverse cultures learned they could build on mutual respect and appreciation. Sterling Harris had become a bridge.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p21" pid="qJFfbi_Mk0ifHWJGii5TvQ" hash="IuuliA">Sterling Harris still lives in Tooele; he is ninety-one years of age. He went on to accomplish many other things in his life, including superintendent of schools and a leader in the Church, but none was more important than when he helped a community to unite itself and reestablish the principle of respect for others of different backgrounds and cultures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p22" pid="B4pUmLc0NkS8fQOL7w3mPA" hash="06VMww">In the cities of this world, in the towns, in the neighborhoods, in the homes, we need more Sterling Harrises from every walk of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p23" pid="eAOX-FoKPkua6Sh0s0uLbg" hash="QE2_4A">Robert Frost once wrote:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="CDBYef5noUiiXiXWWqVG3A" hash="yNXj9w">
            <span class="emphasis">Before I built a wall I’d ask to know</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="moZILY5V0UKcgd3z_fdoVA" hash="HwcWog">
            <span class="emphasis">What I was walling in or walling out,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="o3M48vbDY0GRefhPf4uPwg" hash="GGv9WQ">
            <span class="emphasis">And to whom I was like to give offense.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="beVGCrS1dUKtKMHep752Uw" hash="qcSo4Q">
            <span class="emphasis">Something there is that doesn’t love a wall.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p24" pid="VvErEUrBDk-L3epE8GHmXA" hash="3pGmTw">People will always have opposing views, and I suppose there will always be conflict and even misunderstanding; but the principle of mutual respect mixed with charity and forgiveness can lay the foundation for the resolving of differences and the solving of problems.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p25" pid="GYQs8NcxEEWkOC-ns1qdnw" hash="gWQhaw">Was it not the Savior, speaking of the first and great commandment, who said that we are to love the Lord our God with all our heart, might, mind, and strength and that the second is like unto it, that we are to love our neighbors as ourselves? (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.36-39" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:36–39</a>.) The quality of mutual respect is a great quality. It can be found in the hearts of great people, and in this sense, we all should be great people. It does not have to compromise truth or principle, but it can create brotherhood and sisterhood and the resolution of many problems.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall.p26" pid="meHfcSMaVECH3H1AXRL4Jg" hash="CYlq8A">May the Lord bless us that we may look upon one another in that spirit. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1991/04/before-i-build-a-wall</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1991-general-conference/1991-04-5030-elder-loren-c-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="5890905" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 1991 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Witnesses</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Since the restoration of the gospel there has been given at this pulpit and in many other places the most marvelous array of direct testimony to the divine mission of the Redeemer that possibly has ever been recorded.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95911_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="M48aqw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="NFkQsInL4UCr3hq5Mt9SAA" hash="0gZwRw">Witnesses</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="O2RJyoFnOkqoiCk73q4u3w" hash="osADdw">Loren C. Dunn</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-213c.jpg" alt="Elder Loren C. Dunn" pid="lIXgJjd-pE-bu276oooXtw" hash="GbmNXw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p1" pid="OZge8sfYVkWmzReMo02iNA" hash="kPJFeQ">Since the restoration of the gospel there has been given at this pulpit and in many other places the most marvelous array of direct testimony to the divine mission of the Redeemer that possibly has ever been recorded.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p2" pid="wihttNN3dEuG4VUEqgFzOg" hash="plV_JQ">The law of witnesses has always been a part of the Lord’s work on earth. This law states that “in the mouth of two or three witnesses shall every word be established” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-cor/13.1" class="scriptureRef">2 Cor. 13:1</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/ot/deut/17.6" class="scriptureRef">Deut. 17:6</a>; <a href="/scriptures/ot/deut/19.15" class="scriptureRef">Deut. 19:15</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/18.15-16" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 18:15–16</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.12-29" class="scriptureRef">John 8:12–29</a>). This witness confirms that certain events took place and that God-given doctrine and principles are true.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p3" pid="5iwbbZlMpUa1ord0GpIsqg" hash="xHfw8g">The first duty of a witness is to testify. A person who can testify to the truths of the restored gospel of Jesus Christ is speaking of things he or she knows to be true. With the Lord and his true witnesses there is truth that reaches beyond worldly understanding. Paul understood this when he said: “Now we have received, not the spirit of the world, but the spirit which is of God; that we might know the things that are freely given to us of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p4" pid="Rs9GNLIKE0aWUnv_gZu6RA" hash="PLhONQ">“Which things also we speak, not in the words which man’s wisdom teacheth, but which the Holy Ghost teacheth; comparing spiritual things with spiritual” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/2.12-13" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 2:12–13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p5" pid="Vs9DKhrXaESTNmzNQagliA" hash="wTkm0w">I was just a young boy when I sat in a stake conference in the Tooele Utah Stake, listening carefully to the visitor. He was LeGrand Richards, and he preached the gospel in his warm and spiritual way. That positive experience has stayed with me. I don’t remember what he said, but I do know how I felt as he spoke. I learned later that I felt that way because I was listening to a special witness of Jesus Christ. I knew he knew, and somehow my roots grew deeper that day as to truths of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p6" pid="HfdQejCIJEqNAflfwkC55w" hash="u4TSxg">Orson Pratt said: “A person can not be a witness to that which he merely believes. God requires mankind, or certain individuals among mankind, to be witnesses for him—witnesses of his existence—so that they can bear testimony to others” (in <span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses,</span> 16:209–10).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p7" pid="ciyZvdrRRkmqYXblkXhwcg" hash="mtJg3A">There were many who saw the great miracles and heard the teachings of the Savior as he dwelled on earth, but not all became witnesses. There were no personal administrations of Christ to the unbelieving. Only to certain ones did the Lord open their eyes so they knew who he really was.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p8" pid="pgrt7MF84UySjM3PqiY7xw" hash="9vrzzA">With the calling of the Twelve by the Savior there was instituted the calling of the special witnesses of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p9" pid="SHc41qbBvEOl_oqOxVms8w" hash="WG8FLA">The Prophet Joseph, referring to the resurrection of the Lord, said, “God raised Him from the dead, and we (the apostles) are His witnesses, … and so is the Holy Ghost, whom God ha[s] given to [all those who] obey Him” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 2:19).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p10" pid="akHXR7ix_0a6TQfXjYpZ_Q" hash="8pXYjQ">Every person who receives baptism into the Church and has received and felt the confirmation of the Spirit through the gift of the Holy Ghost stands as a witness “of God at all times and in all things, and in all places” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:9</a>). When partaking of the sacrament, that person renews that witness to take the Savior’s name, keep his commandments, and remember him. A person so moved by the Spirit not only knows these things himself, but the Spirit carries them into the hearts of others. This is the basis of the Church’s great missionary effort. “For when a man speaketh by the power of the Holy Ghost the power of the Holy Ghost carrieth it unto the hearts of the children of men” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/33.1" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 33:1</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p11" pid="m1KcIn6q5UOTCaxAD8GT7Q" hash="AbE4lg">The witness of the Holy Ghost is even more compelling than the witness of sight. As members of the Church, we become witnesses of the Savior and the truthfulness of this work not only in word but also in keeping our covenants and in how we treat others and in how we live our everyday lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p12" pid="d_6NRf35BUONlqFdNu--TQ" hash="8mGd9g">The First Presidency and the Twelve are called as “special witnesses of the name of Christ in all the world” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:23</a>). They are men who by divine designation, priesthood ordination, and the fire of the Holy Ghost hold the keys to the ministry on earth. The Seventy act under the direction of the First Presidency and the Twelve and are special witnesses unto the Gentiles and in all the world. Together, all the members become what Paul refers to as a “cloud of witnesses” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/12.1" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 12:1</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p13" pid="k8C7PCVcHUG_Stvvrepz2Q" hash="v-Uelg">The Prophet Joseph defined the work of the kingdom in our dispensation with these sacred words: “And now, after the many testimonies which have been given of him [Jesus Christ], this is the testimony, last of all, which we give of him: That he lives!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p14" pid="Hkd1CQhpz0GPu3aOHCH6jg" hash="K0e2xw">“For we saw him, even on the right hand of God; and we heard the voice bearing record that he is the Only Begotten of the Father” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.22-23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:22–23</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p15" pid="myILBMDqa0-rzLv3F5Kg2A" hash="cnpK6Q">The Three Witnesses to the Book of Mormon, Oliver Cowdery, David Whitmer, and Martin Harris, stated, “And we declare with words of soberness, that an angel of God came down from heaven, and he brought and laid before our eyes, that we beheld and saw the plates, and the engravings thereon; and we know that it is by the grace of God the Father, and our Lord Jesus Christ, that we beheld and bear record that these things are true” (“The Testimony of Three Witnesses,” Book of Mormon).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p16" pid="izjORINYIEuxy50B_SaVQw" hash="qS3Htg">Said Wilford Woodruff from this Tabernacle: “Joseph Smith was what he professed to be, a prophet of God, a seer and revelator. He … lived long enough to deliver the keys of the kingdom … unto the Twelve Apostles. … The foundation that he laid we have built upon” (in <span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses,</span> 13:164).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p17" pid="8Cayvf7QK0qMQYpBqoE0gg" hash="PgoOzQ">And said David O. McKay, whose life reached from some of those who began this work to some of us serving today and who were called by him: “I have an abiding testimony that the Father and the Son appeared to the Prophet Joseph Smith, and revealed through him the Gospel of Jesus Christ. … Godhood, Brotherhood, Service—these three guiding principles in the Christ[like] life permeate all our Church activity” (<span class="emphasis">Testimonies of the Divinity of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints by Its Leaders,</span> comp. Joseph E. Cardon and Samuel O. Bennion, Independence, Mo.: Zion’s Printing and Publishing Co., 1930, p. 178).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p18" pid="rhuVHLJ49EKuhqYeaVzQrg" hash="uMJ02w">And from our living Prophet-President, Gordon B. Hinckley: “I have a testimony of the living reality of the Son of God, Jesus Christ, my Savior, and my Redeemer, the Jehovah of the Old Testament, the Messiah of the New Testament. … Because of His atoning sacrifice … each of us, if we will walk in obedience to His truths, may go on to exaltation and an eternal life beyond our ability at this stage to understand or comprehend. He is my Redeemer, my Lord, my Savior, my King, my friend” (Vacaville/Santa Rosa California Regional Conference, priesthood leadership session, 20 May 1995).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p19" pid="A345izZyk0iAjah0FtOvfQ" hash="ZNfE2g">The witness borne by those who occupy this pulpit today is consistent with those who, by divine authority, began this work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p20" pid="mN7GZjpz3EyusxbzQ80AyQ" hash="W5SqIg">That same witness is echoed by the members and missionaries of this church to every one of our Father’s children. It is an invitation to learn of the doctrine, to feel the Spirit, and to be healed by partaking of the fulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses.p21" pid="j6Wgc-oy40-JeaxWV_Kq-Q" hash="qinnXg">And to that witness I would add my own witness as to the truthfulness of this work. I know that we have a God in heaven who looks after us and is watching over us. I know God lives. I know he lives. I know God lives. I know this. I know this. I know that Jesus Christ is our Savior and our Redeemer. I know that Joseph Smith was a true prophet of God. I know that Gordon B. Hinckley is a prophet of God today and that this is the gospel of Jesus Christ. May the Lord so bless us that we may listen to the witnesses and bear witness ourselves, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/10/witnesses</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1995-general-conference/1995-10-2040-elder-loren-c-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="4992872" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1995 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Because My Father Sent Me”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me?lang=eng</link>
      <description>A father succeeds when he steps forward and accepts his commitment as a father, always loving, praying for and doing what he can for his family, and never giving up.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10033256_000_033" doc-version="2" hash="42ICxQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="woHDDnk_CEWBQRQFeAH9fQ" hash="JVmZ9Q">“Because My Father Sent Me”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="zSKSOLPq9kuvFlnG6bzNzw" hash="osADdw">Loren C. Dunn</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="q-FtYq0n8EmnUmbUFYB-Ig" hash="IdxIOw">A father succeeds when he steps forward and accepts his commitment as a father, always loving, praying for and doing what he can for his family, and never giving up.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1767.jpg" alt="Elder Loren C. Dunn" pid="8WbkO0VDhUyS1Le7MhwxWA" hash="ndhh4g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.p1" pid="SCsCG7k3VUOYtSkrwPjMHA" hash="MLRXxA">I was in a busy airport last week and there, amidst great numbers of people rushing to catch their planes, was a father kneeling down by his son, patiently feeding him an ice cream cone which the son was too small to hold himself. The little boy needed help because his snowsuit, which kept him warm, also made it impossible for his arms to bend. I thought to myself, <span class="emphasis">What a great dad!</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.p2" pid="ajK8YxAYckSEPRIPwJ-aTw" hash="fo1UlA">There should be no other word that is more important to us than <span class="emphasis">father</span> or <span class="emphasis">mother,</span> and it is the word <span class="emphasis">father</span> that I would like to talk about. It’s not just a matter of how to be a good father. There is plenty written and much good advice given, even at this conference. It is the commitment to be a good father that I want to talk about also.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.p3" pid="cR6CJGsgWUSR0MjfM6pwew" hash="mhWrQw">The history of the gospel of Jesus Christ from Adam and Eve down to the present day is closely associated with father and mother and family. The introductory pages of the Book of Mormon have the great prophet Nephi, while recounting the trials and blessings of his day, first paying homage to his father: “I, Nephi, having been born of goodly parents, therefore I was taught somewhat in all the learning of my father; and having seen many afflictions in the course of my days, nevertheless, having been highly favored of the Lord in all my days; yea, having had a great knowledge of the goodness and the mysteries of God, therefore I make a record of my proceedings in my days.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.p4" pid="HooOb3HBoESGnC9G_UIwBQ" hash="pmatNQ">Enos, likewise, first recognized his father for the preparation he received: “Behold, it came to pass that I, Enos, knowing my father that he was a just man—for he taught me in his language, and also in the nurture and admonition of the Lord—and blessed be the name of my God for it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.p5" pid="xxhhXIw-nkeVxlvua_awKg" hash="j_p8KQ">When the Prophet Joseph Smith first received the vision of the angel Moroni, he was instructed to tell his father, who, in turn, confirmed that it was true and that Joseph should follow the directions of Moroni. Even with the restoration of the gospel, the Lord did not separate a son from his righteous father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.p6" pid="ifOLWiyG9USlTU852bxUYw" hash="GIR8ZQ">The Savior of the world, in giving us a definition of the meaning of the gospel in 3 Nephi, chapter 27, said simply that He came to work out the plan of salvation and give His life for the sake of all mankind because His Father sent Him. The love between the Father and the Son was so perfect that the Savior gave it as His first reason for coming into mortality and the suffering He did for us in the Garden of Gethsemane and on the cross.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.p7" pid="f4e0kVLQlE6kjtb8i7M0jA" hash="Sj-aQg">The gospel is designed to teach us what to do as fathers and mothers, and it would seem that when families are intact, we may very well do good things and give as our first reason “because my Father sent me”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> or because a father showed me the way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.p8" pid="_Dc7t0dMBkOJoGItwwBXWQ" hash="xXO9Lw">I have had the honor of working with the missionaries of the Church for over three decades, and I know that a great many of them were able to get through those first shaky minutes and hours and days of their mission because of their fathers or mothers. I remember one experience of a fine young man who spent his life on the ranch, just as his own father did. When the boy got into the mission field, it was all strange: too many people, not enough open spaces. He wanted badly to go home. Finally, the mission president had the young missionary call his father. The father listened patiently as his son said how homesick he was, and then the father spoke in terms that his son could understand, and as I heard about this, it brought a smile to my face. He said with firmness but love, “Son, you’re just going to have to ‘cowboy up.’” The boy knew exactly what that meant, and he is hanging on as the spirit of his mission begins to come. He knows his father will not give up on him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.p9" pid="uz9obrv9MU6_KHnKJnO1hQ" hash="Xdrhng">Innumerable are the numbers of those young people who did not quit and go home during those first days of being away at school or away from home the first time because of the good influence of fathers and mothers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.p10" pid="VJzDG7WF5kWWpSL_aK55Tg" hash="QA9nKA">When I sat across from President David O. McKay and was first called to this calling some 32 years ago, I remember that after he discussed with me what would be expected, he then charged me to serve by asking me to carry out this calling in a way that would be pleasing to my own father. That was enough of a challenge for a lifetime. President McKay knew my father, who had been a stake president for 20 years, and I looked on my father as one of the greatest men I knew. My first understanding of how important I was to my father and how real the Savior was, was when I heard him pray for us in family prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.p11" pid="hFrOHfpmEk-hjjshMqEvfA" hash="FmFMlA">Now there are some exceptions, such as death and other serious circumstances, but what is needed today is for fathers to commit to being fathers, whatever that might take—to assume the responsibility and to live by it, that you may become an anchor to all who come after you. If the example has not been set in your life, then reach out and try to help establish it, and resolve that that example will begin with you, if there is no one else. If all is not perfect in your home, then let it begin with you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.p12" pid="gLu_bjxupku18Sj2JueLOw" hash="MhhS8g">It was President Harold B. Lee who said that the turning of the hearts of the children to their fathers and the fathers to the children was not only a commission to do work for the dead, but it also applied to the living and the importance of keeping those family relationships intact in this life.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.p13" pid="UgRWpYAG9km0TC1_gk02aQ" hash="PG5dxQ">I finish with the words of the poet Edgar A. Guest, who wrote of an average, everyday man—a father—and his family. The last words of his poem say, “This his praise, if praise be needed, As a father he succeeded.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> A father succeeds when he steps forward and accepts his commitment as a father, always loving, praying for, and doing what he can for his family, and never giving up.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.p14" pid="m5QSQxegiEOs0h2z7FiiGA" hash="FH73hQ">May the sacred name of Heavenly Father be spoken with reverence in our homes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.p15" pid="NUpOB6qmsEafAGzKnvhpLA" hash="CTu9tA">May the name of father carry with it the kind of love and confidence that will bring peace and hope and righteous determination.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.p16" pid="9Okom2PkRUS8rdJAQSeg4g" hash="mWsQKQ">May I add at this point my own witness and testimony as to the truthfulness of this work, adding to that which has been said from this pulpit during this great conference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me.p17" pid="o9Q-5QDwSUWxoAZQzfIj9Q" hash="-RDidA">I feel like I have stood with the Prophet Joseph in the Sacred Grove when there appeared the Father and the Son; I have sat with the Saints in Kirtland when the temple of the Lord was accepted and dedicated; I received my covenants in Nauvoo; I knelt at the cemetery in Winter Quarters when a loved one was buried; I also held up my arm to sustain Brigham Young as the President of the Church; I stood on Ensign Peak with Brother Brigham the day after he arrived in the valley, when he looked over an expanse which he had already seen by revelation and knew from that experience where the temple was to be built. I know this work is true. I know God lives. I know He lives. I know God lives. I know that Jesus Christ is our Redeemer and our Savior, that the Prophet Joseph saw what he said he saw, that Gordon B. Hinckley carries the keys of this great work today, and that this is the gospel of Jesus Christ. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2000/04/because-my-father-sent-me</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2000-general-conference/2000-04-5040-elder-loren-c-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="5034988" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2000 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testimony</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2000/10/testimony?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I know that God our Father is in this work in great congregations such as this, and in the smallest branch and the smallest congregation God is in this work.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/testimony" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10028166_000_007" doc-version="2" hash="E1D3eQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/testimony.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="O3x0k48yW0uelWI3vBk-Ug" hash="w8s8fg">Testimony</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="G0K3NTi9RkuPCKajJU7fUQ" hash="osADdw">Loren C. Dunn</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="vddVS5ukwEqe6t4k96IdAA" hash="L9YAlA">I know that God our Father is in this work in great congregations such as this, and in the smallest branch and the smallest congregation God is in this work.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/testimony.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1767.jpg" alt="Elder Loren C. Dunn" pid="K3YrCatp3EKKXtvzZDAFaw" hash="ndhh4g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/testimony.p1" pid="rNrUXqtKoESL-zrkWBraBQ" hash="e9KZoQ">Just six days ago President Gordon B. Hinckley, accompanied by President Boyd K. Packer and Elder Neil L. Andersen and their wives, dedicated the Boston Massachusetts Temple. The dedication came at the end of an open house that saw over 83,000 people go through the temple. There were over 16,000 who attended the four sessions of the dedication, either at the temple or at nearby stake centers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/testimony.p2" pid="VkAbJ2qAIkCvsqUjqXIyOg" hash="_W6psQ">While every temple is important and offers the same ordinances necessary for eternal life, this dedication was, in many ways, historic. This is the first temple in a city recognized as the birthplace of freedom in what was then the New World, and also it is recognized as the early home of many of the first leaders and members of the Church. The dedication seemed to represent the coming together of the great heritage of America and the sacred roots of the restored gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/testimony.p3" pid="2SprmAbAWUaemU45KxKxGA" hash="n0lgAw">Some in attendance had previous ties to Boston and the surrounding area. Most were there because they live there and were rejoicing in the dedication of a temple in their midst. All were there as members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, “fellowcitizens with the saints, and of the household of God,” as President Hinckley said at the cornerstone ceremony, “built upon the foundation of the apostles and prophets,” with Jesus Christ Himself as “the chief corner stone” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/2.19-20" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 2:19–20</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/testimony.p4" pid="KHnBn-frMEWrvh1RSwtCnw" hash="tRjM7g">There were native residents of the area who came, many with their children and grandchildren: three generations of worthy temple recommend holders.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/testimony.p5" pid="30ihnr4A7EOlv27uxQLg-A" hash="GmmgWw">In the dedicatory prayer of the Kirtland Temple, the Prophet Joseph Smith asked the Lord to break off the yoke of the persecutions of that day (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/109.31-33,47" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 109:31–33, 47</a>). While challenges still remain, we are seeing the yoke of misunderstanding and prejudice being broken in this era of temple building and open houses.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/testimony.p6" pid="nrfzFpuNsUCZNc7wvKrDXw" hash="r5p6gw">In the temple, in the sealing rooms, we find mirrors that are on opposite walls from each other. As a person looks in the mirror, he can see his reflection going back from one generation to another, as it were, forward from one generation to another, and there is no end, signifying the eternal nature of us all. Perhaps there is another reason for the mirrors situated in that way. It speaks of all who came before us and all who will come after us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/testimony.p7" pid="HPkmcESYy06N_gEA3K6pOg" hash="6Cf5MA">I think of the words of the Prophet Joseph: “And now, after the many testimonies which have been given of him, this is the testimony, last of all, which we give of him: That he lives!” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:22</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/testimony.p8" pid="05on5G_qoUegW1DphdULXA" hash="wGcxfA">For all who have borne witness of this work and all who will yet bear witness of this work, in my day and my time, I bear that witness and testimony to you this day at this time. I know that there is a God in heaven, and I know He lives. I know God lives. I <span class="emphasis">know</span> He lives. I know He lives, and I know that He is the Father of all of us. I know that God our Father is in this work in great congregations such as this, and in the smallest branch and the smallest congregation God is in this work. I know that Jesus Christ is our Savior and our Redeemer and that He has purchased us by the shedding of His blood and by the anguish which He suffered on Gethsemane. I know that apostles and prophets are at the foundation of this work, beginning with the Prophet Joseph and coming to President Gordon B. Hinckley this day. This, my brothers and sisters, is the gospel of Jesus Christ. This work is true. May the Lord bless us to live by it. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2000/10/testimony</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2000-general-conference/2000-10-1050-elder-loren-c-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="2479934" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2000 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
