<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Lynn G. Robbins</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Lynn G. Robbins.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Lynn%20G.%20Robbins.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Lynn G. Robbins.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Apr 1998 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 1998 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Agency and Anger</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger?lang=eng</link>
      <description>A cunning part of [Satan’s] strategy is to dissociate anger from agency, making us believe that we are victims of an emotion that we cannot control.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_98905_000_033" doc-version="2" hash="8zXLsA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="U-z6PYmClkGwKek4ViodIA" hash="n7g6KA">Agency and Anger</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="lG_gnM5Ec0qLy2s5Z3NYmg" hash="E__f3A">Lynn G. Robbins</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="qPL4wCRbrU6R5DdokjsJww" hash="nR9UUA">A cunning part of [Satan’s] strategy is to dissociate anger from agency, making us believe that we are victims of an emotion that we cannot control.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1d60.jpg" alt="Elder Lynn G. Robbins" pid="UNd_9rRh90y5H7O2OMNhDQ" hash="rwFBhQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p1" pid="PMWOWFbW4E-aZi9pI9OPfA" hash="_1SFdg">“I have a family here on earth. <span class="emphasis">They are so good to me.</span>” This is the hope of every child expressed in the words of one of our hymns (“Families Can Be Together Forever,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 300; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p2" pid="09Eb936MyUWtl4FH3lMCMg" hash="6zJCJA">We learn in the proclamation on the family that “the family is central to the Creator’s plan” and that “husband and wife have a solemn responsibility to love and care for each other” and a “sacred duty to rear their children in love and righteousness” (“The Family: A Proclamation to the World,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1995, 102).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p3" pid="deYs5P3ZzEK_grjrjlU2Rg" hash="fj6Yfw">The family is also Satan’s primary target. He is waging war on the family. One of his schemes is the subtle and cunning way he has of sneaking behind enemy lines and entering our very homes and lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p4" pid="x1KZ3_HA8kCJkdA4q94afw" hash="yhlQuw">He damages and often destroys families within the walls of their own homes. His strategy is to stir up <span class="emphasis">anger</span> between family members. Satan is the “father of contention, and he stirreth up the hearts of men to contend with <span class="emphasis">anger,</span> one with another” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.29" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:29</a>; emphasis added). The verb <span class="emphasis">stir</span> sounds like a recipe for disaster: Put tempers on medium heat, stir in a few choice words, and bring to a boil; continue stirring until thick; cool off; let feelings chill for several days; serve cold; lots of leftovers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p5" pid="mCmKopsfKUyj6Sc-AWLX8g" hash="CVijZw">A cunning part of his strategy is to dissociate anger from agency, making us believe that we are victims of an emotion that we cannot control. We hear, “I lost my temper.” Losing one’s temper is an interesting choice of words that has become a widely used idiom. To “lose something” implies “not meaning to,” “accidental,” “involuntary,” “not responsible”—careless perhaps but “not responsible.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p6" pid="POLz4l6UukKBoE6cB08-0Q" hash="0GIWgw">“He made me mad.” This is another phrase we hear, also implying lack of control or agency. This is a myth that must be debunked. No one makes us mad. Others don’t make us angry. There is no force involved. Becoming angry is a conscious choice, a decision; therefore, we can make the choice not to become angry. <span class="emphasis">We</span> choose!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p7" pid="8_m3duKEe0yJitdGcM4ziQ" hash="KC8Qmw">To those who say, “But I can’t help myself,” author William Wilbanks responds: “Nonsense.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p8" pid="XyNsFKh-jUm_8r52D0dyUA" hash="1kU3Iw">“Aggression, … suppressing the anger, talking about it, screaming and yelling,” are all learned strategies in dealing with anger. “We <span class="emphasis">choose</span> the one that has proved effective for us in the past. Ever notice how seldom we lose control when frustrated by our boss, but how often we do when annoyed by friends or family?” (“The New Obscenity,” <span class="emphasis">Reader’s Digest,</span> Dec. 1988, 24; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p9" pid="XAWy9qnwB0yMlDSqGt_jew" hash="DGakOQ">In his sophomore year Wilbanks tried out for the high school basketball team and made it. On the first day of practice his coach had him play one-on-one while the team observed. When he missed an easy shot, he became angry and stomped and whined. The coach walked over to him and said, “You pull a stunt like that again and you’ll never play for my team” (23). For the next three years he never lost control again. Years later, as he reflected back on this incident, he realized that the coach had taught him a life-changing principle that day: anger can be controlled.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p10" pid="4YEc5AcToUyQfSUwKhbtfg" hash="e3zlPg">In the Joseph Smith Translation of Ephesians 4:26 [<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/4.26" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 4:26</a>], Paul asks the question, “Can ye be angry, and not sin?” The Lord is very clear on this issue: “He that hath the spirit of contention is not of me, but is of the devil, who is the father of contention, and he stirreth up the hearts of men to contend with anger, one with another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p11" pid="dzvFz7DwMEK1MU_ttfhHzw" hash="IhWZTw">“Behold, this is not my doctrine, to stir up the hearts of men with anger, one against another; but this is my doctrine, that such things should be done away” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.29-30" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:29–30</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p12" pid="hyEoC2F9A0K1ya0H-gN7OA" hash="ThaKmA">This doctrine or command from the Lord presupposes agency and is an appeal to the conscious mind to make a decision. The Lord expects us to make the choice <span class="emphasis">not</span> to become angry.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p13" pid="I6ZBD1qxIUCFmMam02ppSQ" hash="1khGEw">Nor can becoming angry be justified. In Matthew 5, verse 22, the Lord says: “But I say unto you, That whosoever is angry with his brother <span class="emphasis">without a cause</span> shall be in danger of the judgment” (emphasis added). How interesting that the phrase “without a cause” is not found in the inspired Joseph Smith Translation (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.24" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:24</a>), nor in the 3 Nephi 12:22 [<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/12.22" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 12:22</a>] version. When the Lord eliminates the phrase “without a cause,” He leaves us without an excuse. “But this is my doctrine, that such things should be done away” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.30" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:30</a>). We can “do away” with anger, for He has so taught and commanded us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p14" pid="14QmsH3yvE-KR0BYortuqg" hash="qdLfeg">Anger is a yielding to Satan’s influence by surrendering our self-control. It is the thought-sin that leads to hostile feelings or behavior. It is the detonator of road rage on the freeway, flare-ups in the sports arena, and domestic violence in homes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p15" pid="0L7oO2dENEynMFgRCf2MKw" hash="fdS0Zg">Unchecked, anger can quickly trigger an explosion of cruel words and other forms of emotional abuse that can scar a tender heart. It is “that which cometh out of the mouth,” the Savior said; “this defileth a man” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/15.11" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 15:11</a>). David O. McKay said,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p16" pid="hy-ptrWBcUu1zx3T2fWF6A" hash="YG5tRA">“Let husband and wife never speak in loud tones to each other, ‘unless the house is on fire’” (<span class="emphasis">Stepping Stones to an Abundant Life,</span> comp. Llewelyn R. McKay [1971], 294).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p17" pid="oaFNdE27pUaDKwPmspjo3g" hash="vTh07w">Physical abuse is anger gone berserk and is never justified and always unrighteous.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p18" pid="6AV9-mdg80OZ3TiOcbsWrg" hash="4Ni0bQ">Anger is an uncivil attempt to make another feel guilty or a cruel way of trying to correct them. It is often mislabeled as discipline but is almost always counterproductive. Therefore the scriptural warning: “Husbands, love your wives, and be not bitter against them,” and “fathers provoke not your children to anger, lest they be discouraged” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/col/3.19,21" class="scriptureRef">Col. 3:19, 21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p19" pid="2W5xgFXPiEGWefkPxEKvMw" hash="K3mMoA">Choice and accountability are inseparable principles. Because anger is a choice, there is a strong warning in the proclamation “that individuals … who abuse spouse or offspring, … will one day stand accountable before God.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p20" pid="Mfk5ijcmbEehdDWnC2ReMA" hash="vno9DA">Understanding the connection between agency and anger is the first step in eliminating it from our lives. We can choose not to become angry. And we can make that choice today, right now: “I will never become angry again.” Ponder this resolution.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p21" pid="xqgaQBPSlEaeY6hn2tBDUQ" hash="GgxnBw">The 121st section of the Doctrine and Covenants is one of our best sources to learn correct leadership principles. Perhaps the most important application of section 121 is to spouses and parents. We are to lead our families by persuasion, by long-suffering, by gentleness, kindness, and meekness, and by love unfeigned (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.41-42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:41–42</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger.p22" pid="oGbzL3f1aUawekS6QHBSwQ" hash="Gepllw">May each child’s dream of having a family here on earth that is good to them come true. This is my prayer and my testimony in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1998/04/agency-and-anger</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1998-general-conference/1998-04-5040-elder-lynn-g-robbins-64k-eng.mp3" length="3646931" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 1998 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tithing—a Commandment Even for the Destitute</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Genuine sacrifice has been a hallmark of the faithful from the beginning.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10032029_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="RegoJw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="MP09eieDa0-7eQU0MbHiCw" hash="CyL5QQ">Tithing—</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="DkSRfRDZe0mTulE7m8vCjw" hash="xiEh5A">a Commandment Even for the Destitute</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="kAvzmmzQG0a_2E_H5T5kHQ" hash="E__f3A">Lynn G. Robbins</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="UnidpvrCDkKaixYO7g6itw" hash="UOZdkA">Genuine sacrifice has been a hallmark of the faithful from the beginning.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-d5.jpg" alt="Elder Lynn G. Robbins" pid="Eq4r2N3YSE2gbgZdVuADjg" hash="MR4cgg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p1" pid="zCsZ6lvGh0aidcufyiRKdQ" hash="3wfApg">In Charles Dickens’s timeless classic <span class="emphasis">A Christmas Carol,</span> Bob Cratchit hoped to spend Christmas Day with his family. “‘If quite <span class="emphasis">convenient,</span> Sir,’” he asked his employer, Mr. Scrooge.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p2" pid="gcOwFVcfGkyAZpmDC4qXUg" hash="uh6qyQ">“‘It’s <span class="emphasis">not convenient,</span>’ said Scrooge, ‘and it’s not fair. If I was to stop half-a-crown for it, you’d think yourself ill used.’ …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p3" pid="08gjZIO8Qkqm25U8HSAFfg" hash="vXACGw">“‘And yet,’ said Scrooge, ‘you don’t think <span class="emphasis">me</span> ill-used, when I pay a day’s wages for no work.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p4" pid="xvTjAa78XUqHDNgJ8EI2LQ" hash="U4Xvhg">“The clerk observed that it was only once a year.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p5" pid="L66eFNliCUiPBJ1uvWx1ag" hash="azUyTw">“‘A poor excuse for picking a man’s pocket every twenty-fifth of December!’ said Scrooge.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p6" pid="JHlPs098hUaHX-nUMGPPfQ" hash="YDon5w">For Scrooge—as with any selfish, or “natural,” man—sacrifice is never <span class="emphasis">convenient.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p7" pid="aFwtswlkREW4vOKX36IEzg" hash="oTnXYA">The natural man has a tendency to think only of himself—not only to place himself first, but rarely, if ever, to place anyone else second, including God. For the natural man, sacrifice does not come naturally. He has an insatiable appetite for more. His so-called needs seem to always outpace his income so that having “enough” is forever out of reach, just as it was for the miser Scrooge.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p8" pid="dsIsAi9CTkiXHlEtzQKisw" hash="KLKmxg">Because the natural man tends to hoard or consume everything, the Lord wisely commanded ancient Israel to sacrifice not the last and poorest of the flock, but the firstlings—not the leftovers of the field, but the firstfruits (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/deut/26.2" class="scriptureRef">Deut. 26:2</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.3" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2:3</a>; <a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/5.5" class="scriptureRef">Moses 5:5</a>). Genuine sacrifice has been a hallmark of the faithful from the beginning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p9" pid="Bzi4d9qbeUSf2qpaq0QgQQ" hash="Qzt-1Q">Among those who do <span class="emphasis">not</span> sacrifice there are two extremes: one is the rich, gluttonous man who won’t and the other is the poor, destitute man who believes he can’t. But how can you ask someone who is starving to eat less? <span class="emphasis">Is</span> there a level of poverty <span class="emphasis">so</span> low that sacrifice should not be expected or a family so destitute that paying tithing should cease to be required?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p10" pid="UGrnCEEIHkqI7aqmKekt9g" hash="xU_Kpw">The Lord often teaches using extreme circumstances to illustrate a principle. The story of the widow of Zarephath is an example of extreme poverty used to teach the doctrine that mercy cannot rob sacrifice any more than it can rob justice. In fact, the truer measure of sacrifice isn’t so much what one gives to sacrifice as what one sacrifices to give (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/12.43" class="scriptureRef">Mark 12:43</a>). Faith isn’t tested so much when the cupboard is full as when it is bare. In these defining moments, the crisis doesn’t create one’s character—it reveals it. The crisis is the test.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p11" pid="gCK6jRlH3EWgkp6VG5PUdQ" hash="WVHMWQ">The widow of Zarephath lived in the days of the prophet Elijah, by whose word the Lord brought a drought upon the land for three and a half years (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/4.25" class="scriptureRef">Luke 4:25</a>). The famine grew so severe that many were finally at the point of death. This is the circumstance in which we find the widow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p12" pid="oTympg3zB0yO9DBBVDM5Cw" hash="M7XINQ">The Lord says to Elijah, “Arise, get thee to Zarephath … : behold, I have commanded a widow woman there to sustain thee” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-kgs/17.9" class="scriptureRef">1 Kgs. 17:9</a>). It is interesting that Elijah is not told to go to Zarephath until the widow and her son are at the point of death. It is at this extreme moment—facing starvation—that her faith will be tested.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p13" pid="WS2S7Q5Om0Cge-Bbkpj_mg" hash="kHUXWw">As he comes into the city he sees her gathering sticks.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p14" pid="cV-P7W80wk-2A7ZV5X8mJQ" hash="eGr6hA">“And he called to her, and said, Fetch me, I pray thee, a little water in a vessel, that I may drink.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p15" pid="P73QYCY_gkeln3CR2HwyPQ" hash="oUSjDw">“And as she was going to fetch it, he called to her, and said, Bring me, I pray thee, a morsel of bread in thine hand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p16" pid="VU_HiuqdrE-2sXHki7vJmA" hash="Wwc4rA">“And she said, As the Lord thy God liveth, I have not a cake, but an handful of meal in a barrel, and a little oil in a cruse: and, behold, I am gathering two sticks, that I may go in and dress it for me and my son, that we may eat it, and die” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-kgs/17.10-12" class="scriptureRef">1 Kgs. 17:10–12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p17" pid="hE6v55K9mk25rbazdJgtuQ" hash="zeEPSA">A <span class="emphasis">handful of meal</span> would be very little indeed, perhaps just enough for one serving, which makes Elijah’s response intriguing. Listen: “And Elijah said unto her, Fear not; go and do as thou hast said: but make me thereof a little cake <span class="emphasis">first</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-kgs/17.13" class="scriptureRef">1 Kgs. 17:13</a>; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p18" pid="sAQH8ONZvU2ekr3atsVGcg" hash="zP11aQ">Now doesn’t that sound selfish, asking not just for the first piece, but possibly the only piece? Didn’t our parents teach us to let other people go first and especially for a gentleman to let a lady go first, let alone a starving widow? Her choice—does she eat, or does she sacrifice her last meal and hasten death? Perhaps she will sacrifice her own food, but could she sacrifice the food meant for her starving son?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p19" pid="r1Ukkmu5U0aJxWY7TYU58w" hash="SL4k8A">Elijah understood the doctrine that blessings come <span class="emphasis">after</span> the trial of our faith (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.6" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:6</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/132.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 132:5</a>). He wasn’t being selfish. As the Lord’s servant, Elijah was there to give, not to take. Continuing from the narrative:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p20" pid="b1lt1uYwdUCiiFpxryy7FQ" hash="TInLYw">“But make me thereof a little cake<span class="emphasis"> first</span> [the firstlings], and bring it unto me, and <span class="emphasis">after</span> make for thee and for thy son.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p21" pid="hicGB4sHfUSswrMIKMYQyQ" hash="7LEe8w">“For thus saith the Lord God of Israel, The barrel of meal shall not waste, neither shall the cruse of oil fail, until the day that the Lord sendeth rain upon the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p22" pid="UTZajwhq80ud5tUExtxJyQ" hash="mXhc-Q">“And she went and did according to the saying of Elijah: and she, and he, and her house, did eat many days.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p23" pid="J3sgsYRUuEOxoVx1c9SFvQ" hash="gsZDDw">“And the barrel of meal wasted not, neither did the cruse of oil fail, according to the word of the Lord, which he spake by Elijah” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-kgs/17.13-16" class="scriptureRef">1 Kgs. 17:13–16</a>; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p24" pid="qxZzxPZpXk69qvbqC6Aj9A" hash="kz3Ppg">One reason the Lord illustrates doctrines with the most extreme circumstances is to eliminate excuses. If the Lord expects even the poorest widow to pay her mite, where does that leave all others who find that it is not <span class="emphasis">convenient</span> or easy to sacrifice?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p25" pid="Xy53G2yof0GU4FeZfAepBQ" hash="RVUa4g">No bishop, no missionary should ever hesitate or lack the faith to teach the law of tithing to the poor. The sentiment of “They can’t <span class="emphasis">afford</span> to” needs to be replaced with “They can’t afford <span class="emphasis">not</span> to.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p26" pid="r5BFxrKowUSrncgG6Qf-Fw" hash="ZBQsDQ">One of the first things a bishop <span class="emphasis">must</span> do to help the needy is ask them to pay their tithing. Like the widow, if a destitute family is faced with the decision of paying their tithing or eating, they should pay their tithing. The bishop can help them with their food and other basic needs until they become self-reliant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p27" pid="j5yif_IZbkGSAlyGBlPppA" hash="vph9og">In October of 1998 Hurricane Mitch devastated many parts of Central America. President Gordon B. Hinckley was very concerned for the victims of this disaster, many of whom lost everything—food, clothing, and household goods. He visited the Saints in the cities of San Pedro Sula and Tegucigalpa, Honduras; and Managua, Nicaragua. And like the words of the loving prophet Elijah to a starving widow, this modern prophet’s message in each city was similar—to sacrifice and be obedient to the law of tithing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p28" pid="YfUneHLhikmYbJ0oljFP7A" hash="FKWlcA">But how can you ask someone so destitute to sacrifice? President Hinckley knew that the food and clothing shipments they received would help them survive the crisis, but his concern and love for them went far beyond that. As important as humanitarian aid is, he knew that the most important assistance comes from God, not from man. The prophet wanted to help them unlock the windows of heaven as promised by the Lord in the book of Malachi (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/3.10" class="scriptureRef">Mal. 3:10</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.24" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2:24</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p29" pid="hrjAWgooA0iaQRg3D99eeQ" hash="GZSCvw">President Hinckley taught them that if they would pay their tithing, they would always have food on their tables, they would always have clothing on their backs, and they would always have a roof over their heads.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p30" pid="nSxDol1cg0SBa2rPcYw2-A" hash="qQsMaA">When serving a meal, it is much easier to set one more plate at the beginning of the meal than it is to find food for a latecomer once the meal is over and the food has been served. Likewise, isn’t it actually easier to give the Lord the firstlings or the firstfruits than it is to hope that there are sufficient “leftovers” for Him? As the founder of our feast, shouldn’t <span class="emphasis">He</span> be the guest of honor, the first to be served?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p31" pid="YRqCGdeyt0mgvOG5qwJIOQ" hash="QyoHUQ">My loving mother, Evelyn Robbins, taught me the law of tithing when I was four years old. She gave me an empty Band-Aid box, the tin kind with a snapping lid. She taught me to keep my tithing pennies in it and then take it to the bishop. I am eternally grateful for her, for that Band-Aid box, and for the blessings that have come from paying tithing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p32" pid="eApemW35HUaKStD-bdbWDg" hash="KCEr0g">In <span class="emphasis">A Christmas Carol,</span> Mr. Scrooge changed his ways—he was not the man he had been. Likewise, this is the gospel of repentance. If the Spirit is prompting us to more fully obey the law of sacrifice in our life, may we begin making that change today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute.p33" pid="ep5vyql5uUSS5oAsiDQ2dA" hash="u5knRw">I am so grateful for the Savior, who was the perfect example of obedience through sacrifice—who offered “himself a sacrifice for sin” and became, in Lehi’s words, “the <span class="emphasis">firstfruits</span> unto God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.7,9" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:7, 9</a>; emphasis added). I bear witness of Him and of these, His doctrines, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2005/04/tithing-a-commandment-even-for-the-destitute</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2005-general-conference/2005-04-2070-elder-lynn-g-robbins-64k-eng.mp3" length="4577437" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2005 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Manner of Men and Women Ought Ye to Be?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be?lang=eng</link>
      <description>May your efforts to develop Christlike attributes be successful so that His image may be engraven in your countenance and His attributes manifest in your behavior.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50028768_000_5040" doc-version="2" hash="STs-Wg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.head1">
    <h1 class="title" pid="g_YmNmYd-E25UjOc1QwO6w" hash="1ED8aA">What Manner of Men and Women Ought Ye to Be?</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="eBxQOO6Wo0yoiFSGrVKVfw" hash="E__f3A">Lynn G. Robbins</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="q9Rfm5daekyyByBz068_nw" hash="ICKnMQ">May your efforts to develop Christlike attributes be successful so that His image may be engraven in your countenance and His attributes manifest in your behavior.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p1" pid="UwvXdoayekWQ4jAdDbdLrw" hash="Ioo1tA">“To be, or not to be” is actually a very good question.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> The Savior posed the question in a far more profound way, making it a vital doctrinal question for each of us: “What manner of men [and women] ought ye <span class="emphasis">to be</span>? Verily I say unto you, even as <span class="emphasis">I am</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.27" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 27:27</a>; emphasis added). The first-person present tense of the verb <span class="emphasis">be</span> is <span class="emphasis">I Am.</span> He invites us to take upon us His name and His nature.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p2" pid="qBWpWJbLN0qBycgx2tZiQA" hash="8zhhgA">To become as He <span class="emphasis">is,</span> we must also <span class="emphasis">do</span> the things He <span class="emphasis">did:</span> “Verily, verily, I say unto you, this is my gospel; and ye know the things that ye must <span class="emphasis">do</span> in my church; for the works which ye have seen me <span class="emphasis">do</span> that shall ye also <span class="emphasis">do</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.21" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 27:21</a>; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p3" pid="Cg1pojmAe0GIIFrQywsIpA" hash="lQyXDQ">To <span class="emphasis">be</span> and to <span class="emphasis">do</span> are inseparable. As interdependent doctrines they reinforce and promote each other. Faith inspires one to pray, for example, and prayer in turn strengthens one’s faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p4" pid="rrHi_2yDkEiSgz7k8QoQdg" hash="EqXJFw">The Savior often denounced those who <span class="emphasis">did</span> without <span class="emphasis">being</span>—calling them hypocrites: “This people honoureth me with their lips, but their heart is far from me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/7.6" class="scriptureRef">Mark 7:6</a>). <span class="emphasis">To do</span> without <span class="emphasis">to be</span> is hypocrisy, or feigning to be what one is not—a pretender.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p5" pid="ho3xwmZ6wUShKpiLq6GJRQ" hash="U9OR9w">Conversely, <span class="emphasis">to be</span> without <span class="emphasis">to do </span>is void, as in “faith, if it hath not works, <span class="emphasis">is dead,</span> being alone” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/2.17" class="scriptureRef">James 2:17</a>; emphasis added). <span class="emphasis">Be</span> without <span class="emphasis">do</span> really isn’t <span class="emphasis">being</span>—it is self-deception, believing oneself to be good merely because one’s intentions are good.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p6" pid="_YBMJP3PCU-3FNI_Atcqug" hash="L5WvBg">
        <span class="emphasis">Do</span> without <span class="emphasis">be</span>—hypocrisy—portrays a false image to others, while <span class="emphasis">be</span> without <span class="emphasis">do</span> portrays a false image to oneself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p7" pid="hWxU0cWvtUunvbsql7ckuw" hash="b3r7-g">The Savior chastised the scribes and Pharisees for their hypocrisy: “Woe unto you, scribes and Pharisees, hypocrites! for ye pay tithe”—something they <span class="emphasis">did</span>—“of mint and anise and cummin, and have omitted the weightier matters of the law, judgment, mercy, and faith” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/23.23" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 23:23</a>). Or in other words, they failed <span class="emphasis">to be</span> what they should <span class="emphasis">have been.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p8" pid="LfCdyjT-xUelC5T8ZJYh7A" hash="iKt35A">While He recognized the importance of <span class="emphasis">do,</span> the Savior identified <span class="emphasis">be </span>as a “weightier matter.” The greater importance of <span class="emphasis">being</span> is illustrated in the following examples:</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.f2">
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="YeSNUHTwH0GE23eOoZw9Kg" hash="F0vG9Q">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="3oVjh0UGNkmdFNIBhB2ICA" hash="ZRM3fQ">Entering the waters of baptism is something we <span class="emphasis">do.</span> The <span class="emphasis">be</span> that must precede it is faith in Jesus Christ and a mighty change of heart.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="oas7X-PC50KLG_fZq5a1NQ" hash="zSoXzQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="xe91BrPmbk2bPjUZnCQLzA" hash="vago0Q">Partaking of the sacrament is something we <span class="emphasis">do. Being</span> worthy to partake of the sacrament is a weightier and much more important matter.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="dyOpE6t7SUGevKEiI8D7MQ" hash="pIq-PA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="jMzzdoRpJ0auZGDXNH7PGA" hash="rHfyXQ">Ordination to the priesthood is an act, or <span class="emphasis">do.</span> The weightier matter, however, is power in the priesthood, which is based “upon the principles of righteousness” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:36</a>), or<span class="emphasis"> be.</span></p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p9" pid="WqBRgId0W0OWW4R4RHRQ3Q" hash="Y7P27Q">Many of us create <span class="emphasis">to do</span> lists to remind us of things we want to accomplish. But people rarely have <span class="emphasis">to be</span> lists. Why? <span class="emphasis">To do</span>’s are activities or events that can be checked off the list when <span class="emphasis">done. To be,</span> however, is never done. You can’t earn checkmarks with <span class="emphasis">to be</span>’s. I can take my wife out for a lovely evening this Friday, which is a <span class="emphasis">to do.</span> But <span class="emphasis">being </span>a good husband is not an event; it needs <span class="emphasis">to be</span> part of my nature—my character, or who I am.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p10" pid="gj_lExw3ikebeq4g5yvqAQ" hash="VKUtkQ">Or as a parent, when can I check a child off my list as <span class="emphasis">done</span>? We are never done <span class="emphasis">being</span> good parents. And to be good parents, one of the most important things we can teach our children is how <span class="emphasis">to be</span> more like the Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p11" pid="eKl42bbcK020hAwoXmI3yQ" hash="4hD6aw">Christlike<span class="emphasis"> to be</span>’s cannot be seen, but they are the motivating force behind what we <span class="emphasis">do,</span> which can be seen. When parents help a child learn to walk, for example, we see parents <span class="emphasis">doing </span>things like steadying and praising their child. These <span class="emphasis">do</span>’s reveal the unseen love in their hearts and the unseen faith and hope in their child’s potential. Day after day their efforts continue—evidence of the unseen <span class="emphasis">be</span>’s of patience and diligence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p12" pid="5bpN2_fbnk-U6nzaUXA9FQ" hash="uEETdQ">Because <span class="emphasis">be</span> begets <span class="emphasis">do</span> and is the motive behind <span class="emphasis">do,</span> teaching <span class="emphasis">be</span> will improve behavior more effectively than focusing on <span class="emphasis">do</span> will improve behavior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p13" pid="Qe1TzIHqN025z_RRVuR9Ug" hash="CrtbFw">When children misbehave, let’s say when they quarrel with each other, we often misdirect our discipline on what they <span class="emphasis">did,</span> or the quarreling we observed. But the <span class="emphasis">do</span>—their behavior—is only a symptom of the unseen motive in their hearts. We might ask ourselves, “What attributes, if understood by the child, would correct this behavior in the future? Being patient and forgiving when annoyed? Loving and being a peacemaker? Taking personal responsibility for one’s actions and not blaming?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p14" pid="lwpQiVJO40uetTIb0wkNbg" hash="SJ__iQ">How do parents teach these attributes to their children? We will never have a greater opportunity to teach and show Christlike attributes to our children than in the way we discipline them. <span class="emphasis">Discipline</span> comes from the same root word as <span class="emphasis">disciple</span> and implies patience and teaching on our part. It should not be done in anger. We can and should discipline the way that <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121" class="scriptureRef">Doctrine and Covenants 121</a> teaches us: “by persuasion, by long-suffering, by gentleness and meekness, and by love unfeigned; by kindness and pure knowledge” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.41-42" class="scriptureRef">verses 41–42</a>). These are all Christlike <span class="emphasis">be</span>’s that should be a part of who we, as parents and disciples of Christ, <span class="emphasis">are.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p15" pid="XaeoQeBfcUuJ5zCbDuotCw" hash="FX1AZw">Through discipline the child learns of consequences. In such moments it is helpful to turn negatives into positives. If the child confesses to a wrong, praise the courage it took to confess. Ask the child what he or she learned from the mistake or misdeed, which gives you, and more important, the Spirit an opportunity to touch and teach the child. When we teach children doctrine by the Spirit, that doctrine has the power to change their very nature—<span class="emphasis">be</span>—over time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p16" pid="cVk-2ZGRXkygCf0vTBpMBQ" hash="pV0_1w">Alma discovered this same principle, that “the preaching of the word had a great tendency to lead the people <span class="emphasis">to do</span> that which was just—yea, it had had more powerful effect upon the minds of the people than the sword” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/31.5" class="scriptureRef">Alma 31:5</a>; emphasis added). Why? Because the sword focused only on punishing behavior—or <span class="emphasis">do</span>—while preaching the word changed people’s very nature—who they <span class="emphasis">were </span>or could<span class="emphasis"> become.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p17" pid="0iqM3nQ-JEKvVXewm4b_Jg" hash="RuOkiw">A sweet and obedient child will enroll a father or mother only in Parenting 101. If you are blessed with a child who tests your patience to the nth degree, you will be enrolled in Parenting 505. Rather than wonder what you might have done wrong in the premortal life to be so deserving, you might consider the more challenging child a blessing and opportunity to become more godlike yourself. With which child will your patience, long-suffering, and other Christlike virtues most likely be tested, developed, and refined? Could it be possible that you need this child as much as this child needs you?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p18" pid="4dsXu3kMI06mMjVmxG8-rw" hash="F9JGpg">We have all heard the advice to condemn the sin and not the sinner. Likewise, when our children misbehave, we must be careful not to say things that would cause them to believe that what they <span class="emphasis">did</span> wrong is who they <span class="emphasis">are.</span> “Never let failure progress from an action to an identity,” with its attendant labels like “stupid,” “slow,” “lazy,” or “clumsy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Our children are God’s children. That is their true identity and potential. His very plan is to help His children overcome mistakes and misdeeds and to progress to become as He <span class="emphasis">is.</span> Disappointing behavior, therefore, should be considered as something temporary, not permanent—an act, not an identity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p19" pid="o7Xt39PC9EWPYBQENPXUVg" hash="mBCSfg">We need to be careful, therefore, about using permanent phrases such as “You always …” or “You never …” when disciplining. Take care with phrases such as “You never consider my feelings” or “Why do you always make us wait?” Phrases like these make actions appear as an identity and can adversely influence the child’s self-perception and self-worth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p20" pid="AG1QiY60HUWUFgYzUs8sSw" hash="T-Ywpw">Identity confusion can also occur when we ask children what they want to <span class="emphasis">be</span> when they grow up, as if what a person <span class="emphasis">does</span> for a living is who he or she <span class="emphasis">is.</span> Neither professions nor possessions should define identity or self-worth. The Savior, for example, was a humble carpenter, but that hardly defined His life. </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p21" pid="rSDpc2b6YUCkpsL1VCmrwA" hash="BBgTwA">In helping children discover who they are and helping strengthen their self-worth, we can appropriately compliment their achievement or behavior—the <span class="emphasis">do.</span> But it would be even wiser to focus our primary praise on their character and beliefs—who they <span class="emphasis">are.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p22" pid="vGF-sPWx4kuBmFCJfJnBYQ" hash="MTKTvg">In a game of sports, a wise way to compliment our children’s performance—<span class="emphasis">do</span>—would be through the point of view of <span class="emphasis">be</span>—like their energy, perseverance, poise in the face of adversity, etc.—thus complimenting both <span class="emphasis">be</span> and <span class="emphasis">do.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p23" pid="qu2I8qkSg0CAzO4zo210FA" hash="0Yhg7w">When we ask children to <span class="emphasis">do</span> chores, we can also look for ways to compliment them on <span class="emphasis">being,</span> such as, “It makes me so happy when you do your chores with a willing heart.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p24" pid="8A4BjVJA3k2_mOrzfX1XXA" hash="JUXeQw">When children receive a report card from school, we can praise them for their good grades, but it may be of greater lasting benefit to praise them for their <span class="emphasis">diligence: </span>“You turned in every assignment. You are one who knows how to tackle and finish difficult things. I am proud of you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p25" pid="MoRaWJ-4g0CX7lbvlCpeKA" hash="WXkrmg">During family scripture time, look for and discuss examples of attributes discovered in your reading that day. Because Christlike attributes are gifts from God and cannot be developed without His help,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> in family and personal prayers, pray for those gifts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p26" pid="KGzGDPJQrkmn-kirYIIL1A" hash="eiMMEQ">At the dinner table, occasionally talk about attributes, especially those you discovered in the scriptures earlier that morning. “In what way were you a good friend today? In what way did you show compassion? How did faith help you face today’s challenges? In what way were you dependable? honest? generous? humble?” There are scores of attributes in the scriptures that need to be taught and learned.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p27" pid="2lmyVFpjDk2JSOZnqNs7-A" hash="n-kVzQ">The most important way to teach <span class="emphasis">to be</span> is <span class="emphasis">to be</span> the kind of parents to our children that our Father in Heaven is to us. He is the one perfect parent, and He has shared with us His parenting manual—the scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be.p28" pid="-DYhrLg3g0yJQLFRTw3roQ" hash="sCnSfg">My remarks today have been addressed primarily to parents, but the principles apply to everyone. May your efforts to develop Christlike attributes be successful so that His image may be engraven in your countenance and His attributes manifest in your behavior. Then, when your children or others feel of your love and see your behavior, it will remind them of the Savior and draw them to Him is my prayer and testimony in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/04/what-manner-of-men-and-women-ought-ye-to-be</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2011-general-conference/2011-04-5040-elder-lynn-g-robbins-64k-eng.mp3" length="4837777" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which Way Do You Face?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Lynn G. Robbins of the Seventy teaches us to show courage by putting God first, regardless of peer pressure or difficult circumstances.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10991_000_13robbins" doc-version="5" hash="Kns9oQ">
			
			<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.head1">
				<h1 class="title" pid="CwEsvaSx30OD83g9ei0Vng" hash="2i5B7g">Which Way Do You Face?</h1>
				<div class="byline">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p2" pid="cHIlQPnN-kieXhhtvBYn4Q" hash="0z8NDQ">By Elder Lynn G. Robbins</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p3" pid="Pwha3x5xG0-2pKZMWNFZtg" hash="hptprg">Of the Presidency of the Seventy</p>
					<a href="gl://image/?pid=CsOafgrWt0Oaio3pCQP4eg"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255576/e76934415a0941669fa6bc4c18fbc916/100x126.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x63="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255576/e76934415a0941669fa6bc4c18fbc916/50x63.jpg" data-src-100x126="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255576/e76934415a0941669fa6bc4c18fbc916/100x126.jpg" data-src-200x252="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255576/e76934415a0941669fa6bc4c18fbc916/200x252.jpg" data-src-320x404="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255576/e76934415a0941669fa6bc4c18fbc916/320x404.jpg" data-src-460x580="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255576/e76934415a0941669fa6bc4c18fbc916/460x580.jpg" data-src-640x808="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255576/e76934415a0941669fa6bc4c18fbc916/640x808.jpg" data-src-1024x1293="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255576/e76934415a0941669fa6bc4c18fbc916/1024x1293.jpg" data-src-2048x2586="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255576/e76934415a0941669fa6bc4c18fbc916/2048x2586.jpg" altText="Elder Lynn G. Robbins" pid="CsOafgrWt0Oaio3pCQP4eg" hash="1MkoLw"></img></a>
				</div>
				<p class="kicker" pid="NuCmG5KpqUmEHPq4UXtH5A" hash="5D_SbQ">Trying to please others before pleasing God is inverting the first and second great commandments.</p>
			<p class="authorName" pid="DIEHVvQb-Uq7-x_teAHGBw" hash="0z8NDQ1">By Elder Lynn G. Robbins</p></div>
			<div class="bodyBlock" pid="ybO8-TGHXU-93l2KCeIesg" hash="5jYQkg">
				<span class="story">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p5" pid="Xt7Y4oSc1kCM5-KJPuOobQ" hash="uQ1bSg">“Which way do you face?” President Boyd K. Packer surprised me with this puzzling question while we were traveling together on my very first assignment as a new Seventy. Without an explanation to put the question in context, I was baffled. “A Seventy,” he continued, “does not represent the people to the prophet but the prophet to the people. Never forget which way you face!” It was a powerful lesson.</p>
				</span>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p6" pid="tLKS4hb06Eye2s5CxbO2gg" hash="1HW5wA">Trying to please others before pleasing God is inverting the <span class="emphasis">first and second great commandments</span> (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.37-39" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 22:37–39</a>). It is forgetting which way we face. And yet, we have all made that mistake because of the fear of men. In Isaiah the Lord warns us, “Fear ye not the reproach of men” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/51.7" class="scriptureRef">Isaiah 51:7</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/8.7" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 8:7</a>). In Lehi’s dream, this fear was triggered by the <span class="emphasis">finger of scorn</span> pointed from the great and spacious building, causing many to forget which way they faced and to leave the tree “ashamed” (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/8.25-28" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 8:25–28</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p7" pid="Wbo6NiP7h0OOOO7zAZpihQ" hash="neIT9w">This peer <span class="emphasis">pressure</span> tries to change a person’s attitudes, if not behavior, by making one feel guilty for giving offense. We seek respectful coexistence with those who point fingers, but when this fear of men tempts us to condone sin, it becomes a “snare” according to the book of Proverbs (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/29.25" class="scriptureRef">Proverbs 29:25</a>). The snare may be cleverly baited to appeal to our compassionate side to tolerate or even approve of something that has been condemned by God. For the weak of faith, it can be a major stumbling block. For example, some young missionaries carry this fear of men into the mission field and fail to report the flagrant disobedience of a companion to their mission president because they don’t want to offend their wayward companion. Decisions of character are made by remembering the right order of the first and second great commandments (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.37-39" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 22:37–39</a>). When these confused missionaries realize they are accountable to God and not to their companion, it should give them courage to do an <span class="emphasis">about-face.</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p8" pid="mkT78MggU0OJMHe_vgSWFw" hash="nffcdA">At the youthful age of 22, even Joseph Smith forgot which way he faced when he repeatedly importuned the Lord to allow Martin Harris to borrow the 116 manuscript pages. Perhaps Joseph wanted to show gratitude to Martin for his support. We know that Joseph was extremely anxious for other eyewitnesses to stand with him against the distressing falsehoods and lies being spread about him.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p9" pid="21SjvLMViUm2H4TiWyKMkg" hash="Z_2Kbw">Whatever Joseph’s reasons were, or as justified as they may appear, the Lord did not excuse them and sharply rebuked him: “How oft you have transgressed … and have gone on in the persuasions of men. For, behold, you should not have <span class="emphasis">feared</span> man more than God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/3.6-7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 3:6–7</a>; emphasis added). This poignant experience helped Joseph remember, forever after, which way he faced.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p10" pid="OxQwIOnyxkaZADjwEuDWpw" hash="l_8PIQ">When people try to <span class="emphasis">save face</span> with men, they can unwittingly <span class="emphasis">lose face</span> with God. Thinking one can please God and at the same time condone the disobedience of men isn’t neutrality but duplicity, or being <span class="emphasis">two-faced</span> or trying to “serve two masters” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.24" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 6:24</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/13.24" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 13:24</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p11" pid="zvGDNpVhKEWrANKVTK-yBA" hash="vUkXTQ">While it certainly takes courage to face perils, the true badge of courage is overcoming the fear of men. For example, Daniel’s prayers helped him face lions, but what made him lionhearted was defying King Darius (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/dan/6" class="scriptureRef">Daniel 6</a>). That kind of courage is a gift of the Spirit to the <span class="emphasis">God-fearing</span> who have said their prayers. Queen Esther’s prayers also gave her that same courage to confront her husband, King Ahasuerus, knowing that she risked her life in doing so (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/esth/4.8-16" class="scriptureRef">Esther 4:8–16</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p12" pid="Sm8M4tn_50CMM37_6zwhkQ" hash="2NLUAQ">Courage is not just one of the cardinal virtues, but as C. S. Lewis observed: “Courage is … the form of every virtue at the testing point. … Pilate was merciful till it became risky.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> King Herod was sorrowful at the request to behead John the Baptist but wanted to please “them which sat with him at meat” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/14.9" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 14:9</a>). King Noah was ready to free Abinadi until peer pressure from his wicked priests caused him to waver (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/17.11-12" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 17:11–12</a>). King Saul disobeyed the word of the Lord by keeping the spoils of war because he “feared the people, and obeyed their voice” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-sam/15.24" class="scriptureRef">1 Samuel 15:24</a>). To appease rebellious Israel at the foot of Mount Sinai, Aaron crafted a golden calf, forgetting which way he faced (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/32" class="scriptureRef">Exodus 32</a>). Many of the New Testament chief rulers “believed on [the Lord]; but because of the Pharisees they did not confess him, lest they should be put out of the synagogue: for they loved the praise of men more than the praise of God” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/12.42-43" class="scriptureRef">John 12:42–43</a>). The scriptures are full of such examples.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p13" pid="6Tz61S1fKkyzj4sl_S3U1Q" hash="DSvqKw">Now listen to some inspiring examples:</p>
				<ul class="bullet">
					<li pid="2Q2rxiyarkqeNG8anbIbmA" hash="X9lTdw">
						<span class="label">•</span>
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p14" pid="_cJ3Ml0WX0WIVuYGRqlDvw" hash="MrhBNQ">First, Mormon: “Behold, I speak with boldness, having authority from God; and I <span class="emphasis">fear not</span> what man can do; for perfect love casteth out all fear” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/8.16" class="scriptureRef">Moroni 8:16</a>; emphasis added).</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="VZO-XjyieUGpOeikal_JQQ" hash="6DSKaw">
						<span class="label">•</span>
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p15" pid="UjiHU-AT4Uiw8hrgEacDBg" hash="3lBWgw">Nephi: “Wherefore, the things which are pleasing unto the world I do not write, but the things which are pleasing unto God and unto those who are not of the world” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/6.5" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 6:5</a>).</p>
					</li>
					<li pid="wuD4uC9RXUOd5UfT820ppw" hash="KpCUUA">
						<span class="label">•</span>
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p16" pid="BDicZSYZIESCdwgvyi3ZQg" hash="ThbsQg">Captain Moroni: “Behold, I am Moroni, your chief captain. I seek not for power, but to pull it down. I seek not for honor of the world, but for the glory of my God, and the freedom and welfare of my country” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/60.36" class="scriptureRef">Alma 60:36</a>).</p>
					</li>
				</ul>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p17" pid="15DRSpGwSk2wHwVjiUrlMQ" hash="byOGOg">Moroni had such great courage in remembering which way he faced that it was said of him, “If all men had been, and were, and ever would be, like unto Moroni, behold, the very powers of hell would have been shaken forever; yea, the devil would never have power over the hearts of the children of men” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/48.17" class="scriptureRef">Alma 48:17</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p18" pid="fcUTDro34EmnpT4jcu10mA" hash="EdB0vg">Prophets through the ages have always come under attack by the finger of scorn. Why? According to the scriptures, it is because “the guilty taketh the truth to be hard, for it cutteth them to the very center” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/16.2" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 16:2</a>), or as President Harold B. Lee observed, “The hit bird flutters!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Their scornful reaction is, in reality, guilt trying to reassure itself, just as with Korihor, who finally admitted, “I always knew that there was a God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/30.52" class="scriptureRef">Alma 30:52</a>). Korihor was so convincing in his deception that he came to believe his own lie (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/30.53" class="scriptureRef">Alma 30:53</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p19" pid="1P8eHFHx7USKnABizBAqdQ" hash="_S46cQ">The scornful often accuse prophets of not living in the 21st century or of being bigoted. They attempt to persuade or even pressure the Church into lowering God’s standards to the level of their own inappropriate behavior, which in the words of Elder Neal A. Maxwell, will “develop self-contentment instead of seeking self-improvement”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> and repentance. Lowering the Lord’s standards to the level of a society’s inappropriate behavior is—apostasy. Many of the churches among the Nephites two centuries after the Savior’s visit to them began to “dumb down” the doctrine, borrowing a phrase from Elder Holland.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p20" pid="IrcX3gLedE61VTKRSNEUEQ" hash="iDXxaQ">As you listen to this passage from 4 Nephi, look for parallels in our day: “And it came to pass that when two hundred and ten years had passed away there were many churches in the land; yea, there were many churches which professed to know the Christ, and yet they did deny the more parts of his gospel, insomuch that they did receive all manner of wickedness, and did administer that which was sacred unto him to whom it had been forbidden because of unworthiness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/4-ne/1.27" class="scriptureRef">4 Nephi 1:27</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p21" pid="OrQwqgKeAkGoarLWfLu7Tw" hash="UOtCpA">Déjà vu in the latter days! Some members don’t realize they are falling into the same snare when they lobby for acceptance of local or ethnic “tradition[s] of their fathers” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.39" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:39</a>) that are not in harmony with the gospel culture. Still others, self-deceived and in self-denial, plead or demand that bishops lower the standard on temple recommends, school endorsements, or missionary applications. It isn’t easy being a bishop under that kind of pressure. However, like the Savior who cleansed the temple to defend its sanctity (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/2.15-16" class="scriptureRef">John 2:15–16</a>), bishops today are called upon to boldly defend the temple standard. It was the Savior who said, “I will manifest myself to my people in mercy … if my people will keep my commandments, and do not pollute this holy house” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/110.7-8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 110:7–8</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p22" pid="dfVP5LHHzkmnpRvLAnmxIQ" hash="-erIlg">The Savior, our great Exemplar, always faced His Father. He loved and served His fellowmen but said, “I receive not honour from men” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.41" class="scriptureRef">John 5:41</a>). He wanted those He taught to follow Him, but He did not court their favor. When He performed an act of charity, such as healing the sick, the gift often came with the request to “tell no man” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/8.4" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 8:4</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/7.36" class="scriptureRef">Mark 7:36</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/5.14" class="scriptureRef">Luke 5:14</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/8.56" class="scriptureRef">8:56</a>). In part, this was to avoid the very fame which followed Him in spite of His efforts to eschew it (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/4.24" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 4:24</a>). He condemned the Pharisees for doing good works only to be seen of men (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.5" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 6:5</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p23" pid="ioc52hwjfEKif7bIHLk4kw" hash="W-BYyQ">The Savior, the only perfect being who ever lived, was the most fearless. In His life, He was confronted by scores of accusers but never yielded to their finger of scorn. He is the only person who never once forgot which way He faced: “I do <span class="emphasis">always</span> those things that please [the Father]” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.29" class="scriptureRef">John 8:29</a>; emphasis added), and “I seek not mine own will, but the will of the Father which hath sent me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.30" class="scriptureRef">John 5:30</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p24" pid="LiNC4GGok0K2lw4rK62DBw" hash="yJMdow">Between <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi chapter 11</a> and <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/28" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi chapter 28</a>, the Savior used the title <span class="emphasis">Father</span> at least 150 times, making it very clear to the Nephites that He was there representing His Father. And from John chapters 14 through 17, the Savior refers to the Father at least 50 times. In every way possible, He was His Father’s perfect disciple. He was so perfect in representing His Father that to know the Savior was also to know the Father. To see the Son was to see the Father (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.9" class="scriptureRef">John 14:9</a>). To hear the Son was to hear the Father (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.36" class="scriptureRef">John 5:36</a>). He had, in essence, become indistinguishable from His Father. His Father and He were one (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.21-22" class="scriptureRef">John 17:21–22</a>). He flawlessly knew which way He faced.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face.p25" pid="02vDBpdZG0WKU0jV48rcuQ" hash="6683rg">May His inspiring example strengthen us against the pitfalls of flattery from without or of conceit from within. May it give us courage to never cower or fawn at the feet of intimidation. May it inspire us to go about doing good as anonymously as possible and not “aspire to the honors of men” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.35" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:35</a>). And may His incomparable example help us always remember <span class="emphasis">which</span> is “the first and great commandment” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.38" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 22:38</a>). When others demand approval in defiance of God’s commandments, may we always remember whose disciples we are, and which way we face, is my prayer in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div>
			
		</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/10/which-way-do-you-face</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2014-general-conference/2014-10-1030-elder-lynn-g-robbins-64k-eng.mp3" length="5278702" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Righteous Judge</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Robbins shares the importance of judging in righteousness and of teaching and correcting others with love, as the Savior would.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60001311_000_57robbins" doc-version="1" hash="FGt3IQ">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="3ygSS7Bb70qeqLoGSDCXIg" hash="_cHQWA">The Righteous Judge</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p2" pid="GVt_BrTqPk6T9JaporF6AQ" hash="0z8NDQ1">By Elder Lynn G. Robbins</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p3" pid="7xv1_pZV2EWbXy2KFnmWmw" hash="hptprg">Of the Presidency of the Seventy</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="OLqWJRtN2EKoR0uSu1zFCQ" hash="JQGckg">There is only one way to judge righteous judgment, as Jesus Christ does, and that is to be as He is.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="qM7BlCGS7U6CA5EZOh1oQg" hash="0z8NDQ">By Elder Lynn G. Robbins</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p5" pid="qGsmhrVZh0aL6_UXtr8_mA" hash="Yai1YA">In His mortal life, Jesus Christ was a loving judge, uncommonly wise and patient. He is known in the scriptures as “the righteous judge” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/4.8" class="scriptureRef">2 Timothy 4:8</a>; <a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/6.57" class="scriptureRef">Moses 6:57</a>), and His counsel to us is to also “judge righteous judgment” (see Joseph Smith Translation, Matthew 7:1–2 [in <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.1" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 7:1</a>, footnote <span class="emphasis">a</span>]) and to “put your trust in that Spirit which leadeth to do good … [and] to judge righteously” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/11.12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 11:12</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p6" pid="Mii8MhLJZEe6h6ekKUB1UQ" hash="5Nx8lw">This counsel to the Nephite Twelve will help us judge as the Lord does: “Ye shall be judges of this people,<span class="emphasis"> according to the judgment which I shall give unto you,</span> which shall be just. Therefore, what manner of men ought ye to be? Verily I say unto you, even as I am” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.27" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 27:27</a>; emphasis added). We sometimes forget that when He gave the counsel to be as He is, it was in the context of how to judge righteously.</p>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.t1">
				<h2 pid="oGDMxnBB1UK5oAGk1OW7vQ" hash="XgK2eg">Unrighteous Judgment</h2>
				<a href="gl://image/?pid=8Ih8769P90yrwYnaARrCEw"><img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813935/875c3886c12c49dcae4c277b124d4d6f/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813935/875c3886c12c49dcae4c277b124d4d6f/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813935/875c3886c12c49dcae4c277b124d4d6f/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813935/875c3886c12c49dcae4c277b124d4d6f/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813935/875c3886c12c49dcae4c277b124d4d6f/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813935/875c3886c12c49dcae4c277b124d4d6f/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813935/875c3886c12c49dcae4c277b124d4d6f/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813935/875c3886c12c49dcae4c277b124d4d6f/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813935/875c3886c12c49dcae4c277b124d4d6f/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813935/875c3886c12c49dcae4c277b124d4d6f/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Savior with Pharisees and scribes" pid="8Ih8769P90yrwYnaARrCEw" hash="UyEvyw"></img></a>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p8" pid="H8VYPshF70yPmPPzTBrYpw" hash="uhzhcA">A shameful example of unrighteous judgment comes from the parable of the lost sheep, when the Pharisees and scribes ill-judged both the Savior and His dinner company, saying, “This man receiveth sinners, and eateth with them” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15.2" class="scriptureRef">Luke 15:2</a>)—they were oblivious to the fact that they were sinners themselves. Possessed of condemning hearts, the scribes and Pharisees never knew the joy of rescuing lost sheep.</p>
				<a href="gl://image/?pid=-pSo4g6hvkGnmhxt93DSPQ"><img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813936/2c18fbf91f274daa827c904da816cb0f/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813936/2c18fbf91f274daa827c904da816cb0f/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813936/2c18fbf91f274daa827c904da816cb0f/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813936/2c18fbf91f274daa827c904da816cb0f/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813936/2c18fbf91f274daa827c904da816cb0f/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813936/2c18fbf91f274daa827c904da816cb0f/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813936/2c18fbf91f274daa827c904da816cb0f/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813936/2c18fbf91f274daa827c904da816cb0f/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813936/2c18fbf91f274daa827c904da816cb0f/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813936/2c18fbf91f274daa827c904da816cb0f/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Savior with woman taken in adultery" pid="-pSo4g6hvkGnmhxt93DSPQ" hash="pkRjCA"></img></a>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p9" pid="E2Qe5rooykO1VtFuWNMZ3w" hash="5xqI1Q">It was also “the scribes and Pharisees” who brought “a woman taken in adultery” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.3" class="scriptureRef">John 8:3</a>) to the Savior to see if He would judge her according to the law of Moses (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.5" class="scriptureRef">verse 5</a>). You know the rest of the story, how He humbled them for their unrighteous judgment and how they were “convicted by <span class="emphasis">their own </span>conscience” and departed “one by one” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.9" class="scriptureRef">verse 9</a>; emphasis added). He then said to the woman, “Neither do I condemn thee: go, and sin no more. And the woman glorified God from that hour, and believed on his name” (Joseph Smith Translation, John 8:11 [in <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.11" class="scriptureRef">John 8:11</a>, footnote <span class="emphasis">c</span>]).</p>
				<a href="gl://image/?pid=AOiSQrj90kGsRWDA9aQJCg"><img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813937/21a6c304467947a5a55316d91247bf60/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813937/21a6c304467947a5a55316d91247bf60/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813937/21a6c304467947a5a55316d91247bf60/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813937/21a6c304467947a5a55316d91247bf60/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813937/21a6c304467947a5a55316d91247bf60/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813937/21a6c304467947a5a55316d91247bf60/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813937/21a6c304467947a5a55316d91247bf60/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813937/21a6c304467947a5a55316d91247bf60/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813937/21a6c304467947a5a55316d91247bf60/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813937/21a6c304467947a5a55316d91247bf60/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Savior speaking to woman taken in adultery" pid="AOiSQrj90kGsRWDA9aQJCg" hash="QSU0mw"></img></a>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p10" pid="8JItO_eAA0mxZ-Fs4ZLi8w" hash="xp2H_Q">The natural man and woman in each of us has a tendency to condemn others and to judge unrighteously, or self-righteously. This even happened to James and John, two of the Savior’s Apostles. They were infuriated when the people of a Samaritan village treated the Savior disrespectfully (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/9.51-54" class="scriptureRef">Luke 9:51–54</a>):</p>
				<a href="gl://image/?pid=KiKrBj6GH0qy_XBY0jHJPw"><img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813938/724d5a7d09234810b61800200c679115/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813938/724d5a7d09234810b61800200c679115/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813938/724d5a7d09234810b61800200c679115/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813938/724d5a7d09234810b61800200c679115/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813938/724d5a7d09234810b61800200c679115/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813938/724d5a7d09234810b61800200c679115/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813938/724d5a7d09234810b61800200c679115/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813938/724d5a7d09234810b61800200c679115/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813938/724d5a7d09234810b61800200c679115/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813938/724d5a7d09234810b61800200c679115/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Savior with followers" pid="KiKrBj6GH0qy_XBY0jHJPw" hash="V_fZ7Q"></img></a>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p11" pid="VYbKUSB52EC9A5L8GnRnVQ" hash="j4x8ZA">“And when [they] saw this, they said, Lord, wilt thou that we command fire to come down from heaven, and consume them, even as Elias did?</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p12" pid="PnnCYpEKDkue4Z8nBml_Og" hash="WAgioA">“But he turned, and rebuked them, and said, Ye know not what manner of spirit ye are of.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p13" pid="UW5uPWMlsUmeWgEzdBES4A" hash="9MH2QA">“For the Son of man is not come to destroy men’s lives, but to save them” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/9.54-56" class="scriptureRef">verses 54–56</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p14" pid="c6D8FFp75UiMdRQP1fIQRQ" hash="rmdUug">Today’s “common judge[s]” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.74" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:74</a>), our bishops and branch presidents, should avoid any similar impulse to condemn, as James and John did on that occasion. A righteous judge would respond to confessions with compassion and understanding. An erring youth, for example, should leave the bishop’s office feeling the love of the Savior through the bishop and enveloped in the joy and healing power of the Atonement—never shamed or held in contempt. Otherwise, the bishop may unwittingly drive the lost sheep further into the wilderness (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15.4" class="scriptureRef">Luke 15:4</a>).</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.t2">
				<h2 pid="0EfxT100L02QH4mVb7ABYg" hash="iuE0_w">Discipline</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p16" pid="0fkeM5_36EOBiW1qzbqUNg" hash="bOv1qA">However, compassion doesn’t nullify the need for discipline. The word <span class="emphasis">discipline</span> comes from the Latin word <span class="emphasis">discere,</span> “to learn,” or <span class="emphasis">discipulus,</span> “learner,” making a disciple a student and follower.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> To discipline in the Lord’s way is to lovingly and patiently teach. In the scriptures the Lord often uses the word <span class="emphasis">chasten</span> when speaking of discipline (see, for example, <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/23.21" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 23:21</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/95.1" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 95:1</a>). The word <span class="emphasis">chasten</span> comes from the Latin <span class="emphasis">castus,</span> meaning “chaste or pure,” and <span class="emphasis">chasten</span> means “to purify.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p17" pid="kuoPnqwgoUq5K61c4pFj-w" hash="_KJSqg">In the world, it is an earthly judge who condemns a man and <span class="emphasis">locks </span>him in prison. In contrast, the Book of Mormon teaches us that when we willfully sin, we become our “own judges” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/41.7" class="scriptureRef">Alma 41:7</a>) and consign ourselves to spiritual prison. Ironically, the common judge in this case holds the keys that <span class="emphasis">unlock</span> the prison gates; “for with the chastisement I prepare a way for their <span class="emphasis">deliverance</span> in all things out of temptation” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/95.1" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 95:1</a>; emphasis added). The proceedings of a righteous judge are merciful, loving, and redemptive, not condemning.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p18" pid="4bC4sllSikOlMqG2r69Ung" hash="gvKP8g">Young Joseph Smith was disciplined with a four-year probation before obtaining the golden plates, “because you have not kept the commandments of the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Later, when Joseph lost the 116 manuscript pages, he was disciplined again. Though Joseph was truly remorseful, the Lord still withdrew his privileges for a short season because “whom I love I also chasten that their sins may be forgiven” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/95.1" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 95:1</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p19" pid="9ltb4taf2EyTyyjf3PRAPw" hash="vt2DKA">Joseph said, “The angel was rejoiced when he gave me back the Urim and Thummim and said that God was pleased with my faithfulness and humility, and loved me for <span class="emphasis">my penitence</span> and diligence in prayer.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Because the Lord wanted to teach Joseph a heart-changing lesson, He required a heartrending sacrifice of him—sacrifice being an essential part of discipline.</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.t3">
				<h2 pid="3n5YObDAQU2upCz8TrCz-Q" hash="vY_iGQ">Sacrifice</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p21" pid="yGrhEO7XsEKD0ZZEvhgqUw" hash="fzlN-g">“In ancient days, <span class="emphasis">sacrifice</span> meant to make something or someone holy,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> which links it, in an interdependent way, to the definition of the word <span class="emphasis">chasten—</span>“to purify.” Likewise, in ancient Israel, forgiveness came through a sin or trespass offering, or sacrifice.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> The sacrifice not only “point[ed] to that great and last sacrifice” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/34.14" class="scriptureRef">Alma 34:14</a>) but also helped engender a deeper sense of gratitude for the Savior’s Atonement. An unwillingness to sacrifice as part of our penitence mocks or belittles Christ’s greater sacrifice for the same sin and trivializes His suffering—a callous sign of ingratitude.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p22" pid="St3SLhJsSUuB-jeQDTIqWA" hash="XqdnDA">On the other hand, through the sweet irony of sacrifice, we actually <span class="emphasis">gain </span>something of eternal worth—His mercy and forgiveness and eventually “all that [the] Father hath” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:38</a>). As part of the repentance process, sacrifice also acts as a healing balm to help replace “remorse of conscience” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/42.18" class="scriptureRef">Alma 42:18</a>) with “peace of conscience” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.3" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:3</a>). Without sacrifice, a person may find it hard to forgive himself or herself, because of a lingering consciousness of something withheld.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.t4">
				<h2 pid="zMTHEolim0W4qKzzV8WLkg" hash="QFB-RA">The Parent as a Righteous Judge</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p24" pid="BZYZWy_5sE2W2V_jeeKphQ" hash="ap7UVA">While few of us will be called to be common judges, the principles of righteous judgment apply to all of us, especially to parents who have a daily opportunity to use these principles with their children. To effectively teach a child is the very essence of good parenting, and to lovingly discipline is the very essence of being a righteous judge.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p25" pid="2sdKwp3g3USkEoQFEg8bZg" hash="dtvcjw">President Joseph F. Smith taught, “If children are defiant and difficult to control, be patient with them until you can conquer by love, … and you can then [mold] their characters as you please.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p26" pid="z9LaUextSUyUxgTGKRr0ZA" hash="bBZVlA">It is insightful that in teaching how to discipline, the prophets seem to always refer to Christlike attributes. The Doctrine and Covenants gives us this well-known advice on discipline:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p27" pid="UMKQB-DrkE6tjILTux0StQ" hash="nkeFvA">“No power or influence can or ought to be maintained by virtue of the priesthood, only by persuasion, by long-suffering, by gentleness and meekness, and by love unfeigned;</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p28" pid="ipAInrJAL0OcoBL7jelvJw" hash="yGGnbQ">“By kindness, and pure knowledge, which shall greatly enlarge the soul without hypocrisy, and without guile—</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p29" pid="jAYWPBc5CUGg5FyDVLsoUg" hash="A4HVDw">“Reproving betimes with sharpness, when moved upon by the Holy Ghost; and then showing forth afterwards an increase of love” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.41-43" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:41–43</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p30" pid="qLmzNIJqw0GiR68M--6rxw" hash="n-y8jw">This scripture teaches us to reprove “when moved upon by the Holy Ghost,” <span class="emphasis">not</span> when moved upon by anger. The Holy Ghost and anger are incompatible because “he that hath the spirit of contention is not of me, but is of the devil, who is the father of contention, and he stirreth up the hearts of men to contend with anger” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.29" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 11:29</a>). President George Albert Smith taught that “unkind things are not usually said under the inspiration of the Lord. The Spirit of the Lord is a spirit of kindness; it is a spirit of patience; it is a spirit of charity and love and forbearance and long suffering. …</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p31" pid="IHocJPPp3EicwBMyyd2Zxw" hash="biNNpw">“… But if we have the spirit of fault finding … in a destructive manner, that <span class="emphasis">never</span> comes as a result of the companionship of the Spirit of our Heavenly Father and is <span class="emphasis">always</span> harmful.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p32" pid="qgO_EAuOOEugtZDPhB5yyA" hash="vR_gAg">“… Kindness is the power that God has given us to unlock hard hearts and subdue stubborn souls.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.t5">
				<h2 pid="DvUUXzqOakekuteXonWD9Q" hash="8klQ3g">Our Children’s True Identity</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p34" pid="aoffhhrZekOW6sXcFoCQIA" hash="1Vah9Q">When the Savior visited the Nephites, He did something extraordinary with the children:</p>
				<a href="gl://image/?pid=0xdgKy8XmE2vxmVgcyU5ZA"><img xmlns="" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813939/d3c43823ed6243318eb2a042fc6eaad2/100x138.png" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813939/d3c43823ed6243318eb2a042fc6eaad2/50x69.png" data-src-100x138="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813939/d3c43823ed6243318eb2a042fc6eaad2/100x138.png" data-src-200x276="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813939/d3c43823ed6243318eb2a042fc6eaad2/200x276.png" data-src-320x441="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813939/d3c43823ed6243318eb2a042fc6eaad2/320x441.png" data-src-460x634="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813939/d3c43823ed6243318eb2a042fc6eaad2/460x634.png" data-src-640x883="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813939/d3c43823ed6243318eb2a042fc6eaad2/640x883.png" data-src-1024x1413="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813939/d3c43823ed6243318eb2a042fc6eaad2/1024x1413.png" data-src-1304x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1813939/d3c43823ed6243318eb2a042fc6eaad2/1304x1800.png" altText="Savior with Nephite children" pid="0xdgKy8XmE2vxmVgcyU5ZA" hash="O6zfpA"></img></a>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p35" pid="yACoiATyc0S2nWv-npdgWg" hash="EnLDuw">“And it came to pass that he did teach and minister unto the children of the multitude … , and he did loose their tongues, and they did speak unto their fathers great and marvelous things. …</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p36" pid="iaqSla5exkWJzb292YDf3g" hash="ryBANw">“… And they both saw and heard these children; yea, even babes did open their mouths and utter marvelous things” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/26.14,16" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 26:14, 16</a>).</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p37" pid="u__UeRlq3EGNl0QxEU86nA" hash="y1rGXg">Perhaps more than <span class="emphasis">opening the mouths</span> of babes, the Lord was <span class="emphasis">opening the eyes </span><span class="emphasis">and ears</span> of their astonished parents. Those parents had been granted the extraordinary gift of a glimpse into eternity and of beholding the true identity and premortal stature of their children. Would that not forever change the way the parents <span class="emphasis">saw </span>and treated their children? I like this variation of a quote attributed to Goethe: “The way you see [a child] is the way you treat them, and the way you treat them is [who] they [will] become.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> To remember a child’s true identity is a gift of foresight that divinely inspires the vision of a righteous judge.</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.t6">
				<h2 pid="M-MuAa9ANE6ImpwUDxZ0jQ" hash="JZFLeA">Conclusion</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p39" pid="gU4FS6xNu0-gm4e2KlXqDg" hash="e8sNzg">President Thomas S. Monson has taught us, “Never let a problem to be solved become more important than a person to be loved.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> How vital that principle is in becoming righteous judges, especially with our own children.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge.p40" pid="I3fXoSmKuUazS2ehKCtUxA" hash="fELB5w">There is only one way to judge righteous judgment, as Jesus Christ does, and that is to be as He is. Therefore, “what manner of men [and women] ought ye to be? Verily I say unto you, even as I am” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.27" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 27:27</a>). In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/10/the-righteous-judge</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2016-general-conference/2016-10-4070-lynn-g-robbins-64k-eng.mp3" length="4947733" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
