<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Lynn A. Mickelsen</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Lynn A. Mickelsen.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Lynn%20A.%20Mickelsen.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Lynn A. Mickelsen.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1990 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>What Is Truth?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth?lang=eng</link>
      <description>What is truth? This poignant question was asked by the Roman ruler Pilate as the accused Savior was brought before him declaring, “For this cause came I into the world, that I should bear witness unto the truth. Every one that is of the truth heareth</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_90911_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="xvwqhw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="vUSP1EEbBEOJTAdP4BTk-w" hash="NTb7sQ">What Is Truth?</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="GxaqZkl4tUaA9C5ROyr1Dw" hash="h9ZMTA">Lynn A. Mickelsen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2140.jpg" alt="Elder Lynn A. Mickelsen" pid="KMVE43n-LU6Mk9NEiOsSfw" hash="ysMZNw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p1" pid="c8ByGzTyrEupcRcy9tPYXg" hash="pNFZww">What is truth? This poignant question was asked by the Roman ruler Pilate as the accused Savior was brought before him declaring, “For this cause came I into the world, that I should bear witness unto the truth. Every one that is of the truth heareth my voice.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/18.37" class="scriptureRef">John 18:37</a>.) In modern-day revelation, He declared, “Truth is knowledge of things as they are, and as they were, and as they are to come;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p2" pid="2IzXNPuXO0-reyplzKVqNQ" hash="ys9LPA">“And whatsoever is more or less than this is the spirit of that wicked one who was a liar from the beginning.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.24-25" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:24–25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p3" pid="HoRIi5eDqEmI3yhu-JZxxw" hash="04yr5w">How can we know the truth? The early members of the Church brought with them many customs, traditions, and practices from their earlier beliefs. Not all of these practices conformed to the will of the Lord. In a revelation given in May 1831, He explained to the elders of the Church how to discern and decide which of these practices were appropriate. He referred to both sides of the issue of teaching and receiving. Not only must we teach by the Spirit, we must receive by the Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p4" pid="tvsldVYm9kmMx2CK3-ewQw" hash="cQ9oow">“And again, he that receiveth the word of truth, doth he receive it by the Spirit of truth or some other way?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p5" pid="hJrtFOCs3UihEGMTezwVQQ" hash="ReX-TQ">“If it be some other way it is not of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/50.19-20" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 50:19–20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p6" pid="a0C0RaaLS0OJw21KgaJYyQ" hash="nYKLmQ">If we do not receive the truth by His spirit, it is not His word. In a latter-day revelation the Lord speaks very strongly about those who get on the wrong side of the question:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p7" pid="WAheKN5ymEClY0iO9uG1MA" hash="AyLqCw">“Verily, verily, I say unto you, that Satan has great hold upon their hearts; he stirreth them up to iniquity against that which is good; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p8" pid="jFQo5VLujEW3SJrsvhF80g" hash="-l4PYg">“And they love darkness rather than light, … therefore they will not ask of me.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/10.20-21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 10:20–21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p9" pid="lxLRWU2wJEKiUt_qRcqO_g" hash="-7cEPQ">A few months ago, a friend came to our home under the pretext that he had some questions about the Church he needed help in answering. He said he had discovered the Book of Mormon was not the word of God and that Joseph Smith was not a prophet of God. He then proceeded to quote articles and books which were written by enemies of the Church. As he listed his sources, I replied that I also had read them and others, and they had only served to confirm my faith in the Book of Mormon and the Prophet Joseph Smith. He was surprised that I could have read the same things he had read and not believe as he believed. I suggested that he devote at least equal time to the right side of the issue, but he had come with a decision, not a question. His mind was made up. He did not want to know. His heart was closed. I thought of the children of Israel and their reaction to the Lord after he had guided them out of bondage: “And notwithstanding they being led, the Lord their God, their Redeemer, going before them, leading them by day and giving light unto them by night, and doing all things for them which were expedient for man to receive, they hardened their hearts and blinded their minds, and reviled against Moses and against the true and living God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.30" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:30</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p10" pid="GwlJPHCp2kSptdfNReZWzg" hash="5GMCVA">The promise of the Lord with regard to his word and his works is very explicit: “If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it be of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/7.17" class="scriptureRef">John 7:17</a>.) This was His constant rejoinder to those who rejected Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p11" pid="-BVX4MSK20mDjvJsD-PmlQ" hash="OvKtAg">He told the Pharisees and the Sadducees they were looking in the right places with the wrong objectives in mind when He said, “Search the scriptures; for in them ye think ye have eternal life: and they are they which testify of me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.39" class="scriptureRef">John 5:39</a>.) They had obviously made a very careful study of the word that testified of Him and failed to find Him. Their foregone conclusions had not allowed the Spirit to guide them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p12" pid="5gApGzFTqUedF_xOkLQ18w" hash="jmxEpg">The same conditions exist today: we must ask the right questions; we must seek in the right places and knock on the right doors. That sometimes is very difficult to do. Nicodemus had to come to the Savior by night because his position in the community and in his church would have been seriously threatened had his contemporaries known of his inquiry in the right place. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.1-21" class="scriptureRef">John 3:1–21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p13" pid="G4j4RW-Iyk-rSSfCHLxtHA" hash="jUuzMA">King Lamoni asked the right questions of Ammon when he said, “Who are you? How do you know these things? Where is God? Are you sent from him?” Then Ammon explained the plan of salvation to him, and he was able to understand because he opened his mind to knowledge and his heart to the Spirit. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/18.18-40" class="scriptureRef">Alma 18:18–40</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p14" pid="yuHOn4kOWky4BTlfKhpP8g" hash="eIhrPA">The prophet Alma, in his great discourse to the Zoramites, said, “But behold, if ye will awake and arouse your faculties, even to an experiment upon my words, and exercise a particle of faith, yea, even if ye can no more than desire to believe, let this desire work in you, even until ye believe in a manner that ye can give place for a portion of my words.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.27" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:27</a>.) He explained to them that we open the door to receive by the Spirit with just a desire to believe. We must want to know the truth; we manifest that desire by asking, seeking, and knocking; the explicit promise is that He will answer, open, and help us find the truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p15" pid="OhXmhozPpEuTIBPV6uWb4A" hash="QZEBJw">We must prepare our hearts and our minds with a sincere desire to know the truth. King Benjamin taught, “My brethren, all ye that have assembled yourselves together, you that can hear my words which I shall speak unto you this day; for I have <span class="emphasis">not</span> commanded you to come up hither to trifle with the words which I shall speak, but that you should hearken unto me, and open your ears that ye may hear, and your hearts that ye may understand, and your minds that the mysteries of God may be unfolded to your view.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2:9</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p16" pid="ijX-EGXrFk-TANF2WxBU5A" hash="kZyeCQ">On the day of Pentecost, when Peter and John obviously were speaking with great power and by the Spirit, the men were pricked in their hearts and asked the question, “Men and brethren, what shall we do?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/2.37" class="scriptureRef">Acts 2:37</a>.) In order to receive the truth, we must do the same. That is our responsibility—to ask and to seek.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p17" pid="Kb8FHjDdnU6_Oo1-NCWsLg" hash="O2Wm6g">As we seek for the truth, we should always bear in mind the counsel of Mormon when he explained, “Wherefore, all things which are good cometh of God; and that which is evil cometh of the devil.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.12" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:12</a>.) He then counseled us to be very careful in choosing and gave us the way to decide:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p18" pid="tyMWltX4eEapx1VHw2PreQ" hash="ZvBmKQ">“For behold, my brethren, it is given unto you to judge, that ye may know good from evil; and the way to judge is as plain, that ye may know with a perfect knowledge, as the daylight is from the dark night.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p19" pid="BkHba1X2GEaY2EDoixTY3g" hash="D0BWUA">“For behold, the Spirit of Christ is given to every man, that he may know good from evil; wherefore, I show unto you the way to judge; for every thing which inviteth to do good, and to persuade to believe in Christ, is sent forth by the power and gift of Christ; wherefore ye may know with a perfect knowledge it is of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.15-16" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:15–16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p20" pid="N3sAZl0jBECfp-YBC0_TWg" hash="7Z0XYg">What a blessing it is for us that the Prophet Joseph Smith asked the right questions in the right places for the right reason. As he and Sidney Rigdon pondered the question of the state of man’s existence after this life, the Lord touched the eyes of their understanding, and they were opened to a vision of the kingdom of God. In recording this vision they said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p21" pid="Ni9OcSC2HESuJv9btTkDEw" hash="DkHgJQ">“And now, after the many testimonies which have been given of him, this is the testimony, last of all, which we give of him: That he lives!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p22" pid="qpHBnsoCfUqv8BmXirYoOg" hash="E7qA3w">“For we saw him, even on the right hand of God; and we heard the voice bearing record that he is the Only Begotten of the Father—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p23" pid="xteUS3IGi0KjAW-42PNRQg" hash="HuUMpw">“That by him, and through him, and of him, the worlds are and were created, and the inhabitants thereof are begotten sons and daughters unto God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.22-24" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:22–24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth.p24" pid="YGX9-jx4kkm7oVczYjuomQ" hash="ZAHpKw">Yes, for me it is as clear as the night from the day. Their witness of the Savior is true. I have heard His voice as I have read His word in the sacred writings of the prophets of the Book of Mormon and rejoiced with the further light and knowledge granted to our latter-day prophets. I add my witness to theirs: He lives; I know He lives. This is His church. May we all look in the right places and ask the right questions and thus be taught by His Spirit to know the truth, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1990/10/what-is-truth</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1990-general-conference/1990-10-2060-elder-lynn-a-mickelsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="4537309" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1990 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eternal Laws of Happiness</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/10/eternal-laws-of-happiness?lang=eng</link>
      <description>President Hinckley, I feel that I can speak for the Saints throughout the world, that we were profoundly stirred by your prophetic charge to move the work forward with greater energy. We pledge our lives and our obedience to accomplish that purpose.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/eternal-laws-of-happiness" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95911_000_031" doc-version="2" hash="czI-qQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/eternal-laws-of-happiness.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="g3SNjK-7MUOUpV1QNrYnDA" hash="piWdfg">Eternal Laws of Happiness</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Ew563swYk069XN_xV_t0BQ" hash="h9ZMTA">Lynn A. Mickelsen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/eternal-laws-of-happiness.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2140.jpg" alt="Elder Lynn A. Mickelsen" pid="-jNfCt8j4kKzYoYQwfI_yA" hash="ysMZNw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/eternal-laws-of-happiness.p1" pid="ThtQF2Fxyk-ZsGAMX1WxBw" hash="r6F5mA">President Hinckley, I feel that I can speak for the Saints throughout the world, that we were profoundly stirred by your prophetic charge to move the work forward with greater energy. We pledge our lives and our obedience to accomplish that purpose.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/eternal-laws-of-happiness.p2" pid="Xaq6WW6cO0yoeqAEeUDInQ" hash="QP-g6A">While teaching at BYU in 1978, Brother Dennis Rasmussen applied and was selected to study at the Jewish Theological Seminary of America. In the opening session, as he gave his name and university, Rabbi Muffs boomed, “You’re the Mormon! … Do you pay your tithing?” “Yes,” he answered. “Do you pay it with a joyful heart?” “I believe,” the rabbi said, “that joy is the essence of religion. There is nothing more fundamental to religious living than joy. … I am working on a book about joy.” Brother Rasmussen responded, “There’s a passage in the Book of Mormon … , ‘Adam fell that men might be; and men are, that they might have joy.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Rabbi Muffs was profoundly touched and exclaimed, “I’ve found the text I’ve searched for all my life … in the Book of Mormon.” Turning to Brother Rasmussen he said, “Say it again, but not so fast.” As he repeated the familiar words, the rabbi’s eyes glowed in appreciation of this great truth he understood but had not heard so succinctly expressed.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/eternal-laws-of-happiness.p3" pid="2T3Tsp7YVEe3pOt82XQ3Jw" hash="fYKF1A">How important it is to know the purpose of our existence. Man <span class="emphasis">is</span> that he might have joy, and that joy will come to us as we keep God’s commandments!<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/eternal-laws-of-happiness.p4" pid="bN5S-8tZV0abqDQBJCe6qw" hash="B0r_Gg">Last February I saw this joy personified as I accompanied the missionaries in Santiago, Chile, to visit some of their converts. At the Basuare home, eight-year-old twin boys, Nicolas and Ignacio, met us at the door, dressed in white shirts and ties, just like missionaries. Their father had been baptized three weeks earlier, and the following week he baptized his wife and sons. We talked of their conversion. They shared their feelings of love for the missionaries and the joy they were experiencing in living the gospel and keeping the commandments. They proudly showed us the picture of the Santiago temple displayed in their living room, a symbol of their goal to become an eternal family one year from the date of their baptism.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/eternal-laws-of-happiness.p5" pid="a0JWLQYw_0Kj_I2poyNUcw" hash="PBRQPA">I asked Nicolas if he would like to be a missionary when he grew up. He answered yes, and we shook hands on the promise that he would prepare for the day. Then I asked Ignacio the same question. He hesitated and replied, “I’m not sure I can make that promise. I’m only eight years old.” I persisted, “Nicolas made the promise. Wouldn’t you like to do the same?” He still hesitated and said, “I don’t know if I could be ready.” I could see I had taken on more than I could manage, so I said, “Perhaps you’d better talk this over with your father.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/eternal-laws-of-happiness.p6" pid="Xvl2uRZYTEqU39ZYlX5AVw" hash="DbCyng">He went to his father, who took him in his arms and said, “Ignacio, Jesus was a missionary. He walked the streets like Elder Sheets and his companion and made the people happy by teaching them to keep the commandments. Wouldn’t you like to be like Jesus?” “Yes, Papi, I would.” “Do you think if we work together, you can be ready to be a missionary when you are nineteen years old?” “I think so.” He came to me, and we shook hands to confirm the promise. I marveled that this young father, a convert of just three weeks, could be so sensitive in helping his family follow the Savior and how he emulated the missionaries in teaching his son. Their goal of becoming an eternal family will surely be reached under the guidance of this faithful father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/eternal-laws-of-happiness.p7" pid="-3YDI1yztUiUX9Y2iyExsA" hash="2ibV_w">Since the beginning of creation such family happiness has been central to our Heavenly Father’s plan. Having been cast out of the Garden of Eden, Adam and Eve began to multiply and replenish the earth. As their family increased, they called upon the Lord for help. He gave them commandments and told them to teach them to their children.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> These eternal laws were reiterated to Moses on Sinai, summed up by the Savior in the two great commandments,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> and repeated to Joseph Smith in a revelation known as the “law of the Church.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> We also must teach these commandments to our children. Our happiness in this life and joy in the future as eternal families depend on how well we <span class="emphasis">live</span> them. I believe we can teach the Ten Commandments to our children in a positive way so they will reflect the higher law the Savior has given us.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/eternal-laws-of-happiness.f2">
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="QsDcAFLRkUyoLnqB61ijBw" hash="F-rlog">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="yo-1PtIes0K8Xj4NPLSjlw" hash="3xsykw">“Thou shalt have no other gods before me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> Teach them that God lives, that He really does exist, and that He is the literal Father of our spirits. We are created in His image. We have all of His attributes in embryo.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> He loves us and wants us to be like Him. He wants us to communicate with Him. <span class="emphasis">Teach them to pray.</span></p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="3owF9b7Xbk-OIBzfEltHrQ" hash="uVscow">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="aybsDfCCHUm5OB5UVYviUQ" hash="TFnhkQ">Thou shalt not bow to any graven image.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span><span class="emphasis">Our Father in Heaven must come first. Nothing in this world can take His place.</span> Teach your children to recognize His hand in all things, to respect and honor Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Show them how to worship Him through selfless service to others. Worship Him in family prayer and family home evening. We fail to worship Him when we give preeminence to sports, academics, entertainment, wealth, vanity, or anything else of this world.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="YMJtc6KTr0GLNAVuQFLsBw" hash="djxxZQ">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="Pgx-lHfxfECPoReRmtqm1w" hash="hW-hgA">“Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord thy God in vain.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> Prepare your children to take upon themselves the name of Christ through the covenant of baptism. When we make this covenant, we become known as His children and promise to keep His commandments.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> When we break the promises and covenants we make to Him and do not repent, we take His name in vain.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="mc-oXlRGqk-rjFKZyAc43A" hash="sBY8jg">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="r0rlUfjAcEK1AFysbr-OqA" hash="DgUP4Q">Thou shalt honor the Sabbath day to keep it holy.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> Teach your children to set apart one-seventh of their time to learn of Him, to take their minds from the burdens of daily work, and to remember Him. As we dedicate this time to Him, it concentrates our hearts and our minds on the <span class="emphasis">real purpose</span> of our existence and takes us out of the world. It is a day to become as He is, to worship Him, and to minister to others as He did. We don’t need rules for the Sabbath day when we understand and live its purpose.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Q2j4AqBHuEiyjNmHmR5dng" hash="6s_-xA">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p pid="CsCMD8QWxEqpHEcoc0iKwQ" hash="H0ez4w">“Honour thy father and thy mother.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> Teach your children obedience; train them up in the way they should go.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> Our children learn to obey their Father in Heaven through honoring, respecting, and obeying their earthly parents. Teach them family ethics and establish the parameters of their conduct. The Lord gave the children of Israel the promise that their days would be long upon the land the Lord had given them. The same promise is valid today. For them it was the land of Canaan; for us it is eternal life with our families.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="GKKHB7x9nU6_J_lZRnmarg" hash="FWF4Yg">
          <span class="label">6.</span>
          <p pid="GPI6KquuRkGSXIrDuZ4hsA" hash="_x5ukQ">“Thou shalt not kill.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> We are created in the image of God.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> The union of the flesh with the spirit can bring us a fulness of joy.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> Teach your children to respect the sanctity of human life, to revere it and cherish it. Human life is the precious stepping-stone to eternal life, and we must jealously guard it from the moment of conception.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span></p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="taqL6aNcrUCO6veMzqedDg" hash="yAqZGw">
          <span class="label">7.</span>
          <p pid="2FDCP0uEvUK0UpYo8QEIYA" hash="FCERSQ">“Thou shalt not commit adultery.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span> Teach your children that our bodies are temples of God, wherein the Spirit of God can dwell.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> Teach them the sacred nature of the family, the beauty of marriage, and the godlike nature of procreation, which our Father in Heaven has given us. We enter into a partnership with Him in the creation of life. This power must be respected, protected, and exercised only within the sacred bonds of marriage.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> It is a celestial power that, if abused, will be taken away.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="yB9zAFE750CCJNpQYReWfQ" hash="fP2Bzg">
          <span class="label">8.</span>
          <p pid="BsMoccm1ZkC4TNB08b79TQ" hash="2IHz_Q">“Thou shalt not steal.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span> Teach your children to be honest and to respect that which belongs to others, especially that which belongs to our Father in Heaven. Teach them by example to pay a full tithing and give generous offerings. As they stamp their actions with honesty, they will be filled with the Spirit and power of God.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26">26</span> Teach them the joy of giving and sharing.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_27">27</span></p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="oE9_3FYKb0eQ3woXH36FGQ" hash="mWtfxA">
          <span class="label">9.</span>
          <p pid="Nv7ZGlmCqEygKU3gBO0FCA" hash="BGlHVw">“Thou shalt not bear false witness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_28">28</span> Teach your children to always tell the truth, to tell things as they really are, to build, to find the good in others, and to be positive and complimentary. Truth is more precious than any earthly possession. Truth is the essence of our existence.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_29">29</span> As we tell the truth, our confidence will wax strong in the presence of God and our fellowman.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_30">30</span></p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="G052-Gbck06BodDlORNZww" hash="Pfbycg">
          <span class="label">10.</span>
          <p pid="1NQ2CtrW-EqXM2vWEN3zlQ" hash="XBfi7w">“Thou shalt not covet.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_31">31</span> We must love our children and teach them they are children of a Heavenly Father, who loves them. As they feel our love, they will feel His love and will be grateful for their good name and for the name of Christ, which they bear. As they feel our love and the love of their Heavenly Father, they feel no need for the possessions of others. Help them to measure personal progress and not compare themselves to others. Teach them to love others and to rejoice with their achievements.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/eternal-laws-of-happiness.p8" pid="Xl_8n92ju0ORu7iT6UWg3Q" hash="6GK27Q">As we keep the Ten Commandments, we express our love to God, and with the active application of these eternal principles, we express our love to our fellowmen. These are eternal laws of happiness that, if followed, will lead us back to our Father in Heaven.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_32">32</span> I pray that we may be able to teach them by example and precept. May we all feel the joy the Basuare family felt as they came to know the truth of the gospel and are now teaching the commandments to their children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/eternal-laws-of-happiness.p9" pid="VATKqq3OZkSluMFK8tnjHQ" hash="nq-AYg">With a positive understanding of the commandments, our children will have a greater desire to follow them and a better comprehension of the power of the Atonement for forgiveness when they make mistakes. As they understand His sacrifice for us, they will repent and go forward with a perfect brightness of hope, knowing that Christ will pay for their sins if they follow Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_33">33</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/eternal-laws-of-happiness.p10" pid="kpaQSpC9QkWmNUBwPGq6lw" hash="w5PLAw">May we teach and live the commandments so that together with our families we may fill the measure of our creation<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_34">34</span> and obtain the joy our Father in Heaven desires for us. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/10/eternal-laws-of-happiness</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1995-general-conference/1995-10-5030-elder-lynn-a-mickelsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="4998042" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 1995 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Atonement, Repentance, and Dirty Linen</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The promise of the Lord is that He will cleanse our garments with His blood. … He can redeem us from our personal fall.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030835_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="_ts-Aw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="T9QG3uRCuEmcD0fzJb-27g" hash="3brciA">The Atonement, Repentance, and Dirty Linen</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="RdiX9ECRu0m9Dv5hEx1lnQ" hash="h9ZMTA">Lynn A. Mickelsen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="1k3MLA5FTk2RhVT4J6pIHA" hash="N7HDHg">The promise of the Lord is that He will cleanse our garments with His blood. … He can redeem us from our personal fall.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-61f.jpg" alt="Elder Lynn A. Mickelsen" pid="5ywjtC6SjUW1zfvX6lRecA" hash="TI80lg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p1" pid="rpkNrpqoDEagZqt62HlemQ" hash="-RD77w">While driving through a small town in Mexico, a man ran over and killed a dog that darted in front of him. From that day on, he was known in the village as <span class="emphasis">mataperros.</span> No consideration or thought was given to the origin of the name; he was simply the “dog killer.” For those who came along later, not knowing the circumstance, their minds conjured up a terrible image of what he had done.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p2" pid="PeUrVfOMtUmEDo34v0fPlA" hash="JFE4UQ">Reputations built on rumor, reality, or established by nickname can be virtually impossible to overcome. The adage “Do not wash your dirty linen in public” is wise counsel. It is not necessary, appropriate, nor healthy to expose our private or family mistakes and sins for public scrutiny. The more widely a sin is known, the more difficult the repentance or change.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p3" pid="nhGEw2-7-kCHFjYWd5TT-Q" hash="xX3BTQ">This is not to say that sin should be covered, although that is the natural impulse of anyone who commits a sin. Rather than repent, we want to hide any mistakes or sins committed. But as Cain discovered when he killed Abel, he could not hide his sins from the Lord,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> for all things are present before Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> He knows of every disobedient act we commit, but—different from the general public—He, with His knowledge of our sins, gives the specific promise that He will remember them no more if we repent.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p4" pid="p4_MbzVh4kObEk_Pu-K10g" hash="F0Y52w">Washing dirty linen and repentance are intrinsically linked. Sin brings an uncleanliness before the Lord that must be reconciled. There is, however, a time and a place for confession and asking forgiveness. The scope of those parameters depends on the nature and the magnitude of the sin. Where there has been a public offense or a violation of public trust, the responsibility would be to air that wrongdoing in public and ask forgiveness. The span of our responsibility in repentance is to the Lord, His servants, and those we have offended.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p5" pid="xohoWov6hky62sVXtqwFBQ" hash="XrVqGA">There is a parallel between our garments being washed clean through the blood of the Lamb and how we wash our own dirty linen. It is through His atoning sacrifice that our garments will be cleansed. The scriptural reference to garments encompasses our whole being. The need for cleansing comes as we become soiled through sin. The judgment and forgiving are the Savior’s prerogative, for only He can forgive and wash away our sins.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p6" pid="HX4MUygWLUaaOZrlbdfiew" hash="L5zk4Q">When King Benjamin gave his great sermon in the land of Zarahemla,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> the Saints changed their hearts,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> and there was peace and prosperity throughout the land. Time went by, and Alma was called to preside over the Church. Caught up in their prosperity, some of the members of the Church fell into sin. Alma’s heart was troubled when they were brought before him. Not knowing how to handle the problem, he took them before King Mosiah, but the king remanded them to Alma’s judgment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p7" pid="BbBGM1c2ik-8jDlZPrzYXA" hash="W6VlQQ">Fearing to do wrong in the sight of God, Alma poured out his whole soul to God and pled with Him for answers as to how to handle the transgressors. Because of Alma’s great love for his fellowman and his fervent desire to do God’s will, the Lord blessed him mightily, even with a promise of eternal life. Then the Lord explained to him why his pleading for understanding in judgment was so important, saying: “This is <span class="emphasis">my</span> Church. It is <span class="emphasis">my</span> name through which they will be saved. It is through <span class="emphasis">my</span> sacrifice. It is <span class="emphasis">I</span> who will judge.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p8" pid="c8UfJQLQxUuVA6WFsSrzXw" hash="d-qxoA">How often do we forget who has the right to judge? Forgiveness of sin depends on Him, not on us. So the next time we are tempted to hang dirty linen in public, let us remember:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p9" pid="HIIeJsQYIkqD2aJZJ6Ki-Q" hash="-dD1DA">First, go to the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p10" pid="SDlu_-NMQkGb_2nLWRYo2Q" hash="Iz4bJQ">Second, go to the one we have offended.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p11" pid="QRv0boIaI0yzxEqxcVeymg" hash="xxJUlQ">Third, if necessary, go to our judge in Israel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p12" pid="-xmFuWh4pUyHK5Ki8KrOBA" hash="0_TUMA">And fourth, then put it away.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p13" pid="ZjfrCOz8UkWIyhY56RJ2VQ" hash="PQMypg">Another side of exposing dirty linen is the carnal, insatiable appetite that some have to expose the faults of others. The Lord challenged Job as he was chafing under his burden: “Wilt thou condemn me, that thou mayest be righteous?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> This can happen even in the family, when one, supposing he is protecting his <span class="emphasis">own</span> good name, exposes in elaborate detail the faults and mistakes of his siblings, his children, or his parents in a form of self-justification designed to alleviate his personal pain.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p14" pid="73a8pcpbX0eVmdXsVGd7bw" hash="XyUJsw">In the parable of the prodigal son, the prodigal was reclaimed by a faithful father who spoke of his son’s worth, not of his faults.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p15" pid="nU0lPOiE6kSJYC4RQ4Tq6w" hash="pBZD1Q">Whenever we tell of others’ sins or mistakes, we are in effect passing judgment on them. I heard a man tell his son that an individual would never work for him again because he felt the individual had charged him unfairly. The boy responded, “I’m surprised to hear you say that, Dad, for you have taught us differently.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p16" pid="nKWnjHRvK0SIq7w1O5CC_g" hash="uuJ22g">The father was judging without basis. What should he have done? If he had questions about the charges for the work, he should have discussed them with the man, resolved their differences, and laid it to rest without grousing to others. The Savior taught: “Judge not, that ye be not judged. For with what judgment ye judge, ye shall be judged: and with what measure ye mete, it shall be measured to you again.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p17" pid="jld7BQ17QEaTB0_REkJw-A" hash="j28IwQ">When the scribes and Pharisees brought the woman taken in adultery to Jesus, He stooped and wrote with His finger in the sand that others might not see nor hear. Then He said, “He that is without sin among you, let him first cast a stone.” When her accusers had all squirmed away in their sins, He said to the woman, “Go, and sin no more.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.f2">
	<p pid="KBg0MRmHHUWT5t1X9uMecA" hash="8XmX0Q">What should we do when we have knowledge of others’ problems?</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="WlnFTqJeA0qUYEPLe7Dq9Q" hash="IFtzfg">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="LEVcgVpobEuPFsafSjvGYg" hash="iFHFuA">Don’t judge. Leave judgment to the Lord, the perfect judge. Let us not examine or explore others’ sins but look to their divinity. It is not ours to delve into others’ problems but rather to perceive the breadth of their goodness.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="lYj2W_BA_UOkutEuu92-MA" hash="QiOUGA">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="Ktg8NIbdkEiA1bikj3AzWw" hash="3vAiEA">We must forgive. Although we may have been personally wounded, the Lord said, “I, the Lord, will forgive whom I will forgive, but of <span class="emphasis">you</span> it is required to forgive all men.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="vmQAXM-zB0KztCtmFPsXDg" hash="CBicwQ">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="mZ2-iq0PCE-mypzPIs_1_A" hash="DGOsWA">Forget. A relentless memory can canker the most resilient spirit. Leave it alone; lay it down; put it away.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p18" pid="O5Qci_o6bk68n2amLDzHPQ" hash="2-xZrQ">If the wave of temptation to reveal others’ sins comes over you, don’t tell your neighbor or even your best friend. Go to your bishop. Leave the burden with him. If it is required, report it to the civil or criminal authorities and then leave it alone. I believe that to receive the precious promise that Alma received requires the same spirit and action he took regarding his, and others’, dirty linen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p19" pid="6jmZ0S2FS0qwSv4nE38dwQ" hash="2GYtYg">But what if we are right and they are wrong? Shouldn’t we make our position public so others will not judge us to have made the mistake? The Lord has been clear in His instruction regarding this dilemma. It is not our prerogative to judge. The mote is not ours to measure, for the beam in our own eye obstructs our capacity to see. There is no pancake so thin it has only one side. Empathy is required here, the gift to feel what others feel and to understand what others are experiencing. Empathy is the natural outgrowth of charity. It stimulates and enhances our capacity to serve. Empathy is not sympathy but understanding and caring. It is the basis of true friendship. Empathy leads to respect and opens the door to teaching and learning. The Sioux Indians understand this great principle as they pray, “Great Spirit, help me to never judge another until I have walked for two weeks in his moccasins.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p20" pid="2YLMSsKWmE2Nu1IpCcxWdw" hash="hXvAPA">So what should we do with dirty linen? The process begins with repentance. The Savior stands at the door and knocks; He is ready to receive us immediately.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Our responsibility is to do the work of repentance. We must abandon our sins so the cleansing can begin. The promise of the Lord is that He will cleanse our garments with His blood.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> He gave His life and suffered for all our sins. He can redeem us from our personal fall. Through the Atonement of the Savior, giving Himself as the ransom for our sins, He authorizes the Holy Ghost to cleanse us in a baptism of fire. As the Holy Ghost dwells in us, His purifying presence burns out the filthiness of sin. As soon as the commitment is made, the cleansing process begins.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p21" pid="ishGQAZE7kGqgcTcl0r0Og" hash="5AubJg">Our commitment to the Lord begins with our focus on Him. We were recently in a stake conference in Nauvoo, Illinois. The choir music was exceptional. The director, who is a professional musician and teaches at a local university, was a master at captivating the choir and congregation. Every movement of his body was intrinsically linked to the music. We wanted to sing exactly as he was leading. All eyes were on him. I thought of the Savior. He has challenged us to be as He is. If we would give Him the rapt attention we were giving Brother Nelson, we would quickly be transformed into the Savior’s image.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p22" pid="te2ts3-zBEa0rXHAS_QeFQ" hash="ATCy0g">The transformation as we were singing was momentary. We were where we needed to be, and all had a great desire to follow. If we find ourselves in the places we should be, with the fervent desire to follow the Lord, He will touch our lives and cleanse us that we may live in His presence permanently. There was no coercion by the director to get us to sing, just connection. Real repentance comes with that connection to the Savior. Let us consider our personal prayers and everyday thoughts. We all have work to do to make the connection the Lord requires.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p23" pid="xF3-ry1qPUy4CBEnK-7e_A" hash="x1S1ew">I asked Brother Nelson how he could draw so much out of us. He humbly replied, “Because their hearts are pure.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p24" pid="XnpXRjE_GE-Lm7fQGDH5jw" hash="IjsLMg">“What else?” I asked.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p25" pid="rEu3n4_Afky-zJXZ3LU02Q" hash="DatNYA">He answered, “It is through the Spirit. That is the only way we can communicate at that level.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p26" pid="nKt3UnxsZk-b7rR8LjRkXA" hash="MiRGeg">So where should our focus be? “And if your eye be single to my glory, your whole bodies shall be filled with light, and there shall be no darkness in you; and that body which is filled with light comprehendeth all things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> That can happen if we take responsibility for our dirty linen through repentance and make sure it is clean.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen.p27" pid="MUASoHnYNUmKixxyqVle8A" hash="wP9X7g">May we enjoy the Savior’s promise through Moroni to “arise … and put on thy beautiful garments. … Come unto Christ … and love God with all your might, mind and strength, … that by his grace ye may be perfect in Christ; … through the shedding of the blood of Christ, which is in the covenant of the Father unto the remission of your sins, that ye become holy, without spot.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2003/10/the-atonement-repentance-and-dirty-linen</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2003-general-conference/2003-10-1030-elder-lynn-a-mickelsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5342177" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2003 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
