<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Marcos A. Aidukaitis</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Marcos A. Aidukaitis.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Marcos%20A.%20Aidukaitis.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Marcos A. Aidukaitis.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Because My Father Read the Book of Mormon</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I invite all who hear me today to read the Book of Mormon and to apply the promise it contains. Those who do will know that the book is true.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00009501_000_007" doc-version="2" hash="hptPWg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="2QyvdwO6CEiyC8gkmZcpNw" hash="yq9Rvg">Because My Father Read the Book of Mormon</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="KebedQS-m06YWEGfLiJ77g" hash="0NNABQ">Elder Marcos A. Aidukaitis</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="6GC5rLSznUadxd17LYPqug" hash="07PaQQ">I invite all who hear me today to read the Book of Mormon and to apply the promise it contains. Those who do will know that the book is true.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.p1" pid="IK6aBTiy6Um7WjdYCiu6zg" hash="kwVcsA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="15"></span>Good morning, dear brothers and sisters. I feel a profound joy and honor in speaking to you today. I pray that God may guide my words and that His Spirit may be with us so that “he that preacheth and he that receiveth, [may] understand one another, and both [may be] edified and rejoice together” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/50.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 50:22</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.p2" pid="qvdxnmbh606yKmADNeId3w" hash="qEc8bQ">I consider June 2, 1940, to be a very important day in the history of my family. On this day my father was baptized into this Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.p3" pid="Fb3e22keLUWs0qC2bnRWUw" hash="gBmGkg">Writing to his father, Elder Jack McDonald, one of the missionaries who baptized my father, described the day with these words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.p4" pid="65__aA6Q9kWKb5kXkAOkiA" hash="8yiX5Q">“Last Sunday was an especially beautiful day. We missionaries went out to a secluded spot on the river’s edge, out in the country, and there Elder Jones and I [Elder McDonald] made our first baptism. Antony Aidukaitis entered into the icy waters and became a member of the Church. … Everything was perfect. The sky so blue, the countryside so still, so green, so lovely that none of us could help feeling the presence of some great influence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.p5" pid="_JkpyFmlxUyj-MQ9tOzHqQ" hash="ccAxwg">“[As we walked] with our new member, he said that he just couldn’t explain how wonderful this day had been for him, how he actually felt like a new man. … That was our first baptism—no credit to me or anybody. He converted himself.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.p6" pid="Qgqs0ZzMjESOFCyqcyHxXg" hash="BFPzhA">This event changed the history of my life. I am not sure my father was able to foresee the wisdom of his act, but I love him for what he did that day. He passed away more than 30 years ago, but I will honor and bless his name forever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.p7" pid="mucsnNKFg0OK1B0LCqt34w" hash="UGweuw">My father was the son of Lithuanians, but he was born in Scotland. He moved to Brazil when he was still young. His ability to speak English facilitated his conversion since he could read the Book of Mormon in English, and there was not yet a reliable translation into Portuguese. This language barrier prevented my mother from joining the Church until a few years later, but when she did, she became a powerful example of dedication to others and love of God in our family. She is now 92 years old, and she is here today. It gives me great joy to say that I love her for her great faithfulness. I will also honor and bless her name forever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.p8" pid="4xFIQmwiHEGV_yZ1gabi-g" hash="QVYbRw">I admire the courage my father had to be baptized into the Church in spite of the circumstances he faced at the time. It was not easy for him. His wife did not get baptized with him. The vices of drinking alcohol and smoking were strong temptations for him. He was poor. His mother was against his joining the Church, and she told him that if he were baptized, she would no longer consider him her son. With fewer than 300 members in Brazil, the Church did not have a single chapel there. I am truly astonished by my father’s determination and courage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.p9" pid="p2yTsl0qQkyPjOGCEEOgSQ" hash="115g8A">How could he make such a decision in the face of so many unfavorable circumstances? The answer is simple: it was because my father read the Book of Mormon. When he read it, he came to know of the truthfulness of the message of the Restoration. The Book of Mormon is a proof that The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is true. <span class="emphasis">Preach My Gospel</span> teaches that “the Book of Mormon, combined with the Spirit, is [the] most powerful resource in conversion” ([2004], 104).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.p10" pid="DO6UQbguTEGRS587XPKO9A" hash="fynmbA">President Gordon B. Hinckley declared: “Those who have read [the Book of Mormon] prayerfully, be they <span class="pageBreak" page-number="16"></span>rich or poor, learned or unlearned, have grown under its power. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.p11" pid="OTx7s1Ogik-hPFRc6I8s-g" hash="tEdqFQ">“… Without reservation I promise you that if you will prayerfully read the Book of Mormon, regardless of how many times you previously have read it, there will come into your hearts … the Spirit of the Lord. There will come a strengthened resolution to walk in obedience to his commandments, and there will come a stronger testimony of the living reality of the Son of God” (“The Power of the Book of Mormon,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> June 1988, 6; see also “The Book of Mormon,” <span class="emphasis">Tambuli,</span> Oct. 1988, 7).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.p12" pid="_XkEdPKsvEqy3yyoFk9QWw" hash="0Huv9w">These promises came true for my father and for my family. In accordance with what we have been taught, we read the scriptures as a family every day. We have done so for many years. We have read the Book of Mormon several times in our home, and we will continue to do so. As promised, the Spirit of the Lord has come into the heart of our family, and we have felt a strengthened resolution to walk in obedience to His commandments and a stronger testimony of the living reality of the Son of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.p13" pid="OS4cO6rxmEaB26lKS5Xlnw" hash="XY9fPQ">When you know that the Book of Mormon is true, you know that Joseph Smith was called by God to restore the Church of Jesus Christ to the earth. You know that Joseph Smith saw the Father and the Son. You know that there is only one faith and one valid baptism. You know that a prophet of God lives on the earth today and that he has all the keys of the priesthood and the right to exercise them, as Peter did anciently. You know that Jesus Christ is the Son of God, the only name whereby you can receive salvation. You know that God the Father lives and that He loves us. You know that His plan of salvation is perfect, and you have the desire to perform ordinances, live the commandments, and endure to the end.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.p14" pid="iFb19hli4E-nBpg1M2-o9A" hash="IomG1Q">I feel sad when someone who has been given the Book of Mormon and had these things explained to him still refuses to read it. I feel sad that some people allow themselves to be influenced by others, refuse to investigate the book, and set it aside as something without worth, never participating in the spiritual banquet it offers. To me, this is incomprehensible. It is as if a son or a daughter, separated from a loving father, refused to read a letter from him without even opening the envelope. Those who make such a choice are like spoiled children who refuse to even taste the meal tenderly prepared for them by their loving mother.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.f2">
	<p pid="HqJYnWAPY0ez4Dg_LngWpw" hash="ocHb1Q">God reveals His truth when people follow Moroni’s exhortation in Moroni 10:3–5. Preach My Gospel summarizes Moroni’s instructions as follows:</p>
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="73N7gKwYJEKK00GI20I5Iw" hash="-4K72A">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="g1U8XxiSFEqlWNtin2UkxA" hash="oiFyKQ">One, “read the Book of Mormon and ponder its message concerning Jesus Christ.”</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Kd-cznEZJUCiQjxx6FMDiw" hash="Pj7ocA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="3VydBaRflk-GicH6--O17g" hash="UQ2Gpg">Two, “pray to God with faith in Jesus Christ to receive a testimony that the Book of Mormon is true <span class="pageBreak" page-number="17"></span>and that Joseph Smith is the prophet of the Restoration.”</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="-4D2rY_9FESChYooTL0LCg" hash="QHgPbQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="JizRt6kGBE-NA1FD6n5pOA" hash="-SXtFA">Three, “pray sincerely and have real intent, which means that they intend to act on the answer they receive from God” (111).</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.p15" pid="RymMrQ_YZE2ufzgJ0qPBpw" hash="pKpe9A">To those who may argue that we cannot know these things, I testify that we can, when we are humble enough to do as God has instructed us through His prophets on this earth. To believe otherwise would be to accept the absurd notion that God also does not know where truth can be found or does not have the power to show it to us. Just because someone has not acted on the promise of this book does not mean that others have not done so.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.p16" pid="yT9w5Yziwka7GELh0fzn_w" hash="y_RaSw">Why do I love and honor the name of my father? Because my father read and acted on the promise of the Book of Mormon. Why do I love and honor the name of my father? Because he did not recoil from the answer he received, even while facing great challenges. Why do I love and honor the name of my father? Because he blessed my life, even before I was born, by having the courage to do what God expected him to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.p17" pid="5pbnhZxSaUqMNu4gkFbc3Q" hash="07PaQQ1">I invite all who hear me today to read the Book of Mormon and to apply the promise it contains. Those who do will know that the book is true.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon.p18" pid="IpkODlQUpkeTSfDMab2gvw" hash="HUUOkg">I bear my testimony that the Book of Mormon is the word of God. Because of this, I know that Joseph Smith is a prophet of God. I know that he did not write the Book of Mormon but translated it by the power of God. I know that Thomas S. Monson is a prophet of God on the earth today, the only man on the earth who holds all the keys of the priesthood and has the right to exercise them. I know that Jesus Christ is our Savior and that He lives. I know that God lives and loves us. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2008/10/because-my-father-read-the-book-of-mormon</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2008-general-conference/2008-10-1050-elder-marcos-a-aidukaitis-64k-eng.mp3" length="4871372" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If Ye Lack Wisdom</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Marcos A. Aidukaitis gives guidance for recognizing truth—observing its fruits, experimenting on the word of God, and seeking personal revelation.
		</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10985_000_56aidukaitis" doc-version="3" hash="Z0PLMQ">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="GIvoMndd_k-5QoHgkUHWmg" hash="Jj91JQ">If Ye Lack Wisdom</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p" pid="ufFYMlF87UmeHDZuLp6HbQ" hash="fF4ryQ">By Elder Marcos A. Aidukaitis</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p" pid="VE1IkKIs30-1iEucYG5SqA" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
		</div>
		<img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/leaders/marcos-a-aidukaitis.jpg" altText="Elder Marcos A. Aidukaitis" pid="r8_UvRe5bEKl8TJRxDzy_Q" hash="GF7MdQ" />
		<p class="kicker" pid="-tYfY9SyWEOLhCvBeqenkA" hash="YtSa_Q">God will reveal truth to those who seek for it as prescribed in the scriptures.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="dWgu-v5PHUmrfYohpHBYfQ" hash="fF4ryQ1">By Elder Marcos A. Aidukaitis</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p5" pid="wtJyu4B5K02SZ44ljM57Zw" hash="f9AXyA">The other day my 10-year-old son was studying about the human brain on the Internet. He wants to be a surgeon one day. It’s not difficult to note that he is a lot smarter than I am.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p6" pid="966Rf_q76kmLMnhLU8QC8g" hash="WRsCTQ">We like the Internet. At home we communicate with family and friends through social media, by email, and in other ways. My children do much of their schoolwork through the Internet.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p7" pid="Q11-7asrH0muMtJAHn1Dyw" hash="dINxQA">Whatever the question is, if we need more information, we search it online. In seconds we have a lot of material. This is marvelous.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p8" pid="5e3lH50GaEasuwIP7mLd9A" hash="QPfHFg">The Internet provides many opportunities for learning. However, Satan wants us to be miserable, and he distorts the real purpose of things. He uses this great tool to promote doubt and fear and to destroy faith and hope.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p9" pid="gB2537iRfkCHLRX0IQCb6w" hash="OfO8tA">With so much available on the Internet, we must carefully consider where to apply our efforts. Satan can keep us busy, distracted, and infected by sifting through information, much of which can be pure garbage.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p10" pid="uomXh0Bt0kmkFYM1Mts7Lg" hash="UKokFw">One should not roam through garbage.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p11" pid="C9mbXEvJTEunNKFQ1e-vcg" hash="8BRAHQ">Listen to this guidance, provided by the scriptures: “The Spirit of Christ is given to every man, that he may know good from evil; wherefore, I show unto you the way to judge; for every thing which inviteth to do good, and to persuade to believe in Christ, is sent forth by the power and gift of Christ; wherefore ye may know … it is of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p12" pid="7ZU790v5T0Sb_8J8luXaMQ" hash="1s_e2g">In a real sense, we face the same dilemma that Joseph Smith faced in his youth. We too often find ourselves lacking wisdom.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p13" pid="6x1bD6loGUWPLmljax1LUg" hash="s2OBqw">In the kingdom of God, the search for truth is appreciated, encouraged, and in no way repressed or feared. Church members are strongly counseled by the Lord Himself to seek for knowledge.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> He said, “Seek ye diligently … ; yea, seek ye out of the best books words of wisdom; seek learning, even by study and also by faith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> However, how can we recognize truth in a world that is increasingly blunt in its attacks on the things pertaining to God?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p14" pid="y7d4v5VxWU6N4Fvzv9vi9g" hash="scip9w">The scriptures teach us how:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p15" pid="xdMiFB62dEiBp-u7pnUGEA" hash="OF2iNQ">First, we can know the truth by observing its fruits.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p16" pid="pwECb_5wCEuo9oIbL3zWsw" hash="zbcCXQ">During His great Sermon on the Mount, the Lord said:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p17" pid="J2wFQWpDhU-HQwvR17USoQ" hash="hDTDpQ">“Even so every good tree bringeth forth good fruit; but a corrupt tree bringeth forth evil fruit. …</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p18" pid="-E7EGg6MtECOUxGXfvJo9A" hash="ajmeKA">“Wherefore by their fruits ye shall know them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p19" pid="f3vzC6zQFUSBO30qVap64g" hash="S2J18w">The prophet Mormon taught this same principle when he said, “By <span class="pageBreak" page-number="109"></span>their works ye shall know them; for if their works be good, then they are good also.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p20" pid="oO1lxQav3UauWk_Z0SG0Pg" hash="y9DwAA">We invite all to study the fruits and the works of this Church.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p21" pid="x6KaFfKcEk6GfpWiCJtoWQ" hash="RcjTJg">Those who are interested in the truth will be able to recognize the difference that the Church and its members make in the communities where they are established. They will also note the improvement in the lives of those who follow its teachings. Those who examine these fruits will discover that the fruits of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints are delicious and desirable.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p22" pid="Ms4O3zQqPUCAC-ddynd4uA" hash="GwLYsg">Second, we can find truth by experimenting on the word ourselves.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p23" pid="qeTF8ecI1UGJm85TyK40Hw" hash="2SYPxg">The prophet Alma taught:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p24" pid="59VGDUP-0EGKIEWrejFtSg" hash="lUQc5A">“We will compare the word unto a seed. … If ye give place, that a seed may be planted in your heart, behold, if it be a true seed, [and] … if ye do not cast it out by your unbelief, … behold, it will begin to swell within your breasts; and … ye will begin to say within yourselves—It must … be that this is a good seed, … for it beginneth to enlarge my soul; yea, it beginneth to enlighten my understanding, yea, it beginneth to be delicious to me. …</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p25" pid="7gfVXKf4B0-2ThQ0_sleog" hash="2HVbAQ">“… And now, … will not this strengthen your faith? Yea, it will strengthen your faith. …</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p26" pid="0C5PAf6YM0yKM0qOlKySag" hash="ux6s-w">“… For every seed bringeth forth unto its own likeness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p27" pid="4jVoSgEwdk2Jl52YWCNASQ" hash="pAZYOA">What a superb invitation by a prophet of the Lord! This could be compared to a scientific experiment. We are invited to test the word, we are given parameters, and we are told the outcome of the test if we follow the instructions.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p28" pid="hAGLBwBsJk-CW1IkRAHjXA" hash="tad4AA">Thus the scriptures teach us that we can know the truth by observing its fruits or by experimenting with it personally, giving place for the word in our hearts and cultivating it like unto a seed.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p29" pid="Rj1gF-f-bEuIqi4ud831oA" hash="lnTgCw">However, there is yet a third way to know the truth, and that is by personal revelation.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p30" pid="abms08RgeE6ZEbI8XyjIHw" hash="OVJAXg">
			<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/8" class="scriptureRef">Doctrine and Covenants section 8</a> teaches that revelation is knowledge—“knowledge of whatsoever things [we] ask in faith, with an honest heart, believing that [we] shall receive.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p31" pid="9hH0SJDPeUmwqivo6cWA3w" hash="aEJyUA">And the Lord tells us how we will receive this revelation. He says, “I will tell you in your mind and in your heart, by the Holy Ghost, which shall come upon you and which shall dwell in your heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p32" pid="kPSwZF_OJ0KIXBLuzRPxVw" hash="byFyOw">Thus we are taught that revelation can be obtained by asking in faith, <span class="pageBreak" page-number="110"></span>with an honest heart, and believing we will receive.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p33" pid="SWmOGEySpkawTlCMwamXcw" hash="BiwGhg">But notice that the Lord made it very clear when He warned, “Remember that without faith you can do nothing; therefore ask in faith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Faith requires work, such as studying it out in your mind, then asking in prayer if it is right.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p34" pid="16bzPmUMpUSaGNBgCFNquA" hash="COtYvQ">The Lord said:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p35" pid="HCXQPzvqoEqVtgvpn0cG3A" hash="9BwyGw">“If it is right I will cause that your bosom shall burn within you; therefore, you shall feel that it is right.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p36" pid="bqaMmB96_UiHgQpLelQojQ" hash="NjETFw">“But if it be not right you shall have no such feelings, but you shall have a stupor of thought that shall cause you to forget the thing which is wrong.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p37" pid="BhRW9AQQJEqe3bJi0vYMaQ" hash="wknWAw">Faith without works is dead.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> Thus, “ask in faith, nothing wavering.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p38" pid="bJefVyFwr0eyVvGfOyhXtA" hash="LM4oLw">I have a friend, not of our faith, who indicated to me that he is not a spiritual person. He will not study the scriptures or pray because he says he cannot understand the words of God, nor is he sure that God exists. This attitude explains his lack of spirituality and will lead to the opposite of revelation, as explained by Alma. He said, “And therefore, he that will harden his heart, the same receiveth the lesser portion of the word.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p39" pid="AZVV6Exlnk-dpG8-alhL4A" hash="9bvOGQ">But, Alma added, “he that will not harden his heart, to him is given the greater portion of the word, until it is given unto him to know the mysteries of God until he know them in full.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p40" pid="GXKTmbPe-kKwHAd_-BD3Xw" hash="LjQfeQ">Alma and the sons of Mosiah are examples of the principle that faith requires works. In the Book of Mormon we read:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p41" pid="w3aYi0sZDEekFTqUUG8eSg" hash="FVdYIw">“They had searched the scriptures diligently, that they might know the word of God.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p42" pid="GGZ7u_TRU0-EIj15AOpKgA" hash="7iA99w">“But this is not all; they had given themselves to much prayer, and fasting; therefore they had the spirit of prophecy, and the spirit of revelation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p43" pid="vqUxoeeU4k-ovtp-zf0mwA" hash="9SVTZQ">Asking with an honest heart is equally important in this process. If we are sincerely seeking the truth, we will do all in our power to find it, which can include reading the scriptures, going to church, and doing our best to keep the commandments of God. It also means that we are willing to do God’s will when we find it.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p44" pid="jtQZq1CvkkaBEZMT-RVNvg" hash="Pjxopw">Joseph Smith’s actions when he was seeking for wisdom are a perfect example of what it means to have an honest heart. He said he wanted to know which of the sects was true so “that [he] might know which to join.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> Even before he prayed, he was ready to act upon the answer he would receive.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p45" pid="JvY4ixaNx02DXlFDZc4jiA" hash="YKYiyg">We must ask in faith and with an honest heart. But that is not all. We must also believe that we will receive the revelation. We must trust the Lord and have hope in His promises. Remember what is written: “If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask of God, that giveth to all men liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> What a wonderful promise!</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p46" pid="6sr-51FvAEyyJYBi6QL_iQ" hash="GFe6VA">I invite all to seek truth from any of these methods but especially from God through personal revelation. God will reveal truth to those who seek for it as prescribed in the scriptures. It requires more effort than to just search the Internet, but it is worth it.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom.p47" pid="EFqoh--pRkme_iarL4n6VA" hash="GjhlTg">I bear my testimony that this is the true Church of Jesus Christ. I have seen its fruits in communities and in the lives of many thousands, including family members; thus I know it is true. I have also tried the word in my life for many years, and I have felt its effects on my soul; thus I know it is true. But most important, I have learned of its truthfulness for myself by revelation through the power of the Holy Ghost; thus I know it is true. I invite all of you to do the same. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/04/if-ye-lack-wisdom</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2014-general-conference/2014-04-5060-elder-marcos-a-aidukaitis-64k-eng.mp3" length="4938481" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
