<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Marcus B. Nash</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Marcus B. Nash.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Marcus%20B.%20Nash.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Marcus B. Nash.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2006 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Great Plan of Happiness</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Just like a fish needs water, you need the gospel and the companionship of the Holy Ghost to be truly, deeply happy.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006562_000_021" doc-version="2" hash="kqu2ug">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="4fHXisgDsUCTlkrayEEZBg" hash="LkdWvQ">The Great Plan of Happiness</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="FI6sjpFlv0OsxrG-EOQ-Nw" hash="JczggQ">Marcus B. Nash</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="LeZ9adGC7kmSyjbbL3IJaQ" hash="8jQ-tQ">Just like a fish needs water, you need the gospel and the companionship of the Holy Ghost to be truly, deeply happy.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/NashMB_06.jpg" alt="Elder Marcus B. Nash" pid="XywrYYUJKUCN-iUoWACYBA" hash="T_hK0w" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p1" pid="FTeHFCCoKk65_rd2JxGsrA" hash="v2FZcw">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="49"></span>When I was a deacon like many of you young men, my father and I hiked to a mountain stream to fish for trout. As my dad attached the bait to the hook on the end of my fishing line, he told me that I would need to set the hook in the fish’s mouth when it tried to take the bait, or it would get away. I did not understand what it meant to set the hook, so he explained to me that the hook needed to be embedded in the fish’s mouth when it struck at the bait so it could not shake the hook loose and that the hook would be set if I quickly pulled back on the pole when the fish tried to take the bait. Now, I really wanted to catch a fish, so I stood on the bank of that mountain stream like a coiled spring, every muscle taut, waiting for the telltale movement at the end of my pole which would signal that the fish was trying to take the bait. After a few minutes I noticed movement at the end of my pole, and in that instant I jerked back on the pole with all of my strength, expecting a big fight with the fish. To my surprise, I watched as that poor trout—with the hook now set very firmly in his mouth—was launched from the water into the air over my head and landed on the ground flopping behind me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p2" pid="Hp-AsKg70EaNijYdxZ3fMg" hash="oHF-vw">I have two observations from that experience: First, a fish out of water is miserable. Although its gills, fins, and tail work very well in water, they are all but useless on land. Second, the unfortunate fish I caught that day perished because it was deceived into treating something very dangerous—even fatal—as worthwhile or at least as sufficiently intriguing to warrant a closer look and perhaps a nibble.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p3" pid="l7qk69wF1kurbTntZ9WfVg" hash="EsSa9A">My dear brethren of the Aaronic Priesthood, there are a couple of lessons to be learned from this: First, a basic purpose of your life, as Lehi taught, is “[to] have joy” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.25" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 2:25</a>). In order to have joy, you need to understand that, as a child of your Heavenly Father, you inherited divine traits and spiritual needs—and just like a fish needs water, you need the gospel and the companionship of the Holy Ghost to be truly, deeply happy. Because you are the offspring of God (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/17.28" class="scriptureRef">Acts 17:28</a>), it is incompatible with your eternal nature to do wrong and feel right. It cannot be done. It is part of your spiritual DNA, as it were, that peace, joy, and happiness will be yours only to the degree you live the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p4" pid="GgT51POOakWvZAihjCEo9A" hash="h-LhRg">In contrast, to the degree that you choose not to live the gospel, you will be as miserable as a fish out of water (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.30" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:30</a>). As Alma stated to his son Corianton:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p5" pid="Yl_jz6KjG0ObnbNLwld_iQ" hash="9HrKxA">“Behold, I say unto you, wickedness never was happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p6" pid="416Ly9LFpUKK9Cmu2wQMqw" hash="UXBM8g">“And now, my son, all men that are … in a carnal state … are without God in the world, and they have gone contrary to the nature of God; therefore, they are in a state contrary to the nature of happiness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/41.10-11" class="scriptureRef">Alma 41:10–11</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p7" pid="iMFw5-cC3UW-aCo7WqWsVg" hash="R3RBtQ">Note that to be without God in the world—in other words, to refuse to live His gospel and therefore lack the companionship of the Spirit—is to be in a state contrary to the nature of happiness. The gospel of Jesus Christ is, in fact, <span class="emphasis">the</span>—note that this is singular, meaning it is <span class="emphasis">the only</span>—“great plan of happiness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/42.8" class="scriptureRef">Alma 42:8</a>). If you opt for any other way of life or try to live only the parts of the gospel that seem convenient, such a choice will cheat you of the full, resplendent joy and happiness for which you were designed by our loving Father in Heaven and His Son.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p8" pid="tMXcgTBbT0KHB0DthQOmqQ" hash="F8-FTA">Now to the second lesson from my fishing experience: just as a fish in a mountain stream must be careful of the lures placed in its path to avoid being pulled away from the water, so must you and I be wise in order to avoid being pulled away from a happy, gospel-centered life. Remember that, as Lehi observed, the devil “seeketh that all men might be miserable like unto himself” and obtains “power to captivate” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.27,29" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 2:27, 29</a>) us when we involve ourselves in unclean and <span class="pageBreak" page-number="50"></span>evil things. Thus, do not be deceived into even nibbling at unworthy things, for Satan stands ready to set the hook. It was the very real risk of the hook being set subtly or suddenly that led the ancient prophet Moroni—who actually saw our day (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/morm/8.35" class="scriptureRef">Mormon 8:35</a>)—to pointedly warn you and me to “<span class="emphasis">touch</span> not the evil gift, nor the unclean thing” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.30" class="scriptureRef">Moroni 10:30</a>; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p9" pid="uUp-U1g0yU-_vttEE6IEmQ" hash="wq2q8A">There is much that is evil and unclean in music, the Internet, movies, magazines, and in alcohol, drugs, and tobacco. As to any evil and unclean thing, my young friends, do not even touch it! Disguised in such things is a hook that sets subtly and much more suddenly than you dare think—and it can be an excruciatingly painful process to extract the hook. Alma described that for him the process of repentance was “nigh unto death” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/27.28" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 27:28</a>); indeed, he stated that “nothing [could be] so exquisite and so bitter as were my pains” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/36.21" class="scriptureRef">Alma 36:21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p10" pid="cmegsiKIKEy0audwKKGCYg" hash="8GW15w">There may be some of you who have been involved with that which is evil or unclean. Take hope in the doctrinal and historical fact that Alma’s faith in the Lord led him to repent, and as a direct result of his repentance he experienced such happiness through the power of the Atonement of Christ that, in his words, “there can be nothing so exquisite and sweet as was my joy” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/36.21" class="scriptureRef">Alma 36:21</a>). Such will be your experience as you seek the Lord through repentance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p11" pid="sdpyikdEkE245t81BNMX4Q" hash="G8VkTw">Each of us needs to repent to some degree or another. To repent means to make the real changes in your life the Savior desires you to make for your happiness. Repentance is the great enabling principle of the gospel: when your faith in the Lord causes personal change, such action on your part, as Helaman states, “bringeth [you] unto the power of the Redeemer, unto the salvation of [your] souls” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/5.11" class="scriptureRef">Helaman 5:11</a>). As you seek to change, remember that our loving Savior, as Alma states, has “all power to save every man that believeth on his name and bringeth forth fruit meet for repentance” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/12.15" class="scriptureRef">Alma 12:15</a>). This is powerful, liberating, hope-filled doctrine!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p12" pid="1bpzulNr3UGUItldi3Or0A" hash="PjiNag">The Prophet Joseph Smith learned from firsthand experience that the Lord expects us to avoid misery by living His gospel and wants us to understand that we can repent. When he lost the 116 pages of the manuscript of the Book of Mormon translation by giving in to the persuasions of men, Joseph was miserable. The Lord told him: “You should have been faithful; and [God] would have extended his arm and supported you against all the fiery darts of the adversary; and he would have been with you in every time of trouble” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/3.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 3:8</a>). Such is the case for each of you young men: be faithful, and you will be supported by the hand of God. The Prophet was then reminded that—as with each of us—he would be forgiven if he repented. Imagine what joy he felt when he heard the Lord state, “But remember, God is merciful; therefore, repent of that which thou hast done which is contrary to the commandment which I gave you, and thou art still chosen” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/3.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 3:10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p13" pid="fRVgooldrEyY_eRV3oHoBg" hash="u99B0Q">My invitation to each of you tonight is to live the gospel to be truly happy, avoid evil and the misery it brings, and if you have become involved with the evil or unclean thing, make the changes the Lord desires of you for your own happiness—and I witness that He will enable you to succeed through His matchless power.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness.p14" pid="VRKlg0ErkUyj0W6A6fkdOA" hash="bH9fMg">As you accept this invitation, you will reap lasting happiness and build the foundation of your life upon “the rock of our Redeemer,” such that when the shafts of the evil one and the storms of the world assail you, they will, as Helaman taught, have “no power over you to drag you down to the gulf of misery and endless wo, because of the rock upon which ye are built, which is a sure foundation, <span class="emphasis">a foundation whereon if men build they cannot fall</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/5.12" class="scriptureRef">Helaman 5:12</a>; emphasis added). Of the Lord Jesus Christ I bear my ardent witness: He is the Rock, the one sure foundation for happiness and healing. He lives, has all power in heaven and earth, knows your name, and He loves you. In the sacred name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/10/the-great-plan-of-happiness</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2006-general-conference/2006-10-3030-elder-marcus-b-nash-64k-eng.mp3" length="4445529" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2006 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>By Faith All Things Are Fulfilled</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2012/10/by-faith-all-things-are-fulfilled?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Faith will help us to safely climb the gospel path, overcome every challenge of mortality, and return to the majestic presence of our Heavenly Father.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/by-faith-all-things-are-fulfilled" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10491_000_54nash" doc-version="2" hash="msAOsg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/by-faith-all-things-are-fulfilled.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="F_Ufis4VHEaC4HohE6FBQw" hash="LTyO8Q">By Faith All Things Are Fulfilled</h1><p class="authorName" pid="wfKHk_5ksEyssZe69P2egQ" hash="miOZFw">By Elder Marcus B. Nash</p><p class="kicker" pid="aTQrH4I4xEeFO5bddNB2-w" hash="SdWYKQ">Faith will help us to safely climb the gospel path, overcome every challenge of mortality, and return to the majestic presence of our Heavenly Father.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" pid="Ov0VKhOpPE-i-eg43aQqTA" hash="1sT6MQ">
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/by-faith-all-things-are-fulfilled.p5" pid="IBJl4bVz9U2tTsHlsFdOZg" hash="H8h4_Q">
      <span class="pageBreak" page-number="99"></span>Not long ago several of us in the Nash family hiked to the top of Huayna Picchu, a tall peak adjoining the ancient Incan ruins of Machu Picchu in the mountains of Peru. It is a very steep climb with breathtaking views and precipitous drop-offs. Sadly, some hikers have lost their lives by falling off that narrow, steep trail. To avoid such tragedies, strong cables have since been secured to the solid rock along the mountainside of Huayna Picchu. We held to those cables as we climbed, and they enabled us to safely reach the summit, where the view was majestic!</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/by-faith-all-things-are-fulfilled.p6" pid="F7cd5BVVHES6nQuLFyxHGw" hash="lFEutQ">Like the path on Huayna Picchu, our mortal journey is a steep and difficult climb, one that requires our Heavenly Father’s help to successfully complete. For this reason, He established the principles and ordinances of the gospel to bring us unto the Savior and His saving power.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> The first of those principles, faith in the Lord Jesus Christ,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> is like the cables on Huayna Picchu: if strong and securely attached to “the rock of our Redeemer,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> faith will help us to safely climb the gospel path, overcome every challenge of mortality,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> and return to the majestic presence of our Heavenly Father. All things are fulfilled by faith.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/by-faith-all-things-are-fulfilled.p7" pid="XcczPLImgU-Gh1i_Z4jW9w" hash="GT-EZQ">Faith is both a principle of action and of power.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> It “is not to have a perfect knowledge of things; therefore if [we] have faith [we] hope for things which are not seen, which are true.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> It is an assurance<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> of the Spirit gained through our learning that moves us to act<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> to follow the example of the Savior and prayerfully keep His commandments, even through times of sacrifice and trial.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Faith brings us the power of the Lord, which—among other things—is manifested by a hope of good things to come,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> miracles that confirm our faith,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> and divine protection in spiritual and temporal matters.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/by-faith-all-things-are-fulfilled.p8" pid="c6CRcK0720q7wOoAOY5qaA" hash="FFHvPA">The life of Ann Rowley, a pioneer woman in the early days of the Church, demonstrates how exercising faith impacts our lives for good. A widow from England, Sister Rowley exercised her faith to answer the prophet’s call to gather to Zion. She was a member of the Willie handcart company, which encountered deep snowdrifts along the trail in the fall of 1856. They had reached a point in the trek where her seven children were literally starving. She wrote: “It hurt me to see my children go hungry. … Night was coming and there was no food for the evening meal. I asked God’s help as I always did. I got on my knees, remembering two hard sea biscuits that … had been left over from the sea voyage. They were not large, and were so hard they couldn’t be broken. Surely, that was not enough to feed 8 people, but 5 loaves and 2 fishes were not enough to feed 5,000 people either, but through a miracle, Jesus had done it. So, with God’s help, nothing is impossible. I found the biscuits and put them in a dutch oven and covered them with water and asked for God’s blessing. Then I put the lid on the pan and set it on the coals. When I took off the lid a little later, I found the pan filled with food. I kneeled with my family and thanked God for his goodness. That night my family had sufficient food.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
    </span>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/by-faith-all-things-are-fulfilled.p9" pid="5aQWd2Tty0GMLL2kP94P7w" hash="c_0x9Q">Ann Rowley was living the gospel at great personal sacrifice. She needed help and asked for it in prayer. Because of her faith, she was filled with hope and miraculously provided with food for her family. The Lord also blessed her with the eternally significant ability to “endure in faith to the end.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> Despite an uncertain future, she did not demand to know how she was going to feed her children the next day; instead, she patiently “wait[ed] upon the Lord”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> and pressed forward with hope—just as the beautiful hymn expresses:</p>
    <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/by-faith-all-things-are-fulfilled.f1">
      <div class="stanza">
        <p class="line" pid="Yqdv_bPqakaJwTqPmlsuOA" hash="65Chug">Lead, kindly Light, amid th’ encircling gloom; Lead thou me on!</p>
        <p class="line" pid="Xc1XpiNSvUemidxu4greFw" hash="-4csgw">The night is dark, and I am far from home; Lead thou me on!</p>
        <p class="line" pid="RLXIs652LUep7D8Y-dCCjA" hash="T85wng">Keep thou my feet; I do not ask to see</p>
        <p class="line" pid="QzxBrLJYR0Seu904-PonHA" hash="Lqccdg">The distant scene—one step enough for me.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
      </div>
    </div>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/by-faith-all-things-are-fulfilled.p14" pid="XBcUiDE9J0epkLEUUCu0QA" hash="9HPVgA">
      <span class="pageBreak" page-number="100"></span>We too can exercise such faith in the Lord, believing and trusting that our kind and constant God<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> will bless us with His miraculous power suited to our circumstance, according to His timing. As we do so, we too will see the hand of God manifest in our lives.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/by-faith-all-things-are-fulfilled.p15" pid="eEfgjDXzIEOmg-UK-hMgNg" hash="niWFQw">The Lord commands us to take “the shield of faith wherewith ye shall be able to quench <span class="emphasis">all</span> the fiery darts of the wicked.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> Satan will use such things as doubt, fear, or sin to tempt us to let go of faith and lose the protection it offers. Let us briefly examine each of these challenges to faith in turn so that we can recognize and heed not the adversary’s temptations.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/by-faith-all-things-are-fulfilled.p16" pid="X-DvPjXSNUCEaTiTaHDasA" hash="6MUj-w">First, unbelief in the Lord or His gospel will cause us to resist the Spirit of God.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> The Lord’s antidote for doubt is simple. As King Benjamin declared, “Believe in God; believe that he is, and that he created all things, both in heaven and in earth; believe that he has all wisdom, and all power, both in heaven and in earth; believe that man doth not comprehend all the things which the Lord can comprehend.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/by-faith-all-things-are-fulfilled.p17" pid="fehOJUg4g0qTn10kizUbzw" hash="5cj5rA">If, because of unbelief or doubt, you find your faith wavering, remember that even the ancient Apostles implored the Lord to “increase our faith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> Bearing in mind that faith and reason are necessary companions, consider the following analogy: faith and reason are like the two wings of an aircraft. Both are essential to maintain flight. If, from your perspective, reason seems to contradict faith, pause and remember that our perspective is extremely limited compared with the Lord’s.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span> Do not discard faith any more than you would detach a wing from an aircraft in flight. Instead, nurture a particle of faith and permit the hope it produces to be an anchor to your soul—and to your reason.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span> That is why we are commanded to “seek learning … by study <span class="emphasis">and also</span> by faith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_26">26</span> Remember, faith precedes and produces miracles for which we have no immediate explanation within our experience, such as a Dutch oven full of food from two small biscuits or simply enduring in faith against all odds.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_27">27</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/by-faith-all-things-are-fulfilled.p18" pid="NI46E1cP1Uqt2X5EENzDNQ" hash="Uwhwig">Second, fear distracts from and undermines faith in the Savior. The Apostle Peter looked to the Lord one stormy night and walked on water—until he averted his gaze and “saw the wind boisterous [and] was afraid” and then sank into the stormy sea.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_28">28</span> He could have continued walking if he had not feared! Rather than our focusing upon and fearing the boisterous wind and waves in our lives, the Lord invites us to “look unto me in every thought; doubt not, fear not.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_29">29</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/by-faith-all-things-are-fulfilled.p19" pid="WmQs0yccNU2AGvuLstD1Qw" hash="xxeImw">Third, sin diminishes the presence of the Spirit in our lives, and without the Holy Ghost, we will lack the spiritual stamina to hold onto and exercise faith. It is best to exercise our faith to “touch not the evil gift, nor the unclean thing”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_30">30</span> and to “be diligent in keeping all [the] commandments, lest … your faith fail you, and your enemies triumph over you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_31">31</span> If sin has stained your life, I invite you to exercise “faith unto repentance,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_32">32</span> and the Savior, through the Atonement, will purify and heal your life.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/by-faith-all-things-are-fulfilled.p20" pid="gsrkNub8h0O0oHzJDMpnnA" hash="hWe_xw">Brothers and sisters, the Lord will, according to our faith, fulfill His promises and work with us to overcome every challenge.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_33">33</span> He did so for Ann Rowley and has done so for His people in all nations and in every age and generation. Because He is a “God of miracles” and “changeth not,” He will likewise bless each of us with hope, protection, and power according to our faith in Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_34">34</span> Steadfast faith in the Lord Jesus Christ will—like the cables on the path of Huayna Picchu—anchor you and your loved ones to “the rock of our Redeemer”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_35">35</span> and His matchless power to save.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/by-faith-all-things-are-fulfilled.p21" pid="_RGuHdqVs06Y47zF43bC1w" hash="8IAd8w">President Thomas S. Monson has stated, “The future is as bright as your faith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_36">36</span> I testify of that sublime, hopeful truth and invite each of us to <span class="pageBreak" page-number="101"></span>steadfastly press forward with faith in the Lord, “nothing wavering.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_37">37</span> I know that the Savior lives, is “the author and the finisher of [our] faith,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_38">38</span> and the “rewarder of them that diligently seek him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_39">39</span> I so testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2012/10/by-faith-all-things-are-fulfilled</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2012-general-conference/2012-10-5040-elder-marcus-b-nash-64k-eng.mp3" length="5240687" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
