<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Margaret D. Nadauld</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Margaret D. Nadauld.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Margaret%20D.%20Nadauld.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Margaret D. Nadauld.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Mar 1998 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 1998 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Turning Hearts to the Family</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Heavenly Father has a plan for His children and … families are the central part of that plan.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_98905_000_038" doc-version="2" hash="w0vmrg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ZJWtQ5bobUyYFgRM1E2juA" hash="NJ21qA">Turning Hearts to the Family</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Jqs0UCSjaUetFlnuTjCPrw" hash="zJRadA">Margaret D. Nadauld</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="qWpwPmSwhEmo6yySN_6NSA" hash="pQy7jw">Heavenly Father has a plan for His children and … families are the central part of that plan.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1d58.jpg" alt="Margaret D. Nadauld" pid="oS8M0P8dBEum0rNidDD5lQ" hash="yJI00g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p1" pid="-hKM4UfR20qD8pfutqE4PA" hash="F6BlNg">All over the world, from Asia to Africa, from New Zealand to Norway, the wonderful young women of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints are turning hearts to the family. It’s a worldwide celebration of families this whole year. We know that families are a vital part of Heavenly Father’s plan for His children. This is explained in the document “The Family: A Proclamation to the World.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p2" pid="DH4YKo8xBkm5Ym3EC5CR1A" hash="lWkcEw">I remember so well when that proclamation was presented. It was very impressive to me. On September 23, 1995, the women of the Church were gathered in a great general Relief Society meeting. Our prophet, President Gordon B. Hinckley, stood to speak to us. As part of his talk, he read for the first time a document called “The Family: A Proclamation to the World.” In this proclamation we are taught again, by the First Presidency and the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles, that Heavenly Father has a plan for His children and that families are the central part of that plan. It is vital, then, that we strengthen these families which are so very important in the sight of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p3" pid="kAiMEPQn0U6NiVc866-zQQ" hash="rqgjYw">You young women have an important role to play in at least three families. The first is the family you are part of now, the second is your future family, and the third is the heavenly family of which we are all part. Let us consider our place in each of these three families.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p4" pid="u1Mh9uuPqU2c0OZhIsCPLg" hash="jmCSRQ">First, let’s consider the family you are growing up in now. When I think about the family I grew up in, I remember how my little sister and I shared the bedroom and the piano and washing dishes. I remember getting the giggles with my brother at suppertime, and we laughed so hard we had to be sent away from the table until we quit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p5" pid="NQqvjsDE4EGt5HMr3A3SEQ" hash="YiysMg">Oh, you learn a lot of things in a family, don’t you? And they’re important things—things like praying and sharing and laughing and loving and working and getting along with others. How thankful I am for all the important lessons of life that I learned in my family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p6" pid="VjVnISMi802P6hmT0eo3ew" hash="3v28BQ">Many of you young women have written and shared with us your family experiences and some of the things you are learning as you have turned your hearts to your families. Twelve-year-old Katie Quinn wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p7" pid="nJpMol2gf0CLFFm4NIFJmw" hash="EwML3Q">“My mother was expecting a baby. … She was bedridden much of the time … and all of a sudden there was a ton of responsibility on my shoulders because I am the oldest. I was also just starting middle school and had loads of homework.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p8" pid="DR-4JQsXikWpoWZYVT16Xw" hash="JXSFgQ">“I knew I needed to help a lot, and I even prayed to know what I should do. I felt an answer came when my grandmother, who was staying with us for a few weeks, told me a story about one of my ancestors who at age 11 had driven a covered wagon by himself across the plains to the Salt Lake Valley. His parents had died along the way, and he was left to care for four younger sisters, including a baby, and take them to Zion. This story made me realize that I could be like my great-great-great-grandfather and push forward.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p9" pid="-RulZ2S7v0qQuq7Sv-q5UQ" hash="K1jO4w">“I decided it would help my family if I made sack lunches for my sisters or do other duties like folding clothing and ironing and other extra chores.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p10" pid="ns52MaNNQUufnvIJrVtsbw" hash="-0oeDA">“I gathered my younger sisters and brother every morning before school and carried on our family scripture reading, even though my father had left earlier for work and my mother was too sick to lead us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p11" pid="VcEea7fhEkaCZ8DH8Yv77g" hash="NSKizw">“My family … grew closer together because [we] had to help each other. The greatest blessing happened on May 1, 1997, when Hannah Ada Quinn was born” (personal letter in author’s possession).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p12" pid="z9RcJ2i9kUaYxKeRVVdPUQ" hash="bZMlSw">Thank you for the letter, Katie.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p13" pid="-pM2scl1uEah5ksOJCCJmQ" hash="_sd57Q">She learned about determination and courage and loyalty to family from her third great-grandfather who lived so long ago, and then she used those qualities as she helped her family who needed her. Many of you are doing similar things to bless and strengthen your families.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p14" pid="V1K0bcsW_kG3hhnxXRzPOg" hash="93KHyQ">Do you realize that Katie and you are preparing for your future family by learning and practicing on your parents and brothers and sisters?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p15" pid="e5kg4EGLoUicWisBI7ycow" hash="Mt7Obw">May I ask you to think now for a moment about your future family. Can you imagine yourself as a mother? Close your eyes. Picture yourself in 10 years. What will you be doing? Will you be getting an education or learning a useful skill? What will you be like? Open your eyes. In your mind’s eye, do you see yourself as nurturers of precious sons and daughters of Heavenly Father? You can practice now by being loving and gentle to little children and by saying the kindest things in the kindest way in your home. Do you picture yourself as a mother who could help her children with learning math or science or history? If so, guess what you’d better do at school! Do you want to have beauty and music and refinement in your home? Today you can begin developing your artistic and musical talents for the sake of your future home and family. Do you want to have peace and order in your home? Then, my dear young sisters, be the peacemaker, help keep your home clean and orderly, help with the laundry. Can you imagine your future family sitting around a table laughing and sharing ideas and enjoying the delicious, nutritious food that you prepared with love? Then it looks like you’ll have to learn to cook! Help prepare the meals. Collect recipes from your mother and grandmother. Learn how to make strudel or poi or tortillas—your family favorites, whatever they are.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p16" pid="jD8JccucuEOJ2ISKtwqCBA" hash="EmcAZQ">Let me tell you what I see in you. I see in you young women who are getting an education and are preparing to bless others through it. Please, for yourself and your future family, choose a fine education. Be qualified. Be well rounded. Work hard. In you young women, I see girls who look forward to establishing a home of love, a home of order, a home of faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p17" pid="zrMN0xQr-E2bpr7fzh1UOQ" hash="WGhtlQ">I see young women who understand that the things you do today will make you the kind of strong, faithful woman that the Lord needs to bless His children. You want to teach your family of Heavenly Father and His ways, and you know how and where to go for that preparation, don’t you? Scripture study, Church meetings, prayer, seminary, family home evening.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p18" pid="k6sYFgY0vkiBgl04sLz7qA" hash="4UkIgA">In preparation for your future, may I invite you to do something when you get home tonight? Would you please go to your journal and write in it all about the kind of woman you would like to become? And then will you work toward making that dream of your future become a reality in your life? In this way you will be turning your heart to the family you will one day have.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p19" pid="IMrNGb1Ir06FNyWo0IQ30Q" hash="FNoqYg">Now, let us consider your part in Heavenly Father’s family. You are a remarkable, precious daughter of Heavenly Father who loves you. You were chosen before this world was to come forth to do some very unusual and wonderful things! Listen to this scripture from the Doctrine and Covenants, section 138, verse 56: “Even before they were born, they, with many others, received their first lessons in the world of spirits and were prepared to come forth in the due time of the Lord to labor in his vineyard for the salvation of the souls of men.” Did you know that? Our Heavenly Father sent us here to earth for a purpose.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p20" pid="2PIgkEVxfUKGMoVuKIkIYA" hash="Afil0A">It is a divine and priceless blessing to be born a woman. Your Heavenly Father blessed you, His daughters, with some very precious qualities in extra capacity—qualities such as sensitivity, spirituality, a loving, nurturing nature. Please take opportunities to develop these divine gifts and then use them to bless others. Be happy. Scatter a little sunshine. You could observe faithful women you admire and then adopt into your own life the qualities that make these women successful, happy daughters of God. He will help you do that because He wants you to be the best you can be.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p21" pid="h6mO2vZc60a0HYvA3G_KkQ" hash="uQ0zaw">Because we were sent here to earth to be tested and to prove ourselves, there may be some things in life that won’t turn out exactly as we have planned. That’s the way with earthly life. But remember this: when you work hard and prepare yourself to make contributions and keep covenants you make at baptism and in the temple, you can meet any of the challenges of life with faith and hope and courage! As part of His plan, Heavenly Father provided a Savior who will help us in this life, and He will help us return back home to Him. He said, “This is my work and my glory—to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>). He loves you. He wants you to be successful. And He will help you succeed in your life’s mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family.p22" pid="_edVF_CwZ0en2mE7M7ce-g" hash="uPEpLA">As I began talking to you tonight, I was remembering the family I grew up in. In closing, let me tell you something else I remember about that family. When I was only nine years old, our one-day-old baby brother died. We were so sad and disappointed and crying so hard. And do you know what our father did? He gathered us together, and we knelt in family prayer. He thanked Heavenly Father for this little baby that we’d had such a short time, and then he asked the Lord to bless this little baby, David, who was now in heaven. Daddy asked Heavenly Father to bless our mom, who was very sick. Mother regained her health, and we’ve all tried to live so that we can be reunited as a family with David one day. I always pray for David. He will always be my brother. We are an eternal family because our parents were married in the temple. You can give your children that same gift, the blessing of belonging to an eternal family. It is the most priceless gift you could ever provide for them. Plan to do it. Prepare to do it. Live worthy of it. May He bless you to do so, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1998/04/turning-hearts-to-the-family</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/1998-general-young-women-meeting/1998-03-0010-margaret-d-nadauld-64k-eng.mp3" length="12371706" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 1998 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Come unto Christ</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We want to come unto Christ because it is only in Him and through Him that we can return to the Father.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_98905_000_027" doc-version="2" hash="xy-cGg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="k9CyoKdOnEC9hnxG52zDLQ" hash="lpCr0A">Come unto Christ</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="bvQlsNic20WCWzxRZKyvAQ" hash="zJRadA">Margaret D. Nadauld</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="s1eacNMQn0qGJF3WsqzqJw" hash="qebVpw">We want to come unto Christ because it is only in Him and through Him that we can return to the Father.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1d58.jpg" alt="Margaret D. Nadauld" pid="IPusaL-uGE6z-3x3jzLZeg" hash="yJI00g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ.p1" pid="b9pg46Wdak-w0hXcUAYqgg" hash="6m3CTg">As this Easter season approaches, and always, we rejoice in the most meaningful invitation ever extended to mankind. It is the invitation to come unto Christ. And we’re all invited. The scriptures are replete with that glorious invitation, which is beautifully summarized in the hymn:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="6OnUKv7xhE-N0pWW4yDEiw" hash="MKk3qw">
            <span class="emphasis">Come unto Jesus from ev’ry nation,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Q4fo7KzD50-RMcI4f1gFkA" hash="itI5pA">
            <span class="emphasis">From ev’ry land and isle of the sea.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="lHDOoGz7b0CaAIPFmzrL2g" hash="KZIMPg">
            <span class="emphasis">Unto the high and lowly in station,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="XeWSEUteTkaSxOq41tn4yA" hash="6GdT9g">
            <span class="emphasis">Ever he calls, “Come to me.”</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ.p2" pid="1eg8VxhxjUywCnwAfoHpkg" hash="Icb4MA">The Savior extends His generous invitation simply because He loves us and He knows we need Him. He can help us and heal us. He understands us because of His own experiences. The scriptures report: “And he shall go forth, suffering pains and afflictions and temptations of every kind … , that he may know … how to succor his people according to their infirmities” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/7.11-12" class="scriptureRef">Alma 7:11–12</a>). We want to come unto Christ because it is only in Him and through Him that we can return to the Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ.p3" pid="FJuwcPsqtk2fCNBJjaEfsw" hash="108vTQ">A simple thing happened many years ago that I have always remembered because it caused me to think about the Savior’s mission. Although it was just a childish incident, it has some meaning. It happened when our twins were only about five years old. They were just learning to ride their bicycles. As I glanced out the window, I saw them speeding down the street on their bikes going very fast! Perhaps they were going a little too fast for their level of ability, because all of a sudden Adam had a terrible crash! He was tangled up in the wreck, and all I could see was a twist of handlebars and tires and arms and legs. His little twin brother, Aaron, saw the whole thing happen, and immediately he skidded to a stop and jumped off his bike. He threw it down and ran to the aid of his brother, whom he loved very much. These little twins truly were of one heart. If one hurt, so did the other. If one got tickled, they both laughed. If one started a sentence, the other could complete it. What one felt, the other did also. So it was painful for Aaron to see Adam crash! Adam was a mess. He had skinned knees, he was bleeding from a head wound, his pride was damaged, and he was crying. In a fairly gentle, five-year-old way, Aaron helped his brother get untangled from the crash, he checked out the wounds, and then he did the dearest thing. He picked his brother up and carried him home. Or tried to. This wasn’t very easy because they were the same size, but he tried. And as he struggled and lifted and half-dragged, half-carried his brother along, they finally reached the front porch. By this time, Adam, the injured one, was no longer crying, but Aaron, the rescuer, was. When asked, “Why are you crying, Aaron?” he said simply, “Because Adam hurts.” And so he had brought him home to help, home to someone who knew what to do, to someone who could cleanse the wounds, bind them up, and make it better—home to love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ.p4" pid="wPYP00XfQUS8dE3UDtB04g" hash="prMKcA">Just as one twin helped his brother in need, so might we all be lifted, helped, even carried at times by our beloved Savior, the Lord Jesus Christ. He feels what we feel; He knows our heart. It was His mission to wipe away our tears, cleanse our wounds, and bless us with His healing power. He can carry us home to our Heavenly Father with the strength of His matchless love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ.p5" pid="vsZYI9N3zke3D11QStkilw" hash="vzGeoQ">Surely it pleases the Lord when we, His children, reach out to one another, to give help along the way, and to bring another closer to Christ. He taught, “[When] ye have done it unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.40" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:40</a>). He wants us to “mourn with those that mourn[,] … comfort those that stand in need of comfort” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:9</a>), and “by love serve one another” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/gal/5.13" class="scriptureRef">Gal. 5:13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ.p6" pid="6EwZsmQ9nUCrza48k_qLQg" hash="AY-Y0w">The words of Susan Evans McCloud say it well:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ.f3">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="kIwg7z5Hp0G-Rk9PjfTE8A" hash="Fb3xpA">
            <span class="emphasis">Savior, may I learn to love thee,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="-_X-lvNLTkibCPH4O9GHFQ" hash="NIoTLg">
            <span class="emphasis">Walk the path that thou hast shown,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="OFuMnP3BSk-Tw6Z8bhWt6w" hash="89WDOw">
            <span class="emphasis">Pause to help and lift another,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="wCAFkRrnokasEROeHdbgcQ" hash="eBBv0g">
            <span class="emphasis">Finding strength beyond my own. … </span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="9Td5DKHMy0OMJCLHK2SsYg" hash="oFdsaw">
            <span class="emphasis">I would be my brother’s keeper;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="L7Xf5xqFh0qrzlNbzeFH0w" hash="ohfRdw">
            <span class="emphasis">I would learn the healer’s art.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="vRdD0_lDDkOxtoc76uNddg" hash="nWSl9g">
            <span class="emphasis">To the wounded and the weary</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="mamWvyl3gU-Xage3EOu2Vg" hash="_sON8A">
            <span class="emphasis">I would show a gentle heart. …</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="uu8557Ael0CiVrutdqNkrw" hash="QPYV8A">
            <span class="emphasis">Savior, may I love my brother</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="SiUtw9kBYE2uvIjo3znLwA" hash="OdxVfA">
            <span class="emphasis">As I know thou lovest me,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="jOmqoimnPkmMVcE-5CBK8Q" hash="jdWzcQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Find in thee my strength, my beacon,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="iPSTDzTIMUu0kwknuimQBg" hash="Rr0SMQ">
            <span class="emphasis">For thy servant I would be.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ.p7" pid="xU0Ezy0VHUSFgWqDnsn21A" hash="v-Ex_g">Dear brothers and sisters, these lines express the humble desires of my heart as I joyfully embark on an errand from Heavenly Father to walk with the young women of His Church. I pray constantly that in the Lord will be found strength, a beacon, for this willing servant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ.p8" pid="1NvqvjT9i0WH6cCL6AL89Q" hash="fSkg5A">It is the mission of Young Women, and it is our greatest desire, to help young women grow spiritually and to assist their families in preparing them to come unto Christ. Many, many of them are well on their way. For example, when we asked some young women what they liked about sacrament meeting, one said, “The sacrament, because it reminds me of Jesus and all He did for me.” Another said, “I never come away with an empty heart, and I love taking the sacrament.” When asked how often they prayed, many said, “Morning and night.” They pray before a test. They pray in the face of temptation. They read the scriptures. Along with their own personal preparation, these beautiful young women are found blessing lives of others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ.p9" pid="WQ7SVwrUV0W3M2ja6ySFcg" hash="1z1G7w">May I share a letter from a grateful recipient of their loving service. He writes:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ.p10" pid="eTL8ST3CnESxOycS6AKg-g" hash="uCZWNw">“The young women [of my ward] very literally saved my life. I was a young bishop, just 29, the father of four beautiful little girls, including a small baby, when Heavenly Father called my wife home to Him. As I met with each of our little girls and asked them what impact this change would mean to them, the concerns of six-year-old Emily, the oldest of the four, were many, including, ‘Who is going to comb and curl my hair for church and put ribbons and clips in it?’ That was a good question to me as well. Who? I was consumed with the idea that life would be as ‘normal’ as possible for all of us—which meant that I would have to learn a whole new way of life. I was their father, and I was going to be <span class="emphasis">the</span> only parent. I realized that I was not equipped with the motherly skills that I needed. I called upon the young women of the ward to train me to be able to satisfy at least the needs of hair care. They came to my home, numerous times, to begin my training. They even showed me how to care for my six-month-old Natalie as far as washing her hair without so much trauma. By the time I ‘graduated,’ I could whip up a mean (but simple) hairdo. Much more than the skill—those young women gave me confidence as a father of daughters—that I could love them, care for them, be there for them, no matter how the rest of my life continued.” Thank you, Brother Michael Marston, for your tender letter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ.p11" pid="vIEAGnQTVEqJ1jP8oPRg1g" hash="4-o1oA">I pray that parents of precious young women all over the world will be ever thankful for the stewardship they have to guide their daughters with love. May leaders of these young women understand the everlasting importance of their assignment. And may each young woman understand how blessed she is to be a daughter of Heavenly Father, who loves her very much and wants her to be successful!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ.p12" pid="hjTD-DYU7UKj3VbgQOD2hQ" hash="4Bi7gA">In closing today, may I express my gratitude. First of all, gratitude for the home of my youth, which was filled with the kind of love Christ taught about; gratitude for the privilege of walking by the side of my dear husband, Stephen, where I have been blessed and prepared and sustained; and gratitude for precious children whose lives of constant, tender support inspire us, give us great joy, and often show us the way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ.p13" pid="9fw5ahwlRky5M3EP1FNl0A" hash="QVc3Tg">I bear testimony that as we accept the invitation to come unto Christ, we will find that He can heal all wounds. He can lift our burdens and carry them for us, and we can feel “encircled about eternally in the arms of his love” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/1.15" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 1:15</a>). In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1998/04/come-unto-christ</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1998-general-conference/1998-04-4040-margaret-d-nadauld-64k-eng.mp3" length="5177221" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 1998 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Light</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Lord invites us to come out of the cold danger of worldliness and into the warmth of His light.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_99260_000_040" doc-version="2" hash="gctcqQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ZRgmaqVbXUG7pnulT-iH7A" hash="IjmQeA">Follow the Light</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="n2UfQv9XXEGVNJZkMPIcBQ" hash="zJRadA">Margaret D. Nadauld</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="8PH7dl3li0KKxMewcGmH9Q" hash="56NV-w">The Lord invites us to come out of the cold danger of worldliness and into the warmth of His light.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-ee5.jpg" alt="Margaret D. Nadauld" pid="72rk2mR64UeM76k4jVEFhQ" hash="5iwElw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p1" pid="g2kUQdKU3UODDB7i6NG9Vg" hash="KoSQKw">Have you ever stumbled around in the dark and stubbed your toe and said, “Ouch, that hurts!”? What if the lights went out in this building tonight? We would have mass confusion! Darkness can be hazardous to our health—our physical and our spiritual health! It is a great blessing to have light in our lives—a light that helps us see things as they really are, light that illuminates our understanding, light we can follow with confidence and perfect trust. Let me share with you a story to illustrate what I mean.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p2" pid="BBl-u2MMdEiYi-FpCLo-rQ" hash="7ohYAg">It was just a few days before Christmas, and we were newlyweds traveling home for the holidays. It was a 42-hour drive by car, but that didn’t discourage us at all because we were so excited to be home with our families again! We had been on the road all day and most of the night when we came upon a terrible snowstorm. We found ourselves in a blinding blizzard, and the snow was growing deeper on the highway with each passing moment. The night was pure black. We couldn’t see where we were going, and because of the deep snow we couldn’t see the lines on the road. This was a frightening situation!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p3" pid="4QBEbxRXzUyh81hrm9XXOQ" hash="5f_W1w">Suddenly in front of us we began to see a huge semitruck going slowly and steadily ahead. We could barely make out his taillights, but seeing them gave us hope. My husband, who was driving, fixed his eyes on the lights from the truck, and we drove along in the tracks it made through the deepening snow. Our panic subsided somewhat with that guide up ahead, because he knew the route, he sat up higher than we and could have a better view, and surely he had communication equipment if it was needed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p4" pid="Chg-jXfJ5k2KK18XtNgbVQ" hash="i8Hokg">With prayers on our lips and white-knuckled hands holding on, we followed that light through the storm. We passed many cars off both sides of the road before we sensed that the truck was slowing down and pulling off the highway. In an act of faith, we followed him and soon found ourselves, to our great relief, in a place of safety, a place of refuge. We were so very thankful! We could hardly wait to tell the driver of the truck how grateful we were for his help—for leading the way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p5" pid="FVsjzHb6uUWyhUqjbXtOKw" hash="-b1hZw">We are each one on a road going toward home, but we’re not trying to get there for Christmas. We’re trying to get there for eternity. We want to arrive home safely to our loving Father in Heaven. He wants us to make it safely there, so He has sent a guiding light for us to follow: a Savior, the Lord Jesus Christ, the perfect example. He knows the way. He lights our path in the dark of night, in storms, at crossroads, and in the daylight. He is always ready to show the way back home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p6" pid="tNO5cZOZeUGLipp3pcq5eQ" hash="-FGR-w">He tells us, “And I will also be your light; … I will prepare the way before you, if it so be that ye shall keep my commandments; … ye shall know that it is by me that ye are led” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.13" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p7" pid="zEueEMyWkUm34HpRvCs1BQ" hash="DKHqEQ">One young woman wrote to me about a road she was on. She said: “I was with a group of my friends watching a video. It was one I knew I shouldn’t be sitting through. The Spirit prompted me to leave. I was able to listen and get up and leave. I felt the Spirit so strong. I know it was because of the choice I made” (letter in possession of Young Women office). She followed the light to safety.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p8" pid="67qAE_8QbE2Fnm-MKuJb6g" hash="af4nqg">That same light showed two teenage sisters the way to go on a very frightening day in 1833. An angry mob stormed through the quiet streets of Independence, Missouri, where 15-year-old Mary Elizabeth Rollins and her 13-year-old sister Caroline lived. The terrifying mob was destroying property and burning and rioting. Some of the mobsters broke into the home of Brother William Phelps, where the printing press was located. He had been printing revelations received by the Prophet Joseph Smith. They tore apart the printing press and threw it into the street. They carried the priceless printed pages out of the building, throwing them in a pile in the yard to burn.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p9" pid="aYcBMcKSd0mU-dyIkoGnjg" hash="mGEBqQ">Mary Elizabeth and her sister Caroline were hiding behind a fence, trembling as they watched the destruction. Mary knew full well the danger of angry mobs, but in spite of that, she felt the urgency to save those precious pages. The two teenage sisters ran out to the street, grabbed armfuls of the scriptures, and fled. Some of the mob saw this and ordered them to stop as they chased after the courageous sisters. The girls ran into a large cornfield, where they fell breathless to the ground. Between the rows of corn they laid the copies of the revelations on the ground and then spread themselves over the pages. The men were relentless in their search for the girls among the tall cornstalks, coming very near at times, but they never were able to find the girls, and eventually they gave up and left to finish their destruction in the town.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p10" pid="6it-swiV3UyhGPWS_0a7GA" hash="8VbGfg">The light of the Lord showed those young women what to do and where to go for safety. That same light shines for you. It can keep you safe as it did them. We have a sculpture of those sisters in the Young Women office to remind us of the courage of young women then and now.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p11" pid="Qdrjf5TS4U-U6mxVW9mFHA" hash="UMeS-Q">Jane Allgood Bailey wasn’t about to give up the light of her new religion. She would not be defeated by the cold, starvation, and sickness on the plains of Wyoming. She grasped hands with other women to wade through icy streams. They came out on the other side with their clothes frozen to them, but they carried on. On the trek, her 18-year-old son, Langley, became ill and was so weak that he had to be pushed on the handcart much of the way. One morning he rose from his bed on the cart, which had frozen canvas for bedding, and he went ahead of the company and lay down under a sagebrush to die, feeling that he was too much of a burden. When his faithful mother found him, she scolded him and told him: “Get on the cart. I’ll help you, but you’re not giving up!” Then the family moved on with what was left of the Martin-Willey Handcart Company.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p12" pid="1VSsf7je00y5zp00o84lVQ" hash="zPQPAw">Upon arrival in the Salt Lake Valley, Langley was still alive! He was 18 years old and he weighed only 60 pounds. That 18-year-old boy was my great-grandfather. I’m grateful for the preservation of his young life and for the fortitude and stamina of his noble, courageous mother, who was a light to her family and kept her son going in spite of deathly odds.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p13" pid="YJDuMScQ6km9JGHw2cBP3Q" hash="w1X8GQ">You probably will not have to push a handcart in a blizzard over the plains, sisters, or run away from a mob, but you may have to walk away from friends and fashions and invitations which would compromise your standards of goodness. And that takes courage. Soon you will be Relief Society sisters and one day mothers who must lend strength and testimony to future generations. Now in your preparing years, you can’t afford to say: “I’m going to give up. The Church standards are too high. It’s too hard to live the standards of personal purity with exactness. I’m too weak.” You can do it! For the sake of your future, you must do it!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p14" pid="f2Zugp8E2kSJ9XQkeIJYMg" hash="0b47Kw">You can live in the world and not be of the world. The Lord invites us to come out of the cold danger of worldliness and into the warmth of His light. This requires integrity, strength of character, and faith—faith in the truths taught by the Lord Jesus Christ, who said, “I am the light of the world: he that followeth me shall not walk in darkness, but shall have the light of life” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.12" class="scriptureRef">John 8:12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p15" pid="I-1ki12Igkev_Nol2vDHpA" hash="S2eDKA">The Lord’s light helped Shelly Ann Scoffield face a frightening trial in her young life, but she faced it with great faith and love for Heavenly Father. One day Shelly began to feel sick. She saw a doctor, who determined that there was something seriously wrong. Shelly said: “I was scared. I had huge masses on my lungs, and the doctor began to say things like cancer and chemotherapy and radiation.” But Shelly didn’t give in to her fears. True to her training in Personal Progress, she got busy and set a long list of goals to accomplish while she couldn’t go to school because of her treatments. She busied herself with accomplishing good things. She was mindful of her blessings, including a father with the priesthood who had administered to her, a wonderful family, super friends, and great doctors. “Best of all,” Shelly said, “I have a testimony of my Heavenly Father, that He loves me and will help me through this struggle.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p16" pid="KO8h5g99kkOeLd6ArB7aWg" hash="4NdkBA">Shelly recorded her thoughts for her young women friends, and I would like to share with you some of what she said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p17" pid="b0JYZ0Dyu02EZxCDD1fK6g" hash="M_-AlQ">“I want you girls to know that now is the time to grow close to your Heavenly Father. Work to show Him you can do all that you promised you would do. I am trying. I am learning more now than I have ever in my life known about the gospel. I know that Heavenly Father is with me. When I’m feeling pain and sorrow, He is too, and He just wants me and every one of you, when you’re feeling those things, to get down on your knees and pray for His help, because He is so willing. He loves you so much. I pray that throughout your life, throughout your struggles, that you’ll learn from them and stay close to Him and have faith. Gain a testimony and stay true to what is right.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p18" pid="Jxpg3uIz-UKjzrbcshgl3A" hash="dzbUww">Shelly Scoffield passed away November 3, 1998, strong in the faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p19" pid="RYGscWoJz06HdixtdslWEg" hash="h0CdIQ">Dear, precious young sisters, we will not all have experiences like Shelly’s or the other ones I’ve shared with you tonight, but we will each one of us have a need to draw close to the Lord in our journey through life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p20" pid="kApmU6knE0e1E1vZKX4l5g" hash="kNmgpA">May we suggest three things that will help you see the light and follow it in your lives. First, and most important of all, pray. As you talk to Heavenly Father and pour out your heart to Him, you will draw closer to Him. Then pause, stop, and listen to the feelings of your heart. Seek to understand the promptings of the Spirit. As you pray sincerely, you will come to feel Heavenly Father’s great love for you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p21" pid="F4ArTMbgZ0KVIYjgfgTGPQ" hash="cbU5ww">Second, study the scriptures. The scriptures teach us the ways of the Lord. They answer questions about how to live today. They bring a light and a spirit into our lives that we can get in no other way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p22" pid="K7tKcdQdp0OtcSgD3FXU_A" hash="TCczgw">Third, be anxiously engaged in a good cause. That means: Serve your family and friends. Be active in the Church and in seminary. Develop talents and skills. Set a good example. Stand as a witness of God at all times and in all things and in all places. As you do that, the light will grow brighter and brighter in your life, and it will be reflected in your countenance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p23" pid="t_GqMfUVwkWXf0Ih6tINPQ" hash="kM4Ntw">The Young Women office looks out at the holy Salt Lake Temple, and we can see brides as they come out to have pictures taken. These lovely temple-married brides all look so beautiful because there is a glow in their faces and a light in their eyes. That light comes from their understanding of the influence of the Savior in their lives. There is something very special about a young woman who has prepared herself and is worthy to make and keep sacred covenants and receive the ordinances of the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p24" pid="2fGYqzZ_tEKDAqrEuT8QDA" hash="mO49GA">Just as we followed the light of a truck one stormy winter night, so did Shelly and Mary Elizabeth and Jane follow the light of the Lord, and so can you. And when you come to those times that will require courage and strength and faith, remember the words of the hymn:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="xf6wa_zwXk2MEZsqCC76pw" hash="6bTh5g">
            <span class="emphasis">The Lord is my light; then why should I fear?</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="WtibNVPHVUqhOM0-JwEKJA" hash="c_sP5A">
            <span class="emphasis">By day and by night his presence is near.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light.p25" pid="iAstVEZZy0S8E4ICJMJbwg" hash="weLL3Q">I testify that the Lord is always there to help you. The example of His life and His teachings is a steady, sure guide. We can follow Him with confidence and perfect trust, for He is our Savior. I love Him. I love you and bear testimony of His love for you in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1999/04/follow-the-light</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/1999-general-young-women-meeting/1999-03-0030-margaret-d-nadauld-64k-eng.mp3" length="7367676" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 1999 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stand as a Witness</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness?lang=eng</link>
      <description>You have all you need to stand strong and firm and true because you have the Lord on your side.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10033256_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="W5wBoA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="jESQp2qVP0GO3o700O6pEg" hash="OKZUCg">Stand as a Witness</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="OWyRExiHw0edv_oJtHMbwQ" hash="zJRadA">Margaret D. Nadauld</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="MLhFxGLw10q5VHtREViyJw" hash="owd6kg">You have all you need to stand strong and firm and true because you have the Lord on your side.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-ee5.jpg" alt="Margaret D. Nadauld" pid="wT9rFkhilECQ2pGMRzq5bQ" hash="5iwElw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p1" pid="1fdYrajxSUSypdoT-ViqAg" hash="rz16Qw">Whitney is a very bright 14-year-old girl who joined the Church about a year ago. It was a magical moment as I looked at the girls’ soccer team who were there for her baptism. They had been there for each other many times. That’s the way it is with teams, and this team was one of the best, in soccer—and in life. Each girl was a Beehive, setting an example, standing as a witness of goodness, even on the playing field. Whitney liked being part of that. It felt good.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p2" pid="gsWqrj7OPkqwpFMNeLemYQ" hash="0Nq_vQ">After her baptism, Whitney stood before us with her friend Elizabeth. Their faces were glowing, their eyes were bright, and their smiles sincere as they repeated these words they had learned by heart: “We are daughters of our Heavenly Father, who loves us, and we love Him. We will ‘stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things, and in all places.’” Whitney already had the whole Young Women theme memorized. In fact, it was because Whitney’s friends had stood as witnesses that we were all there on that memorable day to welcome a beautiful daughter of God into The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p3" pid="3wVVDXolsk6r50t2h-p-qw" hash="cJrR0Q">What does it mean to stand as a witness of God at all times and in all things and in all places?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p4" pid="6M82cR-oQEumsaigyQ3oXw" hash="gRQ5qg">First of all, in standing as a witness at all times, we promise to love the Lord, to honor Him all the time—daytime and nighttime, summer and winter, good times and bad times—love the Lord and let that love show by the way we live. We also take time to thank Him, take time to ask for help, take time to seek guidance, and then take time to listen. Take time for that still, small voice which will whisper to us, help us, and give us courage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p5" pid="QOdip8jeFkWzojRvqgT4DQ" hash="Yj978A">Let me illustrate:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p6" pid="wGuIjqQyYUSG66MtQgg2Zg" hash="QtQXiQ">Anya lives in Russia. When she was only 14 years old, she was being taught the gospel by the missionaries. One day in her school class, the teacher was saying false things about the Church and about the Book of Mormon. There were no Latter-day Saints in the school to defend it; but little Anya, who was not even a member, only an investigator of the Church, knew that what the teacher was saying was wrong. She stood up in front of the whole class and defended the Book of Mormon and the Church. What courage! She told them that what they were saying was not true and that she knew the Book of Mormon was true, and if anyone wanted to know the truth for themselves, she invited them to read it like she had done. Then Anya went home and told the missionaries she was ready to be baptized. I love Anya’s courage as she stood as a witness at an important time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p7" pid="g8edBdFChUiQd7DcLZJyrw" hash="YS57Pg">Standing as a witness in all things means <span class="emphasis">all</span> things—big things, little things, in all conversations, in jokes, in games played and books read and music listened to, in causes supported, in service rendered, in clothes worn, in friends made.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p8" pid="uxzkPzuN60SU7hnVVp2jlA" hash="pD5dug">Kendra, a Laurel, says: “I never thought that I was being an example or ‘standing as a witness’ when I made right choices. I was only trying to live worthy to obtain all the blessings Heavenly Father has promised me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p9" pid="TtFtaxkWfEutgtg9F12bIA" hash="MbmAcQ">Standing as a witness in all things means being kind in all things, being the first to say hello, being the first to smile, being the first to make the stranger feel a part of things, being helpful, thinking of others’ feelings, being inclusive.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p10" pid="F1SQyTU0gEep3Rr8gwsdTw" hash="zO3wDQ">Our Heavenly Father does bless us when we show our love for Him in all things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p11" pid="RIsWHbylzkGidB-syvTxFw" hash="-5kZ3A">Finally, we say that we will stand as a witness in all places. That means not only in public places but in private places, in secret, in dark or in light places; in church, school, home, or cars; in mountain places or beach places; on the street or in the park. Stand as an example of a worthy daughter of God in all places.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p12" pid="dLDYV7ACqkm2eRFGX6TFyQ" hash="yPlwHA">I read about Shannon in the <span class="emphasis">New Era. </span>Her high school speech teacher assigned a group project to the students. They were to select a scene from a play to perform for the class. One group chose a questionable scene dealing with morality issues. The teacher allowed them to keep their selection “for the sake of art.” But knowing that it might be offensive, the teacher gave permission for those who felt uncomfortable to leave the room.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p13" pid="rb1LtL4HQUWMkSeRcm9C2Q" hash="a9pGKg">As the students’ scene began, Shannon felt a little bit nervous. Several of her classmates blushed and giggled uneasily, but no one left. She looked at a few of her Latter-day Saint friends, watching for one of them to give the signal for them all to walk out together. But none of them did. Shannon remained at her desk with her head down so no one could see her crimson cheeks. She felt very uncomfortable, but she was also afraid to leave. After all, it was art, right? Shannon states:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p14" pid="3usPqQDrxkuPFCkKMqicqg" hash="4f2B7g">“At [that] moment, the Young Women theme came into my mind: ‘We will “stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things, and in all places.”’ (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:9</a>). Immediately, I knew what [I was going to] do. ‘All places’ meant everywhere, even in a classroom with my friends.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p15" pid="k2muNXcbi0-_AQ8IP8iJ_A" hash="Qac3mA">“Quietly, I got up and left the room. That was it. No one got up and followed me. No one applauded my valiant act. No one was converted by my example. But inside I knew I had done the right thing” (Shannon D. Jensen, “Stand as a Witness,” <span class="emphasis">New Era,</span> Nov. 1998, 10).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p16" pid="Ugaf8uFKc0mVaSqaXPoZ7A" hash="Rf98bQ">l As we read in Moroni, chapter 7, verse 15: “It is given unto you to judge, that ye may know good from evil; and the way to judge is as plain, that ye may know with a perfect knowledge, as the daylight is from the dark night.” It says we can know that clearly! How? The way to do it is laid out for us very simply in verse 16: “For every thing which inviteth <span class="emphasis">[1]</span> to do good, and <span class="emphasis">[2]</span> to persuade to believe in Christ, is sent forth by the power and gift of Christ; wherefore ye may know with a perfect knowledge it is of God” (numbering added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p17" pid="ISjngNWqW021eHXqLHZq-Q" hash="bYBciw">But listen to this in verse 17: “Whatsoever thing persuadeth men<span class="emphasis"> [1]</span> to do evil, and <span class="emphasis">[2]</span> [to] believe not in Christ,<span class="emphasis"> [3]</span> … [to] deny him, <span class="emphasis">[4]</span> … [to] serve not God, then ye may know with a perfect knowledge it is of the devil; … for he persuadeth no man to do good, no, not one” (numbering added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p18" pid="tDYEyQ4HFkStRRHmkVG1Wg" hash="ZMuyfA">Remember Joseph who was sold into Egypt? Certainly he exercised good judgment when he was tempted by Potiphar’s wife to become involved with her in an immoral act. We read in the Bible that at this critical time in his young life, Joseph stood up and got himself out of the situation (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/39.7-12" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 39:7–12</a>). He didn’t sit around wondering what to do. He didn’t linger a little longer. He <span class="emphasis">stood</span>—he stood as a witness of righteousness at this crucial time. He exercised good judgment, and it made all the difference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p19" pid="gGTo744wxUKf-TWnhsyMZw" hash="K2KmXw">You, like Joseph, are of noble heritage. You have a royal inheritance, for you are a spirit daughter of God. You are of a chosen generation. You were chosen, before this world was, to come forth at this time. You were taught in a premortal world by God Himself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p20" pid="JST2juhs4UW5NEdcpX8EGA" hash="8EeTmg">The time is here for you to stand up for what you know is right. You must judge right from wrong. No longer can you be complacent or go with the flow or wonder what to do. You must decide now which path you will follow and which answer you will give. Decide well in advance, before the pressure is on, what you stand for.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p21" pid="Fw5RzGALEUKRmNhuKpJGDg" hash="vfrP1w">The great good news is that you can win any assault that is aimed at you! And it is not that hard. Just use good judgment! You can stand up and change the channel on the television, turn off the pornography on the computer, leave a movie, and don’t rent the racy video. Don’t wear the revealing clothes that are too tight or too bare or too short. Leave them in the closet. Better still, leave them in the store. Stand up and walk away from temptation, just like Joseph did—only he didn’t just walk away, he ran! You can do this too, literally and figuratively, and you will be safer, more pure, more secure.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p22" pid="lxuwLuUGK0iQEGIVe_ioMg" hash="92G2lQ">One way to disrupt God’s plan for you would be to desensitize young women. Give them a small, seemingly innocent taste of something ultimately destructive, next time a little more, and next time even more again, and soon, when it was time for the big whammy, it would hardly be noticed. It is said if you want to boil a frog, don’t throw him in a pot of boiling water. He will immediately jump out. Put him in a pot of cold water and turn the heat up so slowly that he won’t even notice the dangerous increase in temperature. Young women, I fear that the trend in our world is to slowly turn up the heat. Pay attention. Don’t allow yourselves to be desensitized by gradual lapses in good judgment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p23" pid="5YdKCQdkykOxuKjlIu3WdA" hash="Fiqx6g">As you view images, whether on TV or videos or movies or Internet or magazines, you will see some good things and most probably you will see things that are not good. Wrong and evil may be made to appear acceptable. Don’t be tricked! Simply stand up and walk away!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p24" pid="4MDb2iZeLEaodUZs98miVA" hash="PWsLjg">Dear beautiful young women, you know some things that the good people of this world don’t know because you have been taught truth. You have all you need to stand strong and firm and true because you have the Lord on your side. The Savior will help you stand strong by the power of His love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p25" pid="qEyasy9_70WJr6xoRQLv6A" hash="w9h5bg">There are so many of us who care about you. Walk with us. Walk with God. “Be thou humble; and the Lord thy God shall lead thee by the hand, and give thee answer to thy prayers” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/112.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 112:10</a>). Put your hand in His, and He will lead and guide you in peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p26" pid="zB-wpLcTRkGkFN06YRouAA" hash="ztahng">We stand together in this, the morning of a new millennium. Newly baptized Whitney and young women all over the world join to commemorate the 2,000 years since the birth of the Savior, the Son of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p27" pid="CkEM5noGY06Wv6uMASdwDg" hash="nZMRrg">I think it truly remarkable that the world still remembers that little baby boy born in Bethlehem so long ago. He lived a life that we still try to follow. He showed us the way. He taught truths we still try to live. He willingly suffered for our sins because He loved us so completely. He gave us the right to repent. And He gave His life that we might be resurrected and live again after death.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness.p28" pid="Rx-E9orOn0mFg9S2t8zkeA" hash="y3Cjrw">When we think of the magnificence of His gift to us, what small thing could we do for Him and for our Heavenly Father who sent Him? We could stand as witnesses of Their love and teachings at all times, in all things, and in all places. It is my prayer that we will, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2000/04/stand-as-a-witness</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2000-general-young-women-meeting/2000-03-0030-margaret-d-nadauld-64k-eng.mp3" length="7240148" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2000 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Joy of Womanhood</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Daughters of God know that it is the nurturing nature of women that can bring everlasting blessings, and they live to cultivate this divine attribute.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10028166_000_008" doc-version="2" hash="X_x66g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="bB-bhsEfe0ywuaMYHkYvgw" hash="9VRCNQ">The Joy of Womanhood</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="3mBFvLD6tEKSNNLJ0cQxTQ" hash="zJRadA">Margaret D. Nadauld</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="ks9KsIMzwE21XDti9Pii4g" hash="zFjJGg">Daughters of God know that it is the nurturing nature of women that can bring everlasting blessings, and they live to cultivate this divine attribute.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-ee5.jpg" alt="Margaret D. Nadauld" pid="RLjE3dkZJkeaQRbrBeF5nA" hash="5iwElw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p1" pid="5oRTGZn26kqC2qNErsfhHw" hash="-Rb5rg">It is a remarkable blessing to be a daughter of God today. We have the fulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ. We are blessed to have the priesthood restored to the earth. We are led by a prophet of God who holds all of the priesthood keys. I love and honor President Gordon B. Hinckley and all of our brethren who bear the priesthood worthily.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p2" pid="eH0Gc-RlDE6o1LDa-F3j9g" hash="kdECIA">I am inspired by the lives of good and faithful women. From the beginning of time the Lord has placed significant trust in them. He has sent us to earth for such a time as this to perform a grand and glorious mission. The Doctrine and Covenants teaches, “Even before they were born, they, with many others, received their first lessons in the world of spirits and were prepared to come forth in the due time of the Lord to labor in his vineyard for the salvation of the souls of men” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/138.56" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 138:56</a>). What a wonderful vision that gives us of our purpose on earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p3" pid="a5iuX3nLP0qRTOn7fASx1g" hash="WJZqSQ">Where much is given, much is required. Our Heavenly Father asks His daughters to walk in virtue, to live in righteousness so that we can fulfill our life’s mission and His purposes. He wants us to be successful, and He will help us as we seek His help.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p4" pid="1CptO6b0iUyakkCpP_n59A" hash="7VQkhQ">That women were born into this earth female was determined long before mortal birth, as were the divine differences of male and female. I love the clarity of the teachings of the First Presidency and the Quorum of the Twelve in the proclamation on the family, where they state, “Gender is an essential characteristic of individual premortal, mortal, and eternal identity and purpose.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> From that statement we are taught that every girl was feminine and female in spirit long before her mortal birth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p5" pid="049qyMZXzEqGHbMkdyO6tA" hash="7jj2TQ">God sent women to earth with some qualities in extra capacity. In speaking to young women, President Faust observed that femininity “is the divine adornment of humanity. It finds expression in your … capacity to love, your spirituality, delicacy, radiance, sensitivity, creativity, charm, graciousness, gentleness, dignity, and quiet strength. It is manifest differently in each girl or woman, but each … possesses it. Femininity is part of your inner beauty.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p6" pid="KTbd8ZCr9Emm6vjGQfcyDQ" hash="WiTRyQ">Our outward appearance is a reflection of what we are on the inside. Our lives reflect that for which we seek. And if with all our hearts we truly seek to know the Savior and to be more like Him, we shall be, for He is our divine, eternal Brother. But He is more than that. He is our precious Savior, our dear Redeemer. We ask with Alma of old, “Have ye received his image in your countenances?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.14" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:14</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p7" pid="9CQmt_S860-yd3ghaz9Eeg" hash="71_3Dg">You can recognize women who are grateful to be a daughter of God by their outward appearance. These women understand their stewardship over their bodies and treat them with dignity. They care for their bodies as they would a holy temple, for they understand the Lord’s teaching: “Know ye not that ye are the temple of God, and that the Spirit of God dwelleth in you?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/3.16" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 3:16</a>). Women who love God would never abuse or deface a temple with graffiti. Nor would they throw open the doors of that holy, dedicated edifice and invite the world to look on. How even more sacred is the body, for it was not made by man. It was formed by God. We are the stewards, the keepers of the cleanliness and purity with which it came from heaven. “If any man defile the temple of God, him shall God destroy; for the temple of God is holy, which temple ye are” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/3.17" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 3:17</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p8" pid="7drmOg0vX0i-LZfJ0-VgvA" hash="75S0Gg">Grateful daughters of God guard their bodies carefully, for they know they are the wellspring of life and they reverence life. They don’t uncover their bodies to find favor with the world. They walk in modesty to be in favor with their Father in Heaven. For they know He loves them dearly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p9" pid="owTIstNtaEiHARghZrwV1g" hash="IyiJ2A">You can recognize women who are grateful to be a daughter of God by their attitude. They know that the errand of angels is given to women, and they desire to be on God’s errand to love His children and minister to them, to teach them the doctrines of salvation, to call them to repentance, to save them in perilous circumstances, to guide them in the performance of His work, to deliver His messages.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> They understand that they can bless their Father’s children in their homes and neighborhoods and beyond. Women who are grateful to be daughters of God bring glory to His name.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p10" pid="p97pk21FO0yqdY7Mkmp_sw" hash="1Pt_hg">You can recognize women who are grateful to be a daughter of God by their abilities. They fulfill their divine potential and magnify their God-given gifts. They are capable, strong women who bless families, serve others, and understand that “the glory of God is intelligence” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:36</a>). They are women who embrace enduring virtues in order to be all that our Father needs them to be. The prophet Jacob spoke of some of those virtues when he said their “feelings are exceedingly tender and chaste and delicate before God, which thing is pleasing unto God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/2.7" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 2:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p11" pid="OaHVbv8VRUmNCrqSrOWzdQ" hash="GjZs7w">You can recognize women who are grateful to be a daughter of God by their reverence for motherhood, even when that blessing has been withheld from them for a time. In those circumstances, their righteous influence can be a blessing in the lives of children they love. Their exemplary teachings can echo the voice of a faithful home and resonate truth in the hearts of children who need another witness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p12" pid="63xOATmwBEuqXqXl3gUV8w" hash="bWFY3g">Grateful daughters of God love Him and teach their children to love Him without reservation and without resentment. They are like the mothers of Helaman’s youthful army, who had such great faith and “had been taught by their mothers, that if they did not doubt, God would deliver them” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/56.47" class="scriptureRef">Alma 56:47</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p13" pid="cEQyxk6wSke_dq5zBOcpSg" hash="EAJfAA">When you observe kind and gentle mothers in action, you see women of great strength. Their families can feel a spirit of love and respect and safety when they are near her as she seeks the companionship of the Holy Ghost and the guidance of His Spirit. They are blessed by her wisdom and good judgment. The husbands and children, whose lives they bless, will contribute to the stability of societies all over this world. Grateful daughters of God learn truths from their mothers and grandmothers and aunts. They teach their daughters the joyful art of creating a home. They seek fine educations for their children and have a thirst for knowledge themselves. They help their children develop skills that they can use in serving others. They know that the way they have chosen is not the easy way, but they know it is absolutely worth their finest efforts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p14" pid="dqXNqVjTTkiR7IpT-jGuVw" hash="4zcXMg">They understand what Elder Neal A. Maxwell meant when he said: “When the real history of mankind is fully disclosed, will it feature the echoes of gunfire or the shaping sound of lullabies? The great armistices made by military men or the peacemaking of women in homes and in neighborhoods? Will what happened in cradles and kitchens prove to be more controlling than what happened in congresses?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p15" pid="NVoq6yHPY0y_Txegg7eDKg" hash="tkYisw">Daughters of God know that it is the nurturing nature of women that can bring everlasting blessings, and they live to cultivate this divine attribute. Surely when a woman reverences motherhood, her children will arise up and call her blessed (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/31.28" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 31:28</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p16" pid="fSusQktgZkKT1fqoLCbyYQ" hash="bxV1Qg">Women of God can never be like women of the world. The world has enough women who are tough; we need women who are tender. There are enough women who are coarse; we need women who are kind. There are enough women who are rude; we need women who are refined. We have enough women of fame and fortune; we need more women of faith. We have enough greed; we need more goodness. We have enough vanity; we need more virtue. We have enough popularity; we need more purity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p17" pid="S1p_IkG2iEiXv4-3oIQy2A" hash="6dIHDg">Oh, how we pray that every young woman will grow up to be all the wonderful things she is meant to be. We pray that her mother and father will show her the right way. May daughters of God honor the priesthood and sustain worthy priesthood holders. May they understand their own great capacity for strength in the timeless virtues that some would scoff at in a modern, liberated world for women.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p18" pid="TRQokOsgdkeatahXfvHsdA" hash="fpZApw">May mothers and fathers understand the great potential for good their daughters inherited from their heavenly home. We must nourish their gentleness, their nurturing nature, their innate spirituality and sensitivity, and their bright minds. Celebrate the fact that girls are different from boys. Be thankful for the position they have in God’s grand plan. And always remember what President Hinckley said, “Only after the earth had been formed, after the day had been separated from the night, after the waters had been divided from the land, after vegetation and animal life had been created, and after man had been placed on the earth, was woman created; and only then was the work pronounced complete and good.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p19" pid="kPSafY58o0SwuY-fY-VBqA" hash="UGvobg">Fathers, husbands, young men, may you catch a vision of all that women are and can be. Please be worthy of God’s holy priesthood, which you bear, and honor that priesthood, for it blesses all of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood.p20" pid="WVhuRAHVJES-c6Erxodi9A" hash="G191FA">Sisters, regardless of your age, please understand all that you are and must be, all that you were prepared to be in royal courts on high by God Himself. May we use with gratitude the priceless gifts we have been given for the lifting of mankind to higher thinking and nobler aspirations, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2000/10/the-joy-of-womanhood</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2000-general-conference/2000-10-1060-margaret-d-nadauld-64k-eng.mp3" length="5683380" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2000 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comforter, a Guide, a Testifier</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier?lang=eng</link>
      <description>By the gift and power of the Holy Ghost, you can be guided in your trip through life.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029247_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="obRSDQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="t1al0KI4VU-ysWefmqgPfA" hash="WcjnLQ">A Comforter, a Guide, a Testifier</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="cO_IDz3rNk27hX7f1W3g7g" hash="zJRadA">Margaret D. Nadauld</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="Z0B37cCt60-cq1AaJuJuig" hash="E4v8SQ">By the gift and power of the Holy Ghost, you can be guided in your trip through life.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-ee5.jpg" alt="Margaret D. Nadauld" pid="k57yNePVnEO_ZORzHDmBwA" hash="5iwElw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p1" pid="l7RvITPk7UWMPja_XZmtjA" hash="haHSOw">Do you remember the song which begins, “I think when I read that sweet story of old, when Jesus was here among men, how he called little children like lambs to his fold; I should like to have been with him then”? (“I Think When I Read That Sweet Story,” <span class="emphasis">Children’s Songbook,</span> 56). Try to imagine what it would have been like to have Jesus place His hands on your head and bless you as the scriptures say He did when He was on earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p2" pid="kIKu5KiuZky6pOpwy2sUZA" hash="s5rm3g">Think of being able to actually be near the Savior. Imagine being loved and healed and blessed and guided by Him as they were then. When He was on the earth the members of His Church loved Him, they depended on Him, and they followed Him. You can imagine how saddened they were at the prospect of Him leaving them, but He promised: “I will pray the Father, and he shall give you another Comforter, that he may abide with you for ever. … The Comforter … is the Holy Ghost” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.16,26" class="scriptureRef">John 14:16, 26</a>). He then gave them the priceless gift of the Comforter to be their companion after He was gone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p3" pid="RW-BKKnhoE-pgMztHNU18w" hash="Xjj1Wg">You too are loved by the Lord, just as were the disciples of old. You are loved more than you will ever know. He wants you to be successful in your life’s mission! You don’t have to face the experiences of this life alone, nor have you been sent here to fail.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p4" pid="UtLmnwe23EiZLGlSP1zvsA" hash="0t3cTQ">For this reason a holy gift was given to you at the time of your baptism and confirmation, when hands were placed on your head and you were told, “Receive the Holy Ghost.” It is almost as if your Father in Heaven gave you a gift to celebrate your official entrance into His kingdom on earth. The Holy Spirit can be with you always and guide you back to Him, but in order to enjoy the benefits of this holy gift, you must truly receive it, and then you must use it in your life. How sad it would be to be given such a precious gift and then set it aside and never use it. I would like to talk to you about just three of the things the Holy Ghost can do. He can comfort, guide, and testify.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p5" pid="RUzpLPmUoEeMgtgInX_xjA" hash="7qsCNQ">First, let’s focus on the comforting power of the Holy Ghost. When I was just a young girl, I became seriously ill. Each day the illness became increasingly severe. Nothing the doctor recommended helped. At that time the dreaded disease of polio was raging in almost epidemic proportions in the land. It was taking the lives of many, and those who didn’t die were often left crippled. Polio was everyone’s worst fear in those days.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p6" pid="YFaREEAmQ0-LVA2kyRBgYA" hash="AGXUKA">One night my illness became critical, and my father and grandfather administered to me using consecrated oil, and through the power of the holy Melchizedek Priesthood, which they held worthily, they called upon God for healing, help, guidance, and comfort. And then my parents took me to a doctor in another town who immediately sent us to Salt Lake City—two and one-half hours away—with the admonition to hurry. I overheard the doctor whisper that he was certain it was polio.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p7" pid="5kn6KOvWcEWERpqKy3DV5w" hash="YUc2Cg">When we finally arrived at the hospital in Salt Lake, there were medical personnel waiting for us. They grabbed me from my parents’ arms and whisked me away. Without a word of good-bye or explanation, we were separated. I was all alone, and I thought I was going to die.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p8" pid="75YcZWAk4Eu9hkGkQJdYDQ" hash="b667ag">Following the painful diagnostic procedures, including a spinal tap, they took me to a hospital isolation room, where I would stay all by myself with the hope that I would not infect anyone else, for indeed I did have polio.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p9" pid="tU8_vrEJNUOdVnFuAezjYA" hash="PJYnhA">I remember how very frightened I was. It was dark and I was so sick and so alone. But my parents had taught me to pray. I got on my knees, and I knelt beside the railing in the criblike bed and asked Heavenly Father to bless me. I was crying, I remember. Heavenly Father heard my prayer even though I was only a child. He did. Heavenly Father sent His comforting power, which enveloped me in quiet love. I felt the power of the Holy Ghost, and I was not alone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p10" pid="LNeo7vYlPkGgSH3lUm06dQ" hash="KKFcZg">Let me tell you a second experience. I know of a precious young woman who needs comfort because of a heartache in her life. She is worried about her family situation and the disharmony between her parents. It is sad and very troubling to her and to her brothers and sisters. She is the oldest child and wonders what she can do about this serious problem in their family. Maybe you find yourself in a similar situation. Although there is no solution that is easy and there is no one formula that will work for everyone with a heartache or a concern, there is One who cares very much about your situation, and He knows what you should do. That is our Father in Heaven. He cares as much about your life as if He were right here with you and could speak with you face-to-face. He knows the feelings of this girl’s heart, and He knows the feelings of your heart as well. To bless you, the gift of peace that the Holy Spirit brings has been given to you. Jesus said: “Peace I leave with you, my peace I give unto you: not as the world giveth, give I unto you. Let not your heart be troubled, neither let it be afraid” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.27" class="scriptureRef">John 14:27</a>). Young women, pray for comfort, and that gift will come to you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p11" pid="M_AeUy_B6UmtUxnrhA5N1Q" hash="V_7kdA">My second point is, the Holy Spirit has the power to guide. A 15-year-old girl felt that she needed to find new friends. Have you ever felt that way? She writes, “Now, I don’t know if you have ever had to change friends, but it honestly was the hardest thing I have ever had to do.” She decided to put her problem in the hands of the Lord, and she also counseled with her parents. She says that after several months “she wanted to just give up.” One afternoon she was casually talking to her seminary teacher, and she confided her problem to him. Then he said, “I really don’t know why I am asking you this, but do you happen to know these girls?” This girl answered with a yes. And then he said, “Have you ever thought about being friends with them?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p12" pid="qpXiE0nyukaceOIjIWuGiQ" hash="ywLPxg">“I told him that there was no way that I could fit in with them. He then asked me if he could talk to one of the girls. I decided I would let him, if he promised not to embarrass me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p13" pid="apJs6T9SIUehxEA0fFXAKw" hash="k_KfZg">“Well, that next day I received a phone call from one of the girls. Now, you have to understand that this girl was on student council, and I hate to use the term, but she was ‘extremely popular.’ She asked if I would like to go to the basketball game with her that night. That night was one of the funnest, most peaceful nights of my life. The next day at school, she introduced me to two other girls. We all instantly became friends. This event has changed me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p14" pid="dzCeMX8tBEOfciVx4uWAkQ" hash="YmOgkg">She concludes by saying, “I don’t know about you, but I would much rather have the Lord, who knows the outcome of everything, direct my life than me, who just sees things as they are at the time. He is right by our side, walking us through life, even when we feel so alone” (letter on file in the Young Women office).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p15" pid="SgmGopO4w0Kq_CMLR28ymw" hash="PAqPYw">The Lord promises us that “because of meekness and lowliness of heart cometh the visitation of the Holy Ghost, which Comforter filleth with hope and perfect love, which love endureth by diligence unto prayer” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/8.26" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 8:26</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p16" pid="13Q6BKHDrk6wis55S3ta3g" hash="1WkqPQ">Your Heavenly Father will help you find the right path as you seek His guidance. Remember though, after you pray you must get off your knees and start doing something positive; head in the right direction! He will send people along the way who will assist you, but you must be doing your part as well. By the gift and power of the Holy Ghost, you can be guided in your trip through life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p17" pid="NcP8g2Iai0yjHX1MNC0t3w" hash="P3KdEQ">Point number three—the Holy Ghost is also a testifier. This Holy Spirit can help you really understand deep down inside the most important truth ever known—that Jesus Christ is the Savior of the world and that because of Him every one of us who ever lived will one day live again. And because of Him we can repent of wrongdoing and get on the path that leads us back to our Heavenly Father. That is what the Atonement is. The Holy Spirit will testify of that truth to our hearts as we seek to know, and He testifies to others as we bear our testimony of these truths to them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p18" pid="DkbSmDQVeEawxY1O9O_Y_w" hash="DsfcKA">Elder Jeffrey R. Holland teaches that when we bear our testimony to others, they “are not only hearing our testimony of Christ, but they are hearing echoes of other, earlier testimonies, including their own testimony of Him,” for they were among the valiant who chose Christ and chose to follow Him over Satan in the premortal life. Elder Holland says, “When they hear others bear that witness of [Christ’s] saving mission, it has a familiar feeling; it brings an echo of truth they themselves already know.” Furthermore, when you bear testimony of Christ’s mission, “you invoke the power of God the Father and the Holy Ghost” (see “Missionary Work and the Atonement,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign, </span>Mar. 2001, 11–12). In Moroni chapter 10, verse 5 [<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.5" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:5</a>], we are promised that “by the power of the Holy Ghost ye may know the truth of all things.” My dear young sisters, work to gain a testimony of Christ’s mission. It will come to you by the power of the Holy Ghost. Then share your testimony and bear it often.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p19" pid="MD-oSlRipkupikZ5BVh1sQ" hash="pBJhmA">The Holy Spirit is a comforter, a guide, a testifier. What a remarkable and holy member of the Godhead. And you have the right to His influence and inspiration! How blessed and loved you are! Now, because you have been given so much, you too must give. And so tonight, with this in mind, we would like to make a very special request of you. It is an invitation, really, and we hope you will accept it, and we hope you will act upon it. Are you ready? This is the invitation:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p20" pid="yVcrz1_clEWojgsvh6WalA" hash="RPyZMg">Will you reach out and bring one other young woman into full activity in the Church this coming year? Surely each one of you knows of a girl who is less active or a recent convert or who is not a member. We are asking you to reach out and share the gospel of Jesus Christ with one other young woman so that she can also enjoy the sweet blessings of heaven that we have spoken of tonight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p21" pid="PZ1pJQDtdUykBs_emd4ETA" hash="bVE3yw">Think of how many lives would be blessed, how many young women could be comforted and guided and have stronger testimonies. This year there are over one-half million young women in the Church. Just think, if each one of you will accept this invitation to reach out and bring in just one, next year there will be twice as many active young women! Let the Holy Spirit guide you in your effort. Your parents and your leaders will also help you know what to do and how to do it. We will be eager to learn of your experiences and your successes. In my message to you I did not use a story to illustrate the third point of this talk, which was to testify, because this story will be yours to write as you accept our invitation. I hope that you will begin that story tonight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier.p22" pid="cr9AOqz9gkG9C4bcpQ7upQ" hash="5KCJVw">I began with a song reminding us of the days when the Savior lived on earth among men. I now conclude with the words of a hymn reminding us that though He has gone from our view, our Redeemer, the Lord Jesus Christ, still lives to bless us with His love: “He lives to silence all my fears. He lives to wipe away my tears. He lives to calm my troubled heart. He lives all blessings to impart” (“I Know That My Redeemer Lives,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns, </span>no. 136). I testify that He does so through the gift and power of the Holy Ghost. I pray that we will receive and use this sacred gift from God, in the holy name of our beloved Savior, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2001/04/a-comforter-a-guide-a-testifier</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2001-general-young-women-meeting/2001-03-0030-margaret-d-nadauld-64k-eng.mp3" length="7584499" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2001 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hold High the Torch</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Develop the divinity that is within you. Don’t dull the brightness of the spirit you came with from heaven. The Lord needs your goodness and your influence in this world.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029598_000_040" doc-version="2" hash="H3-KNA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="EC3E6TKrF0yukDmuJMW4ww" hash="81HlYg">Hold High the Torch</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="M7zveqBSPkOUo1y0rUqu_Q" hash="zJRadA">Margaret D. Nadauld</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="0vzSVxiaFEKjV7AQjkcacQ" hash="SW5YKg">Develop the divinity that is within you. Don’t dull the brightness of the spirit you came with from heaven. The Lord needs your goodness and your influence in this world.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-ee5.jpg" alt="Margaret D. Nadauld" pid="e6Jf4yp0q0GCWKhMC56g2g" hash="5iwElw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p1" pid="DCjLNhxBdk2XoX8wa970WQ" hash="eBGOKA">This is a torch that carried the Olympic flame on part of its journey from Greece to Salt Lake City last February. It is symbolic of excellence and hope. It was lit for the first time in Greece at the birth of the Olympics so long ago.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p2" pid="-k1axDx9z068HspNaVYGPw" hash="M-NKGg">This is the Young Women torch. It is symbolic of the light of the gospel which comes from our Heavenly Father. This light had its beginning in heaven before you were born. There you were taught the great plan of happiness, and because you accepted this plan, you have the honor of being a torchbearer!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p3" pid="1aixXcbe-k-nEN69w3FvCA" hash="znMeuQ">The Savior taught us to “let your light so shine before men, that they may see your good works, and glorify your Father which is in heaven.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> The divine light which you carry within your soul is inherited from God because you are His daughter. Part of the light which makes you so magnificent is the blessing of womanhood. What a wonderful thing it is for you to know that your female, feminine characteristics are an endowment from God. Our latter-day prophets teach that “gender is an essential characteristic of individual premortal, mortal, and eternal identity and purpose.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> It is a holy blessing to be born with the exquisite qualities of a daughter of God. Women of God, both old and young, are spiritual and sensitive, tender and gentle. They have a kind, nurturing nature. This is your inheritance. Never belittle the gifts God has given to you. Develop the divinity that is within you. Don’t dull the brightness of the spirit you came with from heaven. The Lord needs your goodness and your influence in this world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p4" pid="cFkP8zQpIEK3kH_R71ogbg" hash="-uf00A">And so tonight I’d just like to talk to you from my heart about simply being good and the advantages of being good. It’s about holding that torch high.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p5" pid="BaCTunEDWkGyBjd7sYY_zA" hash="naE41w">The world will try to make you think that being good is outdated and old-fashioned and that popularity comes from breaking the rules and lowering your standards. Don’t buy into that way of thinking. As you watch TV or read magazines, you might be made to feel abnormal when, really, you are the one who has it figured out.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p6" pid="KinX-V0hKECFYaZpyHehcQ" hash="iuCy2A">You may know that I am the mother of seven sons. I know boys! It has been an exciting life at our house! I’ve learned a lot from them and from their friends, both boys and girls, and I could tell you a few of their secrets. Maybe I could just share one and hope that I won’t get in trouble. This is it: boys hate to be embarrassed. I remember the time a young man I know had a date for the prom. He brought her to our house before the dance so we could take pictures. When they got there he came into the kitchen, where I was looking for the camera, and said: “Wait until you see my date’s dress. She looks so beautiful!” This boy had never said anything like that before so I could hardly wait to see what he meant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p7" pid="yaUVfi6NfU-HnysyCX3VVw" hash="475OUg">When I saw her I understood; she was lovely. The dress she was wearing was beautiful; I learned that she and her mother had searched everywhere for it. When they finally found this dress, they knew it would be perfect with some added fabric and finishing touches to meet their high standards.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p8" pid="KN-SfVoAx0a56QkM50XKNw" hash="MLfXfw">All their efforts were rewarded because she was absolutely radiant this night, but it was more than the dress that made her shine. It was her quiet confidence. As I looked at her, I was reminded of the scripture, “Let virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly; then shall thy confidence wax strong.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Where did this confidence that she had come from? I noticed that this young woman could focus on others because she was not worried about how she looked. She had taken care of that detail weeks before. The young man she was with felt comfortable and safe and happy when he was with her because her dress was not revealing. It was modest in every way, and this made her confident and happy. And that’s appealing. He wasn’t embarrassed by her; he was proud of her.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p9" pid="xCkXvrtiK0aNbttraIZolg" hash="2QYWVA">The kind of young woman who can be a terrific torchbearer has high standards all the time, not just in her prom dress, but every, ordinary day. There are so many of you who are like that, and I salute you tonight. You have made modesty your way of life. It is more than how you dress. It includes at least six things that I can think of: (1) your behavior is decent and modest, and yet you are very fun to be with; (2) your language is never crude but happy and interesting; (3) you are well groomed, and that is appealing; (4) you are focused on developing your talents and achieving your goals, not piercing and tattooing and flaunting your body; (5) you play sports with gusto but never lose control; (6) you don’t seem to care about what the latest pop star wears or does because you have a certain style of your own. In summary, you do not imitate the world’s standards because you know a higher standard. You know who you are, and that puts you at a real advantage. You know that you really are a daughter of Heavenly Father. You know that He <span class="emphasis">knows </span>you and that He <span class="emphasis">loves</span> you; you want to please Him and honor His love for you. You know that even if you make foolish mistakes, He will help you if you turn to Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p10" pid="jDpnMJZZdUKJpeP5EPbCDQ" hash="T6yy-w">You act like you have memorized <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth!</span> Isn’t that a great little guide? Sometimes I like to call it “helps for happiness” because living these standards can be your secret weapon for attracting good people to you and keeping you on the right track. When you live the high standards of the Church every day, you hold high the torch.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p11" pid="mlx6EKWPAE265CBI4mVfPQ" hash="uf3PGw">A girl I will call Liz is an example of what I am talking about. She was a student in a math class with a girl I will call Lindsay, who noticed that there was just something about Liz that “glowed,” as she put it. Lindsay admitted that she really didn’t think Liz knew her, but she still made her feel good. She really stood up for what she believed, and she always made others feel good and included. For several weeks Lindsay observed Liz. Then one day, Liz didn’t show up at school. Then another and then another passed. Lindsay finally learned that Liz was very ill with life-threatening meningitis.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p12" pid="AOhKu5V6q0u5HCSkUu_bug" hash="lTJzOw">She came home from school and just sat at the table crying. It wasn’t like she and Liz were close friends, but she said to her mom that they just had to do something to help her. Lindsay suggested that perhaps their whole family could fast and pray for Liz. What a shock it was for the mother to hear that coming from one of her own children, because fasting and prayer had not been mentioned in their home for years. When Lindsay and her mom talked with the rest of the family about it that night at supper, there was some resistance, but Lindsay pleaded with them and finally they all agreed to fast and pray for Liz, a stranger. The most wonderful thing happened. It wasn’t long before Liz returned to school appearing healthy and happy as ever. But even more important than this, the experience brought the most remarkable spirit of hope into Lindsay’s home. Because of it, some serious changes have taken place in their family. They are now having family prayer together, something that had not happened for years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p13" pid="e1WzbGyb1E2twbSPEwvrhQ" hash="XvcYaw">Liz’s goodness glowed, and it was catching. Liz, if you are here tonight, I would just like to say, “Thank you! By your goodness you have blessed at least one whole family whom you probably do not even know. And who knows how many others have been guided as you held high your torch.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p14" pid="daoEuFhrLk69zYNC6Ty0jw" hash="45-XrA">Being good makes you feel good, and it also makes others feel good! Can I just tell you this—it is so much easier to do what is right than it is to do what is wrong. Life is so much less complicated when you are good.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p15" pid="l9_sN3T_3EaUZ-AiiHdxwA" hash="wEE8kw">The greatest advantage of being good is that it will lead you to the temple, the most beautiful and sacred of all the places on this earth. The temple is the place the Savior could visit because it is His holy house here on earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p16" pid="D11iXiJwIE2tZltNTj7qrg" hash="SXwqVQ">President Lorenzo Snow’s granddaughter was in the temple with him on one occasion when President Snow said to her, “‘Allie[,] I want to tell you something. … It was right here that the Lord Jesus Christ appeared to me.’ [Grandfather] put his right hand on [my] head and said, ‘Now granddaughter, I want you to remember that this is the testimony of your grandfather, that he told you with his own lips that he actually saw the Savior, here in the temple, and talked with him face to face.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p17" pid="5Q1HWnaJHkap-sAsakgscg" hash="mWVe9Q">Can you imagine the reverence you would feel to walk the same halls the Savior walked? Do you picture yourself there, pure and clean, a daughter of God, prepared to receive His finest blessings?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p18" pid="kHefsPMRUkORNfDpP40eIA" hash="XlrMQA">Personal Progress will help you in your preparation for the temple. It is inspired of heaven. What a beautiful little treasure it is. It will help you draw closer to the Savior, and it will help you magnify the divine gifts of womanhood of which we have spoken. It is designed just for you at this very important period of preparation, for the patterns you set and the choices you make now will affect the rest of your life. It is our prayer that as you complete your Personal Progress, your light will shine so brightly that it will be an influence for good on generations to come. For these reasons and more, the First Presidency has said: “We desire all young women to strive to earn the Young Womanhood Recognition. As youth work on these goals, they will develop skills and attributes that will lead them to the temple and prepare them for a lifetime of service to their families and the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> The beautiful new Young Womanhood medallion depicts temple spires reminding you that you are preparing to receive the ordinances of the temple, for it is through the temple that we come to Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p19" pid="02WOs0v500u2o9bf8qRpYw" hash="m91b8Q">We are especially thinking of Christ on this Easter eve. More than 2,000 years ago on this eve, as His body was in the tomb, some believed that the light had gone out. But we know that on the morning of the third day, which we call Easter, He arose to be our salvation, our Savior, our eternal light that will never fail us. I testify that Christ is the light and the life of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch.p20" pid="SYvzhoqTukekX7xHYLKHmg" hash="Pc1MPA">Dear young women, let your light shine so brightly before all of your family and friends that they may see your good works and glorify your Father who is in heaven. It is a privilege to carry the torch. It is our prayer that His light will shine on your path every step along your way and that your goodness will qualify you to one day receive the ordinances of the temple, for it is in that holy place that you will find the greatest light of all, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2002/04/hold-high-the-torch</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2002-general-young-women-meeting/2002-03-0030-margaret-d-nadauld-64k-eng.mp3" length="7133786" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2002 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Woman of Faith</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2002/10/a-woman-of-faith?lang=eng</link>
      <description>A woman of faith trusts God. … She knows of His interest in her life. She knows that He knows her. She loves His words and drinks deeply of that living water.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-woman-of-faith" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029898_000_024" doc-version="2" hash="3dgnPQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-woman-of-faith.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="8WDzO3wKPkagkElrYrypmg" hash="S9BOcQ">A Woman of Faith</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Wk-OZPtTnEeJrfYW8P320g" hash="zJRadA">Margaret D. Nadauld</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="DgCTYIzfLk6aVVCL3hYcuw" hash="H51iXg">A woman of faith trusts God. … She knows of His interest in her life. She knows that He knows her. She loves His words and drinks deeply of that living water.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-woman-of-faith.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-ee5.jpg" alt="Margaret D. Nadauld" pid="QvUbPm9oNkKEecCWk79CdQ" hash="5iwElw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-woman-of-faith.p1" pid="LuXha6z-KEuuAH4ikwfZDQ" hash="fUoiFw">I love the Lord Jesus Christ and His Church, which has been restored to the earth in our day. I treasure the teachings of His holy life from newborn infant to resurrected man, Son of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-woman-of-faith.p2" pid="bqaZi_JykUSOizrNI1UThw" hash="pTRevg">As I have read from the pages of the Bible, in my mind’s eye I have watched Him as He “increased in wisdom and stature, and in favour with God and man.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> In my reading, I was there when He raised the dead. He healed the sick, fed the 5,000, brought comfort and hope and a process for peace into the world that He had created. He forgave those who mocked and tortured and crucified Him—for they knew not what they did. I saw the divine love and concern He had for His mother, though He suffered in supreme agony Himself. He overcame death so that we can too. He has prepared a place for us in heaven with our Eternal Father. He has taught us the plan for happiness and given us the vision of it and the hope to follow it. His was the ultimate life of sacrifice and a life of service to fulfill the plan of God His Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-woman-of-faith.p3" pid="-6zX8d-MN0SHWjcD571DmA" hash="xn3QEw">A Latter-day Saint woman who follows Christ’s example in her daily living begins to fulfill the plan of our Heavenly Father for her. By so doing she can be a powerful influence for good in today’s world and meet the challenges of mortality. I have known such women, and they have been a guiding light to me. The Latter-day Saint woman who follows Christ is a true Christian in the very best sense of the word. She is a woman of faith who trusts God and is confident and fearless.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-woman-of-faith.p4" pid="12Hw4m5KXEy_BUU0IWKHWw" hash="VqPa6g">
        <span class="strong">A woman of faith trusts God</span> and faces adversity with hope. She knows of His interest in her life. She knows that He knows her. She loves His words and drinks deeply of that living water. She is grateful for the prophet He has sent for these latter days, and she trusts his counsel and follows it, for she knows that by so doing she will find safety and peace. In prayer she seeks the kind, unfaltering guidance and help of a listening Heavenly Father. As she prays, she listens—allowing the communication to be two-way. She trusts that in His still and quiet way, He will lead her by the hand and give her answer to her prayers.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-woman-of-faith.p5" pid="I-qbY6sWekKMC1XSTBPD-g" hash="wiQFvg">
        <span class="strong">A woman of faith is confident</span> because she understands the divine plan of our Heavenly Father and her role to bless lives. She is confident that any sacrifice she makes is worth something in an eternal sense. She knows about sacrifice from knowing of the life of the Savior. She knows that her sacrifices may be small by comparison, but she knows that Heavenly Father understands and values what she does to strengthen her home and her family and the world in which she lives. Her confidence grows because she is virtuous and lovely and gracious, which is even better than beautiful. She has pure motives. She is loving and gentle and kind. The hearts of her husband and her children safely trust in her.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> And so do the children or youth or women that she has been called to teach, lead, serve, and love—they are drawn to her because of that special spirit that she radiates. It is the image of God that she has in her countenance that is appealing and important.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> She is confident that she is fashioning a character and a record of performance that will be invited to stand in the presence of her Heavenly Father. She will be able to do so with the sense that she fully belongs there, that she is known by Him and loved and valued and treasured forever and always.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-woman-of-faith.p6" pid="-YARF26nnUKbcwXImkGJmw" hash="TuHbNA">
        <span class="strong">A woman of faith is fearless.</span> She fears no evil, for God is with her.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> There is no ambiguity, no uncertain trump in her life. She can live a principled life because she studies the doctrine and teachings of a perfect teacher, the Master. She is a noble example to all who know her. She is less than perfect, of course, not because she doesn’t have perfect principles or the perfect example in Christ, but because she is human. She stays away from the evil influence and the unclean thing, and if it encroaches on her territory, she is as a lioness protecting her cubs. A fearless woman of faith has the courage to talk with her children about practices which would destroy them. They not only hear her discuss her commitment, but they see her commitment in her daily living—in the way she dresses, what she reads and watches, how she spends her leisure time, what she loves and laughs at, whom she attracts, and how she acts at all times, in all things, and in all places. She has a certain style of her own that is attractive and joyful and bright and good. Our little girls and our young women can safely trust in her example. We pray that they too will be fearless as they seek out and promote that which is uplifting and happy and decent, for they are our future.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-woman-of-faith.p7" pid="E0iSPK_CK06sJ9ZqhoMmHA" hash="GKcaog">Thank heaven for women of faith in our lives. A woman of faith loves the Lord. She wants Him to know it by the life she lives, by the words she speaks, by the service she renders to His children, by her every action. She knows that He loves her even though she is imperfect and still trying to be better. She knows that when she does her very best, that it is enough, as President Hinckley has told us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-woman-of-faith.p8" pid="CaDPzkjcwUGxA9dcY_cXfQ" hash="MnC3cg">A woman of faith is blessed by faithful men in her life who hold the priesthood of God and honor this privilege: her father, bishop, husband, brothers, sons. They value her and the divine gifts given by God to His daughter. They sustain and encourage, and they understand the great mission of her life as a woman. They love her; they bless her. They are in turn blessed by this woman of faith as they walk the path of life together. They know, as scripture teaches, that “two are better than one. … For if they fall, the one will lift up his fellow.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-woman-of-faith.p9" pid="o_zoqftg8UixNkdJVr46xg" hash="ykdQng">I express my gratitude for wonderful women of faith, for great, noble men, and for my beloved family, who have lifted me up and inspired me throughout my life. They have been an especially great blessing as I have tried to fulfill the sacred errand from the Lord as the Young Women general president.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/a-woman-of-faith.p10" pid="5QUdsWokjUuTckxg_8CbJA" hash="F_plHg">Dear brothers and sisters, please know of my love for you and my great gratitude to our Father in Heaven and His Beloved Son, the Lord Jesus Christ. I will honor and serve Them with all my heart forever and be thankful for the privilege. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2002/10/a-woman-of-faith</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2002-general-conference/2002-10-4040-margaret-d-nadauld-64k-eng.mp3" length="4582258" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2002 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
