<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Marian R. Boyer</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Marian R. Boyer.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Marian%20R.%20Boyer.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Marian R. Boyer.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Sep 1980 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 1980 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Organize Yourselves</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear sisters, it’s a privilege to meet with you here in the Tabernacle and to be part of a telecast to the rest of the Church. You represent the best of life, for you are the daughters of our Heavenly Father who reflect the rich blessings of gospe</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03128_000_048" doc-version="2" hash="MHz1PQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="8-EXGSFOwE-eLtkr4mGrNA" hash="34200w">Organize Yourselves</h1><p class="authorName" pid="qjUs3MjBmEuOwxfiKc0KCg" hash="GjDzLg">Marian R. Boyer</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2d6e.jpg" alt="Marian R. Boyer" pid="yZSQFgR3zkmPdr25ScA3dA" hash="dFF2SQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.p1" pid="h4_avdMC-0q239OsAQ-WxA" hash="Yi5L-w">My dear sisters, it’s a privilege to meet with you here in the Tabernacle and to be part of a telecast to the rest of the Church. You represent the best of life, for you are the daughters of our Heavenly Father who reflect the rich blessings of gospel membership.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.p2" pid="zF5FG0bHFkOmz8VOPvW2Xw" hash="O4WRcQ">To all of us the word <span class="emphasis">homemaking</span> has great significance. To us as women a special mission has been given to be the homebuilders of the Church, the community, and the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.p3" pid="mYT94tL3SEG18OpqsBYMRA" hash="4BZUOQ">Speaking at a Relief Society conference, President J. Reuben Clark said, “May God … give you the vision of the true homemaker, that you will be able to save by this course, not alone Zion, but the world. And that is your destiny … to save the world.” (<span class="emphasis">Relief Society Magazine,</span> Dec. 1949, p. 798.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.p4" pid="3bjObDoPF0qRhfkrtqduyw" hash="7VOlOA">The work of women, then, takes on a deep and significant meaning. The daily business of homemaking becomes very important—in fact, the most important business in the world. A home is more than a house or a room to live in. For one person making a home for herself, or for the mother of a large family, the home should be a place of learning, a place where prayer can point the way to eternal life. <span class="emphasis">That</span> is how the world will be saved—by strengthening every child of God in every home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.p5" pid="VCXBRTxXukmr_HQAhZVn9A" hash="28kaOw">In a revelation to the Prophet Joseph Smith, the Lord tells us, “Organize yourselves; prepare every needful thing; and establish a house, even a house of prayer, a house of fasting, a house of faith, a house of learning, a house of glory, a house of order, a house of God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.119" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:119</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.p6" pid="JBIfviUR8UeIkDb0KmkGSQ" hash="nH38mQ">As I ponder this admonition of the Lord, I am reminded of a special friend. As I have worked with her, I have been inspired by her devotion to her family and church. A large family and an invalid husband didn’t keep her from accepting a leadership responsibility in Relief Society. I asked her how she managed so well. She answered, “My Relief Society sisters help me. Their love lifts my spirit when I feel down; the lessons give me strength and direction. My problems don’t seem so big when they are shared.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.p7" pid="RcBKeyndOkeNaOpQuVLATQ" hash="pXuLqw">She set a pattern for her day, starting with an early morning prayer while the rest of her family slept. She organized in her mind the duties to be performed that day and asked her Heavenly Father for his help in accomplishing them. Each day ended with a grateful report as she expressed her appreciation and love to her Father in Heaven for his help and the help of kind friends. She felt she could not have accomplished the day’s tasks alone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.p8" pid="373wXMc65k-MFFit86VXfA" hash="BKvxaA">What an example this mother has been to her family! She has taught them the power of prayer, the value of being organized, and the joy that comes from serving others and the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.p9" pid="DaQ4fAI_VkaxTDBT3lAEuA" hash="tsSMJA">Referring again to the revelation, the Lord admonishes us to prepare every <span class="emphasis">needful</span> thing. Many Latter-day Saint women find great joy in developing their creative talents as they prepare needful things. Sewing for children, grandchildren, and friends unites families in love and appreciation. A mother of eight confided in me recently that her family could not have some of the necessities of life if she did not sew their clothing. She had even learned to make levis and T-shirts in a Relief Society miniclass and to remodel outgrown clothing for younger members of the family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.p10" pid="bx3_f5jgWkqjkIEsip1OxA" hash="nVMUTg">Another needful thing is the food we eat. President Kimball has repeatedly admonished us to have gardens and to preserve what we grow. In our homemaking book we are given help not only for planting gardens, but for collecting seeds to insure next year’s planting. Suggestions are given for miniclasses on using your basic storage every day. How many ways do you use the powdered milk you have stored? Homemaking miniclasses can show you many ways, such as doubling the amount of margarine by adding milk.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.p11" pid="IqK39xeYS0KMrZgrDohSdg" hash="KM9kZA">Recently I went to a Relief Society meeting in a Brigham Young University ward. The girls were being taught breadmaking in a miniclass. The fragrance from the kitchen attracted the young men in the building, and as they gathered around the door looking hungry, hot bread, butter, and honey were soon being enjoyed by all as they socialized together.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.p12" pid="XticIHhZg0WPAMDmVv012Q" hash="IlrwaQ">In our meeting a year ago, President Spencer W. Kimball admonished us to be different from the women of the world “in happy ways” (see <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1979, p. 104).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.p13" pid="0AC4myfGDUCGsNV1MLFDNQ" hash="CE5i5Q">Nephi writes of his people in the wilderness sowing, reaping, and working to set their homes in order. Then he continues, “And it came to pass that we lived after the manner of happiness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/5.27" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 5:27</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.p14" pid="DVbcsm-5-k6hPGdH6gB-Xg" hash="LD8APA">As Latter-day Saint homebuilders, our greatest challenge is to bring up our children in light and truth—to develop the spiritual nature of each family member. Our greatest role is as a teacher.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.p15" pid="UbT2lhqy1ECRCXeBnXKteA" hash="y7vYqA">“Home,” said President Harold B. Lee, quoting from a newspaper editorial, “is the seminary of all other institutions” (<span class="emphasis">Relief Society Magazine,</span> Jan. 1965, p. 9). The multifaceted nature of the home finds expression in a new focus given to the stake board structure. Included now in the concept of homemaking is music and the enrichment it brings to the home; the nursery, complete with materials that have been prepared according to the finest of child development principles; and recreation with its binding, health-giving contribution. Relief Society homemaking includes all of these elements, combining them into a day of training, preparing women to make a home that embodies skills, refinement, knowledge, and delight along with the love and warmth that have always meant home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.p16" pid="KLLiBBNawky0PYd43g5s_g" hash="dqki2w">In order to help every Latter-day Saint woman realize her full potential as a homemaker, we urge homemaking counselors to plan meetings that will meet the needs of each sister. We know that no two sisters have situations that are alike, and yet we hope that each will find purpose and fulfillment in creating a place that is home. One well-planned, two-hour, monthly meeting can provide the training and motivation that will enable each woman to succeed in her most essential work, which gives heart to all other work of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.p17" pid="1M2AUZ5Fhka7XFaITthHgw" hash="iEdhvA">In well-ordered homes we must keep bright the spark of testimony and build faith within each heart. Through Relief Society we can learn how to organize ourselves and prepare every needful thing and how to establish a house of prayer, a house of fasting, a house of faith, a house of learning, a house of order, a house of God (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.19" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:19</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves.p18" pid="ESXa4iIBrke5u3_SyQHTug" hash="CNs0yg">May we make our homes havens of peace and happiness where all enjoy being together—and like Nephi’s people live after a manner of happiness—is my prayer, and I ask it in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1980/10/organize-yourselves</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/1980-general-relief-society-meeting/1980-09-0060-marian-r-boyer-64k-eng.mp3" length="3951797" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 1980 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relief Society in Welfare</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The roots of Relief Society in welfare lie at its very founding, for it was at the first meeting that the Prophet Joseph Smith admonished the sisters to  after objects of charity and  to their wants.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03141_000_042" doc-version="2" hash="NINl0g">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="krcq42_aRkWAoTTZBwOcYw" hash="p1cwug">Relief Society in Welfare</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="xZNTxxJvBECOx5Nf8i2jSQ" hash="GjDzLg">Marian R. Boyer</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.t1">
			<img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2d6e.jpg" alt="Marian R. Boyer" pid="BRSBf5gmk0iIo6Y_0iHVDg" hash="dFF2SQ" />
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p1" pid="xMHNhG5OT0ePikpxqV-aSQ" hash="e_VGyA">The roots of Relief Society in welfare lie at its very founding, for it was at the first meeting that the Prophet Joseph Smith admonished the sisters to <span class="emphasis">search</span> after objects of charity and <span class="emphasis">minister</span> to their wants.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p2" pid="zonzO5lDIUKEWxNHwCydOA" hash="fcDEVA">How well they accepted the charge is reflected in a report of the Nauvoo “Necessity Committee” on August 5, 1843:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p3" pid="zPwXJkkR_E-UwgPmVOPCkQ" hash="mNOKvg">“Sister Jones, Sister Mecham and myself have visited our ward—went to every house, <span class="emphasis">found</span> many sick. … <span class="emphasis">Found</span> Sister Miller, an old lady, sick without bed or bedding, no changes of clothing. <span class="emphasis">Found</span> Sister Broomley very sick, nothing at all to eat.” (Amy Brown Lyman, comp., Minutes of the General Board of Relief Society, 1842–1892, p. 72.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p4" pid="I_57iXYi8kiLCwBKelMxlw" hash="QbIPLQ">The sisters rose one by one and offered the needed donations. Sister Woolley would give “one yard of fine muslin, a flannel petticoat … , 60 cents … , Sister German, “a suit of clothes [for] old [Sister] Miller.” (Ibid.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p5" pid="aWRgpgHYOEeEWhe0ftM7hg" hash="utyDsg">A young Nauvoo widow with several children, Sister Ellen Douglas, gives a glimpse of the early Relief Society ministrations in a letter dated April 14, 1844, to her parents in England:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p6" pid="g0_hNSVWOEGC6vmfjZdQuw" hash="Cf71_g">“I was taken very ill. … Sometimes I thot I should die and then I thot of my poor children. I prayed for their sakes that I might live. I didn’t pray alone, but many of my brothers and sisters prayed likewise and our prayers were answered.” (Kate B. Carter, comp., <span class="emphasis">Our Pioneer Heritage,</span> Salt Lake City: Daughters of Utah Pioneers, 1960, 3:159.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p7" pid="x68cy7R2Zk2SssY0zWB2Og" hash="OeWZYw">After Sister Douglas began to recover, she visited a friend who suggested she “make application to the female Relief Society for some clothing which I needed for myself and family. … I [reluctantly] agreed and we went to one of the sisters [of the Society]. … I told her … while I was sick my children wore out their clothes because I could not mend them, so she said she would do the best she could for me. … In a few days … they brought a wagon and fetched me such a present as I never received before from no place in the world.” (Ibid.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p8" pid="9WQ6CdbrQkKdS9FIPlLhEA" hash="cTPrjw">In the Salt Lake Valley, the sisters continued their ministrations—sometimes in dramatic ways—as Sister Lucy Meserve Smith, wife of Elder George A. Smith, recalls in her Reminiscences. News of the approach of a handcart company came to President Brigham Young as he was conducting October conference in the old Tabernacle. She stated:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p9" pid="iZTZmy403kS_TqUg2W-DwQ" hash="5wUVIQ">“President Young and others were [so] excited and anxious for fear those companies would be caught in the snows in the mountains [that] they could not go on with the Conference. The president called for men, teams, clothing and provisions. … The sisters stripped off their petticoats, stockings, and every thing they could spare, right there … and piled [them] into the wagons to send to the Saints in the mountains.” (Reminiscences of Lucy Meserve Smith, MS, 1886, Historical Department, The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, Salt Lake City.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p10" pid="G2tiFbgkeEWUogrrV1dkvQ" hash="AdrcwQ">Other conditions and other times in the history of the Church created other challenges and responses and <span class="emphasis">new</span> frontiers for Relief Society in welfare work. <span class="emphasis">Today is such a time.</span>
			</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p11" pid="9tkFGeGocU-56HPeu2r6Zw" hash="AXUe5w">The poor are still with us. There are refugees, the homeless. There is an ever increasing number of the aged. There are those without work, the sick, the bereaved, the poor in spirit, those with personal problems and burdens that press upon them. Even in our urban society, more and more suffer from feelings of isolation. There is no social ill that hasn’t in some way affected us, bringing the need for succor and prevention.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p12" pid="go_EWTSKDE23QW0vRod7GA" hash="r1QIjg">So, what is, or what shall be, Relief Society’s response as an organization? as leaders? as individual members of Relief Society?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p13" pid="-HYfojl350yTXDJoERw5ag" hash="O4V9og">Though the problems of our day are enormous, we have excellent resources with which to solve them. In addition to the million and one-half women members—Relief Society’s greatest asset—the organization itself is one of the most important Church welfare resources. <span class="emphasis">First,</span> because its chief purposes have always been welfare-related. <span class="emphasis">Second,</span> because in its curriculum, welfare principles are taught, and sisters are provided a laboratory experience that trains them in personal and family preparedness, in parenting, and in homemaking. <span class="emphasis">Third,</span> because the organization is a structure through which the prescribed welfare program of the Church is carried out. <span class="emphasis">Fourth,</span> because it is a fast, effective means of providing women volunteers for welfare.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p14" pid="qTaL1qHeZ0eSceJ5mXuB1g" hash="D5vAQw">To illustrate, after the collapse of the South Vietnamese government, many refugees were sent in 1975 to the United States.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p15" pid="QI3wpafIv02Yn2eYlxFUdw" hash="exy99g">“As the first group came into the Presidio Army Base in San Francisco, Relief Society sisters in that area were called during the night to come to the base [to] help wash, feed, and put clean clothes on the children. The Relief Society sisters began arriving at 4:00 <small>A.M.</small> and worked all day, giving immunization shots.” (<span class="emphasis">Relief Society Courses of Study 1979–80,</span> Salt Lake City: The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, 1978, p. 42.) These sisters treated infections, comforting and ministering to the homeless children.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p16" pid="E26UKB_GVESkBMd5lCvQaQ" hash="ztsn8g">As an organization, Relief Society provides a network through which <span class="emphasis">every</span> woman can be quickly reached in times of disaster. In the Teton Dam disaster of 1976, calls for needed volunteer help went from nearby stake Relief Society presidents to ward presidents, to visiting teaching supervisors, to visiting teachers, to sisters who responded willingly. Thus, in a very short time, the needed help was recruited.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p17" pid="Fvixugi_DEuGrvOYiNU3_g" hash="Wnmezw">Another important resource for dealing with welfare problems is informed, compassionate Relief Society leaders.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p18" pid="a9kSPZMgQE-UkFHFvJesZg" hash="3mmivw">When a Relief Society president and her counselors attend welfare services committee meetings and contribute meaningfully to discussions, when they observe welfare needs of members and bring that information to the agendas of welfare meetings, when they help implement the action of welfare committees, they <span class="emphasis">are</span> carrying out the welfare objectives of the Society. A ward Relief Society president making a family-needs visit at the direction of the bishop <span class="emphasis">is</span> ministering to the needy. A president training visiting teachers to search out the poor and needy <span class="emphasis">is</span> following the Prophet’s instruction.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p19" pid="viP2uOlRXEyo5SE9K4AMjA" hash="aunmUA">Too often, needs go undiscovered because they are not readily observed. Ward Relief Society presidents, therefore, should instruct visiting teachers on how to recognize signs of depression, of loneliness, and of physical want.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p20" pid="1YpK0m2bmUuvL9LVQirnbw" hash="WiApWQ">One pair of sensitive visiting teachers visited the young family of a recently graduated dental student. The family had, through self-sacrifice and stringent budgeting, endured the hard years of schooling required of the husband. As the sisters visited the mother the noticed that the soles of the shoes of the young children playing on the floor were completely worn through and would give scant protection to their little feet. This was confidentially reported to the Relief Society president, and the parents were persuaded to accept a little help until the young father could begin earning.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p21" pid="Yqa7esfb_kuLO9u5K42TRw" hash="yl5_Bg">Of all the ways Relief Society furthers the welfare cause, its best effort comes as it helps <span class="emphasis">individual</span> sisters anticipate and meet their <span class="emphasis">own</span> needs, for welfare problems are most effectively solved before they <span class="emphasis">become</span> problems. Therefore, when you, the individual member, put into daily practice the principles of welfare, you are <span class="emphasis">personally</span> reducing the woe of the world. When you add to your home storage, particularly with goods you have produced by your hands, in your garden, with your needle, or in your kitchen, you are addressing welfare needs in the most effective way. When preventive health care, good nutrition, and financial management are practiced by you, the individual sister, the welfare system <span class="emphasis">is</span> working. When you teach your children how to work—when you, as members, and your children become educated and engage in appropriate employment and careers—future problems are averted.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p22" pid="7wyHkGUbFkukNG86ijYSkw" hash="02a23A">The emotional support and strength that you Relief Society sisters can provide one another can be as important, or more so, than food or shelter. The husband of a sister recently lost his job. In relating the experience, she said the family was financially somewhat prepared, in that they had food storage and some money saved. But they were <span class="emphasis">not</span> prepared for the emotional shock of unemployment. The wife recalled that the single greatest help the family received to lessen the trauma of that experience was the love and sympathetic concern shown by the sisters of Relief Society.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p23" pid="QP1cLlYKIUuEhH4jsDMMfg" hash="Oe3X0w">In a Spiritual Living lesson a few years ago (1979–80, p. 42), we were told, “Fear that we haven’t enough energy, money, or other means can keep us from giving love.” We may think, “We can’t feed all the hungry, lodge all the homeless, nor comfort all who grieve … ; therefore, [we] will help no one.” (Ibid.) But Alma has told us that “by small and simple things are great things brought to pass.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.6" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:6</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p24" pid="hg6QrXj1REW9m1JBODmmWQ" hash="dS7r5Q">One dollar given for a welfare assessment or a fast offering, one day of volunteer service, a visit (even without the loaf of bread), multiplied by a million and one-half members, can relieve much suffering.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p25" pid="a9z_hmwcvUWZSuTI_WrQaQ" hash="fiaBtQ">Thus, though frontiers of welfare needs stretch before us different in scope from those of 1842, but similar too, the challenge for Relief Society today remains as then: to <span class="emphasis">search</span> out the poor, to <span class="emphasis">minister</span> to their wants, to <span class="emphasis">prevent</span> problems by learning, teaching, and practicing the principles of welfare. The Lord spoke plainly when he told Joseph Smith:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p26" pid="LxyOlt8diU2H0LPFfPgQIw" hash="nw4sSQ">“And remember in all things the poor and the needy, the sick and the afflicted, for he that doeth not these things, the same is not my disciple.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/52.40" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 52:40</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare.p27" pid="tUIvQRAD6kKGz_tDMH4AbQ" hash="Al4Umw">I ask it in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1981/10/relief-society-in-welfare</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-relief-society-meeting/1981-general-relief-society-meeting/1981-09-0040-marian-r-boyer-64k-eng.mp3" length="7884736" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 1981 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
