<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Marlin K. Jensen</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Marlin K. Jensen.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Marlin%20K.%20Jensen.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Marlin K. Jensen.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1989 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1989 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>“An Eye Single to the Glory of God”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Brothers and sisters, I am grateful for the opportunity to greet all of you and to tell you how thankful I am to have been called as a member of the First Quorum of the Seventy. My wife, Kathy, says she always knew I would receive a life sentence of </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03245_000_012" doc-version="2" hash="sqo-Zw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="r4BKLEhzJ06bRRRgQraUzw" hash="NJ5Xcw">“An Eye Single to the Glory of God”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="wm6xZObAmUaEbpLpWU6vAg" hash="Z8S8og">Marlin K. Jensen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e68.jpg" alt="Elder Marlin K. Jensen" pid="7yrdfuaJOEu7iFMipGQuQA" hash="IjwVbw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p1" pid="5wVXE51joU2r83u5JAKEaw" hash="sgW-jQ">Brothers and sisters, I am grateful for the opportunity to greet all of you and to tell you how thankful I am to have been called as a member of the First Quorum of the Seventy. My wife, Kathy, says she always knew I would receive a life sentence of some type, but neither of us dreamed it would be something so rewarding!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p2" pid="AAI5XETePkC8ve48VwaboA" hash="2SIczA">No one can stand at this pulpit for the first time—where so many truly great men and women have stood over the years—without experiencing a strong sense of his personal inadequacy and an overwhelming desire to express appreciation. I feel both today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p3" pid="UndzSgTLDU6z2qtd3ZHrmw" hash="wRqamg">I want to express appreciation to my friends and neighbors in the little mountain valley where I was born and where I have chosen to live my life thus far—also, to my noble ancestors and my living extended family. I am constantly aware of their goodness and their interest in me. I sincerely thank my parents, who continue to work on a project that began at my birth forty-seven years ago. I am especially indebted to my companion. Her support, love, and cheerful disposition make my life very enjoyable. She would want you to know of her own strong conviction of the truthfulness of the restored gospel. Together we have been blessed with eight delightful children, whose development and happiness are our primary concerns. I love each one of them very much.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p4" pid="EASLB6PwuUaozKRE73J0Ng" hash="64flGw">I am also very grateful for the blessing of daily association with the General Authorities of the Church. I pledge to these dedicated men my loyalty, my love, and my untiring efforts in building up God’s kingdom. I promise them also that I will always heed the Lord’s admonition contained in the Doctrine and Covenants: “Therefore, strengthen your brethren in all your conversation, in all your prayers, in all your exhortations, and in all your doings.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/108.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 108:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p5" pid="GZkmAuy8lk-ZtGnsI0D5LQ" hash="wg6XJg">Finally, I am very grateful for each of you, my brothers and sisters all over the world, who have come to a knowledge of the Redeemer and are part of His Church. I appreciate your goodness and devotion and look forward to meeting you and serving at your side in the years ahead. With you, in the words of the Apostle Paul, I am humbled to know that “neither death, nor life, nor angels, nor principalities, nor powers, nor things present, nor things to come,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p6" pid="EC-aUDZvKEOFzqBsJq2U3w" hash="tJz9XA">“Nor height, nor depth, nor any other creature, shall be able to separate us from the love of God, which is in Christ Jesus our Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/8.38-39" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 8:38–39</a>.) For this knowledge I am most grateful of all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p7" pid="0XFdhKqJ102VcyWPldGnKg" hash="YedZFw">As I have searched the scriptures in recent months for guidance in my new calling, I have become aware of the importance to our eternal welfare of our motives, our desires, and our attitudes. I speak of one of these today: the necessity of performing our earthly labors with “an eye single to the glory of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/4.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 4:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p8" pid="rifTKT4E-kGSsfJH_8lG6g" hash="YrOpGw">The temptation to seek personal recognition and reward from our service to others is ever-present. The pattern was established in the pre-earth life by Satan himself. There, when the Father explained His plan of salvation for the inhabitants of this earth and the need for a redeemer, Satan responded by saying: “Behold, here am I, send me, I will be thy son, and I will redeem all mankind, that one soul shall not be lost, and surely I will do it; wherefore give me thine honor.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/4.1" class="scriptureRef">Moses 4:1</a>.) In contrast, Christ showed us for all time that God’s work is to be done with an attitude of <span class="emphasis">Thine,</span> not <span class="emphasis">mine.</span> Said He: “Father, thy will be done, and the glory be thine forever.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/4.2" class="scriptureRef">Moses 4:2</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p9" pid="Shfk1SLkYUuQphArCTNqmQ" hash="C0JmIA">Those who seek honor and gain for themselves in doing the Lord’s work are guilty of what the scriptures call priestcrafts. Of this sin, Nephi stated: “Priestcrafts are that men preach and set themselves up for a light unto the world, that they may get gain and praise of the world; but they seek not the welfare of Zion.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/26.29" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 26:29</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p10" pid="2E9lwG7BOkyiH4JUSHO6Bw" hash="tlR-qw">Latter-day Saints whose eyes are single to God’s glory see life from a vastly different perspective than those whose attention is directed elsewhere. Such members, for instance, care little about receiving credit or recognition for their good deeds. They are more interested in feeding the Lord’s sheep than in counting them. In fact, they frequently find their greatest happiness in serving anonymously, thereby leaving the beneficiaries of their kindness with no one to thank or praise except the Lord. In this regard, we can perhaps learn a lesson from our Christian brothers and sisters in the Amish communities of Pennsylvania. It is reported that their writers frequently compose and publish poetry and religious literature anonymously, so as to deflect attention from themselves and ensure that only God receives the glory.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p11" pid="SJHmsIPmD0O9fpxJa5dLmw" hash="E3CiWA">There is something particularly noble about the good works of those who act without restraint or compulsion and with no expectation of reward or recognition. Their goodness has its source in the “desires of their hearts” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/41.3" class="scriptureRef">Alma 41:3</a>) and is the result of pure motives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p12" pid="2Uy0W4zEtkyOZE9ckf4TxQ" hash="K6zULA">Our second-youngest daughter illustrated this principle in a simple way a year or so ago when she was three. Without special occasion, except the joy of doing something nice for someone, she hid a tasty bedtime treat under my pillow. When I thanked her and asked her the next morning why she had done such a good deed, she said, “Just because I love you, Daddy—just because I love you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p13" pid="PSJvQ_jEHUefoLDFnRCGVQ" hash="DtLVjA">Considerations of church position and title are also of little consequence to Latter-day Saints whose eyes are directed toward God’s glory. Their concern is focused on the opportunities for service that church callings present, rather than on gaining personal notoriety. Such members, who serve competently and quietly, regardless of whether they are the “highest” or the “least” in the kingdom, are probably those that the Apostle Paul had in mind when he wrote, “And those members of the body [meaning the Church], which we think to be less honourable, upon these we bestow more abundant honour.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/12.23" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 12:23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p14" pid="pQT6qoEh40mX43UtvPvRKg" hash="WAgKOA">The merit of rendering faithful service, regardless of one’s position in the Church, was tenderly brought to my attention several years ago during the funeral service of a man who had done much good in his life without ever being recognized with a high church office. I was touched as I heard the deceased’s brother-in-law describe him as a man who had never served as an elders quorum president, as a bishop, or as a stake president, but who “had made a lot of them look awfully good.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p15" pid="Odm5NvVrWESgFjikf2LdSg" hash="YtXQnw">All of us who have observed a loving Primary nursery leader ministering patiently to her flock of two-year-olds or who have felt the gentle spirit of those wonderful white-haired men and women who faithfully serve in the temples of the Lord, will understand perfectly the Savior’s comment: “For he that is least among you all, the same shall be great.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/9.48" class="scriptureRef">Luke 9:48</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p16" pid="xnd0cG_v3Ee-33FbrNHrKQ" hash="yvup5w">When our eyes are fixed on God’s glory, we feel the majesty of His creations and the grand scope of His work on this earth. We feel humble to be participants in His latter-day kingdom. If we pause and quietly reflect on our role in all of this, we will come to know that placing our egos and our vain ambitions on the sacrificial altar is one of the most important offerings we can ever make. Well might we acknowledge, as did Moses after beholding in vision God’s glory: “Now, for this cause I know that man is nothing, which thing I never had supposed.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.10" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p17" pid="gjjIM1erWEmWr5o7RiNdng" hash="3WV7Zg">Paul demonstrated a similar attitude and recognition in his first letter to the Corinthians, in which he asks rhetorically,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p18" pid="3lzGhhAYNEOeFwG5o9Jp4g" hash="DH9jWA">“Who then is Paul, and who is Apollos, but ministers by whom ye believed, even as the Lord gave to every man?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p19" pid="c8Kn4MjmGUK-m0Kwf5Yd4A" hash="5soggA">“I have planted, Apollos watered; but God gave the increase.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p20" pid="g9YbVT0tqUqdIZtIDUYyBw" hash="MRRC3A">“So then neither is he that planteth any thing, neither he that watereth; but God that giveth the increase.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/3.5-7" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 3:5–7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p21" pid="BX43w_-PbkS5ZKLwc1gIrw" hash="ghMvmg">Brothers and sisters, I testify that The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is God’s kingdom on the earth today. This kingdom will roll forward with or without us as individuals. Men and women who even momentarily take their eyes off of God’s glory and seek to exalt themselves, or who become entangled in the vain things of this world, will find that the kingdom quickly moves on without them. Unfortunately, none of us is immune from this all-too-human tendency. In the final dramatic hours of the Savior’s life, even His Apostles—those stalwart men who certainly should have known better—argued with one another about who should be accounted the greatest. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/22.24" class="scriptureRef">Luke 22:24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p22" pid="bSd17DtU3US4PGTDq747oQ" hash="sNjIWA">To those faithful Latter-day Saints whose view of their own importance in God’s plan is in perspective, the Lord has promised: “And if your eye be single to my glory, your whole bodies shall be filled with light, and there shall be no darkness in you; and that body which is filled with light comprehendeth all things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p23" pid="gMVPmTKFuEO2dBe6Hk9c9Q" hash="eZReDQ">“Therefore, sanctify yourselves that your minds become single to God, and the days will come that you shall see him; for he will unveil his face unto you, and it shall be in his own time, and in his own way, and according to his own will.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.67-68" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:67–68</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god.p24" pid="nGJBVxzvM0ykQPuVkdVL4g" hash="iL88FA">Of these truths I testify, adding my own humble witness of the reality and goodness of God and His Son. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1989/10/an-eye-single-to-the-glory-of-god</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1989-general-conference/1989-10-2050-elder-marlin-k-jensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="4825344" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1989 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of a Good Life</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Brethren, I am grateful to be a part of this vast assembly of priesthood bearers. I am also especially mindful of a wonderful little band of missionaries with whom my wife and I are currently blessed to labor in the New York Rochester Mission. Speaki</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_94905_000_022" doc-version="2" hash="QfUG4g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="gp5SDCLJy0yd_Y84yYJ2Ng" hash="VbeHvw">The Power of a Good Life</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="T7HU0IK3ikKFl2Vnw7YSdg" hash="Z8S8og">Marlin K. Jensen</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e68.jpg" alt="Elder Marlin K. Jensen" pid="nmcD4yMdZEC0zIGXorOdyQ" hash="IjwVbw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p1" pid="Z0wE20eXIUWfTUGry5pOkg" hash="85IYDg">Brethren, I am grateful to be a part of this vast assembly of priesthood bearers. I am also especially mindful of a wonderful little band of missionaries with whom my wife and I are currently blessed to labor in the New York Rochester Mission. Speaking perhaps for all mission presidents and the missionaries’ parents, I wish to say during my temporary absence from them, “Please work hard, drive carefully, and be good!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p2" pid="EIwQL5tRnkGlmZWVhDs5Qg" hash="m8YWwQ">All of us who hold the priesthood of God are involved in a glorious common cause—helping our Father in Heaven bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man (see <a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>). This task, in its simplest form, involves qualifying ourselves for the blessings of the Savior’s atonement and helping others to do the same.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p3" pid="0Vx1h9nna0CTYZ7V3h_8UQ" hash="6MAW2g">Over the years as I have struggled with my own weaknesses and have tried in my way to help others overcome theirs, I have received assistance and motivation from a variety of sources. Personal prayer, my knowledge of an interested, loving Father in Heaven and His Plan of Salvation, the scriptures, the temple, and the promptings of the Holy Ghost have been especially helpful. However, even more immediate than these in some ways have been the influence and inspiration provided by the lives of noble people. I am ever impressed and deeply moved by the power of even one good life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p4" pid="IIvxyiAXbUm5B9SCR5Tw2A" hash="XuluRQ">From among many exemplary lives in our rich history as a people, I wish to share examples from just two. The first is from the life of the Prophet Joseph Smith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p5" pid="AsXdmYiPJEmpW4whhqB0mA" hash="HR8dnw">During a bitter winter of imprisonment in Richmond, Missouri, Joseph and some fifty other brethren were subjected to great hardship and exposure. One of their greatest trials was to endure the blasphemies and filthy language of their guards as they boasted of their unspeakable cruelty to the Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p6" pid="dSHo0fQS4UuvxfljPcNvqA" hash="7M69ZA">Of one particularly tedious night, Elder Parley P. Pratt wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p7" pid="bg9cP2lZAE--nRdZ5yFc_w" hash="TlTHXw">“I had listened till I became so disgusted, shocked, horrified, and so filled with the spirit of indignant justice that I could scarcely refrain from rising upon my feet and rebuking the guards; but had said nothing to Joseph, or any one else, although I lay next to him and knew he was awake. On a sudden he arose to his feet, and spoke in a voice of thunder, or as the roaring lion, uttering, as near as I can recollect, the following words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p8" pid="7GkVLqRxFkSSVX40-YiESQ" hash="7nxl2Q">“‘<span class="emphasis">SILENCE, ye fiends of the infernal pit. In the name of Jesus Christ I rebuke you, and command you to be still; I will not live another minute and hear such language. Cease such talk, or you or I die THIS INSTANT!’</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p9" pid="6UbfhN2f8keleJdS1LDmVw" hash="KQQRHg">“He ceased to speak. He stood erect in terrible majesty. Chained, and without a weapon; calm, unruffled and dignified as an angel, he looked upon the quailing guards, whose weapons were lowered or dropped to the ground; whose knees smote together, and who, shrinking into a corner, or crouching at his feet, begged his pardon, and remained quiet till a change of guards.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p10" pid="xGeAE1bOs0SBRhPyhFUCoQ" hash="M93UmQ">Elder Pratt continues:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p11" pid="Ba2ECF56ukuKtnXGnPpX3w" hash="DelD5Q">“I have seen the ministers of justice, clothed in magisterial robes, and criminals arraigned before them, while life was suspended on a breath, in the Courts of England; I have witnessed a Congress in solemn session to give laws to nations; I have tried to conceive of kings, of royal courts, of thrones and crowns; and of emperors assembled to decide the fate of kingdoms; but dignity and majesty have I seen but <span class="emphasis">once,</span> as it stood in chains, at midnight, in a dungeon in an obscure village of Missouri” (<span class="emphasis">Autobiography of Parley P. Pratt,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1985, pp. 210–11).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p12" pid="BZLd2K2f_0O32oP-QZw3iQ" hash="0sjlCg">Does not this image of the Prophet Joseph courageously rebuking the forces of evil move us to do likewise?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p13" pid="usJCUtkxIUGXf74_wz_EzA" hash="u0WZ0Q">The second example is from the life of Willard Bean, a remarkable man who became known as the “fighting parson.” In the spring of 1915, Willard and his new bride, Rebecca, were called by President Joseph F. Smith to serve a mission for “five years or longer” in Palmyra, New York. (Vicki Bean Topliff, <span class="emphasis">Willard Bean, “The Fighting Parson”,</span> Huntington Beach, California, 1981, p. 87. For the account of their life in Palmyra, see pp. 86–131.) Their task was to occupy the recently acquired Joseph Smith home and farm and to reestablish the Church in the hostile environment which still existed at the time in Palmyra.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p14" pid="QK8a_0u6uEageQSjpvNwRw" hash="JtUwdA">The Beans were rebuffed on every front as they settled into the Smith home. The townspeople would not speak to them or wait on them in their stores. Passersby would pause in front of the home and shout obscenities. Their children were assigned to sit in the back corners of the schoolroom and were shunned by the other children in class.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p15" pid="bRXGxEQ9sE-StxDoAK4PQQ" hash="y9fkNw">Willard, who was an accomplished athlete and had been a prize-winning boxer, decided to improve public relations by putting on a boxing exhibition in Palmyra. A ring was set up in an old opera house, and the “fighting parson” challenged all comers to a boxing match.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p16" pid="oULE--RsE0yF6cU5q7pWMQ" hash="8bbjww">When the night of the exhibition arrived, the toughest men in Palmyra sat in the first few rows. One by one they entered the ring, only to be carried out again in a matter of seconds! This continued until the seventh challenger was similarly disposed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p17" pid="t73yhpGimEOiG4QrSB9B3g" hash="hfCmxA">Brother Bean’s fighting abilities were more spontaneously employed on another occasion as he walked along the unfriendly streets of Palmyra. A man watering his front lawn one afternoon suddenly turned the hose on Willard and taunted: “I understand you people believe in baptism by immersion.” The spry, athletic Willard reportedly vaulted over the fence separating them and replied, “Yes, and we also believe in the laying on of hands!” (<span class="emphasis">Willard Bean, “The Fighting Parson,”</span> p. 14.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p18" pid="AhdwNtBZqEi2xS5qyk24lw" hash="JPF54A">Although Brother Bean’s methods were a little unorthodox and definitely not compatible with the current approved missionary program of the Church, they were nonetheless effective. The people of Palmyra began begrudgingly to yield and to accept the Beans as the good people they were. In time, they were invited to participate in local churches and to join the civic organizations of the day. They established a branch of the Church and helped acquire the Hill Cumorah and the Martin Harris and Peter Whitmer farms. The “five years or longer” mission to which the prophet had called them stretched to nearly twenty-five years before it concluded. During that time, the attitude of the people of Palmyra had changed from hostility toward the Beans to toleration, then admiration, and finally to love. The power of good lives is truly great.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p19" pid="7BDV12JK_0aAlvPIMqeQ1g" hash="ANlH_w">I am personally greatly motivated by the modest written and oral traditions of my own fathers which have been handed down.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p20" pid="-33PZzOI30mtGABxgTh40A" hash="h_ocsw">For instance, as a young boy, my great-grandfather arose one Christmas morning with great anticipation and came down from the loft where he slept to inspect the stocking he had hung by the fireplace the previous night. To his dismay he found what was to constitute his entire Christmas that year—one piece of horehound candy! He was immediately faced with a weighty decision: Should he eat the candy in one glorious burst of flavor, or should he make it last? The scarcity of such delicacies apparently convinced him to make it last. He carefully licked the solitary piece of candy a few times and then wrapped it in tissue paper and hid it under his mattress. Each Sunday thereafter, following dinner, he retreated to his bed, retrieved his treasure, and enjoyed a few pleasurable licks. In that way he nursed the piece of candy through an entire year’s enjoyment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p21" pid="ew0kP4DrS0ar72T9SaIrGA" hash="Y0bmyA">This is obviously not an account of deeds of heroic proportions. And yet, in these times of overindulgence and excess, it is somehow very inspiring and strengthening to me to know that a little of my great-grandfather’s frugal blood flows in my own veins.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p22" pid="ZZWTbl0SS02uwLybA94LKA" hash="_Em5Qw">The Lord is surely aware of our need to feel the influence of good people. That may be one reason why He has established a pattern of companionships as we work together through the priesthood to serve Him and His children. That also may be why He has counseled that “if any man among you be strong in the Spirit, let him take with him him that is weak, that he may be edified in all meekness, that he may become strong also” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.106" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:106</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p23" pid="7gv1REgP80axDO_JOxWzhg" hash="mhoaUQ">I have personally experienced the benefit of such a priesthood apprenticeship. In my Aaronic Priesthood years, a man who this evening is a silver-haired stake patriarch became my “senior” home teaching companion. Under his wise tutelage, and in spite of considerable resistance on my part, I learned for the first time how to “warn, expound, exhort, and teach, and invite all to come unto Christ” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.59" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:59</a>). When the time later came at age nineteen for a full-time mission, I did not really need a missionary preparation course; I had had one! I thank God for the love and influence of such mentors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p24" pid="-_CdfqLjDUGJ9dHhhCRBJQ" hash="mPMC5Q">Before concluding, I hope you will pardon a personal reference to my own father and the power of his good life in mine. For a half century now I have benefited from his wisdom, his generosity, and his goodness. I am not sure I realized the full extent of his influence until recently as I prepared to return home following the final session of a stake conference to which I had been assigned. An elderly brother came up from the congregation to meet me. He thanked me for coming, and then, in obvious reference to the many times I must have quoted my father and referred to his teachings during the conference sessions, he said: “Brother Jensen, if you are ever assigned again to our stake, why don’t you just send your father!” My hope is that in some small way I will have a similar influence for lasting good in the lives of our own children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p25" pid="JZmQerbfA0yqbb_Ned2Xpg" hash="XjAr-w">The list of valiant people whose lives touch our own includes family members, missionary companions, friends, Church leaders, teachers, and associates from various walks of life. Some we know intimately and others only by reputation. Less obvious to most of us is the influence we may be having in the lives of others. This interaction, to me, is one of the reasons why a community of believing Latter-day Saints is a foundational element of the gospel. It also explains why we build meetinghouses rather than hermitages.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p26" pid="OZlvUquRV0mN4lnkXWsEFA" hash="2PiHkA">It is through the lives of good people that we at least in part become better acquainted with the greatest of all lives. When we see Christ’s image in the countenances of others, it helps us live to receive it in our own.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life.p27" pid="94hFndI4m0GS5rSTtXCuhw" hash="-Gcvzw">I thank God for the blessing of good people in all of our lives and pray that we may all in some small way serve that same purpose in the lives of others, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1994/04/the-power-of-a-good-life</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1994-general-conference/1994-04-3040-elder-marlin-k-jensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5194418" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 1994 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Friendship: A Gospel Principle</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle?lang=eng</link>
      <description>If we truly want to be tools in the hands of our Heavenly Father in bringing to pass His eternal purposes, we need only to be a friend.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_99260_000_027" doc-version="2" hash="ssTGZw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="jw1g_qd3Sk-Sw1l_Bvq79w" hash="Us5RFQ">Friendship:</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="U7lvyUwUnU6hlkZ8Qe0IwA" hash="O6kMdQ">A Gospel Principle</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="I84bChzJq0yVHDQ-yxuwyA" hash="Z8S8og">Marlin K. Jensen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="lpAyhy4tzk-lpbIsGpD6rg" hash="iZeDVQ">If we truly want to be tools in the hands of our Heavenly Father in bringing to pass His eternal purposes, we need only to be a friend.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-f07.jpg" alt="Elder Marlin K. Jensen" pid="zpi2flFgmEq_Tghqy_4gIw" hash="g-5cJQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle.p1" pid="RCSRhuzKo0yW53OmbuV47g" hash="7UB-jQ">Good morning, brothers and sisters. Although, candidly, one is never completely comfortable with an assignment like this, I do sincerely appreciate the opportunity to speak to all of you on this beautiful Easter morning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle.p2" pid="8QE9VGb0j0yFjd1lzlLo6A" hash="l2bNhw">My wise father once told me that if I listened carefully to what people talk about from the pulpit in church, I would know which principles of the gospel were of concern to them and those with which they might be struggling at any given time. Through the years, my father’s observation has caused me to be very careful in the choice of subjects about which I speak! Nevertheless, I have an admission to make today. Since President Gordon B. Hinckley shared with us the three fundamental needs every new member of the Church has for a friend, a responsibility, and nourishing by the good word of God, I have been personally concerned about my performance as a friend.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle.p3" pid="1OVf_gt55Eug6vGmFcAK8Q" hash="YeubCA">The Prophet Joseph Smith taught that “friendship is one of the grand fundamental principles of ‘Mormonism.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> That thought ought to inspire and motivate all of us because I feel that friendship is a fundamental need of our world. I think in all of us there is a profound longing for friendship, a deep yearning for the satisfaction and security that close and lasting relationships can give. Perhaps one reason the scriptures make little specific mention of the principle of friendship is because it should be manifest quite naturally as we live the gospel. In fact, if the consummate Christian attribute of charity has a first cousin, it is friendship. To paraphrase the Apostle Paul slightly, friendship “suffereth long, and is kind; [friendship] envieth not; … seeketh not her own, is not easily provoked, thinketh no evil; … [friendship] never faileth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle.p4" pid="l3-tBWix80SdjUpADqF7jw" hash="OgqJWg">Like so much of what is worthwhile in life, our needs for friendship are often best met in the home. If our children feel friendship within the family, with each other, and with parents, they will not be desperate for acceptance outside the family. I think one of life’s most satisfying accomplishments for my wife and me is to have lived long enough to see our children become good friends. It’s definitely a miracle that those in our family who in younger years occasionally threatened one another with serious bodily harm now seek out and genuinely enjoy each other’s friendship. Similarly, I think no finer compliment can be paid to parents than to have children say that their parents are among their best friends.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle.p5" pid="uXWjhzuZ306BaC3o92Ch-g" hash="KF8inA">Friendship is also a vital and wonderful part of courtship and marriage. A relationship between a man and a woman that begins with friendship and then ripens into romance and eventually marriage will usually become an enduring, eternal friendship. Nothing is more inspiring in today’s world of easily dissolved marriages than to observe a husband and wife quietly appreciating and enjoying each other’s friendship year in and year out as they experience together the blessings and trials of mortality. A recently published report on 25 years of landmark marital research finds that “the linchpin of a lasting marriage … is a simple concept with a profound impact: friendship.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> In a poignant letter written by the Prophet Joseph Smith to his wife, Emma, during the separations and tribulations of Missouri, he comforted her by saying, “Oh my affectionate Emma, I want you to remember that I am a true and faithful friend, to you and the children, forever.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle.p6" pid="rY76KgyP2EWI5HcooDoMrQ" hash="mHtqhQ">The inspired organization of the Church also fosters friendships. From our youngest to our oldest years we are in settings where friendship and sociality can flourish. In interviews, meetings, classes, quorums, councils, activities, and a variety of other opportunities for association, we can make friends and find understanding. The salutation prescribed for greeting the elders attending the School of the Prophets in Kirtland expresses the spirit of friendship that might well serve as a creed for each of us: “I receive you to fellowship, in a determination that is fixed, immovable, and unchangeable, to be your friend … through the grace of God in the bonds of love.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle.p7" pid="Ik_YIUa6hUOqGF1CfVcmWg" hash="dkHvQg">All of our interactions in the Church are made more enjoyable and productive when they are accompanied by genuine feelings of friendship. A teacher of the gospel, for instance, who doesn’t befriend his or her students will seldom teach with lasting influence and effect. I still treasure a one-sentence entry in my high school yearbook in which a seminary teacher I loved and from whom I learned much told me he was grateful to be my friend.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle.p8" pid="hjJoxKLwgUOU0jYX4DvzWQ" hash="se8FoA">A bishop, no matter how skilled in administrative matters, must be a friend to children, youth, and adults if he is to help them reach their spiritual potential. I was touched once when a young woman I knew went to her bishop to confess a serious transgression. She had been worried about how the bishop might react to her deviation from the gospel path and had only gone to him after considerable urging. When I asked her afterward what his response had been, she told me with great emotion that her bishop had wept with her and that in working with him to gain the Lord’s forgiveness, she now considered her bishop to be one of her best friends.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle.p9" pid="vCvPzVnheE6F4kI3jbFhlg" hash="tkjm4w">There is a particular challenge we face as Latter-day Saints in establishing and maintaining friendships. Because our commitment to marriage, family, and the Church is so strong, we often feel challenged by constraints of time and energy in reaching out in friendship to others beyond that core group. I experienced this dilemma personally in recent days as I tried to steal a few moments at home to prepare this talk. Twice, friends from my past, whom I love dearly but see only occasionally, dropped in to visit. During what ought to have been choice times of reunion and reminiscence, I ironically found myself growing inwardly impatient for the visits to end so that I could get back to writing my talk about friendship!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle.p10" pid="CSDcHjylnUOhMLCoUtuKSg" hash="4bWhyQ">I have since felt ashamed. How selfish we can be. How unwilling to be inconvenienced, to give, to bless and be blessed. What kind of parents or neighbors or servants of the Lord Jesus Christ can we be without being a friend? In this information age, is not friendship still the best technology for sharing the truths and way of life we cherish? Is not our reluctance voluntarily to reach out to others in friendship a significant obstacle to helping God accomplish His eternal purposes?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle.p11" pid="9THpYF0fbUGpkFWFOipxcw" hash="3rJasQ">Years ago when I was serving as a bishop, a recently converted family moved into our rural Utah community. These good people had joined the Church in the eastern United States and had been warmly fellowshipped and put to work in a small branch there. When they came to our larger, more-established ward, they somehow slipped through the cracks. Some of the family members, particularly the father, became disenchanted with the Church and its members.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle.p12" pid="G5pgUz3A0kq9QVxxNpwpFg" hash="L--MBQ">One Sunday morning when I noticed the father was missing from priesthood meeting, I left the meetinghouse and drove to his home. He invited me in, and we had a very honest conversation about the struggle he was having with his new faith and neighbors. After exploring various possibilities for responding to his concerns, none of which seemed to appeal to him very much, I asked him with a tone of frustration in my voice just what we could do to help him. I’ve never forgotten his reply:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle.p13" pid="_oGXmIoNCEqCk9bj8SuIuQ" hash="84GM4g">“Well, bishop,” he said (and I will need to paraphrase here slightly), “for heaven’s sake, whatever you do, please don’t <span class="emphasis">assign</span> me a friend.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle.p14" pid="nbuvqgQDQ0yYZ9mhId5GwQ" hash="6_mx9w">I learned a great lesson that day. No one wants to become a “project”; we all want spontaneously to be loved. And, if we are to have friends, we want them to be genuine and sincere, not “assigned.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle.p15" pid="mjUYxS5CDkWTjR7EwIXcnQ" hash="BZPe8Q">Brothers and sisters, my message today is very simple: if we truly want to be tools in the hands of our Heavenly Father in bringing to pass His eternal purposes, we need only to be a friend. Consider the power of each one of us, 10 million strong, of our own free will and choice reaching out to those not yet of our faith in unconditional friendship. We would no longer be accused of offering warm bread and a cold shoulder. Imagine the consequences for good if each active family in the Church offered consistent concern and genuine friendship to a less-active family or a new-member family. The power is in each one of us to be a friend. Old and young, rich and poor, educated and humble, in every language and country, we all have the capacity to be a friend.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle.p16" pid="JRM0I-wlK0iim8JNAIu29A" hash="sHEs0g">Our Savior, shortly before His Crucifixion, said to His disciples: “Greater love hath no man than this, that a man lay down his life for his friends. Ye are my friends.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> Having been so richly blessed by Christ’s friendship, I pray that we will now be to others what He is to us: a true friend. At no time will we be more Christlike than when we are a friend. I testify of the inestimable value of friends in my own life and express my gratitude to all of them this morning. I know that when we offer ourselves in friendship, we make a most significant contribution to God’s work and to the happiness and progress of His children. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1999/04/friendship-a-gospel-principle</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1999-general-conference/1999-04-4030-elder-marlin-k-jensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5437014" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1999 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“To Walk Humbly with Thy God”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god?lang=eng</link>
      <description>True humility will inevitably lead us to say to God, “Thy will be done.”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029247_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="6ozrxg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="KLqINwwo4kOdl2N8hhM4Gg" hash="ezBggw">“To Walk Humbly with Thy God”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="9VeYVWPj_0mdk4Qmwl-86g" hash="Z8S8og">Marlin K. Jensen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="YdddN8MPNk69jzquk4Ejrg" hash="BIKSuw">True humility will inevitably lead us to say to God, “Thy will be done.”</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-f07.jpg" alt="Elder Marlin K. Jensen" pid="xZ8WiPIjGECMfkYblndEkw" hash="g-5cJQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p1" pid="9YUcWlMp5USDATG8axjMnw" hash="q_O7EA">One of the memorable themes of last October’s general conference was that, in addition to being concerned about what we <span class="emphasis">do,</span> we Latter-day Saints ought also to pay attention to what we <span class="emphasis">are</span> and are striving to <span class="emphasis">become.</span><span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> With that principle in mind, I listened attentively last November to President Gordon B. Hinckley’s address to the youth of the Church. I was touched by the six priceless bits of wisdom he shared describing what youth ought to <span class="emphasis">be.</span> One of the six—“be humble”—was of special interest to me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p2" pid="SbAqxzsf30K6JQU7ql7YTg" hash="wLucdA">When I suggested to my wife several weeks ago that because of President Hinckley’s talk I was considering humility as a possible topic for my remarks today, she paused and, with a twinkle in her eye, teasingly replied, “That leaves you only a few days to gain some!” Being thus encouraged, I have reflected on what might be involved in obeying President Hinckley’s injunction to “be humble.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p3" pid="pAa9mghKH0iVax0YiAxu3w" hash="bvaWPQ">To begin, it should come as no surprise that, in the estimation of some, humility ranks quite low on the scale of desirable character traits. Popular books have been written in recent years on integrity, common sense, civility, and a host of other virtues, but apparently there is little market for humility. Obviously, in these coarsening times when we are taught the art of negotiating by intimidation, and <span class="emphasis">assertiveness</span> has become a byword of the business world, those seeking to become humble will be a small and overlooked but critically important minority.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p4" pid="pCvE8fxH-UyTfr619IpqKQ" hash="KPRHXg">Consciously trying to acquire humility is also problematic. I remember once hearing one of my colleagues in the Seventy say about humility that “if you think you have it, you don’t.” He suggested we should try to develop humility and be sure we didn’t know when we got it, and then we would have it. But if we ever thought we had it, we wouldn’t.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p5" pid="gqlpm2wrVk-n2In6PzPnNw" hash="Yoaplg">This is one of the lessons C. S. Lewis teaches in his well-known <span class="emphasis">Screwtape Letters.</span> In letter XIV, a good man who is being recruited by a devil and his apprentice to their side is growing humble, and the devil remarks that “this is very bad.” With great insight, Lewis has the devil say to his associate, “Your patient has become humble; have you drawn his attention to the fact?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p6" pid="zKpnwFdR5UOdso4sDXyp-A" hash="sVtkRA">Fortunately, the Savior has given us a model for developing humility. When His disciples approached Him and inquired, “Who is the greatest in the kingdom of heaven?” He responded by placing a little child in their midst and stating, “Whosoever … shall humble himself as this little child, the same is greatest in the kingdom of heaven.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p7" pid="1T76eydTlEaoo6D0ZE87ww" hash="cfmGGg">In this passage the Savior teaches us that to become humble is to become as a child. How does a person become as a child, and what are the childlike qualities we ought to develop? King Benjamin, in his profound Book of Mormon sermon, provides guidance:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p8" pid="AULlnAvKHUGG7al6D2Urvg" hash="sJ-56Q">“For the natural man is an enemy to God, and has been from the fall of Adam, and will be, forever and ever, unless he yields to the enticings of the Holy Spirit, and putteth off the natural man and becometh a saint through the atonement of Christ the Lord, and becometh as a child, submissive, meek, humble, patient, full of love, willing to submit to all things which the Lord seeth fit to inflict upon him, even as a child doth submit to his father.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p9" pid="RaJhWCQVVkaOHAWuj4b2Dg" hash="_ENxsw">King Benjamin seems to teach that becoming like a child is a gradual process of spiritual development in which we are aided by the Holy Ghost and our reliance on Christ’s Atonement. Through this process, we will eventually acquire the childlike attributes of meekness, humility, patience, love, and spiritual submissiveness. True humility will inevitably lead us to say to God, “Thy will be done.” And because what we <span class="emphasis">are</span> does affect what we <span class="emphasis">do,</span> our submissiveness will be reflected in our reverence, gratitude, and willingness to accept callings, counsel, and correction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p10" pid="BYFjSXHBE029jDbInYEoFg" hash="_HoDZA">A story contained in the family lore of Brigham Young’s descendants illustrates the submissive nature of humility. It recounts that in a public meeting the Prophet Joseph, possibly as a test, sternly rebuked Brigham Young for something he had done or something he was supposed to have done but hadn’t—the detail is unclear. When Joseph finished the rebuke, everyone in the room waited for Brigham Young’s response. This powerful man, later known as the Lion of the Lord, in a voice everyone could tell was sincere, said simply and humbly, “Joseph, what do you want me to do?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p11" pid="MOrAFIFrDkOnHuMzPwDFTQ" hash="XNBVbQ">The power of that response itself brings a feeling of humility. It reminds us that the greatest act of courage and love in the history of mankind—Christ’s atoning sacrifice—was also the greatest act of humility and submissiveness. Some may wonder if those seeking to become humble must forever defer to the strongly held opinions and positions of others. Certainly the Savior’s life evidences that true humility is anything but subservience, weakness, or servility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p12" pid="T6j2qxALnU6wP4gP7t5xJQ" hash="beQxzg">Another helpful perspective on humility can be obtained by examining its antithesis—pride. Just as humility leads to other virtues such as modesty, teachableness, and unpretentiousness, pride leads to many other vices. In Latter-day Saint theology, it was through pride that Satan became the adversary of all truth. It was the growth of this arrogance, termed <span class="emphasis">hubris,</span> that the wise men of ancient Greece portrayed as the sure road to destruction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p13" pid="HM8LRXDj1E61Q9aSZGacJg" hash="eNa9ag">Twelve years ago President Ezra Taft Benson delivered a powerful conference address declaring that pride is “the universal sin, the great vice.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> He taught that pride is essentially competitive in nature and made reference to this quote from C. S. Lewis: “Pride gets no pleasure out of having something, only out of having more of it than the next man. We say that people are proud of being rich, or clever, or good-looking, but they are not. They are proud of being richer, cleverer, or better-looking than others. If every one else became equally rich, or clever, or good-looking there would be nothing to be proud about. It is the comparison that makes you proud: the pleasure of being above the rest. Once the element of competition has gone, pride has gone.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> What an interesting commentary on today’s highly competitive and thus prideful world. What an important reminder as well, for those of us who are blessed with the fulness of the gospel, to avoid both the condition and appearance of haughtiness or condescension in all of our human relationships.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p14" pid="eujq0oKFJkynQ2xGZwXeIQ" hash="ZwvWlg">I think sometimes of what life would be like if we all possessed greater humility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p15" pid="AIaWtr7ggEmobDrFjkGPPA" hash="kbiocg">Imagine a world in which <span class="emphasis">we</span> would replace <span class="emphasis">I</span> as the dominant pronoun.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p16" pid="LqdJ42Lk50Sqgx_V5vsVHA" hash="72RItg">Think of the impact on the pursuit of knowledge if being learned without being arrogant were the norm.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p17" pid="wfnRCQKS6UWK5sSZGjdt4g" hash="_uCwcQ">Consider the climate that would exist within a marriage or family—or any organization, for that matter—if through genuine humility mistakes were freely admitted and forgiven, if we were not afraid to praise others for fear they might gain on us, and if all were able to listen as well as we now verbalize.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p18" pid="vdSUab0ZwkmXVdOm7oFnoQ" hash="PWKlQA">Contemplate the advantages of life in a society in which considerations of status were only secondary, where citizens were more concerned with their responsibilities than their rights, and where those in authority might even occasionally step forward and humbly acknowledge, “I could be wrong.” Must our need to be “right” be so all-consuming? Surely this intolerance of others and their viewpoints is nothing less than the hubris the Greeks viewed and warned against as the suicidal sin. One wonders how differently even recent world history might be written if its principal participants had yielded to the gentle nudgings of humility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p19" pid="qqP37Q3p3E6vU_0W-2UAlw" hash="eYzv_w">Even more importantly, think of the role of humility in the process of repentance. Is it not humility, coupled with strong faith in Christ, that carries the transgressor to God in prayer, to the offended party in apology, and, where necessary, to his priesthood leader in confession?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p20" pid="RJe7SxkpvES1NrJVSXoFYA" hash="tw0Ycg">I am grateful for examples of humility I have encountered in my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p21" pid="JgD42phEuUCaA-967COkyA" hash="H_YpwA">Once my father, in the heat and frustration of a humid July afternoon, overreacted to my youthful farming blunders and administered punishment which I felt was in excess of the crime. Later he approached me with an apology and a much-appreciated expression of confidence in my abilities. That humble expression has remained in my memory for more than 40 years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p22" pid="w6PXOREKJEONitFbQ1T-nw" hash="--bHQg">I have seen a constant humility in my wonderful wife. Like Nephi turning to Lehi for direction after Lehi had momentarily faltered, she has stayed at my side for 34 years and consistently supported and loved me “notwithstanding my weakness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p23" pid="UjQHfA7gvE-7yY5RvZryHg" hash="Y94CAg">I am often deeply moved by evidences of humility in the scriptures. Consider John the Baptist declaring of the Savior, “He must increase, but I must decrease.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Think of Moroni pleading with us not to condemn him because of his imperfections, but to thank God that He made Moroni’s imperfections manifest so that we can learn to be wiser than Moroni was.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> Nor should we forget the exclamation of Moses, who, after experiencing the greatness of God and His creations, acknowledged that “for this cause I know that man is nothing, which thing I never had supposed.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Is not Moses’ recognition of our complete dependence on God the beginning of true humility?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p24" pid="XHiuPPbYnk-kL_KKmJI8cw" hash="1QCJsQ">I resonate to the English author John Ruskin’s memorable statement that “the first test of a truly great man is his humility.” He continued: “I do not mean, by humility, doubt of his own power. … [But really] great men … have a curious … feeling that … greatness is not <span class="emphasis">in</span> them, but <span class="emphasis">through</span> them. … And they see something Divine … in every other man … , and are endlessly, foolishly, incredibly merciful.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p25" pid="W-1vmg4xpkG5c90q12iNdg" hash="NEat0A">The Old Testament prophet Micah, like our living prophet, President Hinckley, was concerned about nurturing the development of humility. To his people he said, “He hath shewed thee, O man, what is good; and what doth the Lord require of thee, but to do justly, and to love mercy, and to walk humbly with thy God?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god.p26" pid="6NdclXeKaEmCfkj6OgnnEQ" hash="DDCPig">God bless us all to walk humbly with Him and with all men. I testify that President Gordon B. Hinckley is a true prophet and that his counsel to “be humble” comes from God. I testify that Jesus Christ, God’s meek and lowly Son, personifies humility. I know that it will be in humility that we one day kneel at the Savior’s feet to be judged of Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> May we live our lives to prepare for that humble moment is my prayer, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2001/04/to-walk-humbly-with-thy-god</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2001-general-conference/2001-04-1030-elder-marlin-k-jensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5846316" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2001 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remember and Perish Not</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Remembering in the way God intends is a fundamental and saving principle of the gospel.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008333_000_016" doc-version="2" hash="EmXIOw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ioigVwYkgEycCoEV64bE9w" hash="L2ClQA">Remember and Perish Not</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="cZAD4nCwnEuT5437T3kwUA" hash="Z8S8og">Marlin K. Jensen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="ztwPb9yVVUS3ljGYs-DFDw" hash="n_8y-w">Remembering in the way God intends is a fundamental and saving principle of the gospel.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/JensenMK_01.jpg" alt="Elder Marlin K. Jensen" pid="D4CUC3jcM025sZsC37bRvw" hash="G_1odw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not.p1" pid="_jfJYXQGKEqUcTu0PVxAnQ" hash="VHWBgA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="36"></span>I feel honored to follow Sister Parkin. Her service and teachings as well as those of her counselors have blessed all of us. About this same hour 18 1/2 years ago, I was standing near this pulpit waiting for the congregational singing to end, when I was to step forward and give my first general conference address. My anxiety at that moment must have been obvious. Elder L. Tom Perry, who was standing behind me, leaned forward and, in his positive and enthusiastic way, whispered in my ear. “Relax,” he said, “we haven’t lost anyone at that pulpit in years!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not.p2" pid="RAOh21ZMB0mpXBjTNbAypQ" hash="UDasTQ">Those encouraging words and the few minutes that followed in which I spoke for the first time to a worldwide audience of Latter-day Saints constitute a treasured memory for me. Like all of you, I am constantly accumulating a reservoir of memories which, when recalled, make up a very useful and often enjoyable part of my consciousness. And, despite resolutions I made as a young man never to weary others with reminiscing when I grew older, I now take great pleasure in sharing my own memories at almost every possible occasion. Today, however, I wish to speak of a more profound role of memory and remembering in the gospel of Jesus Christ than the passive recall and enjoyment of information.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not.p3" pid="2G4_d-KH5E6mR2UOw8H42w" hash="oPhiqA">If we pay close attention to the uses of the word <span class="emphasis">remember</span> in the holy scriptures, we will recognize that remembering in the way God intends is a fundamental and saving principle of the gospel. This is so because prophetic admonitions to remember are frequently calls to action: to listen, to see, to do, to obey, to repent.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> When we remember in God’s way, we overcome our human tendency simply to gird for the battle of life and actually engage in the battle itself, doing all in our power to resist temptation and avoid sinning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not.p4" pid="UUa2zv1TxUukAA9cl97CaQ" hash="aiZxng">King Benjamin called for such active remembering from his people:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not.p5" pid="90EDYzgboEKuw10Q785zww" hash="0cvSRg">“And finally, I cannot tell you all <span class="pageBreak" page-number="37"></span>the things whereby ye may commit sin; for there are divers ways and means, even so many that I cannot number them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not.p6" pid="cmk9XWfzyE29dOpkGnFNOg" hash="O6A0DA">“But this much I can tell you, that if ye do not watch yourselves, and your thoughts, and your words, and your deeds, and observe the commandments of God, and continue in the faith of what ye have heard concerning the coming of our Lord, even unto the end of your lives, ye must perish. And now, O man, remember, and perish not.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not.p7" pid="bZw4Lex1KUKKCXxnulGkIQ" hash="T9qFhQ">Realizing the vital role remembering is to play in our lives, what else ought we to remember? In response, assembled as we are today to remember and rededicate this historic Tabernacle, I suggest that the history of the Church of Jesus Christ and its people deserves our remembrance. The scriptures give the Church’s history high priority. In fact, much of scripture is Church history. On the very day the Church was organized, God commanded Joseph Smith, “Behold, there shall be a record kept among you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Joseph acted on this command by appointing Oliver Cowdery, the second elder in the Church and his chief assistant, as the first Church historian. We keep records to help us remember, and a record of the Church’s rise and progress has been kept from Oliver Cowdery’s time to the present day. This extraordinary historical record reminds us that God has again opened the heavens and revealed truths that call our generation to action.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not.p8" pid="Gerg9H-gWkaoCvGW9HrydA" hash="19WxyA">Of all that has been collected, preserved, and written by historians over those many years, nothing exemplifies the importance and power of the Church’s history more than Joseph Smith’s simple and honest story of God the Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, appearing to him in what our history books now call the First Vision. In words that generations of missionaries have committed to memory and shared with seekers of truth the world over, Joseph describes the miraculous way in which he received an answer to his question posed in prayer of which Church is right:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not.p9" pid="cB3ymwyYw0uK9FDk_CRnKw" hash="U_btDw">“I saw a pillar of light exactly over my head, above the brightness of the sun, which descended gradually until it fell upon me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not.p10" pid="53NHwLzgqEG0qNqkhMk9og" hash="9mQ0Jg">“… When the light rested upon me I saw two Personages, whose brightness and glory defy all description, standing above me in the air. One of them spake unto me, calling me by name and said, pointing to the other—<span class="emphasis">This is My Beloved Son. Hear Him!</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not.p11" pid="XfwY-vhWpU2vH5NiZWq1vA" hash="CsFJug">Hear him, Joseph did! And millions have heard or read and believed his account and have embraced the gospel of Jesus Christ he helped restore. I believe Joseph Smith and know he was a true prophet of God. Remembering his experience of the First Vision never fails to stir my soul to greater commitment and action.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not.p12" pid="_UPz9b1KqEm1QJFtsiLn3A" hash="CPM42Q">No one has greater appreciation for the value of the Church’s history than President Gordon B. Hinckley. We love <span class="pageBreak" page-number="38"></span>his delightful sense of humor, but his sense of history is equally keen. Inspiring stories and anecdotes from our past punctuate his writings and sermons. As our living prophet, he consciously emphasizes the past and the future to help us live more righteously in the present. Because of his teachings, we understand that remembering enables us to see God’s hand in our past, just as prophecy and faith assure us of God’s hand in our future. President Hinckley reminds us how members of the early Church faced their challenges so we, through the grace of God, can more faithfully face our own. By keeping our past alive, he connects us to the people, places, and events that make up our spiritual heritage and, in so doing, motivates us to greater service, faith, and kindness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not.p13" pid="NO5psmC5Xk6Dwe3rdRq0HQ" hash="ACXHbQ">In an exemplary way President Hinckley also openly shares from his own personal and family histories. Scores of discouraged new missionaries have been comforted to learn that early in his own mission, President Hinckley was also discouraged and admitted as much to his father. He even courageously shared his father’s brief response: “Dear Gordon, I have your recent letter. I have only one suggestion: forget yourself and go to work.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Over 70 years later, we are all witnesses to how earnestly President Hinckley took that counsel to heart. His sterling character and prophetic wisdom provide persuasive proof for the benefits of remembering the Church’s history as well as our own.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not.p14" pid="pxbPsMTiFUSknFxwZeMMwA" hash="o7S_nQ">There is much more to say about memory and remembering in the gospel of Jesus Christ. We often speak of remembering our sacred covenants and God’s commandments and of remembering and performing saving ordinances for our deceased ancestors. Most importantly, we speak of the need to remember our Savior Jesus Christ and not just when convenient, but always, as He asks.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> We witness always to remember Him as we partake of the sacrament. In return, we are promised His Spirit will always be with us. Interestingly, this is the same Spirit sent by our Heavenly Father to “bring all things to [our] remembrance.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> Thus, by worthily receiving the sacrament, we are blessed by the Spirit to enter into a wonderfully beneficial circle of remembering, returning again and again in our thinking and devotion to Christ and His Atonement.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not.p15" pid="StdcK0jwXUmVm6SUTlDkDQ" hash="F9x6jQ">Coming unto Christ and being perfected in Him is, I believe, the ultimate purpose of all remembering.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Therefore, I pray that God will bless us always to remember, especially His perfect Son, and perish not. I gratefully testify of Christ’s divinity and saving power. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/04/remember-and-perish-not</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2007-general-conference/2007-04-2050-elder-marlin-k-jensen-64k-eng.mp3" length="4975493" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2007 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
