<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Mary N. Cook</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Mary N. Cook.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Mary%20N.%20Cook.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Mary N. Cook.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Strengthen Home and Family</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Lord is depending on you to assist in the exaltation of your eternal family.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008332_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="iKeryw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="4-QKAxQ-h0ixetQSA16mXQ" hash="3tQ1xg">Strengthen Home and Family</h1><p class="authorName" guid="a5a0ea04-63cd-4450-ab6a-c8da4f58c2f9" pid="M7RcAojEJUqHKO8ZGoGDwg" hash="eowP4Q">Mary N. Cook</p><p class="kicker" pid="ZfuqYW8CC0W7rJNvuxWA2A" hash="6QW41A">The Lord is depending on you to assist in the exaltation of your eternal family.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="6810855a-f7b7-44f1-a5f2-6b1e67faa13d">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/CookMN_07.jpg" alt="Mary N. Cook" guid="ebac0afd-4e78-4381-ae6f-b992ecdc7674" pid="LBiDBh0vYkS-XUdYsxdpmw" hash="YpAhvg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="f7dICJacbUmwXpedPC0iig" hash="uSsvsw">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="11"></span>Each Sunday, from Mongolia to Manchester to Mississippi, the young women of the Church repeat these inspired words: “We will be prepared to strengthen home and family, make and keep sacred covenants, receive the ordinances of the temple, and enjoy the blessings of exaltation” (“Young Women Theme,” <span class="emphasis">Young Women Personal Progress</span> [booklet, 2001], 5).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="c2cygKUhB0SPUN5hR9YFKA" hash="9CNHMQ">While this is the Young Women theme, it applies to all youth in the Church. I hope I can help you, my young brothers and sisters, understand how powerful your individual actions can be in strengthening your home and family, no matter what your circumstances. I understand, for example, that many of you may be the only member of the Church in your family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="s-puyQEyiUG84yDeUB7QJg" hash="qSsdnA">
        <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth</span> reminds us that “being part of a family is a great blessing. … Not all families are the same, but each is important in Heavenly Father’s plan” ([pamphlet, 2001], 10).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="evxcpxNYu0ONEcj-V1ubPQ" hash="8wgZEA">All families need strengthening, from the ideal to the most troubled. That strengthening can come from <span class="emphasis">you.</span> In fact, in some families you may be the only source of spiritual strength. The Lord is depending on you to bring the blessings of the gospel to your family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="IeaTK0XOQkC5FUo-GZrqjw" hash="jrWTBA">It is important to establish patterns of righteousness in your own life, which will enable you to set a good example for your family, whatever form your family may take.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="w2wsQY-m00CtWIGSmQ60nw" hash="OHpycw">The example of your righteous life will strengthen your family. President Hinckley gave the young women “a simple four-point program” in the general Young Women meeting last spring that will not only “assure your happiness” but will bless your family as well. He counseled each of us to “(1) pray, (2) study, (3) pay your tithing, and (4) attend your meetings” (“Let Virtue Garnish Thy Thoughts Unceasingly,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 2007, 115).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="dCwu3dyDZEmPsulgZofRLg" hash="028l-Q">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="12"></span>Seeking the help of the Lord daily through prayer will bring great blessings to your family. Ask yourself: “Who in my family could benefit from my personal prayers?” “What could I do to support and encourage family prayer?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="sf9KtIkPbkyA6_zVAqsrrA" hash="xV8blg">As you personally study the scriptures, you will come to know the Savior and His teachings. From His example you will know how to love, serve, and forgive members of your family. Consider how you could share your understanding of the scriptures with your family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="_tA1bG2lIkutf0v6bZq9kA" hash="Dkc_vQ">On several occasions, President Hinckley has admonished us to “get all of the education you can” (<span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 2007, 116). Your education will benefit your family now and will surely bless your future family. What can you do now to plan and prepare for a good education?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="hiwpTDE5ykikFvyuFaasqQ" hash="qSro3Q">President Hinckley taught us, “While tithing is paid with money, more importantly it is paid with faith” (<span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 2007, 117). Are you experiencing the blessings of paying tithing—with faith? As you obey this commandment, the Lord will “open … the windows of heaven” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/3.10" class="scriptureRef">Malachi 3:10</a>) to bless you and your family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="YLfFP40lmkmG3HrIRZu1xQ" hash="uoghfA">How can attending your meetings—particularly sacrament meeting—bless you and your family? Regularly partaking of the sacrament will help you keep your baptismal covenant. As you live worthily and renew this covenant weekly, you will qualify for the guidance of the Spirit. The Holy Ghost will guide you and will teach you what you should do to bless your family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="sx-_OXjGR0iJXomSkgI5BQ" hash="2VJxtg">As you commit to these patterns of righteousness, you will be blessed throughout your life and will develop the spiritual foundation from which you can strengthen your family by example. In 1 Timothy, Paul teaches us about example: “Let no man despise thy youth; but be thou an example of the believers, in word, in conversation, in charity, in spirit, in faith, in purity” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-tim/4.12" class="scriptureRef">1 Timothy 4:12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="LwQuQbKRNkmDb6PnOqlVVg" hash="zxlxLQ">The family section in <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth</span> gives some great ways you can be “an example of the believers” in your own home:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="Weg_prglYUyAPSKZ8LmAqQ" hash="MFuFQw">“Be cheerful, helpful, and considerate of others. … Concern yourself with the needs of other family members. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="xYz5k83yhUi1ebSXJ5LGnA" hash="8iyuxw">“Honor your parents by showing love and respect for them and by being obedient. … Participate in family activities and traditions, including family prayer, family home evenings, and family scripture reading. These traditions strengthen and unify families. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="l5YOD00ZA0W8nyfSY2jLeQ" hash="joMXxg">“Strengthen your relationships with your brothers and sisters. They can become your closest friends” (10–11).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="67dIguew1UqWTVETrYkZGQ" hash="EEs6Eg">Example is often the best teacher. Who in your family could benefit from your example—a brother, a sister, your mom or dad?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="E8mFBHg95UalMl9JqxJjzA" hash="ftB88w">Let me tell you an experience from my own life and how my brother’s patterns of righteousness and example resulted in our family being blessed eternally.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="wUnYnAfTOUKSkhGBQ_ePeg" hash="YTH8Lg">My brother and I were “born of goodly parents” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/1.1" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 1:1</a>), who loved and made great sacrifices for the two of us, but our family had not been blessed with the sacred ordinances of the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="BuYfZqHLA0-BCD-tVbJTGQ" hash="VTlpGw">Many years ago on a day in late December, we received a letter from my brother, who was serving in the California North Mission. The outside of the envelope cautioned, “<span class="emphasis">Do not</span> open until you are <span class="emphasis">all</span> together!!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="Rq-_ThhPWEWC2FJTramE-A" hash="cYVdgg">As my father, mother, and I gathered to open his seven-page typewritten letter, we read his testimony of prayer. He taught us the doctrine of eternal families from the scriptures. We read his experiences of how fasting and prayer helped his investigators prepare to receive the ordinance of baptism. He assured us that our family too could be blessed through fasting and prayer. Then came his challenge: “The bishop of the Stanford Ward <span class="pageBreak" page-number="13"></span>spoke on a topic a couple of months ago which really hit home. … The bishop’s talk made me stop and realize the goals I want to accomplish in life. Uppermost in my mind is the goal I want to achieve with my own family … that, of course, being sealed to you, Mom and Dad, for time and all eternity in the house of the Lord. I love you very much and want our family to be together in the eternities.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="BZ9kdyj5Zky7pxPRfnMSmA" hash="vK1NnA">Then his closing words: “May the Lord guide you in this important decision and may you pray together as a family is my prayer.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="6tUVc2tgDUGcfKl1BzoiMQ" hash="aTwfQw">As a teenager, I too had prayed for this blessing to come to my family. This letter now brought hope for my righteous desire.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="RhVMvkQIz0uEOrV7rJJkUQ" hash="QrIWJA">The new year was an opportunity for our family to make some changes. In the many months that followed, we established family patterns of righteousness. We prayed together, studied about the ordinances of the temple, paid tithing, and attended our meetings regularly—as a family. Shortly after my brother returned from his mission, we were prepared to receive the ordinances of the temple. I knew the Lord had heard and answered our prayers as we surrounded the holy altar in the temple and were sealed as a family for time and all eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="5wI7W-Z2sEytl_DgLPgpTw" hash="VXFP1g">Can you make a difference in your family? Yes, you can! I often wonder about my family’s eternal progression if my brother had not written that powerful letter. His patterns of righteousness and example changed our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="tSkO-FFs50yDfas9vubpWQ" hash="NWJYwA">Elder Robert D. Hales said: “If the example we have received from our parents was not good, it is our responsibility to break the cycle. … Each person can learn a better way and in so doing bless the lives of family members now and teach correct traditions for the generations that follow” (“How Will Our Children Remember Us?” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1993, 10).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="xXQ3exTarUOmkhWpxXA8sg" hash="uahj6A">Remember, “the family is central to the Creator’s plan for the eternal destiny of His children” (“The Family: A Proclamation to the World,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> Oct. 2004, 49; <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1995, 102). Eternal families are made up of individuals. “Do your part to build a happy home” (<span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth,</span> 10). Establish patterns of righteousness in your life. And be an example of the believers. The Lord is depending on you to assist in the exaltation of your eternal family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family.p" pid="FUoKYMYIpUWfmGWPfpI9wA" hash="Vn-pNA">I know that Jesus Christ lives. He knows you and loves you. He has blessed me and my family, and I know He will bless you and yours. Of this I humbly testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/CookMN_07.jpg" alt="Mary N. Cook" guid="ebac0afd-4e78-4381-ae6f-b992ecdc7674" pid="T2y0BIZ2iU2aTnNkCbQjxQ" hash="YpAhvg1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="ebac0afd-4e78-4381-ae6f-b992ecdc7674"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/10/strengthen-home-and-family</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2007-general-conference/2007-10-1040-mary-n-cook-64k-eng.mp3" length="3917314" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anchors of Testimony</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Strengthen your faith by following this pattern of prayer, study, and obedience to the commandments.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00009475_000_044" doc-version="2" hash="lRixQQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="GAdZvMjqN0myBgW_Ehqiyg" hash="TrdUKQ">Anchors of Testimony</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="6BUZO5_qj0OV8w0wloDSKw" hash="eowP4Q">Mary N. Cook</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="wuw9zLbnAUCsEfzGEFbeGA" hash="JlzdhQ">Strengthen your faith by following this pattern of prayer, study, and obedience to the commandments.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p1" pid="3QWfVWUNHUiFq_STb1fy1Q" hash="Xdqffg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="120"></span>When I lived in Asia, I saw many ponds covered with beautiful flowering water lilies. They added a serene beauty and sweet fragrance to otherwise muddy, stagnant ponds. The leaves of the water lily floated on the water’s surface, and a long, firm stalk anchored its position in the pond. The continued growth of the stalk ensured the flower’s stability, even when torrential rains raised the level of the water in the pond.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p2" pid="UDVRhPsdwkyej_wDq_K9kQ" hash="1UR5Xg">My dear young sisters, you are much like this beautiful flower. Your freshness, purity, and beauty add much goodness to our lives and to the lives of your family. You live in a challenging world polluted with temptations and trials, yet your testimony of Jesus Christ can be your anchor. Faith in the Lord Jesus Christ will strengthen and help your testimony grow, and you will be able to rise above the evils of the world and maintain your position of righteousness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p3" pid="cSYO3kURikuSnCqWc4n8AQ" hash="ec9xqQ">An anchor is defined as something “that provides stability or confidence in an otherwise uncertain situation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Your testimony will be your anchor and will give you the confidence to stand “steadfast and immovable”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> in keeping the Lord’s commandments in an uncertain world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p4" pid="woBVcMMuW0OSW4eJ66HSUQ" hash="Bdcs1w">Right now, your testimony is growing, like the stalk of the water lily. Your faith will help it grow and keep it strong, even when you face challenges and temptations of a world polluted with drugs, immorality, pornography, and immodesty.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p5" pid="YFcowFQ3dUWBDq9PQW2D6g" hash="VeNguw">“Faith is a gift from God, but you must nurture your faith to keep it strong. … You can nurture the gift of faith by praying to Heavenly Father in the name of Jesus Christ. … You can strengthen your faith by keeping the commandments. … You can also develop your faith by studying the scriptures and the words of latter-day prophets.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p6" pid="s9jX1vpegE-CVZ4TQKRckA" hash="M_tI_g">I know some young women who had questions about modest clothing. To find answers to their questions, they followed this exact pattern: they prayed to Heavenly Father, they studied the scriptures and the words of our latter-day prophets, and they were obedient in living the standard of modesty. As they received answers to their questions, their faith increased and their testimonies were strengthened. I would invite each of you to follow this pattern.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p7" pid="y1Y4RzJVVEiqOPSO00geUg" hash="01nbqA">First, pray to your Heavenly Father. Ask Him for help in finding answers to your questions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p8" pid="WP_-SDDWVkGtNZZ5Y2nIcg" hash="QDtLhA">Our prophet, President Thomas S. Monson, said in his first news conference:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p9" pid="NABD4VoIg0SeTUPlIYvVNw" hash="ZE1Dcg">“Sometimes the best answers that young people can [get] to the questions of life are found there upon their knees calling upon our Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p10" pid="l1MH8XK07kqnkyzbbW1huw" hash="88sxrQ">“If they will remember that the Lord is mindful of them and will answer their prayers, they will be able to meet every challenge that comes to them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Prayer will strengthen your faith and anchor your testimony.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p11" pid="CjzoJuJBnEGJoWFyPT_KeQ" hash="2CunBQ">In addition to prayer, study the scriptures about faith. <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.27" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:27</a> is a great place to begin learning the process of increasing your faith: “But behold, if ye will awake and arouse your faculties, even to an experiment upon my words, and exercise a particle of faith, yea, even if ye can no more than desire to believe, let this desire work in you, even until ye believe in a manner that ye can give place for a portion of my words.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p12" pid="tgj4-_sY8UaHy6iihiBIug" hash="nA23dQ">Are you willing to try Alma’s experiment to increase your faith? Can you exercise even a particle of faith? Do you have a desire to believe?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p13" pid="kiInv3sao0uGJGiJBknvEQ" hash="OlGnqA">As you learn from the scriptures, I know the Lord will bless you with His Spirit, and like the young women we heard from tonight, your understanding will be enlightened. The scriptures will increase your faith and help anchor your testimony.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p14" pid="l3besSBU8kWnKRCQwAYoEw" hash="L_V1cQ">Studying the words of our latter-day <span class="pageBreak" page-number="121"></span>prophets will also increase your faith. “You can always trust the living prophets. Their teachings reflect the will of the Lord”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> and will help anchor your testimony.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p15" pid="gKvaIlg5CUOv0nFqOq5_QQ" hash="H7OzOg">President Spencer W. Kimball, one of our latter-day prophets, counseled youth to drive down stakes to help them be “steadfast and immovable” when he taught: “Our young people should drive down stakes early. … The stakes are of two kinds: ‘This I <span class="emphasis">will do’</span> and ‘This I <span class="emphasis">will not do.’ … </span>Very early, youth should have been living by a plan. … When such a course is charted and the goal is set, it is easier to resist the many temptations and to say ‘no’ to the first cigarette, ‘no’ to the first drink, … ‘no’ to the first improper advances which lead eventually to immoral practices.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p16" pid="gdebn7q--0SLu47RBAd0ng" hash="JOeiyA">We have a great tool to help us drive down those stakes. It is <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth. </span>In this little book you will find the words of our latter-day prophets. The “stakes” that President Kimball described are in this book: the things “I <span class="emphasis">will do”</span> and the things “I <span class="emphasis">will not do.”</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p17" pid="IpCk8Z1-7U6zaeLJsAEzAA" hash="EPK9SQ">It’s not enough, however, to just read the words of the prophets. You must follow the final step in our pattern and “keep these standards and live by the truths in the scriptures.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> This is the challenging part, but by planning ahead what you will and will not do and then living by that plan, you can do it!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p18" pid="nbnFUtPolUu5pdQXX1uGpg" hash="K9lPwQ">Faith is a principle of action. Let me tell you about some young women who studied the words of the prophets in <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth,</span> then took action. They made a plan, decided what they would and would not do, and then lived by that plan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p19" pid="E_Y0VP3zgE22aySSmoyaqA" hash="9FwGJg">One of the guidelines in <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth</span> states: “Through your dress and appearance, you can show the Lord that you know how precious your body is. You can show that you are a disciple of Jesus Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p20" pid="laFJJp0ciE6ZKNuMD8YOzg" hash="J9nWyQ">After studying these words, one young woman realized that perhaps some of her clothes were not completely modest. Through prayer and study of the scriptures, she was reminded that she was a disciple of Jesus Christ and that, as His representative, she needed to make some changes. She didn’t want to have anything in her wardrobe that was a temptation, so she went through her closet and drawers and got rid of anything that wasn’t modest. She said, “I would be smart if I didn’t even try on anything in stores that I knew I shouldn’t wear. Why be tempted?” That firm resolve showed the Lord that she respected her body, and she drove down a deep stake for modesty.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p21" pid="nPo3jw0_Z0GUMH-oE7oo4A" hash="yOMgHw">Another young woman in the class recognized that her choices in clothing were affecting the way her little sister was dressing. A line in <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth </span>states: “Your dress and grooming send messages about you to others and influence the way you and others act.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> She decided to make some changes in her clothing, realizing that she had a responsibility to be a good example to her little sister. She drove her stake down more deeply and influenced her sister’s clothing choices.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p22" pid="ffMKFERbhkWV16rV41qg7A" hash="0f366w">The standard of “Entertainment and the Media” teaches us to “choose only entertainment and media that uplift you. Good entertainment will help you to have good thoughts and make righteous choices.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> I know of a young woman and her sister who were listening to a CD when they realized that the words were not uplifting and did not help them have good thoughts. They both looked at each other and knew through the Spirit that they shouldn’t be listening to this kind of music. The older sister got a hammer, and together they took the CD, and they smashed it into bits. Earlier they had driven down stakes regarding music. They knew what they would and would not listen to <span class="pageBreak" page-number="122"></span>and were able to live their plan by following the promptings of the Spirit. This small act strengthened them and gave them confidence to obey in more challenging situations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p23" pid="IsGToRYziESPSFewF9WBIA" hash="W5i3qA">Another young woman decided that one of the stakes in her life was to observe the Sabbath, regardless of her circumstances. One year after she was baptized a member of the Church with her family, her ward was divided. Her family was assigned to the newly formed ward, and she was the only young woman in the new ward. Her parents resisted the change and stopped attending church, but she wanted to follow the guidelines in <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth </span>on “Sabbath Day Observance.” She decided to go to church in the new ward whenever she could, even though it meant attending all of her meetings alone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p24" pid="yvPWrxi0SEmz4DyWpMUf1w" hash="7tS3bA">On Sundays she read her scriptures and worked on Personal Progress. Her decision to be “steadfast and immovable” in observing the Sabbath encouraged her mother and younger sister to begin attending church again. Her mother testified that her daughter’s steadfast example of living the gospel and her goodness helped them return to activity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p25" pid="0TN5fflmIkaBhZq8bbUCxw" hash="mdfetg">“You express your faith through action—by the way you live.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> The lives of these young women expressed their faith. And note that their faith and exemplary lives resulted in good works. Sisters blessed sisters, and a daughter helped her mother return to Church activity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p26" pid="IFaD4ixozEOrYhVvJVfrjw" hash="0iNsCg">Some of you may feel that you can’t rise above the polluted pond, that your circumstances are too difficult, your trials too hard, your temptations too great. But remember Alma’s promise: “Whosoever shall put their trust in God shall be supported in their trials, and their troubles, and their afflictions, and shall be lifted up at the last day.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Remember, the stalk of the water lily grows in adversity, and as the stalk lifts the water lily, your faith will support and lift you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p27" pid="1DXLqD9tck2V6xuabpDKNQ" hash="ZzhMAQ">My dear young sisters, your testimony of Jesus Christ is your anchor. Strengthen your faith by following this pattern of prayer, study, and obedience to the commandments. Drive down stakes by deciding now what you will and will not do, and then act on your plan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony.p28" pid="wD0GkV5cdEmM6WVHBQgykw" hash="bizTFA">I testify that the Lord loves each of you and will bless you in your efforts to be “steadfast and immovable.” The gospel of Jesus Christ is true, and your knowledge and testimony of Jesus Christ will keep you well anchored, and you will be able to maintain your position as you stand for truth and righteousness. Of this I humbly testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2008/04/anchors-of-testimony</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2008-general-young-women-meeting/2008-03-0040-mary-n-cook-64k-eng.mp3" length="5255189" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2008 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Never, Never, Never Give Up!</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up?lang=eng</link>
      <description>What does the Lord want you to do? He wants you to be a valiant and virtuous daughter of God, dedicated to living each day so that you can be worthy to receive the blessings of the temple.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021388_000_046" doc-version="1" hash="a6-PqA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="9b-uMYDZbUyluQYal5drzA" hash="qLfWRw">Never, Never, Never Give Up!</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="-a6ycaoO8UiA9bvUv4PfMA" hash="eowP4Q">Mary N. Cook</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="ASp1ZxaCbUWKFKgvrFN8eQ" hash="2PG0kQ">What does the Lord want you to do? He wants you to be a valiant and virtuous daughter of God, dedicated to living each day so that you can be worthy to receive the blessings of the temple.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p1" pid="G0JdTKFMJk6gmaOXKX4QAA" hash="WzPmOg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="117"></span>Last August we took some of our grandchildren to Timpanogos Cave National Monument, one of Utah’s most popular destinations. It is a rather strenuous one-and-a-half-mile (2.4 km) hike to reach the cave but well worth the effort to witness the cave’s beautiful, spiraling formations. I was certain that nine-year-old Ruthie would have little difficulty, but I wondered whether six-year-old Caroline would have the strength and stamina to make it all the way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p2" pid="ERE3V70exU-eLVJeA4XoSw" hash="XRVKAg">We were all very excited to begin the hike, and at first we moved rapidly along the paved trail. One-fourth of the way came quickly, but it took longer to reach the halfway point. Caroline started to get discouraged. Ruthie was doing well and encouraged Caroline to continue. We slowed down so Caroline could keep up. Then it seemed that everything went wrong. Strong winds came up, and the dust from the winds made it difficult to see. It was a little scary, and as if that weren’t enough, we came across a signpost that read, “Rattlesnake Habitat. Stay on the Trail. Stay Safe.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p3" pid="VKC9mOQ-q0-XUxziN_U7Kw" hash="86p_og">Slowly we trudged along, three-fourths of the way to our goal, but we still had the steepest part of the mountain to climb. Tired, scared, and doubting her abilities, Caroline sat down and tearfully declared, “I give up! I can’t go any farther!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p4" pid="4Wn6SnwU3U27wPEXhkUBWA" hash="U465kQ">We sat down, and we talked about what we should do. We made a plan. We decided to count our steps and see how we felt after 100 steps. Ruthie and I assured Caroline that we would help her. We were to look for something that made us happy along the way and share our discoveries. We even sang some Primary songs.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p5" pid="APZsDmByFEeVoIbDLO8kwQ" hash="cEvzMw">Things changed. Caroline made the choice to follow the plan. One hundred steps made an impossible task seem doable. Caroline knew we would help her, and as we looked for the good things around us and sang songs, we felt happier.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p6" pid="FpG_LkiR8kGsQOmtXlKPfQ" hash="D6G61w">Have you ever been afraid and discouraged as you’ve faced a challenge that seemed far beyond your ability? Have you ever wanted to give up?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p7" pid="zbQe5j3ZpkuJi7KOShrxnw" hash="qdcOog">Imagine how Joshua, the successor to the great prophet Moses, must have felt, knowing that he was to lead the children of Israel to the promised land. At times I’m sure he wanted to give up. But the Lord comforted him by reminding him three times to be strong and courageous (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/1.6-9" class="scriptureRef">Joshua 1:6–9</a>). With faith that God would be with them, the children of Israel committed, “All that thou commandest … we will do” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/1.16" class="scriptureRef">Joshua 1:16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p8" pid="5hUsenEOuEydeATZNsoDcw" hash="apwfAw">The scriptures are full of accounts of men and women who showed great courage to do whatever the Lord commanded, even when the tasks seemed impossible, even when they may have wanted to give up.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p9" pid="wzH_Wh0pK0W7WaoTd_OitA" hash="51f0Bw">What does the Lord want you to do? He wants you to be a valiant and virtuous daughter of God, dedicated to living each day so that you can be worthy to receive the blessings of the temple and return to Him. In today’s world that will take courage. You have the plan of salvation, which makes it <span class="pageBreak" page-number="118"></span>possible to do this. Moral agency, the ability to choose, is an essential part of this plan. You’ve already made some good choices. Before you were born, you made the choice to come to earth to receive a body and to prove yourself. You’ve made the choice to be baptized, which is the first ordinance required on the path to eternal life. You are now experiencing mortal life, where you continue to make choices, to learn, and to grow. Making sacred covenants and receiving the ordinances of the temple is another important step in the plan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p10" pid="b95d172-6k2vwxYI2nrBbQ" hash="3NeV4w">As you are growing older, young women, the path is becoming steeper, and you may want to give up. Life is more challenging, filled with decisions and temptations at every turn. Satan will blow winds of confusion that may cause you to question if this is the path you want to take. You may be tempted to try another route, even when signs of danger are posted. You may doubt your abilities, and you may wonder as one young woman did, “Is it really possible to remain virtuous in today’s world?” The answer, my young friends, is “Yes!” And my counsel to you is similar to that given by Winston Churchill during World War II: never, never, never give up! (see “Never Give In” [speech, Harrow School, London, England, Oct. 29, 1941]).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p11" pid="xj6IUPLGskKF0Bv5GaItWw" hash="YA4o2g">This will take great courage, but you have His plan! What will help you follow the plan and be a valiant and virtuous daughter of God? First, gain a strong testimony, step by step. Second, seek the help of Heavenly Father, Jesus Christ, your family, and others who will support you in your decision to follow the plan. And finally, live to be worthy of the companionship of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p12" pid="5h6G2hvDfUCS8G51O7zLTg" hash="2s0UHQ">Of the importance of gaining a strong testimony, President Thomas S. Monson promised the young women, “Your testimony, when constantly nourished, will keep you safe” (“May You Have Courage,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 2009, 126).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p13" pid="6iz0uMrNZkm3_UGZCOGSAQ" hash="0lCItQ">Your testimony is strengthened “gradually through your experiences. No one receives a complete testimony all at once” (<span class="emphasis">True to the Faith: A Gospel Reference</span> [2004], 179). You’ll recall that in order to climb the steepest part of the mountain, we approached it one step at a time. To gain a testimony, you must nourish it step by step. “[Your testimony] will increase as you make decisions to keep the commandments. As you lift and strengthen others, you will see your testimony continue to develop.” As you establish personal habits of prayer, scripture study, obedience to the commandments, and service to others, “you will be blessed with moments of inspiration that will [strengthen] your testimony” (see <span class="emphasis">True to the Faith,</span> 179–80).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p14" pid="KASXc4NDl0q9kRTd4mW7ow" hash="RwKd0Q">Personal Progress provides a wonderful way for you to nourish your testimony step by step. Value experiences and projects are small steps that will nourish your testimony of Jesus Christ as you learn His teachings and regularly apply them in your life. This constant nourishment will keep you safely on the path.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p15" pid="XTpQWTRUqkaOq9wvpImy0g" hash="kWLPJw">Second, seek the help of others to give you added strength and support. Look first to your Heavenly Father through prayer. You are His daughter. He knows you and loves you. He hears and answers your prayers. We are taught countless times in the scriptures to “pray always” (see, for example, <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/90.24" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 90:24</a>). As you pray, the Lord <span class="emphasis">will</span> be with you just as the Lord was with Joshua.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p16" pid="iNJwGWSTkEi2Gdjz8QuA-A" hash="jX9NDA">We each need the help of the Savior to follow the plan and return to our Father in Heaven. Perhaps you have made some mistakes or started down another path. “Because the Savior loves you and has given His life for you, you can repent. … The Savior’s atoning sacrifice has made it possible for you to be forgiven of your sins” (<span class="emphasis">Young Women Personal Progress</span> [booklet, 2009], 71). “The sooner you repent, the sooner you will find the blessings that come from forgiveness” (<span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth</span> [pamphlet, 2001], 30).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p17" pid="RPetW6LXakCVngSk5PQMAg" hash="KmTQOg">Determine now to do what is required to repent. “Partake worthily of the sacrament each week and fill your life with virtuous activities that will bring spiritual power. As you do this, you will grow stronger in your ability to resist temptation, keep the commandments, and become more like Jesus Christ” (<span class="emphasis">Young Women Personal Progress,</span> 71).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p18" pid="tQ3oxX_EAkCJTxA-NE3w5g" hash="50Yx1g">Latter-day prophets are on the earth to help you as well. Prophets speak for today. Be riveted on their words. They will give you the signposts that will warn you of danger and keep you safely on the path. The signposts specific to you are found in <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth.</span> “Follow the prophet; he knows the way” (<span class="emphasis">Children’s Songbook,</span> “Follow the Prophet,” 110–11).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p19" pid="tCphF-PLZUWP4PJaOkEvRQ" hash="1znu3g">One of the great blessings of the plan is that we are organized into families. You have parents whose greater wisdom and experience will help you <span class="pageBreak" page-number="119"></span>reach your divine potential. Trust them. They want the best for you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p20" pid="MlJ2FCIl2US5a9FOM_JMzg" hash="rY42iw">Learn from your mother, your grandmother, and other righteous women with strong testimonies. The role of a mother in the plan is to be a nurturer. Mothers, no one loves your daughter as you do. You are her best leader, mentor, and example. We hope you will accept the invitation to work on Personal Progress with your daughter. As I learned from working on the virtue value with my mother, your relationship will be strengthened and you both will be blessed by your mutual love, support, and encouragement.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p21" pid="thYBU9x_n0y7tqkIMTumdw" hash="ED3ncg">Young women, choose good friends who will support you in your righteous decision to follow the plan. Like Ruthie, who gave encouragement to Caroline, we know that many of you can do much to strengthen each other. After you receive your Young Womanhood Recognition, it is your turn to be the “big sister.” Earning your Honor Bee will give you opportunities to strengthen another young woman with your righteous example and testimony as you mentor her with her Personal Progress.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p22" pid="O5La9gUev02k8eKPsk6Ajg" hash="qqMt1w">Finally, live to be worthy of the companionship of the Holy Ghost. When we helped Caroline, looked for the good around us, and even sang Primary songs, we invited the Spirit. We felt love, joy, and peace, which are fruits of the Spirit (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/gal/5.22" class="scriptureRef">Galatians 5:22</a>). You will need that peace and assurance when Satan tries to confuse you with winds of doubt, when you are tempted to take another path, or when others are unkind or mock you for your beliefs.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p23" pid="tuTBJ47DiUukaAc0aDqgHw" hash="KYCW1A">Let me share with you the experience of Julie, a young woman who was able to face a challenge by following the promptings of the Holy Ghost. She was studying the Old Testament one day, and the thought came to her mind, “Read <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 5</a>. Read <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 5</a>.” She thought, “Why would the thought come to me to read the New Testament?” She acted on that prompting and read in Matthew, “Love your enemies, bless them that curse you, do good to them that hate you, and pray for them which despitefully use you, and persecute you” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.44" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 5:44</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p24" pid="hgBbdc165kWMvC2XRUj4VA" hash="xe_EVA">The next day she had some difficulties with her friends who were unkind and betrayed her. At first she was very upset, and then she thought, “I’ve been prepared for this. The Spirit prompted me to read Matthew, and I must love and pray for my friends.” The small step of reading the scriptures prepared her to respond in a Christlike way. From that experience, she was assured that the Lord knew her, and through the promptings of the Holy Ghost, she knew what she was to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up.p25" pid="C1RNiq7qa0uJwbPyvRndwA" hash="asqqbA">My dear young women, I have met many of you who, just like Julie, have not given up when faced with difficult circumstances but have chosen to follow the plan. I pray that step by step you will continue to strengthen your testimony. Seek the help of our Heavenly Father, Jesus Christ, prophets, and others who will support you in your decision to follow the plan. Live a virtuous life so that you may have the companionship of the Holy Ghost to safely guide you. I testify that if you will do these things, the Lord will be with you and you will be able to stay on the path that leads to the temple and to eternal life. “Be strong and of a good courage” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/1.9" class="scriptureRef">Joshua 1:9</a>) and never, never, never give up! In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/04/never-never-never-give-up</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2010-general-young-women-meeting/2010-03-0020-mary-n-cook-64k-eng.mp3" length="5642001" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2010 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be an Example of the Believers</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I would like to invite you to “be … an example of the believers … in faith [and] in purity.”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021411_000_4040" doc-version="2" hash="E_wtiA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="3GMz-rLBtU6TSgsgck028Q" hash="mUTHdg">Be an Example of the Believers</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="JIGWvpt0LkS2Lmzu0IxIwg" hash="eowP4Q">Mary N. Cook</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="UMiKBFpM_kyh7yE1Pmr87Q" hash="3yktAA">I would like to invite you to “be … an example of the believers … in faith [and] in purity.”</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p1" pid="jMHZQGqPTkSIq6QiNHEiwA" hash="W1rQjA">A short time ago little Ruby was born into our family. As I looked into her sweet face, I marveled at the knowledge that before she came to earth, she lived in the presence of our Heavenly Father. She had accepted His great plan of happiness and chose to follow Him and Jesus Christ, our Savior.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Because of her decision, she was permitted to come to earth to experience mortality and progress toward eternal life. With her spirit united with her body, Ruby has entered a time of learning in which she can prove herself, choose to follow Christ, and prepare to be worthy of eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p2" pid="-RJtWwXznUq3L1Y4FwMB3A" hash="bhIasw">Ruby came to this earth pure, but as part of the plan, she will face trials and temptations and she will make mistakes. Through our Savior’s Atonement, however, Ruby can be forgiven, receive a fulness of joy, and be pure again—ready to live forever in the presence of our Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p3" pid="o6_4VUnidkyamTnP3uKtRw" hash="Avl6Cw">A few hours after her birth, I was privileged to hold this precious child in my arms. I said to her mother, “Oh, we have to teach Ruby how to be a virtuous woman, pure and priceless as her name implies.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p4" pid="vu9dzre8H0iAEHHSA0YBGg" hash="ZE4nPQ">Her mother replied, “I am starting today.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p5" pid="0ZTl5Ajv8EeNWiCYjEzitQ" hash="BG5NJQ">What will Ruby’s mother do to “start today”? How can we as parents, grandparents, and leaders start and keep our children—our youth—on the path to eternal life? We must “be … [examples] of the believers.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p6" pid="oXSCZCMi2US_Zy0FJWmm0g" hash="Rl04BQ">The prophet Brigham Young said: “We should never permit ourselves to do anything that we are not willing to see our children do. We should set them an example that we wish them to imitate.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Each of us can start today by being that good example.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p7" pid="QUaz7Rejx0KTrEobgzDuhw" hash="n5xGqw">Today I would like to invite you to “be … an example of the believers … in faith [and] in purity”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span>—two principles required for salvation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p8" pid="4nHevxF2Hk67xpSbLcposA" hash="i0szGg">Be an example of the believers in faith. Actively strengthen your own faith and testimony of Jesus Christ, thus preparing to testify by word and example to your children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p9" pid="hm55ELJNvUK4fOJsxwRvXQ" hash="x6o4aA">Let me tell you of a wonderful mother whose life was an example of faith. When the Prophet Joseph Smith was a very young boy, he watched and learned about faith in God from his mother, Lucy Mack Smith. Lucy sought answers by searching the scriptures,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> and Joseph too employed the practice, turning to the Bible for guidance as his mother had.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p10" pid="taiD5PopwkG6eqtKSKji6Q" hash="CeAtpw">Lucy also solved family problems by privately seeking the Lord’s help through prayer. One day, experiencing discord in her family regarding the subject of religion, Lucy said she “retired to a grove of handsome wild cherry trees not far distant and prayed to the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p11" pid="x6wAltT73UOQzqDdl46mYg" hash="kkK_hw">Lucy also prayed with great faith when faced with personal health issues, when Joseph nearly lost his leg to osteomyelitis, and when Joseph’s sister Sophronia almost died from typhoid fever. Regarding Sophronia’s illness, Lucy wrote: “I gazed upon my child. … My husband and I clasped our hands together and fell upon our knees by the bedside and poured our grief and supplications into his ears.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Sophronia lived. I am confident that Lucy’s children often witnessed her praying with faith and receiving answers to those prayers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p12" pid="Eiz2GMUqkUmAybMkACUFkQ" hash="TFLrAA">Lucy prayed in faith for guidance, and Joseph too retired to a grove of trees, where he prayed with faith, seeking an answer from the Lord as his mother had.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p13" pid="I0rxdVA_F0WYahMfRRO_Tg" hash="3vx_Rg">Like Lucy, we must show our children and youth how to strengthen their faith and testimony of Jesus Christ by strengthening our own through studying the scriptures and through prayer, personally as well as with them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p14" pid="JpPpjQnIU0aWjP-hpj050A" hash="TeKt0A">Unlike Lucy, today we are blessed to have more than the Bible. We have latter-day scriptures and the words of our latter-day prophets to “safely guide us”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> on the path to eternal life. From the Book of Mormon we learn about those on the path who were “continually holding fast to the rod of iron,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> likening it to “the word of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> In today’s world replete with temptations, “holding fast” can be challenging, as Satan in his conniving ways tries to pull us away from God’s ways. If we have one hand on the rod and one hand in the world, we put our children and youth in danger of losing their way on the path. If our example is confusing, then in Jacob’s words we lose “the confidence of [our] children, because of [our] bad examples.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p15" pid="zQ7T7k3-hU6CyFBY6Ymq3w" hash="tHRJHw">Parents, grandparents, and leaders, your message must be clear. Clarity can only result from having both hands on the rod and from living by the truths found in the scriptures and the words of latter-day prophets. You may not be raising a prophet as Lucy was, but you are certainly raising tomorrow’s leaders, and your actions are just as tangibly linked to their faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p16" pid="SdXPEldxgk-UF5TOMWVFLQ" hash="516ESA">Next, be an example of the believers in purity. The only way for us to become pure is through the Atonement of our Savior. For each of us, the process of becoming pure begins with faith, repentance, and our first covenant of baptism.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p17" pid="fzKHnDofy0OP6L_TJRA7WA" hash="P-EJ5w">To help our children live their baptismal covenant, Elder Robert D. Hales advised: “We teach that the moment they step out of the water, they step out of the world and into the kingdom of God. By covenant, they agree to obey His commandments.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p18" pid="H2JkIipGU0CbMqhPTHYxOQ" hash="4rraJg"> “Covenants place us under a strong obligation to honor our commitments to God. To keep our covenants, we must give up activities or interests that prevent us from honoring those covenants.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p19" pid="pAegUakM6k64sp7urFOZKw" hash="vQoxAQ">
        <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth</span> is a marvelous tool to help youth understand this sacred obligation of covenant making and the blessings of purity that come from covenant keeping. It contains words of latter-day prophets—the iron rod that will safely guide them along the strait and narrow path, turning them away from Satan’s entrapments that can delay their progress. In this booklet, you will also find the many blessings that come from obedience and seeking that which is “virtuous [and] lovely.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p20" pid="Lz0NigDaQEmhhG9JLXqgaQ" hash="URQAcg">Parents, obtain a personal copy of this booklet and read it often. Live the standards yourself. Have thoughtful gospel conversations with youth that will help them develop their own desire to live and discover for themselves the meaning and purpose of the standards.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p21" pid="ziWG7YG5T0uejKE3qu5jXQ" hash="ORccHA">The standards found in the sections “Entertainment and the Media” and “Dress and Appearance” can be particularly challenging because they are becoming increasingly at odds with the standards of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p22" pid="X9uQpwnsY0aqacyQr12Y6w" hash="NPqcPA">We must model that which is virtuous and lovely by our personal media choices. We must take care that the media we invite into our homes does not dull the sensitivity to the Spirit, harm relationships with our family and friends, or reveal personal priorities that are inconsistent with gospel principles. By example we can help our children understand that spending long periods of time using the Internet, social media, and cell phones; playing video games; or watching television keeps us from productive activities and valuable interactions with others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p23" pid="iY6TqOxch06xY25EIifR4Q" hash="JQ-qIA">We also model that which is virtuous and lovely by our dress and appearance. As a covenant people we have the responsibility to care for, protect, and properly clothe our bodies. We must help our children and youth understand that we respect our bodies as temples and as gifts from God.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> We set the example by refusing to purchase or wear immodest clothing that is too tight, too sheer, or revealing in any other manner.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p24" pid="UsSCh7_tlkCqqSN-3gXUog" hash="HnkdUw">Covenant keepers strive to be obedient “at all times … and in all places”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> because of their love of God and His promised blessings. One evening, while walking with my husband, we passed by an outdoor wedding reception in progress. We didn’t know these people, yet there was an immediate impression of virtue. Their choices of music and dress were lovely. The radiant bride’s gown was unquestionably modest, as were her bridal attendants’ dresses. This family chose not to mix the ways of the world with the sanctity of that day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p25" pid="tHN_URkiJEq30m2NkB2Jgg" hash="VrtDCw">Now, may I say a word to the marvelous youth of our Church. Thank you for your righteous examples to your friends, teachers, leaders, and families. I recognize that many of you are the only member of the Church in your family. You may even attend church alone. I commend you for your commitment and righteous example. Be patient and continue to live righteously. There are many who can help you. President Thomas S. Monson said, “Even an exemplary family … can use all the supportive help they can get from good men [and women] who genuinely care.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p26" pid="sjc5nj3k8kOnOCXxLI5DDg" hash="_KYK8Q">Look around in your ward and stake for leaders and friends who are examples of the believers and learn from them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p27" pid="pT0UEqimCkqib2JkQfm9Cw" hash="9BvXNw">When I was a young woman, I identified examples of the believers. In addition to my parents, one was my aunt Carma Cutler. I vividly remember her speaking at a stake standards night when I was 16. She taught of the importance of being chaste and worthy of a temple marriage. I was deeply touched by her testimony. I had observed her virtuous life since I was a very young girl, and I knew it was consistent with her teachings. I wanted to follow her example.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p28" pid="txo32_VLIESUlDfFFtRoBw" hash="Ofls-w">Young men and young women, <span class="emphasis">you</span> can start today by being an example of the believers in faith and in purity. Strengthen your faith and testimony daily through scripture study and prayer. Keep your baptismal covenant, which will keep you pure and worthy of the guidance of the Holy Ghost. You can start today to be that example for others to follow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p29" pid="qzoF872-tUeVpx6caFggsw" hash="xCaJcA">And you never know—you might be the example my little Ruby will need someday. For now, Ruby has a wonderful start on the path to eternal life. Her parents are setting patterns of righteousness in her home, starting each day with a resolve to be examples of the believers. Hopefully, using her agency, Ruby will choose to follow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers.p30" pid="HVATGqNpSkOoLd0gdSoPiw" hash="9iwSRg">I am grateful for the plan of happiness, and I testify it is the only way that Ruby—and each of us—can be pure again and live forever in the presence of our Father in Heaven. May we each start today. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/10/be-an-example-of-the-believers</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2010-general-conference/2010-10-4040-mary-n-cook-64k-eng.mp3" length="5159373" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2010 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Remember This: Kindness Begins with Me”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Benevolence can bring joy and unity to your home, your class, your ward, and your school.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50028768_000_0020" doc-version="1" hash="rTPJJw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.head1">
    <h1 class="title" pid="JbJjMyoLX0CGZt25yOJpUg" hash="pvZ_oA">“Remember This: Kindness Begins with Me”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="7g5nulU0FECoCs-xeRTgEw" hash="eowP4Q">Mary N. Cook</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="SopuhdioXkWM4o0e1WLeag" hash="6Mgvmw">Benevolence can bring joy and unity to your home, your class, your ward, and your school.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p1" pid="vJAOaSXx_0GG_QkFCYsYJQ" hash="SDrmWw">A few weeks ago I learned an important lesson from a Laurel who was the youth speaker in my ward. I was touched as she confidently taught and testified of Jesus Christ. She concluded her remarks with this statement: “When I make Jesus Christ the center of my life, my day goes better, I’m kinder to my loved ones, and I am filled with joy.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p2" pid="PKP3FaCRkkCmUih2GksRbg" hash="fGBoew">I have observed this young woman from a distance over the past few months. She greets everyone with sparkling eyes and a quick smile. I’ve watched her rejoice in the success of other youth. Two Mia Maids recently reported to me of this young woman’s decision to forfeit her ticket to a movie when she realized that it was not going to be an experience that was “virtuous and lovely.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> She’s loving, kind, and obedient. She comes from a single-parent home, and her life has not been without challenges, so I’ve wondered how she maintains her happy, kind spirit. When this young woman testified, “I center my life on Jesus Christ,” I had the answer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p3" pid="OJol10bYNEiISTvTVhkLPw" hash="DT4sXA">“We believe in being honest, true, chaste, benevolent, virtuous, and in doing good to all men.” This beautiful list of Christlike attributes, found in the thirteenth article of faith, will prepare us for temple blessings and eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p4" pid="5UwQUZIr1U2Rg3YUDTLWdA" hash="uZ40EA">I would like to focus on just one of these words—<span class="emphasis">benevolent.</span> <span class="emphasis">Benevolent</span> is a lovely word that we don’t hear very often. Its roots are Latin, and it means “to wish someone well.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> To be benevolent is to be kind, well meaning, and charitable. Many of you learned about the idea of benevolence when you were in Primary and committed this song to memory:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="uktSz6jpr0C8oLOOhxHSjg" hash="BR4qFw">I want to be kind to ev’ryone,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="ZB_Wh066AE6X7uUPXzapZg" hash="L4Qtmg">For that is right, you see.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="jDrUKmmOrEecN7NNp-Sl1Q" hash="i9m1Bw">So I say to myself, “Remember this:</p>
          <p class="line" pid="LoFL1U7EtkmABBmKx4T5Wg" hash="P8H7fw">Kindness begins with me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p5" pid="hHNO6GnNlUSO_gudKW0UKQ" hash="OX1L3g">Our Savior taught us about and lived a benevolent life. Jesus loved all and He served all. Centering our lives on Jesus Christ will help us acquire this attribute of benevolence. For us to develop these same Christlike attributes, we must learn about the Savior and “follow in His ways.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p6" pid="2hdZYd5NKkCABDgKnheyzA" hash="nFHXVA">From the parable of the good Samaritan we learn that we are to love all. The story begins in Luke, chapter 10, when a lawyer asked the Savior, “What shall I do to inherit eternal life?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p7" pid="G76TmdAdR0eIrTxsQSxxyw" hash="yF2lZQ">The answer: “Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy strength, and with all thy mind; and thy neighbour as thyself.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p8" pid="7Xi7isxxQEC3cjoeSA4nPg" hash="iXVODw">The lawyer then asked, “Who is my neighbour?” That was a very interesting question for the lawyer to ask, since the Jews had neighbors to the north, the Samaritans, whom they disliked so much that when they traveled from Jerusalem to Galilee, they would take the longer way through the Jordan Valley rather than travel through Samaria.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p9" pid="y4Gx_deaskmeKNfz4HDr2g" hash="7Tromg">Jesus answered the lawyer’s question by telling the parable of the good Samaritan. According to the parable:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p10" pid="e5s3LtnMvkSg5A3_xVmN1Q" hash="OOolRg">“A certain man went down from Jerusalem to Jericho, and fell among thieves, which stripped him of his raiment, and wounded him, and departed, leaving him half dead. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p11" pid="Q2A3QvBNAUiHn5On0z3JCQ" hash="xab-Gg">“But a certain Samaritan, as he journeyed, came where he was: and when he saw him, he had compassion on him,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p12" pid="CXKno7Jf50Wfirw4Lw5B-A" hash="0Ku1Sg">“And went to him, and bound up his wounds, pouring in oil and wine, and set him on his own beast, and brought him to an inn, and took care of him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p13" pid="uwiHrSa3wEeYjjpwJZ8pCw" hash="Mkm3qw">“And on the morrow when he departed, he took out two pence, and gave them to the host, and said unto him, Take care of him; and whatsoever thou spendest more, when I come again, I will repay thee.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p14" pid="VuFKzeICo0mmDJrnkp94pw" hash="OKBGnQ">Unlike the Jewish priest and Levite who passed by the wounded man, one of their own, the Samaritan was kind regardless of differences. He demonstrated the Christlike attribute of benevolence. Jesus taught us through this story that everyone is our neighbor.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p15" pid="WbxC1blBjE660qnnNbKjdg" hash="sg5Nyg">A counselor in a bishopric recently shared an experience that teaches how important each neighbor is. While looking out over the congregation, he saw a child with a large box of crayons filled with a variety of different hues. As he looked at the many members of his ward, he was reminded that, like the crayons, they were very similar but each person was also very unique.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p16" pid="DAt6BvKJoka0xySY-G94gw" hash="4im7Yg">He remarked: “The shade they brought to the ward and the world was all their own. … They had their individual strengths and weaknesses, personal longings, private dreams. But together, they blended into a color wheel of spiritual unity. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p17" pid="o80X8WONSEGq7rjeilUFeA" hash="FZN_Hw">“Unity is a spiritual quality. It’s the sweet feelings of peace and purpose that come from belonging to a family. … It’s wanting the best for others as much as you want it for yourself. … It’s knowing that no one is out to harm you. [It means you will never be lonely.]”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p18" pid="3RAvS2TE3EKUcmFIBBur5Q" hash="-LhRPw">We build that unity and share our unique colors through benevolence: individual acts of kindness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p19" pid="NykiEQSNEkaOklzlWpsHSA" hash="I6hJSQ">Have you ever felt lonely? Do you notice those who are lonely, living in a black-and-white world? Young women, I’ve watched as you bring your unique color into the lives of others with your smiles, your kind words, or a note of encouragement.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p20" pid="fEMeKQmTdUy_1dYeMLYGVQ" hash="17GV8Q">President Thomas S. Monson taught us how to interact with our peers and everyone we meet when he told the young women of the Church, “My precious young sisters, I plead with you to have the courage to refrain from judging and criticizing those around you, as well as the courage to make certain everyone is included and feels loved and valued.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p21" pid="7aEM-CeZxEufCqYBZAX1uA" hash="kcJ5Ng">We can follow the example of the good Samaritan and “change the world” of just one person by being benevolent.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> I would like to invite each of you to do at least one Samaritan-like act this coming week. It may require that you reach beyond your usual friends or overcome your shyness. You may courageously choose to serve someone who doesn’t treat you well. I promise that if you will extend yourself beyond what is easy to do, you will feel so good inside that kindness will start to become a part of your everyday life. You’ll see that benevolence can bring joy and unity to your home, your class, your ward, and your school. “Remember this: kindness begins with me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p22" pid="pp-ousWxKEKoz17xLRfMHA" hash="XVU4yQ">Not only did our Savior love all; He served all. Expand your goodness to many. Old and young can be greatly blessed by your kind service. President Monson, since the time he was a young man, has always had a special place in his heart for the elderly. He recognizes the value of a short visit, a ready smile, or a squeeze of a well-worn, wrinkled hand. Such simple acts of charity bring color into a life that sometimes is made up of long, lonely, gray days. I would invite each of you to be mindful of your grandparents and the elderly. Look around at church tomorrow and identify those who could use your shade of color added to their life. It doesn’t take much: greet them by name, engage them in a short conversation, be available to assist them. Could you open a door or offer to help with their home or garden? What is a simple task to you at your young age can be an overwhelming project for an older person. “Remember this: kindness begins with me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p23" pid="tHdgLfZjRU6mNC5iEJyYeA" hash="H0r0XQ">Sometimes being benevolent is most difficult in our own families. Strong families require effort. “Be cheerful, helpful, and considerate of others. Many problems in the home are created because family members speak and act selfishly or unkindly. Concern yourself with the needs of other family members. Seek to be a peacemaker rather than to tease, fight, and quarrel.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> “Remember this: kindness begins with me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p24" pid="SXajWGasuUWQfHY9ai3xig" hash="5VmTpw">Jesus loved the children, took them in His arms, and blessed them.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Like the Savior, you can bless all children with your kindness, not just those in your home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p25" pid="fTfYjGjo7U29M9EHSoI5Iw" hash="UbiSYg">You may not know the impact your life and example may have on a little child. I recently received a note from a friend who manages a day-care center in a local high school. Attending that high school are several young men and young women who are members of the Church. She shared with me this experience: “As I walk through the halls with the little children, it is nice to see how many lockers have pictures of Jesus or of temples taped to the inside of the doors. One of the children saw a picture of Jesus on the inside of a [young woman’s] opened locker door and said, ‘Look, Jesus is at our school!’ The student was moved to tears as she bent down and gave the child a hug. I thanked the young woman for the good example she was to those around her. It is uplifting to know that there are so many youth that are trying to stand for truth and righteousness and do their part in inviting the Spirit into their lives, even though it is difficult at times with all the noise and harshness in the world around them. We have some wonderful youth in the Church.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p26" pid="OZr-LPccvEGsW_75s364ng" hash="x9EBXw">I couldn’t agree more! Young women, <span class="emphasis">you</span> are changing the world by centering your life on Jesus Christ, and you are “becoming what He wants you to be.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p27" pid="u9Zq6Mq3AU672nd3EWyt1A" hash="gyOsOQ">Thank you for your benevolent lives; for including those who may be different; for your kindness to your peers, the elderly, your family, and little children; for being neighbors to those who are lonely and those who have challenges and heartache. Through your benevolence, you are “pointing others to [the Savior’s] light.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Thank you for remembering “kindness begins with me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p28" pid="-eG_mna2QESskSv91o6jng" hash="j4HiCQ">I know that President Thomas S. Monson is a prophet of God whose life has been a model of benevolence from which we can learn. Follow our prophet. Learn from his example and listen to his words. I believe in the gospel of Jesus Christ, and I know that through Joseph Smith the priesthood has been restored to the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me.p29" pid="5cs61wJZu0mv62J7BIEg6g" hash="i2hcoA">I know that our Savior lives and loves each of us. He has given His life for all. I pray that we will center our lives on Jesus Christ and “follow in His ways” by loving and serving one another.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> By so doing, I know that we can make the world a better place, because “we believe in being … benevolent.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> I so testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/04/remember-this-kindness-begins-with-me</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2011-general-young-women-meeting/2011-03-0020-mary-n-cook-64k-eng.mp3" length="5524874" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seek Learning: You Have a Work to Do</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Bless your children and your future home by learning as much as you can now.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10485_000_62cookm" doc-version="1" hash="9KlJtA">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="gUivNCkpyEu_MxYeiCOg6A" hash="vTegDg">Seek Learning: You Have a Work to Do</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="2Y9rt5P7CkOADH6fpP6lrw" hash="-QRzpg">By Mary N. Cook</p>
		<p class="kicker" pid="ICvEvmBLHU2BGwW_zUgFHw" hash="MI0Kxg">Bless your children and your future home by learning as much as you can now.</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p5" pid="Dqhf_KdFvkibvbkwpYCasw" hash="6uvhbA">
			<span class="pageBreak" page-number="120"></span>My dear young women, how we love each one of you. We see you courageously arising and shining forth with light in a world where great challenges accompany great opportunities. This may cause you to wonder, what does the future hold for me? I assure you that as you are a virtuous daughter of God, your future is bright! You live at a time when the truths of the gospel have been restored, and these truths can be found in your scriptures. You received the gift of the Holy Ghost at the time of your baptism, and the Holy Ghost will teach you truth and prepare you for life’s challenges.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p6" pid="_2mSywIV6ki0jonP7c7slA" hash="u5e0ZA">God gave you moral agency and the opportunity to learn while on earth, and He has a work for you to do. To accomplish this work, you have an individual responsibility to seek learning. The key to your future, your “bright ray of hope,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> can be found in the new <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth</span> booklet under the standard of education and in the Young Women value of knowledge.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p7" pid="9ukH5BPOa02ZHJRpjQ3amw" hash="0nmkRA">“Education … will open the doors of opportunity.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> As you follow the Lord’s admonition to “seek learning, even by study and also by faith,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> you gain not only knowledge from your study but added light as you learn by faith.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p8" pid="Pe8_tnBv_UKrkCacXEIWpw" hash="aXcZCA">Seek learning by studying diligently. Rarely will you be able to spend as much time dedicated to learning as you can now. President Gordon B. Hinckley wisely counseled the youth of the Church: “The pattern of study you establish during your formal schooling will in large measure affect your lifelong thirst for knowledge.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> “You must get all of the education that you possibly can. … Sacrifice anything that is needed to be sacrificed to qualify yourselves to do the work of [this] world. … Train your minds and hands to become an influence for good as you go forward with your lives.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p9" pid="_ANNHWOUakyk8vjTkHe6Xg" hash="iS_i8Q">In speaking specifically to women, President Thomas S. Monson said: “Often the future is unknown; therefore, it behooves us to prepare for uncertainties. … I urge you to pursue your education and learn marketable skills so that, should such a situation arise, you are prepared to provide.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p10" pid="VTZ8NK9PrUSS06WU1Jm5FA" hash="fW27nw">Young women, follow the advice of these wise and inspired prophets. Be a good student. Arise and shine forth in your schools with hard work, honesty, and integrity. If you are struggling or discouraged with your performance in school, seek help from your parents, teachers, and helpful Church members. Never give up!</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p11" pid="-EFuEQGOQ0WT-BzEcE6XKw" hash="2cgLJw">Make a list of the things you want to learn; then “share your educational goals with your family, friends, and leaders so they can support and encourage you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> This is the pattern of Personal Progress.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p12" pid="sKJsqv_-fkGLFmOtjA1wWQ" hash="kpBZiw">With technology you are witnessing an explosion of knowledge. You are constantly bombarded by sound, video, and networking. Be selective and don’t allow this surge of information to distract you or slow your progress. Arise, young women! <span class="emphasis">You</span> determine your goals. <span class="emphasis">You</span> decide what enters your mind and heart.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p13" pid="iSVBKOywF0qOEIxZr4h2OQ" hash="VrqUfA">Some of your most important learning will be outside of the classroom. Surround yourself with exemplary women who can teach you skills in homemaking, art, music, family history, sports, writing, or speaking. Get to know them and ask them to mentor you. When you have learned something new, teach it at Mutual or become a mentor to other young women as part of the requirements for your Honor Bee.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p14" pid="ncIsXu_sBE-efG8UV2FA2A" hash="OD_9Xw">In addition to my wonderful mother, I’ve had many mentors in my life. I first became acquainted with the process of mentoring when I was just nine years old. My Primary teacher taught me to cross-stitch “I Will Bring the Light of the Gospel into My Home,” a picture that hung in my room during my teenage years. My teacher guided me, corrected me, and always encouraged me along the way. Other mentors followed. Two excellent seamstresses in my ward taught me sewing. With their guidance, <span class="pageBreak" page-number="121"></span>patience, and encouragement, I entered a dress in a sewing contest when I was 14, and I actually won a prize! The process increased my thirst for knowledge and excellence in other areas as well.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p15" pid="P5E3ZpaR802oz4i4Hiwwnw" hash="lKv5hg">Gaining knowledge now will pay huge dividends when you become a mother. “A mother’s education level has a profound influence on the educational choices of her [children].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> A mother’s education can hold the “key to halt [the] poverty cycle.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Educated women “tend to: Give birth to healthier babies, have children who are healthier, be more confident, resilient and have improved reasoning and judgment.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p16" pid="Um7rDjEP-kqwd2jQ6tf8Ow" hash="NRQz8Q">We learn in “The Family: A Proclamation to the World” that “mothers are primarily responsible for the nurture of their children.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> Providing an education for your children is part of that nurturing and is your sacred responsibility. Like the stripling warriors, who “had been taught by their mothers,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> you will be the most important teacher your children will ever have, so choose your learning carefully. Bless your children and your future home by learning as much as you can now.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p17" pid="zFlsmbKnAUGL4stEEqY0WQ" hash="kYTWaw">Seek learning by faith. We learn by faith as we diligently gain spiritual knowledge through prayer, scripture study, and obedience and as we seek the guidance of the Holy Ghost, who testifies of all truth. If you do your part to gain knowledge, the Holy Ghost can enlighten your mind. As you strive to keep yourself worthy, the Holy Ghost will give direction and added light to your learning.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p18" pid="EyCO1K84R0yeXyBBf1iWNg" hash="C2JWbw">When I was a young woman, I borrowed skis that were way too long and boots that were way too big, and a friend taught me to ski! We went on a beautiful spring day filled with bright sun, perfect snow, and cloudless, blue skies. Anxiety about the steep slopes gave way to delight as I learned. And though I tumbled quite a few times on those long skis, I got up and I kept trying. I came to love the sport!</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p19" pid="0LbuBOm4rEqM70F16UweeA" hash="gZsgaw">I soon found out, however, that not all ski days and weather conditions were that ideal. On days with overcast skies, we skied in a condition called “flat light.” Flat light occurs when the light from the sun is diffused by the clouds. Looking ahead at the white snow, you find that your depth perception vanishes, and it is difficult to judge the steepness of the slope or see the moguls and bumps on the hill.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p20" pid="xSBX2JkSHUKOrv1PfUbgaw" hash="iD39JA">Young women, you may be looking forward to your future as I looked at that steep ski slope. You may feel at times that you are living in flat light, unable to see what lies ahead of you. Learning by faith will give you confidence and will help you navigate your way through times of uncertainty.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p21" pid="QGDbtPQE30qL9jLwyMiViw" hash="joA-VA">In the 25th chapter of Matthew, the parable of the ten virgins teaches us that spiritual preparation is vital and must be achieved individually. You will recall that all ten virgins were <span class="pageBreak" page-number="122"></span>invited to escort the bridegroom into the wedding feast, but only the five wise virgins were prepared with oil in their lamps.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p22" pid="WHLmd4h9A0-_2uhviYPabA" hash="CyFCeg">“And the foolish said unto the wise, Give us of your oil; for our lamps are gone out.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p23" pid="jqw_SY5JJ0u_7mAQRTQ1XA" hash="JXveig">“But the wise answered, saying, Not so; lest there be not enough for us and you: but go ye rather to them that sell, and buy for yourselves.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p24" pid="oMqFWUfMcUmyoN9AA3ZD9A" hash="GE65tA">“And while they went to buy, the bridegroom came; and they that were ready went in with him to the marriage: and the door was shut.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p25" pid="hX1hhXppzEyZW-84BP-q7g" hash="9vWbCw">You may think it selfish that the five wise virgins did not share their oil, but it was impossible. Spiritual preparation must be acquired individually, drop by drop, and cannot be shared.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p26" pid="6-2ninAYnkS4qyd0YjCH6Q" hash="12sQ3A">The time is now for you to diligently apply yourselves to increasing your spiritual knowledge—drop by drop—through prayer, scripture study, and obedience. The time is now to pursue your education—drop by drop. Each virtuous thought and action also adds oil to your lamps, qualifying you for the guidance of the Holy Ghost, our divine teacher.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p27" pid="Hzaj6oJqSkaMGPevPfOebw" hash="z_NAPQ">The Holy Ghost will guide you on your journey here in mortality, even when you feel you are in flat light, uncertain of what lies ahead. You need not fear. As you stay on the path that leads to eternal life, the Holy Ghost will guide you in your decisions and in your learning.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p28" pid="0DwmTUBRc0-MhNdvP3vquA" hash="R88cbg">I testify from personal experience that if you will seek learning not only by study but also by faith, you <span class="emphasis">will</span> be guided in what “the Lord … will need you to do and what you will need to know.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p29" pid="IqZqETiBxECuJqm8i258gw" hash="bTj22A">I received my patriarchal blessing as a young woman and was counseled to prepare myself with a good education and to learn early in life those virtues that go into homemaking and rearing a family. I so wanted the blessing of a family; however, that blessing wasn’t fulfilled until I was 37, when I eventually married. My husband had been widowed, so the day we were sealed in the temple, I was suddenly blessed with not only a husband but a family of four children.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p30" pid="AlOYOQSZO0WHmoxLy77l1A" hash="CUfr2w">Long before that, there were many days when I felt like I was skiing in flat light, asking the question, “What does the future hold for me?” I tried to follow the admonitions in my patriarchal blessing. I studied diligently to become a schoolteacher and continued my education to become an elementary school principal. I prayed to my Heavenly Father and sought the guidance of the Holy Ghost. I held fervently to the promise of prophets who assured me that if I “remain true and faithful, keep [my] covenants, serve God, and love [my] Father in Heaven and the Lord Jesus Christ, [I] will not be denied any of the eternal blessings our Heavenly Father has for His faithful children.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p31" pid="M5If7UPbjEeGjXy6IT5Frw" hash="9KYGuw">I know that my education prepared me for a life that has been nothing like I had envisioned as a young woman. I thought I was studying education to teach school and my future children, but I did not know the Lord was also preparing me to teach English in Mongolia on a mission with my husband and to teach the young women of the Church throughout the world and to teach my grandchildren the value of knowledge—all wonderful blessings I could never have imagined.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do.p32" pid="UUDH0W_sjkipu8926ZMq7w" hash="ehfwOg">I testify that our Father in Heaven does know and love you. He has placed great trust in you and has work that only <span class="emphasis">you</span> can do. I want to assure you that you <span class="emphasis">will</span> be prepared for that great work if you seek learning by study and also by faith. Of this I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2012/04/seek-learning-you-have-a-work-to-do</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2012-general-young-women-meeting/2012-03-0020-mary-n-cook-64k-eng.mp3" length="5484831" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When You Save a Girl, You Save Generations</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Your virtuous lives will bless your ancestors, your families now, and family members yet to come.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10785_000_62cook" doc-version="1" hash="1Du99A">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="9RoLkp9JF0yDxvxbW7FADw" hash="yMiRIA">When You Save a Girl, You Save Generations</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="rC1HSO_lb06xrdcprXJ2uQ" hash="-QRzpg">By Mary N. Cook</p>
		<p class="kicker" pid="H8_IMafAA02NWv0BW8_VcQ" hash="mLiUkA">Your virtuous lives will bless your ancestors, your families now, and family members yet to come.</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="DjWz3sn050mU8XYDSGQ8pQ" hash="rqzS4w">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p5" pid="IlYl9gvLlEKoaWuOUP4ajg" hash="sC8sHg"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="118"></span>It is an honor for me to address the valiant young women of the Church. We see you progressing on the path of those who honor their covenants, and we know your virtuous lives will bless your ancestors, your families now, and family members yet to come, for as President Gordon B. Hinckley stated, “When you save a girl, you save generations.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p6" pid="Sa2s2HR5nkCnCjNpJa7_uQ" hash="yoYwIw">Your covenant path began at the time when you were baptized and received the gift of the Holy Ghost. It continues weekly in sacrament meeting, a holy place where you renew your baptismal covenant. Now is the time for you to prepare to make temple covenants. The “sacred ordinances and covenants available in holy temples make it possible for [us] to return to the presence of God and for [our] families to be united eternally.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p7" pid="2tgFRs2kDEWVKF6H8bQSFA" hash="5eo1vQ">Stand in holy places for your ancestors. “Every human being who comes to this earth is the product of generations of parents. We have a natural yearning to connect with our ancestors.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> As you participate in family history and temple work, you weave your life with the lives of your ancestors by providing saving ordinances for them.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p8" pid="9Qm5sPUx30-wGTNhTTHZKw" hash="0S9IXQ">Stand in holy places for yourself and your immediate family. Your righteous example will be a source of great joy, regardless of your family circumstances. Your righteous choices will qualify you to make and keep sacred covenants that will bind your family together eternally.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p9" pid="n_xFNT_yRkqVVHF7oumAKw" hash="6dXe5A">Stand in holy places for your future family. Commit to being sealed to your husband by the holy priesthood in the temple as you begin an eternal family unit. Your children will be blessed with truth as you weave your virtuous example and unshakable testimony into their lives and show them the way on the covenant path.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p10" pid="TdMsnJJOxEG_il-h2rjVLg" hash="F7lApA">I saw these eternal principles displayed at the recent International Art Competition for Youth. Megan Warner Taylor digitally composed a work of photography, taking a modern approach to Christ’s parable of the ten virgins.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> I met Megan, and she explained the symbolism of the tenth virgin, whom she described as a young woman of virtue and faith, prepared to make and keep sacred temple covenants. As with all the wise virgins, her individual preparation came as she added oil to her lamp, one drop at a time, by consistent righteous living. I noted the beautiful braid in her hair. Megan explained that the braid represented the weaving of this young woman’s virtuous life into countless generations. One strand represented the weaving of her love and respect for her ancestors, the second the weaving of her righteous influence upon her current family, and the third strand the weaving of her prepared life into the lives of generations to come.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p11" pid="-_eHzX4TTEiUNp7LZhbhIg" hash="syIczw">I met another young woman whose early spiritual preparation has woven a life of righteousness into many generations.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p12" pid="UtoWsWp2w06VzkB_mBnReg" hash="WCHC1w">On a beautiful September afternoon, my husband and I were in the temple awaiting the opportunity to participate in temple ordinances. Chris, a friend of ours, entered the room. It was great to see this young man, who had recently returned from a mission to Russia.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p13" pid="2u9g_zXOjU2H3qdczapBhw" hash="2U3ddQ">As the session was about to begin, a lovely young woman sat next to me. She was radiant, smiling, and filled with light. I wanted to know her, so I quietly introduced myself. She whispered her name, Kate, and I recognized her last name as a family that had lived in Michigan, where my family once lived. Kate was their grown-up daughter, who five weeks earlier had returned from her mission to Germany.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p14" pid="HNKG0rKtoE65A7uz39S4Gg" hash="qbJ6UQ">During the session the thought kept entering my mind: “Introduce Kate to Chris.” I put this prompting aside, thinking, “When, where, how?” As we were preparing to leave, Chris came over to tell us good-bye and I seized the opportunity. I pulled Kate over <span class="pageBreak" page-number="119"></span>and whispered, “You are two virtuous young people who need to know each other.” I left the temple satisfied that I had acted upon my prompting.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p15" pid="K8l0Am92ckqdx9fT64-QZA" hash="FI6jtw">On the way home, my husband and I discussed our recollections of the challenges that had come to Kate’s family. I have since come to know Kate better, and she has helped me understand the reasons for the joyful countenance I observed in the temple that day.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p16" pid="4DStMfJA3EOA-xwBPyR7qQ" hash="odKI9g">Kate has always tried to stay on her covenant path by seeking holy places. She was raised in a home where having family home evening, praying together, and studying the scriptures made her home a holy place. As a child, she learned about the temple, and the song “I Love to See the Temple” was a favorite for family home evening.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> As a little girl, she watched her parents set an example of seeking a holy place as they went to the temple on a weekend evening instead of going to a movie or to dinner.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p17" pid="plZz6je2b0ygu5mFrK3Aeg" hash="6v10bQ">She loved her father dearly, and he used his priesthood authority to help her make her first covenant of baptism. She then had hands laid on her head and received the Holy Ghost. Kate said, “I was excited to receive the Holy Ghost, and I knew that it would help me stay on the path to eternal life.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p18" pid="cMhIfcqUDEWt2O9N3q9fMg" hash="9YaJiw">Life continued on for Kate in a very blessed and happy way. When she was 14, she started high school and loved seminary, another holy place to learn about the gospel. One day her teacher started to talk about trials and guaranteed that we would all face them. She said to herself, “I don’t want trials; I don’t want to hear this.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p19" pid="QA9cwSUjZEGn6p-e74nagw" hash="dezvZg">It was just a few weeks later that her father woke up on Easter Sunday extremely ill. Kate said: “My father was a very healthy person; he was a marathon runner. My mother was so alarmed by how sick he was that she took him to the hospital. Within 36 hours he had a massive stroke that shut down most of his body. He could blink, but the rest of his body was not working. I remember seeing him and thinking, ‘Oh no, it’s happening. My seminary teacher was right. I am having a trial.’” Within a few days Kate’s father passed away.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p20" pid="V5kAnVUTeUyHV2TxQGVijw" hash="dIMUPQ">Continuing, Kate said: “It was so hard. You never want to lose the hero of your life. I knew I could make it a springboard for growth or allow it to be a roadblock. I didn’t want to let it ruin my life, because I was only 14 years old. I tried to be as close to the Lord as possible. I read my scriptures a lot. Alma chapter 40 assured me that the resurrection is real and through Christ’s Atonement, I could be with my father again. I prayed a lot. I wrote in my journal as often as I could. I kept my testimony vibrant by writing it down. I went to church and to Young Women every week. I surrounded myself with good friends. I kept close to caring relatives and especially to my mom, who was the anchor in our family. I sought out priesthood blessings from my grandfather and other priesthood holders.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p21" pid="5QDnM6q-CEq5heoaX--xxQ" hash="D4yNyw"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="120"></span>These consistent choices, like those of the wise virgin, added oil to Kate’s lamp. She was motivated by her desire to be with her father again. Kate knew her father was aware of her choices, and she did not want to disappoint him. She wanted an eternal relationship with him, and she understood that staying on her covenant path would keep her life woven tightly with his.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p22" pid="vNNG_vkTZkmOseJJrJwz9Q" hash="lsPDkA">The trials didn’t end, however. When Kate was 21 and submitting her mission papers, her mother was diagnosed with cancer. Kate had to make an important decision in her life. Should she stay home and support her mother or go on her mission? Her mother was given a priesthood blessing promising that she would survive the illness. Assured by this blessing, Kate went forward with faith and continued her plans to serve a mission.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p23" pid="cia1LyHVQkuoJ4o7VIrFOw" hash="nk5AXQ">Kate said: “It was taking a step in the dark, but while I was on my mission, the light eventually came and I received news that my mother’s blessing was realized. I was so glad that I didn’t put off serving the Lord. When hard things come, I think it’s easy to become stagnant and not really want to move forward, but if you put the Lord first, the adversities can lead to beautiful blessings. You can see His hand and witness miracles.” Kate experienced the reality of President Thomas S. Monson’s words: “Our most significant opportunities will be found in times of greatest difficulty.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p24" pid="PxCfsOpngEqOyQNop2njhw" hash="tC5bUg">Kate had this kind of faith because she understood the plan of salvation. She knew we lived before, that earth is a time of testing, and that we will live again. She had faith that her mother would be blessed, but from her experience with her father, she knew that if her mother were to pass away, it would be all right. She said: “I didn’t just survive my dad’s death; it became part of my identity for good, and had my mom been taken away, it would have done the same thing. It would have woven a greater testimony into my life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p25" pid="jkpWKI__FkOWvmqxquOBqg" hash="YKBzjA">Kate was seeking a holy place the night I met her in the temple. Desiring to weave tightly the eternal relationships that come through temple service, she followed the pattern set by her parents of regular temple attendance.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p26" pid="P5o8QQlTqUmn7DWAx6483A" hash="a4bIsg">Not much happened the night I introduced Kate to Chris, but in seeking another holy place the following Sunday, Kate saw Chris amid hundreds of young single adults at an institute devotional. There they found out more about each other. A few weeks later, Chris invited her to watch general conference with him. They continued seeking places that invited the Spirit throughout their courtship and were eventually sealed in the temple, the holy place where they were introduced. Both are now fulfilling the sacred responsibility of parenthood, weaving their testimonies of the plan of salvation into the lives of three little boys, showing them the way on the covenant path.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p27" pid="qkY-_gGQBkivzbzPueUu0A" hash="OmEYhw">“When you save a girl, you save <span class="pageBreak" page-number="121"></span>generations.” Kate’s decision as a 14-year-old to stay on the path, to consistently add oil to her lamp, and to stand in holy places <span class="emphasis">has</span> and <span class="emphasis">will</span> save generations. Seeking out her ancestors and serving in the temple have woven her heart with theirs. Participating in family history and temple work will likewise weave your hearts together and give your ancestors the opportunity of eternal life.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p28" pid="1M_275FznkGbOsqSBavIjA" hash="qDp0Mw">Living the gospel in your home will also add oil to your lamp and weave spiritual strength into your home now and bless your future family in countless ways. And furthermore, as Elder Robert D. Hales has said, “If the example we have received from our parents was not good, it is our responsibility to break the cycle … and teach correct traditions for the generations that follow.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations.p29" pid="49F1dVVbkEW2OKvHNV4FGA" hash="zAwwRA">Decide now to do all you can to fill your lamps, that your strong testimony and example may be woven into the lives of many generations—past, present, and future. I testify that your virtuous life will not only save generations, but it will also save <span class="emphasis">your</span> eternal life, for it is the only way to return to our Father in Heaven and find true joy now and throughout eternity. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2013/04/when-you-save-a-girl-you-save-generations</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2013-general-young-women-meeting/2013-03-0020-mary-n-cook-64k-eng.mp3" length="11625078" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
