<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Merlin R. Lybbert</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Merlin R. Lybbert.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Merlin%20R.%20Lybbert.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Merlin R. Lybbert.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 1990 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>A Latter-day Samaritan</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, there is a feeling of deep appreciation in my soul this afternoon as we worship together. On behalf of the members of the Church in Asia, where we are now serving, I extend their love to President Benson and to the other</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_90905_000_036" doc-version="2" hash="zxASBA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Yw0dCUzoy06b24QK_WvvCQ" hash="6u0pvA">A Latter-day Samaritan</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="3C86SwDjG06GomZyQXTRGw" hash="PqHwHg">Merlin R. Lybbert</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-21e2.jpg" alt="Elder Merlin R. Lybbert" pid="ySPJBo43pkW6hcZmHeQ1Lw" hash="W690iQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p1" pid="OmIrhwSIlkGIKVAeM6vDmQ" hash="HiAdZw">My dear brothers and sisters, there is a feeling of deep appreciation in my soul this afternoon as we worship together. On behalf of the members of the Church in Asia, where we are now serving, I extend their love to President Benson and to the other leaders that they have come to know and love, and to all of the members of the Church everywhere. It is a joy to serve among them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p2" pid="Nt_UsOZi6Euk-jr2_ORr5w" hash="pUc8UA">I also express my love and appreciation to my family and my aging parents for their unswerving support.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p3" pid="ijz2Yo20x0mn9Uei7q-rOw" hash="j_-01Q">When I measure myself against the enormity of the work before us, an overwhelming sense of humility washes over me. I have come to know that the work of the salvation of mankind is beyond the capacity of any man. It is indeed the work of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p4" pid="wpIe0NQYMU-aNC8n0bfg6w" hash="Mv5heQ">One of the best-known parables of the Savior is the story we have come to know as the good Samaritan. As related by Luke, a certain lawyer tempted Jesus, saying, “Master, what shall I do to inherit eternal life?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.25" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p5" pid="-_GXdulDkEGi8O5xK5jXsQ" hash="XRmTfA">In New Testament times a lawyer was the equivalent of a scribe, who was by profession a student and teacher of the law, including the written law of the Pentateuch, and also “the traditions of the elders.” (Bible Dictionary, s.v. <span class="emphasis">Lawyer</span>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p6" pid="9rFNvuZ-QUCxWD34vo9q0g" hash="i4sOEw">This learned man sought either to test the Lord concerning His knowledge of the law or to display his own. The Savior responded with a question: “What is written in the law? how readest thou?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.26" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:26</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p7" pid="Y48hP187DEemQA8mLmyAiA" hash="X-d_0g">The scholar responded, “Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy strength, and with all thy mind; and thy neighbour as thyself.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.27" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p8" pid="kZ2KLdMN1ECu4gp-VItaKQ" hash="W_pnIw">Jesus said unto him, “Thou hast answered right: this do, and thou shalt live.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.28" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p9" pid="mzylHa8onk2g-PEeQaJAMA" hash="osDPug">The answer to the inquiry was solicited from his own mouth through the questioning of the Lord, who then directed him to live in accordance with what he knew. However, the scholar was not satisfied with so simple a response. Luke records that the learned man, “willing to justify himself,” asked a further question of the Lord, “Who is my neighbour?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.29" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:29</a>.) And Jesus answered by telling a story:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p10" pid="UW-bprD1_kOvqJ-Oud-Rng" hash="wutI7Q">“A certain man went down from Jerusalem to Jericho, and fell among thieves, which stripped him of his raiment, and wounded him, and departed, leaving him half dead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p11" pid="HCNVOPVgbkiuDTu7TcMqHQ" hash="71JI-w">“And by chance there came down a certain priest that way: and when he saw him, he passed by on the other side.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p12" pid="CVY7GVeifEut80WeU20f0g" hash="3-Pa8Q">“And likewise a Levite, when he was at the place, came and looked on him, and passed by on the other side.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p13" pid="_WT7YKVe7U6WpZENDTtR2w" hash="xab-Gg">“But a certain Samaritan, as he journeyed, came where he was: and when he saw him, he had compassion on him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p14" pid="B1D7sGvmREWyrsIbtf1FRQ" hash="0Ku1Sg">“And went to him, and bound up his wounds, pouring in oil and wine, and set him on his own beast, and brought him to an inn, and took care of him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p15" pid="nYv99E27OEqpMuyutY71oA" hash="FeISGw">“And on the morrow when he departed, he took out two pence, and gave them to the host, and said unto him, Take care of him; and whatsoever thou spendest more, when I come again, I will repay thee.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.30-35" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:30–35</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p16" pid="rroFeYTVX0SFrHG1iWN6BQ" hash="OUaGbQ">Understanding of this parable is improved when we recall that the work of the ministering in the sanctuary was assigned to the tribe of Levi. The Levite’s duty was to assist the priests in their religious services. Likewise, the essential responsibility of a priest was to serve as a mediator between his people and God by representing them officially in worship and sacrifice. (See Bible Dictionary, s.v. <span class="emphasis">Priest </span>and <span class="emphasis">Levites</span>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p17" pid="ihawYIVa006nyFQ4wrcLcw" hash="35FWug">The people of Samaria consisted of a mixed population of Israelites and Gentiles. The Jews despised them. The priest and the Levite refused aid to the half-dead man who was in obvious need, and even distanced themselves from him by walking on the “other side.” It was the despised Samaritan who had compassion on the wounded fellow. He tenderly bound up his wounds, administered soothing oil, disinfected his wounds, placed him upon his own beast and took him to an inn, and stayed with him overnight. He then paid the cost of his care and assured the host that whatever more was spent would be repaid.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p18" pid="fLyXlEii-k618dS3zbycZA" hash="f6d6ZA">The Savior then asked a further question of the scholar, “Which now of these three, thinkest thou, was neighbour unto him that fell among the thieves?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.36" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:36</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p19" pid="h2pn9mCKRkOQB6fTB9zPsQ" hash="8x-HOg">The lawyer was caught in his own cunning, but accurately answered, “He that shewed mercy on him. Then said Jesus unto him, Go, and do thou likewise.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.37" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:37</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p20" pid="WYS8UqkGUkG9SLJeHVsMyg" hash="fN79iw">This was the second time in this brief conversation the scholar of religious law was instructed by the Savior to live in accordance with his knowledge of the principles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p21" pid="8c13NuZ6DEuF56cjkLalhg" hash="vhKV3w">I presume that most of us have visualized this parable as requiring our aid to an injured person, even a stranger, who is in need because of an injury or sickness. The beauty of the parables of the Lord is that they have many applications, and thus their teaching value is unending. I would like to suggest an application of the principles taught in this parable to a current setting.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p22" pid="CQBrmHiskESLyzuAZT5hgg" hash="9EaQ3g">There are many of God’s children who are wounded or sick in spirit. Many once enjoyed fellowship with the body of the Saints, but for one reason or another are now on the roadside. They are the less active among us. Generally, we know who they are and have association with them in various settings, but because they are not physically sick or injured, we too often play the part of the priest or the Levite and walk by “on the other side.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p23" pid="hcvApj9zAkyI5BjL6G4CEw" hash="ByhSnw">In this dramatic parable, Jesus contrasted the response of the two respected religionists with that of a despised citizen of Samaria. There is at least a scintilla of similarity here to an elders president, a high priests group leader, a member of the bishopric, or a home teacher, and to the less-active brother or sister who has fallen inactive by the wayside. Perhaps we do not despise them, but we sometimes ignore them or otherwise disregard them. Each of us can be a good Samaritan by dealing compassionately with these neglected brothers and sisters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p24" pid="4A0zIHfTjUeKe0eK28Wb-w" hash="mWh_sg">We can bind up their spiritual wounds by rendering needed service, pouring in the soothing oil of friendship and supplying the soul-healing balm of genuine brotherly and sisterly love. We can set them in our own automobiles and accompany them to our homes and places of worship, devote the necessary time and attention to warmly fellowship them. The good Samaritan spent the night with his wounded friend and stayed with him until satisfied that he was on his way to recovery. Similarly, we ought to become close enough to these less-active brothers and sisters to truly become their friends and support and sustain them while they spiritually heal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p25" pid="xP02CWy_XEeInmQiXzzh-Q" hash="MDWjeg">This parable also teaches that a little sacrifice and investment of one’s time and money may be necessary. Such healing care should not be given out of duty, but rendered out of a full heart. Indeed, even the lawyer seemed to catch the spirit of the Lord’s teachings in the parable, because it was he who defined a neighbor as “he that shewed mercy.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.37" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:37</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p26" pid="Kl2Ced3eP0Sk2CbD3wIWaQ" hash="e-UJVQ">Most of us are acquainted with someone who is spiritually ill or wounded, lying on the roadside half dead, and who desperately needs the assistance of a good LDS brother or sister—that is, <span class="emphasis">a Latter-day Samaritan.</span> Our prophet has repeatedly reminded us that rescuing the less active is one of our greatest challenges of service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p27" pid="zxYeCmRX8E2lwp3zmchgYQ" hash="i5XzBQ">I recount a simple parable, as told through an interpreter by a Sunday School president in Hong Kong:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p28" pid="2ILh34iNk0aMgfCAgbmOzw" hash="rR6How">“An enterprising turkey gathered the flock together and, following instructions and demonstrations, taught them how to fly. All afternoon they enjoyed soaring and flying and the thrill of seeing new vistas. After the meeting, all of the turkeys walked home.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p29" pid="e6Dhon9hi0ub-y-pGqPWLA" hash="zMXxOg">It is not our understanding of the principles of the gospel that brings the blessings of heaven, but the living of them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan.p30" pid="lvAXeVaaE0KC8opjaNMzKQ" hash="iDfREw">I pray that each of us will develop a receptive and understanding heart that will motivate us to seek out a less-active brother or sister and truly become a good Latter-day Samaritan. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1990/04/a-latter-day-samaritan</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1990-general-conference/1990-04-5060-elder-merlin-r-lybbert-64k-eng.mp3" length="9529373" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 1990 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Special Status of Children</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In a day when one of “the greatest problem[s] in our society is the abandonment of children through the abandonment of parental leadership” (Richard Lloyd Anderson,  Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1983, p. 354), the First Presidency has asked that</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_94905_000_016" doc-version="2" hash="XChj0g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="jh_q7y64cECaY8iG8vNBPA" hash="4G8AcA">The Special Status of Children</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="NO9mLzBuIUaAsYGLSOqouw" hash="PqHwHg">Merlin R. Lybbert</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-21e2.jpg" alt="Elder Merlin R. Lybbert" pid="ec6gvBXF_0G_rVBfUFNtBA" hash="W690iQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children.p1" pid="w4iprFzMO0O3MFWnPF0b7Q" hash="OD2YSQ">In a day when one of “the greatest problem[s] in our society is the abandonment of children through the abandonment of parental leadership” (Richard Lloyd Anderson, <span class="emphasis">Understanding Paul,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1983, p. 354), the First Presidency has asked that “we reemphasize the need for all adult members to focus on our children in an ongoing effort to help them learn to follow the teachings of the Savior.” Also they have asked each of us to “rededicate ourselves to nourish and bless them temporally and spiritually” (First Presidency Letter, 1 Aug. 1993; see <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Jan. 1994, p. 80).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children.p2" pid="NF3mueViYU2RUotqFua3bg" hash="-JeF6g">It may be helpful to review some of the doctrines as contained in the scriptures pertaining to the special status of children. These doctrines provide direction for those who are raising children and comfort to those of us who have lost a child in death at an early age.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children.p3" pid="bpDcAMZ7-kK-ASMM5gMRGg" hash="9DoA-w">Heavenly Father intended that each child should have the combined loving protection and guidance of caring parents. The pattern was established by Adam and Eve, our first parents. Joseph, the descendant of David, agreed to become the surrogate father of Jesus, the Son of God, when he accepted Mary as his wife, following a visitation of the angel Gabriel. In Nazareth, Joseph was regarded as the father of Jesus (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/13.55" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 13:55</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children.p4" pid="LcQxwOFEbUq5ja1ThOeGpw" hash="q98ccQ">The Christ child grew and developed in a modest home, where Joseph earned a humble living as a carpenter, and where Jesus also learned this craft (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/6.3" class="scriptureRef">Mark 6:3</a>). There were other members of the family. Mary and Joseph had four other sons and at least two daughters, all of whom were referred to in the community as the brothers and sisters of Jesus (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/13.55-56" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 13:55–56</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/6.3" class="scriptureRef">Mark 6:3</a>). The example of Joseph and Mary in providing a suitable home for their large family was such that Luke recorded that Jesus “grew, and waxed strong in spirit, filled with wisdom: and the grace of God was upon him” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/2.40" class="scriptureRef">Luke 2:40</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children.p5" pid="RBBSXaMp5UawsmBeug7XOQ" hash="O8qKcw">The Lord extends special protection to children and shares jurisdiction with earthly parents, even as we enjoy their presence. They cannot sin until they reach the age of accountability, which the Lord has declared to be eight years (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:42</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/29.47" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 29:47</a>). In fact, the power to even tempt them to commit sin has been taken from Satan. The prophet Mormon taught that “little children are whole, for they are not capable of committing sin. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children.p6" pid="tvl2eTjz4E-aV2-QyyffHw" hash="G1R0xA">“Little children are alive in Christ, even from the foundation of the world; if not so, God is a partial God, and also a changeable God, and a respecter to persons; for how many little children have died without baptism!” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/8.8,12" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 8:8, 12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children.p7" pid="hkSE69pepES1OLvot3NiYQ" hash="9oyKUg">Because they cannot sin, they have no need of repentance, neither baptism. Adam’s original transgression has no claim as a result of the atonement of Jesus Christ. Mormon declared the practice of baptizing little children to be a “solemn mockery before God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/8.9" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 8:9</a>), for repentance and baptism apply to those who are “accountable and capable of committing sin” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/8.10" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 8:10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children.p8" pid="RJC-2aoLlkqU9hiF-oYfeg" hash="4Uf0jA">Because all children who die before the age of accountability are pure, innocent, and wholly sin-free, they are saved in the celestial kingdom of heaven (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/137.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 137:10</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/3.18" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 3:18</a>). Understanding the special status of little children before God, because of their pure and innocent nature, brings understanding of the Lord’s commandment to “repent, and become as a little child, and be baptized in [His] name” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.37" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:37</a>). The childlike qualities the Lord had reference to are developed by yielding to “the enticings of the Holy Spirit,” so as to become “submissive, meek, humble, patient, full of love, willing to submit to all things which the Lord seeth fit to inflict upon him, even as a child doth submit to his father.” Truly, such a person “becometh a saint” as spoken by Mosiah (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/3.19" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 3:19</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children.p9" pid="NKBhY9LXv06XFelnx4hd9Q" hash="kEoovQ">Parents in Zion have the special responsibility of teaching and training their children in righteousness. They are to be taught “to understand the doctrine of repentance, faith in Christ the Son of the living God, and of baptism and the gift of the Holy Ghost by the laying on of the hands, when eight years old.” Otherwise, the Lord declared, “the sin be upon the heads of the parents” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.25" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:25</a>). This teaching is to be done before a child reaches the age of accountability, and while innocent and sin-free. This is protected time for parents to teach the principles and ordinances of salvation to their children without interference from Satan. It is a time to dress them in armor in preparation for the battle against sin. When this preparation time is neglected, they are left vulnerable to the enemy. To permit a child to enter into that period of his life when he will be buffeted and tempted by the evil one, without faith in the Lord Jesus Christ and an understanding of the basic principles of the gospel, is to set him adrift in a world of wickedness. During these formative, innocent years, a child may learn wrong behavior; but such is not the result of Satan’s temptations, but comes from the wrong teachings and the bad example of others. In this context, the Savior’s harsh judgment of adults who offend children is better understood, wherein he said, “It were better for him that a millstone were hanged about his neck, and he cast into the sea, than that he should offend one of these little ones” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/17.2" class="scriptureRef">Luke 17:2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children.p10" pid="nPjbOOrg8E6_JBaxrQRQMw" hash="iQYFFg">We offend a child by any teaching or example which leads a little one to violate a moral law; causes him to stumble, or go astray; excites him to anger; creates resentment; or perhaps even leads him to become displeasing and disagreeable. Certainly, in the context of the Savior’s harsh indictment concerning anyone who “offends” a child, one guilty of such conduct is in serious jeopardy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children.p11" pid="o_bGBKELm0CfULIPhNCYkQ" hash="Wd8XVg">Every child is entitled to live in a home, as Jesus did, where there is an environment permitting growth in gospel understanding, where each can wax strong in spirit and his life be filled with wisdom, so that the grace of God will be upon him (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/2.40" class="scriptureRef">Luke 2:40</a>). These precious little ones are as angels among us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children.p12" pid="KBUI4efbGEmP15qceJZ1rA" hash="BrOscg">Fulfilling this opportunity of teaching is not dependent upon social status, wealth, or position. In fact, the most effective instruction may well be done at the humblest fireside. Some may rationalize their failure to follow this God-given instruction by assuming that children of tender years are not capable of understanding gospel principles. Parents who have followed the practice of teaching their children know otherwise. Family home evening presents a special opportunity to teach the gospel to the family. The parents of a five-year-old were concerned about how they should teach of Nephi’s encounter with the wicked Laban. Laban had repeatedly refused to make the precious brass plates containing a religious record available to Nephi and had sought to kill him and his brothers after confiscating their family wealth. When Nephi encountered the drunken Laban, the Spirit directed Nephi to slay him:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children.p13" pid="SmlCml4Lh0uKQktjrr_2eA" hash="KXkpfw">“Behold the Lord slayeth the wicked to bring forth his righteous purposes. It is better that one man should perish than that a nation should dwindle and perish in unbelief” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/4.13" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 4:13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children.p14" pid="CUUEsRdtDUeSpx-rAnavpw" hash="rwDi1w">As this young boy, my grandson, knelt beside his bed that evening, his prayer demonstrated his understanding and personal application of the lesson. He said, “And help me, Heavenly Father, to be obedient like Nephi, even when it’s hard.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children.p15" pid="GqPV2eJp002XN6PDP3_i-A" hash="VPUzlA">Demonstration of these principles of truth as taught in the scriptures, and applied in the various settings of life, is a sure way of developing understanding and obedience in the lives of children. The Primary of the Church also teaches children the gospel of Jesus Christ. This is a valuable support the Church gives to parents and their children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children.p16" pid="HYAXdMS940y8Amih5Y1OSQ" hash="k7E8Yg">It is my witness that our kind and loving Heavenly Father has made special allowances for little children, consistent with their innocence and the eternal principle of agency. It is also my witness that he gave parents, and all adults, the responsibility of properly teaching and protecting them. Offenders of these little ones face a divine wrath. The Savior’s injunction to become as a little child is an invitation to purify our lives that we also may stand blameless before Him. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1994/04/the-special-status-of-children</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1994-general-conference/1994-04-2070-elder-merlin-r-lybbert-64k-eng.mp3" length="5229243" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 1994 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
