<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Michaelene P. Grassli</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Michaelene P. Grassli.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Michaelene%20P.%20Grassli.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Michaelene P. Grassli.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 1988 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>I Will Follow God’s Plan for Me</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I have prepared my message especially for you ten- and eleven-year-old girls.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03232_000_035" doc-version="2" hash="t6E0dg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="oOu06LSI-kqdpsnsFbP7hA" hash="ckxfQA">I Will Follow God’s Plan for Me</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="QpoFeKbTI0u_ds9lXV5nHQ" hash="k3t2_w">Michaelene P. Grassli</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p1" pid="RdKBGNmrpUm4Cm1XUziY6A" hash="pDbCSQ">I have prepared my message especially for you ten- and eleven-year-old girls.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p2" pid="_JpKLvNDA06-hIOw62tXiw" hash="VoG1nQ">When I was a girl of about ten, one summer afternoon a friend and I took blankets and crackers out into the hayfield behind our Idaho home. The hay, in the middle of the summer, was sweet-smelling, lush, and so tall that when we spread our blankets in the middle of the field, we could sit on our blankets and eat crackers with the hay making a wall around us and hiding us from sight. There we were in a world all of our own.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p3" pid="HGmUSmzKO0eQSXey5shraQ" hash="Or1EfA">We liked to pick the dandelions that grew large and abundantly there. We split their stems lengthwise—have any of you ever done that?—and submerged the stems in the water of the irrigation ditch. As we watched, the dandelion stems began to curl from the end. We split the stem a little farther, and each piece curled until the entire stem was a fluff of curly fibers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p4" pid="nCClOVO1-UepTYdIaEV0_w" hash="dIn7Qg">It was an afternoon of wonder for us. We were there all alone under that bright, blue, clean, warm sky. It seemed as if God had created this day and dandelion stems especially for us to enjoy. I said to my friend, “Don’t you just feel happy inside?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p5" pid="RCCpAc_RhUqF1hw8IM1emQ" hash="o3DpqA">My friend looked at me and said, “No, I don’t.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p6" pid="jkYiXEyTikeQkaCVRS-eWA" hash="DlSs8A">I was shattered by her blunt, almost emotionless statement. “Why?” I exclaimed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p7" pid="UCPTPGGmc02S9rVJnDzMQw" hash="hpmrhw">“Because it won’t last,” she said. “You can be happy for a minute, but not for very long. Life just doesn’t make sense to me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p8" pid="RlcmwYXAnEaIqJpH4SQ-BA" hash="I8BAgQ">I didn’t know what to say to my friend that day, but I do now. And I want to talk to you ten- and eleven-year-old girls—my sweet little sisters—and answer my friend, as I speak to you tonight as if we were, you and I, sitting in that beautiful hayfield together.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p9" pid="1-0YZ97E5keWwsxj4LljfQ" hash="FHd5pg">Our Heavenly Father expects and intends for us to be happy. Man is that he might have joy, the scripture says. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.25" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:25</a>.) That means ten- and eleven-year-old girls are that they might have joy as well. Life does make sense because there is a plan—a plan by which we may have joy and be happy here on earth and eternally. My friend didn’t know that.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p10" pid="rrk__lnlW0KYGYVmZgI8ZA" hash="LN1kXQ">You girls have often repeated in Primary this motto: “I can follow God’s plan for me.” What is the plan? I think you know it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p11" pid="jqNrtCcAEU61H6gFnOPxMw" hash="iGE9NQ">In our pre-earth life we had proved ourselves faithful. We needed to have a chance to show Heavenly Father that we could be obedient when we were away from him, and so he permitted us to come to this earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p12" pid="AdABMlKNXEuAeIu-EhA92Q" hash="8EDpqQ">Satan was terribly angry that his method of implementing our Heavenly Father’s plan was not accepted. He swore he would turn us away from Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p13" pid="bvdZc2wkBUS8qMbEFfjc0g" hash="InCDoA">So we have a choice. We can either choose Heavenly Father’s plan, or we can follow Satan. It’s as simple as that. Now, the scriptures tell us that everything good comes from Heavenly Father and that following Satan brings misery and unhappiness. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.27" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:27</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.40" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:40</a>.) This is important for us to know.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p14" pid="vHCj_3ka8UW6x9x4TXsuxw" hash="MEm18w">My birthday was a few weeks ago, and my children asked me the question they always ask on my birthday or Christmas or Mother’s Day—“Mother, what would you like for your birthday?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p15" pid="XJA8RuHeykiuipwl5cdNGA" hash="hApOhg">I answered them, as I always do, “Sweetheart, just be good so you can be happy.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p16" pid="SCpBP2ILv0u03UCnDp084Q" hash="WPJkwQ">Their happiness is my fondest desire. Our happiness is our Heavenly Father’s fondest desire. He has given us the gospel of Jesus Christ. We learn his teachings through the scriptures, through revelation, and through our prophet in order that joy might be ours through our own personal goodness, or personal righteousness. He wants us to be good so we can be happy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p17" pid="Bss5jKUl202RkZzOFydYTg" hash="Ashgvw">The great Book of Mormon prophet Lehi, whom you have learned about this year, told his children, “If there be no righteousness there be no happiness.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.13" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:13</a>.) When we are good, or righteous, we are following God’s plan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p18" pid="sjXym201nkGEIzOjh8cIvw" hash="c_Jnfg">But isn’t it hard to be good sometimes? We struggle with the temptations that come from being human, being mortal in a mortal world. But that, too, is part of the plan. That is where the choice comes in.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p19" pid="tJ8R76B0SUGp3w9tY1PlMg" hash="8f1Gfw">Lehi also taught his children, “And to bring about his eternal purposes [that is, that we might be happy and glorified forever] … it must needs be that there was an opposition; even the forbidden fruit in opposition to the tree of life; the one being sweet and the other bitter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p20" pid="7KY5qHY3Q0a3HNuR-J0IaQ" hash="XYHIIw">“Wherefore, the Lord gave unto man that he should act for himself. Wherefore, man could not act for himself save it should be that he was enticed by the one or the other.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.15-16" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:15–16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p21" pid="2gMvt40Kq0SzDqkuQdVQ_Q" hash="G04gMw">Yes, you have a choice. The Lord has given you control of your life by giving you a choice. Let me repeat that. The Lord has given you control of your life. I’m not saying that nothing bad will ever happen to you. You will not always be able to control what others may say or do, but you can control how you will react to them. Temptation, illness, accidents, and tragedy are part of this life. There will be some tough days in your lives—very tough days. But when you follow God’s plan, you can know what to do, and that’s when you are in control. You can decide whether or not you are going to be happy by making choices that will lead you close to your Heavenly Father and away from Satan. You can decide what you will say and do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p22" pid="6eTCctkYCkKcPv0WTCxIUg" hash="X6OTMA">I think you know what I mean. You have already made some good decisions that have made you happy. You’ve chosen to be baptized. You’ve chosen to attend Church meetings like this one. You may have decided not to use profanity or not to watch bad television programs, or to dress modestly, or to observe the Word of Wisdom. Every day brings many opportunities to choose to follow God’s plan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p23" pid="pCih-nIhw0el-GihYK_sBg" hash="BW52vw">Susan was eight years old. She had just been baptized. She was playing out in the yard with her sisters and some friends, and she went into the house to get a drink of water. Her mother said, “Susan, dinner’s ready. Will you please call your sisters to eat?” So she went to the door and called to them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p24" pid="rWalZyo2cUCOsssZAsZuPw" hash="sOJFQw">They really didn’t want to go in, so they argued and said, “Oh, no, it isn’t time for dinner. You are just teasing us.” And they accused her of not telling the truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p25" pid="aGVt4yq-KUaL-9Crtvuuqg" hash="1eoQdw">Well, she gathered herself up in all of her eight-year-old dignity, put her hands on her hips, and said, “It is dinnertime. I’m telling you the truth, and you can believe me because I have been baptized.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p26" pid="KG4_C2w3N0eJIJo9EMOgtw" hash="bw4zkw">She knew that her baptism required of her a certain standard of behavior. Her choice was that she would tell the truth, and she was willing to commit to that.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p27" pid="ZgZVITo4sk-Tjl0e-pf72Q" hash="5RuHYg">Now, I don’t suppose that little girl grew up without ever telling a lie, but as I have studied the word <span class="emphasis">righteousness,</span> I have found nothing that indicates that being righteous is being perfect. <span class="emphasis">Goodness, virtue, morality</span> are all dictionary synonyms, but not <span class="emphasis">perfect.</span> All of us will make mistakes in our lives, but although perfection is our ultimate destination, righteousness, or goodness, is the chariot to carry us there. How tragic, were we never to climb aboard the chariot or, once aboard, climb off, fearing a wheel would break along the way! Wheels can be mended, and we can begin again to be good, to follow God’s plan for us so we can be happy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p28" pid="LOz0CE3AhkODDJMv7XGnvg" hash="yQPi5g">Every good thing you do in your life is following God’s plan. Every time you are kind to another person, each time you have courage to do something difficult, each time you do a thoughtful act without being asked, each time you say your prayers, each time you read the scriptures, each time you go to church, each time you help a friend—you are following God’s plan for you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p29" pid="tQ0gjZWaTUGV7ClIgza8xA" hash="yzyrAA">Often the choices are hard because we sometimes want to do what everyone else is doing, or because something frightens us or worries us, or because we really don’t know what is the right choice. When hands were placed upon your head at the time you were confirmed a member of the Church, you were given the Holy Ghost to help you know what your Heavenly Father would have you do and to have the courage to do it. So even when it’s hard, you can pray for answers, you can read in the scriptures, and the Holy Ghost will help you know. Sometimes you will know in your heart what you should do. Sometimes you’ll have a feeling that you should talk to someone else who could help you. Sometimes the answer comes quickly, sometimes it takes a while, and when the answer comes, you be the one to follow that answer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p30" pid="zm4Wk8fUWkWcvQAmOoZniQ" hash="XD7MUg">Now, as we contemplate being good and being happy, it is helpful to remember this: It is possible to make a right choice and at the time you make it to feel lonely or rejected or embarrassed. When you have to leave a party, for example, because things are going on there that are not right, or others criticize you for doing something you know is right, you may not feel exactly happy. If this happens to you, remember, what others think of you is far less important than what your Heavenly Father thinks of you and what you think of yourself. Your happiness will be in the comfort you feel inside, knowing that what you have done is right and that your Heavenly Father approves your choice. Eventually, time will prove you right, and others will respect and admire you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p31" pid="qMsdlpYOtE639Ie4Nghg6w" hash="M64Dbg">I wish that day in the green hayfield that I had been able to help my friend. I knew the plan, but I didn’t know that was what she needed to hear. Life would have made sense to her had she known Heavenly Father’s plan. I hope someone taught her. I wish I had been the one. Today’s world needs ten- and eleven-year-old girls who know the purpose of life and who can with courage and sincerity make a declaration of their determination to follow God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p32" pid="Jxb0fWbOKEGfT8R2oldzHA" hash="3iKoig">If I had the wish of my heart, I would hear all you ten- and eleven-year-old girls in the Church right now stand and with one voice say together, “I <span class="emphasis">will </span>follow God’s plan for me.” Instead, as you sit quietly here in the Tabernacle or watch in your stake center or in your home, let us together make that declaration in our hearts, a private promise to our Heavenly Father in this silent moment. “I <span class="emphasis">will </span>follow God’s plan for me.” Only your Heavenly Father knows if you have made this promise, but know that thousands of girls all over the world just now have united with you in that commitment. And I pledge publicly to you, my sisters, that I have made this commitment. I promise you that I will continue repeating it frequently to help me remember. I know God lives and loves us, and I <span class="emphasis">will</span> follow God’s plan for me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p33" pid="bMTGM8USGkyH9NrU0X_Eqw" hash="H2vTEA">Now, in a moment we are going to hear Primary girls of the Holladay Utah Region choir sing. You’ll notice that one word has been changed in this familiar song that makes it now reflect the commitment we have made together tonight. I <span class="emphasis">will </span>follow God’s plan for me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p34" pid="BNZnJ9V-qU279od0vva7Fw" hash="k7pTwQ">I pray that we will keep this commitment, all of us. I hope you will repeat it together often. I hope you’ll write it down and put it where you’ll always see it. I hope you will have many opportunities to say and to sing, “I <span class="emphasis">Will </span>Follow God’s Plan for Me.” And wherever I go I hope that you girls will come to me and let me know that you have committed to your Heavenly Father always to follow his plan for you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me.p35" pid="TI8_geCNH0S0N1UFcbISQQ" hash="YVfUgw">Now, let us go forth as sisters, determined that no force will turn us from our Heavenly Father’s way. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1988/10/i-will-follow-gods-plan-for-me</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1988-general-womens-meeting/1988-09-0020-michaelene-p-grassli-64k-eng.mp3" length="6852931" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 1988 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Children at Peace</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Thank you, President Hinckley. Elder Scott, you have touched our hearts, and with our hearts we sustain you.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03232_000_030" doc-version="2" hash="PGUi1Q">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="LL-KHdltyEyodmcrj0kNzA" hash="Zb8twA">Children at Peace</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="cQxeHTPo1kqXXJp41rBpUQ" hash="k3t2_w">Michaelene P. Grassli</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-21d2.jpg" alt="President Michaelene P. Grassli" pid="m6glTx6gTESKyOKXsg6poQ" hash="k7jqRg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p1" pid="bwbuWVN2NEi5EbLbrOa1-g" hash="K7PH4g">Thank you, President Hinckley. Elder Scott, you have touched our hearts, and with our hearts we sustain you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p2" pid="pnyJFNTVEEWCLiPIzpYQQQ" hash="fsox5g">Seven-year-old Jamie loved her mother dearly. The family had known for nearly a year that their wife and mother was dying of cancer. The father and seven children fasted and prayed; they pled with the Lord to heal her. Everything possible was done for their mother, yet at the end of three painfully difficult months, she passed from this life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p3" pid="u32hZTCaiUm1w8O97WS_xQ" hash="unvunA">In the first hours following her death, the father brought the grieving family together. After prayer, the children went to their own rooms to prepare for bed. Jamie, who had spent many hours with her mother and was devoted to her, knelt at her own bedside. “Heavenly Father,” she prayed through her tears, “we thank thee for the great mom you gave us. We thank thee for helping us try to make her well. Help us to be good so we can live with her again.” Without a hint of bitterness, this little seven-year-old girl continued for several minutes in a sweet attitude of peaceful prayer, reflecting her understanding and acceptance of her mother’s death.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p4" pid="TfThrf9WqUmcgagj1WyoIQ" hash="9DhEcA">Jamie was a child at peace. How did she come to that peace? She had been prepared by parents with spiritual understanding. Such preparation brings peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p5" pid="plmXKdDUAEaHLCJLjJY_WA" hash="Ikgdeg">I have chosen to speak about our children—precious children of our Heavenly Father throughout the earth. I pray that my message will be received and understood, for these are among the most valiant spirits to come into the world. We can do no less than to bestow on them a legacy of peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p6" pid="14uNgbdrmUqj4L6S92lGEQ" hash="69NTTg">Our Heavenly Father has promised peace to his children. “All thy children shall be taught of the Lord; and great shall be the peace of thy children.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/22.13" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 22:13</a>.) Peace in the Lord can give them freedom from self-doubt, freedom from fear, freedom from the confinement of their environment, freedom from enslaving habits. His peace can free them to unfold from the tender buds they are to the mature and fruitful adults they can be.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p7" pid="l0ADZS00IU2XwVn8mgztFw" hash="I8eDwQ">Just as the fragile bud contains all of the essential elements to develop into a lovely plant or flower, so does each child come to us with the potential for individual self-fulfillment of his eternal destiny. In both instances, in order that what is inside can be fully developed, it must be nurtured from the outside. In nature, plants require light, water, air, and nutrients to thrive. The human spirit thrives on love, knowledge of its origin, and teachings of a spiritual nature. It is important that we provide a favorable environment for spiritual growth and the peace that will accompany it. This peace I speak of will result in quiet assurances even in the midst of worldly pressures and turmoil.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p8" pid="a3asZmzlEUKNnNZBTORuoA" hash="_Q9C4Q">Brothers and sisters, the children need our help. They need us to prepare them. They need us to help them obtain the peace of the Lord. Today is neither too early nor too late to prepare the children, and anyone can do it. A young, new family just beginning; an established family with children of several ages; a family with one parent; grandparents, aunts, uncles, neighbors; and kind, understanding Church leaders and teachers—all of us can teach children of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p9" pid="7SyDwCo9sUSWIlRUOhjj7w" hash="W8cK_g">We begin by teaching what we are. The children need us; they need to see in us what they can become. They need to see us keeping the commandments. <span class="emphasis">We</span> must come unto the Lord and seek for the peace of the gospel in <span class="emphasis">our own</span> lives. “Learn of me,” the Lord said, “and listen to my words; walk in the meekness of my Spirit, and you shall have peace in me.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/19.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 19:23</a>.) When we are at peace, then our children can be at peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p10" pid="bOihUl9ki0uU_aiTEkOflw" hash="ZLDGIw">A wise bishop made this observation: “I have seen families where parents are at home with the gospel, where gospel principles are a matter-of-fact, everyday way of life, where parents treat their children with courtesy and respect with the full understanding that they are children of God. In these homes, the children seem to be at peace because their parents have given them a clear message. They know they are children of God. They feel their worth and have focus to their lives, knowing that eternity is their goal.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p11" pid="Ugwkp1QtgUGRYk0AMk5MRQ" hash="OSJ9Hg">To some, a family like the ones described by that bishop may seem impossible to attain. No family is perfect—all families are made up of human beings with mortal weaknesses, who sometimes go astray. But family members, including parents, can begin where they are and learn and grow together.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p12" pid="NcUr1H6uTUe8v1xayIT-Cg" hash="-BcsEQ">Now, we have been promised that family home evening, family prayer, and reading the scriptures together can strengthen and give direction to each member of a family and can knit the family together. If you haven’t been having family home evening or family prayer, you may feel awkward about beginning. That’s all right. Do it anyway. Gather the family together; tell them that although you haven’t been doing so, you want to begin.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p13" pid="hAUaYrbkp0WCFRiWi02i4w" hash="kz52GA">Now, I must warn you that Satan will attempt to thwart your efforts because family strength is a threat to his work. So persevere, even though it takes some effort and planning to overcome attitudes and obstacles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p14" pid="_z63SVOr1kajS7PspmUXlQ" hash="vb0oCA">When the family gathers for evening prayer, it is a good time for sharing the day’s experiences, reading the scriptures, and sharing testimonies. Children especially need to hear the testimonies of their parents. One family repeats one article of faith every evening for a week, or memorizes a scripture, or recites books in the Book of Mormon. Another family focuses on one child or a parent each day with each member telling something good about that person. It takes just a few minutes. Children of all ages need to hear positive observations about themselves—especially from their parents.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p15" pid="UyMh04ANYESlO--y1_iMeg" hash="JFIrMg">Immerse the children in the stories of Jesus so that they can know him and can imagine what it might have been like to have lived when he was on earth. Tell them how he took the children on his knee and blessed them and prayed for them. Tell them how the people knew he was the Son of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p16" pid="Umx7SKIo2kWEYa4VEcwpTw" hash="S2K2DA">When I was a child I loved to hear about the Savior’s triumphal entry into Jerusalem. Many people heard Jesus was coming to Jerusalem for the Feast of the Passover. They knew he was the Son of God. They went out to meet him. Imagine what it must have been like to be a child in that happy crowd. The scripture says it was “a very great multitude.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/21.8" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 21:8</a>.) They were probably waiting along the narrow streets of Jerusalem becoming more and more excited as they strained to see if he was coming yet. Then as he came into view, riding on a donkey, can’t you just hear a great cheer going up? They spread their clothes and tree branches on the ground for the donkey to walk on, like they did for kings, and they waved palm leaves in the air. They cried “Hosanna to the Son of David … Hosanna in the highest.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/21.9" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 21:9</a>.) Oh, wouldn’t you love to have been there?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p17" pid="EfvHui-xjUaJcLS9eugOFw" hash="nr1-OQ">Yes, tell them about the Savior so they’ll trust him, so they’ll develop a desire to be like him, and want to be with him again. Yes, our homes can provide peace for the children. Blessings be on you parents.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p18" pid="HTizDNJvY0GG6Ga5cClHIQ" hash="MxtzBQ">And blessings be on you devoted Church leaders who hold the welfare and spiritual growth of children in high priority—priesthood and Primary leaders who minister to the children. At Primary, children are taught of the Lord. A wise stake Primary president in Australia has as her goal that when the children come to Primary, they will feel the Spirit of the Lord. Those will be children at peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p19" pid="tyURujuWvEOKaFUkMMWsVA" hash="xewwNQ">President Benson, I’m proud to say, that Primary children have this year read and discussed the Book of Mormon. Nine-year-old Matt in Wisconsin spoke in the children’s sacrament meeting presentation in his ward recently about something he had learned that brought him peace. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p20" pid="oTeJj4hj90q_iAqzNa9Fzg" hash="CV9gng">“When my father told our family that we would be moving from Denver to Wisconsin, my mother reminded us of Lehi’s family. Like them, I was leaving the only home I had known, all my friends, my school, and my ward. Luckily <span class="emphasis">we</span> got to bring all our possessions with us, though they were in storage for three months, and we missed having a house and our ‘precious things.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p21" pid="aPhSSbJd7U2Y4aWal5EbMQ" hash="PS6lsA">“My mother reminded us of how Nephi accepted this challenge—willingly—knowing that the Lord would ‘prepare a way for them that they may accomplish the thing which he commandeth them.’ (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 3:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p22" pid="elnkd7z4wUKy230WlHYLKQ" hash="Zi87uw">“I have learned that I can do without things, but not without my family. My brothers and sisters and I have tried to be more like Nephi than his complaining brothers. I am grateful for the things that the Book of Mormon teaches us.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p23" pid="3rlTGyNa6E69MJGghuSC4A" hash="-IE4oA">Yes, when children are taught of the Lord, we bestow on them a gift, a legacy of peace, that can lead them to eternal life. We must not fail them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace.p24" pid="qjMDRmdrdEydWwG9TYnfew" hash="JXGOOQ">May all our children have the blessing to be taught of the Lord that they might be, indeed, children at peace, I pray, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1988/10/children-at-peace</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1988-general-conference/1988-10-5030-michaelene-p-grassli-64k-eng.mp3" length="5250339" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 1988 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Follow Him</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Have you Primary girls ever wondered what your life is going to be like as you grow up? What do you dream of? Ten-year-old Amy told me, “I dream about what I will be like, and where I will go, and what I will do.” Eleven-year-old Kristine said, “I wo</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03245_000_037" doc-version="2" hash="fuTfig">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="eWFjL0ScAkOzkLv6lfoyWw" hash="0XKR7A">Follow Him</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="CnUTBFl65kWWhBVLxVlBrw" hash="k3t2_w">Michaelene P. Grassli</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-21d2.jpg" alt="President Michaelene P. Grassli" pid="ytTJA3TuRUiYNvAmWpObTQ" hash="k7jqRg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p1" pid="qwNxOToPuE6c8lLqKNwNUA" hash="0vZz4A">Have you Primary girls ever wondered what your life is going to be like as you grow up? What do you dream of? Ten-year-old Amy told me, “I dream about what I will be like, and where I will go, and what I will do.” Eleven-year-old Kristine said, “I worry about bad things that happen at school. Some things scare me!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p2" pid="FMadCu6w5k6rCqjW3SPkdQ" hash="UB4Vvg">What is in the future for you? Will there be adventure? Will there be danger? Will there be sorrow? Will there be love and families? Will there be disappointments? Will there be fun and laughter?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p3" pid="4yslTEJx70yD2WepGqUYMw" hash="clF-3A">The answer to all of these dreams and questions is yes! Yes! Yes! Anything and everything is possible.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p4" pid="KJkLItJ5vUmp2MQxHapaSQ" hash="lD1gBg">Let’s imagine that you are terribly hungry when you are ushered into a room full of banquet tables spread with many kinds of food. You are allowed to choose which foods to eat.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p5" pid="5YGWB464Jk2APG-S2EQGDQ" hash="e3FgRw">One table holds foods that taste good, but aren’t very nutritious. Another holds foods that are actually harmful to your body and could even cause you to get sick or die. Some tables hold just one kind of food—like all desserts. That sounds good to me. And yet another is filled with a rich variety of delicious foods that are well-balanced and nutritious. Which will you choose?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p6" pid="BbYZzEXwpEmXEG0BDc9L8g" hash="uaf3JQ">No matter what the future holds for you, just as the banquet tables are laden with food waiting to be savored, life is a fabulous feast of experiences just waiting for you to choose and explore. You are now hungering to know all about life, and there are many tables from which you may choose. Some choices <span class="emphasis">seem</span> good, but are harmful. Some choices are fun but don’t lead you anywhere. Some choices could destroy you. However, just as the feast on the banquet table with a variety of good food is best for our physical bodies, the best feast in <span class="emphasis">life</span> is at the table of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p7" pid="du1_OhMUIUm2nOT4ibpX-A" hash="DlaSWQ">What is on the Lord’s table? Love, good fun, uplifting music, peaceful prayer, scriptures, smiles, learning, happy talk, warm hugs, good friends, and service to others. This is where eternal joy can be found. That’s why in Primary you repeat the motto, I Will Follow God’s Plan for Me. Although you will have disappointing days, and discouragement and sorrow along with the good, if you follow God’s plan, you will be feasting at the table of the Lord where the spiritual satisfaction is far greater and lasts longer than the physical satisfaction of food.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p8" pid="D1IyCnPAuUiskUOgP3roIQ" hash="lSfujw">My dear sisters, Satan wants you very much. He swore an oath before the world was that he would try <span class="emphasis">anything</span> to capture and enslave and ruin you. He wants you especially because you have the truth. You are the ones who can touch hearts, change lives, and lead others to our Heavenly Father. We women of the Church have significant and critical work to do for the Lord. That’s why Satan wants <span class="emphasis">you .</span> Having you on his side is the best victory of all for him because not only will he have cheated you out of your eternal blessings, but he will also cheat others whom you could have influenced through your good example.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p9" pid="gqY5ANFRH0qkwi5tH16QdA" hash="7yQfRA">The contents of Satan’s table sometimes appear inviting. They may seem fun and harmless. In fact, Satan can make us feel that terrible things are really all right to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p10" pid="ISSu0XrXuEmv05IxElNW-w" hash="FQ6qnw">Now, if he came to you looking ugly and scary and said, “Come with me,” you’d turn around and run as fast as you could. But Satan knows you’re too smart for that, so he has to trick you. One way he does that is by making bad things seem good. Listen to this: “Everybody does it.” “No one will know.” “Just this once won’t hurt.” “It’s not really a bad thing to do.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p11" pid="SYPOB6ON8kiHWzh09dTYhQ" hash="usm5qw">You’ve heard some of those phrases before, haven’t you? “But that wasn’t Satan who said it,” you answer. To that I reply, “It was Satan’s message delivered to you, perhaps by someone who is, to one degree or another, in his power.” Those phrases are warnings. When you hear them, <span class="emphasis">that</span> is when you should turn and run away from danger.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p12" pid="XzXWvUuiqkexYvG-mApYKg" hash="_y327w">Sometimes we try to tell <span class="emphasis">ourselves</span> that wrong is right. We do this to try to feel better about doing wrong things. On a television show recently, a girl was caught breaking a serious family rule. She said, “I wasn’t being disobedient. I was just learning independence.” Well, no matter what she said or how she tried to justify what she had done, the truth was she had disobeyed a rule that was made to protect her. When she disobeyed, the protection was gone. That’s important to remember, so I want to say it one more time. When she disobeyed, the protection was gone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p13" pid="fdHX3UxpdkCgwbC5OyBBBg" hash="i4AKCw">Satan <span class="emphasis">wants</span> us to lose our protection—that is, the help of the Holy Ghost—because that’s when he can gain power over us. When we obey, we can have the protection of the Holy Ghost. “I, the Lord, am bound,” he said, “when ye do what I say; but when ye do not what I say, ye have no promise.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/82.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 82:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p14" pid="ckGaNZMW6UqqYnH79br5jg" hash="aMHcyQ">Satan keeps at us all our lives. As we grow older, he adds phrases like these to the messages he delivers: “I’m not worth much.” “I’ve done my part, now it’s someone else’s turn.” “It’s too late for me.” “The Brethren just don’t understand. I know better than they do.” When these thoughts or feelings come into our minds and hearts, they, too, are warnings that let us know we are in danger—in danger of losing the Spirit, losing our testimonies, forfeiting eternal joy. These, too, are times to turn around and run to escape from the danger before us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p15" pid="h_4GY90gM0yw28xVIERnsQ" hash="ycLgSQ">And where do we run? To our Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p16" pid="CtjdJ6jioE-UPSQTnX9VJA" hash="7_A9PA">Suppose you had a very important job that needed to be done, and there were several people you could ask to do the job for you. Which person would you choose? Wouldn’t you choose the person who was best prepared to do the job?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p17" pid="2fw4AfTjVU2-cmgDuw9TcA" hash="pWqFdQ">That is what our Heavenly Father did. The very important work that had to be done was to save us from sin and spiritual death and to show us how we could return to him. Unlike Satan, who wants to destroy you, Heavenly Father wants you because he loves you. He has provided ways to protect you from Satan. And whom did He choose to show us the way? His Son Jesus Christ. “Behold, I am he who was prepared from the foundation of the world to redeem my people.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/3.14" class="scriptureRef">Ether 3:14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p18" pid="5TUvq2FFgUG6RGX569o8Qg" hash="ECeirw">That is our Heavenly Father’s work. <span class="emphasis">Our</span> work is to live worthy of returning to him and help others do the same.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p19" pid="khzt5WT_PEeq0IflWjePag" hash="n0naFA">When Jesus was in the wilderness, Satan promised him power and fame if Jesus would worship him. Jesus, knowing Satan’s promises are false, said, “Get thee behind me, Satan,” meaning, “Go away. Don’t bother me. I won’t listen to you.” (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/4.8-10" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 4:8–10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p20" pid="tFzPBY-gW0aryDHouXlj-Q" hash="N9pnpA">Satan can influence us only if we let him. Each time we resist evil, the Lord blesses us with more strength to resist. When I do something I shouldn’t, I don’t like the way I feel. But the first time I say in my mind or by what I do, “Get thee behind me, Satan,” I feel a surge of strength and power to resist. It is the Holy Ghost helping me. It’s a wonderfully secure feeling. Resisting Satan is the appetizer at the banquet table of the Lord. It prepares us for more of the life-giving sustenance the Lord has for us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p21" pid="2ucJyZT3Fke0CtlGvF3OcA" hash="YeZ4xA">While it is important to be aware of the desire Satan has to own us, it is not necessary for us to live in fear. In the Doctrine and Covenants we are taught, “If ye are prepared ye shall not fear.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.30" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:30</a>.) As we prepare ourselves to receive the blessings of the Lord and to be worthy to serve him, we are gathering strength—power from the Holy Ghost—preparing ourselves to overcome evil.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p22" pid="-SXkiekG0EWazre4om5kRA" hash="h2yYGg">One part of preparing is repenting. If you have done something wrong, I hope you know it was wrong and will repent. Talk to your parents or your bishop. They love you, and they can help you know what to do to repent so you can be clean again and start over.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p23" pid="izKF51a-FkWlzPLlXSKgQA" hash="-k8qWw">Little sisters, do not be afraid of Satan or afraid of the future. Instead, follow the example of Heavenly Father’s Son, our Savior, Jesus Christ. Then you will be strong and be able to say with confidence, “Get thee behind me, Satan.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p24" pid="9AyRUpTzTkundWKEVa-7tQ" hash="WTPqjw">When I was a girl, on summer mornings the first sound I heard through my open window as I was waking was the song of a meadowlark. I liked the call of the killdeer, the chirp of the chickadee, and the screech of the magpie. But the song of the meadowlark was especially beautiful to me, and I trained my ear to hear it amid other sounds.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p25" pid="M0pPlj96d0aEEKpp9Se8hg" hash="uK5dag">We can train our spiritual senses the same way so that we can recognize our Heavenly Father’s will for us. We train our spiritual senses by doing good things. We are taught to “search diligently in the light of Christ that ye may know good from evil; and if ye will lay hold upon every good thing, and condemn it not, ye certainly will be a child of Christ.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.19" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p26" pid="qXLTJ98P8061eiRyfO7ipg" hash="JCoPFQ">To “lay hold upon every good thing” means to look for good and do good. Then you will have good feelings. You can know which choices to make. Although you usually will not hear an answer as easily as I heard the song of a meadowlark, you will be able to feel that what you are doing is right.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p27" pid="CJsJA1rgyE2Zu3j1X5G0VQ" hash="g6ndtg">President Benson spoke to all the children last general conference and told you how to be happy. He was telling you what our Heavenly Father wants you to know. Get a copy of his message and keep it right with your scriptures. Read it over and over. Do what the prophet says, and you will know God’s plan for you and how you can follow his plan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p28" pid="BZ4I1CVSHEm25E2fIMA-4A" hash="b-YqjQ">Follow the example of good women. Tonight you have seen women who are trying to follow God’s plan. Sister Jepsen, who is conducting, and Sister Doxey and Sister Jack, who have spoken, are great examples—models you can follow. I testify of the truthfulness of their words. Sisters Joy Evans, Jayne Malan, and Ruth Wright, also counselors in the Relief Society, Young Women, and Primary, are spiritual women and great leaders. Members of the Primary, Young Women, and Relief Society general boards, whom you see on the stand, have made choices to unselfishly serve the Lord. These are women who have dreamed, worried, and grown as you are doing. They have done much good in small, private ways, as well as in their public church service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p29" pid="Nf-RifBflUyl463n1LVuVQ" hash="hk5_hg">And my dear friends Relief Society President Barbara Winder and Young Women President Ardeth Kapp are real heroines. When Sister Kapp was a young girl, like many of you, she struggled with her schoolwork. Later she graduated with honors and earned advanced degrees. And when Sister Winder was your age, like many of you, she worried because her parents were not active in the Church. Now they’ve been sealed in the temple. Just like you and me, Sister Kapp and Sister Winder still have things they worry about and struggle with. They know that things don’t always turn out the way we want, but that our Heavenly Father will always help us if we do our best and are obedient. Then we will have what is best for us. They have prepared themselves. They follow the Savior, and they follow the prophet, and by doing so, they have learned what God’s plan is for them, and they are faithfully trying to follow that plan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p30" pid="8Nk77hCNFkO5YjfUt0obBA" hash="VNbDNg">Like you, they were ordinary girls with the same dreams and fears you are experiencing. Now they are ordinary women living extraordinary lives, doing some of the critical, important work of the Lord, as you will do. Barbara and Ardeth, how I love you! You are worthy examples for all of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p31" pid="OHOsK4Nz-06atJHuDEEhAg" hash="JH1o5g">You girls can follow the example of these women. You also have many good women who are close to you. Watch the good things your mothers do. Your grandmothers, sisters, aunts, leaders, and teachers also have good qualities and can teach you many good things. They know how important it is for them to follow the Savior and to be good examples to you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p32" pid="gbz78rHnVEyQfZFiJ4ZUiw" hash="Tpijjw">Above all, follow God’s plan for <span class="emphasis">you.</span> Prepare and do not fear, for God knows you and loves you and will watch over you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p33" pid="uL6CyYZ3H0uoBgsj71QwAA" hash="9x4cXQ">The final words of the song we are about to hear from this magnificent choir tell us <span class="emphasis">how</span> Heavenly Father wants us to follow his plan. The words are:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p34" pid="M0spPlKUCEKT0Gr8e0cLcw" hash="KzCqrQ">“What does He ask? Live like his Son.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him.p35" pid="2umwqdoUeka6ZdTqCLFUlQ" hash="KETgpA">Just as food satisfies our physical hunger, we can partake with satisfaction and delight in all the Father has for us as we, living like his Son, feast at the table of the Lord. Of these things I testify, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1989/10/follow-him</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1989-general-womens-meeting/1989-09-0030-michaelene-p-grassli-64k-eng.mp3" length="7452240" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 1989 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Behold Your Little Ones”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones?lang=eng</link>
      <description>A bishop told me about extending a call to a woman in his ward. Together they read from the Book of Mormon, 3 Nephi, chapter 17.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_92911_000_039" doc-version="2" hash="BTs7VQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="XJX4ViYPAUedrK2Dge-lSw" hash="HlEk9g">“Behold Your Little Ones”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="upEgXdX7pUaX5WYaVP7cLA" hash="k3t2_w">Michaelene P. Grassli</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p1" pid="Kqg6Endr8kKSLpPUcqV01Q" hash="IhvaeA">A bishop told me about extending a call to a woman in his ward. Together they read from the Book of Mormon, 3 Nephi, chapter 17.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p2" pid="Q7X6iGNblEePdSgKbl-JLg" hash="YxiNgg">They read how the Savior invited the Nephites to bring their children to him, how Jesus prayed for the children and blessed them, and how angels appeared and ministered to them within the fire that encircled them. Those familiar words are powerful, poetic verses.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p3" pid="N-NMtna8nEiLVLTt0L68dQ" hash="EaMQ-w">Then, interestingly, the bishop said, “Sister Breinholt, the Savior cannot personally be in our ward every Sunday. But through inspiration from our Heavenly Father, we are calling you to do for some children of our ward what the Savior would do for them if he were here. We are calling you to serve as a Primary teacher!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p4" pid="FYpDl8vnFEytp1qwFPZcgg" hash="_VCTOQ">When I heard that extraordinary experience, I wanted to study those verses again to understand better what the Savior did with the Nephite children and what he would do for our children if he were here. The Savior’s example and the bishop’s admonition apply to all of us—whether we love and serve children in our families, as neighbors or friends, or at church. Children belong to all of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p5" pid="QlsbOzRGMU6Dd1vRJ6yWhQ" hash="EEnKiQ">With that in mind, let us examine together some verses in the seventeenth chapter of 3 Nephi [<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.title" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17</a>]. Let us discover together the pattern the Savior gave us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p6" pid="Tk-BD_4xQkeqt3bMpDSDEQ" hash="9fjYtg">His invitation in verse 11 [<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.11" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:11</a>] was neither casual nor inconsequential. “He <span class="emphasis">commanded</span> that their little children should be brought.” (Emphasis added.) And notice what verse 11 <span class="emphasis">doesn’t </span>say. It doesn’t say never mind the little ones because they aren’t accountable yet. It doesn’t say the children were to be taken elsewhere so they wouldn’t disrupt the proceedings. And it doesn’t imply that the children won’t understand. But it <span class="emphasis">does</span> teach that children need to learn the significant things of the kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p7" pid="uuOxoyBIrUqZ5NpDQ8cUTg" hash="oztiVQ">God’s children share with all of us the divine right to spiritual enlightenment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p8" pid="0Q_GBc62CU-xkj-2uLYt1Q" hash="ExJKzg">“So they brought their little children and set them down upon the ground round about him, and Jesus stood in the midst.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.12" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:12</a>.) Do any of us ever consider serving children to be beneath us? Clearly the Savior felt that the Nephite children were worthy not only to be in his presence, but they were also worthy of his time and his attention. The children needed <span class="emphasis">him,</span> and he stood right in their midst.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p9" pid="Dj6zeV_JRE-WMHyENIBB9g" hash="5Sz_eA">Verse 12 also indicates that Jesus waited “till they had <span class="emphasis">all</span> been brought to him.” He wasn’t looking for a representative sample, and he wasn’t content with just some of the children. He wanted them <span class="emphasis">all</span> to be there, and he ministered to them <span class="emphasis">all</span>.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p10" pid="7mNHLJg9QUCDA6EQOSs1Sg" hash="m3c12g">Then Jesus prayed unto the Father so powerfully that “no tongue can speak, neither can there be written by any man, neither can the hearts of men conceive so great and marvelous things.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.17" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:17</a>.) And the children were there! They heard that prayer; they saw that event, and they were affected by it. Children can understand and should witness marvelous events—events like priesthood blessings, special ward and family fasts, the testimonies and prayers of their parents and leaders, and gospel discussions with people they love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p11" pid="fSZ_CBBT80uROZpqOxnYcg" hash="Y3Bmiw">“He took their little children, one by one, and blessed them, and prayed unto the Father for them.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.21" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:21</a>.) Jesus was ministering to a group of about 2,500 men, women, and children. Consider how much time it must have taken for him to bless and pray over each child, “one by one.” He must have held many of them in his arms or on his lap. And he wept because he was overcome with joy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p12" pid="l_fCmi7tY0ebI0pl8qzPww" hash="Vy6TfA">“He spake unto the multitude, and said unto them: Behold your little ones.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.23" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:23</a>.) Jesus specifically directed the attention of the multitude to the children. To me, the word <span class="emphasis">behold</span> is significant. It implies more than just “look and see.” When the Lord instructed the Nephites to <span class="emphasis">behold </span>their little ones, I believe he told them to give attention to their children, to contemplate them, to look beyond the present and see their eternal possibilities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p13" pid="Q3a0lR5wa0m1hV5zVsTEZg" hash="rQGpfA">“And as they looked to behold … they saw the heavens open, and they saw angels descending out of heaven as it were in the midst of fire; and they came down and encircled those little ones about, and they were encircled about with fire; and the angels did minister unto them.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.24" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p14" pid="RTe9lQtSUkScxi2BBxyLMA" hash="xGYk4A">I can’t help but wonder what would have happened if the multitude had just looked and not<span class="emphasis"> beheld </span>with spiritual eyes. Would they have seen the angels descend? Could they have watched their children encircled about with fire? Would they have been able to observe as the angels ministered to their children? It’s significant to me that later the Savior gave the most sacred teachings only to the children, then loosed their tongues so they could teach the multitude. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/26.14" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 26:14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p15" pid="1uosqYUsPU69y0Gs0Gy2yw" hash="9I6vjQ">Is it any wonder that following the Savior’s visit to the Nephites, they lived in peace and righteousness for two hundred years? Because of miraculous instructions, blessings, and attention they and their children received, righteousness was perpetuated by their children’s children for many generations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p16" pid="dYByuCT3FUacQWsykCPIkw" hash="DojWEQ">Let us not underestimate the capacity and potential power of today’s children to perpetuate righteousness. No group of people in the Church is as receptive to the truth, both in efficiency of learning and with the greatest degree of retention. No group is as vulnerable to erroneous teaching, and no group suffers more from neglect or abuse. Children cannot provide for themselves. We, the adults of the world, must open the way for them. Our little children worldwide deserve to be “remembered and nourished by the good word of God, to keep them in the right way.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/6.4" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 6:4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p17" pid="eUurNwnOg0-9bz2brfRefw" hash="ZwXvTQ">Jesus gave us a clear pattern to follow in fulfilling our responsibility to nurture and teach children. Our challenges differ from those of the Nephites because we live in a different time. But the Savior’s way is timeless. In his church, there can be no other way. As he demonstrated, <span class="emphasis">our</span> physical presence and attention is vital to the children in our families, church, and communities. We can know their needs and minister to them <span class="emphasis">when we spend time with them.</span> We can <span class="emphasis">behold</span> our children in their eternal perspective and see that they <span class="emphasis">all</span> know of the Savior and learn the significant truths of his gospel. We can help them witness marvelous spiritual events. They can hear our earnest prayers in their behalf. We are their ministering angels on earth if we follow the Lord’s example.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p18" pid="jy2bk8v9kkiLE0h6uH_Rlg" hash="nRi5Hg">One busy Sunday with the meetinghouse hallway crowded with people, a bishop noticed a little boy sitting on the floor crying. Disregarding his busy schedule, the bishop immediately focused his attention on the weeping child. He sat right down on the floor and held the little boy close until the crying subsided and the boy was able to explain what was wrong. Then, comforted, the child went off down the hall holding the hand of his earthly ministering angel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p19" pid="Ah5OeFqE3k-22aSeUZ4vUw" hash="HlLDCQ">I sense that the Savior would have done that too.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p20" pid="XQbxva7jQkis2r8QHIrX0Q" hash="N8esHg">A young Latter-day Saint mother from Alaska, living in Russia temporarily, visited the home of a member family with two small sons. She learned that the children read and love the scriptures and hunger to know more. Then she attended the small branch and found that because the Church is so new there, they had no experience in teaching the children at church on Sunday.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p21" pid="S7mw4De4R0y6T6g1J24ORA" hash="ieDOSQ">She said, “Knowing what the children were missing, I had an overwhelming feeling that I should help.” And she added, “I felt I would be held accountable if I did not.” So she did. Not long after, she was called as the district Primary president to become an earthly ministering angel to these children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p22" pid="PXBJ7BZIIkKRQythqoKC1A" hash="lmt_4A">A friend of mine received an invitation to the temple wedding of a young man she had taught in Primary. When she responded to the invitation, she asked, “David, you moved away, and I haven’t seen you for years. Why did you think of me?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p23" pid="aojAf1UDdUiCSql0bcosnA" hash="uwTNfQ">“Sister McMullin,” he said, “you taught us about being clean and worthy to receive the priesthood. You taught us about scrubbing our hands and wearing clean clothes when we would pass the sacrament. You taught us about being clean inside too. When I was faced with temptations and decisions in my dating years, your voice would come into my mind: ‘A deacon is clean inside and out.’ I am worthy to go to the temple because of you. That’s why I want you to come with us.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p24" pid="-hLxE9FZSEmdDm0vegm25g" hash="KlOrcQ">A sister missionary in New Guinea with her husband wrote us of teaching little children the gospel under a tree at a large coconut plantation. After the lessons, the children line up for drinks of scarce and precious, cool water from a plastic jug which these earthly ministering angels fill and freeze before they come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p25" pid="cRPfHY00SE6TY9K_RbhiGQ" hash="AdgPng">I sense that the Savior would approve of that too.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p26" pid="DD0BpQXyMEKVj0R7CyaEwg" hash="qUw8Jg">Each of us, whatever our circumstances, can help a child in a particular, important way that no one else can. We can give them life-giving water, food, love, comfort, and more importantly we can offer the “living water” of the gospel. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/4.10-14" class="scriptureRef">John 4:10–14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p27" pid="oM1IyCk3N0ayTieKB3joDw" hash="Xrtp4A">As we minister to children with the same devotion and commitment demonstrated by the Savior, we bless them with love, security, faith, testimony, and the courage to resist evil. These are preventive measures that will help stem the raging tide of today’s epidemic immorality. The gospel can, and must, become a way of life for them today. Imagine what tomorrow’s Church could be like if we fulfill the needs of our children today. Imagine what it will be like if we don’t.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones.p28" pid="qjhYgWtVWkedhutlikSfEw" hash="6bQkMg">Sisters, by ministering to children we too can help the gospel live for many generations, for in our hands are our most valuable and our most vulnerable resource—our children. Of this I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1992/10/behold-your-little-ones</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/1992-general-womens-meeting/1992-09-0030-michaelene-p-grassli-64k-eng.mp3" length="5744939" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 1992 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helping Children Know Truth from Error</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error?lang=eng</link>
      <description>It is a distinct privilege to participate in this historic meeting, adding my heart and hand and voice to sustain the Lord’s living prophet—and I do so with all my heart. I support also the action taken today sustaining Sister Patricia Pinegar as the</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_94911_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="WptHeQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="nl5OMYz6h0KLG8lW-hptuw" hash="jMAehg">Helping Children Know Truth from Error</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Uk3p4RCG2k6Li27nvygbSw" hash="k3t2_w">Michaelene P. Grassli</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-21d2.jpg" alt="Michaelene P. Grassli" pid="hQaU9OvcZEuL96M7DiSl8w" hash="k7jqRg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p1" pid="HylORdo91UiVKimlfsZNgA" hash="UZS-AA">It is a distinct privilege to participate in this historic meeting, adding my heart and hand and voice to sustain the Lord’s living prophet—and I do so with all my heart. I support also the action taken today sustaining Sister Patricia Pinegar as the new Primary general president. My time here has been full of extraordinary experiences, and I will miss them. But I know Sister Pinegar, Sister Wirthlin, and Sister Warner, and I know our children are in good hands. I wish this new presidency well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p2" pid="ttw-8f-jVUK1Fm5BTLuChw" hash="RRDXBA">The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints has always cherished children. The First Presidency, recognizing today’s unprecedented world conditions, has taken unprecedented action that renews our commitment to our little ones. Through a message to the Church called “Focus on Children,” they have asked us to love and protect our children as never before, to teach them better than we have done in the past, to prepare them more thoroughly to conquer Satan’s power in their lives and to receive of the Lord’s eternal peace and glory (see <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Jan. 1994, p. 80).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p3" pid="U0c3WlsnH0ipcs55p1P_EA" hash="nMmDCQ">We care what happens to our children. They are precious to our Heavenly Father, and they are our hope for bringing about good in the world. President Boyd K. Packer once told me, “It is today’s children who will bring the gospel to all the world. The children must be powerful and strong and independent in their agency. In order for that to be, they must have a knowledge of the gospel and a testimony that it is true.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p4" pid="TxmWRzntL0uO5Yc4FBhDQA" hash="rejWLw">Let me tell you about a little girl who is well on her way. Eight-year-old Lindsay had studied well for her math test at school. She said: “When the test began, my friend leaned over and asked if I would help her with the answers. I thought of the family home evenings we have at the first of every school year. Dad reminds us that we should always do our own work. He says it’s better to be honest than to cheat for a higher grade. I knew if I helped my friend cheat, I would be cheating too. So I shook my head, no. The next day, the teacher called my friend and me out into the hall and said our answers were the same. It was easy for me to look at the teacher and tell her I didn’t cheat. When I looked at my friend, she was crying. She told the teacher she had looked on my paper. I was really sorry for my friend, but I was very glad I had been honest.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p5" pid="yOikC22bN0q49wiKmCMGhA" hash="AjiOJg">Children need to be able to discern truth from error for themselves and have the courage to act on what they know, as Lindsay did. As I have studied principles governing discernment, I’ve made some discoveries. One discovery comes from the book of Moses in the Pearl of Great Price.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p6" pid="IFSfOPUZy0CbJSmB6QndmA" hash="jt3l4A">We read in the first chapter of Moses that God talked to Moses face to face, taught him that he was a son of God, and showed him the earth from its beginning to the end. Then “Satan came tempting him, saying: Moses, son of man, worship me” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.12" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p7" pid="eWM0uEzL30600pqOAWcsag" hash="iY3F_Q">And how did Moses respond to Satan’s confrontation? “It came to pass that Moses looked upon Satan and said: Who art thou? For behold, I am a son of God, in the similitude of his Only Begotten; and where is thy glory, that I should worship thee?” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.13" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p8" pid="2pZYeH1KekCe1H8Nlce6aw" hash="zjH2tg">Because Moses knew God, he recognized that Satan was an imposter. If our children know truth, they can recognize error.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p9" pid="vRiovB1z_0im0GqXffaiPQ" hash="ILlKnQ">When Moses recognized error, he took action. He didn’t hang around with Satan for the experience. No, he said: “I can judge between thee and God; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p10" pid="4pWLByFzjk6Jpy-Yt86rPw" hash="-UFIDA">“Get thee hence, Satan; deceive me not” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.15-16" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:15–16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p11" pid="sLmmgSgtwkKMJQANfh9-UA" hash="bVnEVg">He prayed for help and continued to do so, although Satan became agitated and insistent and redoubled his efforts, tempting Moses again. Satan told him, “I am the Only Begotten, worship me” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.19" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:19</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p12" pid="yJAQqrzAUkq8_nLoCpZ2hw" hash="UjP7Ig">Moses knew this was not true, but Satan’s rantings had a terrifying effect on him. However, he did not let fear overtake him. He prayed again, received strength from God, and commanded Satan again to depart. Then with loud wailing, weeping, and gnashing of teeth, Satan finally departed (see <a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.20-22" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:20–22</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p13" pid="Bl13OjJRtUGYZWAkKL6wmA" hash="iEeYEA">Moses recognized error, he prayed continually for help, and he overcame fear. Thus he was able to defy Satan’s attempts to intimidate him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p14" pid="ZBPdhh2xZ0iGyK7DHYGrjw" hash="-g7a4w">We want to enable our children to recognize error and take action, as Moses did. This is much more than simply telling them what to think and what to do. It is helping them seek for and love truth and choose to act independently, to act according to it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p15" pid="SEn4AqrNnECCEJXtc92vgg" hash="ZQ2FaQ">Two ways we can do this are, first, teach them of Jesus Christ and the simple truths of his gospel. To do that we need to be with them so we can verbalize our beliefs to them and so they can watch us as we apply principles in our lives. Work time, playtime, planned lessons, the teaching moments that just happen—anytime is the time! Family home evening, family prayer, and times alone with each child will help plant truth in the hearts of our children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p16" pid="4iq6rbY0tUOJ_JOjdul8Fg" hash="jvVlkA">Our children need to know that if we read the scriptures and the words of the prophets and heed the whisperings of the Spirit, we are learning from the source of all truth. If we oppose the Lord’s appointed teachers of truth, then we oppose truth. But if we honestly desire to know what is true, it follows that we would want to learn from the source of truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p17" pid="cy1_6CazPkWlKS2G7sVd2A" hash="7y23RA">Parents, use the support the Church offers you, including taking your children to Primary. Primary leaders and teachers can provide loving, supporting arms and hearts and unforgettable gospel lessons and activities for your children. They can help you immerse your children in truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p18" pid="fPDhFCO78U2TlbbSGF7n-w" hash="N68jiQ">With all my heart, I thank each of you who are serving in Primary. You are blessing the children, and you are helping yourselves. President Hunter recently stated about Primary leaders and teachers:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p19" pid="4gxznjVwMUaaP4UdacDTrg" hash="XymHIw">“Those who have the opportunity to teach children in the Church are particularly blessed as they help children understand their divine origin and Heavenly Father’s plan for them. These individuals will receive spiritual understanding in their own lives as they teach the precious truths of the gospel to children.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p20" pid="9im5RVO9gkC7BHKd4LAEsg" hash="S1yd1g">A second way we can help children learn to discern truth from error is to give them opportunities to <span class="emphasis">practice</span> discerning the truth and choosing righteously.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p21" pid="Ykurc-FNNkCk1zC91fPyzA" hash="DKc4Fg">One mother says each time one of her children leaves the house, “Remember!” And they respond, “I know, CTR!” They know CTR means “choose the right.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p22" pid="uJDEaBnWK0yOz_XAIkxq7A" hash="gHQxZQ">In family home evening, a family we know role-play situations they are likely to encounter, and they practice possible responses to the situations. In this way the children are able to have a plan before the confrontation comes. These children are learning to discern truth from error and to be independent in using their agency wisely.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p23" pid="sIJla_Kui0ir9oCJqVfs9A" hash="FllRxw">When our children are familiar with truth, they can face opposing voices with confidence. No one can tell them the Church is not true, because that will sound wrong to them. When they make mistakes or have questions about doctrines as we all do, the feelings and memories of truth from their childhood can help draw them back.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p24" pid="HMRuZWXu4E-1jA9_7_19nA" hash="QrdUXA">When I was a little girl, my father sat at the foot of my bed at night and taught my sister and me that we had lived with our Heavenly Father before the world was, that we had made a choice to obey God’s commandments and to reject Satan. He taught us that Satan rejoices when we disobey Father. I made a determination then as a very young child that I wanted my Heavenly Father to rejoice over me, not Satan. That commitment has had a very powerful effect on my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p25" pid="3wlSLHDoh0yE6zXxuahSvw" hash="_qoP2A">May all our children be immersed in gospel teachings and have opportunities to practice using their agency wisely. I pray that all children will have the opportunity to know, as I do, that God lives, that Jesus Christ is our Savior, and that we are led by a living prophet today. May the words to this favorite Primary song ring in their hearts as they do in mine today:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="bm-nZA7HHE-ugLgkWmUfHg" hash="ByEJEQ">
            <span class="emphasis">I feel my Savior’s love</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="wFgdmX4mUka9tZnMshmASw" hash="32EYzw">
            <span class="emphasis">And know that he will bless me.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Bxq0YlFuu067LQhrZlC33A" hash="zWO9kw">
            <span class="emphasis">I offer him my heart;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="eCi-JmhFgUyuW4zoSz3Lvg" hash="OQy1fw">
            <span class="emphasis">My shepherd he will be.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="_ocdb8ZHX0GfPl18BxU2iw" hash="WnCHhw">
            <span class="emphasis">He knows I will follow him,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="zIu9mXV9mESuJR_jG4lSZQ" hash="XyRw_w">
            <span class="emphasis">Give all my life to him.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="aNJ4kWk1qkO_eWRC9LFfmQ" hash="ByEJEQ1">
            <span class="emphasis">I feel my Savior’s love,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="CI8xJZwdPk27dQ6ZIN9h-g" hash="PzlZbA">
            <span class="emphasis">The love he freely gives me.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error.p26" pid="Ila50AiE7kaGfEJ7zqeTgg" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1994/10/helping-children-know-truth-from-error</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1994-general-conference/1994-10-1040-michaelene-p-grassli-64k-eng.mp3" length="5357528" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 1994 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
