<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Milton R. Hunter</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Milton R. Hunter.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Milton%20R.%20Hunter.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Milton R. Hunter.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>“Thou Shalt Not Commit Adultery”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We still hear the voice of Jehovah as it thundered down from Mount Sinai, commanding, “Thou shalt not commit adultery.” (.) For over three thousand years this commandment has reverberated throughout the Hebrew and Christian world. It has been the gui</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03006_000_2040" doc-version="2" hash="Mube7w"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="R72kZIY1_UWiu5k9cNp4pg" hash="8pEjrQ">“Thou Shalt Not Commit Adultery”</h1><p class="authorName" guid="0a74aa6c-4b27-4fd5-bd64-7b5771dd0f1f" pid="gaJjOsHLv0-_yoPxvrY7Ug" hash="_F0-6A">Milton R. Hunter</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="41351c07-43de-4869-a9b4-c68804b80c9d">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-33b2.jpg" alt="President Milton R. Hunter" guid="1eb3ea47-9a10-458c-a0f0-2b064bd5f588" pid="wRo0DcOpHECcWSEary4LNw" hash="1ws_6Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p1" guid="eae70d40-3c1f-4edd-8ba8-5e7ea8311b4a" pid="ksa7howkRUmM5SRZoAv5Ag" hash="hKxCiQ">We still hear the voice of Jehovah as it thundered down from Mount Sinai, commanding, “Thou shalt not commit adultery.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.14" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:14</a>.) For over three thousand years this commandment has reverberated throughout the Hebrew and Christian world. It has been the guideline by which millions of people have patterned their lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p2" guid="e6159da4-47e8-4404-ad62-e6e3448e38b6" pid="6c9iXHdKLUyXdWkvGtGlWg" hash="Js_rIA">Many people throughout the Church and, generally speaking, throughout the world have now abandoned the anciently cherished Hebraic-Christian moral standard of chastity. Frequently married people commit adultery and single people indulge their passions in acts of fornication. The results are unhappiness, the loss of love, breaking up of homes and destroying of family life, increase in the number of divorces, shame, loss of spirituality, apostasy, and eventually loss of eternal salvation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p3" guid="af61a741-3ce9-49ba-bebf-7a116438a132" pid="PeSzBbwzoku-3QEtktKdHg" hash="01xXRw">Let us cite only a few of the numerous cases that have come to my personal attention recently. A few months ago a mother of five children came to my office. She wept bitterly as she told me that her husband had spent most of his time during the past year with another man’s wife. She explained that on a number of occasions she followed him in her car to the other woman’s place. Naturally, the sinful husband was miserable, the wife was very sorrowful, and the children were brokenhearted. “… wickedness never was happiness.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/41.10" class="scriptureRef">Alma 41:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p4" guid="afca5c0f-bead-43b8-b1af-5355005876b9" pid="E9Qel0i5AUOQKrYFLurBAg" hash="UZL7tw">About a year ago a young man came to my office and wept as if his heart would break. He said, “I committed adultery about two years ago. The sin is causing me such mental anguish that I cannot bear it any longer. If I must be excommunicated, please have the Church take action soon. My suffering is beyond description. I want to do what I can to pay for that terrible sin.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p5" guid="d0a889ff-8df3-4dcd-8ded-e85f55d00efd" pid="zxTjLBQsMU6tu5t-lMedNw" hash="q5SMSw">Cases could be multiplied. But these two examples should be enough to illustrate the gravity of the sin of adultery.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p6" guid="c8e0d1bb-4b77-416e-a2ff-6c5d767f0143" pid="PAPdxITYE0KJLKT_zKFxvg" hash="MZuVtA">We are living today in a very permissive society. Having abandoned the ancient Christian morality, many people claim to accept a new morality, which in reality is to live contrary to the laws of chastity as proclaimed by God. We are living in a day when a sexual revolution is being proclaimed. Enticements to illicit behavior are found everywhere. Day by day a flood of them is growing worse in novels, magazines, movies, TV, and advertising.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p7" guid="408bb466-c8ba-4b88-8335-7e64e55d3ad8" pid="PX-wEN-jH0mxMJ47nLPIPQ" hash="2G5loQ">Many religious leaders have ceased teaching that sin exists. Where are the Christian ministers who stir their audiences with sermons on chastity; who proclaim condemnations of adultery and of all manners of immoral acts? Some ministers and religious teachers have become converted to modern permissive thinking and even have become advocators of it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p8" guid="12601b89-6c4f-4e97-9d1f-9b46f13bf61c" pid="ZygYd9FRBUiZuTnnAVle1A" hash="nQpaRQ">On May 17, 1970, certain newspapers reported that several prominent Christian ministers had completed a three-year study on a proposed new sex code for a prominent Christian church. Although that church is absolutely against adultery, such liberalized statements on moral behavior appear in the report of a committee as follows:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p9" guid="2bfd53c8-83cf-435b-bdac-60d154b1077c" pid="EYFVWeloM0aVHpUAu5SAag" hash="5YD8kw">“We recognize that there may be exceptional circumstances where extra-marital activity may not be contrary to the interests of a faithful concern for the well-being of the marriage partner.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p10" guid="1465e2b1-db63-4c60-b710-735b052ce32a" pid="8RVvAHKIhUe56H-Vz6lTNg" hash="XdiyWw">“… the difficult decision must be made ‘by and on the responsibility of the person taking the exception.’ But a principal point is that the final judge is not the Bible or the church or even God—it is the individual and his or her conscience.” (Will Oursler, “Religious Storm Center: New Sex Code,” <span class="emphasis">Parade, </span>May 17, 1970, p. 28.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p11" guid="9699e387-0a3d-44e5-91db-c64720a24827" pid="wi1cm2zbJkaRNTThrnkTxQ" hash="TBx1nw">The new permissiveness, or new morality, as it is often called, is nothing more than ancient immorality dressed in new clothing. In ancient times, the people worshiped fertility gods and goddesses. Many of their ceremonies were centered in gross immorality against which Israel’s prophets denounced continuously.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p12" guid="baa579bb-bbd3-47f7-98c1-f592f1e534ab" pid="78OoImB02E6B1nN3DPnjUw" hash="dGTDYg">In the days of Noah, practically all flesh became corrupted by immorality. The result was that God destroyed the world with a flood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p13" guid="76372429-e506-4ed8-b09a-726e438ba643" pid="AZGoR2WiH0qLz16NvWkKzg" hash="pBO01A">The Bible contains excellent examples of men who otherwise would have been great. But when they broke the law of chastity it broke them. For example, Samson, a man of powerful physical strength, with an uncontrollable lust for women, was betrayed by Delilah and finally committed suicide while in chains of bondage to the Philistines. God blessed Solomon with great wisdom; nevertheless, he debauched his life with numerous concubines.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p14" guid="a90dc203-30dc-44af-8246-23af28abfaeb" pid="BrnBsffVeUuTDSn9awLC6w" hash="Ly3C5g">David, whom the Lord loved and who is regarded by many people as Israel’s greatest king, spent the latter part of his life in brokenhearted sorrow over his sin against Uriah and his adultery with Bathsheba. His deep feelings were expressed in one of the most pitiful prayers in the holy scriptures:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p15" guid="cdcc2fe6-b7b2-489a-91e3-37e7b741d135" pid="ByL8XSsFCEWEReoi0YxfJA" hash="ZySKWQ">“Have mercy upon me, O God, according to thy loving kindness: …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p16" guid="641a87f5-355b-4743-b28a-aeea9cc4d238" pid="BRRGaR81fkiLmkAZkOSF8w" hash="0amCoA">“Wash me thoroughly from mine iniquity, and cleanse me from my sin.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p17" guid="2fec71fa-e4bb-486a-b23d-d66b7ee4ea1c" pid="bTm05P8m60qRkIEaFUN5Fw" hash="fVR8nQ">“For I acknowledge my transgressions: and my sin is ever before me.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/51.1-3" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 51:1–3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p18" guid="71f7ef36-e02e-489f-b608-1fd2e0682954" pid="K0MZuQtdw02KJNZkTUB6Ag" hash="EfFznA">Having an understanding of the plan of salvation and a thorough knowledge of the seriousness of the gross sins of adultery and murder which he had committed, King David in anguish cried out unto the Lord: “… thou wilt not leave my soul in hell.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/16.10" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 16:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p19" guid="40ef4b1d-7140-4ce9-9ea5-cd1bb1257a09" pid="b7l4pc2B4E6zVyz0qI9P0w" hash="vFQISg">More than two thousand years after King David’s death and only 127 years ago, Jesus Christ spoke from heaven and informed us that because of David’s sin against him in the case of Uriah and his wife, David “hath fallen from his exaltation” and his wives have been given to another. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/132.39" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 132:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p20" guid="77a727f8-4e0e-42c3-9fc4-c4a1b14fb77d" pid="KfopBzesfUqy3DRS-TUP-w" hash="V-duVA">Perhaps the most famous Bible example of a stalwart and noble man who was tempted but retained his chastity was Joseph, the young, handsome servant of Potiphar, the Egyptian ruler. He resisted the vile allurements of Potiphar’s wife, refusing to commit adultery with her. Joseph’s reply was: “… how … can I do this great wickedness, and sin against God? …” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/39.9,12" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 39:9, 12</a>.) And then he fled from her presence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p21" guid="b0c46caf-6d55-422e-942a-ce5335aba860" pid="37D-91ofWkOhhNWV-ST5pQ" hash="LrbKCA">Rather than betray his ideals, he went to jail, where he was confined in a dungeon for several years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p22" guid="f72cb075-889a-411a-9172-3f79714febb7" pid="jv4mbD6yVk-F733MA87z7w" hash="pv3PzQ">God, the Eternal Father, through Jesus Christ, has revealed to mankind a gospel plan of salvation. Its purpose is to give all who will accept and obey it peace and happiness in this world and eventually eternal life in the presence of God in celestial glory. The greatest of all laws in this gospel plan pertains to marriage for life and eternity. Thus it pertains to the family eternal. The sweetest joys and greatest blessings that can be gained in mortality and in the life to come are attained through family life lived in accordance with the gospel plan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p23" guid="c8291234-a1cc-4df2-a0e1-9459e086ab41" pid="P8yL9rxt00ig_XE1RaRBZA" hash="oGJRwQ">Thus, a basic law in marriage is the law of chastity. Men and women cannot defile the fountain of life and reap a fullness of joy. Happiness and purity of heart and mind go hand in hand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p24" guid="9a5bf1ab-6f65-4a50-bcc9-5eb36427df14" pid="RnWM7mrfE0-1DH0KPpZ8zA" hash="cHMyfA">What are some of the rewards for chastity and some of the terrible results of adultery?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p25" guid="4a94d137-534a-403e-87c3-159e0b074df6" pid="GKHwOFMJMESjFwSPKMtvZA" hash="W881Nw">The Book of Mormon is very explicit regarding the seriousness of sex immorality. Alma’s son Corianton committed sin with the harlot Isabel. Alma, being a good father and a great prophet of God, declared unto his son:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p26" guid="bc2dfe12-f400-425c-b3ea-256e1f83b1dc" pid="TPC8SBIesE6Tu4uyegSECA" hash="5j5b4g">“Know ye not, my son, that these things are an abomination in the sight of the Lord; yea, most abominable above all sins save it be the shedding of innocent blood or denying the Holy Ghost?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p27" guid="8fb1a847-7382-40ae-a635-9205bd267669" pid="-lm78WsGCkKshIBp1LaVcQ" hash="UWgWrA">“Now my son, I would that ye should repent and forsake your sins, … for except ye do this ye can in nowise inherit the kingdom of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/39.5,9" class="scriptureRef">Alma 39:5, 9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p28" guid="299158d9-e156-4b38-94cd-2f074778788c" pid="nsRjDlQoiUOMlW6HdUhCVg" hash="uDIGIw">Throughout the ages the prophets of God have proclaimed that no unclean thing can inherit the kingdom of God. (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/6.57" class="scriptureRef">Moses 6:57</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/gal/5.19-21" class="scriptureRef">Gal. 5:19–21</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/6.9" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 6:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p29" guid="8803ff06-6c9c-4808-8021-a5d044eba7c2" pid="-9xZ2mhZXECL6bi9Z-hFJg" hash="B0hQWQ">Jesus Christ while in mortality vigorously taught the law of chastity. He said: “Ye have heard that it was said by them of old time, Thou shalt not commit adultery:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p30" guid="7676e03a-bd12-4342-9b37-bbca5f359ba7" pid="Vbm4vr8Ds0-7HlEou3Aiqw" hash="xABPQA">“But I say unto you, That whosoever looketh on a woman to lust after her hath committed adultery with her already in his heart.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.27-28" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:27–28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p31" guid="12a5216d-b9a3-4fe5-b2c4-7d0eee5968d7" pid="lyoSspKuwk2SN4XA5lRVog" hash="4flCuQ">Jesus also declared: “Blessed are the pure in heart: for they shall see God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.8" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p32" guid="530dfa97-0f61-471c-980d-a72b0826995a" pid="R2AsAgJa706Y408FB2-LRA" hash="30hj_g">Nearly two thousand years have passed since Alma and Jesus gave their teachings on chastity. Has God withdrawn the laws relative to chastity? Isn’t it a sin to commit adultery today?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p33" guid="7cc7e210-93d9-485f-abc7-3f6f7fa94200" pid="07jbgrtrZ02flf4br68Iaw" hash="sa0fIg">Jesus Christ has spoken from heaven in our day and restored his gospel and church. He has reconfirmed the age-old commandment in several different revelations of “Thou shalt not commit adultery.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p34" guid="e9258685-78c1-43e1-b1f0-86a03a3f825c" pid="JGUcTyWTD0iSl80NdXowcg" hash="7vvdrg">For example, to the people of his church, through the Prophet Joseph Smith, Jesus Christ gave the following commandment:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p35" guid="4153ea76-580e-4ca2-94e7-b744395ad097" pid="YXRWWLsgVkWsh7iw98nWIg" hash="2KKW4g">“Thou shalt love thy wife with all thy heart, and shalt cleave unto her and none else.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p36" guid="8581d2b4-8138-4fd0-9bc8-a447a1824f6b" pid="EMLK9NZsMUuwnCPLZFetZg" hash="3Fw1Rg">“And he that looketh upon a woman to lust after her shall deny the faith, and shall not have the Spirit; and if he repents not he shall be cast out.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.22-23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:22–23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p37" guid="9decff6d-2732-4b2b-bb69-30b121e5a419" pid="F7zid5yn30mmTUVK5a5CNQ" hash="u-o7Pg">Joseph Smith and Sidney Rigdon were shown the fate of adulterers after death in the world to come in telestial glory. The Lord told them:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p38" guid="3590bd9b-488d-4b5a-a68e-74b4c1619f34" pid="oiSB_YzwdUStH4eWvbhrMg" hash="gGqhkA">“These are they who are liars, and sorcerers, and adulterers, and whoremongers. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p39" guid="852c6b63-10fd-454d-abe0-60a08e26a3c2" pid="5dFy4pKaSE65BvW1fubJCA" hash="5c40KQ">“These are they who are cast down to hell to suffer the wrath of the Almighty God. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.103,106" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:103, 106</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p40" guid="4dfcb15b-30d2-42b4-aa69-8be76f6ce941" pid="MPwt-bJGZ0yk7PtOt3DRkw" hash="08XmYQ">The Lord commanded the priesthood holders in our dispensation as follows:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p41" guid="0d06b88b-7f6a-45f8-8900-2a634eedb1fb" pid="mluTbBvLCEKYW11I9PkVoQ" hash="mG0s4Q">“… let virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly; then shall thy confidence wax strong in the presence of God; and the doctrine of the priesthood shall distil upon thy soul as the dews from heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p42" guid="37947bee-17e2-4dfd-973d-a95ab3bfaa5d" pid="xu1K9nzvAUmvvy1a4G3LMQ" hash="FTlNQw">“The Holy Ghost shall be thy constant companion, and thy scepter an unchanging scepter of righteousness and truth. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.45-46" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:45–46</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p43" guid="f69c54c3-bc9d-4637-a37a-44c24e921f4f" pid="BiQQ4vHejESQBT_BhZPh9Q" hash="J6mdlw">May we think clean thoughts and refrain from all impure actions, living by every word that proceedeth forth from the mouth of God. Then shall we have joy in this life and prepare to come back into the presence of the Lord to be crowned with glory and eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery.p44" guid="8972eaeb-85d9-4923-9db6-ffc7c059f393" pid="XSbLAVw6-UOtTR2xQ8pv1w" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/04/thou-shalt-not-commit-adultery</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1971-general-conference/1971-04-2040-elder-milton-r-hunter-64k-eng.mp3" length="5763475" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Vitality of Love</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brethren and sisters, I humbly ask that the Spirit of God will direct me in what I say today.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03012_000_2060" doc-version="2" hash="VZt88Q"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="jPYW10PQJkebp5CDOdvrNQ" hash="RCHzcA">The Vitality of Love</h1><p class="authorName" guid="0a74aa6c-4b27-4fd5-bd64-7b5771dd0f1f" pid="-J6X6cR0gU2hdjNiJppj7w" hash="_F0-6A">Milton R. Hunter</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="366c0cd1-de7a-4333-bf16-1280e7611f57">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-33b2.jpg" alt="Conference photo" guid="99297aba-a893-4a8c-9189-82887af2ae4a" pid="0yvZxIyJcUSzOVkaH9cbxQ" hash="1ws_6Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p1" guid="4abe145b-01a7-4c32-9226-18029ede7402" pid="uvjKaGO-S0C1gSjKpAWIMQ" hash="_sTmgw">My dear brethren and sisters, I humbly ask that the Spirit of God will direct me in what I say today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p2" guid="58be2bbe-ecd2-497e-8a37-72855b0d7867" pid="5E2dAX70EkSK4URhByKhwA" hash="FrpzBg">The devil is mustering his forces to full strength to bring about discord, sin, and sorrow among the human family. These calamities can be averted to the extent that people live the basic principle of the gospel of Jesus Christ, which is love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p3" guid="53993b21-2389-4819-bb07-86cc61de3e4b" pid="7cLZacPUzEKIJimlOtoktw" hash="eljHBw">On a certain occasion a lawyer asked Jesus a question, “tempting him, and saying,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p4" guid="e0e7d9f4-c60e-46b3-aa94-e38cf7093653" pid="lMNuWAoy8E2INVpwwXQ3Bw" hash="25lWDg">“Master, which is the great commandment in the law?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p5" guid="82ecc441-2e04-4ffd-a541-6ec70f26c0d5" pid="moOdW9gncUuFkrySCD7JkQ" hash="4zjMZQ">“Jesus said unto him, Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p6" guid="a8c52e70-2e4f-4b6f-a40e-afea53b837f3" pid="7DDjPmUSKkKged9Mut96Dg" hash="pLnaTg">“This is the first and great commandment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p7" guid="0bd1610e-0ff4-4769-96ac-eb94ea46f6eb" pid="9MOM0UYenUSM0su_V-Ic9w" hash="9pnSeg">“And the second is like unto it, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p8" guid="740a76a8-2973-4433-bb78-2977bc86717e" pid="XSUQ4iY_KUGQM_riAaTt_g" hash="I57GLQ">“On these two commandments hang all the law and the prophets.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.35-40" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:35–40</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p9" guid="edb2e189-7e51-451e-a3ec-6a36a2c9850a" pid="SmHNWXALsUiAwIUQf4nCEQ" hash="Ymt3vA">In the days of our Savior, the Hebrew scriptures were divided into divisions. The first five books were called the Law. Another group was called the Prophets. In answering the lawyer, the Master quoted Deuteronomy and Leviticus, which were two of the books of the Hebrew Law. Thus, Jesus Christ was declaring that the two great laws of love were the basis of all the religious teachings of the Hebrew scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p10" guid="49346ee5-0c34-45d9-a7fa-309f62198052" pid="7VCaa8kfAkWzqEwa9_4akQ" hash="TDXkEA">Since the first great commandment is to love the Lord our God, how can we show our love for him? We can show our love in our prayers to the Father, given in the name of the Son, and also through our worship of those divine Beings. But, to become all-inclusive, Jesus said: “If ye love me, keep my commandments.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.15" class="scriptureRef">John 14:15</a>.) In other words, we should “live by every word that proceedeth forth from the mouth of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.44" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:44</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p11" guid="2650a6bf-c8ec-4713-99dc-03e7680843ac" pid="bZaLO7uj4UG2Q82xYi1iQA" hash="CSJCUg">Our Eternal Father and his Only Begotten Son both have intense, comprehensive, and full love for us. They have much greater intelligence and understanding than we have, and so their feelings of love go far beyond our capabilities to love. The attribute of love is so highly developed in these divine Beings that the scriptures state: “God is love.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-jn/4.16" class="scriptureRef">1 John 4:16</a>.) In fact, Deity’s transcendent love is above and beyond our deepest feelings and keenest conception. At times of great spiritual experience when we feel an abundance of the Spirit, we have a greater realization of the magnitude of God’s love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p12" guid="0071a9f4-d429-4352-91d6-57bb9a0faa51" pid="JvcfeUdpS0q357hz_-aUBg" hash="OnPD1g">God is the Father of our spirits. He placed us upon this earth and provided a gospel plan of salvation through his Only Begotten Son, thereby making it possible for us to come back into his presence and receive exaltation or eternal life. Those who attain that glorious condition will experience the sweetness of love, which surpasses our present understanding.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p13" guid="92f30b95-49a3-41ab-9ba4-284d302be02b" pid="WAfYDcHpgkifDWdwwznpCg" hash="HEQePA">“… God so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son, that whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.16" class="scriptureRef">John 3:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p14" guid="29693fc4-6cbe-4346-bed8-61838c7ad39f" pid="3TQf33Nf2EC_u2FVp_gtCQ" hash="m3RoFQ">Jesus Christ also loved us so much that he freely laid down his life and shed his blood for our sins, and also to bring about a universal resurrection. “Greater love hath no man than this, that a man lay down his life for his friends.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/15.13" class="scriptureRef">John 15:13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p15" guid="aa3a5b05-11e9-47d0-866a-2cf290fd7774" pid="mGKZM331YkyeE3sBnDCdCw" hash="5n1aoA">Among the entire human family, there is no example where the principle of love was demonstrated as perfectly as was shown in the life of Jesus in Palestine and in his ministry among the Nephites following his resurrection. He healed the sick, raised the dead, restored sight to the blind and hearing to the deaf, and cleansed those who were afflicted with leprosy. His heart was filled with compassion upon the poor and any who suffered afflictions. He lifted them spiritually with his deep understanding.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p16" guid="f8ab9fa3-51b9-4175-8193-534dd77d86de" pid="3-_cio2hzkmD_jm0rcuz1Q" hash="ktbrdA">A beautiful example of Christ’s love and compassion is given in the Book of Mormon when he blessed the little children:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p17" guid="1622e041-090d-4db2-9c8f-de00b35d0086" pid="3CQnuVq9UUaaRaW3j79A9w" hash="lJYakw">“And when he had said these words, he wept, and the multitude bare record of it, and he took their little children, one by one, and blessed them, and prayed unto the Father for them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p18" guid="77b935e7-744b-4a3a-be09-919a7aa04073" pid="keNUchTf-0WH7zHI2YA8Hg" hash="0WmMig">“And when he had done this he wept again;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p19" guid="7de2a173-76ea-45d3-98c2-1154b1669045" pid="mHUipYdRqkm0idBV8oLrRQ" hash="b62h6A">“And he spake unto the multitude, and said unto them: Behold your little ones.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p20" guid="cbe189ca-081c-402b-8f0a-73dc6a4e641d" pid="DovVHA8GiUanukJRaHfwXw" hash="yyEdMw">“And as they looked to behold they cast their eyes towards heaven, and they saw the heavens open, and they saw angels descending out of heaven as it were in the midst of fire; and they came down and encircled those little ones about, and they were encircled about with fire; and the angels did minister unto them.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.21-24" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:21–24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p21" guid="04650472-86ec-4c37-b286-0b5430cb02c1" pid="0dLOfw1AwkifgDhARgLfQA" hash="orMtmQ">A superb example of Christ’s great love is shown when he was hanging on the cross in pain and agony nigh unto death. Jesus prayed: “Father, forgive them; for they know not what they do.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/23.34" class="scriptureRef">Luke 23:34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p22" guid="27220243-da88-4184-9d90-77d964ae71af" pid="k_V29mPKrEOgh-gh6cigWw" hash="cubhgA">The central theme and the most dynamic force of the gospel of Jesus Christ is love. The Savior taught his apostles:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p23" guid="14043729-45d6-43f6-85ba-86300f27833d" pid="7B1CFQCag0OLTB4fIn_qyQ" hash="fUNUGQ">“A new commandment I give unto you, That ye love one another; as I have loved you, that ye also love one another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p24" guid="ec4db8dd-8406-4c2b-8e47-c1d67f3a6245" pid="NYWmPr99E0e2jm_b7YPzqw" hash="2hX4vw">“By this shall all men know that ye are my disciples, if ye have love one to another.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/13.34-35" class="scriptureRef">John 13:34–35</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p25" guid="8005eeb0-87a9-4a53-b07a-c980aea1ab8e" pid="RuFo1irhRUWg_L4f-2DgNg" hash="nacjxw">Christ declared that the second great commandment was to love our neighbor as ourselves. The Master Teacher knew that it is human nature for all people to be self-centered. Thus, to be a good Christian, we must love other people as much as we love ourselves. If we loved our neighbors as much as we love ourselves, all our dealings with them would be in kindness, charity, and generosity. All our actions would be tempered by love. Jesus also taught:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p26" guid="ab24a0e2-39a0-4ad6-a6b5-2ae7a89ed9ef" pid="iC7EliqykkCwaHU2_6qesg" hash="e2rtZg">“But I say unto you, Love your enemies, bless them that curse you, do good to them that hate you, and pray for them which despitefully use you, and persecute you;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p27" guid="23ad106c-1440-43de-9607-7ca2a24519d9" pid="wUilwFkLRk6rnNHwUjD_eQ" hash="cEdDxQ">“That ye may be the children of your Father which is in heaven: …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p28" guid="e95f4341-d5f6-4829-85d4-8a09275c88a0" pid="BE56F_WpJkOvPJSzQaxL5A" hash="q6MjaQ">“Be ye therefore perfect, even as your Father which is in heaven is perfect.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.44-45,48" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:44–45, 48</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p29" guid="4855673f-a441-4d67-aad9-f8794c807167" pid="TKYZJzvYjECn3hwLLrBHHQ" hash="353wtQ">What should be the relationship between husbands and wives, especially if they are Latter-day Saints?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p30" guid="1ffe90d0-92b2-4970-824d-be143f6a8f5d" pid="2Qh6kAYifkqPXaxgUsl4GA" hash="wMg6rQ">A husband and wife should always be gracious and kind to each other. Neither of them should ever say or do anything to hurt the feelings of the other. Deepest love and affection should be shown toward each other continuously. At all times each should make a conscious effort to do everything possible to bring joy and happiness into the life of the other. A husband should show and express appreciation for the accomplishments of his mate, and she should do likewise. We should look for ways to build each other up and make each other happy. Neither the husband nor the wife should let a day pass without expressing love for the other. We should not assume that our mate knows and that it is not necessary to express it. At one time I had the honor of having President Joseph Fielding Smith and his beloved wife Jessie attend a conference to which I had been assigned. In her talk Sister Smith said: “I never let a day go by without telling my husband that I love him, and he never lets a day go by without telling me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p31" guid="b2e3b263-35ef-48db-b406-b55eba3baa8b" pid="tiLCDT0dF0OdAx0yP7qY4g" hash="Q2wfdA">Under these circumstances, God’s blessings will shower down from heaven upon the married couple and especially for those married by the power of the priesthood in the house of the Lord. The power from on high will bind the love and marriage of such couples for eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p32" guid="a856d9ca-649a-4dd4-be27-85a316f77bf3" pid="XytMbdZ9_k6UbzSR3AYEHw" hash="de4g_w">President David O. McKay, always an advocate of love and harmony in the home, stated: “Homes are made permanent through love.” (<span class="emphasis">Pathways to Happiness </span>[Bookcraft], p. 114.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p33" guid="92dba504-c312-4e32-8aae-729085e10295" pid="K0WvMKFtj0yI34ZTMfJtnQ" hash="9-u3qQ">“Learn the value of self-control. You are never sorry for the word unspoken. I believe the lack of self-control is one of the most common contributing factors of unhappiness and discord. We see something in the other which we dislike. It is easy to condemn it. And that condemnatory word arouses ill feeling. If we see it, and we refrain from speaking, in a few moments all is concord and peace instead of animosity and ill will. Controlling the tongue is one of the greatest contributing factors to concord in the home, and one which too many of us fail to develop.” (Ibid., p. 120.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p34" guid="7832c54a-fe29-41b2-b45d-b9cb42fb7472" pid="3IIot2kWIU6DEO7hVzO7XQ" hash="GkeSoQ">Love should also characterize the center of the family life. Each child should be made to feel at all times by his parents that he is of great importance in the family. Parents should express their love to their children and show them in numerous ways that they love them dearly. Then the Spirit of the Lord will reside in the home. The family will be love-centered and thereby God-centered. The children in turn will reciprocate the love to the parents and strive to please them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p35" guid="5b37198b-55f3-4021-95a5-a4c7a1c442a9" pid="Ov7cIR4HCkyhO80N57D_gw" hash="ey8YRA">The goal of families who are actuated deeply by love will be to keep the commandments of our Savior in every detail and someday come back into the presence of the Eternal Father and his Only Begotten Son to dwell.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love.p36" guid="2855b85f-7f25-4d75-88e8-b15fb8557c3d" pid="L5LMHo3huE-gxhdK4VwMqw" hash="Q9hc7g">I bear my testimony that the true gospel of our Lord has been restored to earth again, and that the Master’s church is The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/10/the-vitality-of-love</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1971-general-conference/1971-10-2060-elder-milton-r-hunter-64k-eng.mp3" length="10022633" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Miracle of Missionary Work</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brethren and sisters, I humbly ask that the Spirit of God attend me in what I may say today.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03020_000_2020" doc-version="2" hash="dkqu3w"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="jHIOAiXOtEqZirUeSEj4LQ" hash="88218g">The Miracle of Missionary Work</h1><p class="authorName" guid="0a74aa6c-4b27-4fd5-bd64-7b5771dd0f1f" pid="WO7q3SoNPUWAyOsCqs3Zlw" hash="_F0-6A">Milton R. Hunter</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="13ea5154-54b4-4b63-b2b9-4640b9b9b8b6">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-33b2.jpg" alt="President Milton R. Hunter" guid="80a14b7e-11e5-464d-9d77-e5f3c520ef57" pid="nZvjYlrBCEGhSiVhec_pXw" hash="1ws_6Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p1" guid="d53b29bf-ce6d-491d-9e25-ce62e1b9c5cd" pid="YdMJN8mlS06to9pMK7FUmQ" hash="YYNXJw">My dear brethren and sisters, I humbly ask that the Spirit of God attend me in what I may say today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p2" guid="6b1fd2e3-f1ad-4efd-90d6-59629d2f9d2f" pid="OTQgBs51H0mV_DWeHycMbg" hash="nt4i0Q">In my opinion, one of the great miracles in our generation is the miracle of missionary work of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p3" guid="cf9e7968-c4db-4807-9195-08d0b8c92698" pid="OjwbEM-42E-noAN1duvnDA" hash="ednHmA">At the present time, the Church has ninety-eight missions, which cover most of the world. There are over 15,400 missionaries devoting their full time to proselyting activities. In addition to these, there are several thousand mature men and women from all professions serving on a part-time basis in the stake missions. These missionaries are either paying their own expenses or they are receiving financial support from their friends, relatives, or Melchizedek Priesthood quorums.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p4" guid="6fb7505a-46ed-462f-a187-332528de85c6" pid="ISv12wzc10CUe6pgASNKsw" hash="OU-04w">The vast majority of the full-time missionaries are young men nineteen to twenty-one years of age, a time of life in which young people, as a general rule, would not devote themselves to full-time church service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p5" guid="e8ba819b-e75e-4f7c-ab3b-8418dacc01db" pid="55olApSVF0aPSp8cnd5qvw" hash="NcWtrA">It should be pointed out that these young men interrupt their education, put off marriage, and adjust their missions to their military obligations, so they can do missionary work for their church and their Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p6" guid="0c4466f4-117d-4719-93ba-7eda1d8d43ae" pid="ZNDRowQlFUGZQ2MM-3rhWQ" hash="xkQf1Q">Thus the miracle of missionary service is repeated over and over with every missionary who gives of his time and in the sacrifices made by those who supply the financial help.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p7" guid="fc3148b9-1326-4d3e-94e5-255441cd8980" pid="aGMHr7oR606Q3i-wbpM9MA" hash="4z9R2A">Why this modern miracle of missionary work?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p8" guid="bae5588f-c3ab-4036-8d96-10494bf577f7" pid="9vN62BP7i0qiFX_rs0t7Mg" hash="LgNIuQ">First, this extensive missionary work is carried forward because those people who serve as missionaries and those who give them their financial support have strong testimonies in their hearts that they belong to Christ’s true church, which he restored on earth in 1830. They are positive that The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is the only church in the world which possesses God’s holy priesthood, his true doctrines and ordinances, and the power to bring people into celestial glory to dwell with their Creator. And so they go on missions in order that other people may receive the gospel and share the same joy and blessings that they have.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p9" guid="44d8169b-0ed8-41b5-886f-05a2f230b7cb" pid="WS7lnOYMBUmpfLBwKxye7g" hash="ri4YwQ">Second, the modern miracle of extensive missionary work occurs because in several revelations Jesus Christ commanded that it be done. For example, he commanded Church members as follows:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p10" guid="145aeade-b435-450b-8dfa-e961dafd98ff" pid="Ad3a7BDIoUCNgthbhJaFAg" hash="-TAydw">“Go ye into all the world, preach the gospel to every creature, acting in the authority which I have given you, baptizing in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p11" guid="c4fa587f-fa6f-4f11-ac4e-0c121a27159b" pid="NfFIRHA6NE6nJkam6x_6gA" hash="-T4kGA">“And he that believeth and is baptized shall be saved, and he that believeth not shall be damned.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.8-9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:8–9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p12" guid="b3171eef-698d-4bc3-8cb7-2cff9515bc18" pid="FTwCAC6i_kqmMIpIVxYXeQ" hash="2EnftA">As I have toured missions, many missionaries, as well as converts, have reported to me unusual missionary experiences or miracles. A stake president in California told me the following missionary experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p13" guid="0bb30e00-2ad5-40d1-80ee-984ca71a00c9" pid="etc2rq2k_UOB67STyZwXmA" hash="N2l3kQ">A young man in his stake from a well-to-do family had been taught the gospel by missionaries. His interest in the Church was very displeasing to his parents. They endeavored to persuade him not to join, but he still declared that he had a strong testimony that this was the true church of Jesus Christ and that he must join. Then, in desperation, the parents took the drastic step of telling him that if he became a member of the Mormon Church, he would be disinherited. In spite of this warning, the young man joined the Church and his parents literally turned him out of his home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p14" guid="ea3dd377-65f9-40e3-aabd-9bb6e9a02fca" pid="GtxqjV-vTEy6VySpzJQklQ" hash="9WVNeA">He was invited to live with a Mormon family. While he was there, the bishop and stake president asked him to go on a mission. He accepted the call. Before he left, however, his parents heard through a mutual friend that their son was going on a mission. They sent word to him that if he did, they would never write him a word, nor send him money, and that he was not to contact them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p15" guid="4372a413-13e7-4c4f-a9e3-87b53313ea55" pid="_8o6KM6TnUuLrrVY2s-zyg" hash="ns8e_A">About a year later, when the young man was in the mission field, the stake president was called on the telephone about one o’clock in the morning. The gentle voice of a woman on the other end of the line asked if he would please give her that missionary’s address because she wanted to send him some money. Thus, it appears that the love of a mother had risen above her religious prejudice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p16" guid="d520edb0-6ff6-4e82-bc29-328f146809e7" pid="AS3J5BCtYkefegkQSXyCWQ" hash="zinf0w">While touring a mission, I ran across a missionary who had been an all-American basketball star in college. Upon graduation from the university, he had turned down a high-paying contract to play professional ball so he could go on a mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p17" guid="98137e76-360f-4c1f-90c8-1ef903cb9292" pid="jaQd6eeV802xjqwm5EoIfw" hash="I94sJw">Another missionary told me that when he graduated from high school he was offered $30,000 a year to play professional baseball. He refused the offer so he could go on a mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p18" guid="a88adba1-dd85-41c4-bb2b-d8d949694072" pid="doYa3v5dIEyy8yPkKKj4Aw" hash="VaABIg">When a young man is faced with the choice of a mission or of playing professional ball at a high salary, it takes great faith and devotion to choose the mission; but many young Latter-day Saint men have made this choice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p19" guid="4e75c7a3-1a7c-4c7b-a70a-97b835d3dc0f" pid="kp46aYwoR0e_oSnzeeU2Ig" hash="DDCEXg">Recently in South America, a lady missionary, who impressed me greatly, told me the story of her conversion to the LDS Church and her missionary call. Before coming on her mission she was a nurse. Her roommate was a Mormon girl. The nurse liked the girl’s habits, was very pleased with her character and personality, and so she decided to study the LDS religion. The Mormon girl got two missionaries to teach the nurse the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p20" guid="78469314-4d19-4755-bd7a-82c1420495c3" pid="abR8zxHv5ESCIv7qBdw13Q" hash="P7kulg">When the nurse’s parents heard that she was favorably inclined toward the Mormon religion, they thoroughly opposed her actions. They forbade her to join the Church, telling her that if she did she would be disinherited.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p21" guid="e1fb6893-d11d-49ec-8cad-fe699caed081" pid="8okOh1oIy0WahpTkQPfZwQ" hash="leVe9g">The Holy Ghost had borne witness to her so strongly that the Church of Jesus Christ was the true church that she asked the missionaries to baptize her even against the wishes of her parents, whom she loved dearly. It grieved her when her father and mother told her not to return home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p22" guid="20105880-005b-4dfa-9f6d-1eae2da774dd" pid="VUMbShHdvUy45jsWD2FuuQ" hash="nKHyfg">After joining the Church, she had a very strong desire to go on a mission and so she decided to work and save the money. It took her three or four years’ time to save approximately $3,000. She was called to labor in South America, where she is doing an outstanding job in taking the gospel of Jesus Christ to the people of that land. When she returns home, she hopes to regain the love and favor of her parents.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p23" guid="572b5c71-e9ca-43c7-a62e-1c3b1d9b7382" pid="7jz8-KIoaECs7FU8-fNIlA" hash="tvaeZA">Several years ago, after returning from touring a mission, I said to one of my friends, “Did you make any converts when you were on your mission in a certain town?” And I told him the name of the town.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p24" guid="3b0915d3-9f6b-49eb-92fd-3334a8b07705" pid="nMkOU0d-9E2f3KdgOjvyJw" hash="QUCtxQ">He replied, “No, I didn’t make a single convert there. My companion and I had very poor missionary success in that town.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p25" guid="1a7b141a-293d-4d34-8af9-4762ea9a1483" pid="-5fLw0Olj0O0LBIeHiqXlQ" hash="WChxgA">I informed him that recently I had held a meeting in that town. Following the meeting, a woman approached the mission president and me and said, “When I was a girl two Mormon missionaries came to our home a number of times and talked with my mother. Each time the missionaries came to our home, I ran into the kitchen and peeked through the door and listened while they conversed with mother, who wasn’t very interested. As soon as they had left, I would run into the living room, pick up the literature that they had left on the table, and go to my room and study it. I was very thrilled with what I was learning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p26" guid="433079e2-10a4-41d5-a784-bad9de9b3ed1" pid="mSfF26sw3EaEyTkYNPlnmQ" hash="EU3Cjw">“Finally I obtained a copy of the Book of Mormon and read it. I became thoroughly converted to the Church of Jesus Christ, having a firm conviction that it was the true church. When I grew to maturity, two more Mormon missionaries came to town and I asked them to baptize me. After I had become a Church member, I taught the gospel to my friends and relatives. There are over fifty members in this branch who belong to the Church as a result of my conversion and baptism.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p27" guid="2d086918-ec45-46d8-8272-cb124a29f885" pid="Wlf6UPlEPEmIR0GZY8UOCg" hash="N-p3tQ">I then said to my friend, “You see, you and your missionary companion indirectly have over fifty converts in that town in which you thought you got none.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p28" guid="2660b38b-72e9-4f88-b595-d6c4be5a8c95" pid="C3rb7GoDhE2Z0TNkhewICA" hash="P2a7kQ">A missionary related an experience that illustrates one method that God has used to bring the searchers after truth into his true church. He stated that he and his companion had knocked on a door. A woman opened the door immediately, enthusiastically invited them in, and said to them, “You young men have come to my home today in answer to my prayers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p29" guid="f6270793-d729-4e8c-a118-2a2d913f0310" pid="VuncDmNGNkyIp5-cGaSa-g" hash="vIt2RQ">“For a long time I have been dissatisfied with the church to which I belong, feeling that it does not contain many of the doctrines that Christ taught while here upon the earth. I felt that it was not the true church that was founded originally by our Savior. I prayed earnestly and asked our Father in heaven to send somebody to me who would bring me the true gospel plan of salvation and make it possible for me to find the true church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p30" guid="1cee79f7-b69a-48fb-b27f-557f0c04484e" pid="3D0kQkET70qjBGcPNDSong" hash="XjLSYg">“After doing so, I had a dream that two young men knocked on my door and when I let them in they said to me, ‘We have come to bring you the true gospel of Jesus Christ.’ I recognize that you two young men are the same two young men I saw in my dream, and as in my dream, you announced yourselves by saying, ‘We have come to bring you the gospel of Jesus Christ.’ I know that you are the servants of our Master and that you will teach me his gospel.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p31" guid="90fae56a-2f27-4c74-aa39-137b0046c7bc" pid="IY3t3LFvTU6YRrmxlclHAQ" hash="o6ybSg">The two missionaries were surprised at the reception but happy to have the privilege of teaching this good woman the gospel. She eagerly received it and soon thereafter was a baptized member of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. Thus, another modern miracle in missionary work had occurred.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p32" guid="d1a4f91f-fa01-4403-bea2-e8471592e263" pid="TNcvtnVTTUSIIJ7hkjPYzg" hash="e2fJvA">The faith and devotion of mission presidents and their wives and families present marvelous stories of sacrifice and service to spread the gospel of Jesus Christ and build up his kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p33" guid="26810c2a-9a66-40fb-b042-6c1593ed5424" pid="Ud5dDiE3ek6ed9ERFH80gw" hash="CyMZzA">When the First Presidency, serving as God’s holy prophets, call a man and his wife to preside over a mission, regardless of their business situation or economic conditions, the answer is yes. All personal interests are pushed aside and they faithfully accept the call from the Lord through the First Presidency to preside over a mission for three years’ time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p34" guid="4a78bf75-b327-4925-83f8-c2679eab1955" pid="6JDHiX6yyEyb7R28wWNBGg" hash="INH0vg">Each mission president’s individual call, his experiences and faithfulness in accepting that call, adjusting his economic affairs, and completely readjusting the social life for himself and family, is a modern missionary miracle.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p35" guid="db34b0e6-f55c-4f16-9761-650e6f39b899" pid="XhA3omhVKESZtxJqt6lzcg" hash="1SI4Sw">For example, in a casual conversation I had recently with the president of one of the full-time missions of the Church, he told me that when he received his mission call from the First Presidency, he asked his employers for a leave of absence. Within three years his financial interest in the company in which he was employed would be large enough to support him and his family for the remainder of their lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p36" guid="a8cffd3f-3f4c-47ca-bce4-26971a1fa23d" pid="Yh5nPsXC2U2215zwto6KMw" hash="fV5JnA">His employers, being non-church members and unfavorable toward his going on a mission, refused to give him a leave of absence. Also, they informed him that he would lose all of his financial benefits in the company if he accepted the mission call. In spite of this terrific financial sacrifice and the loss of his job, he accepted the mission call and is now faithfully serving his church and his God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p37" guid="6e451389-3478-4ffc-b965-54422dce6649" pid="blcg7YfMLUWXJ8_pRnzSLg" hash="iJVYXA">I asked the mission president, “Why didn’t you tell the First Presidency of the financial loss you would suffer if you went on a mission at that time and ask them to postpone your call for three years?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p38" guid="1b025958-f229-4c6d-b5ee-c70737c78265" pid="kTyx5FKbUUiojuXkXHLqWA" hash="HUOM-g">He replied, “The Lord didn’t call me on a mission for three years from now. He called me to serve now. My wife and I decided to obey the call of the Lord and trust that our financial affairs would be taken care of later.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p39" guid="7fcbf761-84cf-4397-baac-6840db82e3f1" pid="e7rcnHHSm0OLRILnJYr_cQ" hash="gyeFQw">Such a sacrifice to render Christian service is certainly astounding. It is a modern missionary miracle.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p40" guid="1b1aaa3e-53fc-4ead-b9fb-41825f3a4320" pid="DuUMkGI2Jk6NMRNhp_2Dig" hash="g_gaKA">In closing, I bear my testimony that the true church of Jesus Christ has been restored to earth by the Savior and other heavenly beings to the Prophet Joseph Smith. Membership in this church and living in accordance with the revealed teachings therein is the only way back to God. This church marks out the pathway that mankind must follow to attain eternal life in the presence of the Father and the Son.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work.p41" guid="32fe7ab6-5956-4cda-87d3-9c15e09b0865" pid="IicPN-e8fkaXVbUO6prgeA" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/04/the-miracle-of-missionary-work</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1972-general-conference/1972-04-2020-elder-milton-r-hunter-64k-eng.mp3" length="6597140" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
