<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Monte J. Brough</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Monte J. Brough.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Monte%20J.%20Brough.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Monte J. Brough.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 1988 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>A Willing Heart</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1988/10/a-willing-heart?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I can tell you now, after about a hundred minutes of experience, that these big red chairs are not really as comfortable as they look.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/a-willing-heart" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03232_000_017" doc-version="2" hash="VT95GA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/a-willing-heart.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="NQ8uVcHX0067ltXVOMosYA" hash="jhphYg">A Willing Heart</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Ft5JGsSr70eOBpIYnhsZOA" hash="2ho-tA">Monte J. Brough</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/a-willing-heart.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e46.jpg" alt="Elder Monte J. Brough" pid="prngsBbR70yZwGMzcjTGaA" hash="TcY8Qw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/a-willing-heart.p1" pid="f4zsrcijbk2WjsbcQd_Maw" hash="PwDgkw">I can tell you now, after about a hundred minutes of experience, that these big red chairs are not really as comfortable as they look.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/a-willing-heart.p2" pid="_YmOFRMmskS9N0cvNrhA3Q" hash="BnofIA">On Thursday afternoon, my family and I were celebrating my child’s birthday at a rather loud and noisy gathering in our home when the phone rang. A woman’s voice said, “Brother Monte Brough, would you hold the phone a moment? President Hinckley would like to speak with you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/a-willing-heart.p3" pid="YoZ8RBRG9kehmX_NtqXzLA" hash="6n0y6w">I said, “President Hinckley!” in order to gain some attention from my rather raucous family. They quieted rather quickly, I can tell you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/a-willing-heart.p4" pid="V4hAiXxFiU6R_6g4Uvx3Jg" hash="d47oDQ">President Hinckley came on the phone and said, “Brother Brough, would it be convenient for you to come and see me?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/a-willing-heart.p5" pid="fQHTQcGMdUOwjvhuOE81Gw" hash="RhrQlQ">In a rather stilted way, I responded for a moment or two to a couple of questions, then said, “President Hinckley, you have given me a rather frightening phone call.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/a-willing-heart.p6" pid="pbzIlxbYG0OYx4JmlBGC2A" hash="fHQAIA">He said, “Oh, don’t worry about it. We’re just going to give you a new broom and let you sweep the steps in front of the office building.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/a-willing-heart.p7" pid="zwBKgj45bEuKpPQT4xOoPQ" hash="PfiKgA">President Hinckley, I want you and these Brethren to know that I would be honored to take up that broom and sweep those steps where you have walked, where President Benson has walked, and where all these men whom I admire and love with all my heart have walked.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/a-willing-heart.p8" pid="CeswkT_l3U-fcxC-ZXSSRw" hash="Vepmrw">A few years ago while I was presiding over the mission in Minneapolis, Minnesota, an interesting event took place. I would like to use that experience to bear my testimony. A rather severe tornado hit the area. It was severe enough that it came to the attention of the nightly news broadcast over the national networks to California, Arizona, Utah, and Idaho. Before long, the telephone started ringing in our office there at the mission home. This went on for two or three hours, with parents calling from many areas wondering about their Johnny or Richard.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/a-willing-heart.p9" pid="0qt8AjdbHEOmkqA5Ne9idg" hash="Yt1jyA">I recall later walking across the parking lot from the mission office to the mission home saying to myself, “You know these Mormon mothers. They just won’t undo the apron strings. They just won’t let their boys go.” As I walked into the mission home, the phone again was ringing. I picked up the phone and guess who? My mother! She was wondering how her missionary was doing under these circumstances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/a-willing-heart.p10" pid="SaKEfeQG-UC-SP6JAEFTsQ" hash="PuGeAg">I learned a great and deep lesson. A mother’s love and concern never ceases—nor should it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/a-willing-heart.p11" pid="469elBbVMU6FI_fPBlPRWQ" hash="hveQjA">I have no memory of my father. I was not raised in a home where the priesthood was strong. A bishop in Randolph, Utah, and mission presidents later on are responsible for my being here tonight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/a-willing-heart.p12" pid="KX8hv8IAakq5lGQlqibrWA" hash="i5W2zA">In reference to Elder Marvin J. Ashton’s talk, I have work to do on my heart—but one thing I do have is a willing heart. I am willing to do anything and everything that I can to help in this great cause. I bear witness that I know this is God’s work. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1988/10/a-willing-heart</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1988-general-conference/1988-10-3030-elder-monte-j-brough-64k-eng.mp3" length="1731344" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 1988 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Modern Mighty of Israel</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As a young man in one of my first Primary classes, I was fortunate enough to have a leader introduce me to the Old Testament story “David’s” mighty men. This is a detailed account of the actions of the finest soldiers under David’s command. At one ti</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_93911_000_026" doc-version="2" hash="4vmHzg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="nauIbGtS7UyELJ0bzzX7bg" hash="BPRmHw">The Modern Mighty of Israel</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="b3jbOtVal0OvAoomoG2jEw" hash="2ho-tA">Monte J. Brough</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e46.jpg" alt="Elder Monte J. Brough" pid="gZyhdypunU6DexWfzB7Hyg" hash="TcY8Qw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p1" pid="2fdG86P9x0eZzj0cXBkwyA" hash="Zf5tSg">As a young man in one of my first Primary classes, I was fortunate enough to have a leader introduce me to the Old Testament story “David’s” mighty men. This is a detailed account of the actions of the finest soldiers under David’s command. At one time, only thirty-seven men of the huge armies of Israel were considered good enough to receive the coveted title of “mighty man” (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/2-sam/23.39" class="scriptureRef">2 Sam. 23:39</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p2" pid="LFcqGfpjKUG_6MNS6pOq-w" hash="lGEzrw">Let us learn more about the qualities of this outstanding group of soldiers. In Chronicles we read, “They were armed with bows, and could use both the right hand and the left in hurling stones and shooting arrows out of a bow” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-chr/12.2" class="scriptureRef">1 Chr. 12:2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p3" pid="c9V6RTvoWES4IDsu1jXPGQ" hash="Mwq5sA">They were men “fit for the battle, that could handle shield and buckler, whose faces were like the faces of lions, and were as swift as the roes upon the mountains” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-chr/12.8" class="scriptureRef">1 Chr. 12:8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p4" pid="-j7QuaDwDUSNUucLGB16Hg" hash="kqyRDA">These mighty men had developed the skills of a warrior to a very high degree. They were determined and, as with the faces of lions, completely without fear. They were prepared for any battle.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p5" pid="9EJAcLbL8k6hi2XeGgmNxA" hash="LbVMkw">The impression upon me, as the achievements and exploits of these mighty men were explained by my teacher, was profound. In fact, while my friends played their fantasy games as cowboys or spacemen or athletic stars, I imagined that I had been selected by King David as one of his mighty men. I even fashioned wood swords out of plaster laths and spears out of long willow sticks and pretended to go to war against the enemies of the king. Funny … as I think about it, the enemy was just about always my two little brothers. The story of the preparation and devotion of these mighty men has been a source of inspiration to me since my early years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p6" pid="tNlMrjNU5U2N7zaUHFzPxQ" hash="D0H8nQ">One inspiring account tells of three of these mighty men who overheard King David long for a drink of water from the well of Bethlehem. Apparently, in Bethlehem at that time was a well of particularly refreshing water of which the king wished for a drink. The king did not place a demand or order for the water; he simply expressed a desire for a taste of the cool, refreshing liquid from the Bethlehem well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p7" pid="A5oZfMgPo0ubmfovJxITJg" hash="w6E2-Q">Without command or assignment or even duty, three of the mighty men broke through enemy lines, at great personal risk, to travel to Bethlehem. They drew water out of the well and returned, again at great risk through the enemy lines, to bring the wonderful refreshment of Bethlehem water to David. David was so overcome by this demonstrated act of personal, unsolicited service that he refused to drink the water. He considered the act so brave and wonderful that he poured the water upon the ground. The scripture says, “He … poured it out unto the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/2-sam/23.14-17" class="scriptureRef">2 Sam. 23:14–17</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/ot/1-chr/11.17-19" class="scriptureRef">1 Chr. 11:17–19</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p8" pid="1MJLgtoRMkqYw5Kx6P9Fxw" hash="40BgVA">Isn’t that an inspiring story of dedication and volunteer service? Such an act of loyalty and initiative without command was common among these men. Is it any wonder that these mighty men would become heroes to a young boy? Let us examine other qualities and contributions of these mighty men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p9" pid="WrUot8TK8E-InyDPEym_0g" hash="XRSUQA">They were “men that had understanding of the times, to know what Israel ought to do” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-chr/12.32" class="scriptureRef">1 Chr. 12:32</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p10" pid="MuzytYCcj0urAawON2FMnQ" hash="iqvUkw">This special understanding of the times and the resultant ability to know what Israel ought to do are most significant. In other words, these mighty were informed and educated in matters relating to the conditions of their times. How did they gain this understanding? Many of the tribes or states of Israel were numbered among the thirty-seven. They brought additional strength through their cultural diversity to the armies of Israel. Tempered by difficult personal experiences, several of which are accounted in the stories of the thirty-seven, they had come to understand their times. This allowed them to better know the needs of their people and the solutions to many of the challenges of the times. So with this understanding, they came to know what Israel ought to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p11" pid="WLc-CoEmQUaRY-Fbn6Kpvw" hash="NVcF7g">They were men “which could keep rank: they were not of double heart” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-chr/12.33" class="scriptureRef">1 Chr. 12:33</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p12" pid="YsnV3UoUP0uS2-hKpxbn4A" hash="zcGqHw">These mighty men understood the need for an organization which would stay in place during difficult and challenging times. These men did not have a “double heart” which compelled them to seek their own personal interest ahead of that of Israel. Because of their single heart, manifest by pure motives, they did not aspire to a different position or rank within the armies of David. Each of the thirty-seven could absolutely depend upon the others to fulfill the assignment which came to them, whatever their rank. They understood their responsibilities and kept that place.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p13" pid="cTiyrU4CUUudMkz7LAMTsQ" hash="e9b97w">The final quality to which I wish to refer is one which we might assert as the most important quality of these mighty men. Again we read:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p14" pid="ktiju84j0E-G1cGtHu0dfw" hash="kQ_Yhw">“All these men of war, that could keep rank, came with a perfect heart to Hebron, to make David king over all Israel: and all the rest also of Israel were of one heart to make David king” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-chr/12.38" class="scriptureRef">1 Chr. 12:38</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p15" pid="VVMwsKlaZUC7aTCzPwshCQ" hash="hVcRdw">This quality was the condition of their “perfect heart,” which was demonstrated by complete devotion to building the ancient kingdom of Israel. They had no agenda, personal or otherwise, which was separate from their commitment to the king and the building of Israel. They understood the divine nature of David’s station and offered their complete loyalty and devotion to him. Theirs was a perfect heart. So were the mighty men of Israel!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p16" pid="AhLvYmp_XEmYLIZeyvWoPQ" hash="rPNgtA">Later I learned the stories of others whose character would make them mighty men. Consider the story of the development and growth of mighty Peter. He was carefully nurtured by the Lord to gain the skills and commitment which would allow him to become a mighty man. His ultimate achievement of a perfect heart is made manifest by his response to the third question:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p17" pid="LaMqVYL_oEWZrYOK6ASMFQ" hash="Wfx8wA">“Lovest thou me? And he said unto him, Lord, thou knowest all things; thou knowest that I love thee” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/21.17" class="scriptureRef">John 21:17</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p18" pid="eFbBfszRskG62x5RnHBJcQ" hash="ra3mnw">And there is mighty Apostle Paul, whose courage and initiative are summarized in these words of more sure prophecy:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p19" pid="jAAhmtKdvk2V4USJy4cfYA" hash="IYlYNg">“For I am now ready to be offered, and the time of my departure is at hand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p20" pid="obOuAzMcKEGrAhO2d59tTw" hash="PFiCIg">“I have fought a good fight, I have finished my course, I have kept the faith” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/4.6-7" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 4:6–7</a>). What mighty men!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p21" pid="QeIopYDQM0Gq2f8IsnzxWA" hash="zPA46w">Lest anyone misunderstand, let us also include one of the most beautiful examples of the qualities of the mighty men. This statement was offered by a woman with mighty qualities, Ruth:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p22" pid="JSxIio4Q7kCc_yKDL-CZQA" hash="qar3dQ">“Intreat me not to leave thee, or to return from following after thee: for whither thou goest, I will go; and where thou lodgest, I will lodge: thy people shall be my people, and thy God my God:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p23" pid="CjSsi62kMkKtFXvoYtd8aQ" hash="LAEp3Q">“Where thou diest, will I die, and there will I be buried” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ruth/1.16-17" class="scriptureRef">Ruth 1:16–17</a>). What a mighty woman!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p24" pid="JEVX4dEf2kqj-D2aSfz3xw" hash="7qQtvA">David himself, as a youth, provided an example of the qualities of the mighty men he would later lead. As he faced the giant warrior, he affirmed:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p25" pid="ObxnfY8S60mSRlApID2w2g" hash="tv3LqA">“Thou comest to me with a sword, and with a spear, and with a shield: but I come to thee in the name of the Lord of hosts, the God of the armies of Israel” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-sam/17.45" class="scriptureRef">1 Sam. 17:45</a>). What a mighty youth!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p26" pid="zwKDFxukoUi42OEUggsENw" hash="RBV2Qg">Of mortal men, Joseph Smith may best exemplify the qualities of the mighty men. His story of sacrifice and commitment can also be summarized in one of his final statements:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p27" pid="gUvgfo7hD0ewVvi-WdWzOQ" hash="LAPhyg">“I am going like a lamb to the slaughter; but I am calm as a summer’s morning; I have a conscience void of offense towards God, and towards all men” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/135.4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 135:4</a>). What a mighty, mighty man!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p28" pid="Z6xlVe6z7UGWI0e-CM0KKA" hash="dWnEbA">Even now I am searching for additional examples of mighty men and mighty women. Let me tell you what I know about the General Authorities and general auxiliary leaders of the Church, men and women. I’m not sure they can throw a spear with either hand, as did the mighty men, but they bring to their assignments a lifetime of excellent preparation. The families of these modern mighty warriors have not been spared the challenges of life and living. Through life’s experiences, which include tragedy, sickness, accident, poverty, and, in some cases, even infirmities of age, these mighty servants have come to an understanding of the times.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p29" pid="RmW6_JCTsUqttQab1gW1Vw" hash="rKTvjw">These men and women, including their valiant and supportive spouses, have achieved high levels of experience in law, medicine, homemaking, education, business, and agriculture. While certainly not without challenges, they have been remarkably successful in their roles as parents and heads of households. They have contributed collectively many years of full-time service in the Church. They have served as members of state legislatures, city governments, school boards, national and international professional organizations. Their years of community service include service with humanitarian and educational organizations and raising voluntary funds for a great variety of community causes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p30" pid="95CKYGYCYEqnp2atE-cLmw" hash="rZxoFA">As with the mighty of ancient days, these modern mighty come from many states or nations and bring a great diversity of experience and culture. This collective experience includes hundreds of years of service living in countries other than the one of their birth. Some, as they sit before you, are suffering the ravages of jet lag and fatigue from the enormous travel requirements which are part of their assignments. Many have gathered from all over the world and, in a few days, will again disperse to most of the nations of the earth. In most cases, they will leave their children and grandchildren behind as they pursue the demands placed upon them by their single heart. I assure you that these mighty have come to an understanding of these modern times and of what the Church and the membership of the Church ought to do. This understanding and knowledge are not achieved through their substantial intellect alone but through the development of their “perfect hearts.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p31" pid="NTnCBLE2q0K8oUeJD2J5Jg" hash="CUe0ug">I suggest that all who listen to my voice would benefit by an examination of the lives of those we sustain as general officers of the Church. You will find some important examples among them and come to know those who have a “perfect heart.” What mighty men and women!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p32" pid="9HRLXIXRSUmsn3RirkoenA" hash="QCyGMA">Please know that I stand as a witness of Him who is mightiest of all and whom we most want to emulate. Review again the Book of Mormon record of His mighty declaration of devotion and obedience to His Father:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p33" pid="NNqSrP3NGUymLdTP3VIdXA" hash="rmaonQ">“I am Jesus Christ. … I have drunk out of that bitter cup which the Father hath given me, and have glorified the Father in taking upon me the sins of the world, in the which I have suffered the will of the Father in all things from the beginning” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.10-11" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:10–11</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p34" pid="BDY-V4dCzUifUEIgIGPPQQ" hash="AepvOQ">Brothers and sisters, during this conference please listen to the voices of the modern mighty. They speak with a single, perfect heart which, I promise you, gives them an understanding of our times and of what the Church ought to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel.p35" pid="o3er4OZ6sEadBj6cy_bCcA" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1993/10/the-modern-mighty-of-israel</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1993-general-conference/1993-10-4030-elder-monte-j-brough-64k-eng.mp3" length="5967196" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 1993 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Search for Identity</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Have you ever had the experience, as you left your home for a youth activity, to hear your mother say, “Now, Son, remember who you are”? Did you wonder each time, Why does she always say that? And, by the way, who am I?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95905_000_020" doc-version="2" hash="Q--nsQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="YfTL14qggkCSepGDxkPU3Q" hash="OAFHbQ">Search for Identity</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="c0hxHWRZ_0ySKQtop0JPyw" hash="2ho-tA">Monte J. Brough</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e46.jpg" alt="Elder Monte J. Brough" pid="PTA1L5vPD0u51yokbBj6Ow" hash="TcY8Qw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p1" pid="s919Or5ZYEil8wqk150mFw" hash="RAP11w">Have you ever had the experience, as you left your home for a youth activity, to hear your mother say, “Now, Son, remember who you are”? Did you wonder each time, Why does she always say that? And, by the way, who am I?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p2" pid="UMpj8_v7n06-7d3WRCU3xg" hash="1wmLjQ">Others have also asked this very important question:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p3" pid="4-_8ZC6bY0eHHTEssvC-rg" hash="_ih89w">“Moses said unto God, Who am I?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p4" pid="KelErAm1BkaZVbJU44MpOw" hash="nJG3yg">“Then went king David in, and sat before the Lord, and he said, Who am I, O Lord God?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p5" pid="q65IkJYB7kWBQviXPK_9OA" hash="-sO7Ow">Among the magnificent and abundant teachings of President Howard W. Hunter is this assertion, “The greatest search of our time is the search for personal identity and for human dignity.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> This search for personal identity is essentially a search for role models that can become instructive in the conduct of our lifestyles. With only a few exceptions, a young person cannot find adequate role models among those in athletics, entertainment, or commercial music. Not only do these public figures fail to provide positive examples, but they are often the exact inverse of the type of role models that are acceptable to most of us. Access to these contemporary icons is expensive and unproductive. We are almost always disappointed when we come to witness the shallow and murky standards by which the public heaps its praise. No wonder the public areas of so many cities and towns are crowded with young people who are possessed with these same shallow and murky standards of personal behavior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p6" pid="AdN1o81AwEef4YH3hqxdXQ" hash="_Jj0lQ">Yet there is an abundance of role models who can be found much closer and who can have much deeper influence upon each one of us. Most of us, with relatively little effort and much less cost, can provide for our families a veritable list of important role models. This list can be created from a modest search into the lives of our ancestors. Let me give you a few examples:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p7" pid="QMddF62yKU-Pw27HbvbV4g" hash="MmSGJg">A few years ago, as a birthday gift, I went to the FamilySearch® system and retrieved my wife’s entire recorded family pedigree. That was a serious mistake. The computer revealed that my wife is a descendant of European royalty. It has been hard to live with her ever since. Maybe now, through this knowledge of her family history, I am more inclined to treat her as our family queen. But the biggest problem, of course, is that my children share in this royal ancestry, which, sadly, makes me the only “commoner” in my family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p8" pid="4JooFtWgd0OaNlVHY0b7tQ" hash="-2Ntdw">Manasseh Byrd Kearl, born in 1870 and raised near Bear Lake in northern Utah, tells a wonderful story that might be instructional to his descendants, of which I am one. Let me read from his journal:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p9" pid="BWFAzsL7D0-WcDbJwVlcyw" hash="LjqGQg">“That fall father bought some cattle for John Dikens, a very large herd. Dikens had a large ranch on Bear River. … I remember Jimmie was down north buying cattle and he sent father that he needed more money. So father toled me to take some money to him. Mother sewed six hundred dollars in my under clothes, and father put me on a horse and said, ‘Now Byrdie my boy, don’t you get off this horse till you find your brother Jimmie, and keep your mouth shut, and if any one asks you questions don’t reply or tell them where you are going, and do not give this money to any one but Jimmie, no matter what any one tells you.’ Well, when I got to DingleDell, I was toled Jimmie was in Montpelier. So to Montpelier I went to Joe Richs, a friend of father’s, he toled me that Jimmie had gone home. Brother Rich wanted me to go in the house and get something to eat. I toled him no, that father toled me not to get off this horse till I found Jim, and here I stayed. I turned around and headed for home. When I got to Bears Valley, … I could hardly walk. Mr. Potter tried to get me to stop and rest, but I could not stay. At last I got home. Jimmie took me off the horse and carried me into the house. Mother cried to think I had been in the saddle while the horse went over eighty miles.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p10" pid="PWNrRzAo4EexfCO-1yjeUg" hash="hEx0LQ">Let us consider also the eloquent language of Gustave Henriod:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p11" pid="cX8LqwSpgEaIDzDzgeKZXw" hash="WKwEUw">“You, my kind reader, will never know the sports and vicissitudes, joys and fears, gladness and disappointment, grief and delight, cravings and satisfactions, hope and despair, anxiety and contentment, pains and pleasures, all of which are familiar associates, or rather were in the year 1853 between Omaha and Salt Lake City. Yoking up half wild oxen every morning, staking down the tent every night, picking up buffalo chips to cook the food, loading and unloading boxes and bedding mornings and evenings, in the saddle or on foot guarding the stock every night and driving loose cattle in the day, digging trenches around the tents to keep from being drowned by the torrents, singing the songs of Zion, mending a broken wagon, … washing your clothes—everybody forgot a clothes line.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p12" pid="JI523sBDrES8YH3YdCEGWw" hash="X7jydg">Another important quality to emulate is humor in the face of challenge. Hannah Cornaby, another member of the 1853 migration, wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p13" pid="nqYBNACneE63zgTvxGWDiw" hash="BApHNA">“It was three years, to a day, from that memorable first of June … , when our oxen having arrived, we left Keokuk. I wish I could afford a page to a description of our starting. The oxen were wild, and getting them yoked was the most laughable sight I had ever witnessed; everybody giving orders, and nobody knowing how to carry them out. If the men had not been saints, there would doubtless have been much profane language used; but the oxen, not understanding ‘English,’ did just as well without it. But it did seem so truly comical to witness the bewildered look of some innocent brother, who, after having labored an hour or more to get [an ox] secured to one end of the yoke, would hold the other end aloft, trying to persuade [the other ox] to come under, only to see [the first] careering across the country, the yoke lashing the air, and he not even giving a hint as to when he intended to stop.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p14" pid="swqCetD-h0qLpB7kaSAwPA" hash="REhW6w">Of course, there were political and social conflicts in the lives of some of our ancestors, but even these become instructional in the ways they dealt with their circumstances. John Davies was a loyalist during the American Revolutionary War. He had been instrumental in the establishment of the Church of England in America, which became known as the First Episcopal Society of Litchfield. These early immigrants had been taught that next to religion, loyalty was the cardinal virtue. They honestly considered that none but the infidel and traitor would venture to speak of revolution from the motherland. Some argued that any attempt to independence was rank ingratitude. They considered the king to be the head not only of their state but also of their religion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p15" pid="oxlhv72lX0O8X6j3qMs8NQ" hash="de5MIA">John Davies recounts the challenge of building their first church in Litchfield, Connecticut, only to have it seriously damaged by soldiers of the Revolution. His cattle were run off by revolutionists and much of his property severely damaged because of significant persecution of those who had remained loyal to the king. Listen to this about John Davies:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p16" pid="s8sud23BKE2GhMtFjoBX1Q" hash="pUmN1w">“After the close of the war a man who had taken an active part in driving off a number of cattle from his farm, and had committed other acts of plunder, having become destitute, applied for relief in his extremity to Mr. Davies, who not only pardoned him for the wrongs he had done, but liberally relieved his wants.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p17" pid="6h3PkWyNF0qBEVZHCE9i9w" hash="YUWrXQ">Tamma Miner’s first husband, Albert, died in January of 1848 when their youngest child was not yet two years old and their oldest only fifteen years of age. Tamma’s father, Edmond, was murdered by a mob at Nauvoo, Illinois, when Tamma was thirty-two and expecting her ninth child. Their daughter, Melissa, died during the persecution era at seven months; their son, Orson, died of a fever at seventeen; and another daughter, Sylvia, died at age two. Tamma, with her five remaining boys and two girls, started the journey to Salt Lake City across the Plains on June 10, 1850. Tamma’s writings include this wonderful declaration:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p18" pid="euR4dDZiYEmZ_hAEd0cksw" hash="-_VU1g">“I have passed through all the hardships and drivings and burnings and mobbings and threatenings and have been with the Saints in all their persecutions from Huron county to Kirtland and from Kirtland to Missouri back to Illinois and then across the desert. I write this that my children may have a little idea of what their parents passed through. I hope my children will appreciate these lines for I do feel highly honored to be numbered with the Latter-day Saints.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p19" pid="GVrvprMry0WjUInYLqLfZw" hash="SHc5wg">These are a few great examples of role models which are available to all of us as we learn of our own family history.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p20" pid="zGZ5a7aGPEmmIdGN60ehEA" hash="Qp4Kjg">Recently, we met with an executive of a large entertainment corporation. Among her many fine credentials, this corporate leader is of Jewish ethnicity. She obviously enjoyed a tour of our Family History Library and a demonstration of the Church’s commitment to the gathering and preserving of vital records from all over the world. As our meeting ended, she asked me a question, “Why is your church so interested in genealogy?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p21" pid="Wt8fiSsTnESp9I0dr2cfWw" hash="uwpCpw">I responded, “Let me answer you by asking you the same question, why are Jews interested in their genealogy?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p22" pid="ZhI8WGGuyk6Ig1oxulS6Hw" hash="gXLE6g">She answered, a little surprised by my query: “Why? It is of ultimate and profound importance. It is how we obtain and maintain our identity. It is how I know who I am. The history and lives of our ancestors are the glue that holds the entire Jewish community together.” She concluded, “How else would you know who you are?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p23" pid="YFReZdyYMEu0GAbsRX-DpQ" hash="pEakMw">I responded to her, “That is also one of the reasons why our church is interested in genealogy.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p24" pid="NnH823Ge5EeLIo4agMnXgw" hash="XIPWCQ">My brethren of the priesthood, how do we now answer this centuries-old question: Who am I?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p25" pid="_9X3DDthJki1l8F4N3d0rA" hash="mH_12w">First of all, we are sons of God created in His image. We are members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. Our connection and identification with the Church has been maintained by many of our members for more than a century and a half. Without question, the environment of our homes and families is the single greatest influence in our identity as individuals. This was true of our parents’ families and their parents’ families before them. We need not look beyond our own family to find wonderful role models whose high standards are more than adequate in our search for our own personal identity. As Elder Russell M. Nelson taught us this afternoon, we are children of the covenant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p26" pid="xNuGhOpVlkC9ZvSmhIrs6g" hash="sGovHw">For our own families comes this magnificent promise:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p27" pid="ixuhUl48YEKwWWt1HGPyJw" hash="EB2qjg">“Therefore, thus saith the Lord unto you, with whom the priesthood hath continued through the lineage of your fathers—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p28" pid="pV-fjVEFiUaL4iwSSKcpnA" hash="_JUAxA">“For ye are lawful heirs, according to the flesh, and have been hid from the world with Christ in God—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity.p29" pid="u531kK-O1UGzSHzSvNcMXA" hash="xvz1pw">“Therefore your life and the priesthood have remained, and must needs remain through you and your lineage until the restoration of all things spoken by the mouths of all the holy prophets since the world began.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/04/search-for-identity</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1995-general-conference/1995-04-3020-elder-monte-j-brough-64k-eng.mp3" length="5763204" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 1995 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Holy Calling</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Every member must come to know the sacred nature of his or her own service in the Church.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_97905_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="WT89VQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Nmk_fECABUqZhNmJjR98tw" hash="XBEo6A">A Holy Calling</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="xXUvFyRuFUGRfHOjwS6dbw" hash="2ho-tA">Monte J. Brough</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="k0uvaz0WO0Gc7_ckSkWPAw" hash="UK84-w">Every member must come to know the sacred nature of his or her own service in the Church.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e46.jpg" alt="Elder Monte J. Brough" pid="gmcvww2WTUiyWMIrQcBOUA" hash="TcY8Qw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p1" pid="thOuJQBff0SrQxT6xD3-ug" hash="tj-uNQ">A few years ago, I was privileged to be assigned to the Asia Area Presidency, with the area office being in Hong Kong. Our four youngest children accompanied Sister Brough and me to that fascinating city, where we lived for three very interesting years. Our children were accustomed to the wide-open spaces of western America, and Hong Kong required each child to make some very large personal and emotional adjustments. Many nights we sat around our dining room table in our modest 13th-floor apartment, trying to help them with school and cultural challenges.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p2" pid="yf9RarHK6Umr9rKO8IUzCA" hash="HnxMGA">One night, after anxiously working for several hours to complete school assignments, our youngest child, Kami (then eight years old), asked, “Daddy, how come we ‘got choosed’ to come to Hong Kong?” My first reaction was to be somewhat flippant and say, “Just lucky, I guess.” However, I could tell from the very sincere look on this little girl’s face that she wanted a grown-up answer to her question. At that moment, as I surveyed the challenges placed on our little family because of my priesthood calling, I needed to review the answer again for myself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p3" pid="gmoNRYCFTkamKukKoEeM3Q" hash="LU0N2Q">I recalled the day some years earlier when I picked up the telephone to hear the familiar voice of President Spencer W. Kimball, who carefully extended a call to me to serve as a mission president.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p4" pid="wmGnHLCtyEuq8L4f9tMXmQ" hash="f9DonQ">After the telephone call, I was troubled with great feelings of inadequacy. My wife and I were yet in our 30s, with a young family of six children. I remembered the deep love and respect that I felt and still feel for my mission president. Could President Kimball have made a mistake? Did they really understand who I was?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p5" pid="DgvkmDDiEESHWmIZ4pC_-Q" hash="RivoeQ">A few days later, we were granted an appointment with Elder Rex D. Pinegar. We explained to him our feelings. I will always remember Elder Pinegar’s answer: “Brother Brough, have you a testimony as to the divine calling of our prophets and other Church leaders?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p6" pid="Xbzp7N8_00Kt8kYYQbL5dQ" hash="_-CqpQ">“Yes, I do,” I answered. “From my earliest childhood, I have believed in the sacred callings of our Church leaders. From the deepest part of my soul, I believe President Spencer W. Kimball to be a prophet.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p7" pid="yUWkgujFEkSWUY6AfPXM0A" hash="XJekKQ">Elder Pinegar then said, “Now you must gain a testimony as to the divine nature of your own calling. You must come to know that <span class="emphasis">you</span> also have been called of God.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p8" pid="Rjff80nItUCZT7rYc2B3QA" hash="mdiqpA">Paul the Apostle had gained a personal testimony of his own “holy calling” and also that of Timothy. He declared that God “hath saved us, and called us with an holy calling, not according to our works, but according to his own purpose and grace, which was given us in Christ Jesus before the world began” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/1.9" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 1:9</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p9" pid="oxiOYlyRVUSa9uIN3mbOpw" hash="taO6NA">This powerful personal witness would require Timothy to “be [a] partaker of the afflictions of the gospel according to the power of God” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/1.8" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 1:8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p10" pid="A8jZhr0V-U6heV7amJMLHQ" hash="qAq9OQ">As Kami and I read this scripture together, I could see that she very much wanted to understand. I wanted her to know that there can be some “afflictions” associated with our callings in the Church. We talked about being away from our home and family members. I understood it was difficult for her to adjust to these new surroundings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p11" pid="lJRNP5GFgky805qgpqHA_g" hash="UJkv_w">It was obvious, however, that I was <span class="emphasis">still</span> short of my objective when she asked, “But, Daddy, why did <span class="emphasis">we</span> ‘get choosed’ and not someone else?” Now that is a much more difficult question. Why do these callings and responsibilities come to some and not to others? I was reminded of the charge President Hinckley gave me upon my ordination as a Seventy. He said: “Brother Brough, now a lot of people are going to say a lot of nice things about you. Don’t believe them!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p12" pid="o3IJfjfnGEWLGuic06lOKw" hash="9XXk0w">It is very dangerous for any of us to think we have earned the right to a Church calling. However, every member must come to know the sacred nature of his or her own service in the Church. I remember my Primary teacher, Sister Mildred Jacobson, who I believe was divinely called to her position of responsibility. Two bishops, Bishop Lynn McKinnon and Bishop Ross Jackson, who served during my youth, played significant roles in the lives of many. I believe they were called of God in the same process of revelation as were Paul and Timothy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p13" pid="qeOnVPTIX0yoj0lpnRjXNg" hash="N2VAIg">We must each prepare ourselves for every good work that might come to us and then accept the principle that revelation, not aspiration, is the basis for our respective callings. We can learn much from the following New Testament story:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p14" pid="oRgUuM4CWU-rGWhPNLKL2A" hash="34zQ6w">“Then came to him the mother of Zebedee’s children with her sons, worshipping him, and desiring a certain thing of him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p15" pid="7Ky1idQQW0GWaiEWISmDxA" hash="yLVsHA">“… She saith unto him, Grant that these my two sons may sit, the one on thy right hand, and the other on the left, in thy kingdom” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/20.20-21" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 20:20–21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p16" pid="8hfdQkELg0O0uYoaOz8aQg" hash="GzF7eA">I explained to Kami that Zebedee’s children were the Apostles James and John, who would later sit with Peter, one on his right hand and the other on his left. Then we read together how Jesus answered the devoted mother: “To sit on my right hand, and on my left, is not mine to give, but it shall be given to them for whom it is prepared of my Father” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/20.23" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 20:23</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p17" pid="O4XQMEsCBEeZayC8PjA6bg" hash="t_LMsQ">The Apostles also were taught concerning their important calling when Jesus reminded them, “Ye have not chosen me, but I have chosen you, and ordained you” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/15.16" class="scriptureRef">John 15:16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p18" pid="sAWBzEj5v0qQFX02W4jgLg" hash="T3j0vg">I explained to Kami that we definitely had been chosen because we would not seek such a challenging assignment. This was reinforced just a few days later when Sister Brough and I were assigned to travel to India for a missionary conference. The flight from Hong Kong to New Delhi, India, was a late-night flight that arrived in New Delhi at about two o’clock in the morning. Even at that late hour, there were hundreds of taxi drivers who wanted to provide our transportation. After selecting a driver, we began our journey of about 40 kilometers to the hotel. Even though it was late, the roads were crowded with animals, people, and other vehicles. As we were going through an intersection, the taxi’s motor quit. I watched with increasing anxiety as the driver fruitlessly attempted to start the motor. Finally, in obvious frustration, the driver turned to me and in his very best English said, “Push taxi!” It was three o’clock in the morning, and my wife and I were very tired. I got out of the taxi and tried to push it across the intersection but was not able to do so. The driver then said to my wife, “Push taxi.” Lanette got out of the car and began to help me push the taxi through the intersection. As we were struggling to get the taxi through the traffic, I said to my wife, “There were a few things we didn’t understand when we were given this assignment.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p19" pid="R5c406HDTkmF2insFenuyQ" hash="b2oOwg">I shall never forget the experience we had in June of 1993 at a special meeting in Beijing, China, with couples who were then teaching English in North Vietnam and Mongolia. After two days of training and inspiration, we closed with this familiar song:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="0SoD87lJ_Umyrh0yzHWgfA" hash="vu4-Zw">
            <span class="emphasis">It may not be on the mountain height</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="RWSNkQWmR06cI1sBFy-9TA" hash="JPLBHQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Or over the stormy sea,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="RUHdRCHLqU6pGptVX-IePQ" hash="5zOyKA">
            <span class="emphasis">It may not be at the battle’s front</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="5WVxUyIiW0eFpNW_pG6HBg" hash="aY0PyQ">
            <span class="emphasis">My Lord will have need of me.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p20" pid="Q3SxL0PkgkSIdRLxjNSAvQ" hash="MtgZCQ">As we were singing, my wife leaned over and whispered in my ear: “But it might be ‘on the mountain height,’ or it might be ‘over the stormy sea,’ or it might be ‘at the battle’s front.’” The Lord surely had need for these beautiful people serving in this interesting area of the world. These wonderful missionary couples did not choose to come to these countries. Yet as we now look at the results of their service, I know that they were chosen by the Lord for their special calling.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p21" pid="xg5QKFuiYU6trM2CObRaHA" hash="miteew">On four different occasions, Sister Brough and I and our family have excitedly opened the envelope containing the mission call and assignment for one of our children. Each time, we have contemplated with excitement the various possibilities for their service. While preferences were expressed, the moment their eyes saw the words “You are hereby assigned to serve in the [blank] mission,” without exception a wonderful feeling of good and right came over each family member. We each knew that a prophet had guided a divine selection process to which four of our children have gladly responded. Tens of thousands of returned missionaries can also testify of this process and the divine inspiration of their own missionary calling.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p22" pid="11a1-1ofGkaOg9GLhXEwYA" hash="wHi_1g">I never completely satisfied little Kami’s question that night. Over the years, we have recalled that challenging evening when a small child was a bit overwhelmed with life. We have explored other scriptures and many other stories since that time. We have received the wonderful promise to those the Savior had chosen “that whatsoever ye shall ask of the Father in my name, he may give it [to] you” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/15.16" class="scriptureRef">John 15:16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p23" pid="iSBg1WVXR0yuwfhEmooUTQ" hash="JmdG-Q">That promise—of answer to our prayers—is directed even to a small child. This was reaffirmed recently when I heard Kami (now 15 years old) respond to a question directed to her by an adult friend: “How come you were so lucky to live in Hong Kong when you were a child?” She looked directly at me as she gave her answer to our friend: “It wasn’t luck, we ‘were chosen.’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling.p24" pid="G5EWumsUSUy9FLBZY_m51w" hash="c2OYfg">That personal and prophetic revelation is the foundation upon which our Church service is firmly based is my witness, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1997/04/a-holy-calling</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1997-general-conference/1997-04-2050-elder-monte-j-brough-64k-eng.mp3" length="5132625" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 1997 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Young Men—Holders of Keys</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We need young men to stand up in their calling, knowing of their ordained right to act in the office to which they are appointed.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030835_000_017" doc-version="2" hash="6wOBLw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="T1BgelPXu0WJCKGE2yLo9A" hash="cX2BHQ">Young Men—</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="rM0DlyyjpESfcZwbW3CM2g" hash="lzAGnQ">Holders of Keys</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="xFpbZH6rTUydma-dWhLY1w" hash="2ho-tA">Monte J. Brough</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="73mCly8gF06FTNfa_bEBuw" hash="_vHINg">We need young men to stand up in their calling, knowing of their ordained right to act in the office to which they are appointed.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-afd.jpg" alt="Elder Monte J. Brough" pid="Mxyz9RSk7kea47Z87IhjQw" hash="WXpwkw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p1" pid="Bq3YIdMs0E6Mlm55KQ9pVA" hash="QSU4QQ">I hold in my hand a copy of a Sunday School manual titled <span class="emphasis">Leaders of the Scriptures,</span> which was printed in 1947. The authors were Marion G. Merkley and Gordon B. Hinckley. Fifty-six years ago! This manual has been in my home for many years and is part of the motivation for this talk.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p2" pid="Iu2mTA8JBkip1iGbpKKGrA" hash="ExUc0A">One of the most significant events of the Restoration is that of the Aaronic Priesthood in May 1829. John the Baptist appeared to the Prophet Joseph Smith and Oliver Cowdery.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p3" pid="nxQUIYELGUmPhoT0p6NsXg" hash="n1FxoQ">Joseph recounts: “While we were thus employed, praying and calling upon the Lord, a messenger from heaven descended in a cloud of light, and having laid his hands upon us, he ordained us, saying:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p4" pid="dq1Flr1Pr0mqtThYH2cRTQ" hash="DQrqkA">“Upon you my fellow servants, in the name of Messiah, I confer the Priesthood of Aaron, which holds the keys of the ministering of angels, and of the gospel of repentance, and of baptism by immersion for the remission of sins.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p5" pid="JXN59gFTuEOfLyW_YNkJsg" hash="dGKcgA">We have in this priesthood session of general conference tens of thousands of young men who hold the Aaronic Priesthood and who belong to deacons, teachers, and priests quorums all over the world. Each quorum is headed by a quorum presidency, including a president who holds keys to lead the individual priesthood quorum.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p6" pid="8Q2yMoLYJUmImE9FImamGA" hash="5D7p-g">Many of us might consider these youthful leaders to be too young to hold those important, responsible positions. Let us consider a few examples of what youth really can do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p7" pid="ekmvskBfu0yH5SPx5J4lxQ" hash="_yMoMQ">First, the prophet Jeremiah:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p8" pid="P7Qk-vaKpk6FQxFzdb4NWw" hash="xW8Ruw">“Then the word of the Lord came unto me, saying,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p9" pid="hBKc7p-4HkaPv5QI006U_A" hash="e2bRyw">“Before I formed thee in the belly I knew thee; and before thou camest forth out of the womb I sanctified thee, and I ordained thee a prophet unto the nations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p10" pid="-dU-QpaTTUWl8xrL_QqQDg" hash="PLsl6A">“Then said I, Ah, Lord God! behold, I cannot speak: for I am a child.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p11" pid="U-YnMF7z40CjHiBJVZ_DIA" hash="MtCQIQ">“But the Lord said unto me, Say not, I am a child: for thou shalt go to all that I shall send thee, and whatsoever I command thee thou shalt speak. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p12" pid="ueomnHIJfkGgljm3aRRSxA" hash="DASXTw">“Then the Lord put forth his hand, and touched my mouth. And the Lord said unto me, Behold, I have put my words in thy mouth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p13" pid="ilno0ZsFUkyR27CWr_hMtA" hash="TR5aPA">If the Lord desired, couldn’t He also put words in the mouth of a 13-year-old deacons quorum president who “holds the keys of the ministering of angels”?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p14" pid="hL89MZn4D0C9pqHEtZEZdA" hash="DSBdKQ">Another young man, Timothy, was a missionary companion to the Apostle Paul. The epistles from Paul to Timothy are tributes to the faith and testimony of this very young man. Let me read a few extracts from those epistles:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p15" pid="O9QFQvA4BkyFsoDsyirYmw" hash="_q7s3A">“Wherefore … stir up the gift of God, which is in thee by the putting on of my hands. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p16" pid="sMlbhQShKkys-ILaBdaqjQ" hash="TY_NQw">“[Christ] hath saved us, and called us with an holy calling.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p17" pid="LFLDpnd6x0KkvCNCLSzPQQ" hash="rfnNuA">“And that from a child thou hast known the holy scriptures, which are able to make thee wise.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p18" pid="40SwPu4Uh0S017xupd3ldQ" hash="sveUIQ">As with Timothy, wouldn’t a 14-year-old teachers quorum president also be entitled to a “gift of God” when he is set apart by the bishop? Isn’t the calling of teachers quorum president also “an holy calling”? Can a 16-year-old priest be “wise”? The scriptures give us a resounding <span class="emphasis">yes!</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p19" pid="nJkRjL7o0EmU9PPXhEia6g" hash="XsRfNg">One of the greatest examples of a very young man making a contribution of monumental significance is that of Mormon. Let’s read just part of his account:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p20" pid="JZbCi4oMlUaiGzVKwZozTA" hash="A9IOHg">“And now I, Mormon, make a record of the things which I have both seen and heard, and call it the Book of Mormon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p21" pid="iXIDI55XIka-2H6bvInDKg" hash="PMBInA">“And about the time that Ammaron hid up the records unto the Lord, he came unto me, (I being about ten years of age, and I began to be learned somewhat after the manner of the learning of my people) and Ammaron said unto me: I perceive that thou art a sober child, and art quick to observe. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p22" pid="gEjdnkg2S02BkpJsOPNv9Q" hash="3Zpyng">“And behold, [one day] ye shall take the plates of Nephi unto yourself, and the remainder shall ye leave in the place where they are; and ye shall engrave on the plates of Nephi all the things that ye have observed concerning this people.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p23" pid="uWi5-De4t0eHUtbWQ4k7bw" hash="pLlFFg">“… And notwithstanding I being young, was large in stature; therefore the people of Nephi appointed me that I should be their leader, or the leader of their armies.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p24" pid="p7X65pSrTEqJBU2PAIlsBw" hash="whbPTg">“[And so] it came to pass that in my sixteenth year I did go forth at the head of an army of the Nephites.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p25" pid="wGuMIvFXGk6-_rLox-yhAw" hash="J-Tqkw">What a chronology of events in a young life! He began preparing for his prophetic calling at age 10, receiving knowledge of the ancient sacred records. By appointment of the people of Nephi, he became the head of the Nephite armies at age 16.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p26" pid="j_oRA3LO3kugcAYhCwvG3A" hash="RFA-RA">In June of the year I was 12 years old, I was injured in a horse accident while delivering newspapers in my old hometown of Randolph, Utah. I was placed in a wheelchair for six months, until I first walked on Christmas Day. I remember the members of my deacons quorum presidency coming to my home to visit me—Dale Rex, Doug McKinnon, and others who were 13-year-old leaders in the deacons quorum presidency. They seemed to understand their responsibility to me as a member of their quorum.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p27" pid="0bHzMinjz06k0G3UPrrbjg" hash="1-YpPA">I recently was standing at the luggage retrieval at the Salt Lake City International Airport when a woman came to me and asked my name. I recognized her as a former South Rich High School classmate from years ago. She had changed since I had last seen her. You all know how you feel at the old dreaded high school reunion. She had added some gray hair and a few wrinkles. (Of course, I hadn’t changed.) It was obvious that she was meeting her missionary child, who was returning from a mission. It surprised me. While she was yet in school, her family, who were not members of the Church, had moved into our small community. Her name was Alice Gomez. She was about the same age as me and my friends. I remembered that she was friendly and always polite but that she never did attend any of our Church meetings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p28" pid="VQyYNIwQkEKjsKZKl7fhLA" hash="3kGLuA">I said to her, “Alice, tell me your story. You are obviously now an active member of the Church, but you never joined while we were going to school.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p29" pid="3giogKIVa0eqGkssyARcAw" hash="WtUe9g">Her answer was condemning: “No one ever asked me!” Wow! Our quorum really dropped the ball on that one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p30" pid="pxx5KMQeeUqMw72RslliSg" hash="7SIv0w">Recently reported to me was the story of a young priests quorum in Jamaica who decided they would help the missionaries with their work. So this quorum of young men went knocking on doors, trying to find appointments for the missionaries. They soon found more referrals than the missionaries could handle.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p31" pid="uGGkNW5WWE-i4k5BwixBzw" hash="0NaSOw">A priests quorum in Kaysville, Utah, decided they would not lose one member of their quorum. The whole quorum would go to a less-active member’s home and have their Sunday lesson sitting around the less-active boy’s bed. Soon that young man joined his quorum in taking the Sunday lesson to another home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p32" pid="ZoE0R2vl7EGRbaw0t1FUqA" hash="KaGVTw">As of the year 2003, there are more than 26,000 wards and branches in the Church, with approximately 78,000 deacons, teachers, and priests quorums. Talk about an army!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p33" pid="1ubR3I6DQUm5m9s-WkQDhA" hash="-VymTg">The contribution the quorums of the Aaronic Priesthood could make to the work of converting, retaining, and activating other members of their quorums is enormous.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p34" pid="jUnLIKlHdkuu3Lv5u_cuWg" hash="L8IOgQ">If 16-year-old Mormon could be the commanding officer of a large military army, and if Jeremiah as a child could have words put in his mouth by the Almighty God, and if Timothy could be wise as he was, then each young man within the sound of my voice can rise to the challenge of his quorum responsibilities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p35" pid="65greUDlMkSiHtyhgdIQ4Q" hash="IDKysw">The responsibilities of the Aaronic Priesthood quorums are no less important than the responsibilities of elders quorums or high priests groups. Remember, they hold “the keys of the ministering of angels.” We need young men to stand up in their calling, knowing of their ordained right to act in the office to which they are appointed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys.p36" pid="kRqDKqtS-EaAhuNA5lvVSg" hash="NISEFQ">I testify that these Aaronic Priesthood quorums hold the holy priesthood of God. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2003/10/young-men-holders-of-keys</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2003-general-conference/2003-10-3020-elder-monte-j-brough-64k-eng.mp3" length="4322104" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2003 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
