<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Neill F. Marriott</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Neill F. Marriott.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Neill%20F.%20Marriott.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Neill F. Marriott.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Sharing Your Light</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10991_000_63marriott" doc-version="8" hash="t74gIQ"&gt;
			
			&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.head1"&gt;
				&lt;h1 class="title" pid="IKmR0j7Wl0a8EfSamKUvLw" hash="RhAxTw"&gt;Sharing Your Light&lt;/h1&gt;
				&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p2" pid="V3E1qCNzV0yyTrAA1pDzXQ" hash="Yt3GwQ"&gt;By Neill F. Marriott&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p3" pid="VhsPDzMDhk2FkFjNT9ut8g" hash="KrcvzQ"&gt;Second Counselor in the Young Women General Presidency&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=HAKXDzkSukyBw9VDP_rsvQ"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x278="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/200x278.jpg" data-src-320x445="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/320x445.jpg" data-src-460x640="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/460x640.jpg" data-src-640x891="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/640x891.jpg" data-src-1024x1426="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/1024x1426.jpg" data-src-2048x2853="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/2048x2853.jpg" data-src-3504x4882="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/3504x4882.jpg" altText="Neill F. Marriott" pid="HAKXDzkSukyBw9VDP_rsvQ" hash="AFyOEw"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;p class="kicker" pid="BPF3Pwy6FEC3AS5ivsL6og" hash="R-vPMA"&gt;We must stand firm in our faith and lift our voices to proclaim true doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="authorName" pid="sId7sVB2RE22kGL2bp23iA" hash="Yt3GwQ1"&gt;By Neill F. Marriott&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;div class="bodyBlock" pid="LqkraAmwv0accTDJPm_4hA" hash="hGVoLw"&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p5" pid="WGX5HOx240mY20Kra57WIg" hash="kXHGuA"&gt;Tonight I would like to consider two important responsibilities we carry: first, consistently adding gospel light and truth to our lives, and second, sharing that light and truth with others.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p6" pid="_BtRh9t47EGeCCJQczzTVw" hash="EDVInA"&gt;Do you know how important you are? Every one of you—right now—is valuable and essential in Heavenly Father’s plan of salvation. We have a work to do. We know the truth of the restored gospel. Are we ready to defend that truth? We need to live it; we need to share it. We must stand firm in our faith and lift our voices to proclaim true doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p7" pid="pOP9eYI2kEKn2O3AO6cCmQ" hash="OMQg5A"&gt;In the September 2014 &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;Ensign&lt;/span&gt; and&lt;span class="emphasis"&gt; Liahona,&lt;/span&gt; Elder M. Russell Ballard writes: “We need more of the distinctive, influential voices and faith of women. We need them to learn the doctrine and to understand what we believe so that they can bear their testimonies about the truth of all things.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p8" pid="Znwhafzyf0649TTvWXR0MQ" hash="HUmZfA"&gt;Sisters, you strengthen my faith in Jesus Christ. I have watched your examples, heard your testimonies, and felt of your faith from Brazil to Botswana! You carry a circle of influence with you wherever you go. It is felt by the people around you—from your family to the contacts in your cell phone and from your friends on social media to those seated next to you tonight. I agree with Sister Harriet Uchtdorf, who wrote, “You … are vibrant and enthusiastic beacons in an ever-darkening world as you show, through the way you live your lives, that the gospel is a joyful message.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p9" pid="RArR3B04A0OODspc1dGIVw" hash="7NdH5Q"&gt;President Thomas S. Monson pointed out, “If you want to give a light to others, you have to glow yourself.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; How can we keep that light of truth glowing within us? Sometimes I feel like a dim lightbulb. How do we grow brighter?&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p10" pid="dogAko-ZXEW-vPgu6mNkbg" hash="1Qp1-g"&gt;The scriptures teach, “That which is of God is light; and he that receiveth light, and continueth in God, receiveth more light.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; We must continue in God, as the scripture says. We must go to the source of light—to Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ and the scriptures. We can also go to the temple, knowing that all things within its walls point to Christ and His great atoning sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p11" pid="4eOlqYBRqE6SnsrSyfe7CA" hash="2ecgHA"&gt;Think of the effect temples have on their surroundings. They beautify inner cities; they shine from prominent hills. Why do they beautify and shine? Because, as the scriptures say, “Truth shineth,”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; and temples contain truth and eternal purpose; so do you.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p12" pid="-dxDANSh8EmV3PTI3ZOVBw" hash="bJklgQ"&gt;In 1877, President George Q. Cannon said, “Every Temple … lessens the power of Satan on the earth.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; I believe that wherever a temple is built on the earth, it pushes back the darkness. The temple’s purpose is to serve mankind and give all of Heavenly Father’s children the ability to return and live with Him. Isn’t our purpose similar to these dedicated buildings, these houses of the Lord? To serve others and help them push back the darkness and return to Heavenly Father’s light?&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p13" pid="Inu8dKKJdEqAv4t5Qpvw8Q" hash="UU80Fw"&gt;Sacred temple work will increase our faith in Christ, and then we can better influence the faith of others. By the nourishing spirit of the temple, we can learn the reality, the power, and the hope of the Savior’s Atonement in our personal life.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;span class="story"&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p14" pid="9dX-kgtY-kejr5cspNLS0w" hash="RPxw3w"&gt;Some years ago our family encountered a major challenge. I went to the temple and there prayed earnestly for help. I was given a moment of truth. I received a clear impression of my weaknesses, and I was shocked. In that spiritually instructive moment, I saw a prideful woman doing things her own way, not necessarily the Lord’s way, and privately taking credit for any so-called accomplishment. I knew I was looking at myself. I cried out in my heart to Heavenly Father and said, “I don’t want to be that woman, but how do I change?”&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p15" pid="RwPqKKo3m0epZY4KsIjQdA" hash="oC92Zg"&gt;Through the pure spirit of revelation in the temple, I was taught of my utter need for a Redeemer. I turned immediately to the Savior Jesus Christ in my thoughts and felt my anguish melt away and a great hope spring up in my heart. He was my only hope, and I longed to cling only to Him. It was clear to me that a self-absorbed natural woman “is an enemy to God”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt; and to people in her sphere of influence. In the temple that day I learned it was only through the Atonement of Jesus Christ that my prideful nature could change and that I would be enabled to do good. I felt His love keenly, and I knew He would teach me by the Spirit and change me if I gave my heart to Him, holding back nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p16" pid="FO2lYO8Db0qA81mHkJNo2w" hash="Lmfq7g"&gt;I still fight my weaknesses, but I trust in the divine help of the Atonement. This pure instruction came because I entered the holy temple, seeking relief and answers. I entered the temple burdened, and I left knowing I had an all-powerful and all-loving Savior. I was lighter and joyful because I had received His light and accepted His plan for me.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p17" pid="_1zvPCz_gUygdeDmzF9SYA" hash="Ix2EYg"&gt;Placed around the world, temples have their own unique look and design on the outside, but inside they all contain the same eternal light, purpose, and truth. In 1 Corinthians 3:16 we read, “Know ye not that ye are the temple of God, and that the Spirit of God dwelleth in you?” We too as daughters of God have been placed all around the world, like temples, and we each have our own unique look and outward design, like temples. We also have a spiritual light within us, like temples. This spiritual light is a reflection of the Savior’s light. Others will be attracted to this brightness.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p18" pid="RAepyGDc3k6oHuhe6-hGoQ" hash="3LvCsw"&gt;We have our own roles on the earth—from daughter, mother, leader, and teacher to sister, wage earner, wife, and more. Each is influential. Each role will have moral power as we reflect gospel truths and temple covenants in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p19" pid="MnGjy4cJn0OcFuleRn-54g" hash="NiRVHQ"&gt;Elder D. Todd Christofferson said, “In all events, a mother can exert an influence unequaled by any other person in any other relationship.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8"&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p20" pid="eauOQL7mfkmi2-cqxEBwFw" hash="rhmnrw"&gt;When our children were young, I felt like the cocaptain, with my husband, David, of a ship, and I pictured our 11 children as a flotilla of little boats bobbing around us in the harbor, preparing to set forth on the sea of the world. David and I felt a need to consult the compass of the Lord daily for the best direction to sail with our small fleet.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p21" pid="BeVdD1rjBEaefk_dWwheQQ" hash="jqOY4g"&gt;My days were full of forgettable things like folding laundry, reading children’s books, and putting casseroles together for dinner. Sometimes in the harbor of our homes, we can’t see that by the simple, consistent acts—including family prayer, scripture study, and family home evening—great things are brought to pass. But I testify that these very acts carry eternal significance. Great joy comes when those little boats—our children—grow into mighty seafaring vessels filled with gospel light and ready to “embark in the service of God.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9"&gt;9&lt;/span&gt; Our small acts of faith and service are how most of us can continue in God and eventually bring eternal light and glory to our family, our friends, and our associates. You truly carry a circle of influence with you!&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;span class="story"&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p22" pid="UCXJzeP_006HVm1XyboeLA" hash="05DzbQ"&gt;Think of the influence that the faith of a Primary-aged girl can have on her family. Our daughter’s faith blessed our family when we lost our young son at an amusement park. The family rushed around frantically looking for him. Finally, our 10-year-old daughter tugged on my arm and said, “Mom, shouldn’t we pray?” She was right! The family gathered in the middle of a crowd of onlookers and prayed to find our child. We found him. To all the Primary girls I say, “Please keep reminding your parents to pray!”&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;span class="story"&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p23" pid="onvBrvPdd0mgsH_w6Ybk7w" hash="LCrplA"&gt;This summer I had the privilege of attending an encampment of 900 young women in Alaska. Their influence on me was profound. They came to the camp spiritually prepared, having read the Book of Mormon and having memorized “The Living Christ: The Testimony of the Apostles.” On the third night of camp, all 900 young women stood together and recited the entire document word for word.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p24" pid="XggK7e2K5E6ZvRI_ta-Vcg" hash="NdHumg"&gt;The Spirit filled the vast hall, and I yearned to join in. But I couldn’t. I hadn’t paid the price of memorization.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p25" pid="7DQvDnV1c0a_WHZ-e_eJnA" hash="kWa2WA"&gt;I have now begun to learn the words of “The Living Christ” as these sisters did, and because of their influence I am more fully experiencing the sacramental covenant to always remember the Savior as I repeat over and over the Apostles’ testimony of Christ. The sacrament is taking on a deeper meaning for me.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p26" pid="wHhnZTNZjUu_n0g8wPrVfQ" hash="mFvuOQ"&gt;My hope is to offer the Savior a Christmas gift this year of having “The Living Christ” memorized and securely held in my heart by December 25th. I hope I can be an influence for good—as the sisters of Alaska were for me.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/span&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p27" pid="KPBYVSBm102lQhxUZtWuJQ" hash="fwrXBw"&gt;Can you find yourself in the following words of this document, “The Living Christ”? “He entreated all to follow His example. He walked the roads of Palestine, healing the sick, causing the blind to see, and raising the dead.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p28" pid="fyBau7hMPUuoL4_zDELJdA" hash="5LTw7Q"&gt;We, sisters of the Church, do not walk the roads of Palestine healing the sick, but we can pray for and apply the healing love of the Atonement to a sickened, strained relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p29" pid="gv4__WDgyUmEtcAcTgd7WQ" hash="o_P9tg"&gt;Though we will not cause the blind to see in the manner of the Savior, we can testify of the plan of salvation to the spiritually blind. We can open the eyes of their understanding to the necessity of priesthood power in eternal covenants.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p30" pid="TJxq8Gn21kCgmFFEpGNlmw" hash="3naoUQ"&gt;We will not be raising the dead as did the Savior, but we can bless the dead by finding their names for temple work. Then we will indeed raise them from their spirit prison and offer them the path of eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light.p31" pid="XbjijpKw_EOtxTIOET0ukQ" hash="0aVjNA"&gt;I testify we have a living Savior, Jesus Christ, and with His power and light we will be enabled to push back the darkness of the world, give voice to the truth we know, and influence others to come unto Him. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
			
		&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/10/sharing-your-light</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-session/september-2014-general-womens-session/2014-09-0040-neill-f-marriott-64k-eng.mp3" length="5916842" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yielding Our Hearts to God</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sister Marriott teaches that we can make the Lord's way our way when we are humble and open to His Spirit.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13768_000_24marriott" doc-version="4" hash="iVaTXA">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="YtZtk8QbR06VnDVkUE-Eog" hash="qhqtwQ">Yielding Our Hearts to God</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p2" pid="uENj4pFFREG2h5WgOZNOAg" hash="Yt3GwQ">By Neill F. Marriott</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p3" pid="jh16qm98IEe5880MzwdPoQ" hash="KrcvzQ">Second Counselor in the Young Women General Presidency</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=oryxnfX6U0muAM0xTaW_3Q"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" alt="Neill F. Marriott" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x278="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/200x278.jpg" data-src-320x445="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/320x445.jpg" data-src-460x640="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/460x640.jpg" data-src-640x891="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/640x891.jpg" data-src-1024x1426="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/1024x1426.jpg" data-src-2048x2853="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/2048x2853.jpg" data-src-3504x4882="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/3504x4882.jpg" pid="oryxnfX6U0muAM0xTaW_3Q" hash="AFyOEw"></img></a></div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="qzhNlJYhA0OgA-8vyT2MsA" hash="wnuPRA">When we open ourselves to the Spirit, we learn God’s way and feel His will.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="gVhQ0Nr1s0GwCrI_LUrRPQ" hash="EXRH1Q">Neill F. Marriott</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p5" pid="kbVHWYaRcEGC65ls8WsY4w" hash="yY6QOg">Elder Dallin H. Oaks, in April general conference, spoke of the need “to reform our personal lives.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> I submit that personal reformation begins with a change of heart—no matter your life experiences or your place of birth.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p6" pid="IqMUg4qbnk-V8ifl36pgwg" hash="jm9Skg">I come from the Deep South of the United States, and in my youth the words of old Protestant hymns taught me of a true disciple’s heart—one that has been changed. Consider these lyrics, so dear to me:</p>
		<div class="poetry">
			<div class="stanza">
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p7" pid="Ib86T_kQyU-GSrrdF2Rk3w" hash="I-27Mg">Have Thine own way, Lord!</p>
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p8" pid="an10PcGLRUyRUYg9Q0l3Yg" hash="LR6Jjw">Have Thine own way!</p>
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p9" pid="bNGzMV1O_ESeKKSfNN-EyA" hash="OpJ5Yw">Thou art the Potter;</p>
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p10" pid="AL9XcsWkT0KfRKFU1i7zDg" hash="C9lZYw">I am the clay.</p>
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p11" pid="lRPdNjq1l0iPLFzHOQkSVw" hash="9GuBYg">Mould me and make me</p>
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p12" pid="wl5kTtVDdke467hYaDpddQ" hash="eSqRRQ">After Thy will,</p>
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p13" pid="QRc8G2ES1ka23HtmMTffLw" hash="mlKi1Q">While I am waiting,</p>
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p14" pid="tUuryL2XV0Cx8KOobogVZA" hash="-ZKBYA">Yielded and still.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
			</div>
		</div>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p15" pid="Ch5cQFZ-YUmckX5bK6VZBA" hash="mk68CA">How do we, a modern, busy, competitive people, become yielded and still? How do we make the Lord’s ways our ways? I believe we begin by learning of Him and praying for understanding. As our trust in Him grows, we open our hearts, seek to do His will, and wait for answers that will help us understand.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p16" pid="4oS9C-GWR0a-GyDfqgEURA" hash="gCY7Fg">My own change of heart started when, as a 12-year-old, I began to search for God. Other than saying the Lord’s Prayer,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> I didn’t really know how to pray. I remember kneeling, hoping I could feel His love, and asking, “Where are You, Heavenly Father? I know You must be out there somewhere, but where?” All through my teen years, I asked. I did have glimpses of the reality of Jesus Christ, but Heavenly Father, in His wisdom, let me seek and wait for 10 years.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p17" pid="YESVz3UpuUSbXYk1fuSXDg" hash="IkVrrA">In 1970, when the missionaries taught me about the Father’s plan of salvation and of the Savior’s Atonement, my waiting ended. I embraced these truths and was baptized.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p18" pid="fsSgU3AEzU-S3ONA4HxFUw" hash="ASPbEA">Based on this knowledge of the Lord’s mercy and power, my husband, children, and I chose this family motto: “It will all work out.” Yet how can we say those words to one another when deep troubles come and answers aren’t readily available?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p19" pid="g62960_Y8EC6s0Q1qP_-lg" hash="FQzvEQ">When our delightful, worthy, 21-year-old daughter, Georgia, was hospitalized in critical condition following a bike accident, our family said, “It will all work out.” As I flew immediately from our mission in Brazil to Indianapolis, Indiana, USA, to be with her, I clung to our family motto. However, our lovely daughter passed into the spirit world just hours before my plane landed. With grief and shock running through our family like a current, how could we look at one another and <span class="emphasis">still</span> say, “It will all work out”?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p20" pid="hzkIEH_vXU2fNIKxsl_-7Q" hash="rexjIw">Following Georgia’s mortal death, our feelings were raw, we struggled, and still today we have moments of great sorrow, but we hold to the understanding that no one ever really dies. Despite our anguish when Georgia’s physical body stopped functioning, we had faith that she went right on living as a spirit, and we believe we will live with her eternally if we adhere to our temple covenants. Faith in our Redeemer and His Resurrection, faith in His priesthood power, and faith in eternal sealings let us state our motto with conviction.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p21" pid="sx_P3RWleEWeApNMMYCfog" hash="qAw2Aw">President Gordon B. Hinckley said: “If you do your best, it will all work out. Put your trust in God. … The Lord will not forsake us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p22" pid="rCA9569hDkiNw5eMLrWgDw" hash="kEdtbw">Our family motto doesn’t say, “It will all work out <span class="emphasis">now</span>.” It speaks of our hope in the eternal outcome—not necessarily of present results. Scripture says, “Search diligently, pray always, and be believing, and all things shall work together for your good.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> This doesn’t mean all things <span class="emphasis">are</span> good, but for the meek and faithful, things—both positive and negative—work <span class="emphasis">together</span> for good, and the timing is the Lord’s. We wait on Him, sometimes like Job in his suffering, knowing that God “maketh sore, and bindeth up: he woundeth, and his hands make whole.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> A meek heart accepts the trial and the waiting for that time of healing and wholeness to come.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p23" pid="w4d7FVgvokyZBRoTQLFFGQ" hash="XavZLg">When we open ourselves to the Spirit, we learn God’s way and feel His will. During the sacrament, which I call the heart of the Sabbath, I have found that after I pray for forgiveness of sins, it is instructive for me to ask Heavenly Father, “Father, is there more?” When we are yielded and still, our minds can be directed to <span class="emphasis">something more</span> we may need to change—something that is limiting our capacity to receive spiritual guidance or even healing and help.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p24" pid="ARav8rKZIEOjlKwgLdGrMg" hash="yO6vxA">For example, perhaps I have a carefully guarded resentment toward someone. When I ask if there is more to confess, that “secret” comes clearly to my memory. In essence, the Holy Ghost is whispering, “You honestly asked if there was more, and here it is. Your resentment diminishes your progress and damages your ability to have healthy relationships. You can let this go.” Oh, it is hard work—we may feel quite justified in our animosity—but yielding to the Lord’s way is the only way to lasting happiness.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p25" pid="1ogweKIvZEqeuFbdn_2tMA" hash="EBZqwQ">In time and by degrees, we receive His gracious strength and direction—perhaps leading us to frequent the temple or to study more deeply the Savior’s Atonement or to consult with a friend, a bishop, a professional counselor, or even a doctor. The healing of our heart begins when we submit to and worship God.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p26" pid="Jx5VT7xlskG9JYegSwYmrg" hash="Dy0aVQ">True worship begins when our hearts are right before the Father and the Son. What is our heart condition today? Paradoxically, in order to have a healed and faithful heart, we must first allow it to break before the Lord. “Ye shall offer for a sacrifice unto me a broken heart and a contrite spirit,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> the Lord declares. The result of sacrificing our heart, or our will, to the Lord is that we receive the spiritual guidance we need.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p27" pid="MgoajJmXzEKoO-y9Aa5ygw" hash="7RJtZA">With a growing understanding of the Lord’s grace and mercy, we will find that our self-willed hearts begin to crack and break in gratitude. Then we reach for Him, yearning to yoke ourselves to the Only Begotten Son of God. In our brokenhearted reaching and yoking, we receive new hope and fresh guidance through the Holy Ghost.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p28" pid="rD9rfwtehEOprt5DdwnAzg" hash="woVPQg">I have struggled to banish the mortal desire to have things <span class="emphasis">my</span> way, eventually realizing that my way is oh so lacking, limited, and inferior to the way of Jesus Christ. “<span class="emphasis">His</span> way is the path that leads to happiness in this life and eternal life in the world to come.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Can we love Jesus Christ and His way more than we love ourselves and our own agenda?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p29" pid="0kQGh_cSTUiFRuoWZG2Abg" hash="3MeU0Q">Some may think they have failed too many times and feel too weak to change sinful acts or worldly desires of the heart. However, as covenant Israel, we don’t just try and try on our own to change. If we earnestly appeal to God, He takes us as we are—and makes us more than we ever imagined. Noted theologian Robert L. Millet writes of “a healthy longing to improve,” balanced with the spiritual “assurance that in and through Jesus Christ we are going to make it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> With such an understanding, we can honestly say to Heavenly Father:</p>
		<div class="poetry">
			<div class="stanza">
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p30" pid="sbpEtNXkvUyfNfXu6Qc6Pw" hash="1AbcmQ">So trusting my all to thy tender care,</p>
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p31" pid="Tkg2ih0PIUiAQS8QbfJqYw" hash="SO-oRg">And knowing thou lovest me,</p>
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p32" pid="8LGdwg-et02HMYPX6sjHvg" hash="85CVMQ">I’ll do thy will with a heart sincere:</p>
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p33" pid="A_CcXU7U5E6bKE9ggX6fdg" hash="CgKTnQ">I’ll be what you want me to be.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
			</div>
		</div>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god.p34" pid="V7W35K09GUKwSi3l9yGuDw" hash="Yeai6A">When we offer our broken heart to Jesus Christ, He accepts our offering. He takes us back. No matter what losses, wounds, and rejection we have suffered, His grace and healing are mightier than all. Truly yoked to the Savior, we can say with confidence, “It will all work out.” In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/10/yielding-our-hearts-to-god</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2015-general-conference/2015-10-1040-neill-f-marriott-64k-eng.mp3" length="4620113" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Shall We Do?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13285_000_12marriott" doc-version="2" hash="J2WquQ"&gt;
	
	&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.head1"&gt;
		&lt;h1 class="title" pid="9hf09ZaRnEqQzIr05uOuGg" hash="GeIplA"&gt;What Shall We Do?&lt;/h1&gt;
		&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p2" pid="PXRsKEqnvEGwDZ1KOPbIPQ" hash="Yt3GwQ1"&gt;By Neill F. Marriott&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p3" pid="NGEDzFSHx0ygJyliYuzWxg" hash="KrcvzQ"&gt;Second Counselor in the Young Women General Presidency&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=_dSxhvJUoUyn8e9OMdjr4Q"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" altText="Neill F. Marriott" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x278="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/200x278.jpg" data-src-320x445="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/320x445.jpg" data-src-460x640="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/460x640.jpg" data-src-640x891="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/640x891.jpg" data-src-1024x1426="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/1024x1426.jpg" data-src-2048x2853="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/2048x2853.jpg" data-src-3504x4882="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255549/073840702ed040d4b0e52e435b94f623/3504x4882.jpg" webURL="neill-marriott-second-counselor-young-women_1255549.jpg" pid="_dSxhvJUoUyn8e9OMdjr4Q" hash="AAAAAA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="kicker" pid="IDByhOWXxUGcXfW4OleLgg" hash="Z7HMhQ"&gt;We build the kingdom when we nurture others. We also build the kingdom when we speak up and testify of truth.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="authorName" pid="ciP2NKFkCUCRHyxAQtXVaA" hash="Yt3GwQ"&gt;By Neill F. Marriott&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class="bodyBlock"&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p5" pid="benDvDHQBEu9ohyxAdBAYQ" hash="9aMQHQ"&gt;Soon after the Resurrection and Ascension of Jesus, the Apostle Peter taught, “Let all … know assuredly, that God hath made that same Jesus, whom ye have crucified, both Lord and Christ.” The listeners were stricken in their hearts and asked Peter and the others, “Men and brethren, what shall we do?”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; And they subsequently obeyed Peter’s teachings with gladness.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p6" pid="M1u7BgVVrkm1Xp-j21rqJg" hash="gjxqlA"&gt;Tomorrow is Easter Sunday, and I hope that we also are stricken in our hearts to acknowledge the Savior, repent, and obey with gladness.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p7" pid="cVNLLiTlHUuzaUIqWNglqw" hash="KvR_Bw"&gt;In this general conference, we will hear inspired direction given by Church leaders, both male and female. Knowing that our hearts will be touched by their words, I ask you tonight, “Women and sisters, what shall we do?”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p8" pid="5PeEkR6eFE6TeMt1xzkovw" hash="b7iz1g"&gt;The Relief Society general president Eliza R. Snow declared to sisters almost 150 years ago, “The Lord has laid high responsibilities upon us.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; I testify that her declaration is still true today.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p9" pid="CGeAb17n4EOjfCLsAu55iQ" hash="SWy0TA"&gt;The Lord’s Church needs Spirit-directed women who use their unique gifts to nurture, to speak up, and to defend gospel truth. Our inspiration and intuition are necessary parts of building the kingdom of God, which really means doing our part to bring salvation to God’s children.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.t1"&gt;
			&lt;h2 pid="WI0mwnHu1U6T9EmCH2qAeQ" hash="H8Y-Kw"&gt;Building the Kingdom through Nurturing&lt;/h2&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p11" pid="XXiX4ItU_kyaLle5oXNzvg" hash="poP3aQ"&gt;We build the kingdom when we nurture others. However, the first child of God we must build up in the restored gospel is ourselves. Emma Smith said, “I desire the Spirit of God to know and understand myself, that I might be able to overcome whatever of tradition or nature that would not tend to my exaltation.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; We must develop bedrock faith in the Savior’s gospel and move forward, empowered by temple covenants, toward exaltation.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p12" pid="m83lYBmdZ0W-mDp43DowNA" hash="lq-uAw"&gt;What if some of our traditions don’t have a place in the restored gospel of Jesus Christ? Letting go of them may require the emotional support and nurture of another, as it did for me.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p13" pid="8ysjN6jVvUyWetIDBIQWwQ" hash="5R6JwQ"&gt;When I was born, my parents planted a magnolia tree in the backyard so there would be magnolias at my wedding ceremony, held in the Protestant church of my forefathers. But on the day of my marriage, there were no parents at my side and no magnolias, for as a one-year convert to the Church, I had traveled to Salt Lake City, Utah, to receive my temple endowment and be sealed to David, my fiancé.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p14" pid="AKMuGYd2-k-26cBwkF7StA" hash="CrwBPA"&gt;When I left Louisiana and neared Utah, a feeling of homelessness swept over me. Before the wedding, I would be staying with David’s step-grandmother, who was lovingly known as Aunt Carol.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p15" pid="1CPg3d8B9ESGp_eDm1Yu1w" hash="8to9TA"&gt;Here I was, a stranger to Utah, going to stay in a stranger’s house before being sealed—for eternity—to a family I barely knew. (Good thing I loved and trusted my future husband and the Lord!)&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p16" pid="eiItpO_Mv02BysTVjfSlvw" hash="BXW27Q"&gt;As I stood at the front door of Aunt Carol’s house, I wanted to shrink away. The door opened—I stood there like a scared rabbit—and Aunt Carol, without a word, reached out and took me into her arms. She, who had no children of her own, knew—her nurturing heart knew—that I needed a place to belong. Oh, the comfort and sweetness of that moment! My fear melted, and there came to me a sense of being anchored to a spiritually safe place.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p17" pid="06MdAuw-V0ujWh-uXLEWYg" hash="YXwpfg"&gt;Love is making space in your life for someone else, as Aunt Carol did for me.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p18" pid="wEkf8SuKdUGMIAepdsT_6A" hash="Is7Zwg"&gt;Mothers literally make room in their bodies to nurture an unborn baby—and hopefully a place in their hearts as they raise them—but nurturing is not limited to bearing children. Eve was called a “mother” before she had children.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; I believe that “to mother” means “to give life.” Think of the many ways you give life. It could mean giving emotional life to the hopeless or spiritual life to the doubter. With the help of the Holy Ghost, we can create an emotionally healing place for the discriminated against, the rejected, and the stranger. In these tender yet powerful ways, we build the kingdom of God. Sisters, all of us came to earth with these life-giving, nurturing, maternal gifts because that is God’s plan.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p19" pid="DO9UqQ5hg0yqIVd_vgIcmA" hash="F0ltRQ"&gt;Following His plan and becoming a builder of the kingdom require selfless sacrifice. Elder Orson F. Whitney wrote: “All that we suffer and all that we endure, especially when we endure it patiently, … purifies our hearts … and makes us more tender and charitable, … and it is through … toil and tribulation, that we gain the education … which will make us more like our Father and Mother in heaven.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; These purifying trials bring us to Christ, who can heal us and make us useful in the work of salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.t2"&gt;
			&lt;h2 pid="I0EjACeqFU2rZtYZtBdTmQ" hash="3Fx4kg"&gt;Building the Kingdom through Speaking and Testifying&lt;/h2&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p21" pid="d8ILazPMxkO1O-Ny_9DwRA" hash="0EooEg"&gt;We also build the kingdom when we speak up and testify of truth. We follow the Lord’s pattern. He speaks and teaches with power and authority of God. Sisters, we can too. Women generally love to talk and gather! As we work by delegated priesthood authority given to us, our talking and gathering grow into gospel teaching and leading.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p22" pid="pXjHCKzpQk66lu0p7zunyQ" hash="HmZWAw"&gt;Sister Julie B. Beck, former Relief Society general president, taught: “The ability to qualify for, receive, and act on personal revelation is the single most important skill that can be acquired in this life. … It requires a conscious effort.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p23" pid="Du8vXSaH5EChTsCR_Igikg" hash="iwRlIg"&gt;Personal revelation from the Holy Ghost will prompt us to learn, speak, and act on eternal truth—the Savior’s truth. The more we follow Christ, the more we will feel His love and direction; the more we feel His love and direction, the more we will want to speak and teach truth as He did, even when we face opposition.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p24" pid="JU5y0_CmoUSuD1u4rcmH9Q" hash="SQOv4A"&gt;Some years ago, I prayed for the words to defend motherhood when I received an anonymous phone call.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p25" pid="T0ZiqUOEo0-BVYenT47CBw" hash="1iN2WA"&gt;The caller asked, “Are you Neill Marriott, the mother of a big family?”&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p26" pid="rQAtfCBzxE22uiEK3Lk1LA" hash="VHpilQ"&gt;I answered happily, “Yes!” expecting to hear her say something like, “Well, that’s good!”&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p27" pid="0aGi7ku48kCq9uegs4_zqA" hash="QudExA"&gt;But no! I’ll never forget her reply as her voice crackled over the phone: “I am highly offended that you would bring children onto this overcrowded planet!”&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p28" pid="Nfs9NS5PTkKEL0BCCqzfCA" hash="AzAG1w"&gt;“Oh,” I sputtered, “I see how you feel.”&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p29" pid="gKuiBRQAGEeOLVG0K7NpGA" hash="olbmkg"&gt;She snapped, “No—you don’t!”&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p30" pid="Vw8hK7GJpUCOG7BnqSf1WQ" hash="M4ct5A"&gt;I then whimpered, “Well, maybe I don’t.”&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p31" pid="s21HwqfX-02G0-12Cl4TWQ" hash="qZlywg"&gt;She started on a rant about my foolish choice to be a mother. As she went on, I began to pray for help, and a gentle thought came to mind: “What would the Lord say to her?” I then felt I was standing on solid ground and gained courage at the thought of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p32" pid="-VEwE7yD0EiBijsaRCtA7g" hash="MSv_cg"&gt;I replied, “I am glad to be a mother, and I promise you I will do everything in my power to nurture my children in such a way that they will make the world a better place.”&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p33" pid="NxOYjT1TWkinyQdnVF3K-g" hash="Q13DTQ"&gt;She replied, “Well, I hope you do!” and hung up.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p34" pid="nwpARz1lTE6b-m7xi8407g" hash="tGGD7w"&gt;It wasn’t a big thing—after all, I was standing safely in my own kitchen! But in my own small way, I was able to speak in defense of family, mothers, and nurturers because of two things: (1) I understood and believed God’s doctrine of the family, and (2) I prayed for words to convey these truths.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p35" pid="f8cIWyZ-8U2yA4u27OhwRA" hash="_BCy1A"&gt;Being distinct and different from the world will draw some criticism, but we must anchor ourselves to eternal principles and testify of them, no matter the world’s response.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p36" pid="48u6lf9YUEib5CmambF2vA" hash="YEecdA"&gt;When we ask ourselves, “What shall we do?” let’s ponder this question: “What does the Savior do continually?” He nurtures. He creates. He encourages growth and goodness. Women and sisters, we can do these things! Primary girls, is there someone in your family who needs your love and kindness? You build the kingdom by nurturing others too.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p37" pid="t2ruCPfiTEa0uqpeuDY7VA" hash="chjOcw"&gt;The Savior’s creation of the earth, under the direction of His Father, was a mighty act of nurturing. He provided a place for us to grow and develop faith in His atoning power. Faith in Jesus Christ and His Atonement is the ultimate place of healing and hope, growth and purpose. All of us need a spiritual and physical place of belonging. We, sisters of all ages, can create this; it is even a holy place.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do.p38" pid="gIXNosveaE-AU5q8tPt0Tw" hash="9Gm48A"&gt;Our high responsibility is to become women who follow the Savior, nurture with inspiration, and live truth fearlessly. As we ask Father in Heaven to make us builders of His kingdom, His power will flow into us and we will know how to nurture, ultimately becoming like our heavenly parents. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/04/what-shall-we-do</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2016-general-conference/2016-03-0030-neill-f-marriott-64k-eng.mp3" length="5761952" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
