<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By O. Leslie Stone</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by O. Leslie Stone.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/O.%20Leslie%20Stone.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by O. Leslie Stone.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>To Serve the Master</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters: I don’t know why I should be shaking as I am. I am among friends. I know that no one loves me more than these brethren who are sitting before you, and I love them. Nearly all of them have visited our home and stayed with</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03027_000_4030" doc-version="2" hash="h2XESA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="JvWKeZ8JBUigYxC4vKXRbw" hash="eTZFxQ">To Serve the Master</h1><p class="authorName" guid="a016eae0-2af0-4657-9fab-cdaa6d13bc35" pid="swqTqaTFnU6Kuw1u5CKipg" hash="XDOjPg">O. Leslie Stone</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="e5cc9f37-796f-4a20-b521-4ddbcd539334">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master.p1" guid="17df968c-0b80-4950-a0be-bb86c52b08ed" pid="Ul2NSIj570qnW5WH6bkh4g" hash="K35bDQ">My dear brothers and sisters: I don’t know why I should be shaking as I am. I am among friends. I know that no one loves me more than these brethren who are sitting before you, and I love them. Nearly all of them have visited our home and stayed with us and left their blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master.p2" guid="14935110-161d-40ee-8882-58ceb682f39e" pid="yqszGdUrukap_vhAycH6dQ" hash="HYzYDg">When President Lee called me to be a stake president about sixteen years ago, I remember on the way home he said, “President Stone, I want you to prepare now for the day when you will be released.” And I assured him that I was ready any time the Brethren wanted to release me. But you know this time when he called me the other day, he didn’t say a word about that. Later he told me the appointment was for life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master.p3" guid="f26455de-de30-4514-abe9-573365c40684" pid="huvYOknhSkC9l1-CVjiO5Q" hash="FrZo6A">I feel humble, grateful, and assure you and the Brethren of my willingness to serve, to devote my time, energy, and means for the upbuilding of the kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master.p4" guid="0fb17102-d37d-4acd-9231-710cdbf980e1" pid="uaZqUpUYBkOI5nqV8Fpjxw" hash="3fHl9w">The Savior on one occasion, realizing the many temptations that we are faced with in this life, made this statement: “… seek ye first the kingdom of God, and his righteousness; and all these things shall be added unto you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.33" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 6:33</a>.) We have tried to live by that rule in our family. My sons, who have both been mission presidents, used to quote that to me when I was talking to them about their future.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master.p5" guid="7bd5dded-c1e4-44f6-bef8-6187d419ff5c" pid="3qBFGeSOfkebTm1-YEEqyA" hash="BKSIBg">Now, I want you all to remember the program of prospective elders, and I am going to tell you why. I was a prospective elder when I met my wife in Blackfoot, Idaho; and after I had courted her for some time and decided (and let her know) that she was the girl of my dreams, she let me know in no uncertain terms that I had to “shape up.” A temple marriage was the only marriage she was interested in.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master.p6" guid="179261ab-b1df-4615-8f36-42b54fc39f7e" pid="Nxe5oc0djEe0ZN4OLKjSlw" hash="cowoXw">After shaping up, I was ordained an elder and secured a temple recommend. We were sealed for time and eternity in the Salt Lake Temple April 23, 1924. I am very grateful for my eternal companion and for my family, including fourteen grandchildren. It was my wife’s birthday yesterday, the day that I was sustained as a General Authority.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master.p7" guid="3d07c747-32c7-460d-aa8a-6adbe1681b01" pid="gN8R3UMRAkyrSeYjvMvp9g" hash="Z3S2BA">I would like to testify to you that the greatest happiness that has come into our lives has been when we have been living the gospel and serving the Master, and I have to tell you just a little story.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master.p8" guid="6b81ba30-dbc7-42e8-9f4c-8966390dad85" pid="ERmltbU1ZkeIcdnnPqUtdg" hash="1YthMw">A few years ago, roughly twenty-five, I was starting a new business. I was having difficulty in getting it into black figures. I don’t like to operate in the red, and I went to my Heavenly Father on bended knees and made a covenant with him that if he would bless me with inspiration and guidance to make that business successful, I would serve him and I would be liberal with my time and means for the up-building of the kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master.p9" guid="89ab2661-6d83-4e28-beee-a8517d4a026a" pid="IHsM56gNlUq4eIbQQI9iYw" hash="HroHnw">The Lord did bless us abundantly, and I now pledge to President Lee, President Tanner, President Romney, and all these Brethren that I shall put forth my best efforts to fulfill this new assignment. I love the Lord, and I want to serve him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master.p10" guid="6167a642-9e49-4055-8227-9f49cf3a3fea" pid="9Ix6-GInV0CSHNDH8Zlghg" hash="AQ2vtg">On the day I was put in as stake president, President Lee quoted this scripture. It has always stuck in my mind, and I would like to quote it to you because it is one of my favorites:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master.p11" guid="8c6a0441-ef32-43cb-af93-40fd2688260e" pid="ym1M6_H89EaL9-Cx4XxlCA" hash="FVxn3Q">“Trust in the Lord with all thine heart; and lean not unto thine own understanding.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master.p12" guid="a33cd192-7516-46fd-85a3-d1b1d5a4e755" pid="lxbrOBrtdECuEzb6ntkybg" hash="Whk-PA">“In all thy ways acknowledge him, and he shall direct thy paths.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/3.5-6" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 3:5–6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master.p13" guid="6a127ade-f35f-45d0-92a2-5bdc040ec987" pid="EgEtKPPd_ky5OKiyql9lyA" hash="xCjTlg">I pray I may always do this, in the name of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master.p14" guid="3fe88e81-047f-4855-9e60-999f7a2a5ae5" pid="jhPNXqxYz0iUVWvCfuGX5Q" hash="7SyakQ">Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/10/to-serve-the-master</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1972-general-conference/1972-10-4030-elder-o-leslie-stone-64k-eng.mp3" length="2262206" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Constant Exercise of Our Faith</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I am sure that as grandfathers and fathers, you rejoice with me in these children who have rendered the singing at this session of the conference. They are wonderful. Being a grandfather of 14, I have learned to love grandchildren.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03033_000_4040" doc-version="2" hash="QuYtVg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="3SarOAhl40iLg1j5vEtl1w" hash="FkEeIg">The Constant Exercise of Our Faith</h1><p class="authorName" guid="a016eae0-2af0-4657-9fab-cdaa6d13bc35" pid="cO3tpQTtwk23RfHN7r3nNA" hash="XDOjPg">O. Leslie Stone</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="4136194d-0869-4768-9061-0a642f6397a9">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p1" guid="67cd7e6d-e804-4f61-b068-e46e6b7475a1" pid="1SC-z3CTGk-OHRGWhaOVvA" hash="TrXz_A">I am sure that as grandfathers and fathers, you rejoice with me in these children who have rendered the singing at this session of the conference. They are wonderful. Being a grandfather of 14, I have learned to love grandchildren.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p2" guid="460a115d-11a6-49be-bf1b-14282ae87f1a" pid="d5Txo12eGUaouBFJ9abGBw" hash="8RielA">I am reminded of the grandfather who got on the airplane. As he went down the aisle looking for a seat, he came to an attractive woman, and he said, “Are you a grandmother?” And she said, “Yes, I am.” So he passed her up. He went on and repeated it again. Finally he asked a lady, “Are you a grandmother?” And she said, “No, I am not.” He said, “May I sit down? I want to talk about my grandchildren.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p3" guid="547a8c8c-cb77-4d20-9b26-95c8cfb3fc6c" pid="PK7VE0oGIEmRHltabuW-og" hash="uThFyQ">In the few moments allotted to me, I would like to discuss the subject of faith, what it means, and how it affects us as individuals.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p4" guid="d564ccf0-bafb-40a4-85ec-a8af5fa27171" pid="EUch7zUVwEe5pHhQ3WBvCg" hash="BWiXDg">When I made preparation for this talk, I had no idea that in our family we would be called on so soon to exercise great faith and prayers for the well-being of my sweet companion, who underwent major surgery just last Monday. Our faith and prayers were answered, and I want to thank all of my brethren here and all of my friends and others who joined with us in their faith and prayers for her recovery. She is listening from her hospital bed. I would like to take just a moment to tell her how much I love her. She has been a wonderful companion for 49 years this month. She has been an inspiration to me all the days that we have been married. She has been a fine mother and grandmother. We are looking forward to her return from the hospital.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p5" guid="81e0a4e4-6c9e-4235-914b-ae330d074f43" pid="0ARukDBbdUeBqLb24-Bvnw" hash="DdlhOA">The apostle Paul tells us: “… faith is the substance of things hoped for, and the evidence of things not seen.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/11.1" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 11:1</a>.) Faith and belief have been used synonymously, and it is sometimes difficult for us to differentiate between the two. There <span class="emphasis">is </span>a difference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p6" guid="8490c703-3f86-41f4-a5f9-a5e522a5cbe6" pid="Cua4wSUZ8UGUqW4Rif-0sQ" hash="YPzRew">We cannot have faith without belief, but we can believe without having faith. Belief is the foundation of faith. Faith is trusting in our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p7" guid="0e355504-24e7-4622-9e7a-4c358a8399fd" pid="3_K1-pYzqkmtc8MJw662fQ" hash="qD0Ysw">The scriptures contain many assurances of salvation to those who exercise faith and obey the commandments. One such assurance is found in <a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/16.16" class="scriptureRef">Mark 16:16</a>, which reads: “He that believeth and is baptized shall be saved; but he that believeth not shall be damned.” Note that the Lord said: “He that believeth and is baptized shall be saved.” In other words, we must do more than believe—we must act. Faith is the motivating force that impels action.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p8" guid="96bcc25d-0448-4c0c-89ec-85b3bd3c642f" pid="wH_5KsXvSEGT7GaRWLDl_A" hash="0hniOg">In <a href="/scriptures/nt/james/2.20" class="scriptureRef">James 2:20</a> we read: “But wilt thou know, O vain man, that faith without works is dead?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p9" guid="0fd37ea9-6d08-4ed5-9a73-e08232646051" pid="iJvCDAnGc0SrT0DHOK1Ofg" hash="7fQSIQ">Many believe that God will provide, but we cannot sit idly by and expect to get results. The Lord requires us to work for that which we seek. If we do our part and exercise faith, then we are promised he will help us in all our righteous undertakings. However, if we do not do our part, how can we expect the help of our Heavenly Father? Our late President David O. McKay said, “The rich rewards come only to the strenuous strugglers.” In other words, to those who not only have faith but are willing to work and sacrifice in order to achieve their goals.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p10" guid="c6377ec2-9018-49af-ab8d-101af4715240" pid="RRLGOld7jE6ZKCR3uFVWXQ" hash="OmJzcg">Some may ask, “How do we gain faith?” The answer is that we gain faith just as we gain any other attribute. We must first establish a foundation, and then cultivate our thoughts and actions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p11" guid="93ed6b49-7391-40f1-aba0-908531dadf64" pid="bi9ivbERj0CcP7M-rlGrZw" hash="3rinXg">Joseph Smith said: “Faith comes by hearing the word of God, through the testimony of the servants of God. …” (<span class="emphasis">Documentary History of the Church, </span>vol. 3, p. 379.) Our very presence in meetings of this conference will tend to increase our faith because we come here with a desire to learn and to worship, to be motivated, and to be spiritually uplifted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p12" guid="749bd255-1ae4-4562-85aa-c8145078d2f5" pid="hMtfLo6UGE2YeWtySXd9XQ" hash="DnvaDg">I testify to all within the sound of my voice that my attendance at general conferences over a period of many years, hearing the testimonies of our leaders here and in other places, has constantly increased my faith and helped me to build a strong testimony as to the truthfulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p13" guid="b723256e-c3de-435d-88fc-06b8f19cd273" pid="jgucXoy_b0aG9aqXPLkYPg" hash="sdBexw">Partaking of the sacrament administered by those having authority is a great aid to faith. The broken bread symbolizes the broken flesh of our Redeemer, and the holy cup represents his atoning blood. Reading the scriptures nurtures faith. Earnest prayer is essential to increasing one’s faith. Prayer is vocalized faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p14" guid="3fd93020-3f3d-4d92-b134-95768d1fe8fe" pid="WT9ryIrzKkaeR8eYMOV6OQ" hash="allSEQ">Right living is the greatest of all faith builders. Sin is the greatest of all faith destroyers. Even small sins destroy faith. Vanity, pride, selfishness, greed, and hatred wound the fine spirit of God which nurtures and gives life to faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p15" guid="ac0261b8-561e-43e7-96d7-33d703f45440" pid="X5IVuv-3KEyFmmVkSkx1YQ" hash="6H2ahA">Ceaseless striving to find the bright light of living faith purifies the heart, strengthens the will, and develops sterling character.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p16" guid="e7768877-7ea6-4e4d-939e-9b0b8590c050" pid="hmkohfSIBEuiWEmWaDHpOw" hash="lqLmEg">The constant exercise of our faith by lofty thinking, prayer, devotion, and acts of righteousness is just as essential to spiritual health as physical exercise is to the health of the body. Like all priceless things, faith, if lost, is hard to regain. Eternal vigilance is the price of our faith. In order to retain our faith we must keep ourselves in tune with our Heavenly Father by living in accordance with the principles and ordinances of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p17" guid="c9af8e44-2fda-4857-b7b8-09e488f8a775" pid="IgS0tckhrEuD3XN9OTOoeA" hash="10nD5w">Moses exercised faith when he led the children of Israel out of bondage. The Lord instructed him what to do, and he had faith that it could be done. He gathered the Israelites and proceeded on the journey. You will remember that they were closely followed by the Egyptians, who wanted to prevent their leaving.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p18" guid="af6f8a12-c7d8-43a2-8cae-cafe86d4743e" pid="mY0NEZglZUuONcPS4l6tRg" hash="-u9cSQ">They reached the Red Sea, and the Israelites felt there was no chance of escape. The sea lay before them and the Egyptians behind. Some said: “… it had been better for us to serve the Egyptians, than that we should die in the wilderness.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p19" guid="c2131221-6004-4527-b0c4-78ee678a3cf1" pid="7N8Lov8Ua0u1qeM-1rfCUQ" hash="xYwYHw">Moses told them: “Fear ye not. … the Lord shall fight for you and ye shall hold your peace.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p20" guid="fd38d3ef-955d-4a09-b113-349dd41ef933" pid="g77sOo0Ytkai9QKka7qWtQ" hash="86ThvQ">The Lord, speaking to Moses, said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p21" guid="ca4d547a-2191-4f7d-9dae-2bb08870acd5" pid="qb9BxiLiXk6ksx3uWe9wRg" hash="_4hh_Q">“… lift thou up thy rod, and stretch out thine hand over the sea, and divide it: and the children of Israel shall go on dry ground through the midst of the sea.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p22" guid="83f068da-77dc-425d-9f85-9fb8fdb0475a" pid="p_ks_1bbAUWYJ2MGfvu0LQ" hash="p7hr1g">“And Moses stretched out his hand over the sea; and the Lord caused the sea to go back by a strong east wind all that night, and made the sea dry land, and the waters were divided.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p23" guid="41cfe1fc-12db-400e-a53c-4cc08c5c7d05" pid="KCLgN3TsfkWbg6qrkue0og" hash="Ha7rpQ">“And the children of Israel went into the midst of the sea upon the dry ground: and the waters were a wall unto them on their right hand, and on their left.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p24" guid="7e4f8e77-6bc4-4414-9906-de3a49aae52f" pid="DOicKNz7LE26ZH7AHmyWYg" hash="b7Dy9Q">“And the Egyptians pursued, and went in after them to the midst of the sea, even all Pharaoh’s horses, his chariots, and his horsemen.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/14.12-14,16,21-23" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 14:12–14, 16, 21–23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p25" guid="3bb54bba-75d2-4462-87dd-40932a9d802e" pid="87udUOnL00eDDJ2ujfkdCA" hash="_bgAIw">And then the Lord told Moses to stretch out his hand, and the water would come back and destroy the Egyptians. Moses again exercised his faith in God, and the Egyptians were destroyed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p26" guid="4558d7a3-8415-4499-8a29-fa05e12850d7" pid="vIsjGCjtmUidVPiy-HSeFg" hash="3d7uTw">The Prophet Joseph demonstrated great faith throughout his ministry. When he was only 14, he was reading the scriptures, and in the first chapter of James, fifth and sixth verses, he read:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p27" guid="950e9c4c-7941-4daa-8ba8-dde39417c4ff" pid="TkxO1NMhrUGIdlCquvPRjg" hash="47_z1w">“If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask of God, that giveth to all men liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p28" guid="a424b922-9d6a-4026-9b7e-3f46b6955df9" pid="Dehggp67DEmj_LtTXHUg6g" hash="rQkruQ">“But let him ask in faith, nothing wavering. For he that wavereth is like a wave of the sea driven with the wind and tossed.” [<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.5-6" class="scriptureRef">James 1:5–6</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p29" guid="8d4846e1-e99b-4ef3-8355-98f4981e1f61" pid="GZM_SO1M-UyRYuY8GRIhPw" hash="7q-HAQ">This passage of scripture rocked his very soul, for he felt that if ever a person needed wisdom in deciding what to do, it was he.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p30" guid="91bedf9b-4598-41e4-9100-5bc25e2d915d" pid="luMlP7RSN0aTObyAUzGKhg" hash="RiYaTw">He believed; he had faith; his faith impelled action, and so he went into the woods to pray. His prayers were answered.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p31" guid="f5ffa541-5ef0-44f0-b0be-8085d3d9b98e" pid="_s66TW7rUU27xAhqJYzxVg" hash="s0psVQ">How different our lives would be if it had not been for the strong faith of the Prophet Joseph!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p32" guid="31e5d88d-6714-4958-8e79-e378bda489a5" pid="EuP4dMdwxkqkLyVMPzdcTQ" hash="d10SyQ">Brigham Young was a man of great faith. He had faith in a living God. He had faith in every principle and doctrine revealed and taught by the Prophet Joseph. He had faith in himself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p33" guid="c4988eb1-c327-4433-b395-5920878919b2" pid="fc3JHOR_OEu9GwJQB_FZTg" hash="dPRcxA">He once made this statement:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p34" guid="188d3ced-a6a7-4bdf-a115-17ae6e7c47b0" pid="BvUZekHbaEmPrIIMN5P1dg" hash="z4nwxg">“If the Latter-day Saints will walk up to their privileges, and exercise faith in the name of Jesus Christ, and live in the enjoyment of the fulness of the Holy Ghost constantly day by day, there is nothing on the face of the earth that they could ask for, that would not be given to them.” (<span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses, </span>vol. 11, p. 114.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p35" guid="6308b52b-2174-40ad-ba44-fe65ab4fb68f" pid="47_XSjk2lkqhl3cuPExyIQ" hash="9T_6IA">The Latter-day Saint pioneers certainly demonstrated great faith when they crossed the plains. They left their homes and most of their worldly belongings. Some of them left their families and friends to follow the Church leaders to an unknown land. The reason was obvious: they had great faith. They sought and found a place where they could exercise their faith, worship in peace, and serve the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p36" guid="eccd11b0-3741-437f-a441-b61a4bcb5cb7" pid="5oAseRmSrUK1A4fGjxvE2Q" hash="rgG7vA">Sometimes we become impatient because the world is converted so slowly. In our impatience, we wonder why God does not reveal himself in majesty and glory, that the whole world might instantly be brought to their knees to worship him. But when we think intelligently about the matter, we understand that God’s slow, patient way of converting the world is best. When people are required to believe largely upon the testimony of others, they are compelled to grip the threads of truth firmly and hold on until they can develop strong faith. God’s plan makes it necessary for us to nurture, cultivate, and enlarge our faith. In this long, patient process of developing our faith, we acquire fortitude and strength of character. These sterling qualities are of eternal worth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p37" guid="2458d7b3-e5e1-4bd6-91cb-a74dc66d2052" pid="2Ydlddjcq0Kyn_13aghZbQ" hash="eWXOQQ">I have been thrilled with the faith manifested by many of our recently returned prisoners of war. Many have expressed their faith in God, their faith in their families, and their faith in this great country and its leaders.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p38" guid="a065bd02-d199-41a6-94c1-acfbfd77e004" pid="v_glTtufFUKLrQU7Kp8HUQ" hash="KzCVkQ">It is indeed gratifying to hear these expressions of love, faith, and gratitude from these men who have suffered so much. This is in such contrast to those who have protested everything our leaders have done to bring about the release of our prisoners and to reunite them with their families. I am sure we all feel grateful that this has been accomplished, and join together in giving thanks to our Heavenly Father for these great blessings. Our prayers and love are extended to all of these men, that they might get reestablished in the stream of life; that they might have joy in their labors and continue to show love for their God, their families, their country, and their fellowmen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p39" guid="d2d21a9b-4c7b-4866-911b-3f1c9ca2c11a" pid="ChOIwI62KUi_DI8TnrG5Lg" hash="t_W9HA">There has never been a time in our lives, the history of the Church, or the history of our nation, when there existed a greater need for faith than today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p40" guid="68cc8375-92ce-480f-91e5-331a728339bc" pid="rusnRgLSFU-ub2i0uxw2dw" hash="rfwzCw">We need faith in the restored gospel of Jesus Christ, faith in our church leaders, faith in America, faith in ourselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p41" guid="bd9fa368-dba9-4fff-9d16-ce0e1b978ccd" pid="X6cU1-I-w02g3Ied4bqG-A" hash="4twRfg">I conclude by bearing my witness as to the truthfulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ. The greatest blessings we have received in our family have been when we have been most liberal with our time, our means, and our efforts in carrying out our responsibilities in the Church. These blessings are available to everyone if they will but have faith, accept the gospel of Jesus Christ, and then live in conformity with its teachings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p42" guid="773804b6-e8af-4bd6-943d-b72b9ab0559e" pid="_h13FRf_iU253rli5CtVyw" hash="3a8xgA">It is my humble prayer that each of us will increase our faith day by day; that we will keep the commandments; that we will love, honor, and sustain our prophet, President Harold B. Lee, and all who are closely associated with him in building the kingdom of God; that we will so live as to be true to the end and worthy to receive the greatest of all blessings, which is salvation, exaltation, and eternal life in the kingdom of our Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith.p43" guid="e878e782-677f-4021-9580-93dccc682ab6" pid="GkJd6XyQnku0a8WB6HytkA" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1973/04/the-constant-exercise-of-our-faith</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1973-general-conference/1973-04-4040-elder-o-leslie-stone-64k-eng.mp3" length="7395777" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 1973 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Love and Forgive One Another</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another?lang=eng</link>
      <description>It is an inspiration to all of us to remember the teachings of our Savior and the many wonderful things that he gave to the world. He lived long before recorded history. He was in the great council in heaven—he helped his Father in the shaping of the</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03040_000_2050" doc-version="2" hash="ZXQoqw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="UherqBQoj0SBwQbEiNd_Cw" hash="RPD5sQ">Love and Forgive One Another</h1><p class="authorName" guid="a016eae0-2af0-4657-9fab-cdaa6d13bc35" pid="0RC5qx-85EuaF0ultLaRVQ" hash="XDOjPg">O. Leslie Stone</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="c0800244-a48c-4dcc-bb7b-26bb14e84a62">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p1" guid="82893ea6-4027-4c82-8d06-929a44b3bbd1" pid="qAcpNrKF8UutMr_qtNbAYA" hash="zKNFJQ">It is an inspiration to all of us to remember the teachings of our Savior and the many wonderful things that he gave to the world. He lived long before recorded history. He was in the great council in heaven—he helped his Father in the shaping of the heavens, in the creation of the earth, and in the making of man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p2" guid="0b9e5bf3-cc0e-4acc-a1ee-7fafec67c204" pid="5yK-Qg02yk6iaWZmJh8iLg" hash="wrevCg">In opposition to Satan’s plan, it was he who proposed man’s free agency—giving him the glorious privilege of choice which means so much to all of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p3" guid="87512d54-ffe9-406b-a9b7-235553368176" pid="Ks7PmoP_c0e-HwA7EvRO9w" hash="GxjnJQ">He lived on earth in the meridian of time—in the promised land.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p4" guid="a39f99f5-15be-401a-a868-2282ff51a468" pid="RfSOZWWinEKjouvA-SlvOg" hash="cevnuQ">He went about teaching and doing good. Men followed him, not for worldly riches but to gain treasures in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p5" guid="7c0156bb-dc45-43e5-ab9b-eac716b77105" pid="Q8gH0d1Q_kueeHXa501Z5A" hash="rVrYqA">He set up a new code for living—to love one another—even one’s enemies. He enjoined us to judge not, to forgive, and to give all men a second chance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p6" guid="e520b501-07de-4363-ab2d-4f954f798bc2" pid="qXG-Rm0kSka3-v2iBlUlDA" hash="3Dy4Sg">In the Doctrine and Covenants section 64, verses 8–11, he tells us that it is our duty to forgive one another and that he who does not forgive his brother stands condemned and is <span class="emphasis">the greater sinner.</span> [<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.8-11" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:8–11</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p7" guid="e73c1eef-000d-4c42-a7d5-7687dfa7857b" pid="LSD8FO0eqEWDA-pBjzPRFA" hash="8M6uCw">He gave our society our most undying formula for getting along together when he made this statement found in <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.12" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 7:12</a>:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p8" guid="77e9826e-e233-4576-bd68-362783d3221e" pid="tnRv-dJESE6iCK8cXgPKmw" hash="3bmBTQ">“Therefore all things whatsoever ye would that men should do to you, do ye even so to them: for this is the law and the prophets.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p9" guid="a1cf5a7d-6534-4758-a8b7-f81c039f5aff" pid="-0hTcP1YlkSnV5WHUXDFXA" hash="nvymcQ">There are very few of us that are fully living up to this. Yet I am sure we all agree that if men followed this principle they would solve the problems that we are now facing in all the nations of the earth. Yes, if we lived this principle it would be easy to love and forgive those who trespass against us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p10" guid="95035e49-f902-4793-9799-b66d87302f1e" pid="zjrK6LKWKU2ulKkKZtVEtA" hash="Lba42g">In <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.36-39" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:36–39</a>, we read about an instance where Christ was approached by some of the leading lawyers of the day who said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p11" guid="c7661a2d-562e-493c-b897-68992ef66e21" pid="wAL01_fIkkyqQo8O38TQyg" hash="6G0iNQ">“Master, which is the great commandment in the law? Jesus said unto him, Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind. This is the first and great commandment. And the second is like unto it, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p12" guid="1abcb4f4-4a96-49e3-95ca-39b9f7944f02" pid="2BODI_u7mkyydkb9n-b0ig" hash="BsGwJw">It should be remembered that our nearest neighbors are the members of our own family. Next are those living next door to us, in the same block, the same city, the same state, the nation, yes, even the whole world. All whom we associate with or influence in any way are our neighbors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p13" guid="7072b15d-79e8-4e53-aaa2-f5d8df8d07cc" pid="Ggp3Gk2BKESvbfgUJ7CANQ" hash="JtTUxg">Can a man reach the celestial kingdom if he does not love his neighbor as himself? When Jesus gave the second commandment, He said it was like unto the first and repeating both of them he said, “On these two commandments hang all the law and the prophets.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.40" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:40</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p14" guid="96763033-5d85-4938-beda-a320cd77226e" pid="1-WChHRdTk2_B7aFtQLuvg" hash="y8Lz_g">He made them very important—so important that all other laws and commandments rest upon them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p15" guid="24cf8798-bdc8-473d-a08d-8c4a06eaf8ab" pid="uhDXJhZYPkuyC7191NvGCQ" hash="VHICGg">Let us ask another question. Can a man live the first and great commandment if he does not live the second? In other words, can he love God with all his heart if he does not love his neighbor?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p16" guid="2bdf28e5-efa6-444d-9782-0a9bff551191" pid="wMLuQfItdUO1b9AF07dv2Q" hash="350BvA">John the apostle said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p17" guid="971a093a-e6ea-4011-9eba-d6d2138a6e76" pid="kIcAOqwVh0OF8e6NiD6qGw" hash="0G3qVQ">“If a man say, I love God, and hateth his brother, he is a liar: for he that loveth not his brother whom he hath seen, how can he love God whom he hath not seen? And this commandment have we from him, That he who loveth God love his brother also.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-jn/4.20-21" class="scriptureRef">1 Jn. 4:20–21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p18" guid="f06e139b-55fc-4bbe-a3b8-d3b450b011b8" pid="iV5KnGVnIEC6fHoF4RmJng" hash="920LYA">In third Nephi 11:29–30 we find this statement:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p19" guid="a887fa20-e85b-4f46-b52b-85d77152dfbe" pid="wE_T0Q94uEi2_KkFQtSuIA" hash="0axTRA">“For verily, verily I say unto you, he that hath the spirit of contention is not of me, but is of the devil, who is the father of contention, and he stirreth up the hearts of men to contend with anger, one with another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p20" guid="17ecd69e-a332-410c-ae84-0558d433f13d" pid="3lJ4vzR6qUG5plswC5ut9A" hash="IK8zXQ">“Behold, this is not my doctrine, to stir up the hearts of men with anger, one against another; but this is my doctrine, that such things should be done away.” [<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.29-30" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:29–30</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p21" guid="edb61c32-2668-4aca-a375-285ae49f1b03" pid="2fd6zu2axkWtCCifIdE4Bg" hash="m5Ef8w">These statements and many others should make it clear to all of us that the Lord desires us to love and forgive one another. It behooves us to conquer our pride and settle our differences with our fellowmen. As just quoted from third Nephi, contentions and disputations are of the devil and are not approved by our Heavenly Father. Loving our neighbors as ourselves will bring great joy and happiness into our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p22" guid="92541615-2c7c-43bb-8705-1860bff75df4" pid="YMMfXNv47U6d8-SKxiVtOA" hash="f6JILw">Christ practiced forgiveness. You remember the story of the woman that had sinned. The law was that she should be stoned to death. They brought her before the Savior to see how he would judge her. In <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.6-7" class="scriptureRef">John 8:6–7</a> it is recorded:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p23" guid="9754674f-023a-474d-b0a2-6d28ceab0f5e" pid="TI9W88gJ9EacW1h9TF8U1Q" hash="7i28zQ">“This they said, tempting him, that they might have to accuse him. But Jesus stooped down, and with his finger wrote on the ground, as though he heard them not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p24" guid="4bc7773a-8a92-4fe3-8d2d-d9ecd0217fe9" pid="URXN7HFPuEaZFfW6fSg20w" hash="47AfSQ">“So when they continued asking him, he lifted up himself, and said unto them, He that is without sin among you, let him first cast a stone at her.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p25" guid="59ce0afe-aeb4-4aef-a118-3035ad2608d2" pid="QspDN01HgEygz5xs0nFDUw" hash="QcTG1g">Not any in the group could qualify, and the crowd dispersed. He then turned to the woman and said: “Neither do I condemn thee: go, and sin no more.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.11" class="scriptureRef">John 8:11</a>.) He certainly did not approve of what she had done, but he demonstrated forgiveness and left it up to his Father in heaven to judge her.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p26" guid="0991f567-265e-44ca-bc88-64e804b33ceb" pid="VValC2B4Ck6Sa681xEdrQQ" hash="4Oa_JQ">He forgave those who would take his life. At the very time when he was suffering the most, he said: “Father, forgive them; for they know not what they do.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/23.34" class="scriptureRef">Luke 23:34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p27" guid="7e03b3fa-93a0-4ebd-90ca-4c1ff62b8068" pid="i6tg3I4BtUKAjwGfkRWnKw" hash="KEUsDA">The gospel he brought to earth and which was restored in this dispensation provides us with a beautiful plan of salvation. We know that we had a previous existence and were valiant there. The Lord permitted us to come to earth that we might <span class="emphasis">obtain a body, gain knowledge, develop our skills and our characters, learn to overcome evil, and see if we can remain true and faithful to him, </span>and be sufficiently diligent and obedient to the commandments as to be worthy to return and abide in his presence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p28" guid="33416e6b-6c63-4263-878e-8c387d1cb9f3" pid="xoxydIbsVkGjdMHNQ0WdMw" hash="b8WN3g">Many of our problems are blessings in disguise. They are provided so that we might gain the experiences intended for us on this earth and thus prepare us for meeting and solving problems in the next phase of our eternal existence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p29" guid="8a6b4594-afd3-4b83-86ac-e8cf83f094b4" pid="hYcMKs_PvU265I-vXJeOxg" hash="kZV_tA">Today, as I contemplate the many, many blessings that have been given us, I recall the words of King Benjamin in the Book of Mormon when, after enumerating the blessings which had been poured down upon his people by the Lord, he said this to them: “And behold, all that he requires of you is to keep his commandments.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.22" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2:22</a>.) Yes, the only thing the Lord requires of us is that we keep his commandments! This sounds relatively simple, doesn’t it? But we all know that it isn’t simple, nor was it intended to be. Where much is given, much is expected. The Lord requires of those who dwell with him the ability to overcome weaknesses and imperfections. He requires self-denial and self-discipline.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p30" guid="cefcb545-abff-4692-93f8-d0353ac04174" pid="q5aUR9IQSUe3l8erS5vnPg" hash="oojvXg">Some of us may feel from time to time that some of the Lord’s commandments are an impediment to happiness in this life, but this isn’t so; and deep down in our hearts we know that so long as we adhere to the commandments, just as surely as night follows day, we will reap the blessings that are promised to the faithful. Sometimes the way of fulfillment may not be apparent to us, but the actuality of it is assured. The Lord said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p31" guid="c632d203-eef1-4823-96a8-339a390bffd3" pid="-bIuyEQkNkqolJlQDmVzPw" hash="hbPFCQ">“I, the Lord, am bound when ye do what I say; but when ye do not what I say, ye have no promise.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/82.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 82:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p32" guid="656fb76f-7945-4651-b3d2-d921e9922509" pid="l8oh9a9y70m8E2ygKGXHVg" hash="FCOQuA">How many of us on judgment day would like to be told that we had failed to do our part—that we had been unworthy servants of the Lord because our own lives had been such a poor example in keeping the commandments?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p33" guid="9d98392d-9880-4874-bca7-cfe774e8c3ff" pid="SJj91rZBZUaoHM79M1l61A" hash="QwYb-Q">In <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.16" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:16</a> the Lord gives us a very important message:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p34" guid="cf0161f9-7436-482b-9a8e-3c1c7a03fe31" pid="NIbnv_92zk-YDs3oUgCixA" hash="nhqdWw">“Let your light so shine before men, that they may see your good works, and glorify your Father which is in heaven.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p35" guid="1c82ef70-ff8a-498f-8fdd-ec833790c858" pid="A8aAkEmJ6UWI82Jxpdrf4w" hash="_1C8lw">To fail to keep the commandments of the Lord not only brings condemnation, but actually deprives us of many blessings here on this earth—to say nothing of those eternal blessings for which we are all striving. In <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/2.9" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 2:9</a> we read this statement:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p36" guid="ed6e4816-392d-46c5-bc1a-2176272729cc" pid="K7wMchavjkq4HOBKtZ-fyg" hash="6ufZTQ">“Eye hath not seen, nor ear heard, neither have entered into the heart of man, the things which God hath prepared for them that love him.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p37" guid="aaef1ee6-e6af-46d8-ae98-184f992d3a81" pid="HOKgJVKZPkKUEU_xOHzSBg" hash="awvCfA">Think of that great promise. And finally, the wonderful promise given to all men:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p38" guid="e761138e-2d7c-41b1-90d9-56284b65214b" pid="U2oJxndzw026eIn20zgqZQ" hash="8RgrHQ">“And, if you keep my commandments and endure to the end you shall have eternal life, which gift is the greatest of the gifts of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/14.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 14:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p39" guid="d0dde2b7-e880-4dfc-b8d2-99ad1958234f" pid="ixKSC39LfUK1JL53-1HIXg" hash="ETQPLg">Our late President Heber J. Grant told us how to endure to the end when he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p40" guid="cf36ce87-bfe4-4231-8451-c20ff17d9c37" pid="ySIgCl3YQkuvb05yGrGI8w" hash="EbVCAg">“Let us do the will of our Father in heaven today—we will then be prepared for the duties of tomorrow and for the eternities to come.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p41" guid="21966354-c288-4d71-b461-bf4d3f75e92e" pid="Nerf1CQ610ejm3rBk_QhOA" hash="ylxGfA">Christ repeatedly emphasized the fact that the gospel is one of <span class="emphasis">work and service. </span>To gain blessings, we must be doers of the word and not hearers only. In <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.21" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 7:21</a> we read: “Not every one that saith unto me, Lord, Lord, shall enter into the kingdom of heaven; but he that doeth the will of my Father which is in heaven.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p42" guid="5f5f26be-5233-494c-8d87-667132f15dbd" pid="wDVQ8yKhNE6qEyAIw_DJEQ" hash="lG5WAA">This means if we are to gain salvation, exaltation, and eternal life we must live in accordance with the principles of the gospel. We must love and forgive all men and keep the commandments of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another.p43" guid="e4adf2b9-39d4-44b7-81d0-48ee20b2eb2b" pid="wrK5059u1kyRLW1LaTatGQ" hash="NGgJTA">I leave my testimony with you today that I know the true gospel of Jesus Christ has been restored in this dispensation, that Joseph Smith was an instrument in the hands of the Lord in bringing this about. He was and is a prophet of God. I testify that we are led today by a prophet, President Harold B. Lee. May we all give him and his associates our love and support, and pray continually that they may be blessed with health, strength, and inspiration to carry their tremendous responsibilities. May we have courage and determination to keep the commandments and live in accordance with the principles of the gospel, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1973/10/love-and-forgive-one-another</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1973-general-conference/1973-10-2050-elder-o-leslie-stone-64k-eng.mp3" length="5694281" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 1973 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Beatitudes</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We think of the Savior in the early part of his Ministry, high up in the hills overlooking the Sea of Galilee, where in company with his 12 disciples and a multitude of eager listeners, he gave his Sermon on the Mount. An important part of that sermo</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03050_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="BYcofw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="46AdJ5sHt0C99RKxzlxiIg" hash="i6GD0g">The Beatitudes</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="JKUtKh5myUKlaHOZYgbKwQ" hash="XDOjPg">O. Leslie Stone</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2898.jpg" alt="Elder O. Leslie Stone" pid="48qE3qp3jke3sVsS3eNG2g" hash="8ZrpPA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p1" pid="3CN6-SKw9ES2EVXMVdwVMQ" hash="BPI2kw">We think of the Savior in the early part of his Ministry, high up in the hills overlooking the Sea of Galilee, where in company with his 12 disciples and a multitude of eager listeners, he gave his Sermon on the Mount. An important part of that sermon is known as the Beatitudes. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.1-11" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:1–11</a>.) In the few moments assigned to me, I would like to discuss them briefly with you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p2" pid="hCjNN6f5gkOAMvvDaydDgg" hash="1QsSCA">The Beatitudes contain the heart of the Master’s teachings and show his spirit and way of life. It was his aim to teach his disciples and give them a better understanding of the gospel, because a real disciple of Christ should have a character made up of these traits.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p3" pid="tbUw66tFv0Chw7I7Bb4Y6w" hash="Zi8tLQ">Now, the first of the Beatitudes we find in Matthew 5, verse 3: “Blessed are the poor in spirit: for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.” [<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.3" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:3</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p4" pid="rD4cU1CsFUSi6OvTmrQoRA" hash="m8XmKQ">What is meant by “poor in spirit”? Is it not <span class="emphasis">humility,</span> which renders us teachable and eager to learn? They who feel themselves spiritually poor approach God, asking him to supply their needs. They who have faith in him, learn his laws and try diligently to obey him. They thus become eligible for the great blessings he has promised, including salvation, exaltation, and eternal life, which are the greatest of all the gifts of God. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/14.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 14:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p5" pid="GqOLa1Unu0Gx1_X2i_F_dA" hash="pB6iJw">“Blessed are they that mourn: for they shall be comforted.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.4" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p6" pid="JEzwLQhcfEyaaOwMPipozg" hash="cVSc1w">The mourner shall be comforted when he sees the divine purpose in his grief. The Lord has told us: “Come unto me, all ye that labour and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/11.28" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 11:28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p7" pid="qAh_8Q2k-0KWPF89WPn4XQ" hash="6x17_g">We should always remember the Lord intended that we should have problems to meet and solve as a part of our training in this life to help us prepare for the next phase of our eternal existence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p8" pid="70oTZEyjzkieRSkDfHGs5g" hash="QZq2xQ">An unknown author made this statement: “If all suffering and unhappiness could be removed from our lives, what kind of people would we be? I believe it would be impossible to produce strong, noble, generous, compassionate human beings if suffering were eliminated from their lives.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p9" pid="Ewmxt6NUGE2-4RH9PIwAYw" hash="o8vzqw">We must not allow ourselves to become embittered in times of mourning and sorrow. We must keep faith and seek comfort from the Lord through prayer. We have his promise that we shall be blessed. Those who are burdened shall be made happy when they learn the real comfort of the gospel through their faith and <span class="emphasis">through their works.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p10" pid="KebqJiU7L02MEg2N3al1jg" hash="vbeYbQ">“Blessed are the meek: for they shall inherit the earth.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.5" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p11" pid="TdpVGdlhQkGszYwB7Dbb1Q" hash="AVfkAQ">Meekness is a virtue that can be exercised toward both God and man. The meek are those who are gentle, kind, patient, tolerant; not proud, mighty, or conceited. In Proverbs we read, “He that is slow to anger is better than the mighty.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/16.32" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 16:32</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p12" pid="TnPurIh7xE-Tzu4FUKzDCA" hash="QG8Lhg">Meekness must not, however, be confused with self-depreciation. Because it involves self-control, it is not a weak, but a heroic quality. Our Savior at all times was willing to submit to the will of God. Even in his moment of agony, he could say, “Nevertheless not my will, but thine, be done.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/22.42" class="scriptureRef">Luke 22:42</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p13" pid="SQtlPo_R4ESgkX4OXkGHsA" hash="z5jMEQ">“Blessed are they which do hunger and thirst after righteousness: for they shall be filled.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.6" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p14" pid="aRl9F3xjR0OLWsKeS5Dfsw" hash="TITUNw">Those who seek after truth shall be fed in rich abundance. In our modern scripture, the Doctrine and Covenants, section 88, we find this promise: “Draw near unto me and I will draw near unto you; seek me diligently and ye shall find me; ask, and ye shall receive; knock, and it shall be opened unto you.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.63" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:63</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p15" pid="TcBiFL8sw0WqSGSMGWLGww" hash="DLl09A">We can prove our love of God by radiating righteousness. If we really hunger and thirst after righteousness, then it is our duty <span class="emphasis">to know</span> and <span class="emphasis">to do</span> the will of him who sent us here. By keeping his commandments, we will receive great blessings. Remember, the Lord has told us: “I, the Lord, am bound when ye do what I say; but when ye do not what I say, ye have no promise.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/82.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 82:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p16" pid="-KrdyXXr_Eirbi_fDbFewg" hash="n6Kk4g">“Blessed are the merciful: for they shall obtain mercy.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.7" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p17" pid="MaMQGi1Uq0aY1MbvvG3w_Q" hash="YwP69g">They that show mercy shall receive mercy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p18" pid="hcStClR3xkGvlQdLUqgZtA" hash="pHg3Qw">Someone made this compassionate statement: “There is no better exercise for the heart than to reach down and lift someone up.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p19" pid="syUuXBUhcU6xagypkOwNmg" hash="rj_K-Q">The Savior always showed forgiveness and mercy in every situation with which he was confronted. He taught, “Be ye therefore merciful, as your Father also is merciful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p20" pid="mNilEaoBqUOgZQWYR-BlMQ" hash="tHu4aQ">“Judge not, and ye shall not be judged: condemn not, and ye shall not be condemned: forgive, and ye shall be forgiven.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/6.36-37" class="scriptureRef">Luke 6:36–37</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p21" pid="rIk4zVF8WU2Zv-CZLx_fwQ" hash="2rjpiA">Even on the cross when he was near death, he said, “Father, forgive them; for they know not what they do.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/23.34" class="scriptureRef">Luke 23:34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p22" pid="3tASlaS-tUyhkHQOkKfGXQ" hash="GRtgMg">“Blessed are the pure in heart: for they shall see God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.8" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p23" pid="dyltZAvpB0ixQ-T7HEpq2A" hash="1v1H6Q">Christ tells us that purity of heart leads to love and knowledge of God. A love of God and of our fellow beings brings purity of character.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p24" pid="zzQ5w0EzdE-FOUh9M2XPtg" hash="B9r1RA">In Proverbs we read: “As [a man] thinketh in his heart, so is he.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/23.7" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 23:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p25" pid="agffS3gv1kGeb0X-nQCXeQ" hash="Pj7ppw">The Prophet Joseph said: “If you wish to go where God is, you must be like God, or possess the principles which God possesses, for if we are not drawing towards God in principle, we are going from him and drawing towards the devil. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p26" pid="PZxhA5bTKkGt1yoMA951yw" hash="1cj2Sg">“Search your hearts, and see if you are like God. I have searched mine, and I feel to repent of all my sins. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p27" pid="_v9SkaXbnEynvJEqWRv3lA" hash="iMqSRQ">“Is not God good? Then you be good; if He is faithful, then you be faithful. Add to your faith virtue, to virtue knowledge, and seek for every good thing.” (<span class="emphasis">History of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints,</span> 4:588.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p28" pid="i6IAx8R8J0-zY1fYdCdlNQ" hash="9Tu2kQ">He later said: “Be virtuous and pure; be men of integrity and truth; keep the commandments of God; and then you will be able to more perfectly understand the difference between right and wrong—between the things of God and the things of men; and your path will be like that of the just, which shineth brighter and brighter unto the perfect day.” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 5:31.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p29" pid="PWPp_nLjKUO-VVb5ojhMLA" hash="0VImOg">If we strive to be like God, then we will do all we possibly can to cast from our minds and actions all unholy and ungodly things, that our motives will be honorable and our hearts pure.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p30" pid="PeCxazO9O0e0kdfdlHJekA" hash="-RlxYg">“Blessed are the peacemakers: for they shall be called the children of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.9" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p31" pid="sac_eSq15kOfMmap4HrztQ" hash="6PDygQ">Peacemakers are those who try to save themselves and their fellows from strife. Our Heavenly Father delights in peace, and all who seek to bring about peace shall be like God in that respect and shall be called the children of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p32" pid="0e9-kKwUi0CD5ichcp0qUw" hash="5SVGeQ">Was not Christ the great peacemaker? He encouraged men to love and understand each other so that they could live together in peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p33" pid="memdX5SKB0Gxu7r3g5JfMw" hash="FwWV3w">The Lord has commanded us to love all men, including our enemies. He expects us to be peacemakers. He asks us to work out a reconciliation in a Christlike manner with those with whom we have difficulties or misunderstandings. It is his will that we should tolerate abuse rather than retaliate in a spirit of anger. It is better to turn the other cheek, to go the extra mile, to give our coat and our cloak also, than to offend.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p34" pid="uNXu4mdC_k28KnH1Obt1IA" hash="p7v83A">And the last of the Beatitudes: “Blessed are they which are persecuted for righteousness’ sake: for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.10" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p35" pid="NCCNrAsR6k2ZjaBt3kKDLg" hash="-Gb-bg">To the disciples of the Lord, the Lord spoke directly, saying:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p36" pid="3LNIuueL-U-7lP9r56MbPA" hash="JEcTeg">“Blessed are ye, when men shall revile you, and persecute you, and shall say all manner of evil against you falsely, for my sake.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p37" pid="1zbUFoclC02uVONHQEm8Ng" hash="dxg5nA">“Rejoice, and be exceeding glad: for great is your reward in heaven: for so persecuted they the prophets which were before you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.11-12" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:11–12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p38" pid="fIYNCGc-qkuJE2ui25_uFg" hash="FRwu5g">Today members of the Church do not often face persecution in the form of physical violence or harm, but perhaps some application can be made to the pressures we may feel from society, particularly the peer group pressures that our young people feel when they live up to the standards of dress and morality set by our present-day leaders. If these young people are prayerful and live the commandments, they will feel good about these high standards and will be able to stand up to criticism.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p39" pid="WG3MxUWUoUCFm_tN0QDKyA" hash="mE-w9g">Our youth should always remember that when they were baptized they took upon themselves the name of Jesus Christ; they can be proud to stand up for his principles and those of our present-day leaders. By so doing they will receive rich rewards in this life and in the eternities to come, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p40" pid="qAQzakj9MUC1FvFfU1preg" hash="a0vSRQ">Whenever we live up to the best that is in us, we live up to the principles and the ideals the Savior gave us. To follow him brings peace to the soul.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p41" pid="LSFHzRRAC0u6bk7mh7mabQ" hash="twDlww">On one occasion Christ said, “If ye love me, keep my commandments.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.15" class="scriptureRef">John 14:15</a>.) How long? For a day? Should we keep the commandments of the Lord for a week? Should we observe and do his will for a month or a year? To my knowledge, there is no promise to any individual that he shall receive the reward of the just, <span class="emphasis">unless he is faithful to the end.</span> If we fully understand and faithfully carry out in our lives the principles that Jesus taught, we shall be prepared to go back and dwell in the presence of the Father and the Son.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p42" pid="bvRHI7BwckeHqECiatjKBw" hash="Yc0iaA">We are most happy when we conform to the teachings Christ gave us. They should be the signals along the road we should follow. In these troubled times we need all the help we can get. It is available to us if we do our part. Great blessings are in store for us if we follow the teachings of our Lord and Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p43" pid="1TUp1m0xwkyJCQxPY2hldA" hash="iMU4nw">In establishing goals and charting our future course, let us remember the teachings found in the Beatitudes and the commandments the Lord has given us to live by.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes.p44" pid="LQD_CRCVoUyAmaVQxqzueg" hash="p-4SAQ">May his blessings be with all of us, according to our needs, is my prayer in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/10/the-beatitudes</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1974-general-conference/1974-10-2060-elder-o-leslie-stone-64k-eng.mp3" length="5433431" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 1974 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testimony</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/04/testimony?lang=eng</link>
      <description>To a Latter-day Saint, a testimony of the truthfulness of the restored gospel is the most precious possession he can have. It cannot be purchased. No one can give it to him. It can only be secured by prayer, by study, by faith, by repentance, by righ</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03057_000_004" doc-version="2" hash="OE8fCQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="nM-BYP6EWUim0OuBgrk8Ww" hash="w8s8fg">Testimony</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="x9Ch_wBC6kmhv_I3stu0Uw" hash="XDOjPg">O. Leslie Stone</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2898.jpg" alt="Elder O. Leslie Stone" pid="d4zyRUgztEqjATV7E9f_Rg" hash="8ZrpPA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p1" pid="GZG8XMKLWUeKeycQYdVgqg" hash="58UWQg">To a Latter-day Saint, a testimony of the truthfulness of the restored gospel is the most precious possession he can have. It cannot be purchased. No one can give it to him. It can only be secured by prayer, by study, by faith, by repentance, by righteous living, and by listening to others bearing their testimonies, and through the manifestation of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p2" pid="2W-GTpm1ikS_aPFo-Svbcg" hash="s1V_BQ">If we have a testimony of the gospel, we know that Jesus is the Christ, the Son of the living God, and our Redeemer. We know that Joseph Smith was and is a prophet of God. We know that the Book of Mormon is true, that it is indeed a second witness of our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ. A testimony of the truthfulness of the gospel is the motivating force that helps us live the commandments and carry out our responsibilities.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.f2">
	<p pid="Y_IhR6kSKU-mVwhIYd5Ibg" hash="FDYyFQ">Every member of the Church who has a testimony can be an effective missionary in sharing the gospel with nonmember friends, neighbors, and associates. You might ask, “How?” Here are a few suggestions:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="XZJsr5IF7UKAtqsrZW4gWg" hash="zAuH5w">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="uPNaM-SC-0WYvVsS2nMbTw" hash="ZB-oEQ">Live the principles of the gospel. Keep the commandments.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="l3RImuet8keEFEZBBJKrKA" hash="cleB7g">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="7lELwm-mXEe9Eii-S7dW1w" hash="Glsj7Q">Be honest and upright in all your dealings. Let your word always be as good as your bond.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="lLyIrjIlCEmvUwIpbgsBVQ" hash="q-Vmyw">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="RHxA8xhKTUWHsc1oqRlv6w" hash="gv8Y3w">Show love and appreciation by your attitude and by your works.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="cBV60ddGDUiC0bcEUeE7Iw" hash="7IXdCA">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="jO38X-fGDUK0bSiADaPK2A" hash="jiYaOw">Be friendly and both willing and anxious to share the great blessings of the gospel.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="RSi59jUNn0q_nxg5LfNCQA" hash="WYjzyw">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p pid="CSD8Hx3ojku-bOEFMuXZrw" hash="P-jiDg">Bear your testimony of the truthfulness of the gospel.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Yv5RpUGmOEmXhfxLyasK5w" hash="ttN91Q">
          <span class="label">6.</span>
          <p pid="3s8s2mGar0CwQRiKs2XzqA" hash="YhWGzQ">Beautify your home and other properties, as our prophet has just mentioned to you.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="jVEpkJ3pOUu2ncoJNdEqxw" hash="btQtgA">
          <span class="label">7.</span>
          <p pid="UvEmPKejrE6BWYyQN12k6w" hash="OiBORw">See that your dress and grooming conform to Church standards.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="asrDPpsaBUixIjvnxQop6A" hash="xaU7kA">
          <span class="label">8.</span>
          <p pid="9oWMdEi4oEmrvdbS_PDTSQ" hash="_xvVjQ">Follow the admonition of the Savior recorded in <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.16" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:16</a>, which embraces all of these things: “Let your light so shine before men, that they may see your good works, and glorify your Father which is in heaven.”</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p3" pid="9BOBDWbN-UOc3LpN1Mf-UA" hash="jQmUJQ">I frequently have the privilege of associating with the members of the First Presidency and the Council of the Twelve and with the other General Authorities. I hear them bear their testimonies of these great truths. They have had a strong influence in my life and in the lives of the members of my family. During the years I was a stake president in California, nearly all of the General Authorities visited our stake. They stayed with us in our home. They ate with us. They prayed with us. I have continually been strengthened to see their devotion, to feel of their spirit. It is inspiring to hear them bear testimony that God lives, that we are his children created in his own image, and that if we keep his commandments and are valiant in his cause, we can obtain salvation, exaltation, and eternal life, which are the greatest of all the gifts of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p4" pid="P7voZfr7kE-zLPvc9qQ8-w" hash="lkbJxw">You might ask, “How did these men get their testimonies?” Like all of us, they developed their testimonies through study, through prayer, through service, through keeping the commandments, and through the power of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p5" pid="yhk0CvxlJUGstCYCDKjuTg" hash="xPbw6A">Admittedly, it is easier to talk about a testimony than to obtain one. The Lord intended that we should work hard to obtain a testimony, for that will make our testimonies stronger, and they will be more apt to remain with us. Always remember that no good thing comes without effort and sacrifice. When we are required to work for these blessings, we gain knowledge, we develop our skills and our characters, and we learn to overcome evil—all of which are significant parts of our purpose in life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p6" pid="029Try5nzEyQrSaS3RURog" hash="XzHxLg">To any of you—either here or at home—who do not have a testimony or who would like to strengthen your testimony, I would recommend a few things that you can do to develop or strengthen a testimony.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.f3">
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="dvj-ime6AU24H9HCd5uJ5w" hash="OGKk2A">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="iSbnJQeNoky6639WrxZYkA" hash="9ReLCg">Study the scriptures and other books written by Church leaders.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="yLJItK5VAkGUmm_6YC7tXw" hash="SYgYIg">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="5DlosZZiHk62h8PCSUfICA" hash="6PU71g">Keep the commandments, which include loving thy neighbor as thyself, being honest and upright, paying a full tithing, and keeping morally clean.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="S0JMI_-tEkeyeJ5F7XoTyw" hash="FRYruw">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="lDmUsD0xn0qmx6zh6QlMCg" hash="h7eOTQ">Attend sacrament meeting and other Church meetings, in which you can listen to the testimonies of the faithful members of the Church.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="mkhC4Vlc0ESBGyDEubrT4w" hash="2VZFEQ">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="V07dHAUlz0-a9kVKIPSOwg" hash="yC0HzQ">Associate with good people.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="RgdPR050JkWeKyOWPkNBzQ" hash="ZdVHlQ">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p pid="PFK_OX2RRUOUMth_HwsJfQ" hash="J6IktA">Stay out of the devil’s territory by shunning evil.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="ADy-cZSCCECPc6tQuiDDGg" hash="g8_Ffg">
          <span class="label">6.</span>
          <p pid="6eQvtO-VeUaTKkRYOBn28w" hash="SSRG4Q">Repent of all sins and imperfections, and repentance includes both confession and forsaking of such sins.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="cfGFkmoi8Ui2BXHTQnRfPQ" hash="lB7uGA">
          <span class="label">7.</span>
          <p pid="NPGgmLgHIEeDEhm0W4RC1Q" hash="Uo9DBg">Pray to the Lord.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p7" pid="125z3RJh5EGk6ZtX2nw6bw" hash="Dh_4rw">In explaining how to gain a testimony of the Book of Mormon, Moroni taught these same principles. These are recorded in Moroni 10:4 [<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.4" class="scriptureRef">Moro 10:4</a>], which are valuable in gaining a testimony of any part of the gospel:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p8" pid="QAsOylcYPEqzjAa4LMP0xg" hash="-00-mQ">“And when ye shall receive these things, I would exhort you that ye would ask God, the Eternal Father, in the name of Christ, if these things are not true; and if ye shall ask with a sincere heart, with real intent, having faith in Christ, he will manifest the truth of it unto you, by the power of the Holy Ghost.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p9" pid="O-jWNFIvKkKMzjnNvmpDPQ" hash="8nNJ4Q">As we seek to develop and strengthen these testimonies, we must always rely on the Lord and place our highest priority on spiritual values. We must not forget, however, that a testimony does not, in and of itself, guarantee that we will inherit the celestial kingdom. We might know the gospel is true, but unless we are valiant, live righteous lives, and work to build the kingdom here on earth, we will not inherit celestial glory. In the epistle of James this principle is clearly taught: “Yea, a man may say, Thou hast faith, and I have works: shew me thy faith without thy works, and I will shew thee my faith by my works. … But wilt thou know, O vain man, that faith without works is dead?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/2.18,20" class="scriptureRef">James 2:18, 20</a>.) Plainly, we must have both faith and works to obtain all of the blessings we seek.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p10" pid="FoJJytzyYEaoUPo38XiJqA" hash="7NOdPg">President Kimball has said that the price we pay for happiness is keeping the commandments. The greatest blessings of this life, together with eternal salvation and exaltation, are available to us only when we keep the commandments the Lord has given us. Remember, the Lord has told us, “I, the Lord, am bound when ye do what I say; but when ye do not what I say, ye have no promise.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/82.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 82:10</a>.) And remember also the great promise recorded in the Doctrine and Covenants: “If you keep my commandments and endure to the end you shall have eternal life, which gift is the greatest of all the gifts of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/14.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 14:7</a>.) Now, if you want to be happy and to be good parents, I admonish you to keep the commandments and make every effort to secure and retain a strong testimony of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p11" pid="nSFcVp5eGkGzUy-1injG4g" hash="1-6Adg">Once we have developed and obtained a testimony, we can never cease working to strengthen it. We would all do well to remember the statement of President Harold B. Lee concerning a testimony. He said, “Testimony isn’t something you have today, and you are going to have always. A testimony is fragile. It is as hard to hold as a moonbeam. It is something you have to recapture every day of your life.” (<span class="emphasis">Church News,</span> 15 July 1972, p. 4.) We must continue to study, to pray, to obey the commandments, so that the Holy Ghost will continue to strengthen our testimony. When a testimony is not growing, it is in danger of becoming weaker.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p12" pid="XmwwSdhbrEenZ3k_bb2Uvg" hash="bAAL0A">Moreover, we need to be concerned not only with strengthening our own testimonies, but also with supporting those around us. One of the greatest of such responsibilities is that of parents. Parents need to exemplify the principles of the gospel in their own lives, and they need to teach those principles to their children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p13" pid="M_p9lpvArk2IhpwGQU-YHw" hash="FJf1lw">Throughout the ages, strong men have borne their testimonies to strengthen us. One of the greatest testimonies of the Savior was borne by Joseph Smith and Sidney Rigdon when they wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p14" pid="AFkq-Y36WUyOKVJbj2dLOA" hash="DkHgJQ">“And now, after the many testimonies which have been given of him, this is the testimony, last of all, which we give of him: That he lives!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p15" pid="DpK3fyX96EWehhzDY99pHg" hash="E7qA3w">“For we saw him, even on the right hand of God; and we heard the voice bearing record that he is the Only Begotten of the Father—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p16" pid="xIuUwNWy4UuIdzjm17wfBQ" hash="HuUMpw">“That by him, and through him, and of him, the worlds are and were created, and the inhabitants thereof are begotten sons and daughters unto God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.22-24" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:22–24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p17" pid="NIkntQvqw0GbYoxlhS0z8w" hash="a2wPjA">I am sure we all subscribe wholeheartedly to the testimony President Spencer W. Kimball gave at October conference last year when he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p18" pid="VRcfuw6lx0-SnW39ko0hGA" hash="e3SZyg">“I know that Jesus is the Christ, the Son of the living God. I know that. I know that the gospel which we teach is the gospel of Jesus Christ and the church to which we belong is the church of Jesus Christ; it teaches his doctrines and his policies and his programs. I know that if all of us will live the program as he has given it and will continue to give it, that all the blessings promised will be ours.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1974, p. 113.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/testimony.p19" pid="Zl2aa09DcUi7WbWzTeDbSA" hash="u6EE_A">Now, in conclusion, brothers and sisters, I would like to bear my testimony: I know that the gospel of Jesus Christ has been restored in its fulness, that President Spencer W. Kimball is a prophet of God, that he receives revelation from God which makes it possible for him to guide our efforts in establishing the kingdom throughout the world. I love and support all the members of the First Presidency and of the Council of the Twelve and all the other General Authorities. It is an honor and a privilege to be associated with such men. I hope to be found worthy in carrying out my assignments and responsibilities. I pray that all of us will be successful in building strong testimonies of the restored gospel, and then by prayer, faith, study, work, and by righteous living keep such testimonies aglow and vibrant every day of our lives. In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/04/testimony</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1975-general-conference/1975-04-1020-elder-o-leslie-stone-64k-eng.mp3" length="5411947" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 1975 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Reputation</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brethren and sisters, the subject I have chosen to speak about this morning is the value of a good reputation.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03063_000_018" doc-version="3" hash="WsSraw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="9AB1PtbQe0iDY3dRtwya2w" hash="jAcDig">The Importance of Reputation</h1><p class="authorName" pid="AmCUrTiA5kO45n10VGLoOw" hash="XDOjPg">O. Leslie Stone</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2898.jpg" alt="Elder O. Leslie Stone" pid="uI5fLlVxWUGfbMDOYwnU5Q" hash="8ZrpPA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p1" pid="RE-D75OLdEqr9yuJehXpEw" hash="p-GiUQ">My dear brethren and sisters, the subject I have chosen to speak about this morning is the value of a good reputation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p2" pid="pWHvPwh3uUm3SDnTLEQygg" hash="1BkROw">From this pulpit we’ve heard many great messages emphasizing the importance of living the gospel and improving our lives. If you were asked the question, “Why is it important to keep the commandments and live the teachings of Christ?” what would your answer be?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p3" pid="dCkJtViRtUeSQ2v5GfVOKg" hash="e32rrA">Perhaps many of us would say, “To gain eternal life.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p4" pid="kdhCq70yMUuYMBPRWD2NiQ" hash="dYKrMw">That’s right, to gain eternal life. But for whom? For ourselves? Yes, that’s part of it. But Christ taught, “For whosoever will save his life shall lose it; but whosoever shall lose his life for my sake and the gospel’s, the same shall save it.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/8.35" class="scriptureRef">Mark 8:35</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p5" pid="x94Sj41O50O4JJ2zwmpxMA" hash="VJDurg">We should focus, not on serving ourselves, but on serving our fellowmen, thereby losing ourselves in the service of our Heavenly Father, his work and his glory. In order to be most effective in our service, we need to put our own lives in order. Then, as we live the gospel, our lives will reflect righteousness and virtue, and we will be a powerful influence for good in the lives of others. This is why it is not enough to be righteous for the sake of our <span class="emphasis">own</span> salvation. We must let our goodness radiate to <span class="emphasis">others,</span> that through our example and reputation they will lift their lives and have the desire to follow the Savior’s pattern of living.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p6" pid="N0BABLoBd0mTiqGCC_ozfQ" hash="FcsuPg">As we go about our daily activities, we’re often being judged by our fellowmen. Some of these judgments may be just, and some may be unjust. We can’t always control what others think of us, or how others judge us, but we can control the kinds of messages we send out through our behavior. We should do all we can to establish for ourselves a worthy reputation, for such is of priceless worth. It is often the key to influencing others for good, and can be the means of bringing the gospel into their lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p7" pid="6PWi2jNgjE-RLtkF7f1-8g" hash="4pF7hw">The importance of what a good reputation means was emphasized to me when I entered into business many years ago with a great business leader. Our plans were to start a new wholesale business. He was to furnish the capital, and I was to furnish the management. After we reached an understanding he wrote me a check for a very large amount of money, and then he said, “If the business is a success, you will get all the credit; and if the business fails, you will likewise get all the credit.” He then went on to say, “Should the business fail, you will lose more than I will. I’ll only lose money, and I have more of that; but you will lose your reputation, which is much more valuable than money.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p8" pid="-KKSRF-iEEaV3WCxwaTRqQ" hash="bzc9cg">I will never forget the value this highly successful businessman placed on reputation. Fortunately for both of us, the business was successful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p9" pid="OMBt6GKH90iALncWfWZbNw" hash="nNot6A">I prefer not to think of reputation as a superficial facade, attempting to indicate depth where there is only shallowness, honesty where there is deceit, or virtue where there is unrighteousness. Rather, I like to think of reputation as a window, clearly exhibiting the integrity of one’s soul. It is through this integrity of thought and integrity of conduct that we become pure and holy before the Lord. It is in this state that we can be most effective in serving our fellowmen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p10" pid="2cOh5d8wKU2_WwDMaHJ4PQ" hash="gsdq9g">Christ taught us to be <span class="emphasis">other-centered.</span> It is not enough for us to live the gospel inwardly; we need to be shining examples to all with whom we come in contact. In this sense, it’s not only what we <span class="emphasis">are</span> that’s important: what others think of us is <span class="emphasis">also</span> important. In order to be truly effective as missionaries, we need to be known for our good qualities, to have an unspotted reputation in all things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p11" pid="kYzFIPm_9Um8f_SUTChMPg" hash="H9CNSQ">I would like, for example, to be known for my dependability—for being honest and upright in all my dealings. I would like to be known as a man who meets his financial obligations on due date or prior thereto, a man whose word is as good as his bond. I would like to be known as one who is trustworthy and as one whose loyalty is unquestionable. I would like to be known as one who keeps the commandments and one who is fully committed in helping to build the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p12" pid="kk5paQbTZkCZF64fb6fcXQ" hash="iGiATQ">Sometimes we hear a comment like, “What does it matter what I do? It’s my life, and I can do what I want with it.” It may be true that we are the ones most affected by our own actions. But in this life, no man is an island; every mortal’s life is intertwined with others’ lives. It is not possible for a person to represent <span class="emphasis">only</span> himself. <span class="emphasis">Every</span> individual represents certain other people or groups of people as well. For example, we are all representatives of our own families, and the reputation of a family is established through the actions of individual family members.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p13" pid="tHJP4xW0Q0a-gwAMRJaIWw" hash="yJe66Q">President George Albert Smith told the story of a time when he was seriously ill and had traveled to St. George, Utah, to see if it would improve his health. He became so weak that he could scarcely move. In his account he recalled: “One day, under these conditions, I lost consciousness of my surroundings and thought I had passed to the Other Side. I found myself standing with my back to a large and beautiful lake, facing a great forest of trees. … I realized, or seemed to realize, that I had finished my work in mortality and had gone home. I began to look around, to see if I could not find someone. There was no evidence of anyone living there, just those great, beautiful trees in front of me and the wonderful lake behind me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p14" pid="Vl9NsubtGkeMFSrYnK9M0g" hash="JgTqEg">“I began to explore, and soon I found a trail through the woods which seemed to have been used very little, and which was almost obscured by grass. I followed this trail, and after I had walked for some time and had traveled a considerable distance through the forest, I saw a man coming towards me. I became aware that he was a very large man, and I hurried my steps to reach him, because I recognized him as my grandfather. … I remember how happy I was to see him coming. I had been given his name and had always been proud of it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p15" pid="qP7bkrs910mgxlOhGAFRmQ" hash="rKH-bA">“When Grandfather came within a few feet of me, he stopped. His stopping was an invitation for me to stop. Then—and this I would like the boys and girls and young people never to forget—he looked at me very earnestly and said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p16" pid="IyA2aIKjZEuHwzVqU7Bvrw" hash="uLJrig">“‘I would like to know what you have done with my name.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p17" pid="PZiTi70Ck0Ka_Vbk586u1A" hash="fhQNmg">“Everything I had ever done passed before me as though it were a flying picture on a screen—everything I had done. Quickly this vivid retrospect came down to the very time I was standing there. My whole life had passed before me. I smiled and looked at my grandfather and said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p18" pid="tkTmD8qS7kibgyknFdiFWg" hash="lKGirw">“‘I have never done anything with your name of which you need be ashamed.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p19" pid="RlcNnXljEUKX8Gk4rakmZA" hash="_tiKWw">“He stepped forward and took me in his arms, and as he did so, I became conscious again of my earthly surroundings. My pillow was as wet as though water had been poured on it—wet with tears of gratitude that I could answer unashamed.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p20" pid="-3jAUd9iykeAUHHozQFW4w" hash="ehbeog">President Smith continued to say, “I have thought of this many times, and I want to tell you that I have been trying, more than ever since that time, to take care of that name. So I want to say to the boys and girls, to the young men and women, to the youth of the Church and of all the world: Honor your fathers and your mothers. Honor the names that you bear, because some day you will have the privilege and the obligation of reporting to them (and to your Father in heaven) what you have done with their name.” (George Albert Smith, <span class="emphasis">Sharing the Gospel with Others,</span> Deseret Book Company, 1948, pp. 111–12.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p21" pid="b__dBjBdxkuUn0jtpi9C1g" hash="XPqpgA">Not only do we represent our families, but each of us belongs to a community, state, province, or nation whose collective reputation is based on the actions of individuals. Many of us represent the business or organization from which we earn our living. Students represent the schools which they attend. As members of the Church we all represent the Church through our actions. What is our message?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p22" pid="d7KszCwEoUSNaxWZz9h1zQ" hash="i-e3Cg">We have a special sacred responsibility. When we are baptized, we take upon ourselves the name of Christ. Each week as we partake of the sacrament, we renew this covenant with our Heavenly Father, to take upon ourselves the name of his Son, to always remember him and keep his commandments, that we might always have his Spirit to be with us. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.77" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:77</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p23" pid="LHzmbiSfpU6mKLScBrJqDg" hash="apIW5Q">Through baptism we become members of Christ’s family. We bear his name. We represent him here on earth as holders of his priesthood and as members of his kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p24" pid="utTvKkWFW06C8px5-gYMRA" hash="Kx4ENw">We have the privilege to represent him to others, to bear his message to his children throughout the world, to be missionaries. We have the responsibility to be worthy of his name, to represent him well in every way, to every person we meet—to so live that our lives are Christian sermons in operation. For Christ has said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p25" pid="87RWAttLZ0ilBxwCMDbP4A" hash="UUOWCg">“Ye are the light of the world. A city that is set on an hill cannot be hid.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p26" pid="MT_zrcpAd0q_5gBiifphfA" hash="r1g2lQ">“Neither do men light a candle, and put it under a bushel, but on a candlestick; and it giveth light unto all that are in the house.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p27" pid="lQhxrVJeSUWodARPw6WTeg" hash="5DPUGQ">“Let your light so shine before men, that they may see your good works, and glorify your Father which is in heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.14-16" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:14–16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p28" pid="L97a4x_duk2k3RgTGWZnlQ" hash="TVRQ9g">As we build our character, our light will shine brighter, and our outward reputation will become but a reflection of our inward self; then will our reputation be one, both before God and before our fellowmen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p29" pid="nloer1145E2nf2qkSz_8YA" hash="lWMFFA">I know through many years of experience in both Church and business affairs that it is highly important to maintain a good and worthy reputation in all that we do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p30" pid="rbXelPPYtUqGG3YLPlsBKA" hash="P3APqg">I testify that in order to obtain real joy and happiness in this life and be effective servants of the Lord in helping to build his kingdom, we must build and retain a good reputation. This can only be accomplished by repenting of our sins and living the principles of the gospel, thereby keeping the commandments of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation.p31" pid="aSXpFfj1O0GOYuBupIzCTw" hash="0c2f7w">May we all do this, I humbly pray, in the name of our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/10/the-importance-of-reputation</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1975-general-conference/1975-10-3030-elder-o-leslie-stone-64k-eng.mp3" length="11351220" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1975 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parenthood</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters and friends, during the few moments assigned to me, I would like to talk about the responsibilities of parents in the rearing of their children.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03076_000_027" doc-version="3" hash="m644AA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="jstxgrtry0i6wD55Pmg9gw" hash="8ZPy0w">Parenthood</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="MUx4LiKyNU6AVd3FkVHLgA" hash="XDOjPg">O. Leslie Stone</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2898.jpg" alt="Elder O. Leslie Stone" pid="NPQJi7L9CUiE7GZ8U0bdWQ" hash="8ZrpPA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p1" pid="GzN9nErSW0qCs6_4lKBYqQ" hash="bSs6nA">My dear brothers and sisters and friends, during the few moments assigned to me, I would like to talk about the responsibilities of parents in the rearing of their children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p2" pid="eFITOEsZ3kyt1oP6-QUKZA" hash="nsv6UA">To begin I would like to quote President David O. McKay as he had this to say about the responsibility of parents:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p3" pid="DPeuWChC9kKPATgmM2dMFw" hash="6_f6nw">“It is said that ‘to be trusted is a greater compliment than to be loved.’ The greatest trust that can come to a man and woman is the placing in their keeping the life of a little child.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p4" pid="K3f6pjiFp0maUhuwkx5fWg" hash="mL54RQ">“If a man defaults who is entrusted with other people’s funds—whether he be a bank, municipal, or state official—he is apprehended and probably sent to prison. If a person entrusted with a government secret discloses that secret and betrays his country, he is called a traitor.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p5" pid="-Zm0hGc_LEaqOOCjaBTXuw" hash="2FyZdA">“What must the Lord think, then, of parents who, through their own negligence or wilful desire to indulge their selfishness fail properly to rear their children, and thereby prove untrue to the greatest trust that has been given to human beings?” (<span class="emphasis">Treasures of Life,</span> Deseret Book Company, 1965, p. 71.)</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.f2">
	<p pid="g9sFRx45vES9qhzyOMu5ew" hash="Ny9d-Q">And then he said that among delinquent parents are these:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="Tu4sEx_MEEuyyraUCaQ5bw" hash="vzXlbQ">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="U6adIlbaREOGK0oet-bZKg" hash="6JXVrg">Those who quarrel in the presence of their children;</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="xvXox4Q15Ee9AwdADlpFbw" hash="30kFsQ">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="weICB1qrlEShSFR76MR6ew" hash="IUeAqg">Those who pollute the home atmosphere with vulgarity and profanity;</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="ztyOFVyOM06ZDKx-dO1Arg" hash="kq2BtA">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="vVdbgLx4a0i758J68Ip4ww" hash="50jK3w">Those whose daily home life does not conform to their Church pretensions;</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Wtel75lGbkG4Mcyaep3hRg" hash="d6LvVA">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="VyPiyKaGkUOAykqzcNOnQQ" hash="Yd15iQ">Those who fail to teach obedience to their children;</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="RXEF2HWhsUCx_HEWWpNtjQ" hash="6rzBEQ">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p pid="vtEX8Kxug0ePWhiJCI4G4Q" hash="45vE-Q">Those who neglect to teach their children religion by saying, “Let them grow up and choose for themselves,” thus failing in the discharge of a parental responsibility. (See <span class="emphasis">Treasures of Life,</span> pp. 72–74.)</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p6" pid="31rt9dReAESUOhX3ywafnw" hash="WIruTw">He then asks a question and makes a suggestion: “Parents, how do you measure up? Take a personal inventory and see if you are fulfilling your sacred obligations.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p7" pid="BJyeX8fwUk-HByei744lFg" hash="CZMNZA">This statement in the Doctrine and Covenants makes clear our responsibility in teaching our children the fundamentals of the gospel:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p8" pid="5crvMlmgOE6sMm4YfA6WFQ" hash="l-fjvQ">“Inasmuch as parents have children … , that teach them not to understand the doctrine of repentance, faith in Christ the Son of the living God, and of baptism and the gift of the Holy Ghost by the laying on of the hands, when eight years old, the sin be upon the heads of the parents.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p9" pid="OS_a3Rk9m0OC03ar4OZoSQ" hash="TcYM5g">“For this shall be a law unto the inhabitants of Zion.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.25-26" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:25–26</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p10" pid="sin_DAXwQEOqwNcxvhY3OQ" hash="9ugCZw">Note that this does not say the sin be upon the head of the Sunday School, the Primary, or the seminary teacher, <span class="emphasis">but upon the heads of the parents.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p11" pid="a-p0CH-DWE2jTEZj7XV0NQ" hash="MH722A">In speaking on this subject, on one occasion, Elder A. Theodore Tuttle made this significant statement:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p12" pid="yNg0ycmX90Od7czGQhD6ZA" hash="ceEmhQ">“Parental responsibility cannot go unheeded, nor can it be shifted to day-care centers, nor to the schoolroom, nor even to the Church. Family responsibility comes by divine decree. Parents may violate this decree only at the peril of their eternal salvation.” (“Altar, Tent, Well,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Jan. 1973, p. 67.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p13" pid="pPsV1M_0zk6COOycD7XNeg" hash="7fmBNw">Thus it is made clear to all of us that it is the solemn obligation of every Latter-day Saint parent to do everything within his or her power to instill in his or her children a knowledge of the gospel and the true purpose of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p14" pid="SWJ4uvX9KkCp1X8Av-2xSQ" hash="Eti7VQ">Of course, to do this we must be converted ourselves. If we wish our children to be Latter-day Saints, then we must <span class="emphasis">be</span> Latter-day Saints. President Hugh B. Brown once said, “[we] cannot effectively teach [what we do] not profoundly believe. … Our lives and our teachings must not be at variance.” (<span class="emphasis">Eternal Quest,</span> Bookcraft, 1956, pp. 179, 181.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p15" pid="MFFrwE-3Akm-G8XkAlcFAQ" hash="0-kYkw">Young parents, prepare yourselves that your children may be properly taught in the ways of the Lord. Teach them faith in the living God. Teach them to pray always, and teach them to keep the laws and commandments the Lord has given us to live by.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p16" pid="p0O8uAx_t0uHo5u8CjWiPA" hash="I2_R_g">On another occasion President Brown said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p17" pid="aH_6Z94vjkCCFFI8EF8Rdg" hash="JKiFrA">“In this age of selfishness and greed, of birth control and barrenness, of easy divorce, broken homes, and juvenile delinquency, in this age of cheap amusements, idleness and lack of discipline, it is well to search for basic values, to call attention to the fact that the home is the nation’s most fundamental institution and that mothers are the first professors in that character-building school.” (<span class="emphasis">Vision and Valor,</span> Bookcraft, 1971, p. 24.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p18" pid="fsWc6zK2VkOvin03G40s0w" hash="SXWVXg">The home is where we learn what is right, what is good, and what is kind. It is the first school and the first church. The best way to prepare a child for a happy and righteous adult life is to strengthen him during his child life. And happy is the family where this most important trust—that of properly raising the children of that family—is their greatest concern.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p19" pid="yqlp6mqtqUuwYBSjYpR0Hg" hash="l4Jsxg">Equal to the responsibility we have to provide food and shelter and the necessities of life is the responsibility to set the right example for our children in all that we do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p20" pid="ndUVVuW3NkmL6ugGHcAUvg" hash="QYeZQQ">Let us remember that the parent in the home influences the behavior patterns, the habits, the opinions, and the beliefs of the children. Most behavior patterns are established early in life, and it is an extremely difficult, slow task to change them later in life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p21" pid="3rvg66OqO0CMpNem95AVFg" hash="06Kp-Q">There is a great message for parents in the rearing of their children in the song written by Sister Naomi Randall entitled “I Am a Child of God.” I think it is one of the greatest songs we have in the Church. We hear it sung all over the world as we visit the children in the Junior Sunday Schools. I would like to quote the lyrics of this song:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.f3">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="XrFd2usdXEeXptAArhCDWw" hash="Sxrctg">
            <span class="emphasis">I am a child of God,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="nsIsuCTAz0eCTHmWUEYeXw" hash="A_i8KQ">
            <span class="emphasis">And he has sent me here,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="MaQTAfjTr0GIT_aBw5BBRQ" hash="Iy8x2A">
            <span class="emphasis">Has given me an earthly home</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="30sSie4DEku4SVbE0GSOWQ" hash="-jZOWw">
            <span class="emphasis">With parents kind and dear.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="XP1vmK-KwEak_kUlUcBVEw" hash="Sxrctg1">
            <span class="emphasis">I am a child of God,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="rZHGIhJVCUiFCTWHLF2Tng" hash="trRcsw">
            <span class="emphasis">And so my needs are great;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="o41PjRGFD0CP8q8qLlf4lA" hash="Y8zvPw">
            <span class="emphasis">Help me to understand his words</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="CUhzzmzH9Uy-wUPzHZxzpA" hash="qg4zmQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Before it grows too late.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="MDv55122tUu1adddG9xDzQ" hash="Sxrctg2">
            <span class="emphasis">I am a child of God,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="sDPIL6ANZUCOVAyC5l57-Q" hash="W0h_qg">
            <span class="emphasis">Rich blessings are in store;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="ZHNP5vuqL0C_-KuXm-ucBQ" hash="Z4i56Q">
            <span class="emphasis">If I but learn to do his will</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="MeVVxJhDqkyKKshCCqL5GQ" hash="otK5WA">
            <span class="emphasis">I’ll live with him once more.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="pS-2hA6MWEKu6aifrhrv6w" hash="-on1eA">
            <span class="emphasis">Lead me, guide me, walk beside me,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="s6tnoHu_REq-4FjNhUV4Eg" hash="wkwinw">
            <span class="emphasis">Help me find the way.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="_TXPm1MVTkmp7VvRZwLsSA" hash="bt_CJw">
            <span class="emphasis">Teach me all that I must do</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Id1pbpoCm0KdRxupYyStmg" hash="wPuYEw">
            <span class="emphasis">To live with him someday.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p22" pid="OOZJ-O0mN0u6ZiyabbEOTA" hash="p39IMg">Now, as a child grows he becomes more independent. Sometimes teenagers are accused of feeling they have outgrown the need for parents, but, of course, this is a time in life when they need their parents more than ever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p23" pid="p_g3PaHEfkSXqwp1hMcd7w" hash="RPhakQ">Today our youth are faced with tremendous challenges—and what do they need most?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p24" pid="rjFVBYkoL0yOork1HVBUpg" hash="Xeus4w">They need sound knowledge, sensible understanding, a guiding hand. They need real homes that are maintained in a clean and orderly manner. They need fathers who are really fathers and mothers who are mothers in the true sense of the word. They need more than mere progenitors or landlords. They are in need of loving, understanding parents, who give fatherly and motherly care, who put their families first in their lives, and who consider it their fundamental and most important duty to save their own children, to so orient them and their thinking that they will not be swayed by every wind of persuasion which happens to blow in their direction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p25" pid="_hj6TV0MbUaHfhfOiKSpSw" hash="cV61Uw">These young people are inquisitive, hungering for truth. What they want from us as parents is honest, well-informed answers to their questions, and our very lives should reflect the things we say, so that the teacher and the truth taught will be of the same pattern.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p26" pid="uWUvMG7kDUmtHqQ37HoqBw" hash="8D2Ihw">Daniel Webster once said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p27" pid="S5XUkh5yYEeL1DO105-AUQ" hash="9__AQg">“If we work upon marble, it will perish. If we work upon brass, time will efface it. If we rear temples, they will crumble to dust. But if we work upon men’s immortal minds, if we imbue them with high principles, with the just fear of God and love of their fellow men, we engrave on those tablets something which … will brighten and brighten to all eternity.” (Burton Stevenson, <span class="emphasis">The Home Book of Quotations,</span> New York: Dodd, Mead &amp; Company, 1934, p. 1312.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p28" pid="x8UXdUW0PEiEU3D_sBgmvw" hash="L9czog">Sister Stone and I are the grandparents of sixteen grandchildren, and we can assure you there is nothing in the world more dear to our hearts. We are most grateful for the efforts being made by their parents to bring them up properly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p29" pid="pONMJwfZsEKC_0ics23BXA" hash="_0YHfg">I encourage you young people to draw close to your parents—let them help you direct your lives toward righteousness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p30" pid="VpbGc_iyKEqp4VDwHgEU5w" hash="_YBFaQ">The greatest blessings of this life are available to each of us only when we keep the commandments the Lord has given us. And the blessings promised are not just for this life only, but also for all eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p31" pid="sukuKtp1kEqNFZamjFo1Dg" hash="LOl9ZQ">Our prophet and leader today, President Spencer W. Kimball, has told us that the price of happiness is to <span class="emphasis">keep the commandments of God.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p32" pid="k5msvGu3hECudXIsYkHrdg" hash="Kd-ErQ">On judgment day, would any of you parents want to be told that you failed to do your part—that you were unworthy servants of the Lord because your lives were poor examples to the spirits He entrusted to your care?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p33" pid="S36jfH2Et06J7yH_7lUXew" hash="fIcj6w">To paraphrase an admonition the Lord has given us: Let your light so shine before your children, that they may see your good works, and glorify your Father which is in heaven. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.16" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p34" pid="tja3ru_WoUWbLc6OtWPbrw" hash="CLsF-w">As we and our children live the gospel, we make ourselves worthy to receive this great promise recorded in the Doctrine and Covenants: “And, if you keep my commandments and endure to the end you shall have eternal life, which gift is the greatest of all the gifts of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/14.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 14:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p35" pid="aUx61Xmf7kWRqwmXPwTCqg" hash="j1Istg">What a glorious promise—eternal life. And it <span class="emphasis">will</span> be ours if we keep the commandments and endure to the end. The Lord always keeps His promises. Remember that He says in the Doctrine and Covenants:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p36" pid="QMID29FR4E2IL9ByPxMZxg" hash="hbPFCQ">“I, the Lord, am bound when ye do what I say; but when ye do not what I say, ye have no promise.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/82.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 82:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood.p37" pid="1FIET6r2k0GC5TgNvz_RzQ" hash="-DdU8g">May we all live to bring this promise of eternal life to ourselves and our family. Such wonderful blessings are within our grasp, if we live righteous lives. I so testify in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/10/parenthood</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1976-general-conference/1976-10-4050-elder-o-leslie-stone-64k-eng.mp3" length="5548080" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 1976 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Your Marriage Successful</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My remarks today are directed primarily to young married couples and to those who are planning to be married, but perhaps they will apply to all of us who are married or who someday will be married. I would like to talk about the art of making your m</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03096_000_028" doc-version="2" hash="wvBgMw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="1rao6FZz3Uu6JLAMgm57Og" hash="xQ6WiA">Making Your Marriage Successful</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="laVt_XoxvU-wnGNbpz3ZjA" hash="XDOjPg">O. Leslie Stone</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2898.jpg" alt="Elder O. Leslie Stone" pid="WPxarRV4rUiB5iDDnv8TdA" hash="8ZrpPA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p1" pid="jnvOCTJt0UenoDDXsVxirA" hash="9-nxUw">My remarks today are directed primarily to young married couples and to those who are planning to be married, but perhaps they will apply to all of us who are married or who someday will be married. I would like to talk about the art of making your marriage successful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p2" pid="r66ighSYg0e9qzumG7Qavg" hash="4EWmIg">Our Heavenly Father loves all of us and wants us to be happy. The scriptures record, “Men are, that they might have joy.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.25" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:25</a>.) President Kimball has told us that the price of happiness is to keep the commandments. (See <span class="emphasis">Faith Precedes the Miracle,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1972, p. 126.) Nowhere else are happiness and success more important than in your marriage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p3" pid="ScpcipxWW0GegvjDdoGoWQ" hash="z6UHOQ">
        <span class="emphasis">The foundation for a happy and successful marriage</span> is a marriage solemnized in the temple. To you who were married for time only, let me urge you to thoroughly investigate the blessings available to you by going to the temple and having your family sealed to you for time and all eternity. Participating in these sacred ordinances should be your most important objective for achieving a successful marriage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p4" pid="8z9EIxcvSUaimhCYZvEfXw" hash="FbZyeg">
        <span class="emphasis">When our Heavenly Father permitted us to come to this earth,</span> He gave us our free agency, allowing us to make our own decisions. He also furnished us with guidelines to help us live righteously.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p5" pid="yvqbqQK1akGI4dVJwFhqug" hash="Zlw9Jw">In His wisdom He gives us many problems, for He knows that by meeting them and finding solutions we will gain knowledge and skills, develop character, and learn to overcome evil, all of which will help us while we are here on earth, as well as in the life hereafter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p6" pid="GCIvgQ2M_0SLqC0yXHObrQ" hash="UQZWdA">We should, therefore, look at problems in marriage as opportunities for growth and development. As we meet the challenges successfully, we will enjoy peace, love, and tranquility in our marriage and in our home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p7" pid="8aVkj0ixb0aRRfA_s9enDQ" hash="A7pFRA">
        <span class="emphasis">One of the first things a couple must do</span> is establish and maintain good relations with each other. If you want to be sweethearts, you must work at it. I admonish every one of you to do everything possible to make your companion happy. Be kind and considerate of each other. When problems arise, talk things over calmly and resolve differences promptly. On one occasion Elder Gordon B. Hinckley said that quiet speech in the home is the language of peace. (See <span class="emphasis">Conference Report,</span> Apr. 1971, p. 82.) President McKay used to say that we should never yell at each other in the home. And then, facetiously, he would add that maybe on one occasion it would be all right and that would be if the house were on fire. (See <span class="emphasis">Stepping Stones to an Abundant Life,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret Book, 1971, p. 294.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p8" pid="Uvt48X6z-kGbETfLhmF90A" hash="mb4qkQ">Sometimes it is difficult for us to understand why our mates don’t see things the same and arrive at the same conclusions as we do. People are different in their thinking and their understanding, and opinions often vary. Differences must be reconciled promptly if husbands and wives are to be happy and work as a team together.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p9" pid="JP78B_7zWEWrIUaTRRZfmA" hash="EkzDVQ">
        <span class="emphasis">To achieve a successful marriage</span> it is important to reach an understanding on what is expected of each of the marriage partners. Ordinarily the husband is the breadwinner, and he should be willing to work hard and to do all in his power to properly take care of the financial needs of his family. Such needs should be discussed and priorities set for the welfare of the entire family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p10" pid="DrXU7cjD7UGU1tNPzexM4Q" hash="Wbo6nQ">The wife is the homemaker. It is her responsibility to see that a clean, orderly home is maintained. Some divorces have occurred where the wife becomes indifferent about her personal appearance, or becomes a careless housekeeper, or both. I cannot stress too strongly to the sisters the importance of personal cleanliness, good appearance, and maintaining a clean, orderly home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p11" pid="_hT1abFIwUO4lTb4ePNw2A" hash="pd12ow">In the beginning, if the wife’s health permits, she is often temporarily employed outside the home. When this is the case, the husband should help with the housekeeping chores. If a man truly loves his wife, he will not want or allow her to work more than her health and strength permit. He will want to help her in every possible way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p12" pid="8sl2rRyYtEeFz1joLyeRhg" hash="pFVl2w">When I was a young man, my wife would ask me to come and help her with the dishes, with making the beds, or with other household chores. Now, at this time in our lives, I ask her to come and help me wash the dishes, make the beds, and perform other household chores. The important thing is to work together and help each other.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p13" pid="VX-mehpAG0qX3QiPhAIqUQ" hash="nXwMOQ">
        <span class="emphasis">By your actions let everyone know you love each other.</span> Demonstrate consideration at all times. Brethren, open the door of the car for your wife or companion. When you enter or leave a building together, open the door and have her go in first. Help her to be seated before you are seated.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p14" pid="VjwC7iEmRUO14jtO4r5V4A" hash="T4VNsQ">Sometimes our ladies don’t allow us time to perform such courtesies. My advice to you sisters is to take the extra time. If you jump out of the car a few times without his help, he will probably expect you to come and open the door for him. Sisters would do well to remember that a husband generally treats his wife the way she expects to be treated.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p15" pid="g41ShIil6EWl4JKXH5K8qw" hash="5y-etw">Money management is very important. I’d like to give you four guides that I think would be helpful in this respect.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p16" pid="4ldIiLk4C0aMqsnyu95HJw" hash="NK9-vA">1. <span class="emphasis">First, always pay your tithing.</span> Keep yourself eligible for the great blessings the Lord has promised to those who obey this commandment. He made this statement in the scriptures:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p17" pid="HJJj0iAyVkuT7MP1EYZhSg" hash="zEhPDQ">“Bring ye all the tithes into the storehouse that there may be meat in mine house, and prove me now herewith, saith the Lord of hosts, if I will not open the windows of heaven, and pour you out a blessing, that there shall not be room enough to receive it.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/3.10" class="scriptureRef">Mal. 3:10</a>.) I testify to you that this is true.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p18" pid="-Kf1RPB3EE-KHCyGmS93cA" hash="OrHyQw">2. <span class="emphasis">Next, pay yourself something off the top.</span> Save something out of every dollar you earn. I suggest your goal be no less than ten percent of your income after you have paid the Lord His share.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p19" pid="zgkXdVLG_US5hk5sRce6Mw" hash="iTuPWg">Brigham Young once said: “If you wish to get rich, save what you get. A fool can earn money; but it takes a wise man to save and dispose of it to his own advantage.” (<span class="emphasis">Discourses of Brigham Young,</span> sel. John A. Widtsoe, Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1941, p. 292.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p20" pid="f83J1od-iE-DNoeb_rx1jg" hash="k2Y_hQ">3. <span class="emphasis">Next, avoid using credit cards and charge accounts</span> for installment purchases. We are all being urged to “buy now pay later.” This makes it sound easy and even glamorous to surround ourselves with luxuries before they are earned. My advice to all is to <span class="emphasis">save</span> now and <span class="emphasis">buy</span> later. This will not only save a high interest charge, but it will also keep couples out of financial bondage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p21" pid="68ER5XiytkC5pWvtULxr5w" hash="GUQQjg">Our late President J. Reuben Clark, Jr., advised us: “Let us avoid debt as we would avoid a plague; where we are now in debt let us get out of debt; if not today, then tomorrow. Let us straitly and strictly live within our incomes, and save a little.” (<span class="emphasis">Conference Report,</span> Apr. 1937, p. 26.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p22" pid="CfEY8FB7TEOxBmIFK3402w" hash="i83JJA">4. <span class="emphasis">Budget your income and outgo and do not live beyond your means.</span> To consistently spend more than you earn makes it impossible to keep solvent and difficult to control your “wants.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p23" pid="ajyQaLU7bkKJ2bzfT_qcfg" hash="0HxoHw">
        <span class="emphasis">Young couples especially should establish priorities.</span> In establishing priorities, remember that the family always comes first and foremost in your life. Next comes Church responsibilities and then your business affairs—the way you earn your living.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p24" pid="zBeEQ9xZkkqlMdQALW3T7Q" hash="rAjsVg">Remember the admonition of the Savior when He told his disciples, “Seek ye first the kingdom of God, and his righteousness; and all these things shall be added unto you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.33" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 6:33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p25" pid="SnX8juTbg0SsCb9RIuYTbw" hash="-TlBrg">I testify that this is true and that it points the way to success in all respects.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p26" pid="F6ORue_LzEW3XbxaV6ZlwA" hash="ca1emw">
        <span class="emphasis">Time is one of our most valuable possessions.</span> Use it wisely. Remind yourselves often that things that matter most should not be left to the mercy of things that matter the least.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p27" pid="d8OABp5ZLEmbwQiuSydPIg" hash="6pjPnQ">
        <span class="emphasis">We should all constantly evaluate our progress.</span> To live righteous lives and accomplish the purposes of our creation, we must constantly review the past, determine our present status, and set goals for the future. Without this process there is little chance of reaching one’s objectives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p28" pid="fn4UgckhYEanJvUf6sOgJQ" hash="LRnDyg">
        <span class="emphasis">I would admonish everyone within the sound of my voice to associate with good people.</span> Those with whom you associate will contribute to your success or your failure, and their actions and ideals will have a profound influence on life and your actions, either for good or evil. Learn to walk in the company of good people; shun evil by staying out of the devil’s territory.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p29" pid="bDnuczGq3EWohfltEP5fsQ" hash="x8Ptug">
        <span class="emphasis">Next, be honest in all matters.</span> Be honest with your spouse, with your family, with yourself, and with your neighbor. Honesty includes freedom from lying, deceiving, cheating, or stealing, as well as meeting our commitments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p30" pid="YnB4ONQtaE2M8FS2z9Jijg" hash="EUEtLQ">Honesty also includes doing a good day’s work. If we shirk our jobs, we are stealing time from our employers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p31" pid="md1nCXQ-skKIo6OoLaXs4A" hash="XGR-HQ">The business world and other employers are seeking those who are honest and dependable. This has always been the case and will continue to be so for all time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p32" pid="Zr1wyFe0NE-3zuGjLyRNvA" hash="U5yECw">Guard your reputation for honesty and dependability very carefully. It can be one of your most valuable possessions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p33" pid="YuFoP7Q71E2nUGTj4HRnrw" hash="6liu8Q">
        <span class="emphasis">As you become parents, you should feel responsible to teach and train your children.</span> Our scriptures make this very clear. In Doctrine and Covenants 68:25 [<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.25" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:25</a>] we read, “Inasmuch as parents have children in Zion, or in any of her stakes which are organized, that teach them not to understand the doctrine of repentance, faith in Christ the Son of the living God, and of baptism and the gift of the Holy Ghost by the laying on of … hands, when eight years old, the sin be upon the heads of the parents.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p34" pid="hjVzVyNA_EmUpdL9-MUsbw" hash="D2Vt8A">Notice it didn’t say the Sunday School teacher or the Primary teacher. The sin is on the heads of the <span class="emphasis">parents.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p35" pid="w-kHI_1mTUKvIbbXZ7KHGw" hash="9pVfaQ">Home responsibilities and rearing children must be uppermost in the minds and actions of parents if a successful marriage is to be achieved. This famous statement made by our late President David O. McKay should always be remembered: “No other success can compensate for failure in the home.” (<span class="emphasis">Conference Report,</span> Apr. 1964, p. 5.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p36" pid="jTckt35bWE23c6SdqER0CQ" hash="58mVMA">
        <span class="emphasis">Let love radiate in your home</span> and in all walks of life, not only to each other, but also to your children, your relatives, your friends, and your associates.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p37" pid="O8hGl8CwfkS2vOmQ7UiRug" hash="IMsH2g">The Lord commanded us to love one another when he said, “Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.39" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:39</a>.) Quarreling, bickering, and faultfinding should be avoided at all costs. In 3 Nephi 11:29–30 [<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.29-30" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:29–30</a>] the Lord made this significant statement:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p38" pid="GtZ_qQBZlEeSi8D2RSZV5w" hash="vQq8WQ">“He that hath the spirit of contention is not of me, but is of the devil, who is the father of contention, and he stirreth up the hearts of men to contend with anger, one with another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p39" pid="Z2NhWpE9S0uhfqMwp8z0AA" hash="i2Np7Q">“Behold, this is not my doctrine, to stir up the hearts of men with anger, one against another; but this is my doctrine, that such things should be done away.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p40" pid="JNkZigVlREO4OX2oRVT2Ww" hash="I6O0XQ">And also in <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.14" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:14</a>, we read that parents are particularly responsible for the behavior of their children:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p41" pid="HeK-9KkAFki_ST7mNAhc7Q" hash="hKIhEw">“And ye will not suffer your children that they go hungry, or naked; neither will ye suffer that they transgress the laws of God, and fight and quarrel one with another, and serve the devil, who is the master of sin, or who is the evil spirit which hath been spoken of by our fathers, he being an enemy to all righteousness.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p42" pid="o0vMuYmYXEyu5QVv_ssNbg" hash="au5k4w">
        <span class="emphasis">One of the most important things you will need to remember is to get on your knees for family prayers</span> both night and morning. Take turns thanking your Heavenly Father for the blessings He has given you and ask for those things you need that will be for your good. Our Heavenly Father always answers our prayers. Sometimes His answers are not what we expect or ask for, but I promise you His answers are always for our good. He knows better than we how our prayers should be answered.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p43" pid="wv_xG92PCkC5ZuiO-l56Hw" hash="sRL0-w">
        <span class="emphasis">Also, find a few minutes each day to study and ponder the scriptures together.</span> In the scriptures we find answers to all of life’s problems.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p44" pid="lpPNcyYhDki2Z4AoN-pMrw" hash="c180Ww">
        <span class="emphasis">Finally, I would give you a challenge to stay close to the Church.</span> Attend your meetings. Magnify your callings in the priesthood. Wives, support your husbands in their Church assignments; and husbands, support your wives in their Church callings. Go to the temple often and carry the spirit you feel there back into your homes. Be diligent in keeping the covenants you have made or will make in the house of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p45" pid="Bzsgq1dooUOzwNmyWJo2cQ" hash="D1MGhQ">At a fireside talk at Brigham Young University, President Kimball said, “Almost all marriages could be beautiful, harmonious, and happy, and eternal ones, if the two people primarily involved would determine that it should be, that it must be, that it will be.” (“Marriage is Honorable,” in <span class="emphasis">Speeches of the Year, 1973,</span> Provo: Brigham Young University Press, 1974, p. 257.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful.p46" pid="AiPjMB1lk0Cauqd_9o_rjg" hash="pXX5AA">May our Heavenly Father bless you abundantly in your efforts to make your marriage successful for both time and all eternity, I humbly pray in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1978/04/making-your-marriage-successful</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1978-general-conference/1978-04-4040-elder-o-leslie-stone-64k-eng.mp3" length="7042217" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 1978 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commandments to Live By</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by?lang=eng</link>
      <description>It is an inspiration to all of us to remember the teachings of our Savior and the many wonderful things he gave to the world. He lived long before recorded history. He was in the great council in heaven—he helped his Father in the shaping of the heav</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03115_000_028" doc-version="2" hash="PQR4Og">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="6_dL93FXnkGBJqJvPa4ytQ" hash="TlRLmQ">Commandments to Live By</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Mf0kysmkIkOgS4wySUzMww" hash="XDOjPg">O. Leslie Stone</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2898.jpg" alt="Elder O. Leslie Stone" pid="vUaDRT-Bj0Gn9_K-fkmedg" hash="8ZrpPA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p1" pid="ORXSibs0T0uTl1_WR2nnlA" hash="ZTnBIg">It is an inspiration to all of us to remember the teachings of our Savior and the many wonderful things he gave to the world. He lived long before recorded history. He was in the great council in heaven—he helped his Father in the shaping of the heavens, in the creation of the earth, and in the making of man, the latter being in response to the request of the Father when he said: “Let us … form man in our own image, after our likeness” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/4.26" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 4:26</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p2" pid="CbV7g5JnAEOn7NlrsOo_Nw" hash="L9o3NA">In opposition to Satan’s plan of compulsion, it was He who supported the Father’s plan of free agency—thus providing the right of choice which means so much to all of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p3" pid="7oNOW7hk_0yMv95qkwfxjg" hash="7KO0Dw">He lived on earth in the meridian of time in the promised land.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p4" pid="jWNFoREfIk-Twyx626VRKQ" hash="LspxZg">He was born far away from home and was cradled in a manger.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p5" pid="49uySuHU7UKsGsa53NOaCw" hash="cevnuQ">He went about teaching and doing good. Men followed him, not for worldly riches but to gain treasures in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p6" pid="reVe_wTR_UK85rVB8M0ASQ" hash="8fWoig">He set up a new code for living—to love one another, even one’s enemies. He enjoined us to judge not, to forgive, and to give all men a second chance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p7" pid="afnRwlkHl0WbyEYHwyT3wg" hash="G8LLzA">Think what a change this would make in the world today if we as individuals and the nations of the earth could live up to this code. We have often heard people say, “Well, I will forgive, but I won’t forget,” which, of course, means they do not forgive.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p8" pid="6br4b3aSHk6okU39XPiWOA" hash="KPRTmw">In Doctrine and Covenants 64:8–11 [<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.8-11" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:8–11</a>] the Lord tells us that it is our duty to forgive one another, and that he who does not forgive his brother stands condemned and is the <span class="emphasis">greater sinner of the two.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p9" pid="F-Tqj7VGKkCwj6qAGEpFvQ" hash="L7_pgg">In Matthew 22:36–39 [<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.36-39" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:36–39</a>] we read about an instance where Christ was approached by some of the leading lawyers of the day, one of whom said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p10" pid="69Cc55I28Ei8RGIlycV0CA" hash="25lWDg">“Master, which is the great commandment in the law?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p11" pid="y3Dy0LLAjke-r4OW5-Kzzg" hash="4zjMZQ">“Jesus said unto him, Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p12" pid="lCWde3HMS02E5QsXgK9oiA" hash="pLnaTg">“This is the first and great commandment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p13" pid="jRi0YUtceEebBZOj27MIDw" hash="9pnSeg">“And the second is like unto it, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p14" pid="Gs7AnEsCf0SdkzFfY8xThw" hash="0oxySw">Can a man reach the celestial kingdom if he does not love his neighbor as himself? When Jesus gave the second commandment, he said it was like unto the first, and repeating both, he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p15" pid="nFkcMa5kwESd9oVNODtFqQ" hash="0aOa8A">“On these two commandments hang all the law and the prophets” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.40" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:40</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p16" pid="eXh9VlWH-024OPCUtcA65g" hash="y8Lz_g">He made them very important—so important that all other laws and commandments rest upon them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p17" pid="k2iel_5VpEGM_TkmP_ffGQ" hash="tuDH4g">Let us ask another question. Can a man live the first and great commandment if he does not live the second? In other words, can he love God with all his heart if he does not love his fellow men? The answer is obvious.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p18" pid="r1sQbDYSyUCmA7QynJG9WQ" hash="350BvA">John the Apostle said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p19" pid="htV-2nqbcUCPmDt7lk2QMw" hash="O0xdyQ">“If a man say, I love God, and hateth his brother, he is a liar: for he that loveth not his brother whom he hath seen, how can he love God whom he hath not seen?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p20" pid="BC1IhVkQekyivjrEwAzjrA" hash="kYy2Tw">“And this commandment have we from him, That he who loveth God love his brother also” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-jn/4.20-21" class="scriptureRef">1 Jn. 4:20–21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p21" pid="Xw6kzFHj4EubsqqDub6tTw" hash="8Rj1AA">In 3 Nephi 11:29–30 [<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.29-30" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:29–30</a>] we find this statement:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p22" pid="5iGM61zWjEyRW_z9X621dA" hash="0axTRA">“For verily, verily I say unto you, he that hath the spirit of contention is not of me, but is of the devil, who is the father of contention, and he stirreth up the hearts of men to contend with anger, one with another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p23" pid="JOffIib6tEuXNYyfCaKw3A" hash="i2Np7Q">“Behold, this is not my doctrine, to stir up the hearts of men with anger, one against another; but this is my doctrine, that such things should be done away.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p24" pid="G3uHvzfzjUKolRN06dZT7w" hash="Ef5WfA">With all of these statements, it should be perfectly clear to everyone that the Lord desires us to love and forgive one another. It behooves all of us to conquer our pride and make every effort to settle all differences with our fellowmen. As just quoted from 3 Nephi, contentions and disputations are of the devil and are not approved by our Heavenly Father. Loving our neighbors as ourselves will bring joy and happiness into our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p25" pid="0BukVxiiZE-9eXJZyBM7Sg" hash="VbsrpA">Christ lived to bless, heal, and restore. He was a peacemaker. On many occasions he healed the sick, the lame, and the blind. Yes, as we have been told earlier today, he even raised the dead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p26" pid="wZuBTEF3EkWlY7omNY3w6w" hash="BOLNnw">After all these things, he was forced to carry his own cross to Calvary. He forgave those who would take his life. At the very time when he was suffering the most, he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p27" pid="l3cNWwijIUy38Lre1_REbg" hash="bJoxDg">“Father, forgive them; for they know not what they do” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/23.34" class="scriptureRef">Luke 23:34</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p28" pid="2ALhuw3DOUyf8h6IfCYlOw" hash="ZqWoxQ">He died that we might have everlasting life. In <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/11.25-26" class="scriptureRef">John 11:25–26</a> it is recorded that he proclaimed: “I am the Resurrection, and the life: he that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p29" pid="YEOjVQXoCEGxlSkw0uwhCw" hash="0lBX4Q">“And whosoever liveth and believeth in me shall never die.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p30" pid="olu4wXfzpUy3KWNTQvANpw" hash="LvWbMQ">He rose from the grave to triumph over death and to bless the world with resurrection.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p31" pid="W6GNrgWcckapRZLA45GFIA" hash="eWjxLA">The gospel provides us with a beautiful plan of salvation. We know that we come to earth to obtain a body, gain knowledge, and develop skills and character. We also come here so we can learn to overcome evil and see if we can remain true and faithful and be sufficiently diligent and obedient to the commandments so as to be worthy to return and abide in his presence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p32" pid="MYXYeSdRCkus3Gxaa8vngw" hash="Ie_arQ">Today, as I contemplate the many, many blessings that have been given to us, I recall the words of King Benjamin in the Book of Mormon when, after enumerating the blessings which had been poured down upon his people by the Lord, he said this:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p33" pid="X6TTbXjfe0CZhTnfT3FV6Q" hash="HH0Rlw">“And behold, all that he requires of you is to keep his commandments” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.22" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2:22</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p34" pid="1hvJ4gSvaEq9FoHXgYmiJQ" hash="ma_V_g">Yes, the only thing the Lord requires of us is that we keep his commandments! This sounds relatively simple, doesn’t it? But we all know that it isn’t simple nor was it intended to be. Where much is given, much is expected. The Lord requires of those who dwell with him the ability to overcome weaknesses and imperfections. He requires self-denial and self-discipline. No, it isn’t simple, but the Lord has given us many suggestions and instructions to help us keep his commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p35" pid="C9vfRi2T_UGQoYwAEnBh_g" hash="gnVvgw">Some of us may feel from time to time that some of his commandments are an impediment to happiness in this life, but this isn’t so; and deep down in our hearts we all know that so long as we adhere to these commandments, just as surely as night follows day, we will reap the blessings that are promised to the faithful. Remember, the Lord said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p36" pid="vZgdfk_g9EWp3yL8zl61Og" hash="eL5fpw">“I, the Lord, am bound when ye do what I say; but when ye do not what I say, ye have no promise” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/82.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 82:10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p37" pid="bVWu3xiViUWcVz5cgLwcMg" hash="f0FzBg">Sometimes the way of fulfillment may not be apparent to us, but the actuality of it is assured.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p38" pid="7N1yPQZOvEWfZeaIQLjDXw" hash="4MLv1Q">How many of us on Judgment Day would like to be told that we had failed to do our part—that we had been unworthy servants of the Lord because our own lives had been such a poor example? In <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.16" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:16</a> the Lord gives us a very important message:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p39" pid="P7-G8OBQOUmc-JJ9yx31ng" hash="nhqdWw">“Let your light so shine before men, that they may see your good works, and glorify your Father which is in heaven.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p40" pid="N-ihsQ0OcECQetyWmv3AgA" hash="wKemFQ">To fail to keep the commandments of the Lord not only brings condemnation, but actually deprives us of many blessings here on this earth—to say nothing of those eternal blessings for which we are all striving. In <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/2.9" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 2:9</a> we read this important statement: “Eye hath not seen, nor ear heard, neither have entered into the heart of man, the <span class="emphasis">things which God hath prepared for them that love him</span>” (italics added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p41" pid="CER0SwD6fUW-A0fQDXXpKA" hash="UrGwhQ">And finally, the great promise given to all men:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p42" pid="BEQgBTyK_Ua0kgv45cvD1Q" hash="b_iXtQ">“And, if you keep my commandments and endure to the end you shall have eternal life, which gift is the greatest of all the gifts of God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/14.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 14:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p43" pid="MbSGHyYMjUKNH_coeAfBuA" hash="6G17IA">In closing, I would like to bear testimony that the Father and the Son did appear to Joseph Smith and gave him instructions pertaining to the restoration of the true gospel of Jesus Christ. I also testify that our leader today, President Spencer W. Kimball, and his counselors are true prophets of God. We would all do well to follow them in the path of truth and righteousness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by.p44" pid="nOf74zXJQUiWeHNglCbd1Q" hash="IxqASw">I pray that these brethren may be blessed with inspiration at all times. Further, that our Heavenly Father will grant them health and strength sufficient to carry out their heavy responsibilities. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3062.jpg" alt="The First Presidency on 21 May 1945" pid="jBe4vv3mREqPvClKzcEu3g" hash="RrrQkQ" />
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1979/10/commandments-to-live-by</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1979-general-conference/1979-10-5040-elder-o-leslie-stone-64k-eng.mp3" length="4432884" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 1979 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
