<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Patrick Kearon</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Patrick Kearon.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Patrick%20Kearon.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Patrick Kearon.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>“Come unto Me with Full Purpose of Heart, and I Shall Heal You”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Our Savior is the Prince of Peace, the Great Healer, the only One who can truly cleanse us from the sting of sin.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021411_000_3020" doc-version="2" hash="-8WBeA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="xjyVYMCrR0eBBH6cszzVYw" hash="_BOsqw">“Come unto Me with Full Purpose of Heart, and I Shall Heal You”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="PdRa2CXZuU253uD05rlOlA" hash="ndrA7Q">Patrick Kearon</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="-1y8oqK3tEOQzyFgv1BOcg" hash="O_2IQA">Our Savior is the Prince of Peace, the Great Healer, the only One who can truly cleanse us from the sting of sin.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p1" pid="QIBaRBZHsEOFYeqL0FM9Ig" hash="BDNshw">Tonight I would like to share a message of comfort and healing with any of you who feels alone or forsaken, has lost peace of mind or heart, or feels that you have thrown away your last chance. Complete healing and peace can be found at the feet of the Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p2" pid="I2qGt75oZUiOesUuMBZcWw" hash="lMvLIQ">As a seven-year-old boy living in the Arabian Peninsula, I was consistently told by my parents to <span class="emphasis">always</span> wear my shoes, and I understood why. I knew that shoes would protect my feet against the many threats to be found in the desert, such as snakes, scorpions, and thorns. One morning after a night’s camping in the desert, I wanted to go exploring, but I did not want to bother with putting on my shoes. I rationalized that I was only going for a little wander and I would stay close by the camp. So instead of shoes, I wore flip-flops. I told myself that flip-flops were shoes—of a sort. And anyway, what could possibly happen?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p3" pid="DkyBFM2Bp0mvT4A4h-B6Qg" hash="PmWWqw">As I walked along the cool sand—in my flip-flops—I felt something like a thorn going into the arch of my foot. I looked down and saw not a thorn but a scorpion. As my mind registered the scorpion and I realized what had just happened, the pain of the sting began to rise from my foot and up my leg. I grabbed the top of my leg to try and stop the searing pain from moving farther, and I cried out for help. My parents came running from the camp.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p4" pid="kf6-FOsOmkCtP0D2m4dZgw" hash="J3fOSA">As my father battered the scorpion with a shovel, an adult friend who was camping with us heroically tried to suck the venom from my foot. At this moment I thought that I was going to die. I sobbed while my parents loaded me into a car and set off across the desert at high speed toward the nearest hospital, which was over two hours away. The pain all through my leg was excruciating, and for that entire journey, I assumed that I was dying.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p5" pid="8kgfp-AVXU-yv4sW9MGa_w" hash="QrFB8A">When we finally reached the hospital, however, the doctor was able to assure us that only small infants and the severely malnourished are threatened by the sting of that type of scorpion. He administered an anesthetic, which numbed my leg and took away any sensation of pain. Within 24 hours I no longer had any effects from the sting of the scorpion. But I had learned a powerful lesson.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p6" pid="0iEbJe_9cEOTVS4inALb2Q" hash="Bq60bA">I had known that when my parents told me to wear shoes, they did not mean flip-flops; I was old enough to know that flip-flops did not provide the same protection as a pair of shoes. But that morning in the desert, I disregarded what I knew to be right. I ignored what my parents had repeatedly taught me. I had been both lazy and a little rebellious, and I paid a price for it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p7" pid="tQkv1eBSUkmij-hSwoK-eQ" hash="QiPUqg">As I address you valiant young men, your fathers, teachers, leaders, and friends, I pay tribute to all who are diligently striving to become what the Lord needs and wants you to be. But I testify from my own experience as a boy and as a man that disregarding what we know to be right, whether through laziness or rebelliousness, always brings undesirable and spiritually damaging consequences. No, the scorpion did not in the end threaten my life, but it caused extreme pain and distress to both me and my parents. When it comes to how we live the gospel, we must not respond with laziness or rebelliousness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p8" pid="Quwn_QEeLUmxZaShqPJipw" hash="5BV4SA">As members of the Church of Jesus Christ and as bearers of the priesthood, we know the commandments and standards we have covenanted to uphold. When we choose another path from the one we know to be right, as taught by our parents and leaders and as confirmed to our own hearts by the Holy Ghost, it is like stepping onto the desert sand in flip-flops instead of shoes. We then seek to justify our lazy or rebellious behavior. We tell ourselves we’re not really doing anything that wrong, that it doesn’t really matter, and that nothing all that bad will result from letting go just a little from the iron rod. Perhaps we console ourselves with the thought that everyone else is doing it—or doing worse—and we won’t be negatively affected anyway. We somehow convince ourselves that we are the exception to the rule and therefore immune to the consequences of breaking it. We refuse, sometimes willfully, to be “exactly obedient”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span>—as it says in <span class="emphasis">Preach My Gospel</span>—and we hold back a portion of our hearts from the Lord. And then we get stung.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p9" pid="nErBeOX2t0uWhfvuXrAnZg" hash="LYaLig">The scriptures teach us that “the Lord <span class="emphasis">requireth the heart,</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> and we are commanded to love the Lord and serve Him with “<span class="emphasis">all</span> [our] heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> The promise is that we “may stand blameless before God at the last day” and return to His presence.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p10" pid="LZrDE2uA_kmY2d93ejy1xA" hash="OfybBw">The Anti-Nephi-Lehies in the Book of Mormon laid down their weapons of war and buried them deep in the earth, covenanting never again to take up arms against their brethren. But they did more than that. “They became a righteous people” because “they did lay down the weapons of their <span class="emphasis">rebellion,</span> that they did not fight against God any more.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Their conversion was so complete and so profound that they “never did fall away.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p11" pid="Sjm5OK1o6kar-JJqz8Z9Vg" hash="xOXWdA">But before their conversion, remember their state: they were living in what the scriptures call “open rebellion against God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> Their rebellious hearts sentenced them to live “in a state contrary to the nature of happiness” because they had “gone contrary to the nature of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p12" pid="5fsmXqbcZ0GTo0fgRmZ0Og" hash="55K63w">When they laid down their weapons of <span class="emphasis">rebellion,</span> they qualified themselves for the Lord’s healing and peace, and so can we. The Savior assures, “If they harden not their hearts, and stiffen not their necks against me, they shall be converted, and <span class="emphasis">I will heal them.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> You and I can accept His invitation to “return and repent, and come unto me with full purpose of heart, and I shall heal [you].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p13" pid="Mjvb9ePjpUWPlSjotW7ZrQ" hash="Jwi8DQ">Contrast this miraculous healing with what happens “when we undertake to cover our sins, or to gratify our pride [or] our vain ambition. … The heavens withdraw themselves; the Spirit of the Lord is grieved;” and we are left alone “to kick against the pricks … and to fight against God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p14" pid="8Q5wDATisUmoGuNEZ2eTNQ" hash="JMAvxw">Brethren, we find healing and relief only when we bring ourselves to the feet of the Great Physician, our Savior, Jesus Christ. We must lay down our weapons of rebellion (and we each know what they are). We must lay down our sin, vanity, and pride. We must give up our desires to follow the world and to be respected and lauded by the world. We must cease fighting against God and instead give our <span class="emphasis">whole hearts</span> to Him, holding nothing back. Then He can heal us. Then He can cleanse us from the venomous sting of sin.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p15" pid="Vo5ZvWbzy0KzjskVbFfB4A" hash="RvEWzQ">“For God sent not his Son into the world to condemn the world; but that the world through him might be saved.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p16" pid="hZ9rhS9S1EyZaDK03q2DkA" hash="CgSF6g">President James E. Faust taught:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p17" pid="r4KUY_VfOkSWe4TpYh4xEg" hash="DBm87Q">“When obedience becomes our goal, it is no longer an irritation; instead of a stumbling block, it becomes a building block. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p18" pid="iHFBk08CXEejeBXtYQ6nFw" hash="guUgqg">“… Obedience leads to true freedom. The more we obey revealed truth, the more we become liberated.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p19" pid="-9y2pXXluU2hnkYO322Nig" hash="zXJwvQ">Last week I met a 92-year-old man who had been involved in many of the major campaigns of World War II. He had survived three injuries, one of which was a land-mine blast to the jeep in which he was traveling, which killed the driver. <span class="emphasis">He learned that to survive in a minefield, you must follow exactly in the tracks of the vehicle moving ahead of you.</span> Any deviation to the right or left could—and indeed did—prove fatal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p20" pid="-4YgIrWTUUSLQBaPlfR7hQ" hash="q3GtBQ">Our prophets and apostles, leaders and parents continually point out the track we must follow if we would avoid a destructive blast to our souls. They know the path that has been safely cleared of mines (or indeed scorpions), and they tirelessly invite us to follow behind them. There are so many devastating traps to entice us from the track. Straying into drugs, alcohol, pornography, or immoral behavior over the Internet or on a video game will head us straight toward an explosion. Deviating to the right or the left of the safe track ahead of us, whether because of laziness or rebelliousness, can prove fatal to our spiritual lives. There are no exceptions to this rule.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p21" pid="NNZ1-l_CNkuAPDXFtDU6kg" hash="XkSRGg">If we have strayed from the track, we can change, we can return, and we can recapture our joy and our inner peace. We will discover that returning to the track from which the land mines have been removed brings enormous relief.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p22" pid="SeLRo5zR2U6JNx34o0VPpg" hash="2-HrAQ">No one can find peace in a minefield.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p23" pid="5ZQyWB6rDE2GFDV4v4VDjQ" hash="9Q2Jug">Our Savior is the Prince of Peace, the Great Healer, the only One who can truly cleanse us from the sting of sin and the poison of pride and change our rebellious hearts into converted, covenant hearts. His Atonement is infinite and embraces us all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p24" pid="EDMOKwA9W0aAklGha2zAcA" hash="GBn55w">The invitation given to the Nephites, when He ministered to them as the resurrected Christ, is still in force for you and for me: “Have ye any that are sick among you? Bring them hither. Have ye any that are lame, or blind, or halt, or maimed, or leprous, or that are withered, or that are deaf, or that are afflicted in any manner? Bring them hither <span class="emphasis">and I will heal them.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you.p25" pid="9d34pVA4dEyycGVK3eh04g" hash="bx3-Ag">Not one of you has thrown away your last chance. You can change, you can come back, you can claim mercy. Come unto the only One who can heal, and you will find peace. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/10/come-unto-me-with-full-purpose-of-heart-and-i-shall-heal-you</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2010-general-conference/2010-10-3020-elder-patrick-kearon-64k-eng.mp3" length="5290507" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refuge from the Storm</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13285_000_63kearon" doc-version="2" hash="bCrMBQ"&gt;
	
	&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.head1"&gt;
		&lt;h1 class="title" pid="WyLzKN1Kj0635htgufEzgA" hash="b-w4AQ"&gt;Refuge from the Storm&lt;/h1&gt;
		&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p2" pid="sUJo-mm64U22lYKUZ5fNGg" hash="MDbXfQ1"&gt;By Elder Patrick Kearon&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p3" pid="A5jZmyrcA0SakO17phQ23Q" hash="sSmk3g"&gt;Of the Seventy&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=93peJIwivU2LdVRyUh-uhg"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" altText="Elder Patrick Kearon" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255544/2719619c38ad46cf8ef87b967af04958/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255544/2719619c38ad46cf8ef87b967af04958/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255544/2719619c38ad46cf8ef87b967af04958/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x279="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255544/2719619c38ad46cf8ef87b967af04958/200x279.jpg" data-src-320x446="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255544/2719619c38ad46cf8ef87b967af04958/320x446.jpg" data-src-460x641="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255544/2719619c38ad46cf8ef87b967af04958/460x641.jpg" data-src-640x892="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255544/2719619c38ad46cf8ef87b967af04958/640x892.jpg" data-src-1024x1428="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255544/2719619c38ad46cf8ef87b967af04958/1024x1428.jpg" data-src-2048x2857="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255544/2719619c38ad46cf8ef87b967af04958/2048x2857.jpg" data-src-3486x4864="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255544/2719619c38ad46cf8ef87b967af04958/3486x4864.jpg" webURL="patrick-kearon-first-quorum-seventy_1255544.jpg" pid="93peJIwivU2LdVRyUh-uhg" hash="AAAAAA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="kicker" pid="a4A0d0GRy0ePsDqLoApuDA" hash="g6x7ag"&gt;This moment does not define the refugees, but our response will help define us.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="authorName" pid="pUppd3yMTEyiH7mmhvL-VA" hash="MDbXfQ"&gt;By Elder Patrick Kearon&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class="bodyBlock"&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p5" pid="d43CZFLgI0Wx7qMk7Incmg" hash="ad-a6Q"&gt;“For I was an hungred, and ye gave me meat: I was thirsty, and ye gave me drink: I was a stranger, and ye took me in:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p6" pid="sg6eNrY0wkelOoVJPU6Wqg" hash="5G0eVw"&gt;“Naked, and ye clothed me. …&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p7" pid="gearIbeQQUmKe3vIfC8MAQ" hash="sRaDBA"&gt;“… Verily I say unto you, Inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p8" pid="4mTugsksbUyOWHroxEzHrA" hash="mTV_jQ"&gt;There are an estimated 60 million refugees in the world today, which means that “1 in every 122 humans … has been forced to flee their homes,”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; and half of these are children.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; It is shocking to consider the numbers involved and to reflect on what this means in each individual life. My current assignment is in Europe, where one and a quarter million of these refugees have arrived over the last year from war-torn parts of the Middle East and Africa.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; We see many of them coming with only the clothes they are wearing and what they can carry in one small bag. A large proportion of them are well educated, and all have had to abandon homes, schools, and jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p9" pid="t-bepc-a00aFQJZcdvE0-A" hash="kfZKbw"&gt;Under the direction of the First Presidency, the Church is working with 75 organizations in 17 European countries. These organizations range from large international institutions to small community initiatives, from government agencies to faith-based and secular charities. We are fortunate to partner with and learn from others who have been working with refugees around the world for many years.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p10" pid="f54TMqvuSUmNIxndcYSQXw" hash="oYBewg"&gt;As members of the Church, as a people, we don’t have to look back far in our history to reflect on times when we were refugees, violently driven from homes and farms over and over again. Last weekend in speaking of refugees, Sister Linda Burton asked the women of the Church to consider, “What if &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; story were &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; story?”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; Their story &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; our story, not that many years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p11" pid="qLAW9DOoP0yVOyHEV53EAg" hash="dM8SRQ"&gt;There are highly charged arguments in governments and across society regarding what the definition of a refugee is and what should be done to assist the refugees. My remarks are not intended in any way to form part of that heated discussion, nor to comment on immigration policy, but rather to focus on the &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;people&lt;/span&gt; who have been driven from their homes and their countries by wars that they had no hand in starting.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p12" pid="srr2Eo6sZEGF9-O4mSh4Fg" hash="zfjPug"&gt;The Savior knows how it feels to be a refugee—He was one. As a young child, Jesus and His family fled to Egypt to escape the murderous swords of Herod. And at various points in His ministry, Jesus found Himself threatened and His life in danger, ultimately submitting to the designs of evil men who had plotted His death. Perhaps, then, it is all the more remarkable to us that He repeatedly taught us to love one another, to love as He loves, to love our neighbor as ourselves. Truly, “pure religion and undefiled before God and the Father is this, To visit the fatherless and widows in their affliction”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; and to “look to the poor and the needy, and administer to their relief that they shall not suffer.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p13" pid="pbS2Ts1L5UmixqOzwsuVcw" hash="Vh_-Jg"&gt;It has been inspiring to witness what Church members from around the world have generously donated to help these individuals and families who have lost so much. Across Europe specifically, I have seen many members of the Church who have experienced a joyful awakening and enriching of the soul as they have responded to that deep, innate desire to reach out and serve those in such extreme need around them. The Church has provided shelter and medical care. Stakes and missions have assembled many thousands of hygiene kits. Other stakes have provided food and water, clothing, waterproof coats, bicycles, books, backpacks, reading glasses, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p14" pid="2Pt8YYdpuU2dEzqB0bj-0Q" hash="heKuqQ"&gt;Individuals from Scotland to Sicily have stepped in to every conceivable role. Doctors and nurses have volunteered their services at the point where refugees arrive soaked, chilled, and often traumatized from their water crossings. As refugees begin the resettlement process, local members are helping them learn the language of their host country, while others are lifting the spirits of both children and parents by providing toys, art supplies, music, and play. Some are taking donated yarn, knitting needles, and crochet hooks and teaching these skills to local refugees old and young.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p15" pid="l-uv0oG1_Ea8e-ykDz3NBA" hash="nqo7Ig"&gt;Seasoned members of the Church who have given years of service and leadership attest to the fact that ministering to these people so immediately in need has provided the richest, most fulfilling experience in their service so far.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p16" pid="jQyJB76Kh0qu5RB773Ebvg" hash="4Xm52Q"&gt;The reality of these situations must be seen to be believed. In winter I met, amongst many others, a pregnant woman from Syria in a refugee transit camp desperately seeking assurance that she would not need to deliver her baby on the cold floors of the vast hall where she was housed. Back in Syria she had been a university professor. And in Greece I spoke with a family still wet, shivering, and frightened from their crossing in a small rubber boat from Turkey. After looking into their eyes and hearing their stories, both of the terror they had fled and of their perilous journey to find refuge, I will never be the same.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p17" pid="rtYT4gJQpUKok0ner_rBuw" hash="Vw2CoQ"&gt;Extending care and aid is a vast range of dedicated relief workers, many of them volunteers. I saw in action a member of the Church who, for many months, worked through the night, providing for the most immediate needs of those arriving from Turkey into Greece. Among countless other endeavors, she administered first aid to those in most critical medical need; she saw that the women and children traveling alone were cared for; she held those who had been bereaved along the way and did her best to allocate limited resources to limitless need. She, as so many like her, has been a literal ministering angel, whose deeds are not forgotten by those she cared for, nor by the Lord, on whose errand she was.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p18" pid="70WsiCaQd0CB26Ku3Fn_Vg" hash="vWTz1A"&gt;All who have given of themselves to relieve the suffering around them are much like the people of Alma: “And thus, in their prosperous circumstances, they did not send away any who were naked, or that were hungry, or that were athirst, or that were sick, or that had not been nourished; … they were liberal to all, both old and young, both bond and free, both male and female, whether out of the church or in the church, having no respect to persons as to those who stood in need.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8"&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p19" pid="tnKnwnPSVUmDrRGvPm0JbA" hash="rJFqNA"&gt;We must be careful that news of the refugees’ plight does not somehow become commonplace when the initial shock wears off and yet the wars continue and the families keep coming. Millions of refugees worldwide, whose stories no longer make the news, are still in desperate need of help.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p20" pid="X87SaoqfJEG0pgGYiRvV3w" hash="kyHONQ"&gt;If you are asking, “What can I do?” let us first remember that we should not serve at the expense of our families and other responsibilities,&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9"&gt;9&lt;/span&gt; nor should we expect our leaders to organize projects for us. But as youth, men, women, and families, we can join in this great humanitarian endeavor.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p21" pid="lpfGixq3hUuKtq9AfBl1Rg" hash="V2_qHw"&gt;In response to the invitation from the First Presidency to participate in Christlike service to refugees worldwide,&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt; the general presidencies of the Relief Society, Young Women, and Primary have organized a relief effort entitled “I Was a Stranger.” Sister Burton introduced this to the women of the Church last weekend in the general women’s session. There are multiple helpful ideas, resources, and suggestions for service on &lt;a href="http://iwasastranger.lds.org/"&gt;IWasAStranger.lds.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p22" pid="NK1p_u-3gEmQkdfq_vRlCA" hash="TiKJtA"&gt;Begin on your knees in prayer. Then think in terms of doing something close to home, in your own community, where you will find people who need help in adapting to their new circumstances. The ultimate aim is their rehabilitation to an industrious and self-reliant life.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p23" pid="G6iKkZxIgkGEdbHnZtambg" hash="C9IiSA"&gt;The possibilities for us to lend a hand and be a friend are endless. You might help resettled refugees learn their host country language, update their work skills, or practice job interviewing. You could offer to mentor a family or a single mother as they transition to an unfamiliar culture, even with something as simple as accompanying them to the grocery store or the school. Some wards and stakes have existing trusted organizations to partner with. And, according to your circumstances, you can give to the Church’s extraordinary humanitarian effort.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p24" pid="rPbTkcjCfUqYRjPSL5WuJg" hash="gZ6DAw"&gt;Additionally, each one of us can increase our awareness of the world events that drive these families from their homes. We must take a stand against intolerance and advocate respect and understanding across cultures and traditions. Meeting refugee families and hearing their stories with your own ears, and not from a screen or newspaper, will change you. Real friendships will develop and will foster compassion and successful integration.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p25" pid="-cmpx1CCr0CXKjeCvP4Q_A" hash="Puvfbg"&gt;The Lord has instructed us that the stakes of Zion are to be “a defense” and “a refuge from the storm.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11"&gt;11&lt;/span&gt; We have found refuge. Let us come out from our safe places and share with them, from our abundance, &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;hope&lt;/span&gt; for a brighter future, &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;faith&lt;/span&gt; in God and in our fellowman, and &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;love&lt;/span&gt; that sees beyond cultural and ideological differences to the glorious truth that we are all children of our Heavenly Father.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p26" pid="-xNzWEcJaECPU6GsYl_N1A" hash="yzlqwA"&gt;“For God hath not given us the spirit of fear; but of power, and of love.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12"&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p27" pid="ues2_59qkkm8yQ9jA-etQA" hash="njChDg"&gt;Being a refugee may be a defining moment in the lives of those who are refugees, but being a refugee does not define &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;them.&lt;/span&gt; Like countless thousands before them, this will be a period—we hope a short period—in their lives. Some of them will go on to be Nobel laureates, public servants, physicians, scientists, musicians, artists, religious leaders, and contributors in other fields. Indeed, many of them &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; these things before they lost everything. This moment does not define them, but our response will help define us.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p28" pid="P7Xv2dRw1U6sz3qd_RxXuA" hash="9JYWeA"&gt;“Verily I say unto you, Inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt; In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm.p29" pid="ploV1lGN7kaMe0fzAOynBg" hash="nIbcmg"&gt;
			&lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;For further reference, see &lt;a href="http://iwasastranger.lds.org/"&gt;IWasAStranger.lds.org&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.mormonchannel.org/blog/post/40-ways-to-help-refugees-in-your-community"&gt;mormonchannel.org/blog/post/40-ways-to-help-refugees-in-your-community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/04/refuge-from-the-storm</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2016-general-conference/2016-04-5030-patrick-kearon-64k-eng.mp3" length="6066823" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
