<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Paul B. Pieper</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Paul B. Pieper.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Paul%20B.%20Pieper.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Paul B. Pieper.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2006 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2006 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The First Generation</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/10/the-first-generation?lang=eng</link>
      <description>By being the first in your family to accept the gospel, you become the first generation, a chosen generation through which generations past, present, and future may be blessed.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-first-generation" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006562_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="qk7tZA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-first-generation.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="UjIHoxTDSkiMRVXyLqfeeQ" hash="RS-4fQ">The First Generation</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="HcUSSMs3QkC2z2TFGTJfLw" hash="LLAsVw">Paul B. Pieper</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="IWNEvIEg2EWmcX2t0d7hiQ" hash="Ey_Cxg">By being the first in your family to accept the gospel, you become the first generation, a chosen generation through which generations past, present, and future may be blessed.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-first-generation.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/PieperPB_05.jpg" alt="Elder Paul B. Pieper" pid="r9L_vueg9Eq1VBoBINDijQ" hash="9VVk9g" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-first-generation.p1" pid="TGLulRVmzU-flgBxMo00fw" hash="R_sWcA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="11"></span>Several days ago, we were discussing talks during a family meal. Clarissa, our 13-year-old daughter, was preparing a sacrament meeting talk for our branch in Moscow and felt some anxiety. I reassured her that all would be well and released a little anxiety of my own by saying that at least she didn’t have to speak in front of thousands of people in general conference. Clarissa gave me some advice of her own: “It will be OK, Dad. Just pretend it’s a big branch.” Brothers and sisters, you are indeed a very large branch.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-first-generation.p2" pid="jub5M0IRRkClHsnefG0dTw" hash="tfdFdQ">I have chosen to address my remarks this morning to first-generation members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. You are those who are the first in your family to hear and embrace the message that the gospel of Jesus Christ has been restored to the earth in our day with living prophets, seers, and revelators. You humbled yourselves, exercised faith, and repented of all your sins, taking upon you the name of Jesus Christ through baptism by immersion, and received the Holy Ghost.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> By being the first in your family to accept the gospel, you become the first generation, a chosen generation through which generations past, present, and future may be blessed.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-first-generation.p3" pid="g0dEnhcTUE6zwYEYjHL1JA" hash="c49YEQ">Being a first-generation member of the Church is not always easy. You will walk where no one in your family has walked before. Conditions around you may be challenging. You may have few, or no, friends or relatives to understand and support you. At times you may become discouraged, wondering if it is all worth it. My purpose this morning is to assure you that it is.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-first-generation.p4" pid="wmR3V8yDL0CasIhNN9xdQQ" hash="0KPu8A">First-generation members occupy a special and important place in the Church and their families. Did you know that first-generation members constitute more than half of the membership of the Church?<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Perhaps not since the early days of the Church has <span class="pageBreak" page-number="12"></span>the first generation constituted such a large percentage of total Church membership as it does today. Your faith and testimonies are a great strength and blessing to others. Through you, we gain a deeper understanding of gospel principles and our testimonies are strengthened.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-first-generation.p5" pid="knoor02SGUKT-0-Oq5fxxw" hash="hq5KyQ">You add great strength to the Church when you use your testimony, talents, abilities, and energy to build the kingdom in your wards and branches. You are great examples of sharing the gospel, serving missions, sending children on missions, and welcoming new members. You reach out in kindness to those around you, lifting and blessing them through inspired service. So much of what is done in the Church today could not be done without your efforts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-first-generation.p6" pid="GeOgNh86LEGgmc-uVs9hdA" hash="NA46xA">More importantly, as a first-generation member, you occupy an important place in your family. You are an example to your family of a true disciple of Jesus Christ. Whether they are members of the Church or not, as you live the gospel at home, those around you will feel the Savior’s love through you. They know that you are engaged in something good, even if they do not understand it or have enough faith to accept it. Be patient and kind, pray each day to know how you can serve them, and the Lord will help you and bless you to influence your family for good. By being consistently good and upright, you will establish patterns of faithfulness and righteousness. Those patterns will shape your life, but more importantly, they will become a standard for your family and posterity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-first-generation.p7" pid="EHhiZ98e6Uyae6itVhPGKg" hash="WvbAFw">As the first generation, you are also the key to opening the Lord’s blessings to family members who died without hearing the gospel and receiving saving ordinances. Yours is the unique opportunity and privilege to begin this work on their behalf. They are anxious for you to identify them and will help you in your search for their records. Once they are identified, your worthy life will permit you to attend the temple and perform essential ordinances for them. These ordinances will bind you to your ancestors and bring great spiritual power into your life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-first-generation.p8" pid="cyohKy9tokOvyGn6ENl5Vg" hash="2DESeA">Because you are a first-generation member, each choice you make is important. Seemingly small, insignificant decisions will impact past and future generations, as well as your own life. One young first-generation member, Chris, was offered a drink of alcohol at work the day after his baptism. His friends were all there and were drinking. There was considerable pressure. No one else knew that the day before, he had been baptized and made promises to the Lord. He made the decision not to drink and was treated poorly. Reflecting on that event later, he wrote: “It is now forty years since I made those [baptismal] promises and I can truthfully say that I have … kept the Word of Wisdom. … I believe if I had accepted [that] drink that I would, perhaps, never have been able to keep the Word of Wisdom.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-first-generation.p9" pid="zPb-1uKxfUe6Q-UsgKfzlQ" hash="XFyJbw">But Chris kept his baptismal promises. Later he met and married a faithful member. Together they raised eight children in the gospel. Now in the sixth generation, his faithful descendants number in the hundreds. Dozens have served missions and introduced the gospel to others. His efforts in family history opened the blessings of the gospel to hundreds more. One small decision by a first-generation member made a difference for thousands.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-first-generation.p10" pid="3d43gWf4iEWNMmbRTsC0EA" hash="ZPrNHg">Can you see now why the first generation is so important? Can you <span class="pageBreak" page-number="13"></span>understand the position you occupy and the influence you can have for good? Please never underestimate who you are and the power that you have to affect others. Satan understands who you are and will do all possible to entice you to make wrong choices. At times, despite our best efforts, we all make mistakes. Fortunately, Heavenly Father has prepared a way for us to overcome them through repentance and reliance on the Atonement of His Son. Do not be discouraged if you make a mistake. Repenting and continuing to press forward are perhaps the most important patterns to develop in the first generation. Be patient and move forward in obedience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-first-generation.p11" pid="uJIb-yOkPUiZ3xfVAkn__g" hash="nc27rg">In the Church we read and speak much about pioneers in early Church history. They were first-generation members just like you. They lived each day meeting the challenges of family, work, and faith. They lived good, ordinary lives and were faithful, serving in the Church and blessing their families. When they fell down, they got back up and moved on. Now, those of us who are their descendants look back with reverence and gratitude for their faithfulness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-first-generation.p12" pid="Z-fQDQtn1UaI8-Y3--eFRw" hash="TRHIIQ">Their legacy can be yours as fellow members of the first generation. Be faithful, serve your fellowman, bless your family, and make proper choices. You are the first generation, a chosen generation to bless past, present, and future generations. We honor you. Past and future generations will honor you. But most importantly, God will honor you for being faithful in the first generation. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/10/the-first-generation</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2006-general-conference/2006-10-1040-elder-paul-b-pieper-64k-eng.mp3" length="1240040" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2006 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Hold Sacred</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sacred things are to be treated with more care, given greater deference, and regarded with deeper reverence.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10485_000_56piepe" doc-version="2" hash="F53h8g"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="OE5YIS0zsUeY4MSipxW8nA" hash="4k6Gdg">To Hold Sacred</h1><p class="authorName" pid="QoStx1gT2kq4zRVGfD39zw" hash="6JVzKQ">By Elder Paul B. Pieper</p><p class="kicker" pid="JixsBmw8IE6ACdU5rdhjkg" hash="sODomg">Sacred things are to be treated with more care, given greater deference, and regarded with deeper reverence.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p5" pid="jeVWr8F8aEC8I0aatj87XA" hash="N9HL-g">
      <span class="pageBreak" page-number="109"></span>Some 1,500 years before Christ, a shepherd was drawn to a burning bush on the slopes of Mount Horeb. That divine encounter began the transformation of Moses from a shepherd to a prophet and his work from herding sheep to gathering Israel. Thirteen hundred years later, a privileged young priest in a king’s court was captivated by the witness of a condemned prophet. That encounter began Alma’s evolution from a civil servant to a servant of God. Nearly 2,000 years later, a 14-year-old boy entered the woods seeking an answer to a sincere question. Joseph Smith’s encounter in the grove placed him on the path to prophethood and a restoration.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p6" pid="fRLfYqjSvk2wyoLxtM1-wA" hash="meLZtw">Moses’s, Alma’s, and Joseph Smith’s lives were all changed by encounters with the divine. These experiences strengthened them to remain faithful to the Lord and His work throughout their lives despite overwhelming opposition and subsequent difficult trials.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p7" pid="qPdufEmZDU24Rj-lrMeGmA" hash="pbTehw">Our experiences with the divine may not be as direct or dramatic nor our challenges as daunting. However, as with the prophets, our strength to endure faithfully depends upon recognizing, remembering, and holding sacred that which we receive from above.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p8" pid="cXY0rfFq3ke6kREwYdn9Yg" hash="nQZtdQ">Today authority, keys, and ordinances have been restored to the earth. There are also scriptures and special witnesses. Those who seek God may receive baptism for the remission of sins and confirmation “by the laying on of hands for the baptism of fire and the Holy Ghost” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.41" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:41</a>). With these precious restored gifts, our divine encounters will mostly involve the third member of the Godhead, the Holy Ghost.</p>
    <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.f1">
      <div class="stanza">
        <p class="line" pid="xIK3yiBYtECB1hN3aavcjg" hash="EyR7ag">Through a still small voice, the Spirit speaks to me</p>
        <p class="line" pid="rFUXeVO3DkWPI88CqpTWSA" hash="hMJGqw">To guide me, to save me.</p>
      </div>
      <p class="citationInfo" pid="bWkME8pR1kKDws5SMZ7W8Q" hash="E1UXgA">(“The Still Small Voice,” <span class="emphasis">Children’s Songbook,</span> 106)</p>
    </div>
    <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.f2">
      <div class="stanza">
        <p class="line" pid="V0fDgGrN2kK6paUxYZ0KqQ" hash="5zJEJA">Let the Holy Spirit guide;</p>
        <p class="line" pid="tKcNLqIx8USmzJPq-YyPnw" hash="Qu03dg">Let him teach us what is true.</p>
        <p class="line" pid="I5B5MOcK3kyqJlaTjPzVhg" hash="gK7QLw">He will testify of Christ,</p>
        <p class="line" pid="o54MfJbFGU69v_Lfwg0i3A" hash="gajDcg">Light our minds with heaven’s view.</p>
      </div>
      <p class="citationInfo" pid="E2FXtBscnkaJKYzAHFu08A" hash="0zS6WQ">(“Let the Holy Spirit Guide,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 143)</p>
    </div>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p17" pid="AL7JkjkNgEOifnz7qvGjrA" hash="Y5jULw">As we seek answers from God, we feel the still, small voice whisper to our spirits. These feelings—these impressions—are so natural and so subtle that we may overlook them or attribute them to reason or intuition. These individualized messages testify of God’s personal love and concern for each of His children and their personal mortal missions. Daily reflecting upon and recording the impressions that come from the Spirit serve the dual purposes of helping us (1) to recognize our personal encounters with the divine and (2) to preserve them for ourselves and our posterity. Recording them is also a formal recognition and acknowledgment of our gratitude to God, for “in nothing doth man offend God, or against none is his wrath kindled, save those who confess not his hand in all things” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:21</a>).</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p18" pid="1xC7qxuVfEK4lp8tF-F4yg" hash="Dxp10Q">With respect to that which we receive by the Spirit, the Lord said, “Remember that that which cometh from above is sacred” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/63.64" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 63:64</a>). His statement is more than a reminder; it is also a definition and an explanation. Light and knowledge from heaven is sacred. It is sacred because heaven is its source.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p19" pid="S74v6O8WsE2q6WSdEmLKnQ" hash="lre4rA">
      <span class="emphasis">Sacred</span> means worthy of veneration and respect. By designating something as sacred, the Lord signals that it is of higher value and priority than other things. Sacred things are to be treated with more care, given greater deference, and regarded with deeper reverence. Sacred ranks high in the hierarchy of heavenly values.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p20" pid="0wDbTPzCi0aWb1somXbX5Q" hash="Ww6D9A">That which is sacred to God becomes sacred to us only through the exercise of agency; each must choose to accept and hold sacred that which God has defined as sacred. He sends light and knowledge from heaven. He invites us to receive and treat it as sacred.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p21" pid="zoeN8wGu50SLQVtbpr8XNA" hash="SOApfw">But “there is an opposition in all things” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.11" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 2:11</a>). The opposite of sacred is profane or secular—that which is temporal or worldly. The worldly constantly competes with the sacred for our attention and priorities. Knowledge of the secular is essential for our daily temporal living. The <span class="pageBreak" page-number="110"></span>Lord instructs us to seek learning and wisdom, to study and learn out of the best books, and to become acquainted with languages, tongues, and people (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.118" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:118</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/90.15" class="scriptureRef">90:15</a>). Therefore, the choice to place the sacred above the secular is one of relative priority, not exclusivity; “to be learned is good <span class="emphasis">if</span> [we] hearken unto the counsels of God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/9.29" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 9:29</a>; emphasis added).</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p22" pid="L_uIKZqJDkWCwVM37oLdjw" hash="Kx5uoA">The battle for priority between the sacred and the secular in each human heart can be illustrated by Moses’s experience at the burning bush. There Moses received his sacred calling from Jehovah to deliver the children of Israel from bondage. However, initially his worldly knowledge of the power of Egypt and the pharaoh caused him to doubt. Ultimately, Moses exercised faith in the Lord’s word, subjugating his secular knowledge and trusting in the sacred. That trust provided him power to overcome temporal trials and lead Israel out of Egypt.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p23" pid="_eH05fMx2Emvdq91vXmmdA" hash="jbiZYg">After escaping from the armies of Noah only to fall into slavery at the hands of Amulon, Alma could have doubted the spiritual witness he had received while listening to Abinadi. However, he trusted the sacred and was given strength to endure and escape his temporary trials.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p24" pid="XzrGp711vkGL4XzYusGNbw" hash="NSoaog">Joseph Smith faced a similar dilemma in the early days of translating the Book of Mormon. He knew the sacred nature of the plates and the work of translation. Yet he was persuaded by Martin Harris to give priority to the worldly concerns of friendship and finances, contrary to sacred instructions. As a result, the manuscript of the translation was lost. The Lord upbraided Joseph for delivering “that which [is] sacred, unto wickedness” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/10.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 10:9</a>) and deprived him for a time of the plates and the gift to translate. When Joseph’s priorities were properly reestablished, the sacred things were returned and the work continued.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p25" pid="88r8ObQXYEa5u4LPnqpZlQ" hash="XM6YYg">The Book of Mormon provides other examples of the struggle to give priority to the sacred. It speaks of believers whose faith led them to the tree of life to partake of its sacred fruit, the love of God. Then the mocking of those in the great and spacious building caused the believers to shift their focus from the sacred to the secular. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/8.11,24-28" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 8:11, 24–28</a>.) Later the Nephites chose pride and denied the spirit of prophecy and revelation, “making a mock of that which was sacred” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/4.12" class="scriptureRef">Helaman 4:12</a>). Even some eyewitnesses of the signs and miracles associated with the Lord’s birth chose to reject sacred manifestations from heaven in favor of secular explanations (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/2.1-3" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 2:1–3</a>).</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p26" pid="70d89tRa2UeEPojEeoru5w" hash="dIymJg">Today the struggle continues. Secular voices are growing in volume and intensity. They increasingly urge believers to abandon beliefs the world considers irrational and unreasonable. <span class="pageBreak" page-number="111"></span>Because “we see through a glass, darkly” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/13.12" class="scriptureRef">1 Corinthians 13:12</a>) and “do not know the meaning of all things” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/11.17" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 11:17</a>), at times we may feel vulnerable and in need of greater spiritual assurances. The Lord told Oliver Cowdery:</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p27" pid="nmpfMnMvhk2SWxNE-3SFhg" hash="ncGZsA">“If you desire a further witness, cast your mind upon the night that you cried unto me in your heart, that you might know concerning the truth of these things.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p28" pid="FvjX6O6QEUqleOwUwJhXNw" hash="3w22pg">“Did I not speak peace to your mind concerning the matter? What greater witness can you have than from God?” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.22-23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:22–23</a>).</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p29" pid="BNvw9Q7myUyek-3yb8iCfg" hash="14Lf4Q">The Lord reminded Oliver and us to rely on sacred personal witnesses already received when our faith is challenged. Like Moses’s, Alma’s and Joseph’s before, these divine encounters serve as spiritual anchors to keep us safe and on course in times of trial.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p30" pid="aPorCLXt9E-Gp97Wvt365g" hash="HbbHdg">The sacred cannot be selectively surrendered. Those who choose to abandon even one sacred thing will have their minds darkened (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.54" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:54</a>), and unless they repent, the light they have shall be taken from them (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.33" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:33</a>). Unanchored by the sacred, they will find themselves morally adrift on a secular sea. In contrast, those who hold sacred things sacred receive promises: “That which is of God is light; and he that receiveth light, and continueth in God, receiveth more light; and that light groweth brighter and brighter until the perfect day” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/50.24" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 50:24</a>).</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred.p31" pid="Rv2WZafsI0-kH1zACA3swg" hash="g0aVXA">May the Lord bless us to ever and always recognize, remember, and hold sacred that which we have received from above. I testify that as we do, we will have power to endure the trials and overcome the challenges of our day. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2012/04/to-hold-sacred</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2012-general-conference/2012-04-5060-elder-paul-b-pieper-64k-eng.mp3" length="4750865" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
