<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Paul H. Dunn</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Paul H. Dunn.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Paul%20H.%20Dunn.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Paul H. Dunn.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Young People—Learn Wisdom in Thy Youth</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I am deeply honored, my beloved brothers and sisters, to occupy this pulpit again and to add my testimony to those that have been borne so strongly and adequately. I want President [Hugh B.] Brown to know the great feeling of love and appreciation we</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03006_000_7030" doc-version="2" hash="jcGiCA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="x7vkiAeaqEyP565ivOKv5Q" hash="3Pdz7w">Young People—</h1><p class="subtitle" pid="80za8ikUtkCS3y4tRIq7Uw" hash="uRGbMA">Learn Wisdom in Thy Youth</p><p class="authorName" guid="74719440-7a80-44ef-bc3f-eb57a10732cb" pid="Tz0RxEC50U-lqCkj_JTkYg" hash="2gvHCQ">Paul H. Dunn</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="17f81f9e-b409-460e-ac21-de31197b2c7d">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3396.jpg" alt="President Paul H. Dunn" guid="2bc6d887-c9e1-4941-96a3-cbc2fb9b6c7a" pid="1V1f-oC5YUStbC3XQUUBWA" hash="UpGYbQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p1" guid="851743d2-9242-4b0a-957a-527d9bb4a9a7" pid="UDTeeZeGbEGnDIREkh4i6w" hash="_l9abA">I am deeply honored, my beloved brothers and sisters, to occupy this pulpit again and to add my testimony to those that have been borne so strongly and adequately. I want President [Hugh B.] Brown to know the great feeling of love and appreciation we have for him and how much we have missed his presence during this conference. Our thoughts and prayers are ever with him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p2" guid="8be96808-5fc4-427c-b002-6ba3aeb92e29" pid="DtIP6FEwPkeahNBiEoKK6A" hash="Kcl6RQ">Yesterday as I came over to one of the sessions, one of my returned missionaries was kind enough to introduce me to an investigator. We had a wonderful chat and in the course of the conversation the investigator said, “I finally think I have found out the secret to your success as wonderful, righteous people.” I said, “What’s that?” She said, “You attend so many meetings you don’t have time to commit a sin.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p3" guid="05d94c4a-a180-4872-ae18-9a6e87dc2568" pid="YkLCs6XA6Eq5uq2TXzOo6g" hash="QryG9Q">I have thought about that, and it prompted me to turn to this little verse. It goes:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.f1" guid="03523bd3-9cce-4300-b28d-58289ff463ad">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="FkAMjus1e0aVp_4zKCWbuA" hash="R5sREg">“One day for church</p>
          <p class="line" pid="JgUBcbyApk6tRMzoqG5PWA" hash="h54kXg">Six days for fun.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="gwRw-MvCOEeVUAaH92SU-w" hash="b1yQlw">The odds of going to heaven,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="RBY1Gkyt00-UUwMeQkOCQA" hash="MVOYGw">Six to one.”</p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p4" guid="5cc3fd07-2e2a-4078-8d26-2f6f25a74473" pid="MawJ_eIwJ0iGEw9C14Fm4w" hash="zXKf8w">I suppose as a church we have reduced those odds considerably. I can’t resist one other. My father said on one occasion:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.f2" guid="c409724a-49c0-4f90-8873-f6ebb55a9694">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="Njg9EEnwiUiXjYn1lZb0hw" hash="-MDwxA">“Whenever I pass our little ward,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="F2AO0D25hkmyFmxF4RPM6Q" hash="TsTtZQ">I like to linger for a visit,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="S3N8jfxSiEyPoiT7rzbqag" hash="J0nWaQ">So that when I am carried in</p>
          <p class="line" pid="g1Rs5lz1qEilTYbWzfS91A" hash="ZQCG6A">The Lord won’t say, Who is it?”</p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p5" guid="ade3dd4b-ae96-4234-b4cd-81019e76085e" pid="sd9Fmz3bjUKw3AOQswbxWg" hash="tHGkfg">Now I would like to address a few remarks to our wonderful young people, particularly those twenty years of age and under, and I would like to include my new adopted son, Loren [Dunn].</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p6" guid="98d4232a-a19c-4fe4-b718-91499de87e45" pid="pfO2j150E0GWUDXY2WjVug" hash="o-ALZA">Sometimes we are asked by our young people why we stress so much the commandments of God. As one little person put it to me just the other day, “Why do you have to be so churchy?” I would like to share a feeling or two concerning that inquiry. It is because, young people, we love you, are concerned about you, your well-being, and your ultimate welfare. It is important to know that we as parents have taken upon ourselves a very sacred oath and covenant to bring you up in the ways of the Lord, and that is very, very important to us, as it is to him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p7" guid="775b90f3-4151-44e7-8350-41268b1a3915" pid="8K2TfkMAbkm9kD45E8lEOA" hash="Wko66g">One of the scriptures many of your moms and dads take literally is the one recorded in the sixty-eighth section of the Doctrine and Covenants, which says: “And again, inasmuch as parents have children in Zion, or in any of her stakes which are organized, that teach them not to understand the doctrine of repentance, faith in Christ the Son of the living God, and of baptism and the gift of the Holy Ghost by the laying on of the hands, when eight years old, the sin be upon the heads of the parents.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.25" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p8" guid="fda96b9b-29b9-4192-af10-45caa68117a4" pid="z3boWYqtR06Zg9YIIA2STw" hash="M2Fp9w">Now that is rather serious to those of us who sit in such a responsible position. I once asked my mother, “How does it feel, Mom, to have all my sins placed upon your head?” She said, “Oh, but you forgot one thing, Paul. I have transferred them back to you because I have taught you the doctrines of the kingdom.” In a sense that is what we are trying to do, young people: to prepare you to live a happy and full life both now and in the future, and true joy and happiness comes in knowing and living the commandments of our Father in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p9" guid="80509c69-3ffa-40c4-919d-b9233f47422f" pid="hYcSkg0UBE-DhYxbSwFLeQ" hash="qGoUnQ">Would you listen to the words of Alma, that great Book of Mormon prophet. They ring true and clear. He said, “O, remember, my son, and learn wisdom in thy youth; yea, learn in thy youth to keep [all] the commandments of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.35" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:35</a>.) That is why we as parents are concerned. We want to teach you how to get back into the presence of our Heavenly Father by keeping all of the commandments. You can’t keep what you don’t know or understand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p10" guid="b7baf3d3-66c0-493c-8bb0-1645da0338a6" pid="tnpyyf_4OEm1pAoapXLBvw" hash="KfPZRw">Someone once said, “You know we want to help you young people in the worst way,” and I suppose some of us are guilty of doing it in just about that way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p11" guid="27c64804-e781-40e9-8dba-579fdd4b4610" pid="pEsNJKdRYUuhIKFr9LlEHg" hash="BRBqNg">A young mother recently shared with me a story called “The World’s Meanest Mom,” and I would like to share it with you here. She said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p12" guid="be4aa649-b41d-44e7-8b61-e130ee8e65db" pid="DZ0EdUVCkkmGDfiu0VyC8A" hash="_kujKg">“I had the meanest mother in the whole world. While other kids had no breakfast, I had to have cereal, eggs, and toast. When others had pop and candy for lunch, I had to eat a sandwich. My mother insisted on knowing where we were at all times. You’d think we were on a chain gang. She had to know who our friends were and what we were doing. She insisted that if we said we’d be gone for an hour, that we would be gone for one hour or less.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p13" guid="f01da882-818e-4173-ba84-fe9ac7ad3ea6" pid="V71qQIBiX0uqAVXlKRBrvA" hash="rNAZnA">“I am ashamed to admit it, but she actually had the nerve to break the child labor law. She made us wash the dishes, make beds, learn to cook, and all sorts of cruel things. I believe she lay awake nights thinking up mean things for us to do. She always insisted that we tell the truth, the whole truth, and nothing but the truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p14" guid="5fb9cf4a-b399-4720-8b9b-70986479a614" pid="aF16ZzgZP0GABkQnbLes4A" hash="a-byrg">“By the time we were teenagers she was much wiser, and our lives became even more miserable. None of this tooting the horn of a car for us to come running. She embarrassed us to no end by making our dates and friends come to the door to get us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p15" guid="58e31120-f1b7-4e3b-bb29-8af14d1fc345" pid="8Rff5DJso0uiB-fywjJ4wQ" hash="RJpvtw">“My mother was a complete failure as a mother. None of us have ever been arrested or beaten a rap. Each of my brothers has served a mission, and his country. And whom do we have to blame for this terrible way we turned out? You’re right—our mean mother. Look at all the things we have missed. We never got to take part in a riot, burn draft cards, and a million and one other things that our friends did. She made us grow up into educated, honest adults. Using this as a background, I am trying to raise my children. I stand a little taller and I am filled with pride when my children call me mean. You see, I thank God that he gave me the meanest mother in the whole world.” (Orien Fifer, <span class="emphasis">Phoenix Gazette</span>)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p16" guid="a766ee5c-1238-4ac2-9f84-73e9781bb64e" pid="KBMVT1qmlkS_BID6niPfvw" hash="jLUozw">How truly blessed is a person who has a mother who cared. I too am grateful for my parents, who applied the gospel of love in such a wonderful way. And although I often remind my mother of our round-table discussions, in which she chased me around the table, I learned the truths of the gospel by example from her and from my father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p17" guid="c97d4cfd-cb6d-457f-a741-561996094aec" pid="VHkZPv65_kSpv_VSGuRv9g" hash="52CXSQ">As with the bud, so with the blossom. A boy is the only thing known from which a man can be made. I hope that we as parents are teaching our children that they are the sons and daughters of God, and that they have the capacity to become like him. It was the old Edinburgh weaver who prayed, “O God, help me to hold a high opinion of myself.” Likewise I would counsel young people to hold a high opinion of themselves, to remember who they really are, and to put their faith in their Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p18" guid="f89e96f7-b764-40a5-9f46-0841ae1cca30" pid="fR6gfMEJMEiIdWor3o7vhQ" hash="lL_Y5g">In today’s fast-moving, materialistic world, unfortunately many fathers place their business affairs ahead of their children. I am appalled as I look around me, as was Eddie Cantor some years ago, when he said that a man will spend a whole week figuring out what stocks to buy with $1,000—but he won’t spend an hour with his child, in whom he has a greater investment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p19" guid="20b34088-cfe8-4685-851b-02d2b5d290b9" pid="2d12QSkYzE2FBDMOSlqjdQ" hash="rc1KSQ">Is it any wonder that many of our young people are troubled with identity problems? We who are older speak of building a better world, but our progress is slow. Real generosity to the future lies, then, in giving all that we have to the present.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p20" guid="488a7b1a-0afe-4c74-9433-947ec232494a" pid="8AawJosWZkWElUjzgmgdlg" hash="JXSWsg">Now, you young people, listen to the counsel of your parents. They love you. We are not perfect. One day you will stand where we stand, and you will have a similar challenge of rearing your young. Will you go with us the extra mile in trying to understand our true nature and purpose?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p21" guid="d126a98a-9f98-4706-98f2-0f627488e8ba" pid="MzzmbpY4j0uoR642VSlk6g" hash="oHMCUg">Depend on and trust in the great counsel of wise parents. I would also remind you that the Lord has not left you or them unattended in our challenging world. Since the beginning of time the Lord has revealed his mind and will and has counseled us through his prophets on how to find true happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p22" guid="74590832-06a8-466e-9d34-e75c67a04013" pid="oGKCsyT8OE6sY9cMPeI7Lg" hash="JYI0jw">For just a moment, I would like to invite you to come with me into the scriptures, wherein you might become a little more excited about the gospel as it is related to us by great prophets. And I would hope that on your own and in family home evening, church study classes, you could become more excited about our wonderful scriptures. We tend to support and want to do those things we understand. For instance:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p23" guid="cb51d92d-26f9-42a0-ace4-7bf5dce52724" pid="w86VafLSK0iEDLLXXBPInw" hash="5d11OA">Not long ago when I was residing in Southern California, I made a trip from our home in Downey to the University of Southern California, where I was working. One morning as I traveled down a street in order to find a new route to work, I took a road where a beautiful house was under construction, and it caught my eye because it was quite similar to one my wife hoped we would build one day, although it was somewhat out of our financial reach. I took great personal interest in this house because of its familiar floor plan and style, but I noticed several weeks later that the workmen had ceased their labor, and I wondered about it. I thought for a minute maybe there was a strike, or perhaps they had run short of finances, and other possibilities entered my mind. Several months came and went, and that once shiny new lumber seemed to deteriorate. The wood gradually changed to yellow, then brown, and finally commenced to rot.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p24" guid="a059284f-7ddf-487d-aa10-bd07740c9c1b" pid="FAU5tRYi5kKSA5_pfjCejA" hash="rT5xug">As I viewed this scene, young people, and this is so typical of the scriptures, I thought of the great truths that our Savior taught in the New Testament, and my mind was immediately attracted by that house to the fourteenth chapter of Luke. Now if you can, picture in your mind for a moment the Savior teaching the Pharisees and Sadducees, some sinners, publicans, and others who even sought his life. They had asked questions and he turned and made this observation. He said, “For which of you, intending to build a tower, sitteth not down first, and counteth the cost [Can you see why I had caught the message of the unfinished house?], whether he have sufficient to finish it?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p25" guid="1429f586-a7e1-4566-9ea6-9ff33f5e1961" pid="W-PgmbulEEGrOkYzXCGmFA" hash="Z-1Kow">“Lest haply, after he hath laid the foundation, and is not able to finish it, all that behold it begin to mock him,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p26" guid="041a436a-b499-4c75-9b0a-c28642d382c0" pid="Oarc8LI0-kWPe_mIz04Ubw" hash="9jMsEg">“Saying, This man began to build, and was not able to finish.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p27" guid="6dda2557-51ef-47cd-9d1f-0c316dedfc18" pid="tPRdOLrtp02ybm03jOUl6g" hash="rD4ZxA">“Or what king, going to make war against another king, sitteth not down first, and consulteth whether he be able with ten thousand to meet him that cometh against him with twenty thousand?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p28" guid="d2c29e41-0049-4247-b34d-5e0bf3b6e199" pid="o2xofO2pTU--urAFTJeosA" hash="Wbz2og">“Or else, while the other is yet a great way off, he sendeth an ambassage, and desireth conditions of peace.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/14.28-32" class="scriptureRef">Luke 14:28–32</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p29" guid="4605e4ef-0eeb-40f0-bdfc-764a613c538f" pid="CFxUFhpoF0iMq4fZGQcA1A" hash="__62sg">Could I just translate that scripture into 1971 language for you young people? The Lord might say, if he were here today, and he does through his leaders, “For which of you, intending to build an eternal life, sitteth not down first to consider what it is going to cost, lest haply some of you will commence to build and will not finish.” And you and I know you don’t have to look very far at your school to see some lives that are standing idle because they didn’t count the cost. The cost of a wonderful home, the cost of getting an education, the cost of properly marrying, the cost perhaps in many cases of a wonderful mission, the cost of doing the right thing for the right reason. That is what our Heavenly Father would have us tell you. It is a timeless message. We need to plan and prepare if we are to achieve eternal goals.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p30" guid="08b0008f-7c23-49c8-9294-dca7f92c921a" pid="73-Kw4nAPU-IcMU_HZotaQ" hash="bicVMQ">Let me just conclude with one other as recorded in the Gospel of Matthew. Jesus said again to a multitude that had gathered around him, “The kingdom of heaven is like unto a certain king, which made a marriage for his son.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p31" guid="277f1a71-e031-4534-b462-abdd1fb2b6c2" pid="F1ztVXajp0KzI20paqvTig" hash="ayViVA">And to help fill the courts with guests the king sent his servants out and they did bring them in.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p32" guid="647dff1d-529a-4436-b14a-caf647f25729" pid="lsh-eDdsAkGVLUGXQVB55g" hash="ptuQpQ">The Savior continues, “And when the king came in to see the guests, he saw there a man which had not on a wedding garment.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p33" guid="6cc059d0-d94e-4dc6-8c81-41e525e1ea5b" pid="Urg1C5Um-ES-GsEx478Meg" hash="MNJvZA">Now wedding suits were a very important part of the wedding celebration during this period. “And he saith unto him, Friend, how camest thou in hither not having a wedding garment? [Can you imagine going to a modern wedding reception today without proper attire? Your host might say, “Why did you come tonight without a tuxedo?”] And he was speechless.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p34" guid="861a53a2-e79e-437c-b659-6b3c64904f66" pid="5PdCtfKhR0G835uTUOAy6A" hash="Fun3BQ">“Then said the king to the servants, Bind him hand and foot, and take him away, and cast him into outer darkness; there shall be weeping and gnashing of teeth.” (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.2-13" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:2–13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p35" guid="76eef894-3d61-4620-a279-0746488472e6" pid="cEuPncZQUEa-iO16peay3Q" hash="lCbf-w">I used to be a little puzzled about that last part, and now I think I know why we have so many Latter-day Saint dentists.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p36" guid="29462275-1dec-4784-a05b-171dc429b45c" pid="Hzw48bI9X0KxvG_GW3mlRA" hash="_JYhWQ">Again let me translate that marvelous scripture, using a little more modern phraseology for you young people. Think now of the wedding garment as yours and my character. And when the king, our Heavenly Father, came in to see us, his children, he saw there one of us who had not on a good, moral character.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p37" guid="c43892a7-d3c3-40d5-a92e-6d76afdef177" pid="EuZZYSJ9c0CGKzxhTuIdSQ" hash="wphXpg">And he saith unto him, “How comest thou in hither, not having a pure, undefiled character?” And you and I were speechless. And then our Heavenly Father said, “Bind him, and take him out of my presence forever.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth.p38" guid="9b1f4bb4-4f96-4f89-89ce-2165fc7acf59" pid="laE77uLHwUO0Jwg3fLJz7w" hash="kvNAGg">I didn’t say that, young people. The Lord did. And our purpose here is to teach you the doctrines of the kingdom. Know of our love, faith, and trust in you, for the future looms bright in terms of your gospel commitment. May you and I together walk down the Lord’s road in peace and harmony is my humble prayer, as I bear witness to these things, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/04/young-people-learn-wisdom-in-thy-youth</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1971-general-conference/1971-04-7030-elder-paul-h-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="8664234" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is a Teacher?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We have been taught well in this great conference, my brothers and sisters, and I have been thinking a great deal about teaching and great teachers. Last evening, Elder Marion D. Hanks brought to our attention the situation concerning his departed co</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03012_000_6030" doc-version="2" hash="v6r05g"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="wvHwthNQP0ywuH04ckeOew" hash="5xzCrg">What Is a Teacher?</h1><p class="authorName" guid="74719440-7a80-44ef-bc3f-eb57a10732cb" pid="2g17tSB_Uk6OS8y1TABabg" hash="2gvHCQ">Paul H. Dunn</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="d8917f54-65d3-4563-86cc-22f72686f02c">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3396.jpg" alt="Conference photo" guid="a3270142-4936-4cac-9888-982f472c724e" pid="4lh4yXA94ECNJ_VDT6DyRg" hash="UpGYbQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p1" guid="76ae10ca-9868-4d36-9a00-62f6dca67c6e" pid="wibfaABx_0OydPvZNfYD5Q" hash="RumPUg">We have been taught well in this great conference, my brothers and sisters, and I have been thinking a great deal about teaching and great teachers. Last evening, Elder Marion D. Hanks brought to our attention the situation concerning his departed cousin, a Brother [Ivan] Frame, who had a deep impact on humanity. He mentioned that one of the great tributes paid at his funeral was that every boy should have a Brother Frame in his life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p2" guid="3c19b9b5-2017-4525-9fb5-d22cab9af8b5" pid="iCnj_t3Z1Emm8cFbv4CR2g" hash="zhhcTQ">I have thought about that, and I thank God repeatedly for such an individual in my life. He was a 78-year-old man who was assigned to be a priests adviser to six of us who were in our struggling teens and challenged with the future. His name was Charles B. Stewart. His son is here today as president of the great Tabernacle Choir.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p3" guid="df22d8c7-614d-47f8-a190-1c8fb1ee5fca" pid="KCIcjdHYQUyRlr0VT89doA" hash="Po-IRQ">I don’t know what you thought about a 78-year-old man when you were 16, but some of us questioned the wisdom of our bishop, for we thought he had literally brought Moses back.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p4" guid="7b387ec7-ec37-43e3-ba57-67bf0a2af08d" pid="z-ujxCHRJEWiLPiksEVRXg" hash="eQlxZg">I remember the first day I reported to my class in that rickety old upper room of the Hollywood Ward. There was that kind, gentle man to greet me. He took me by the hand as he had the other boys and said, “You’re Harold Dunn’s son, aren’t you?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p5" guid="7885cc6b-8c46-495b-b1a7-88aab5418b02" pid="Qs2Kt7afoU6J4jMSgj_84g" hash="N5HvPg">I said, “Yes, sir.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p6" guid="dc245b57-49ba-439c-8b11-92ac883455fe" pid="KJMoXfvyrk6xC3GhLgX5IA" hash="LkSOWw">He talked a little bit about me, my family, and showed a great personal interest. And then he said, “Paul, one of the requirements for being a member of this class is to think a new thought every day.” He said, “Do you have one this morning?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p7" guid="ae97cb4b-a251-44e9-84f0-5f3d6c32ce72" pid="ywqkztoc0EKEb3DI1IOv0w" hash="MSt6Og">Well now, I hadn’t had a new thought in years, and he could see my plight, and he said, “All right, I will teach you one. Listen carefully. ‘Attention is the mother of memory.’ Now can you repeat it back?” And I tried and finally gave it back to him. He permitted me to enter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p8" guid="50d1bac0-3949-4a36-9614-4aea6ae3e4ad" pid="w2FJiv6i80-0H8NDYG1fhg" hash="RVOHMA">We had a wonderful class. It ended; as I went to leave he said, “I forgot to tell you—before you go home you’ve got to give me another new idea.” I thought, I won’t go home. I didn’t have one, and so he said, “Now listen very carefully and I will teach you one that you’ll always remember.” He said, “‘Oh, what a tangled web we weave, When first we practise to deceive.’” I’ve never forgotten it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p9" guid="12057029-09f9-44ee-9648-be4ee75fa523" pid="ZFYMCiBG50G0p6Qi-UThQQ" hash="3TiMWw">Another week passed, and we went through a similar experience. I still didn’t have a new thought. He said, “Listen very carefully. ‘There’s an odd little voice ever speaking within that prompts us to duty and warns us from sin. And what is most strange, it makes itself heard, though it gives not a sound and says never a word.’” And I’ve never forgotten that one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p10" guid="fca60d3e-5a83-4bcc-996c-e9ffcc2b961f" pid="B0zd40DuVEi7-nZPvj_0ew" hash="s-QYVA">I started to go home and found he wouldn’t let me go until I cited another. When I couldn’t he said, “Listen carefully. ‘There was a wise old owl who sat in an oak, and the longer he sat the less he spoke. The less he spoke, the more he heard. Oh, Paul, why can’t you be like that wise old bird?’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p11" guid="bdf8fcab-f29c-46da-ae1b-a85e3ac57f2e" pid="VGM_b-DS60qIzXzHHYpxAQ" hash="ac_tKQ">I’ve thought a lot about that since. Still another week and another great thought. He said, “‘Remember, young man, example sheds a genial ray which men are apt to borrow. So first improve yourself today and then your friends tomorrow.’” And I haven’t forgotten that concept either.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p12" guid="ba49c012-ce35-4ce8-a142-2f5b4f8975ba" pid="uTAvp09dP0-VvtJ4ShXYzA" hash="Sr0JUA">Time won’t permit a number of others. Two years later I found myself in the fighting forces of our country. I was on the island of Okinawa. I received a letter from Mrs. Stewart, and it told me of the sad news that my kind friend and adviser had passed away. In it she had attached a half-written letter from Brother Stewart to me, and he said: “Dear Paul, I’ve been thinking about you in that far-off country, discouraged, I’m sure, and somewhat depressed; and in order to build your spirits, I have included some additional gem thoughts.” There were twenty-five new ideas, and I have never forgotten them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p13" guid="ad92ea80-0b30-4788-b806-9a20bdd23827" pid="DSGZc-h7SEuxhK5pkJvKYg" hash="zhVF1w">Thank God for people who care, for the Frames and Stewarts. I have since counted on my hand five such teachers who have influenced me for good. I would agree with Elder Hanks; there ought to be a Brother Stewart and a Brother Frame in every boy’s life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p14" guid="29c30c11-ef07-49b4-9039-684ead080353" pid="41AkFC6uPkGbQ2S6oAzfDw" hash="pEpJRQ">What is a teacher? The teacher is a prophet. He lays the foundation of tomorrow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p15" guid="af7fb7ca-cbf6-46b9-8be1-6b7b3f0d00c2" pid="NMtrKppMV0egCsBnWlzqXw" hash="D5Ycfw">The teacher is an artist. He works with the precious clay of unfolding personality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p16" guid="3a001323-3f07-42d2-9f3a-45815d1d38ce" pid="wkiXCSFogEmbeYTugmyQVw" hash="wZDTtw">The teacher is a friend. His heart responds to the faith and devotion of his students.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p17" guid="6e5aa0bd-e7d2-4322-a781-ebad1914a27a" pid="Q9D96Mcvd0WzyU_pn6ls-Q" hash="qh1WvA">The teacher is a citizen. He is selected and licensed for the improvement of society.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p18" guid="3cf9b0ee-857b-4063-80cf-2439c21d2ea8" pid="IM2rI6zfPEakaJVILc713Q" hash="LIL_cw">The teacher is an interpreter. Out of his mature and wider life, he seeks to guide the young.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p19" guid="c7a6e934-b6b5-4670-a4ea-7d2eaf9acb8a" pid="0v5YQYRR3E-lb2WdFLB_tg" hash="hzEQKQ">The teacher is a builder. He works with the higher and finer values of civilization.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p20" guid="29353c69-e927-4da0-98ed-9283e7d5063a" pid="nQylSyGorkGWVAb9hKnEQA" hash="U8dkbw">The teacher is a culture-bearer. He leads the way toward worthier tastes, saner attitudes, more gracious manners, higher intelligence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p21" guid="03568be3-0942-46a1-9f67-4d6b6fb1db16" pid="kq8DSfUlj0CxID_KVQ-gqw" hash="jZ69Ug">The teacher is a planner. He sees the young lives before him as a part of a great system that shall grow stronger in the light of truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p22" guid="e4874374-2d3b-4e08-84c6-e9e3c6c831c0" pid="4Ws7kSRAJUy28QF1XspXlg" hash="Bzh55Q">The teacher is a pioneer. He is always interpreting and attempting the impossible, and usually winning out.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p23" guid="aafc8c95-7f8c-4c2f-9d80-b1b2fbe57082" pid="vhbyT2-lMUWXgVEn8mDEcg" hash="A9r4aA">The teacher is a reformer. He seeks to improve the handicaps that weaken and destroy life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p24" guid="0a2766c1-12f8-432e-bbd3-41cc9465a77c" pid="Gxu3UbvjvkGYN4njeMqu4g" hash="gv6LNw">The teacher is a believer. He has an abiding faith in God and in the improvability of the race. It was James Truslow Adams who said, “There are obviously two educations. One should teach us how to make a living, and the other how to live.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p25" guid="7e2f785d-237a-4dfc-8489-3f956b7540ee" pid="3m1_dXRgm0yQMUpUd-TWxQ" hash="SQQ0pw">
        <span class="emphasis">We </span>are engaged in teaching people how to live.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p26" guid="dd4379f4-d303-48d1-8a6e-88cc1a58eed6" pid="azq6-XemJEigXSGKaP0gsw" hash="7aHL6g">Elbert Hubbard said, “You can’t teach anybody anything. You can only help him find himself.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p27" guid="209601a1-741c-44ac-8b65-baddfa44a008" pid="PDvQnQkyl0Kb4-x0dTA6vA" hash="mn93kA">That was the genius of the Savior. He taught us divine principles we could apply to ourselves and thus solve our personal problems. The Savior had no peer as a teacher.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p28" guid="0aa03893-d6ce-4e83-ab72-672b7f562197" pid="DbW53DrYykWQA2Q8PSVRVA" hash="8n1icA">For just a moment, let me walk you through the fifteenth chapter of Luke, wherein this great master teacher tells us how to solve problems that we all face. Luke records that there drew near him a great multitude, the publicans, the sinners, the Pharisees, the Sadducees, and he spake unto them this parable, saying: “What man of you, having an hundred sheep, if he lose one of them, doth not leave the ninety and nine … and go after that which is lost.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p29" guid="ee72f716-b6bc-4f4c-bc71-3edca6c953e3" pid="z8Bq-XrhyUCjJQyef9sXog" hash="mPl78A">Then he tells about the rejoicing moment when the sheep is found. And then, without even a pause, he goes into a second parable like unto it, which says: “Either what woman having ten pieces of silver, if she lose one piece, doth not light a candle, and sweep the house, and seek diligently till she find it.” And she too rejoices with her neighbors. (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15.4,8" class="scriptureRef">Luke 15:4, 8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p30" guid="d3ba9486-798c-4215-9cd2-0955fee0ba9e" pid="OS6mvCi9XU6-D7EKSCiTTA" hash="QGmIBA">And then he goes into that parable of parables, the Prodigal Son: “A certain man had two sons: And the younger of them said to his father, ‘Father, give me the portion of goods that falleth to me.’” And we recognize how with his agency he squandered it all. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15.11-32" class="scriptureRef">Luke 15:11–32</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p31" guid="79a90e60-6660-436f-a6f8-0cb1c79970dd" pid="d7pBAhkQ6kiOKsakGIo3Uw" hash="IBOr9Q">I used to wonder, as a teacher so-called, why the Savior would spend time citing three parables about things that get lost. And then one day it dawned. People do get lost in various ways, and here in this great chapter of Luke we find the Savior counseling how to recover them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p32" guid="106f2f64-38b3-40c6-aee6-0ecee7852de0" pid="XAFeZWqi3Ee9ZsFL7esgcQ" hash="dwO7pw">Permit me this observation: The Savior might say to us today, if he were to teach this parable again, that sheep (or people who get lost) are not basically sinners by nature or even choice, but people, like sheep, get confused in what’s important. In other words, they have misplaced values. And I am sure the Savior would say to the teacher in the classroom, to the adviser, “If you want to retrieve this kind of person, put a higher value in place of the one he now elects.” Family, service, brotherhood are all greener pastures for today’s sheep. Feeding here brings them home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p33" guid="28fd8ad5-3ae8-42d5-9cd3-d23005ba7fe6" pid="-MsKAnRJZkWAv_1WThCFBA" hash="Cd-i1A">Next, he talks about lost coins. This whole conference has talked about precious coins that become lost—young people, if you please. And there are those of us who are the responsible agents who, like the woman of this great teaching parable, let these priceless gems slip through our fingers. Certainly we wouldn’t recover this kind of lost article the way we would a sheep. He would say love, care, and attention would be the process used to recover lost coins (or people).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p34" guid="d78b30ef-0630-4fa3-be53-222bebc1dece" pid="WOnR7sLXmE-AcKvSX-Yi-g" hash="Hm2kJQ">And then the great parable of the Prodigal Son, with the Savior saying that there are those who get lost by choice; and in the concluding of that parable, he says: “And when he came to himself he [the Prodigal Son] said, How many hired servants of my father’s have bread enough and to spare. …” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/15.17" class="scriptureRef">Luke 15:17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p35" guid="109f3212-25ed-4e8c-a26d-8e1113b27e97" pid="MYCo9qk__kmMy1Jgs1LKyg" hash="05SMzg">There are those who get lost because their free agency takes them down that path. We can’t do a lot at some points to recover this kind of a person except open our arms and our church doors and let them know they are wanted. Teachers and advisers are really needed here. But note: he came to himself. He repented, sought forgiveness, and came home. Many people are like the Prodigal Son.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p36" guid="a0186aaa-e3d4-4013-b772-f3ab02985619" pid="c6Q1jW1zWEy94ALZBdljhQ" hash="_MUVww">Let me just say as a concluding thought that this is a <span class="emphasis">positive </span>gospel. We ought to be the happiest people in the world. The gospel of Jesus Christ is a great building force. It teaches people to be happy and to always wear a smile. But sometimes we neglect the simple things that mean the most. Most people in the rush of modern life never know real friendship and the warmth that the gospel and even a smile can bring.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p37" guid="7839478f-cc44-4769-87cc-5ede11c679f5" pid="5Yg25SzbsEi_dbILmoIr8g" hash="rdWhAQ">An acquaintance of mine recently said to me as we walked down the street and noticed a man with a sour face, “He looks like he was weaned on lemon juice and a dill pickle.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p38" guid="cd2551cb-61e8-4304-9803-4da14067165b" pid="jJkODrauxUmzK3S09GuILA" hash="HXsiDw">I also heard about a mother and her young daughter who were listening to a public speaker when the child said to her mother, “Isn’t that man happy?” The mother replied. “I guess so.” To which the girl remarked: “Why doesn’t he tell his face?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p39" guid="4b7e1672-d0e5-4416-be09-deb27c930c20" pid="jCFF_ZNR_kCO2qaa0UjlNQ" hash="ugxTSg">I think our Heavenly Father would be most disappointed if he saw the expressions of some of us who have all that the world contains and fail to incorporate it into our lives and share it with others. The meaning and purpose of the gospel of Jesus Christ to me is that it brings joy and happiness, peace and contentment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p40" guid="d50ce000-e465-4bdf-b523-6fe7f0fab694" pid="GCESlv_KL0O2EWRbuqgC6A" hash="3zl8Dw">We all have problems. The world is sick with problems. And yet in these sacred words, in the standard works, are the solutions to the problems we face. Let us encourage the world to know the word of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p41" guid="3afa805e-57fe-4e2b-8cdf-cc31fd3841a4" pid="XdYPEXrLQkKx1EFud4JeXQ" hash="z3Xcvw">There are forty-three other parables in the New Testament that teach us how to help people. Search the scriptures, for in them ye shall find the way to eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p42" guid="88daa293-73d7-4814-a1ac-d157f4d7926c" pid="7LSdSsET8EG1-01_sToJ4Q" hash="sYtpOA">My testimony is that the gospel is true and that it works.</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.f1" guid="a47f53a2-eaa1-4683-9ca3-f61e0b6fd2c4">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="EH3UK-LCLkGXccoMGclzNQ" hash="Vvm7Mg">I gave a beggar from my store of wealth</p>
          <p class="line" pid="2BunbaqfDkWT3b44ekxowA" hash="VnvkuQ">Some gold. He spent the shining ore,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="YbxPn7NWAU6JsVeTw874Tg" hash="OGShbA">And came again, and yet again,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="wKX5usCjtkiOg_0hj4Rs0A" hash="zh60IA">Still cold and hungry, as before.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="gF9G4p87CkKUKE6NiXBHsw" hash="jR2VbA">I gave a thought, and through that thought of mine</p>
          <p class="line" pid="N95JoFFnxUGv59OPkQhpWw" hash="vFcy5g">He found himself, the man, supreme, divine—</p>
          <p class="line" pid="4rVNHsryOE268vHrYE4qmg" hash="E0Qtng">Fed, clothed, and crowned with blessings manifold</p>
          <p class="line" pid="sgxK7GMq1kOO0TzAzx5aNg" hash="duImvg">And now he begs no more.</p>
        </div>
        <p class="citationInfo" pid="Jfrqx-itTUGsoHU9YSD5Tw" hash="XJAeSQ">(Adapted from “The True Gift,” Author Unknown)</p>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher.p43" guid="cd5071df-b3e4-4d5c-b154-07daaa36c359" pid="SZcReLDqxkKYTZteq0RreA" hash="sN2vmg">Such is the gospel of Jesus Christ, to which I bear solemn testimony in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/10/what-is-a-teacher</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1971-general-conference/1971-10-6030-elder-paul-h-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="6991208" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 1971 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Know Thyself, Control Thyself, Give Thyself</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My brethren, this is an awesome occasion for me, and I need your support and the Spirit of my Heavenly Father. As Brother Fyans was describing the length of the materials going around the world, I thought back to an English literature text I had in h</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03020_000_5040" doc-version="2" hash="0Iezug"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="8x0ASE-JxEWCsqCuaMnrUw" hash="y2oV3g">Know Thyself, Control Thyself, Give Thyself</h1><p class="authorName" guid="74719440-7a80-44ef-bc3f-eb57a10732cb" pid="o3eUcRPmBkC5t_tMXRkRqQ" hash="2gvHCQ">Paul H. Dunn</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="a4fe3ba1-e872-4ee1-a438-c373380216ee">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3396.jpg" alt="President Paul H. Dunn" guid="401a6102-6c77-47ab-b183-f05015c4c045" pid="d-TGYO7FV0GoS4sv53woMQ" hash="UpGYbQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p1" guid="f67d425b-7559-4f15-8961-5c3c28052ea5" pid="rAyP5TCoP0G8nN7QKje5Iw" hash="sidxOQ">My brethren, this is an awesome occasion for me, and I need your support and the Spirit of my Heavenly Father. As Brother Fyans was describing the length of the materials going around the world, I thought back to an English literature text I had in high school that was about that long and deep.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p2" guid="dcb4f101-64e6-46eb-b7ae-b5ba6ba3ff92" pid="zAnZjDzcWUObWugHTtcWIA" hash="W0kDlQ">I am so honored to be here on this wonderful occasion, to sit at the feet of a prophet of the Lord, to hear his counsel and direction, and to feel his spirit. I was particularly impressed with a number of the younger priesthood bearers in the audience who were taking notes, listening to a prophet. I would hope that you young priesthood bearers tonight have the sensitivity to go home and record what has happened in your life on this wonderful occasion. Think how many people in the world would be so honored, to sit in a special meeting with prophets, seers, and revelators.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p3" guid="0614247e-d45d-413c-90b0-c30ece905e24" pid="Fd1xm6ZqLEuX2H4CMSsd6A" hash="INOULg">I salute you fathers who have brought your sons to this meeting, and to others in buildings throughout the country. You young priesthood bearers might as well learn early that your dads and moms will never let you go. This was brought very vividly to my attention several conferences ago when one of the sessions in which I was a speaker was televised to California. My mother resides there.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p4" guid="2ebb5a06-2e6e-453b-b9ba-880a16f43c74" pid="5KaZYvpTbE2UqI5TQtrztQ" hash="KhxKSw">When I got back to the office after the session was over, there was a note to “call your mother.” And so I did, and I thought, “Well, she is calling to congratulate her son.” When I reached her on the phone I asked, “Mom, how are you?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p5" guid="61bd1f04-e353-4a2c-8fc4-b04d1981f81f" pid="lcEC9XtPEEKEKJBgk723LQ" hash="vpKLiA">She said, “Paul, I just saw you on TV. Young man, you are not getting enough sleep. You look terrible.” Thank God for parents who care and who never let go!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p6" guid="57b383ac-ed8d-4048-8411-c8b4396cd0d4" pid="G398CrdrC0ebk-EEPVYeqQ" hash="6rePsQ">I am grateful for you priesthood leaders, you wonderful bishops and counselors, stake presidencies, others who have precious priesthood assignments. I think of many bishops and other leaders in my life as I look out over this great audience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p7" guid="e33acf35-46bf-46e5-8f8c-24e975fe5348" pid="1rBO7xm9LEW4vGoQ_x6nCw" hash="Id5keQ">Not long ago I had an opportunity to speak in Portland, Oregon. Lo and behold, in the audience was my former bishop, Raymond Kirkham. He was my bishop when I was an Aaronic Priesthood boy. I had the courage to call on him—and you know that can be risky, to call on a bishop who remembers you when you were a boy. I reminded him as he took the pulpit, “Remember, I am the last speaker.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p8" guid="2a8b0e4b-1639-41a4-b9ff-17fa8cde4741" pid="ivFrixJ8pECsW92_d2_ALg" hash="7pg1XA">He got bold and told those young people of some interesting experiences involving my youth. He said, “I knew this young man was destined for a position of leadership. He is the only deacon I ever had who, after passing the sacrament, could crawl under a bench and get out the back door before I recognized he was gone.” He said, “I knew he was going all the way, because he took the whole quorum with him.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p9" guid="46630364-bac8-44c4-9691-43bf20d4657d" pid="tUFz_e8rz0-KmVbQztf8qw" hash="oEVAxA">Now you young priesthood bearers, I have repented; and I am grateful for bishops who stood at the back door and redirected my paths.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p10" guid="009cf65e-7e2e-4d67-86ab-d3334dc669aa" pid="fCitwqbM40CD6jCKMGI12g" hash="DReCCQ">I have been impressed here tonight with a number of things. I have reflected upon the great talks of this conference, wonderful sermons, good counsel and advice. Tonight I would like to summarize my feelings, directed to you, the Aaronic Priesthood, for what value it might have in your lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p11" guid="1a7ff87e-3744-4676-ac97-a5477e1f7eab" pid="ApSI6Cw3JEG5t0qlzeXQUQ" hash="os9F7A">I think if I could give a whole sermon in just six words it would be these: Socrates said many years ago, <span class="emphasis">“Know thyself,” </span>Cicero said, <span class="emphasis">“Control thyself,” </span>and the Savior said, <span class="emphasis">“Give thyself.” </span>Now will you write that down, young brethren; contemplate the meaning while I just share a thought concerning each one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p12" guid="da4a0aca-681a-475b-8b02-c74cc503d4df" pid="fqiCiEt7RkG7z_ngdSmcbw" hash="lhiEYw">To know thyself is to come to know that you and I as priesthood bearers are literally the offspring of Deity; and that means, young men, that you and I were born to succeed; that in the preexistence you and I earned a right by our faithfulness and by our commitment to worthy principles to come into mortality in order that we might learn through the priesthood how to become like our Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p13" guid="e4dd9410-8a92-4cab-a8de-fa6d5c64420b" pid="xjuff4jUDEOaLUiZmaub-A" hash="BJzvSw">That means, if I understand the gospel correctly, that there isn’t one single failure among us. The word <span class="emphasis">can’t </span>is false doctrine in the Mormon Church. When a young man says to me, “I can’t do it,” I become concerned because in a sense he is saying, “I don’t understand the gospel.” He may not be motivated; he may have discouragements; there may be barriers in his life; but you <span class="emphasis">can </span>succeed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p14" guid="c566e815-4505-4de3-bdc0-c9d59a4237dd" pid="aBJaF-sD_k-oSJqJqX5d9w" hash="WScqOg">I promise you young priesthood bearers that if you really come to know who you are through the scriptures and through the revealed doctrine of this church, you can accomplish anything you want in this life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p15" guid="0473ee7c-c425-42b4-8847-1c993c5b0309" pid="drkB3aJ5K0SqPqZfq5pbsQ" hash="ILza1w">I don’t mean to suggest by this that you won’t stumble a time or two. That is a part of the growing process. The lives of many great men will testify to you that ofttimes they have many failures, and there is no disgrace in falling down; the disgrace is lying there. To get up one more time than you fall is to be a winner. To stay down is to be a loser.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p16" guid="1161cbdc-69b3-4077-9f16-41478aee5ae4" pid="Vqf-EwTN_UqWkCn33yK6Zg" hash="AISUVA">I think of that great immortal athlete, Babe Ruth, when I talk about the principle of success and particularly failure. Let me just share a little experience from his life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p17" guid="9222d5d4-a71d-466d-a0bd-6dbcb7b26e64" pid="srDr7XQFIEmR3YjZndUy5w" hash="NEPXSA">It was a beautiful Saturday afternoon in the summer of 1927, and 35,000 wildly excited baseball fans packed Shibe Park. They were giving Babe Ruth the “razzberry”—and good! Lefty (Bob) Grove, one of the greatest left-handed pitchers of all time, had just struck out Babe Ruth on three consecutive pitched balls for the second successive time. Two runners were stranded on the bases.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p18" guid="660d1b98-5da5-42e7-996b-f7db205b45ee" pid="yVwRf5xQKkaLP4HrIAiqHQ" hash="MM1urA">As the great slugger returned to the bench, amidst wild and abusive jeering, he looked up into the stands with an unruffled smile, just as he did the first time, gave his cap a polite little tip from his perspiring brow, stepped down into the dugout, and calmly took a drink of water.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p19" guid="c87e92e3-ff45-4ccd-bd23-905f60586858" pid="zmRRIfOF0Eq8kDRcCKOzTQ" hash="QU0q5Q">In the eighth inning, when he came up for his third time at bat, the situation was critical. The Athletics were leading the Yankees, 3–1. The bases were full and two were out. As Babe selected his favorite bat and started toward the plate, the crowd rose in a body, as if by signal. The excitement was tremendous!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p20" guid="61541383-e52d-477f-a374-78e0cb204dd1" pid="GBSS9-zc5EiZ-tjkZbOT_w" hash="du9FTQ">“Strike ‘im out again!” pleaded the fans to Grove. Strutting around the pitcher’s box, it was easy to see that the big southpaw believed he was just going to do that.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p21" guid="1ca63206-d2d2-4deb-813c-1746ca76f300" pid="wqd1Q2G4LkqIITfvOOcP0Q" hash="kO9UvA">As the mighty batter took his position, the crowd became hysterical. There was a pause. Mickey Cochrane, the A’s great catcher, crouched to give the signal. Grove threw one with lightning speed. Ruth swung; it was a foul tip. “Str—ike one!” roared the umpire. Again the signal, and the pitch was too fast to follow. Again, Babe took that magnificent swing—and missed. “Stri—i-i-ke two!” was the call.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p22" guid="97281aa5-f737-41e1-9f40-1109ed6dffde" pid="tqQa-1lhi0CvpcmzoaUWCQ" hash="BcG3MQ">Ruth staggered and went down. He had literally swung himself off his feet. There was a cloud of dust as the big fellow sprawled on the ground. The crowd was going mad. Finally, regaining his feet, the “Bambino” brushed the dust off his trousers, dried his hands, and got set for the next pitch. Grove delivered the ball so fast not a single fan could see it. Babe swung—but this time he connected! It was only a split second before everybody seemed to realize what had happened. That ball was never coming back.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p23" guid="5d493f91-148e-465e-aabf-644d15d8e354" pid="SQGI4DG9LUOJ4oPg0LMa6Q" hash="jIVdpQ">It disappeared over the scoreboard and cleared the houses across the street —one of the longest hits ever recorded.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p24" guid="ac026e94-37ef-44a1-9c2f-07146a9fc55b" pid="o_R-uPGYkkqmROOx4tM-BQ" hash="j09jWQ">As Babe Ruth trotted around the bases and across the plate behind the other runners—with what proved to be the winning run—he received a wild ovation from the crowd.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p25" guid="cd2dfb99-d9c9-4e7b-bb8a-7ce77249d732" pid="EtsmxgvOIkSvbnIVKHCobw" hash="0XSL8w">Ruth doffed his cap with that little smile, and the expression on his face was exactly like the one he wore on his first two trips, when he had gone down swinging.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p26" guid="7ff75b1a-4aa7-4fd6-bfaa-01742c2d58f3" pid="Blrja-qaQkyzcLJA0MkGDg" hash="IUWjRQ">Later in the season, after the Yanks clinched the American League pennant, Grantland Rice, interviewing the Babe, asked, “What do you do when you get in a batting slump?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p27" guid="a6109073-dc19-4a1f-ad72-13b91f3538bd" pid="3RCMzaEy9k2GL6bSlb3B6Q" hash="q8zagQ">Babe replied: “I just keep goin’ up there and keep swingin’. I know the old law of averages will hold good for me the same as it does for anybody else, if I keep havin’ my healthy swings. If I strike out two or three times in a game, or fail to get a hit for a week, why should I worry? Let the pitchers worry; they’re the guys who’re gonna have to pay for it later on.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p28" guid="4eab227e-2281-4806-8c78-3935d57ed082" pid="8PpJxHvQR069Vz4zWrHQ6w" hash="2_ELww">This unshakable faith in making the law of averages work for him enabled Babe Ruth to accept his bad breaks and failures with a smile. This simple philosophy had much to do with making him baseball’s greatest slugger. His attitude of taking both good and bad in stride made him one of the game’s greatest heroes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p29" guid="e36bd857-8237-4f7b-9c0a-407438ac19c8" pid="unkyVd3O3US2EhtIcy09CA" hash="o5TEIQ">Why is it, when we read about great athletes or men in other professions, we are seldom told about their failures? For example, we now read of the amazing record of the immortal Babe Ruth, with his total of 714 home runs; but another unapproached world’s record of his is carefully buried, and that is that he struck out more times than any other player in history—1,330 times!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p30" guid="369ad00a-5db4-45d7-900d-65a75502e82c" pid="RUsGAbtw5UaubNwz_4KvMw" hash="xJR0Ew">One thousand three hundred and thirty times he suffered the humiliation of walking back to the bench amidst jeers and ridicule. But he never allowed fear or discouragement or failure to keep him down.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p31" guid="6e0e4e1b-c103-425b-8048-a8a524c86af0" pid="stjreG5ZxEq2Ql6UIYsfZg" hash="5tbaXQ">Someone has said that success consists not in never falling, but in rising every time you fall. Get up one more time than you go down, young people, and you will win. Stay down, and you lose.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p32" guid="524f8e1b-1b3b-47c1-8c80-2299ac323b11" pid="qj5DDsRAZkakgMN7I9p7OQ" hash="pyActg">My father used to say, “Paul, there are dozens of rules for success, but none of them work unless you do.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p33" guid="1b3687c7-e82f-412a-b800-3ef158ad7850" pid="GGJophZMlkCgh0Fpiiqwtw" hash="zc_ZXA">Cicero said, “Control thyself.” I had the opportunity in World War II to bat against the immortal Bob Feller in a servicemen’s game. If you ever want a lesson in humility, bat against Feller. Bob Feller had a unique distinction as a sixteen-year-old boy. He could take a 9 1/2-inch, 5-ounce baseball and throw it from 60 feet 6 inches, 105 miles an hour.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p34" guid="cbeedf38-ad07-4b3a-9cc3-9a4c5246748d" pid="-k_2jGMzuUakvRlk1jYDQw" hash="vrNKMQ">Now that may not impress you, but you go to bat and you’re very impressed. To those of you who may not understand that velocity, a 9-inch baseball is the size of an aspirin tablet at 60 feet 6 inches, at 100 miles per hour. I submit to you, it makes a difference which side of the plate he throws it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p35" guid="39af32c7-c8ba-4117-9f99-85113eb79ac7" pid="MZNfOreFJE2x2HDIQnEQFA" hash="xWDLbg">Bob Feller at age sixteen had a problem. <span class="emphasis">He lacked control. </span>He was a great athlete. He had tremendous capacity. He was born to succeed. He knew himself, but he hadn’t disciplined his great talent of speed, so that it was questionable as to whether he would stick in the majors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p36" guid="d40e7faa-d42e-4de1-b372-206732b2a11e" pid="e4cW30O_1UWEKIV-UGJpbw" hash="H6R5sQ">But Bob Feller became the great athlete he was because he listened to wise counsel. He had great coaches, and one of them took him aside one day and said, “Bob, it really doesn’t matter whether you throw 105 miles an hour or 95. If you will take a little speed off your pitch and put the ball where it belongs, you will succeed!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p37" guid="17e42752-e159-4998-89c1-b8af657d026e" pid="obAbd90oPEGPJFOc-oJmZA" hash="K_JutA">We call that <span class="emphasis">control </span>in baseball, and you little leaguers know how important control is to a pitcher. Bob listened and became the strike-out artist of his era.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p38" guid="16a896cb-58e7-4f76-afc5-ee605ca0ab00" pid="BCXDKJYMQEKgKqklMYXwbA" hash="ZMf4Dw">You don’t know Jim Rusick, I think, unless you are related to him. I played ball with Jim. Jim Rusick was a sixteen-year-old boy on the Hollywood High School baseball team. He could throw a 9 1/2-inch baseball 105 miles an hour, but he wouldn’t listen to counsel. He didn’t learn to control the talent that he had, and Jim has never been heard of since.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p39" guid="bf4d7930-9248-4ad2-97c0-843a5b70575b" pid="sDPv0NVzuESHM4qnTjqzeQ" hash="8FgpGA">It’s one thing to be born with ability to succeed; it’s another thing to harness it and to control it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p40" guid="3b10a98b-31e6-4b8f-97be-810f10c3b50e" pid="7bVEALh91k-FPqXx0i_77w" hash="Iqo5fQ">My young brethren, this is the purpose of the gospel of Jesus Christ, to control that which we have been born with. That is the purpose of the Church and its programs. We need to learn how to control that which God has given us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p41" guid="828eca19-ece3-4011-8a38-08b25ddae4cc" pid="v5K-_6zquEalfeJMtOuZUw" hash="6-p-Qw">Finally, the Savior said, Take all that I have given you, harness it, discipline it, and then give it to the world. Give thyself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p42" guid="c64f1f53-771d-405b-a663-49eae67abd28" pid="pYBJb_nWHkyfp6GZFXYNUQ" hash="7zFZeQ">Let me just conclude with a little experience I had recently in New England.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p43" guid="7ad267f2-5841-4c7a-84c7-698d21433e13" pid="Qg7M3Dn8b0a_gXIveAbglA" hash="C1TCKA">I think one of the greatest thrills that a mission president experiences is to receive a new missionary. I received notice from the First Presidency that eight young men were to be assigned to New England. Shortly they arrived. This was a great treat for Jeanne and me, as we greeted these new missionaries in the mission home. One by one, as they came in, we tried to set them at ease.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p44" guid="d9427ce6-5aa9-4e78-82a2-6592fd34b69c" pid="uP62z_FoV0iu9rH_DojaJA" hash="7r4JCg">The first one was a brilliant-looking boy. I won’t describe him, but I thought, “Thank heaven he is here.” The second was just like him, and the third and the fourth. Now this, I thought, will put our mission on top.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p45" guid="9ad04b89-f863-40c6-b071-61739df1a704" pid="Q_XaBGdgskOLsltU3Y3N2w" hash="Doi6Cg">Then I got down to number seven, and I don’t mind telling you some of the concerns of my heart. I thought, This will be a challenge. I couldn’t believe it; and unlike the counsel that President Tanner gave us not to judge our neighbors, here I was judging him. I thought, This kid just doesn’t have the image.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p46" guid="446f9370-e2c7-4dc7-8366-a498fb178b88" pid="imQOhQsWYEOePhNZ5-XLrQ" hash="LW4CaQ">My wife gave me a glance, and her look said, “Good luck for the next two years.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p47" guid="1a8e9790-681d-44f2-90f9-6baecfe25c74" pid="SByQjdcoTU6aiOmNHAJu7g" hash="5SkyNg">Let me just describe him to you. He was wearing a shirt that was size 17; his neck was an 11. I could have pulled out his collar and put another elder in it. He had on a coat that he inherited from his dad, and you couldn’t see his hands. He had a trench coat that he got from an uncle from World War I, and he had a haircut that was an Idaho original.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p48" guid="b2a6040e-1706-416b-aa2f-bab04955ed28" pid="c1r8jfdfskef6BD3DEb3Vw" hash="MSXU0Q">The New England Mission contains six of the United States and four provinces of Canada, including Labrador. As my wife and I lay in bed that night, she said, “What are you going to do with him?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p49" guid="5e37bc67-5fa3-4f34-8e0c-620054d0ae02" pid="gM_AC88REEKV8DP2jkMT2A" hash="D_SIjQ">I said, “It’s time to open up Labrador.” I thought I had to protect the Church’s image from this interesting-looking elder.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p50" guid="15abf88e-9744-43a6-80c8-cda9ba39b525" pid="Fa3voosXf02yDZytd9xq2g" hash="76DSrw">Well, that morning before I made my assignments, I knelt in prayer—thank the Lord for prayer—and I asked the Lord what I should do now; and the Spirit whispered, “Keep him in Cambridge.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p51" guid="acf0bd73-b742-426e-a210-a9268c2586c7" pid="ufofUUwhaUWM7_AYpCJDOw" hash="RSxivQ">And I said, “Spirit, I won’t.” I said, “I am the president of this mission.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p52" guid="f79b7366-0fa7-4e90-ba9d-4e4415cf2454" pid="qd7InYxzpUyXcJQtfXWvlA" hash="P-axQQ">And the Spirit seemed to respond with the counsel, “Yes, but you will keep him in Cambridge.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p53" guid="6ffebfe2-ecec-43a0-b90a-9ed62ce170f9" pid="xgAb_A7lCUacdQx_0eKsQg" hash="mkGuBQ">Cambridge is a very sophisticated area, with all of those universities and art centers. Well, I kept him. When I went down to breakfast, my two assistants were sitting there; and they said, “What are you going to do with him?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p54" guid="99827374-e50e-494d-a565-21961f295118" pid="s7TCsIRYfUOATO6v4LWlJA" hash="P2EHSQ">I said, “We are going to keep him in Cambridge.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p55" guid="b67f83dd-45c2-45c7-83f7-060267aef60d" pid="sVPE5w6M4kSJf0f5Tpt8JA" hash="cmPW6w">And they said, “President, you are kidding.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p56" guid="2f3a746e-b3b0-4e91-ac2e-2e5003ab9fed" pid="-Nz3J4S1ME2o7MNhdf50Uw" hash="JM4xEw">I said, “I have been seeking guidance all night, and we will keep him in Cambridge.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p57" guid="d61e87aa-6677-4b20-a8d6-b096e99e673e" pid="8QFpgexAW0Kl69evWeUfJw" hash="bWXN9A">Two days later I got a call from a distinguished professor. I haven’t time to give you the details. He said, “Paul, Friday night may I be baptized?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p58" guid="cd2af750-a353-414a-aa2a-61961b86e8b6" pid="OPTeCilZakOxeUj4N3SRlA" hash="2LqO-g">I questioned him a bit. He had been through several score of missionaries the past nine years. I said, “What happened?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p59" guid="7ce2cbfd-cdfc-4d74-bc71-81198a5b69ac" pid="KIezAnHthU-tGxrZ5PvaXQ" hash="duvAag">He said, “This little fellow you sent me.” (He was referring to my new elder.) And then he described the experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p60" guid="c2fcd175-d774-47ba-8a7a-aaa7dbdc00e6" pid="qo3G-PdzXEmREuWKpUP_PQ" hash="_QpGrA">He said, “No sooner had he and his companion entered the office and shook my hand when he asked, ‘Would you mind if we had a word of prayer?’” (This was a meeting over in his school office.) The professor said, “Not if it will do you any good.” Then he remarked, “Before I could get back to my desk, this little fellow fell on his knees and started to talk to the Lord.” And he said, “Paul, I looked up three times to see if the Lord was standing there.” He said, “I don’t know what happened to me; you describe it, but I had the most wonderful feeling come over me, and I now know what the Spirit is. I want to be baptized.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p61" guid="e7c2e3b9-9b29-4f14-8ab8-26ccace41652" pid="ekAxzcCij0-sYXGNX8nZAw" hash="A8h-LQ">We baptized him, and he is doing a fine work for the Church and is a great asset on campus. It was all accomplished because this young elder from Idaho, whom I had misjudged, guided by the Spirit, gave himself to the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p62" guid="448e723f-374b-4135-b21c-910c651534fc" pid="VIyG2tyzxk6pR93t_xvzsQ" hash="HcerUg">And I learned as President Tanner has taught us. Don’t judge! “Within the oyster shell uncouth, the purest pearl may hide, but oft you’ll find a heart of truth within a rough outside.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself.p63" guid="8c04b566-39c3-4661-8648-1ea34a63a1f9" pid="Vm4KyAkMCEC8aJ6T5nXnYQ" hash="bSE2ww">The Lord bless us, young brethren, to remember who we are, to control ourselves, and to give it to the Lord, to which I testify, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/04/know-thyself-control-thyself-give-thyself</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1972-general-conference/1972-04-5040-elder-paul-h-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="10097623" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 1972 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Strengthen Thy Brethren”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I am grateful for this opportunity, brothers and sisters, to add my witness to those that have been borne so beautifully here.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03027_000_4070" doc-version="2" hash="DGy50g"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="hpwrqUqeQ0eKFSVbMhX69Q" hash="Bt7A-A">“Strengthen Thy Brethren”</h1><p class="authorName" guid="74719440-7a80-44ef-bc3f-eb57a10732cb" pid="hywxdDpfXU6xldsR-_jfGw" hash="2gvHCQ">Paul H. Dunn</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="4449b645-697f-4f5a-a629-f07e01dede1a">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p1" guid="9cd95589-a022-46fb-9ddd-ef0890b4b2fa" pid="o3UEZunJYUGDyaGBcfWbGw" hash="-gt6tg">I am grateful for this opportunity, brothers and sisters, to add my witness to those that have been borne so beautifully here.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p2" guid="a61073ae-2510-4245-8cc5-513e5a516879" pid="riUXfRzwY0m7njOY3td1gQ" hash="o_1qUQ">The other night I was somewhat amused as I looked through an evening copy of the <span class="emphasis">Deseret News.</span> I noticed a picture depicting a problem that one of the Baptist churches in the South was having. It seems that their parking lot was being used by an adjoining establishment for commercial use, and the enterprising minister put this sign up at the entrance to the parking lot: “Warning—Violators will be baptized.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p3" guid="aa0cfa1d-0f3e-461b-992c-e4125a93556b" pid="e-ubE_INt0O0TnPH9ZseUA" hash="-SuL_Q">I couldn’t help but think of that as I have listened to the real warning of the Lord and the counsel from his servants during these two great days.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p4" guid="1efa41bc-8d7d-49f0-8c56-89fb0e3fac9d" pid="OuJy9EWoiUGKnqZiI9ogNA" hash="iMnTeQ">When the Lord appeared to the Nephites he said, “And again I say unto you, ye must repent, and be baptized in my name, and become as a little child, or ye can in nowise inherit the kingdom of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.38" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:38</a>.) That was his real warning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p5" guid="4c299c65-d9b6-474d-b9e0-6a97592a500b" pid="rpfgE77gfkeK_tdokVSiJQ" hash="TeYkuA">Just twenty-three years ago this fall, I entered Chapman College in Southern California as a student. I came under the wonderful influence of Dr. Guy M. Davis, philosopher, educator, and teacher. Twenty-three years later, just three weeks ago last Friday evening, I saw this magnificent man, with so brilliant a mind, become as a little child, as he entered the waters of baptism and became a member of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p6" guid="0bca745e-03c7-4a9f-a199-6a2d5d360b82" pid="B1LsVcLe1kyY3e1gXcyC1Q" hash="dOsFGg">I thought of another scripture as I witnessed that baptism experience of my friend. The Lord, admonishing his chief apostle Peter, as Luke records it, gave this simple counsel and direction: “… when thou art converted, strengthen thy brethren.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/22.32" class="scriptureRef">Luke 22:32</a>.) I pray the good bishop, the home teacher, the congregation of the ward to which Guy and his family have now been assigned will strengthen my brother.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p7" guid="73bb545b-9515-477b-8e45-00219a04d362" pid="ELYJkm8L_EiIZhpHnxlaEw" hash="K9h61w">Permit a personal experience for just a moment. Strengthening one’s brother, I think, comes closer to home when we think of fellowshiping and friendshiping our family. Some time ago when my youngest daughter was faced with the reality of attending a different school, she looked forward to the new experience with great anticipation and excitement but with the usual anxieties and concerns. Her mom and dad tried to make her experience meaningful, and one that would be positive, and we spent several hours attempting to prepare her mind for the new experience. We even planned a time when we could shop for new clothes and other special school supplies.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p8" guid="0c62eae8-e7a9-4e73-9907-1425b2116845" pid="YUJz2sqoYU2PjwoKacHUfQ" hash="SMyJLQ">Finally, the long-awaited day arrived. A special evening was planned to help give spiritual comfort and guidance. Later she put her clothes out in anticipation of the next day. As she retired to her bed, seemingly all was well, but about an hour later she appeared at my study door where I was making some preparations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p9" guid="465192a2-c458-45d1-81c8-9bd453e6f73b" pid="3HFME5rcf0-FgWtxpEgS5Q" hash="aT6SXA">“Dad,” she said, rubbing her tummy, “I don’t feel very well.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p10" guid="79b9b880-37d5-4acd-aa95-50387bdd152f" pid="vXZGhWojsUiI7CPSVR8wDw" hash="eGtJMA">You know the sign; and I thought I understood it, so I invited her in and sat her on my lap. We put on a little music that we liked to listen to together. I rubbed her tummy, and she soon fell asleep. I took her back upstairs, placed her in her bed, tiptoed toward the door; and she broke the silence with the announcement, “I am not asleep yet.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p11" guid="ee64aa6b-f50d-440b-877b-eb2adaf09203" pid="id53WOq9QkmX0-qK6vJKhA" hash="jZ4gGg">I went back and lay down on the bed with her, stroked her head, gave what fatherly counsel one could under the circumstances, and reassured her. Finally she fell asleep. The next morning she appeared at breakfast in her petticoat. She said, “Dad, I don’t think I had better go to school today.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p12" guid="1206e80f-5315-4c0f-ae20-c004a4fdd51a" pid="SMfdvhQyUUqoL6hHSzMOQw" hash="aI5R8Q">I said, “Why not?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p13" guid="9746508c-7ca3-4eff-bd4e-1c2950233714" pid="QeU084Zk0EuHZ7KC9YYxfg" hash="8uh-LQ">She said, “I think I am going to get sick.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p14" guid="c5b5fd22-cd50-41ee-9293-95edc2e771bb" pid="55BTAjhRLEWIwEAsQv8yTg" hash="pcNY8w">You know what she was trying to tell us, don’t you? I don’t know how to handle a new situation, Dad. Will I make friends? Will my teacher like me? Will I fit into the social group? Will I be accepted? These are the concerns that all of us experience, as we find ourselves in new and different social situations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p15" guid="8e99fdd6-07c3-4161-9bfd-cac5e79d73a4" pid="PvqzHcn9v0u1qTUbrll2pg" hash="nUt80Q">She knew what my answer would be and agreed to have me drive her to school. As we got in front of the school building, the warning bell sounded. The tears started to come to her eyes. I got out of the car and assisted her. We walked about ten feet, and she grabbed hold of my leg. It was as though she were a tackle on some football team. And then, as only a child can do to a father, she looked up at me and said philosophically, “Dad, if you really love me—if you really love me—don’t send me in there.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p16" guid="2f02aff3-6cd5-44c4-860b-0a59cb0a2109" pid="0dCRsYLIxEKO5qp3Zc0SHg" hash="v64p5Q">I said, “Honey, this may be beyond your comprehension, but it’s because I do love you that I am taking you in there.” And I did. When we got inside the door, she grabbed hold of the other leg and held on. Numerous students came and went, and finally the little miracle happened that changed everything.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p17" guid="915cd16d-7c40-4928-a80f-9cbdd94a9db6" pid="8QU3TxhtYUO2DH3eg62fCA" hash="tdwzzA">From I don’t know where came a delightful, wonderful friendshiper, a fellowshiper who knew how to lose herself in serving others; one who would now take the admonishment of the Savior to strengthen her friends. With the exuberance of youth this little girl said, “Kellie, how are you?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p18" guid="4ad02dc4-75f0-41a8-8750-d208b3bec08d" pid="b54hDHtrdU6QjUdFBpSv4g" hash="eXQgfQ">“Fine.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p19" guid="ccbce3ad-07f5-44a9-b499-f9f104949392" pid="4TpCZQ9kL02wziS0ia3Xkg" hash="Vvwj-w">“What is your home room?” And she told her. “Tremendous. I had that home room last year. Come on, and I will take you to it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p20" guid="d41957f1-3a09-4ce7-b341-23ebc7ad36f3" pid="cl3sm4QEHUuTctmraioqoA" hash="vmT_6Q">And before Kellie knew it, she had let go of my leg and got about ten paces away, then realized what she had done. I will never forget her expression and the sermon she taught as she looked back. “Oh,” she said, “Dad, you can go now; I don’t need you anymore.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p21" guid="6afbcecb-eaa6-4ea0-b345-281f8309aa22" pid="q4va9WQ8G0qjcT6E0Jb1Ag" hash="b8_e2Q">Thank God for the little people as well as the big people who know how to friendship and fellowship.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p22" guid="288cb853-4b01-4fc3-bbdf-cf3106446886" pid="zP20Ue-fUkePeytMnNkpvA" hash="jIPISw">Thousands of people are coming into this church every month. I pray that we have the genius to follow the counsel of the Lord to strengthen our brethren. I pray that a great bishop and a wonderful home teacher and other members are taking care of my friend, Guy Davis.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p23" guid="18e5b62d-ca26-42fe-99cf-18513f4ca718" pid="alrnnx03wkiNgt94c-ZYbg" hash="lbTmmg">I testify to the divinity of this church. It is true. I sustain President Lee as a prophet, seer, and revelator. I know he is called and ordained of God. I know God lives and that Jesus is the Christ, to which I add my testimony, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/10/strengthen-thy-brethren</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1972-general-conference/1972-10-4070-elder-paul-h-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="4211859" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Worth of Souls Is Great!</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great?lang=eng</link>
      <description>This is always a wonderful sight and a great occasion, brothers and sisters, and I thrill to add my testimony to that of our president and these great leaders who have preceded me. How delighted I felt this afternoon to see these young people assembl</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03033_000_2020" doc-version="2" hash="qYItNg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="VQ3FHkT3bEGxqpNXHoQEGg" hash="GP1ogg">The Worth of Souls Is Great!</h1><p class="authorName" guid="74719440-7a80-44ef-bc3f-eb57a10732cb" pid="IJrK9OnVg0yYzVoFp6uvQg" hash="2gvHCQ">Paul H. Dunn</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="766f5a54-31bb-44f2-8762-cbd83a97c876">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p1" guid="f36e7b3e-78ee-44e0-947f-4f067366d9cc" pid="uNGkZHD5q0ych3NGTgVb-w" hash="p58Ypg">This is always a wonderful sight and a great occasion, brothers and sisters, and I thrill to add my testimony to that of our president and these great leaders who have preceded me. How delighted I felt this afternoon to see these young people assembled and to hear their sweet voices tell of, I think, the greatest story since the birth of our Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p2" guid="01b24d10-b8e5-4187-b121-21a71bcdf812" pid="c7wtvFvUk0aWTDgdTsEcuQ" hash="AAyGqg">Someone once said, “I am intensely interested in the future because I expect to spend the rest of my days there.” I get excited about young people such as these because they project that kind of a positive future. We love and trust them. Seeing them seated behind me brings to mind a short story from Mt. Kisco, New York, reported in the <span class="emphasis">Reader’s Digest.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p3" guid="3e5572d6-a70e-4234-a92b-0adb49215feb" pid="WMa7QNpEUEeqswZLWeGqRg" hash="JVRNyQ">“Once upon a time, there was a little red schoolhouse with one big room for 27 children. The teacher sat with an American flag on one side of her and a blackboard on the other. The children sat in rows facing her, the littlest ones in front. The youngest was seven, and she was very little. The biggest was 16, and he was six feet tall. The youngest was smart, and she could read with the other children. The biggest was dumb, but he was strong and could help the teacher carry in wood. In bad weather, he carried the littlest girl across the puddle in front of the schoolhouse. And sometimes she helped him with his reading.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p4" guid="cdf4f7b0-a1e7-46a5-a0fe-bd6787e5f03f" pid="0mllc0W7SkOQWCVVObpvZw" hash="mmxJLA">“Then one day the state built a big highway, right past the schoolhouse door. And the State Education Department came by and said, ‘Great things are happening in education. There are special teachers for arithmetic, reading, art and music. If you combine with other schoolhouses, you could have a great big school where your children could have all the advantages. And big yellow buses could carry your children over the new highway right up to the school door.’ So the parents voted to consolidate, and the little red schoolhouse was abandoned.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p5" guid="93702c5d-e89b-45a3-beaa-946275034cb3" pid="vze_27I4JUusav4CfsOhcQ" hash="hCSD-w">“At first things went well in the big school. But after a while, the State Education Department said that it wasn’t providing the children with enough meaningful experiences. And some parents complained that the children were not learning to read and write and figure as well as they had in the little red schoolhouse. ‘We will try some new things,’ said the educators. So they tried the ungraded primer, where fast readers were not slowed down by slow readers, and where children who had trouble with numbers did not get moved on to the next grade before they could add 3 and 5. This helped, but not enough.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p6" guid="4dcbfe74-0a84-431b-aa3c-33d813301588" pid="EQNDEz9PQEeRVSzJP7nmXw" hash="Jilg1Q">“‘We will try something more,’ the educators said. ‘We will tear down some walls at the new school, so the children will be working together in one big room. That way, there will be less peer-group competition.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p7" guid="4509701e-6a64-4681-ba71-69b63c49876e" pid="-r-JVhYgQEuM_2I1WeNBAg" hash="R8a8EA">“Finally, an important educator came along, looked at the school and said, ‘This is good, but it is not good enough. It is too big, and the children are losing their identity. There are not enough interpersonal relationships in the infrastructure. What we really need is a one-room schoolhouse. And since red is a cheerful color, I think we ought to paint it red.’” (From Mt. Kisco, N.Y., <span class="emphasis">Patent Trader, </span>in <span class="emphasis">Reader’s Digest, </span>March 1973, p. 68. Used by permission.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p8" guid="7c89705b-56a8-4466-a4f9-a6564a4d1c27" pid="OcuLNJXjNEuMXcSXS3WoMA" hash="1bjAAw">The educator in this story did not mean that the consolidated school, the special teachers, or the ungraded primer were not advantages. The point of the story is that along with the wonderful new discoveries in education, the emphasis must still be placed upon the individual and upon his needs and relationships with others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p9" guid="21517537-64a8-4f0a-b769-d61b23383931" pid="3tWLC3mCRE-Leqa6MQDDnA" hash="0FTBUg">This philosophy applies just as importantly to Church organizations as it does to the little red schoolhouse. In a revelation given to the Prophet Joseph Smith just prior to the organization of the Church, the Lord said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p10" guid="3acb2150-8034-4a46-a270-4605bed8d3f7" pid="Bf_7YglDX0eloCVJiymRXQ" hash="q4aTzw">“Remember the worth of souls is great in the sight of God;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p11" guid="58f92411-039f-41db-be17-215f0d65dd80" pid="oy1XFctbP02OBBR0TRYKJw" hash="ACNDug">“For, behold, the Lord your Redeemer suffered death in the flesh; wherefore he suffered the pain of all men, that all men might repent and come unto him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p12" guid="b7c0e60d-c393-4576-8572-1497c8422d53" pid="H-_fT9Th6Eefmq7BI8j6Qg" hash="b7ZuxQ">“And he hath risen again from the dead, that he might bring all men unto him, on conditions of repentance.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.10-12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:10–12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p13" guid="adcba30f-fe71-4fc6-b316-7567594bad1b" pid="8tFv-iI7nEWT79YRxi2Yog" hash="gVltHQ">Our Lord’s response to the Pharisees’ question, “Why do they on the sabbath day that which is not lawful?” was, “The sabbath was made for man, and not man for the sabbath.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/2.24,27" class="scriptureRef">Mark 2:24, 27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p14" guid="c5c488fa-d3d6-4595-aadf-74083949e04a" pid="dBZvuTcbL0yFJ543l9DIdA" hash="612XBg">I understand from what the Lord has revealed to us through the prophets that <span class="emphasis">people </span>are his greatest concern. We are his children. We are somebody, as Elder Ashton so wonderfully stated this morning. We are his children, and he continually reveals himself through the prophets so that one day we can be like him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p15" guid="f1820e5d-8d0d-408b-9775-e5cc2f9dd33a" pid="qMf8bcFFkU-_ppfsxOiJMg" hash="-swxAg">Programs, then, wonderfully inspired programs, like the Sabbath, exist to help people. If we are not careful, it is very easy to put the mechanics of the program ahead of the person. Jesus was constantly trying to put the spirit back into the letter of the law. Our first priority, I feel, as parents, leaders, and teachers should be the individual within the home or Church program.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p16" guid="cb337d0e-11a7-4999-9863-f11f42349a41" pid="-txUviITOka_HOkWKXXSsA" hash="n9rSrQ">I remember some years ago an experience I had while directing one of the religious education programs of the Church in Southern California.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p17" guid="ceaab14b-8673-413a-af3e-b1ab9003c3e2" pid="M1vyBj1IkEScfpazxVqr-Q" hash="9dTSYA">One of my responsibilities as a coordinator was to secure property, eventually erect an institute building, and then provide a religious program for our college youth. We had secured a wonderful institute site adjacent to the Los Angeles State College. Shortly after the transaction was consummated, the State of California indicated to me that they wanted to take the property by right of eminent domain, which was their prerogative. I checked with my superiors and they said, “Look into the legal side and see if we still don’t have a chance.” I did. We went into court for a hearing. The judge was impressed with the program of the Church and what we do for youth and people. We were sent back to do some additional homework and gather added information.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p18" guid="a8a9eb2f-8bfa-4d05-b47e-04b1d434a7da" pid="_UKrg-gOUUCzjX4bwWILWg" hash="j3KJmg">The day came for the final hearing, and I had about eight hours of work to do in four when at that very moment about ten o’clock one morning a knock came at the door, and because of my frustration I almost said (but I didn’t), “COME IN!” Instead I said, “Come in.” And in the framework of that door stood a 19-year-old USC freshman student who had refused our offers to come and join our group on four previous occasions. His head bowed, hands in his pockets, he said, “Brother Dunn, I have got to see you, <span class="emphasis">now.</span>” And I almost said (but I didn’t), “Can’t you see I am busy?” Because I was. Fortunately I had the presence of mind to invite him in; and as he took a chair, several questions went through my mind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p19" guid="b14bd30a-a6af-4642-bc89-fa3eb6901863" pid="VoVgMwktf0GMOzsVTn1A7Q" hash="z8xXNw">Question number 1, “What are you going to court for this morning, Paul?” “Well, to try to save a piece of property.” “What do you want the piece of property for, Paul?” “Well, to erect a building.” “Well, what do you want a building for?” “Well, to teach some students.” “What just knocked on your door?” “Oh, a student.” And wouldn’t you know, he took the whole four hours.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p20" guid="85a667d7-befe-4610-ae3b-73ce5ec98bcc" pid="lGP8bf741EikcGEiN3oFrQ" hash="8qbzFw">The time came for legal counsel to arrive, and we went to court. I don’t know all of the ramifications. We lost the hearing and eventually the piece of property, and it took us two years to secure another site. You would be happy with what the Church has done at Los Angeles State College, but more important, we saved the boy. Had it been your son, I think you would agree that we made the right decision.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great.p21" guid="11ad8a85-9636-4143-9e29-810b292c9777" pid="BjGqE5KaYUOatownEPyEcQ" hash="sm_azw">God grant us the vision as leaders, teachers, and parents to put people first. Remember the worth of souls is great in the sight of God. I add my personal witness. God lives. Jesus is the Christ. This is his church. This is his prophet. I so testify in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1973/04/the-worth-of-souls-is-great</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1973-general-conference/1973-04-2050-elder-paul-h-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="5860346" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 1973 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parents, Teach Your Children</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I am grateful this morning, my brothers and sisters, for the uplifting and inspired message we have heard from our president. As he spoke, I thought in my mind that if all the world would heed this counsel, most all of its problems would be resolved.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03044_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="ar_PpA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="IPVgm459fk6dFW2MaVWzug" hash="OSFR7A">Parents, Teach Your Children</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="NwxMXrudy0yyT347_wke9Q" hash="2gvHCQ">Paul H. Dunn</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p1" pid="mso0QDgHfk-k18Oltj_XEg" hash="S9QY9w">I am grateful this morning, my brothers and sisters, for the uplifting and inspired message we have heard from our president. As he spoke, I thought in my mind that if all the world would heed this counsel, most all of its problems would be resolved.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p2" pid="sdnEJGxBCkyaD9GfOzrWDw" hash="VK2_Ng">One of the basic tenets of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is that we believe in continuous revelation. It is our testimony to the world that God communicates to prophets today the same as he did in ancient times. God’s revelations in times past have been sustained and revered in holy scripture. New revelation is the mind and will of the Lord through current prophets, and when they speak when moved upon by the Holy Ghost, it is “the <span class="emphasis">will</span> of the Lord, … the <span class="emphasis">mind</span> of the Lord, … the <span class="emphasis">word</span> of the Lord, … the <span class="emphasis">voice</span> of the Lord, and the <span class="emphasis">power</span> of God unto salvation.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:4</a>. Italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p3" pid="VjTVgaKL_kydvYJCNr3kjA" hash="2_c-nQ">This morning we heard from a prophet of God, and he communicated the mind and will of the Lord to all who would listen and receive counsel. Concerning the importance of such an occasion as this, it was President Kimball some years ago who made this observation:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p4" pid="4OUQACZpMEe4g3fiPZRSfw" hash="hMbdnA">“Sunday night, April 7, the great Tabernacle was closed, the lights turned out, and the record machines stopped, the door locked, and another historical conference became history. It will have been lost motion—a waste of time, energy, and money—if its messages <span class="emphasis">are not heeded.</span> In the seven two-hour sessions and in the several satellite meetings, truths were taught, doctrines expounded, exhortations given, enough to save the whole world from all its ills—and [he concluded] I mean from <span class="emphasis">all</span> its ills. …” (Spencer W. Kimball, “In the World But Not of It,” <span class="emphasis">Speeches of the Year,</span> Provo, Utah: Brigham Young University Press, 1968, pp. 2–3.) He reaffirmed that in our hearts and minds this morning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p5" pid="TWaMbG07uUeMKm3grSF__w" hash="AvQBuQ">I remember hearing President Kimball just the other day quote from Samuel:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p6" pid="DMAIwsCHeUOH6EJBPsLFKw" hash="GNEgkQ">“And the Lord said to Samuel, Behold, I will do a thing in Israel, at which both the ears of every one that heareth it shall tingle.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-sam/3.11" class="scriptureRef">1 Sam. 3:11</a>.) Today our president has caused our ears to tingle.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p7" pid="nCzzu_lMs0KrLHlhXnB7rA" hash="AF0QkQ">Now for a few moments I would like to direct some remarks to parents everywhere in this great listening audience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p8" pid="KtcY6Zj3WEa1rZlkHH8PGg" hash="X2UZTA">An oft-quoted passage of scripture and revelation of the Latter-day Saints is one referred to a few moments ago by President Kimball. It’s contained in the Doctrine and Covenants:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p9" pid="0ctvGbYq-Eea9q63QJZFtQ" hash="EdmSeQ">“And again, inasmuch as parents have children in Zion, or in any of her stakes which are organized, that teach them not to understand the doctrine of repentance, faith in Christ the Son of the Living God, and of baptism and the gift of the Holy Ghost by the laying on of hands, when eight years old, the sin be upon the heads of the parents.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.25" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p10" pid="QKGSZ5ONY0Sqk_gAAJN1OQ" hash="LnDo8w">I don’t know how many times you have heard this passage of scripture, and appropriately so, but certainly no counsel could be more timely or pertinent to the problems besetting families throughout the world. How many times have parents said to themselves after hearing this message, “I know it’s true and I know what the Lord expects, but how do I <span class="emphasis">do</span> it?” In other words, how do I become an effective teacher of the gospel to my own children?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p11" pid="HnX5QdU6DUaD_gg7G_CfEw" hash="AEydxA">As I have thought about this, it has been my observation that most parents really want to be good parents. Most want to do a better job.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p12" pid="TACUuBqRTUO63AAJCuqqdA" hash="jFWmtg">May we consider this morning four things that parents can do that will help them to better achieve success in rearing their children in righteousness?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p13" pid="08wCrzsK10eE29eh4NMDRQ" hash="L-b_dA">First, I would itemize the power of parental precept. Parents teach two ways. The first is by precept—or what we say by way of teaching correct principles to our children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p14" pid="o7IuF2OUTkijR2TaLigy4g" hash="h_H7RQ">I am reminded of the father who, in gathering his children together one morning, asked, “What would you learn of me?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p15" pid="Ebax7aAA1keJAb_3Xv5vWw" hash="taDylg">The reply came, “How shall we care for our bodies? How shall we play? How shall we work together? How shall we live with our fellowmen? How shall we pray? How shall we know God? For what ends shall we live?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p16" pid="tKp_6FGEdUG6zreesh3kQw" hash="hZWLUA">And the father pondered these words and sorrow was in his heart, for his own life and teaching touched not these things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p17" pid="B_FGAFPueEueSpqzIQqzpw" hash="fCVGKA">You may recall the old farmer who had quite a reputation for being a philosopher. He said, “You can no more teach what you ain’t got than you can go back to where you ain’t been.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p18" pid="-8CxZABLmkefirqS9RfzMw" hash="elR9aA">I recall as a young man when I first heard our text quoted from the Doctrine and Covenants, I went to my own mother and exclaimed, “Well, Mom, how does it feel to have all my sins on your head?” Then she taught me the lesson of that passage. She said, “Ah, Paul, you forgot to read carefully what the Lord said. He said that the sin be upon the head of parents if they do not teach their children the principles of the gospel. And you’ve been taught!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p19" pid="13pUjN_PJkyz7uxctsGOOA" hash="afvq3g">And I had been taught! Thank the Lord for parents who realize their responsibility to instill in their children the principles of the gospel and who follow the counsel of the Lord’s prophets. Parents in the Church today have been counseled to regularly, consistently, and inspiringly hold family home evenings and to take advantage of other great teaching moments to so acquaint their children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p20" pid="bBV-GB4QJEGZbFCTm3m2ow" hash="pIgszw">The second way would be the power of parental example. Ralph Waldo Emerson said, “What you do thunders so loudly in my ears I cannot hear what you say.” Will you remember this little couplet:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="NnkD7qVZ50qyKgeaFdzRgQ" hash="PNbG3A">Parents can tell but never teach</p>
          <p class="line" pid="Hx0l4sqcGEuDpXUZlpYQXA" hash="VVURvQ">Until they practice what they preach.</p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p21" pid="iaY1Y-nYG0aXmpGA8Aby-g" hash="2qc4xg">I’m grateful for the example of a father who, as a busy executive of a great supermarket chain, still found the time to demonstrate by his concern that groceries were less important than his boy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p22" pid="NzRFkcz6RUeyod7GjorVhw" hash="cRlZrg">Like many young men, I once had a paper route; and I had to get up early in the morning to deliver them. One morning I woke up and looked outdoors to see one of those torrential Arkansas downpours. I thought we were in for another flood! As I prepared to go out in that rain, my father came into the room dressed in his business suit. “Get in the car, Paul,” he said. “I’ll drive you around your route this morning.” This meant that he would have to go without his own breakfast.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p23" pid="EQ8RgmXGn0uly4qPAUoX0Q" hash="dlvtsg">On that morning, in addition to the heavy rain, the papers came late. By the time we had them delivered, it was considerably past the hour that my father had to be to work. And on this particular morning he had scheduled a very important board meeting.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p24" pid="jyW1HPER80m0nBhUttjLnA" hash="bLmdKQ">He arrived at the meeting late, walked into the board room, and announced, “I’m sorry I’m late, gentlemen, but I had to deliver my papers this morning.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p25" pid="c-zX8lyzgkCvRcGWkb1vXg" hash="Dv0j3A">Do you think that there was ever any doubt in my mind as to my father’s greatest concern? Interestingly, I don’t recall too many lessons my parents verbally taught, but their example is still a part of me till this day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p26" pid="NC2o43_0ZESA9VrWnTHD-Q" hash="EXhtKQ">Third, the power of parental love. Recently I came across a little article by Doris Jehnke, entitled “Saturday with a Teenage Daughter.” It seems all too typical of parent-daughter relationships these days. Let me share it with you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p27" pid="O8ZK2ojFa0Cci2qYarYYnQ" hash="3vgJzg">“Are you going to sleep all day? … Who said you could use my hairspray? … Clean the dishes off the table. … Turn down the radio. … Have you made your bed? … That skirt is much too short. … Your closet is a mess. … Stand up straight. … Somebody has to go to the store. … Quit chewing your gum like that. … Your hair is too bushy. … I don’t care if everybody else does have one. … Turn down the radio. … Have you done your homework? … Don’t slouch. … You didn’t make your bed. … Quit banging on the piano. … Why don’t you iron it yourself? … Your fingernails are too long. … Look it up in the dictionary. … Sit up straight. … Get off the phone now. … Why did you ever buy that record? … Take the dog out. … You forgot to dust that table. … You’ve been in the bathroom long enough. … Turn off the radio and get to sleep now.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p28" pid="HVTiWRY6Bki5gK5-wm7QZQ" hash="lOP8lA">“Another day gone, and not once did I say, ‘I love you.’” (Stanley E. Miller, comp., <span class="emphasis">Especially for Mormons,</span> Kellirae Arts, Provo, Utah, 1971, vol. 1, p. 141.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p29" pid="oUL6d2nxtkeARB91JK3q1A" hash="Y6d9GQ">Too often it is easier to criticize, to point out the faults, than to praise or give love. Mothers and dads, when was the last time you told your children “I love you”?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p30" pid="lCre4YALsECshKA_KjQlcQ" hash="5GPgTw">A good friend of mine makes it a point every day to find something positive that he can compliment in his children so that he can truly say, “I love you.” Will you make the opportunity soon?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p31" pid="QRdN899LdUOti4ymkgXmng" hash="Mg_uRw">Finally, the power of parental prayer. The Book of Mormon provides a great example of a father who recovered a lost son by the power of personal prayer. The conditions of his time are akin to our own day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p32" pid="5-k3Az-IPUSJrKeKx3TYXQ" hash="lF_Rww">“Now it came to pass that there were many of the rising generation that could not understand the words of king Benjamin, being little children at the time he spake unto his people; and they did not believe the tradition of their fathers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p33" pid="JbX_vku1h0elXbMWyBVFwQ" hash="ARaNOg">“They did not believe what had been said concerning the resurrection of the dead, neither did they believe concerning the coming of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p34" pid="0t4sigNQc0iffRFLd83AUQ" hash="wb9nMA">“And now because of their unbelief they could not understand the word of God; and their hearts were hardened.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/26.1-3" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 26:1–3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p35" pid="H6FqKD0oNEyZYBU-nLeCXQ" hash="ter5gw">One of these of the “rising generation” was Alma the Younger. He was “a man of many words, and did speak much flattery to the people,” leading away “many … to do after the manner of his iniquities.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/27.8" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 27:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p36" pid="P_eH4dS4nECLxhLp8t72eQ" hash="Jw3r9w">We are further told that he was “a great hinderment to the prosperity of the church of God” because of the dissension that he caused. (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/27.9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 27:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p37" pid="sGqEHNewOEG4u1s4sS1wiA" hash="zCul4g">I suppose the tendency then, as it often seems to be today, was to “write him off.” But you know the miraculous story of how an angel of the Lord appeared to that young man and how he became one of the greatest missionaries in the church of Christ. What was it that caused that great change to occur? The angel testified to Alma the following: “… Behold, the Lord hath heard the prayers of his people, and also the prayers of his servant, Alma, who is thy father. …” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/27.14" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 27:14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p38" pid="b7-eKP4-40GZegN227lqgA" hash="6POnmA">Think of it! The power of parental prayer! As we consider the challenge of rearing children in a world fraught with temptations, false ideologies, and materialistic enticements, do you not feel the need for guidance and inspiration beyond your human capacity? There is no greater help or strength that a father or mother can obtain than through securing that help from the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p39" pid="PY8pukSf1029n9fDv-mTxg" hash="dKO5IQ">Just the other day I had a sweet experience. I stood in the presence of a mother and a father who had just greeted their long-lost son home from the wars—I mean the worldly wars. What a tender moment! I can tell you their prayers were heard and answered.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p40" pid="xTF3YeVmokijvIC_OYMcdg" hash="qXmmgw">Remember what Alma said: “Counsel with the Lord in all thy doings, and he will direct thee for good. …” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.37" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:37</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children.p41" pid="Lsc4xJ3JREyOIk9XTD9YOA" hash="GZvA3A">May I testify to all parents in Zion everywhere to the efficacy of these great principles in rearing our children righteously: the power of precept, the power of example, the power of love, and the power of prayer. I add my personal witness that Jesus Christ really lives, that his kingdom is here upon the earth, and that this morning we heard from his appointed prophet and servant, Spencer W. Kimball. May we abide by the counsel and teachings given to us by the Lord through his servants, I humbly pray as I testify to these things in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/04/parents-teach-your-children</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1974-general-conference/1974-04-1040-elder-paul-h-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="7020152" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 1974 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Time for Every Purpose</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose?lang=eng</link>
      <description>One of the first public meetings that I was privileged to attend following my recuperation from open-heart surgery was an open house sponsored by a seventies quorum, where they invited nonmember friends to listen to the doctrines of the kingdom. They</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03057_000_029" doc-version="2" hash="rm5KQQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="yU7m0hljZ0SR-H3JIn4KhQ" hash="2_isEw">A Time for Every Purpose</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="1kMY4qyrK0C9tUB1CUuGpg" hash="2gvHCQ">Paul H. Dunn</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3396.jpg" alt="Elder Paul H. Dunn" pid="ODgb6hQ9bU64dMopU0q7DA" hash="UpGYbQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p1" pid="JqR0wi2CnU-o8ZL4gNUwhA" hash="VJHGOQ">One of the first public meetings that I was privileged to attend following my recuperation from open-heart surgery was an open house sponsored by a seventies quorum, where they invited nonmember friends to listen to the doctrines of the kingdom. They selected as their theme that night, “Open Up Your Hearts.” When it came my turn to speak, I said, “I am a little sensitive on that subject,” but I want President Kimball and his counselors and all my brethren to know that I have listened in this conference with an open heart. I have been sensitive to their counsel and will recommit myself to the great work ahead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p2" pid="euSQcakA0021f3qrf27ddg" hash="75V_kQ">The weather is glorious here by the Wasatch Range and throughout many parts of the world. Even the thin birds have reappeared. The fat birds are those that remained here during the cold seasons, overate, and became rotund. The thin birds flew hundreds of miles to stay warm, kept in shape, and have returned with wan looks on their feathered faces. Whether they are birds of passage or frost-bound nonachievers, they remind us of this truth spoken of by the Master: “Behold the fowls of the air: for they sow not, neither do they reap, nor gather into barns; yet your heavenly Father feedeth them. Are ye not much better than they?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.26" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 6:26</a>.) Indeed—if you know, as I know, that the Lord does watch over each one of us with love; for that I’m grateful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p3" pid="jBndvnnisU6mUed7HqX-EA" hash="iItY0A">In springtime, too, as Tennyson said, a young man’s fancy turns to thoughts of love. On campuses everywhere the three Rs tend to become “romance and red roses.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p4" pid="B9nTR0HeP06y_Bo1u9f-rg" hash="ZReC4w">One tragedy of love has already occurred this year. A beardless youth became so enamored of a young miss (although she did not encourage him) that each day for 47 consecutive days he wrote her a special-delivery letter, until finally, on the 48th day, she eloped with the mailman. The lad is probably blessed, since all he had to offer the lady was a mission yet unserved, a college education one quarter complete, and no funds (he had spent all of his money on stamps).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p5" pid="aCnSCira1EymPeqSGw1r9Q" hash="WeIwxQ">Spring is a time for the rebirth of living things from their wintry cover. It typifies and reminds us of the literalness of the resurrection of all living things. Significant to me is the fact that our Lord emerged from the tomb in the springtime!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p6" pid="eHxVlwAzyEG8croKfEKiUg" hash="vR8AeQ">Spring also with “her bursting buds, variegated colors and manifestation of teeming life inspires new hope and gives promise of happy days.” (David O. McKay, <span class="emphasis">Treasures of Life,</span> Deseret Book Co., p. 146.) Indeed, this time of nature’s rebirth should give us pause for reflection, assessment, and commitment to life’s higher priorities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p7" pid="D7sA52E6s0avfBlj_tHq9A" hash="5nwddw">You recall the words of the Old Testament poet: “To everything there is a season, and <span class="emphasis">a time to every purpose under … heaven.”</span> (<a href="/scriptures/ot/eccl/3.1" class="scriptureRef">Eccl. 3:1</a>. Italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p8" pid="m-45yeJyREGxBRK5-xIVmw" hash="VzRraw">“A time to every purpose under heaven,” suggesting that there is a proper sequence for all things. Our prophet, President Kimball, has counseled you, young people, particularly young men, as to that proper sequence. Would you note the sequence of events that will bring orderliness and happiness to your life. I quote from our prophet:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p9" pid="7ygWfP3cL0avtmWw-waH7Q" hash="kcTKJA">“One can have all the blessings if he is in control and takes the experiences in proper turn: first some limited social get-acquainted contacts, then his mission, then his courting, then his temple marriage and [now note] his schooling and his family, then his life’s work. In any other sequence he could run into difficulty.” (Spencer W. Kimball, “The Marriage Decision,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Feb. 1975, p. 4.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p10" pid="cGDKhDLw0EeRCQzYdyLL4g" hash="85k0cw">Now for a few moments, may we talk about this sequence in its “proper turn”?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p11" pid="aCuDO7Odx0mtsLdqsQrKNw" hash="kEEH6g">For many young men, now is the time for preparation—preparation for a planned mission. It’s a time for you to apply yourselves in school, to concentrate on the foundation of a good education so that when you are called as an ambassador for Jesus Christ, you will represent him with the dignity befitting one who holds his priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p12" pid="M3tcWim5B0K_a23HgLBaoA" hash="cJPxUA">It’s a time when I would challenge you to read the scriptures, a time to learn to know your Heavenly Father in prayer. It’s also a time to be cautious in your associations with the opposite sex; for again, as President Kimball has cautioned:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p13" pid="FivjnexH20SX4MASDlmNLQ" hash="-n9fQA">“When you get in the teen-age years, your social associations should still be general acquaintance with both boys and girls. Any dating or pairing off in social contacts should be postponed until at least the age of 16 or older, and even then there should be much judgment used. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p14" pid="VVGLF-U4D0ihu_fBMRMfHA" hash="fp9Njg">“Young people should still limit the close contacts for several years, since the boy will be going on his mission when he is 19 years old.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Feb. 1975, p. 4.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p15" pid="TyFAAQUyTE2GBUGT07iHzg" hash="ib4Uhg">To the young men of the priesthood, if you haven’t served a mission, this is <span class="emphasis">not</span> the time for a lot of involvement in love or romance. It is a time for saving money. Do you know how much a mission costs today? It averages about $150 a month. For a two-year mission, that is $3,600.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p16" pid="oNXU4Uw9gkCqOOtO-wiWmg" hash="DUmvmg">One young man was startled when his father sat down with him to figure how he could earn that money. Noting that the most productive earning time would be from ages 16–19, they figured that he would have to save at least $1,000 each year for that three-year period. This also meant that the young man had to earn another $600 before age 16 (he was then 12) to save sufficiently for his mission. Hopefully, many start earlier than that.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p17" pid="ye2vC0YVHk22hcsJYOCqyg" hash="a0KSTw">You’ve heard some of our young men say, “But I can’t find a job. No one will hire me.” May I suggest to you the example of one enterprising 13-year-old who has already produced some handbills that he is passing out in his neighborhood. The handbill reads: “When you’re on vacation and need someone to care for your yard, or if you want any odd jobs done, call Bill, because when you call me, I’ll be there.” He then signed his name and included his phone number. He already has his summer filled with work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p18" pid="FbuypL_45UOPT64Sf6h-CA" hash="jd2F0w">Preparation for a mission, however, is not just a matter of economics. It’s a time above all else to keep yourself clean in mind and clean in habits. What counsel could be more plain than of our prophet’s words: “There must never be any sex of any kind prior to marriage.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Feb. 1975, p. 4.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p19" pid="lSaN5CJVKUKaTJXFkQE9PQ" hash="vbFQdw">For others of you, after an honorably served mission, it is a time to prepare for marriage. To those of you to whom this applies, our president has said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p20" pid="G2b7LVTGVkSiPgAIKx4vqw" hash="GWFCvA">“Now is the time for you to plan good strong marriages and organize your programs and set your standards and solidify your determination to prepare for that married period of your lives which will be beautiful and rewarding.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Feb. 1975, p. 4.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p21" pid="woixn1Oc5ESQnLimBoDu7A" hash="VbgBgQ">This does not suggest that you rush into marriage impulsively, without proper preparation, forethought, and inspiration. It does say that marriage is a responsibility that cannot be avoided if one desires life’s greatest fulfillment and eternity’s highest possibilities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p22" pid="Da1SHkGTUUaRxjKOFzmsQg" hash="eFgyww">So after an honorable mission, it’s a proper time for courtship, a time to plan a marriage worthy of the Lord’s blessings. Once you can see the vision of what the Lord has in store for you, I’m confident you will want to make any sacrifice necessary to achieve those blessings. To you men in your late twenties and early thirties and not yet married, read again those possibilities as he has described them to us in the Doctrine and Covenants, sections 131 and 132.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p23" pid="yWxNnLpNBEG07p5YftXOgA" hash="k3E8HQ">In proper sequence, in proper order: first, preparation for a mission; next, an honorably served mission; then a temple marriage; and next, a time to have a family, to complete one’s schooling, and plan for your life’s work. Some ask the question “Shouldn’t we get our education first and then have our family?” “I know of no scriptures or authorities,” admonishes President Kimball, “which authorize young wives to delay their families. … Young married couples can make their way and reach their educational heights, if they are determined.” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Feb. 1975, p. 4.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p24" pid="nlt-KHkgU0CMvFgDxKrBzw" hash="dZ6C7w">My, what sound counsel! Any of us who have gone through the educational process can only endorse the counsel of our prophet. It will take sacrifice and perhaps extending one’s education longer than planned by having children as you complete your degree, but you will find, as others have, that those years were among your happiest because you had to struggle.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p25" pid="NyLc0fLVtEaksltUlUvkVg" hash="qqVsLA">Again may you be reminded of the prophet’s admonition: “In any other sequence [you] could run into difficulty.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p26" pid="Kgxx90dmj0yBjXUVhVaRGQ" hash="0Dozwg">Phil Pepe, in his excellent book, <span class="emphasis">The Wit and Wisdom of Yogi Berra,</span> notes that in 1972, when the remarkable major league catcher and manager was voted into baseball’s most exclusive club and distinguished company, the Hall of Fame, an honor which I believe Yogi Berra richly deserved, he addressed a select audience with one of his famous statements: “I thank everybody for making this day necessary.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p27" pid="v5wsi4juvkyBsbI7YemghA" hash="k3mdcA">Yogi Berra spoke in much wiser terms than he knew. He had come all the way from the dirt of a St. Louis slum to the pinnacle of his profession, had withstood ridicule about his personal appearance, had found a lovely wife, had been named “Father of the Year,” and had earned the admiration of all who knew him well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p28" pid="k8qlrxXgckmoquPt3wyZ2Q" hash="_kiuHA">May I suggest to you that the sequence of proper preparation for a mission, an honorably served mission, a temple marriage, and a family is the order that makes our days “necessary” rather than merely possible.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p29" pid="FQUcDGN2tUC_0cvh4kE2kw" hash="8SuUpA">May you, my young Latter-day Saint friends, choose that sequence that will bring you joy in this life and in the eternities to come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose.p30" pid="lyXNxjexKkGwEwW13SjpKA" hash="w-BELg">And so it is that I feel about the youth of this great country and particularly of this Church, and I think you know I do. You and I are friends. Wherever you are in this world, young man, and wherever you are in this universal church, young lady, my prayers and those of all those who sit here are that you may choose that sequence in life which will lead you on to great achievement, each orderly step along the way. You have heard wise counsel from this pulpit. I add my concern for you and my witness that I too know that God lives, and I think you know I know he lives. God bless us to put into action the counsel you have heard, I pray as I leave my blessing and witness here this day, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/04/a-time-for-every-purpose</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1975-general-conference/1975-04-4060-elder-paul-h-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="5899426" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Oh Beautiful for Patriot Dream”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream?lang=eng</link>
      <description>If only the world could be as enthused and excited as Elder Richards. I feel out of breath already.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03063_000_023" doc-version="3" hash="2Lgs8w"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="X6Lj2mmQg0GQUg_jnIUJ-A" hash="0-V18w">“Oh Beautiful for Patriot Dream”</h1><p class="authorName" pid="OEIsDE-XBEuNwHCfuVYSfA" hash="2gvHCQ">Paul H. Dunn</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3396.jpg" alt="Elder Paul H. Dunn" pid="2wJiPCGcg0WUe-noElP-Ig" hash="UpGYbQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p1" pid="g9lrpx2OqEOUf0PL6HICtQ" hash="ohtnqA">If only the world could be as enthused and excited as Elder Richards. I feel out of breath already.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p2" pid="OAhmCDvAq0yVlLZEPoMXew" hash="MYux-Q">Some weeks ago in the summer heat of Boston, two men worked vigorously and perspired mightily to construct displays for the American Bicentennial. One stopped to mop his brow and asked the other, “Do we really have to go through this every 200 years?” The correct answer, of course, is that we have not celebrated often or deeply enough the birth of this promised land, this choice and beautiful and still-young land, which we possess as the Lord’s gift in freedom and joy—just as long as we serve him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p3" pid="0cxmLow7l0Gw8OTIQm8CrQ" hash="FgK1iQ">Boston is a proper place to begin; Boston, in fact, is “a very proper place.” We who have prayed, preached, and tracted in lovely New England did not find it at all that formal. It is a charming place with friendly, wonderful people, and just now, a very successful baseball team—it has a melting-pot of names like Petrocelli, Lynn, Rice, Carlton Fisk, and a thinking, Polish player known as “Yaz” for Yastrzemski—and on all sides the “where it happened” of precious American tradition.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p4" pid="V_KKXhBRKkyf8POQcR7cAg" hash="ywqxDQ">Indeed, it has been just over 200 years since a better-than-average silversmith on a black horse made history as Longfellow later recalled:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="PLCPBIqFA0uEGNKlJScqIg" hash="91uMrg">“The fate of a nation was riding that night;</p>
          <p class="line" pid="_oJ0XiTzc0avK6sZrEHOSg" hash="Ue9HFw">And the spark struck out by that steed in his flight. …</p>
          <p class="line" pid="AqvAgUiokECUWrW0ns9o8A" hash="BVrNug">A cry of defiance, and not of fear. …</p>
          <p class="line" pid="rLcmRI0wnke0Q02syM_WlQ" hash="KKHEAQ">And the midnight message of Paul Revere.”</p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p5" pid="PXPEwK0lFUK4QrUjV8FnmQ" hash="aRDOdA">That’s the way it was, from Boston to Lexington to Concord, as the war for independence and liberty began. Most of all, it was for people, men and women of courage and vision and faith, strengthened by God as a part of his plan, who struggled, froze, starved, and when necessary, died, that these free states in union might be born, in Thomas Jefferson’s incisive words, “To assume, among the powers of the earth, the separate and equal station to which the laws of nature and of nature’s God entitle them.” (“Declaration of Independence.”)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p6" pid="m6SkVk_YpEOxLceWdxzivA" hash="0zra3g">It was worth a lot to the new Americans of that hour to beget this nation—worth all they had, all they were, and all that they had dreamed. What is it worth today, to you and to me, and especially to us as Latter-day Saints, who alone <span class="emphasis">know</span> what the Lord is doing, to assert our free agency toward the fulfilling of his plan?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p7" pid="6VrTJTf5fkSWWwyp8ijG6A" hash="R1vI_Q">As you decide, let me suggest an exciting tour for you. Go, if you can—and if you cannot, then make the trip in your mind’s eye from your study or your armchair or your library, but <span class="emphasis">go</span>—go to Charlestown and Breed’s Hill, to Washington’s Crossing, Brandywine Creek, Saratoga, to the great courthouse and a dozen more, and to King’s Mountain and Cowpens and Guilford Courthouse on the road to Yorktown, where it finally ended. Ask yourself along the way who these people were, and where they got their vision, and listen intently for a drummer boy tapping out a song that is two centuries older than George M. Cohan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p8" pid="Zr9oqocVUUS41C9LemWoQw" hash="gtYsDQ">Give a thought as well to a lad age twenty-one who regretted that he had but one life to give for his country and a twenty-year-old French major general who came 3,000 miles to secure the final victory. And if you are traveling and you come to one of those too-numerous claims that “George Washington slept here,” and you kind of hope that if so the sheets have been changed and that modern plumbing has been installed, pause to remember that there really was such a man as George Washington, sometimes disliked, but respected, gladly followed and <span class="emphasis">superbly</span> there when we needed him most, to lead in carrying out the plan of the Lord in the founding of America. Childless, the Virginia planter today has 220 million living children. You and I are among them. God had set him apart and lifted him up.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p9" pid="ibgEz-EWrkCO94XMs44WtA" hash="833t7A">Carry on with me then to Philadelphia to the year 1787. Gathered to frame a constitution in cramped and overheated quarters, delegates from most of the thirteen sovereign states struggle through the summer months to produce a document upon which a free nation might be built. Fortunately (and it has been said by those not of our Faith), they achieved a Constitution and a Bill of Rights which far exceeded the best that could come from these men. <span class="emphasis">But it did.</span> More than that, it was and is a living document, capable of defending its basic principles but flexible enough to adapt to the needs of this changing and growing United States.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p10" pid="kzYrOxj4bk6Eo5R1r9KLlQ" hash="Dkiesw">You and I are made aware, of course, that there is a better explanation of what really occurred. The scriptures tell us. The Lord “established the Constitution of this land, by the hands of wise men whom I raised up unto this very purpose, and redeemed the land by the shedding of blood.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/101.80" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 101:80</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p11" pid="XQBudbtwZEqt7vO8p0Abqw" hash="H2tIaw">The land was “redeemed” indeed by thousands killed and wounded along the way at Germantown, at Bemis Heights and Charleston, and so many other places in the American Revolution.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p12" pid="bvtrynz5RUe_voAWCG40yg" hash="hvkszQ">President Brigham Young spoke for himself and for every living prophet who has addressed the question since when he said, “The signers of the Declaration of Independence and the framers of the Constitution were inspired from on high to do that work.” (<span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses,</span> 7:14.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p13" pid="7f795wM760WY7JHcEHLwCA" hash="TtmXAw">An objective study of the delegates involved—their fears, their limitations, vested interests, and the like—makes it clear that they were not the sort of men we usually think of as prophets. Nonetheless they were inspired, and the Constitution they provided can be designated accurately as a divine document.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p14" pid="60gZUekYkkOotQUtZm0DuA" hash="9rGSnQ">But even a divine constitution requires something further; it demands a kind of people who will, by their very natures, receive and respect such a constitution and function well within the conditions it establishes. Where indeed shall we find such people today? I recall one. It was in a concentration camp I helped liberate during World War II. As we blew the lock off the door and tried to assist the miserable and the painful inside, I was interrupted by a tap on my boot and found, wallowing in the mud, a Protestant minister. One of his first requests was, “Soldier, do you have a flag?” Later when we retrieved one from the jeep I gave it to him on a stretcher and with tears in his eyes he said, “Thank God, you came.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p15" pid="64hKp_5fAE6rx10di3TsKQ" hash="-xHmHw">Again the Lord said, “Wherefore, this land is consecrated unto him whom he shall bring. And if it so be that they shall serve him according to the commandments which he hath given, it shall be a land of liberty unto them.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/1.7" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 1:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p16" pid="dWMkUc0oSEujT0WeGOGOfQ" hash="QmU7nw">As Latter-day Saints then, we know why some persons came to America and others did not. And as someone has said, “We haven’t done badly for a nation of immigrants.” We are immigrants, you and I, because the Lord made immigrants of us and brought us here. We have done as well as could be expected, and are richly blessed despite our shortcomings because the Lord has thus far held us in his hands and worked his purposes, his ultimate purpose, through us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p17" pid="j4yjzTnH6EiB8dtZMvaqyw" hash="wUm2OQ">Can you understand, this is what America is all about? You and I know, and you and I <span class="emphasis">alone</span> really know, the reason for this blessed and beautiful land. In a world where men have given up on this most vital question, we know the purpose of America.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p18" pid="K_b9Wjrh3EOnI8PiYjFj_g" hash="9bqFsg">For this country did not end in Philadelphia, even if Horace Greeley did mean that city when he urged us to “go west.” It was a new land, fresh, clean, unspoiled with a past. America included the frontier. In 1805 the Prophet Joseph Smith was born, and he grew up toward adolescence just like the new land. He fitted it. He was young, clean, unspoiled—a lad without a past, kneeling in a grove. This pristine land—this innocent young man—and thus the Lord reached out and kept his promise. He established his conditions over centuries; you see, God has time. His plan made it possible for the holy priesthood and the Church to be restored upon the earth—the restoration of the gospel of Jesus Christ—but only in America.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p19" pid="k7MGJeyuS0m3_-2j0H0zfg" hash="_khYwQ">Can you understand the way God has worked? And if you do, will you join me this day in committing yourself to preach the message of the Lord’s glorious achievement in America and to teach it as missionaries wherever the opportunity allows? This is a time when you and I can afford to be patriotic, in the best sense of that term. There is reason to be proud that we live in an established land that has been conditioned by the Lord so that his gospel could be restored. The purpose of America was to provide a setting wherein that was possible. All else takes its power from that one great, central purpose. May I commend to you Mark E. Petersen’s book <span class="emphasis">The Great Prologue</span> (Deseret Book Co., 1975)? Read it in connection with your scriptures and receive greater light on our history and its purpose.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p20" pid="tCGuzCv1TEqFeUE6Aki6nA" hash="miMRyA">As some of you know, I have never counted mathematics as my most exciting subject. Nevertheless, I believe that I can set in sequence the steps the Lord has used in his plan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p21" pid="M5uJzSgwjk2Lub1S6Ag8_Q" hash="F3zDqg">First, there was selecting and bringing the people. The next step was establishing a free nation. The third was inspiring a divine constitution. The fourth was opening the American frontier, new land, fresh and clean. The fifth step was calling young Joseph Smith to become a prophet in such a little time, God’s prophet, seer, and revelator, and later his martyr.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p22" pid="LVUtVRMsAEelhIkK0BEldw" hash="T7JIaw">Let me add one final stop to your American journey. The place—Arlington National Cemetery in Arlington, Virginia—the tomb of America’s unknown soldier. Today the remains of three servicemen from three wars lie there. The inscription reminds us, “Here rests in honored glory an American soldier known but to God.” There are in addition 4,724 other unknown servicemen buried in Arlington, and all across the nation and the world I have seen the crosses, row upon row, marking the places where lie America’s honored dead, literally in the thousands. What did it cost them that this nation might remain “the land of liberty”? How shall we honor them, you and I?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p23" pid="ynlxbxCNi0SA38Li8jvphQ" hash="qW-pyQ">In two ways it seems to me: First, by striving to make our citizenry the righteous people the Lord requires of us. And second, by telling the story of what the Lord has done for you and me and this great church, and why.</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.f3">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="bFrNecvxSkKyjg6hBPpdxg" hash="0-V18w1">“Oh beautiful for patriot dream</p>
          <p class="line" pid="fN_nWnAtaEGg8xDs8roGpQ" hash="LJLXRw">That sees beyond the years.</p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="Hs5W8xTDc0iyNXohhwV_-w" hash="3QV3_w">Thine alabaster cities gleam</p>
          <p class="line" pid="63YztsivUE6Od9oFEbshhg" hash="HfXwyA">Undimmed by human tears.</p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="l9cCo7Rc8kmuTSr-eRmmyg" hash="2kdhbQ">America! America!</p>
          <p class="line" pid="eHIQecxKPUKaOOsq5yJWUQ" hash="ARJVHw">God shed his grace on thee.</p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="65DFUxRFiESdXUZvKsnnfw" hash="1c8jkw">And crown thy good with brotherhood</p>
          <p class="line" pid="vuYem4LCu0SZ35-nmqEt_g" hash="3kz9uA">From sea to shining sea.”</p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream.p24" pid="Gn36qQeaBUWV4wo-LddaCw" hash="aN7Bgw">May that be the song of our heart and our prayer for fulfillment, I humbly pray as I bear witness to these truths and add my testimony that God lives, that Jesus is the Christ, and that here sits his prophet, in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/10/oh-beautiful-for-patriot-dream</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1975-general-conference/1975-10-4020-elder-paul-h-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="12488733" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Follow It!”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The great events of this conference have brought back to my remembrance an experience of last December. One of the physicians who attended my open heart surgery of a few months ago asked if I would participate with him on a Sunday School program. I f</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03076_000_024" doc-version="3" hash="3TraZg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="eSCn6UJA8EWyBruXPErRFA" hash="9OCSGg">“Follow It!”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="bLiwEg0MQUqtj0iLIQTUfA" hash="2gvHCQ">Paul H. Dunn</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26ec.jpg" alt="Elder Paul H. Dunn" pid="1mNdVXPjrUuoqV30aKSYVQ" hash="lWLluA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p1" pid="H0F5rkMbPUOKeUttVLfYcA" hash="xVHGeQ">The great events of this conference have brought back to my remembrance an experience of last December. One of the physicians who attended my open heart surgery of a few months ago asked if I would participate with him on a Sunday School program. I followed him at the pulpit. He gave a tremendous address. As he took his seat, I felt prompted to say, because I felt it, “Brothers and sisters, I want you to know that this man has touched my heart very deeply.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p2" pid="jzXUItbeCEGRoDJPrdCPIw" hash="p0qLDA">The great messages of our presidency, President Kimball and his counselors, and those of the Twelve and others, have touched me deeply. I have reminisced and remembered at this great historic conference. My mind goes back just a week ago when I was privileged to attend a stake conference in Oregon. Lo and behold, in the audience was my very first bishop, a man of great faith and capacity. (I had never known a bishop until I was fifteen years old and had moved to Hollywood, California.) He stood over six feet tall, weighing well over 200 pounds, with a heart to match—and he has never let go since. I remember under his tutelage memorizing this little verse:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p3" pid="79jQdl9RiUOlLrXmtL0Dpw" hash="HDeQXg">“Remember, Paul,” he said, “there is an odd little voice always speaking within, and it prompts you to duty and warns you from sin. And what is most strange, it makes itself heard, though it gives not a sound and says never a word. You follow it.” And last week he said, “Are you still following it?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p4" pid="HrCnHUEAt0yk0IAvcjaXpw" hash="dlvbQg">I remember a great, wise teacher who said, “Paul, always keep in mind that a strong man and a waterfall always channel their own paths.” And I remember a dad who said, “I gave you a great name; remember, a good name is better than a girdle of gold.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p5" pid="G8KBxnJulkeHbne-GpKwPw" hash="uHnv1A">I think every boy and girl ought to have in his or her life a great dad, a marvelous bishop, and wonderful teachers. Many do; some don’t. Thank God for a prophet, for leaders of the Church who add that dimension.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p6" pid="alwyYo9_CUi8ATh7c9n94g" hash="zG_U-g">I thought of another great man in my life—a coach who has affected my life for eternity. I am pleased to announce that he and I are engaged together in learning more fully the gospel of Jesus Christ in a missionary effort.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p7" pid="JwzZaykHdUynmwxY57FXLg" hash="C31KcA">I will never forget the day I walked into his office, scared to death as fifteen-year-olds are, trying to sign up for a varsity team. I stood outside his door for the better part of five minutes; and then, when I got the courage, I knocked timidly. The voice said, “Come in!” I opened the door and walked in.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p8" pid="tWeuBeowU0ubus3UovMSgg" hash="MqO99w">He said, “What can I do for you, son?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p9" pid="FnZjUcN8gkOoT20mP9lW8A" hash="mHQvlA">I said, “Where do you sign up for varsity baseball?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p10" pid="TRzQBL4aQUmZtnF6WfFeMg" hash="WfuUzQ">He said, “Let me ask you a question—do you want to play ball or be a champion?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p11" pid="WLC2mnhvmkCJioiqpXC1DQ" hash="eAKokg">I said, “I came to play ball.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p12" pid="7TTsWlvDRUKhs0jjmc3JUg" hash="Q08LMw">He said, “I’m sorry, we’re all filled up.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p13" pid="BUYGeI8A-02R1cUO0WZXtg" hash="0yFQRg">With a broken heart, I turned and walked out. That wasn’t the answer I wanted to hear! I stood in the hall for a minute (thank goodness my dad had taught me courage to keep trying), then plucked up my courage and again knocked on the door. The answer came as before, “Come in!” I walked in.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p14" pid="uDxY6MC7BEC_UXU66d23Pg" hash="6naLDQ">He said, “Oh, it’s you again.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p15" pid="t09eQm7ZM0-azTWXqYmrDQ" hash="k94MDQ">I said, “Yes, sir, maybe you didn’t understand my earlier question. I asked you where to sign up for varsity baseball.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p16" pid="8prWQ-DbT0-vv6UTiQootA" hash="I15v2Q">He said, “I asked <span class="emphasis">you</span> a question. Do you want to play ball or be a champion?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p17" pid="oxPVqHpoBkeh8W7U45BicQ" hash="xfaZyA">Well, I knew the other answer hadn’t worked, so I said, “I want to be a champion.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p18" pid="W_rmPqxb9UWbScYhmz_6oA" hash="VrUAUQ">“Oh,” he said, “sign here.” And I did. He said, “We build champions.” Then he turned and said, “Have you ever signed a contract before?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p19" pid="tLLSfcUFzE2hGNc09S3t3Q" hash="LyhyYA">I said, “No, sir, I’m only fifteen.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p20" pid="mdtuINI0OEuED83HA_wgmg" hash="spDLJA">He said, “At this institution, we commit ourselves to principles.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p21" pid="WEVTqRqi0UeWQaixwIZ6NA" hash="3aR8wg">He took from the bottom drawer of his file a contract already typed, and on it were the standards that we have been listening to in this great conference. He said, “You take that home and read it over with your parents. If you can agree to the conditions, you sign it and bring it back tomorrow.” I did. Somehow, I made the team.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p22" pid="qWdWLUVqz0u3MDRKTMKBFw" hash="0dLL8Q">In the contractual agreement were promises to be the kind of a Latter-day Saint I knew I ought to be. We went through a great, great season. It ended in a tie with our arch-rival high school. The play-off game was to determine the state championship. As we assembled on the field in the last-minute preparation for the great event, the coach had us around the batting cage. As he was making his little pep talk, he stopped in front of me and said, “Oh, by the way, you will pitch the deciding game.” My heart dropped! He continued his counsel. And then he stopped in front of our excellent second baseman. Most of you would know him because he went on to play for the Chicago White Sox for a number of years. He said, as he looked, “Jimmy, is that a nicotine stain on your finger?” Jimmy, like the rest of us, had made a commitment to keep his body clean.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p23" pid="Kmigk9A2tEyuHC2Qw3uGDQ" hash="dxLl-g">Jimmy, looking at his finger, quickly hid his hand and said, embarrassed, “Yes, sir.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p24" pid="3d7k23GMiU6hjEJ28t_I9A" hash="Lx0lyA">The coach said in front of the whole team, “Did you sign a contract with me?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p25" pid="KFawD_dQekqcMsJawJsFpg" hash="eYhrSg">“Yes, sir.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p26" pid="p7FVRvJFH0mmQJYNbDJqTw" hash="eb_Qxw">“And you broke the contract?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p27" pid="_E8_VMTO1kurkbZO7avuXw" hash="eYhrSg1">“Yes, sir.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p28" pid="Asm0NYqfr0OdjLl5iJWFGQ" hash="huFL0w">“Do you know the penalty?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p29" pid="g2rA_5teIEGJAK9Vlt6Mng" hash="eYhrSg2">“Yes, sir.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p30" pid="M2TS7nd4RESr1eilVzparg" hash="q5CXag">“Would you turn in your uniform? You’re through.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p31" pid="gbwY3GHz30CC5skm_ZBi-Q" hash="025ymQ">I wanted to say, “Coach, tomorrow’s the big game. (Jimmy was batting .385 and hadn’t made an error at second base all year.) But the coach was thinking of a boy, not a game. Jimmy turned in his uniform, but the coach kept close to him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p32" pid="DgYfac6l4UiX3vnWL3AvPw" hash="ErMDBA">I drew the assignment the next day to pitch against Al Yalian, who later signed with the New York Yankees for a fabulous bonus. Thirteen innings we went, and he beat me in the thirteenth—1–0. The run came when a ground ball was hit to second where Jimmy normally played. The ball got through a nervous substitute’s legs onto the outfield grass and eventually scored an unearned run, which defeated us. And now, years later, I thank God for a great coach who taught me that principles are more important than games.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p33" pid="ZN9wBw62_Uu3SIaPRWRgdA" hash="YFAxyw">As I reflect upon these kinds of experiences and the influence that great men have had on my life, I think of the question that young people quite often ask those of us in these positions, “Why do we hold so many meetings in the Church?” The Lord understood and answered, speaking to you and me, young people, through a prophet: “And now, behold, I give unto you a commandment, that when ye are assembled together ye shall instruct and edify each other.” Why? “That ye may know how to act and direct my church.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/43.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 43:8</a>.) And I thank God that in this great conference and others that have preceded it we are taught how to act. “We thank thee, O God, for a prophet to guide us in these latter days.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p34" pid="6UI-ozFIyk-BtCCLw4Ie1Q" hash="AD-MOg">Like many of you, I am frequently before those who are not of our faith, and the challenge is great and wonderful. Not long ago I was given a little honor before a great group of non-Latter-day Saint athletes. In the proceedings of the convention, one of my great idols, a Hall of Famer, was to take the rostrum and speak to us. Being the great athlete that he was, respected by many, I was shocked to hear his language as he repeatedly took the name of the Lord in vain. As I sat there, I wondered, “What do you do as a Latter-day Saint in these kinds of social situations?” And then I remembered—again, a great influence in my life—the counsel from a prophet and an experience that he had had one time coming out of surgery. An orderly who was wheeling the prophet back to his hospital room on a little metal cart caught his hand between the door and the cart in the elevator and, not thinking, let go with a few adjectives, taking the name of the Lord in vain in the process. And a prophet, sick as he was physically but very well spiritually, lifted his head and said, “Please don’t talk that way—that’s my best friend.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p35" pid="O_ZCZXR14E6sageZ4EP-cA" hash="4ZSj2w">Those thoughts went through my mind as I listened to my idol. As he concluded and sat down, I put my hand on his knee and said to him, “You’re terrific! Did you know that when I was growing up I had you on a high pedestal? But, if I might level with you, tonight you fell off that pedestal.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p36" pid="ichYMJ5fg0KRX3xPNlOHIw" hash="k6K7fw">He said, “Didn’t you like my workshop?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p37" pid="1_T_7MxGv0qYAAKyd7XVwA" hash="sT3rjg">I said, “I loved it. But every time you opened your mouth, you offended me and a lot of other people out there. I’m going to challenge you tonight, as your friend, to clean up your language.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p38" pid="VYAKHVIZO0iVBwoPw5P9vA" hash="VHoexQ">I thought of the apostle Paul and Joseph Smith and particularly of a prophet today, Spencer W. Kimball; and I learned on that occasion, as I have on many others, that people really want what you and I have, if we have the courage to give it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it.p39" pid="fZc2zMUP9E-g9-zMwZpBgA" hash="euHAqA">God grant us to have that courage and determination as we go forth, edified and fortified by the influences of great men in our lives, to be an example unto the world. I testify that I know that God lives, that Jesus is the Christ, and that here sits his prophet. In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/10/follow-it</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1976-general-conference/1976-10-4020-elder-paul-h-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="5663107" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 1976 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Because I Have a Father”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Millions throughout the world sustain President Kimball as a prophet of the Lord. We in the Church sing a very important hymn that says, “We thank thee, O God, for a prophet / To guide us in these latter days” ( no. 196). Prophets have done that thro</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03109_000_004" doc-version="2" hash="YVS8_g"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="4T8WXsSWn0iGhM9lcrBdig" hash="SOvbnw">“Because I Have a Father”</h1><p class="authorName" guid="74719440-7a80-44ef-bc3f-eb57a10732cb" pid="rjdkPXDFREOHhdmDzlUJwQ" hash="2gvHCQ">Paul H. Dunn</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="7e4c371f-d304-4871-8000-90e7ac56d25a">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26ec.jpg" alt="Elder Paul H. Dunn" guid="51fdf733-9a73-4d37-8883-650c64055edd" pid="qEXaASuvaEe4JxXlSF0ioA" hash="lWLluA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="EOMygZ5WJUGKYd1y51qAcQ" hash="YrWr4Q">Millions throughout the world sustain President Kimball as a prophet of the Lord. We in the Church sing a very important hymn that says, “We thank thee, O God, for a prophet / To guide us in these latter days” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 196). Prophets have done that throughout all of history. I testify to you that Spencer Kimball really is a prophet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="KKx98sKnHEGiHqWxCSSSDg" hash="lzbFQw">For many years I have been a people-watcher. I love to watch people. They are interesting, fascinating. There is a sermon in every face. Faces! Smiling faces, frowning, angry, calm, unhappy, content. Faces! Round, square, oval, dimpled, beautiful, plain, striking, ordinary. Faces! Old and young.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="3zxsKgQxa0mb8HlsN1DOBA" hash="iUKETQ">Is there anything quite so revealing as a boy’s face at his birthday party, the faces of a young couple just engaged, of new parents with their first child, of a proud mom and dad at their son or daughter’s graduation, of a husband and wife on their golden wedding anniversary?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="ti0aMarbJECHV16YMLAsgA" hash="VSiZnA">Is there anything quite so funny as the face of a six-year-old with bubble gum exploded from ear to ear, a forgetful girl with two dates for the same night, a young bride who innocently cooks the peas in the pod, a parent who calls every name in the house before finding the right one, grandpa without his teeth?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="yJq-2wxFm0yXy8YcP6PQNQ" hash="OvwjWA">And finally, is there anything quite so touching as the face of a teenager alone in a new school, a couple upon the death of their first child, parents worried sick over a wayward child, old people unvisited, a child in prayer?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="hVyvvGDUSEieL448BwBCmA" hash="jyVQ3g">Faces! They reveal so much! They tell a story. Speaking of faces, let me just share a little experience with you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="ZIUOjawHP0W9WdzUGgCDsg" hash="Hd_K3Q">One day I was taping a radio program that was just a series of chats with little children. We had five or six children come down to the studio, and they were all dressed up in their bandbox best. I just started talking to them, one at a time. We were hoping to catch some snatch of conversation that would be good for the broadcast. The first one was a little five-year-old, and as she came in, I put her on my lap. I said to her, “Tell me, do you like to go to church?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="6URsTwwY1EKb5ZJX-Mzgcw" hash="GqmmqA">“Nope.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="2n2oq53EAU2JiKvyzagWaw" hash="aI5R8Q">I said, “Why not?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="nWx8Zo3RgkaNsqWGNDP7Sg" hash="cJrzsw">“Too boring.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="tG7BkP7yOEGbiScTvcknXQ" hash="Un_FeA">I lifted her off and said, “Next.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="D4JuMCfrQUKMEmyx6bz0tQ" hash="lauPDQ">I didn’t think that we ought to air that family secret. I talked to two or three other children, and finally the door opened and a little toddler came in, cute as a button, in a freshly ironed dress. You know what her mother must have put her through to get her ready to come down to the studio. What an innocent face! I picked her up and said, “Well, who are you?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="lGuv03HtPkiIejR0boOvyA" hash="tWR0zA">She said, “Cory.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="mtR47-2SZESo1KEMBZ8QyA" hash="Rc5eEQ">I said, “How old are you, Cory?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="LNjXVp9vn0CSSGdTs8Bp9g" hash="den1Zg">She raised three fingers. “Three.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="BD5BNUMQzU2rRDLylUY5dQ" hash="FtVEZw">By now I was out of questions, so I said, “Do you know how to sing?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="ZMOfe5AliEC9K1yw60-Mug" hash="yTVF1Q">“Uh-huh.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="LtAnGetDcE-JjTF8ipE9Ig" hash="FTRTVA">“Would you sing for me?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="GSnSCPCURUePtQMhgqDHUQ" hash="yTVF1Q1">“Uh-huh.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="EnUbWlC11UODe-Qh65LQkA" hash="kihswg">Without any prompting she commenced to sing a medley of Primary songs, ending with “I Am a Child of God.” I don’t know what that does to you, but I’m kind of tender. I looked through the window, and the engineer was even pushing back a tear or two himself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="v623xcwU40ey75WN3X0jvw" hash="fXDHig">Then I said, “Well, Cory, you sing like you know God.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="S7o08OyRPUetTX9cBUbvuw" hash="yTVF1Q2">“Uh-huh.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="lHE_y0Zic0aIGkrFsV_vRw" hash="dkOmtQ">I said, “How would a three-year-old know God?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="-wHyeFYyU0mH4KNLBXx7Xg" hash="i3D2ig">She looked at me, and I’ll never forget her answer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="rub-s6PZBE-Gpjg-r4Y7Bg" hash="AjRiAA">She said, “Because I have a father.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="CLhWRK53_0O4uyyoNPyWPg" hash="g_zfWA">And I thought, “Oh, the power of a father in the home!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="4IR1QeaCdEWBTl-ePiSDCQ" hash="F7qR2g">I said, “Do you know Jesus?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="1buWBGTGjUOmLv9x13uVWg" hash="yTVF1Q3">“Uh-huh.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="e1fsQsHfDUacAOv4cvhkJA" hash="aPRpqw">I said, “Who’s Jesus?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="45M339ftGU-6tJV2nRhYSw" hash="znhhnQ">She said, “Our Elder Brother.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="oeoMJqsUBkSY4gb0ZWgRog" hash="eSR7rg">I said, “Do you love Jesus?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="e9X6eyQSAUSjG8JJq9XcNQ" hash="yTVF1Q4">“Uh-huh.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="CrGMzRc8RkCfArA0QmYxVg" hash="r2oy-Q">“Why do you love Jesus?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="gWuht7q-9U2Bn7NJXw6FJw" hash="3bQ2xA">She responded, “Because of what he did for us.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="DnNqbMMaY0iKcpfiZkS4XQ" hash="fo0H1Q">I said, “What did Jesus do for us?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="6Ckj9zrPkU2bwGj0rfongw" hash="S1acmQ">She came right back and said, “He died for us.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="VPeHy2-BVk6meFdaGI_PYA" hash="PuM6Ow">I said, “Why would he do that?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="6BeL47zlt0iAEmiJD_DziA" hash="XZ3_Lg">And she looked at me as if to say, “Well, don’t you know?” She said, “So you and I will live again.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="UU68l3TsRUiGZ1aRiN1a6Q" hash="9Eziqg">And I thought, what marvelous insight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="EH_ANjC54EqRetNlAEgAqA" hash="qVO-Ig">Isn’t it amazing how people can know at three what they can’t understand at thirty-three or fifty-three? What she was saying is that God the Father has not forgotten us here in mortality. He has not removed himself to a far corner of the universe to watch our antics with indifference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="QvmZbsoMJEqXgmlN9oftiQ" hash="vOxo0g">Many people, you know, believe that he’s done just that. They can’t believe that he could create a universe, people a world with billions of souls, and still care a whit what happens to a single individual with his small concerns. They can’t believe that they’re that important to anyone, let alone to the Creator of it all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="uRj5XajzAUauxNgLGbhl8g" hash="JDdtDA">May I tell you that I know that God lives, that he cares, and that he knows each one of us individually by name? Somewhere between youth and growing up many of us lose that simple faith of a child. Who puts out the light in our eyes and replaces it with the dull film through which most of us see the world and our place in it? Perhaps it is because our lives sometimes hold more frustration than we think we can bear. We get all caught up in the thick of thin things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="rYvcTUzoUEqvpco7dq8p0g" hash="7w8nNg">As one man said, “Sometimes I hear a great talk or read an inspirational book and I just really feel inspired. It seems that a stirring giant in me comes awake. But then I get a flat tire on the way to work or an unexpected bill I can’t pay, or my children won’t get off the phone, and somebody else gets the promotion at the office. My good intentions just fade away in the crunch of everyday life.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="TpDEPa94YEq-XKdK0gLaaQ" hash="8QML7A">We are all the same way no matter who we are or where we live, no matter what our wealth or position in the world. We have just about all we can do to cope with each day. Oh, the pressures and frustrations may be small ones sometimes. We may have too much to do, we may feel unappreciated, we may lose a button off our coat, or just not be able to get above the mundane. It sometimes doesn’t have to be a whole lot. But the accumulation of it all, day after day, just wears down our motor—like our neighbor’s dishwasher that recently required a fifty-dollar repair job because a toothpick got into the works.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="XsOZRwqQs0iHXP4va-b0ig" hash="nx9ACQ">And for each of us there may be times when we have to cope with real tragedy, real opposition. There are those who lose a loved one who was the very light of their life. Health may deteriorate. There may be some in this very listening audience who cannot make ends meet or get enough food to fill an aching stomach. I remember reading of a man who was a prisoner of war in Vietnam who did not sleep for months because he was in such pain from beriberi. The only rest he got was when the pain became so intense his body could not stand it any longer and he would lose consciousness. How do you cope with that?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="qCJelK3R4k6vHLINFSCCLg" hash="xPvXyg">Well, whether it’s for small reasons or big ones, there are sometimes questions that enter our hearts: Could I have been more? Could I have done more? Is there some evasive, elusive happiness I’ve missed along the way? <span class="emphasis">How do I cope?</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="Mus_o21P6UOp8U8jJpxlpA" hash="B6Slvg">And you know, the answer that men and women have found to those questions has given mankind its greatest moments because the message of the century is: God really lives. Jesus is the Christ. He has revealed himself in latter days, and he speaks to us through a prophet, such a one as we’ve heard this morning. Through modern prophets we can come to know the truth, the divine principles which help us live and adjust, which give meaning and direction to our lives. When these divine principles are applied, nothing can defeat us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="_hVFH3HTBk-73UMBI-OggQ" hash="nmhuIg">You can’t cover up who you really are before His penetrating gaze. Whoever you are, however you are, he’ll take you as you are if you are willing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="JfUwLFA6BkqYm4qmtg2OnQ" hash="tnRD_w">You remember that the Duke of Wellington was talking of the Battle of Waterloo when he said that it was not that the British soldiers were braver than the French soldiers. It was just that they were brave five minutes longer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="Y-ByLbgpJUmyJBjp18GQOw" hash="bugTvA">And in our struggles sometimes that’s all it takes—to be brave five minutes longer, to try just a little harder, to not give up on ourselves when everything seems to beg for our defeat.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="NyYz9pkjf0-l4LhynOqHog" hash="UW2Z5Q">I know a young man who is a quadriplegic. He has no use of his arms and legs, which have deteriorated without use. The only way he can get around is by lying on a specially designed cart which he steers with his chin. But what is most marvelous to me is that he won’t quit. This young man often wears red socks on his useless feet. They are there like a badge of defiance against his handicap, a mark for everyone who sees him wheeling around which says, “Look at me! I won’t give up.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="z8hjoxVzvkK7o4REbSsFHA" hash="AuLm0Q">I remember a great phrase I learned from my father some years ago. He said, “It matters not if you try and fail and try and fail again. It matters much if you try and fail and fail to try again.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="7Adnbgm4yky9YBlVV0TeWA" hash="zY-dJw">How do you cope? I know a woman who is noted for her smile. Her good cheer is rarely daunted. I asked her how she managed it with all the irritations she has had in life, and she told me this: As a child she had been taking an important letter to her father, who stood just behind a barbed-wire fence. In her eagerness to get there she ran toward him and tripped, and she fell against the fence, cutting her face deeply from the forehead down through the cheek. It left a permanent scar, and the scar was mistaken for a frown and grouchiness. She said, “I couldn’t have the world think I have nothing but a frown to give, so I had to smile that frown away.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="TejvIAfx-0Om36T8Wa1b3Q" hash="8e9ikQ">You and I cannot give up, no matter what the size of our struggles. We were not meant to be fear-haunted and defeated nobodies. There is something deep in our hearts saying that we belong to something higher. And that something higher is an eternal family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="9WLx8UWYCUO-2-a54leT_Q" hash="LkcqbQ">We must remember too that our struggles here are not too trivial to interest the Lord. Those of you who follow the developments of astronomy know that lately there has been a big stir in the scientific community about a galaxy prosaically called NGC 1961. It seems this galaxy has ten times the mass of our own Milky Way and billions of young, hot stars. When we think that our Lord created all that and understands the immensities of space that only boggle our minds, we have difficulty believing that his interest could ever devolve on something as minute as our little pain or concerns.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="t4borGg26UyYzsl2S2zKjg" hash="-ynvGw">But the record of Christ’s life on earth certainly shows that he was not above caring for the human-size needs or fears of his earthly companions. Do you remember when Lazarus, the brother of Mary and Martha, died? Both sisters rushed to meet Christ to tell him of their sorrow and find comfort. And as they met him, they said in turn, “Lord, if thou hadst been here, my brother had not died” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/11.21,32" class="scriptureRef">John 11:21, 32</a>). Now, who would know better than Jesus Christ that there was to be a resurrection so that Lazarus would live again? He didn’t just say to them, “Chin up, ladies. It’s only a few years before you see your brother again.” Instead the scriptures tell us, “Jesus wept” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/11.35" class="scriptureRef">John 11:35</a>), wept in pure compassion for the pain and lack of understanding of his two friends. Then he hurried to the tomb and raised Lazarus from the dead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="qJrLel863Um-uCtz7t5E3w" hash="Qd-cNQ">Think, too, when Christ was preaching to the multitude and then performed the miracle of the fish and the loaves to feed the hungry masses. He wasn’t responding then to something earthshaking or lofty. He saw the human need to be fed and he used his divine powers to meet that need.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="wWxjKX-QFkayycbfLYdl_A" hash="H-lh_Q">Well, our frustrations and disappointments may be just pinpricks in the eternal scheme of things, but since they do not seem that way to us, they do not seem that way to the Lord. Quit thinking that tomorrow your problems will go away and life will begin in earnest. The Lord is waiting to help you cope today if you will lay your human-size needs at his divine feet. Pray in specifics about the problems, little or big, that impede your progress and dull your best dreams. Knock, seek, and you shall find the answer to your prayers. That I promise you because you really are his child. He will give you the comfort and the counsel that you need, the courage to lift up your head and face your todays with faith and hope.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father.p" pid="KHhH2rI-_Ei7UBoCcWLrIg" hash="WwCDnw">You see, my bright-eyed, three-year-old friend was right all along. Why will you make it in today’s world? Why will you be able to cope? Cory’s answer was right: “<span class="emphasis">Because you have a Father,” </span>to which I testify, in the holy name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26ec.jpg" alt="Elder Paul H. Dunn" guid="51fdf733-9a73-4d37-8883-650c64055edd" pid="P6Xgp6nqs0u_7Ng0otEkZg" hash="lWLluA1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="51fdf733-9a73-4d37-8883-650c64055edd"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1979/04/because-i-have-a-father</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1979-general-conference/1979-04-1020-elder-paul-h-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="6963142" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 1979 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time-Out!</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1980/04/time-out?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Like many of you, I really enjoy sports. Sports often teach great lessons. The other night while I was watching an NCAA championship basketball game, I heard one of the players call out that familiar word, “time!” The team ran to the sidelines to rec</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03122_000_017" doc-version="2" hash="7ZlD7g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="HHdtu-jwy0OsRNsT6LmSBA" hash="0R-Teg">Time-Out!</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="NQcH1U8CdUWXMcMSkfGD9g" hash="2gvHCQ">Paul H. Dunn</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26ec.jpg" alt="Elder Paul H. Dunn" pid="sReayPAntEOYSaLEQtZlQQ" hash="lWLluA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p1" pid="4BykfxhGVEC0hMMmRNl3OQ" hash="ufuXvQ">Like many of you, I really enjoy sports. Sports often teach great lessons. The other night while I was watching an NCAA championship basketball game, I heard one of the players call out that familiar word, “time!” The team ran to the sidelines to receive some instructions from the man who could give them some help—the coach. And he did.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p2" pid="EH4suzSRn0aTQA7-ZLZSQQ" hash="AHk5Tw">Isn’t it interesting that, generally speaking, a team calls time-out when they’re in trouble, when they need to regroup? I recall many times in my career when we’d call “time,” and the catcher or the pitching coach or the manager would come to the mound and give me some needed instructions or encouragement. Sometimes the language was a little different, but the counsel was most always appreciated, sometimes even humorous.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p3" pid="fU5ymiYZ6EWuIby2p6EZZQ" hash="9MXr8Q">I recall in one of my first professional games many years ago, in the very first inning the first three hitters hit safely, all of them on the first pitch. Out of the dugout came the pitching coach. The catcher joined him, and the three of us assembled on the mound.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p4" pid="LvNYYufu1EieQC7f3GEp0Q" hash="lTJ2Sg">The pitching coach turned to my catcher and said, “What in the world has Paul got on the ball anyway?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p5" pid="6V3SY3Fyi0KJ8JttnGM7iA" hash="nKQQLw">The catcher said, “I don’t know. I haven’t seen it yet.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p6" pid="7usHpum6jUWSbYiS4BzCtA" hash="gIeXCA">Well, what’s that got to do with you and me? Life, you know, is a little like “the big game.” There are times when you and I need to call time-out. Have you ever had the experience of loading the bases while continuing to throw high and wide? Have you experienced “fourth down and one” on the goal line with ten seconds left? Have you watched your twenty-point lead dwindle to two? Or in life’s game do you have a challenge controlling your temper or language? Is that personal weakness you’ve noticed still not under control? Are school subjects your nemesis? Are your finances ready to pull you under? Is your family solidarity sitting on shifting sand? And most important of all, are you trying to do it alone? Or have you been smart enough to call time-out to ask the coach for help?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p7" pid="TM2l9_PTmEelQaBRKyAU3w" hash="VGRrow">You know, it doesn’t always have to be a formal prayer, my young brethren. You can do it as you drive in the car, on a date, in the privacy of your room, or on the playing field.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p8" pid="jcwNZTSI20i5wZuaWrO8iA" hash="tvAwXw">I’m reminded of something I read just the other day. Let me share it with you. It seems that a small boy was trying to lift a heavy stone, but couldn’t budge it. His father, watching very interestedly, said, “Are you sure you’re using all of your strength?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p9" pid="1A5csIZd8k2A5pRewAEMgA" hash="HE4BNw">“Yes, I am!” the boy cried.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p10" pid="4HObe8_WB0aJr04KR36BVw" hash="0oVGiw">“No, you’re not,” said the father. “You haven’t asked me to help you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p11" pid="nbjfFxSTfESnxQ7QnKrVGg" hash="flDr1g">Well, let me just tell you that however tight the game seems at the moment, I know the coach and I know that He can help. There is a personal and loving God who knows all of the plays. He understands the game of life. He understands you and me. And he understands what you and I need now to help in our lives. Talking to him is an easy thing, really. All you have to do is call time-out. Say to yourself, “I’ve had it. I need help.” And be prepared to listen. Say to him, “I can’t take any more of this running without seeing clearly where the bases are or the direction I’m headed.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p12" pid="yFGbzPEYEk-azpZS9WsVYw" hash="uKPmiQ">Are you aware that all through history great leaders have called time-out? Washington at Valley Forge, Lincoln seeking answers in the war, Joseph Smith in the grove. This was true of the prophets of old: Abraham sought God; Moses called upon the Lord. Nephi, a great young champion, says in his own account: “I, Nephi, being exceeding young [like many of you], nevertheless being large in stature, and also having great desires to know of the mysteries of God, wherefore, I did cry unto the Lord; and behold he did visit me, and did soften my heart that I did believe all the words which had been spoken by my father; wherefore, I did not rebel against him like unto my brothers” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/2.16" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 2:16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p13" pid="74l5Fq259kuve58YDAWTHA" hash="CcQfNQ">Accounts such as these in scripture have always given me great courage to do likewise. That’s why I think the prophets, even the leaders today, have counseled us to know the scriptures that we might be motivated to seek help.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p14" pid="6MzT4_rZn0y4HJrBP3OROQ" hash="ouwOrA">Fortunately, like many of you, I came from a home where that kind of influence was available. Near my eighteenth birthday I was drafted into World War II. I found myself in an entirely new environment. I had always been taught in my home to take time out at night to pray, but I found this a little delicate, where in a typical barrack, there would be over fifty men on a floor. I used to try to get a bunk near the end of the room, where there would be a little privacy, and I would wait until the lights would go out before I would crawl out of bed to say my prayers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p15" pid="Sn128tudfEOS_fbMw6koIQ" hash="1ing6w">I remember at Fort MacArthur everything went well for the first few nights and then finally one night, shortly after the lights went out, I crawled out of bed and knelt down to pray. About that time two half-stewed characters came in, flipped on the lights, and aroused all of us. A couple of fellows across the aisle from me saw me on my knees. Typical of that kind of environment, they started to poke fun. One of them, pointing to me, shouted so all could hear, “Hey, holy Paul, pray for me!” I felt a little chagrined and somewhat embarrassed and I thought to myself, “Now, what do you do?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p16" pid="sQ3AgX3yt06ToQzlfDIlMQ" hash="a42z8g">My mother had taught me a great principle. She used to say: “In delicate situations, use a sense of humor. It always helps.” So while still on my knees, I squared my shoulders, looked at both of the soldiers, and said: “Would you give me your full names because I don’t think the Lord knows you.” Later, I’m pleased to say, they did come to know the Lord because they too took time-out.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p17" pid="U3qDpx8DfEiKYFkZT4HsYg" hash="vvpVUw">I noticed later, when we got into combat, that in my battalion—the 305th Infantry—the word soon got around: “Get in Dunn’s squad. He always comes back.” Many is the time that I shared a foxhole with anxious soldiers where we took time-out to talk to our Eternal Coach, even our Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p18" pid="SrY-6beWnUu3iral0miamg" hash="PpJIog">I remember the time so well as we were preparing for my very first invasion, sitting out in the Pacific on a troop ship with three thousand men aboard. This large group of soldiers represented the first seven waves in the invasion force. Prior to disembarking, one of the Protestant chaplains held a final church service. He had us all look around and get acquainted with each other and then he said: “Now, gentlemen, I don’t want to worry you, but do you realize by tomorrow morning at eight o’clock, many of you will be standing before your Maker? Are you ready?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p19" pid="_MOSjwY_vkGB6DH4a16r1Q" hash="07yn3g">Well, how would you feel, young men, if that challenge were hurled at you? At that time I was almost nineteen. Shortly after the service I found a secluded spot on the ship and called time-out and talked to my Heavenly Father. I didn’t sleep that night nor did most of the men. The next morning as the seven waves of infantry went ashore, many not making it, I dug my first foxhole and took another time-out. I remember the event well. I called upon my Heavenly Father and said, “I really need to know if thou art there.” Heavenly Father spoke to my mind, and I haven’t been the same since.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p20" pid="HpD2UicNrUWg6Enz5RNafQ" hash="Q5JoGQ">Will you learn, my young brethren, to take time-out? It even works in sports, because of the amazing influence it wields. I remember my first professional season, playing in a strange town; I had joined the club at midseason. The catcher, who was also the manager, was old enough to be my father. He was an old professional ballplayer from the Washington Senators and had had much experience. The team was a rough lot. I remember so well one night while visiting in a distant town, about two o’clock a knock came at my hotel door. I got up and answered it, and there standing in the framework was my manager.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p21" pid="UnRw7KCu7kOFPyE2oGKXdA" hash="JPOCYQ">He said, “Paul, may I come in?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p22" pid="pbnb2EAExkWATcAHJHzWHA" hash="DE5Bdg">And I said, “Please do. What’s the matter?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p23" pid="GIwQpSM7H0yOL-pdneFYcA" hash="HZCVxQ">He said, “Close the door, and whatever you do don’t tell the others I came.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p24" pid="fpCZMryfa0OouYT81CWmBQ" hash="TPwZYw">I said, “Well, I won’t.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p25" pid="FUgEmREwmka5jedqQqclfw" hash="a9cL0Q">He responded: “I’ve been watching you for these past two months. You know the Lord, don’t you?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p26" pid="jNIV3Zmiek-6sZzB8E-afg" hash="ctxSeQ">I said, “I think he’s my friend.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p27" pid="Kr2obVlufkyDsZu6XUObhw" hash="dW2wQw">He said, “Would you help me find him?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p28" pid="bIh4l-6Bo0CJvrAXIfbugg" hash="ONu0Tw">We sat down in the room, and for over two hours talked about God, the Eternal Father and his Son, Jesus Christ. Tears began to form in his eyes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p29" pid="zHzfFCYN90CuaUpnhCuXDA" hash="1qqy2A">I said, “Danny, have you ever prayed?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p30" pid="SDuSJcAJjE2NDlLy9zGEAA" hash="TYEJEg">He said, “No.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p31" pid="F_ET0Xs79UCg-Z5BKCL-0g" hash="8tG27w">I said, “Would it offend you to pray with me?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p32" pid="Jh5fq-MkakC1cYdVtbZS0w" hash="A8PkDA">“Well,” he said, “not if you will pray.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p33" pid="rZxoWdhOCEK-NRRi5fZ2ug" hash="L_tJUg">I said, “I would be honored.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p34" pid="P_p4G-2U30uXGSsppWCLuw" hash="_5sZKw">So together we knelt down beside my bed, and talked to Heavenly Father. We took time-out. And as we arose from our knees, he pushed back the tears, threw his arms around me, almost choked me to death, and said, “Thank you, thank you. Could we do this some more?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p35" pid="0PhnG6WZ9UyfLEPzB7PRfA" hash="qde9kw">I said, “As often as you would like.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p36" pid="VeImUSyQTEmf6WlNUZxvvA" hash="r4FP7A">We did on several other occasions. But you know what else was interesting? Before the season ended, several other knocks came at my door. One night it was the first baseman, then the shortstop, and the left fielder. And each in his own wonderful way said, “Don’t tell the others.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/time-out.p37" pid="Zd4u-PPDFkmAWdJSceEScA" hash="_rXRwA">I learned on that occasion that people are really seeking and want what you and I have. God bless you, my wonderful brethren, to have the wisdom and strength to call time-out and visit with your Heavenly Father. He really lives, as does his Son, to which I testify in the holy name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1980/04/time-out</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1980-general-conference/1980-04-3020-elder-paul-h-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="5594083" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 1980 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teach “the Why”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why?lang=eng</link>
      <description>What a special delight it is, brothers and sisters, to stand in your presence once more, to feel of your great spirit. I’m just glad we’re friends.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03141_000_028" doc-version="2" hash="HD0tAA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="X8t9CHxfhkqS_9rwK5jLnA" hash="QjDbkA">Teach “the Why”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="dcHc8vnQ3EiFJeXX4hwXTg" hash="2gvHCQ">Paul H. Dunn</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26ec.jpg" alt="Elder Paul H. Dunn" pid="chwAJ76LUUmws6Arqkf-CQ" hash="lWLluA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p1" pid="0B7EBUgWAke1aUy4UtyUjw" hash="JUDj1Q">What a special delight it is, brothers and sisters, to stand in your presence once more, to feel of your great spirit. I’m just glad we’re friends.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p2" pid="8UGyMF4VfEumjTlAdDZ15A" hash="4gLSLQ">You know, conference is a great time for spiritual uplift, for association, and for wise counsel. With all the counsel I’ve been hearing, I couldn’t help but reminisce a little bit about the young athlete who attempted most all sports but had never tried skydiving. And so he took several theoretical courses in how to jump.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p3" pid="c3LFbClE2EiSH1OcQp9EvQ" hash="Gxa2hA">When the day came for the solo flight, he became a little fearful, so he approached his instructor and said, “I’m not sure I want to go through with this.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p4" pid="UxACJWf85UKMEBuhN09GoQ" hash="tSCYPg">The instructor said, “Don’t worry. We’ll protect you by putting two added parachutes on you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p5" pid="cDEy_ogbak6Z2_NDzxR_Yw" hash="raAA5A">The plane took off and arrived at the three thousand foot level. With some fear and trepidation he was pushed out.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p6" pid="K4d3TOjqmUWrPi7ZcVusww" hash="PCckfw">On the way down, at about two thousand feet, he remembered that that’s when you pull the rip cord. He did so, and the chute didn’t open. He pulled the second, and it didn’t open. He pulled the third, and it didn’t open.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p7" pid="Vc0erTHeP06XSGZBpeaycA" hash="Htfp4Q">To his amazement, at about that time he met in the air, coming up from the ground, another man. They passed on the way. The young parachutist shouted to his new friend, “Pardon me,” he said, “do you know anything about parachutes?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p8" pid="J6eXSAzHzkC_B6LNmTdF3A" hash="Pa0HRg">“No,” his friend shouted back, “what do you know about Coleman lanterns?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p9" pid="Y7uG4RJNbU-CoeCdRdnscQ" hash="WV0mIg">I suppose it seems all of us are in need of good counsel. Quite often parents and many young people ask the question, “How do you teach the gospel so that it’s meaningful and applicable?” Do you know, my brothers and sisters, that learning any concept or principle or changing any behavior pattern requires five important steps?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p10" pid="7eDl7XnqUEOFW-ULfTiuVA" hash="SXxtIw">
        <span class="emphasis">First,</span> you have to expose a person. <span class="emphasis">Second</span> is the law of repetition. <span class="emphasis">Third</span> is to give understanding, the why. People of all ages want to know the whys of the gospel, not just the rules. This is the most important aspect of teaching because the <span class="emphasis">fourth</span> step, that of conviction, and the <span class="emphasis">fifth,</span> application, cannot occur until we understand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p11" pid="4vbj2_kaiUaiCrmCA4KzoA" hash="tX_KjA">Too often our answers to young people’s inquiries are “Well, because the scriptures say so” or “That is what the leaders tell us.” Young people want to know why the scriptures say so and why the leaders are so concerned.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p12" pid="IK99ZTST7Uq_qWFT1SpM0A" hash="jOJpcA">Let me just share a little personal experience that happened some years ago at the university.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p13" pid="fKqrKPIixU-PrrXfXJxqgw" hash="CQ6xCg">I’d been in a very special meeting with some young people. We had been talking about temple marriage. As we departed the session, I was walking with three young ladies, one of whom I knew quite well. I had become aware that she had been dating a boy out of the faith, and I just cautiously suggested to her that you tend to marry those you date. I said, “I am planning on the day when I can perform your sealing in the temple.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p14" pid="eC_dd-X5jUqEVyscIx4lig" hash="BhAxFQ">She looked at me and she said, “Well, I may not get married in the temple.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p15" pid="JOhHZXmpnESnkGcLyFhzCQ" hash="gghw1w">And I said, “Why not?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p16" pid="7XH0hqwZV0-DeylIpMX_1Q" hash="4Miaug">And she looked at me as only young people can, and said, “Why should I?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p17" pid="A2xnIct7L0St3WH_zNEXzA" hash="llNc_A">All right, mom and dad, teacher. What do you tell them?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p18" pid="CYnZ406f5EWsw8DzGM9NXg" hash="xzy_XA">Like most teachers, I paused to stall and think. Then, hoping for inspiration, I said, “Well, why shouldn’t you?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p19" pid="D2H3V5CS1UeYJyPBVcw2dw" hash="oC_pbw">She looked at me and she said, “Do you really want to know?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p20" pid="Ipu1abE5cUW-Noj15L8oWw" hash="FJuDCg">And I said, “Please.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p21" pid="8rEZk4l8g0yRVkHVxOJFwg" hash="1Vpv2A">She said, “How well do you know my father?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p22" pid="jihtgG7VwUaAqgFJyJAJbg" hash="VmAxYQ">I said, “Reasonably well.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p23" pid="tdshY9FOUEe2eMdsSx8GqA" hash="Ja-hwQ">She said, “My dad puts on a pretty good front. Oh, he’s a fine man, but he’s a little hypocritical.” She said, “You ought to see the way he treats my mom and us at home. And you know, my mom and dad were married in the temple. And I don’t want a marriage like that.” She said, “How well do you know Brother and Sister So-and-so?”—another acquaintance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p24" pid="Yr3gmd6eY0ubGvLWmDpWSA" hash="Gm8y9w">I said, “I know them.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p25" pid="Sg0aYQUQgEaAuEfpat_0OQ" hash="KI9bRg">She said, “Did you know I babysit for them. They too are married in the temple, and I wouldn’t care for a marriage like that.” She said, “How well do you know Mr. and Mrs. So-and-so?” This is a wonderful member of our community, not of our faith. Ten children. She said, “I babysit that family too, and I’d like a marriage like theirs.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p26" pid="RYM5DZabq0Srskvoth3yaQ" hash="ZjshGQ">Now what do you say, mom and dad? Teacher? The scriptures say so? Well, that’s what the leaders teach. Young people are after whys and wherefores.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p27" pid="xR6r5rK3aEOk9WMjJ4445w" hash="yBcfbA">I was still a little puzzled. Standing nearby was another young lady. I turned to her and I said, “How do you answer that?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p28" pid="Kg1AqIka_0a-06iKL4FdzQ" hash="asJuaQ">She was alert. She turned to her friend and she said, “Jan, you’re not fair.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p29" pid="E69dXrrwIU-HbB2vYAaG1A" hash="pG01Cw">Jan said, “Why not?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p30" pid="x9-QXfnNgU6thMNXZ_GfOQ" hash="1NpFzA">She said, “Because you’re judging the whole church by two or three examples that don’t represent, necessarily, what we believe and teach or how we should live.” She said, “Let me ask you a question. When was the last time you had a little personal crisis, maybe a frustrating date, a test, a social situation that worried you a little bit, where your dad sensed it and came into your bedroom and sat on the edge of the bed and stroked your head and said, ‘Wouldn’t you like a blessing tonight?’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p31" pid="49Kg55FBZkq4XJW_D-QB_A" hash="HUHWNg">Jan looked at her and said, “Well, my dad doesn’t do that.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p32" pid="EGaphtJ6_EKkkAiUeY6C6w" hash="5c92dw">The little girl said, “My dad does.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p33" pid="MSQ5c9POLkWjpE5OGa72Pg" hash="VE1Zjw">And then together they talked about how her dad regularly taught the family. An experience was shared regarding family prayer. She listed some eight or nine such moments without even pausing. I could see a little change in Jan’s heart. You could see in Jan’s eyes the expression, “Oh! I would like a husband like that.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p34" pid="xY3YJLZiH0SK6FZL9oCQtQ" hash="doa5tw">I had the thrill some months later of performing that marriage, in the temple. I’d like to think that night, a change occurred.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p35" pid="J7m7mBSu_USDWOFo7lVH3g" hash="YjvcRw">Most wrong choices before and after marriage are not made out of rebellion or intentional error but because of misinformation, miscommunication, and lack of understanding. In most cases, if couples truly understood the whats and the whys and the hows of eternal marriage, no one would have to talk them into the right choices. Indeed, no one would be able to talk them out of them!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p36" pid="Tby0y9OFm0mW8XkZhU9t0g" hash="nmlxPw">Let me ask you young people a question: have you ever wondered why God would restrict us from some things, advise us strongly against them, warn us, even command us? Do you think his commandments are just arbitrary whims, artificial tests of some kind, generalities that are important for some people but not for others?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p37" pid="_P-JT02D0kysk08vHhCjuA" hash="fUb4KQ">I don’t think so! His commandments are <span class="emphasis">loving counsel from a wise Father.</span> Our understanding and concept of God as a loving and personal Heavenly Father allows us no other definition. He gives us commandments for one reason only—because he loves us and wants us to be happy. Chastity is a perfect example. God simply knows that virtue is its own reward, that the saving of oneself for one eternal partner makes that commitment more beautiful, more joyful. It is the simple question of whether you want a penny now or a diamond later. Any momentary pleasure that might result from a premarital relationship cannot be compared with the vastly greater joy of oneness in marriage. And the indulgence in the former can destroy the potential for the latter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p38" pid="GpetJ7cpaEa3z-AuCoOs5w" hash="c6qcLQ">Chastity is like money in the bank. As you save yourself you are <span class="emphasis">saving</span> the joy of belonging to one and only one. You are saving the joy of being able to say, “I am all yours, and I have never been anyone else’s.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p39" pid="gp7SfdspiEKj_ok38qcqlw" hash="GZtbtg">Some will ask, “What if we already know who ‘the one’ is? What if the commitment is already there and we’re just waiting for the ceremony?” The answer is, <span class="emphasis">it’s not just a ceremony,</span> it’s a covenant, both with God and with your partner, and <span class="emphasis">waiting</span> shows the deepest love and respect for both.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p40" pid="ryV8Y51qW0uvwZFrLywL6w" hash="SWPaZw">Some will say, “But we love each other too much to wait.” The answer is that there is no such thing as too much love and that it is too much selfishness, not love, that debates divine counsel and violates virtue.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p41" pid="PfrcvYc8m0imkB58rtEryQ" hash="cgtKCA">Any love that is to become eternal must include respect, faith, trust, admiration, honor, and have spiritual and mental aspects as well as physical and emotional. No relationship, either temporal or eternal, can exist without these attributes. Every soap opera is filled with accurate illustrations of misery because these qualities are absent.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p42" pid="KTLd6ylBIUiG0ZQv8LdKGg" hash="0mePug">If, in your case, the physical tends to dominate, all the more reason to bridle it and find the other dimensions. <span class="emphasis">Bridle</span> is the word that wise father Alma used in counseling his son Shiblon, and the promise he attached is the key to understanding: “Bridle … your passions, that ye may be filled with love.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/38.12" class="scriptureRef">Alma 38:12</a>.) Bridling increases strength, increases power, increases love. There are absolutely two ways you can control a horse. (We learned a little bit about horses last night.) One is to kill it; one is to bridle it. Alma never said kill your passions. The implication is <span class="emphasis">not</span> that passions are evil, that we shouldn’t have them. On the contrary, we bridle something we love, something whose power we respect.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p43" pid="uO66gp211UClmRbjf86vQw" hash="R4wJ2Q">A horse is stronger than a man, so the man bridles it, thus <span class="emphasis">controlling</span> its power and using that power for good. Passions are stronger than we are, so we bridle them, thus controlling their power and using that power to strengthen a marriage and forge it into eternity. One has to know <span class="emphasis">how</span> to bridle a horse or a passion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p44" pid="dMrT5PsKVES0PC8Rcs0HMw" hash="MAEFFw">Remember, a physical relationship is simply too beautiful to squander, too wonderful to waste. It is the sterling silver too precious to tarnish before the beauty of the banquet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why.p45" pid="iJw9rNqXqUSYQ1I2xt6s7Q" hash="UlyHLQ">Let us remember that understanding “the why” in learning is what develops proper attitudes or changes behavior. God grant us the wisdom to teach wisely and with understanding, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1981/10/teach-the-why</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1981-general-conference/1981-10-5040-elder-paul-h-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="5813008" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 1981 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Honour Thy Father and Thy Mother”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother?lang=eng</link>
      <description>It’s 3:00  in Salt Lake City. Can you just imagine the scramble that’s going on in many homes, with those trying to decide which channel and station to tune in on? Being somewhat interested in sports myself, I couldn’t help but think as I was sitting</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03167_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="Fi93mQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="HKlnwMHMnEyJmxYB5bZZ7A" hash="9jttng">“Honour Thy Father and Thy Mother”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="KmGw743Ty0iHovP3EHyHCA" hash="2gvHCQ">Paul H. Dunn</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26ec.jpg" alt="Elder Paul H. Dunn" pid="1QCabUpO1UiIxQhEvBHAew" hash="lWLluA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p1" pid="aDNARRKzq02alLpJPPEvfA" hash="Wi7zeA">It’s 3:00 <small>P.M.</small> in Salt Lake City. Can you just imagine the scramble that’s going on in many homes, with those trying to decide which channel and station to tune in on? Being somewhat interested in sports myself, I couldn’t help but think as I was sitting here about some wise counsel my father once gave. I think it’s appropriate here.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p2" pid="7SMvQ3gCo0KDM_Rljup_pg" hash="OuMTDg">“Paul,” he said, “remember: one day for church, six days for fun. Odds on going to heaven—six to one.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p3" pid="2O7J7jzrekWx22fjpHkyWg" hash="WLaRMA">He also made this observation. He said, “Whenever I pass our little church I like to linger for a visit, so that when I’m carried in, the Lord won’t say, ‘Who is it?’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p4" pid="HZcUMhjiXEiJfaAhhPQq0g" hash="0CZxgQ">One day while celebrating the birthday of one of my granddaughters, I had her sitting on my lap, as grandfathers do, and we were talking about age, wisdom, and experience, and all of a sudden she looked up at me and said, “Granddaddy, were you born before they invented water?” Now that’s a sobering thought.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p5" pid="CHlXs_K9OEO7aIEYIgI2bw" hash="hWNGUA">Well, speaking of age, someone else has said, “Do you know how to tell when you are getting a little older?” I said no. He said, “You know you’re getting old—</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.f2">
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="WWA2JASkGkK01v65aAThMQ" hash="Ek0ftg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="4GoNaP7onk2ePkx9UZGJRQ" hash="TNkIgw">“When, after you get it all together, you realize you’d do better if you took it apart.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="I8Ck9MgqqEKAbHRQ5Ww6Gw" hash="Zv7YCw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="7YMsaNjPnUOIeNerd1FOlA" hash="nLfDUg">“When you get a little winded while brushing your teeth.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Uo8XFvyl0kS-4oWfBhM_aA" hash="9ZUU4A">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="9rN5ctZ3P0W6OsALLM3oUQ" hash="NlrZ-g">“When you reach the age when you know all the answers but nobody asks any of the questions.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="LiSW7YMq-U-hO-J696BAFw" hash="-g0oXA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="-1cOKAwgB0awl3Ign7AQ3A" hash="hkT8ww">“When your crow’s feet need orthopedic shoes.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="49j0CmdUB0q7XEGki19VMQ" hash="nWchqw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="SGNLUEVwsUm0giY0wclMnA" hash="Lqukag">“When your appendix scar hits your knee.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Qq0R_WyO0UCyyg0LFyhApQ" hash="MtcKEQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="P90oeKxwl0eHU7NL-nVVgQ" hash="s-Eipw">“When instead of Max Factor you may want to consider Kemtone.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="RwumrUp8vEaxnxOUuZzbwg" hash="PmwiVw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="_F1bbql3kUegPe43gxLdiw" hash="0EK_og">“While sitting in a rocking chair you have difficulty in getting it started.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="eI0NXes2d0CJ9MHjUaaJRw" hash="2DIJMg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="atGdI9KEwU-W3iM6sACC5Q" hash="BAd7_w">“When you get out of the shower, you’re glad the mirror’s fogged up.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="JdpJTY59M0as_0kmvccImA" hash="BVYjxw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="NWtL3oqfBketPG4ovdLWNQ" hash="zSUqJQ">“When you get up in the morning and you have one shoe on and one shoe off and you can’t tell whether you are getting up or going to bed.”</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p6" pid="WSd69FjegkKPxgC39zx88w" hash="nttZcA">Well, you may have some different signs, but despite our best plans and efforts, growing older is going to happen to most of us. How those mature years are spent depends on every one of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p7" pid="1ylCjX7a4UWyLfSmgSxVkg" hash="Uv3rpg">To those in their golden years, age should only be hateful if it means the cessation of growth, the withering of dreams, the silencing of feelings. And these qualities, after all, have nothing to do with chronology and everything to do with heart. Douglas McArthur once observed, “Live with enthusiasm! Nobody grows old by deserting their ideals. Years wrinkle the skin, but to give up enthusiasm wrinkles the soul. You are as young as your faith, as old as your doubt, as young as your self-confidence, as old as your fear, as young as your hope, as old as your despair.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p8" pid="MFSMAZBxaku8LyYYd3DFZA" hash="oHgW5Q">History abounds with people who, as they got older, got better. Michelangelo didn’t undertake his monumental frescoed altar wall of the Sistine Chapel until he was sixty-nine years of age. When he died at ninety, he was still busy with his poetry, paintings, and sculpture.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p9" pid="sMWkofwyMEGSt53FA8yYyw" hash="NTRCWw">Goethe, German genius of literature, didn’t finish the classic <span class="emphasis">Faust</span> until he was eighty-one. He had begun it forty years earlier, but when he came back to it, he had enhanced insight and freshness of imagination due to the extra years of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p10" pid="91gsL6HypEWETLM-FalAgw" hash="xxlx7g">Herbert Hoover took on the job of coordinating the world’s food supplying of thirty-eight countries at the age of seventy-two. He was the United States representative to Belgium at the age of eighty-four.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p11" pid="QRB0uEkJsU-8yXMkjWn3jQ" hash="zV8oFA">Thomas Edison was still inventing when past ninety. Benjamin Franklin was a key political figure and a wise, insightful diplomat for America when past seventy-five.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p12" pid="afLZb49voEygUoTBvtaxrw" hash="8_SzHA">My own mother, now past eighty-five, still paints and gardens. Her paintings are sought-after classics. Moses was over eighty when he led the Israelites. Think of the great spiritual contributions of our past prophets and those of President Kimball today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p13" pid="10EDU93IH0KAONjDSvOxVQ" hash="9tGxtw">Winston Churchill was sixty-five when he promised the British people his blood, toil, tears, and sweat during World War II. Albert Schweitzer was in his eighties when he roamed equatorial Africa tending the sick, working on his manuscripts, and playing Bach on the piano.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p14" pid="xYeyUtxrmEyjl44trWgZKw" hash="RAtt6A">Now, you might have a tendency to say, “But these people were and are extraordinary, gifted in ways beyond the average.” But I say to you, the most extraordinary talent each of these had was enthusiasm, a flair for taking each new day with relish and interest, and a refusal to let wastelands of the soul develop and choke out life. Ralph Waldo Emerson put it this way. He said, “We do not count a man’s years until he has nothing else to count.” (John Bartlett, <span class="emphasis">Familiar Quotations,</span> 14th ed. [Boston: Little, Brown and Company, 1968], p. 609.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p15" pid="v0dOWHCrG0iHS6HQ-srZXw" hash="EP7RFQ">To those who have been privileged by the experience of having aging parents and grandparents with them, think of the countless ways the elderly bless our lives. Remember the admonitions of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p16" pid="b3OVRSCAnkaKAPz6iLmhTA" hash="ghV2ug">First from Proverbs:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p17" pid="VERfbYPOvUOqI2bOb0seLQ" hash="4fD9OA">“The glory of young men is their strength: and the beauty of old men is the gray head.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/20.29" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 20:29</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p18" pid="tgfWpWPsQU2PSIcfGJFUtQ" hash="-nUO8A">Next from Job:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p19" pid="ltMsUIWGkkCw2ZFO0gNxHA" hash="EMh9eA">“With the ancient is wisdom; and in length of days understanding.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p20" pid="_wG-jzlXIkCeEkKe5OyrPA" hash="VSQ3Kw">“With him is wisdom and strength, he hath counsel and understanding.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/job/12.12-13" class="scriptureRef">Job 12:12–13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p21" pid="jlgu5OD9akGi7Lyj5z_1rw" hash="gvyj0g">And then there is this concern recorded in Psalms: “Cast me not off in the time of old age; forsake me not when my strength faileth.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/71.9" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 71:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p22" pid="F1y7PvXT7UuplF56vfboJA" hash="ShQqcQ">Many is the time in my current position when those in their advanced years have sought counsel in getting their families to share and take an interest in them. I remember reading of such an experience, which I would like to share. This item was found in an old magazine. No author’s name was mentioned, just this from a heavy-hearted observer. He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p23" pid="rrCf5RiG10WxASyS5BElCQ" hash="jWm4dA">“Just next door lives a wonderful old man. He is still very alert and active. That special morning he awakened earlier than usual, bathed, shaved and put on his best clothes. Surely, he thought, they would come today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p24" pid="-3d8RUNgkUmT79KgB5wFOQ" hash="MJyUTA">“He didn’t take his daily walk to the gas station to visit with the old-timers of the community, because he wanted to be right there when they came.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p25" pid="0xZZTRucG0qstJTGE1bVyg" hash="qZn3fA">“He sat on the porch with a clear view of the road so he could see them coming. Surely they would come today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p26" pid="dap5dOAT2UmVqXtMyvPmLA" hash="3YIFlA">“He decided to skip his noon nap because he wanted to be up when they came.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p27" pid="EUfW1uzl_UGfyuse-Ehzhw" hash="0dobUA">“He had six children. Two of his daughters and their married children lived within four miles. They hadn’t been to see him for such a long time. But today was a special day. Surely they would come today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p28" pid="kKG5DWQzi0-Nd9UPWt1WMQ" hash="Xgr8FA">“At suppertime he refused to cut the cake and asked that the ice cream be left in the freezer. He wanted to wait and have dessert with them when they came.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p29" pid="TXqBk6xzQEefkUOxSoaMcA" hash="nU-ZYw">“About 9 o’clock he went to his room and got ready for bed. His last words before turning out the lights were: ‘Promise to wake me when they come.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p30" pid="CZuGNA1ktUyp8X2CdVUlxA" hash="hTrmVA">“You see, it was his birthday, and he was 91.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p31" pid="Btx4JhUFqkulpVaPmqJaHQ" hash="8Jw7Vw">In our modern age of sophistication and progress, I find it a little disturbing that the old expression “Age before beauty” seems to have been reversed. Never before has there been so much emphasis on youth and beauty. While youth and beauty are cherished attributes, age and experience can be tremendous assets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p32" pid="vQjljDlGSkaHQ7L7clBqIw" hash="QQiUkw">And, while our computer-age technology has been unsurpassed at lengthening and enriching the lives of our older citizens, I’m not so sure it has replaced or improved upon the personal touch. From the scriptures I have just cited, three important conclusions can be drawn:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p33" pid="lMaJpp4avEayFNE87KSFdw" hash="gaXn6w">First, there are advantages to old age;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p34" pid="muhRtg72V0aYQAdZ20kcSg" hash="Ua3b3w">Second, we can learn from the wisdom and understanding that age and experience offer; and</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p35" pid="ffgEtUUmmECoGtpb439qEw" hash="XBUZJw">Third, older folks are able, productive, and useful, and should not be put on a shelf.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p36" pid="Sbrevym4CUebAng8hTPSQA" hash="BWTn3A">To those who wonder if we have an obligation to bring these conclusions to pass, the Lord’s answer to Cain’s question, “Am I my brother’s keeper?” (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/4.9" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 4:9</a>) is a resounding <span class="emphasis">yes!</span> He said, “Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/19.19" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 19:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p37" pid="t9L7lXsqSEOniuWLlEzOGg" hash="CoYR-Q">The final question, I suppose, then, ought to be: “How are we going to accomplish this?” With older friends and family, why don’t you and I first—</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.f3">
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="Hpx-oX-RrE-553R6_f2i_g" hash="fu3JMQ">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="yPKGQSXArkGUYHyXOUaCSA" hash="yUG9sw">Seek their counsel.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="b9x4wTB8QEu9FddLfyFf2w" hash="8SJRSA">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="JBGTAekzfk2uhTov8sbeIg" hash="ohbqvA">Visit or call on them regularly.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="j4rdGaj8BUi3GyfEcLIoNg" hash="pRioBA">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="wnuFahXpQUiJgeO1Wok_uA" hash="D4u4IA">Include them in our activities.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="nIGdyw4IvUuBIclK1xxiWA" hash="twxaDg">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="JDfWurQQqkC1e5m3K-XH-w" hash="refzFA">Let them share their experiences.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="QhDH66mCt0WmQZoU6OMMAw" hash="qXJ1CA">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p pid="XkWFlmf7okqdGj2xKjHPNQ" hash="PIn0HQ">See to it that they have the basic necessities of life.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="46MLussmLUqVNlAkVS--7w" hash="xWFWZg">
          <span class="label">6.</span>
          <p pid="JoV1dYVpYEi40gB9DyXpIw" hash="V72KhA">Provide care for them when they are sick.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="t5O7sA_zjE2E9XAJT3L76Q" hash="yuxXdQ">
          <span class="label">7.</span>
          <p pid="0FW2hPmv8U6CKeRODqUCNQ" hash="Rn0_lw">Treat them as dignified human beings, not as charity cases.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p38" pid="58LiKWgHEU2nZHdGEm4B3A" hash="htZmMA">Let us take advantage of having grandfathers, grandmothers, great-grandparents, friends, and neighbors around us. May we in our own special way reach out to them—not with pity, but with love. Consider again, brothers and sisters, this counsel from the Lord: “<span class="emphasis">Honour</span> thy father and thy mother,” that their days—and ours—might be long upon the earth. (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.12" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:12</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother.p39" pid="0Vvk8v-MQU2mQ0KeJYIjJA" hash="weIc0Q">Finally, may we do unto the aged what we would want to have done to us. Remember: our time is coming. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1983/10/honour-thy-father-and-thy-mother</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1983-general-conference/1983-10-2040-elder-paul-h-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="5145916" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 1983 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>By Faith and Hope, All Things Are Fulfilled</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Near here stands a tall building twenty-six stories high. In it are two banks of elevators, one an express, one that moves a little more normally.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03213_000_027" doc-version="2" hash="icImbg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="BAkx6AJvTk6_97VluBFYoA" hash="V7W4Uw">By Faith and Hope, All Things Are Fulfilled</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="DnminCdG5EaOj2cLSdF2Ng" hash="2gvHCQ">Paul H. Dunn</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26ec.jpg" alt="Elder Paul H. Dunn" pid="Xv5KPFY4IU-MT5DkysaX5w" hash="lWLluA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p1" pid="6XfIAkvbIUWUgaKFumd8dw" hash="Z0z45A">Near here stands a tall building twenty-six stories high. In it are two banks of elevators, one an express, one that moves a little more normally.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p2" pid="leM3CIw4G0WWSH1nI1a8lg" hash="_uIfRA">Not long ago I got on the express elevator. Some of the workers there say it could qualify as a ride at Disneyland. A little boy and his father got on with me. Suddenly the elevator took off, and the little boy, not expecting the thrill, lost his breath and looked up at his dad with great faith and trust and said, “Daddy, does Heavenly Father know we’re coming?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p3" pid="0OM6S84VekG2DDCtjcpr1g" hash="JzHXWw">There is a great lesson in that experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p4" pid="2X85Q1GDG0-KcTlvHKdhVQ" hash="-UQgJg">Dr. JoAnn Larsen, a Salt Lake City family therapist, recently gave some wise and practical counsel on teaching children and building their self-esteem. She reminded us of the tendency most parents have, in their efforts to teach their children responsibility, of so often stressing the negative things the children do—the mistakes and misjudgments they make and the inconveniences and trouble they cause. She made the statement that between birth and twenty years of age the average child hears from parents, teachers, siblings, and peers probably one hundred thousand negative messages, which are rarely balanced with positive messages. With an extremely lucky child, the ratio would probably be ten negatives to one positive, which she claims can be highly damaging, often for life, to a child’s feelings of self-worth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p5" pid="PnCGOGoJ-02hdWG4nT2X8Q" hash="PYWTnA">She encourages us all to develop lenses—vision that sees positives instead of negatives, thus making it possible to perform miracles sometimes and certainly to greatly improve the results of our teaching efforts and our parent-child relationships. The good accomplished toward the making of a better world through upbuilding, trusting approaches to life situations, in contrast to those that tear down, could very possibly never be accurately assessed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p6" pid="ygg-vu48W0CBh7vKSmKamg" hash="EgvMJw">Why is it that as humans we tend to emphasize the negative when there is so much to be positive about? We not only constantly criticize our children and each other, find fault, are very judgmental, and often seek out and build up people’s weaknesses and failings rather than their strengths and successes, but in our own personal life-styles there are those of us who are incessant, chronic worriers. We worry about all the negative things that could happen, but usually don’t, rather than positively trying to face problems with some amount of faith and hope of success.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p7" pid="AQROWBdA3kuC7kpia6nsJg" hash="ADxn9A">In our society, for some reason, we seem to dwell on the bizarre, the tragic, the profane, and the evils of our day. So often the newspapers and television reports center attention around the negative aspects of life: teenage suicides, drugs, AIDS, murders, infidelities, dishonesty, and a host of other social ills.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p8" pid="dInpFumXO0G6cqJqIisz-A" hash="czucxA">As I travel throughout the Church, I occasionally see another form of thinking that can become quite negative—members weighted down, sometimes grimly, with the serious tasks that they must perform to earn livings, pay mortgages, rear children, faithfully fulfill Church callings, attend to school and community responsibilities, live righteously and worthily—the list could go on and on.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p9" pid="t_HrnNSXnUC1c26SCjY6Tg" hash="fpUcRA">I often think that for some of these people the joy and excitement have gone out of their lives and that all they look back on are crowded, grim days, often filled with great guilt because of the pressure of trying to accomplish everything they think is necessary and to be perfect right now. Interestingly, negative attitudes seem to affect us in that way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p10" pid="UoGjHQsZo0SqIPWsnp6w9g" hash="yEnYgA">Now, of course, life is serious. Children must be taught, bills must be paid, we must live righteously—it is the Lord’s counsel to us. We can’t help but worry sometimes; there are and always will be never-ending negatives existing all around us which must be faced, dealt with, and solved. But I wonder if the constant bombardment of dilemmas and challenges and the often seemingly hopeless situations, both personal and nationwide, don’t frustrate, discourage, and depress us sometimes to the point where our minds and attitudes are distracted from the very principles that would allow us to rise above the negative and find the positive answers we need.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p11" pid="ah9sKK3ZFUSNGFG893xo_A" hash="5R3tPw">In spite of the many negative occurrences in life, there are those who seem to have the knack of seeing the positive side. A young businessman was opening a new branch office, and a friend sent a floral arrangement to help celebrate the occasion. When the friend arrived at the opening, he was appalled to find the wreath bore the inscription “Rest in Peace.” Angry, he later complained to the florist. After apologizing, the florist said, “Look at it this way. Somewhere today a man was buried under a wreath that said, ‘Good luck in your new location.’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p12" pid="d-gjJoGgqk2VYERLdxsCNw" hash="_xnCEQ">In the Book of Mormon, in which we find many answers and so much direction in solving problems, there is a scripture that, to me, sheds great light on the matter of a positive, trusting, hopeful attitude of faith as a substitute for facing life’s problems with discouragement and despair. Listen to the words of the prophet Ether as he exhorts us to know and believe in God as a foundation of hope and faith:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p13" pid="oBxz1co4WkajtKDXiJs-Hg" hash="LTyO8Q">“By faith all things are fulfilled—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p14" pid="YJwtdWtcTU-blIvkMnBhDw" hash="np_W_A">“Wherefore, whoso believeth in God might with surety hope for a better world, yea, even a place at the right hand of God, which hope cometh of faith, maketh an anchor to the souls of men, which would make them sure and steadfast, always abounding in good works, being led to glorify God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.3-4" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:3–4</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p15" pid="ZQXle3tfJ0-55sROp6Mhyg" hash="ZPbaFg">Throughout the whole of this marvelous chapter we are taught the wonders accomplished by faith, love, and hope. It seems to me that dwelling on negative thoughts and approaches is, in fact, working directly opposite of hope, faith, and trust—in the Lord, ourselves, and others—and causes continual feelings of gloom, while the positive lifts and buoys us up, encourages us to forge ahead, and is an attitude that can be developed, a habit that we can cultivate.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p16" pid="7pgSvrIx0E6uXl9Gwa-ZeA" hash="02wzNA">The epitome of celebrating the beautiful and overlooking the misfortune is the story of Thomas Moore.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p17" pid="UNe5d-IQeUqud92cmX1aVg" hash="S8QBLA">Soon after he was married, Thomas Moore, the famous nineteenth-century Irish poet, was called away on a business trip. Upon his return he was met at the door, not by his beautiful bride, but by the family doctor.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p18" pid="hl4qvfZ1q0W8vjVXfF1OMw" hash="HPqmGg">“Your wife is upstairs,” said the doctor. “But she asked that you not come up.” Then Moore learned the terrible truth: his wife had contracted smallpox. The disease had left her once flawless skin pocked and scarred. She had taken one look at her reflection in the mirror and commanded that the shutters be drawn and that her husband never see her again. Moore would not listen. He ran upstairs and threw open the door of his wife’s room. It was black as night inside. Not a sound came from the darkness. Groping along the wall, Moore felt for the gas jets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p19" pid="yWObu3XuP0u6gtbS2VKpWg" hash="TqcvnQ">A startled cry came from a black corner of the room. “No!” she said. “Don’t light the lamps!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p20" pid="KSK3CzUK9kCz5R-AUCdhMw" hash="-aTZyw">Moore hesitated, swayed by the pleading in the voice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p21" pid="UqvHtBY400CTBrB7N9kjYA" hash="WqDdxQ">“Go!” she begged. “Please go! This is the greatest gift I can give you now.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p22" pid="n3yVvRBgZk-OUEypOZsV9g" hash="K182Kg">Moore did go. He went down to his study, where he sat up most of the night, prayerfully writing. Not a poem this time, but a song. He had never written a song before, but now he found it more natural to his mood than simple poetry. He not only wrote the words, but he wrote the music, too. The next morning, as soon as the sun was up he returned to his wife’s room.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p23" pid="gXNKzyILTkGT1SPdnKNacQ" hash="lYYDHw">He felt his way to a chair and sat down. “Are you awake?” he asked.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p24" pid="wu8Tp1E3oU2WioYbD3olTw" hash="a_SWHA">“I am,” came a voice from the far side of the room. “But you must not ask to see me. You must not press me, Thomas.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p25" pid="Q13Rtf4pa0mXEcorWL-dMQ" hash="hHS3qg">“I will sing to you, then,” he answered. And so for the first time, Thomas Moore sang to his wife the song that still lives today:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p26" pid="qm9C4yQNhEmdQwIJVNmA7A" hash="uk-DKw">“Believe me, if all those endearing young charms which I gaze on so fondly today, were to change by tomorrow and flee in my arms like fairy gifts fading away, thou would’st still be adored, as this moment thou art—let thy loveliness fade as it will.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p27" pid="Bm_Q1H2QGk6P9h9FL04LiQ" hash="o9jRiQ">Moore heard a movement from the dark corner where his wife lay in her loneliness. He continued:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p28" pid="GSAZFWBRoU-dXhwiXKKoWQ" hash="RVpscQ">“Let thy loveliness fade as it will, and around the dear ruin each wish of my heart would entwine itself verdantly still—”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p29" pid="SW_PpqppDEStU_UnewRjlQ" hash="kxhhnA">The song ended. As his voice trailed off on the last note, Moore heard his bride rise. She crossed the room to the window, reached up, and drew open the shutters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p30" pid="CiQJMccPeEipwzShGMp_8Q" hash="VuchbQ">We need more such attitudes in the world. There is the story of the husband and wife who had saved and saved for a new car. After taking delivery, the husband told his wife that all the necessary legal documents and insurance information were in a packet in the glove compartment. On her first day out in the new car, she was involved in an accident, which demolished the front end of the car. Unhurt, in tears, and near panic, she opened the packet to show the police officer her papers. There she found a handwritten note from her husband which read: “Now that you have had an accident, remember I can always replace the car, but not you. Please know how much I love you!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p31" pid="bJokIon-yU-TeaKuDrQeDQ" hash="42xPew">As stated in the beginning that with children we so often see the negative before the positive, a little boy was almost squelched in his attempt to express his feelings because an adult didn’t understand. A special friend of mine, Dr. Thomas Myers, shared this tender experience:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p32" pid="0fs1NZocCkaCqfZcf5lalA" hash="vibRfw">A small boy accompanied his father and grandparents into his medical office. The old man was leaning on the boy’s two upstretched hands as he moved. The child encouraged him with, “Come on, Grandpa, you can make it! … Only a little farther, Grandpa. … The doctor will make your leg better.” A sweet grandmother walked behind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p33" pid="w_8qngrP4Uq2rWD_voPjCQ" hash="gBoPUQ">After the visit, the three exited the same way. The little boy was given a helium balloon on his way out. He helped his grandfather to the car, then ran back in and, pulling himself up to the counter, asked the receptionist, “Please, may I have another balloon?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p34" pid="CAO5K1FogkCxZIEk_syCbg" hash="xg25pQ">His grandmother, still standing there, scolded him, “Of course you can’t. I warned you not to let that balloon go!” She apologized to the receptionist. “He did this last week—went right outside and let his balloon go. I really did warn him this time.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p35" pid="QJyZ2bX9fEu2WZoFTGoNpw" hash="w-ePRw">The little boy was trying to tell her something. She bent down to listen. Then, with tears showing on her thin, wrinkled face, the grandmother asked, “Could he please have another balloon? You see, his little sister died a few months ago, and he wanted her to have a balloon to play with, too!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p36" pid="H2MIz08ev0CxG81PP7Pl_Q" hash="YIWz8Q">As critical and judgmental as we often must be, as much as we will have to correct, as truly as we must face unpleasant realities all of our days, let us recognize and praise the thousands of beauties of life around us; the many wonderful examples of virtuous living; the strengths and the courage of so many souls; the exceptional talents and achievements of our family members, neighbors, and associates; the countless blessings that we have been given. As has been quoted by so many, but seems to fit well here, “Two men look out through the same bars: One sees the mud, and one the stars” (Frederick Langbridge, <span class="emphasis">A Cluster of Quiet Thoughts,</span> cited in <span class="emphasis">The Oxford Dictionary of Quotations,</span> 2d ed., London: Oxford Univ. Press, 1966, p. 310).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p37" pid="NAXFlrbGUECxim2IgdNoVw" hash="hwfQKg">And as the prophet Mormon taught us:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p38" pid="F_F2-mVe5km7-t0Z4ohELg" hash="Dmn-uQ">“But charity [in this case, the charity in our thinking of and appreciation of others] is the pure love of Christ, and it endureth forever; and whoso is found possessed of it at the last day, it shall be well with him” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.47" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:47</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p39" pid="sMAZ3_D8f0GlZriglEeL3g" hash="GAJnoA">Remember, my brothers and sisters, particularly you young people, Christ came to lift us up, not put us down. I, with these great brethren on this stand, as a witness, invite you to come unto him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled.p40" pid="haoiXQ0pHkukRbg7yag_-A" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1987/04/by-faith-and-hope-all-things-are-fulfilled</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1987-general-conference/1987-04-5020-elder-paul-h-dunn-64k-eng.mp3" length="7027625" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 1987 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
