<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Paul V. Johnson</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Paul V. Johnson.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Paul%20V.%20Johnson.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Paul V. Johnson.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Blessings of General Conference</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Decide now to make general conference a priority in your life. Decide to listen carefully and follow the teachings that are given.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10033479_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="zwN4dw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="c2-ldnXVtEmW3B_pyasGKw" hash="I23r5A">The Blessings of General Conference</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="2ENbk0sK5EqkHECoUXp4Jg" hash="AjMkLg">Paul V. Johnson</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="4K8zr7-Kk0OxO--MU-tT2w" hash="KLX4nQ">Decide now to make general conference a priority in your life. Decide to listen carefully and follow the teachings that are given.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-113.jpg" alt="Elder Paul V. Johnson" pid="ZGLuajr2bU2nNxy8pEAPag" hash="NwLlUg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p1" pid="6lLDC7Y0SkS5ICYWcit2SQ" hash="kG__CQ">It is a sacred responsibility to address you in this general priesthood meeting. I always look forward to attending these priesthood sessions with my sons. I have great memories of sitting by them in our stake center as we listened to the teachings of the General Authorities. These meetings made a difference in my life when I was a young man, and they continue to make a difference in my life now. I know they have been an influence on my sons and on millions of Aaronic Priesthood holders around the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p2" pid="o1yW752EC0WrN4H-rHy46Q" hash="T677oQ">I speak to you Aaronic Priesthood holders tonight. We live in an exciting and wonderful time. The fulness of the gospel has been restored and is spreading across the earth. The keys of the priesthood are on the earth, and saving ordinances are available to those worthy of them. There are millions of good people on the earth striving to do what is right in their lives and in their families and in their communities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p3" pid="5nWLvm_3lE-02H4oMlqSQg" hash="1-KoYQ">This wonderful time in which we live is also filled with peril. You live in challenging times where many temptations and dangers await you. You have already been exposed to some of those temptations and dangers. You may have even seen individuals whose lives have been damaged by succumbing to some of the evils so prevalent in the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p4" pid="bVoy-gnOg0uoKTxr8fCKvA" hash="8LxwMw">How can you, as an Aaronic Priesthood holder, be safe in these challenging times so you can fully do your part in this great work and find true happiness in this life and the life to come?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p5" pid="vlntzwXQ3UufZgOsL4GSjg" hash="-Eqlxw">It is not surprising that in the face of tremendous evil and temptation the Lord does not leave us to find our way on our own. In fact, there is more than enough guidance available to each of us if we will listen. You have received the gift of the Holy Ghost to direct and inspire you. You have the scriptures, parents, Church leaders and teachers. You also have the words of the prophets, seers, and revelators who live in our day. There is so much guidance and direction available that you won’t make major mistakes in your life unless you consciously ignore the guidance you receive.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p6" pid="jHE3l2dGKkK1zY83QI0rYQ" hash="BYz68w">Tonight I would like to focus on one of these sources of guidance—the living prophets, seers, and revelators that we sustained today. In fact, I would like to focus on one of the main ways we get direction from them—general conference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p7" pid="0Qz48g-wnEqocmbCUwWeag" hash="INlCiw">Conferences have been part of the Church since the beginning of this dispensation. The first conference was held just two months after the Church was organized. We meet twice a year to be instructed by the General Authorities and general officers of the Church. The proceedings of these conferences are available through various means, both print and electronic.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p8" pid="LgN1By33_0qQCTarzOJ2kg" hash="s2gHKA">My mother loved general conference. She always tuned in the radio and TV and turned the volume loud enough that it was difficult to find a place in the house where conference couldn’t be heard. She wanted her children to listen to the talks and would ask us from time to time what we remembered. Once in a while I went outside with one of my brothers to play ball during a Saturday conference session. We would take a radio with us because we knew our mother might quiz us later. We would play ball and occasionally take a break to listen carefully so we could report to Mom. I doubt my mother was fooled when we both happened to remember the same thing from an entire session.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p9" pid="nQNs1abkCkCKWHZ3na5Enw" hash="7nsk4Q">That is no way to listen to conference. I have since repented. I have grown to love general conference, I’m sure partly because of my mother’s love for the words of the living prophets. I remember listening to the sessions of a particular conference all alone in an apartment while I was in college. The Holy Ghost witnessed to my soul that Harold B. Lee, the President of the Church at that time, was truly a prophet of God. This happened before I went into the mission field, and I was excited to testify of a living prophet because I had come to know for myself. I have had that same witness about each of the prophets since that time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p10" pid="QZfAvb55oUCEErA6VV-fTg" hash="6i9qmQ">When I was in the mission field, the Church didn’t have the satellite system, and the country where I served did not have broadcasts of general conference. My mother sent me audiotapes of the sessions, and I listened to them over and over again. I grew to love the voices and the words of the prophets and apostles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p11" pid="Czjyn6UsZkGLFMXXslpmjQ" hash="m2xmsA">Recently I was reading the journal of my great-grandfather, Nathaniel Hodges, who was called on a mission to England in 1883. He told of coming to Salt Lake City to be set apart for his mission and attending conference while he was there. Listen to his description of that conference: “Went to meetings in large Tabernacle all day. There were splendid instructions given. The remarks of Joseph F Smith and George Q Cannon and President John Taylor were particularly powerful. I heard some of the oldest inhabitants say they never attended a more powerful and Spiritual Conference.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p12" pid="kop57brbd0GD6HN_nnS1_Q" hash="fh-IIQ">I think the members of the Church have similar feelings about each general conference. It seems that each is more powerful and spiritual than the last.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p13" pid="3VLHWuJsrUWv1rQz3Xu1vQ" hash="8yHbZw">In order for the messages of general conference to change our lives, we need to be willing to follow the counsel we hear. The Lord explained in a revelation to the Prophet Joseph Smith “that when ye are assembled together ye shall instruct and edify each other, that ye may know … how to act upon the points of my law and commandment.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> But knowing “how to act” isn’t enough. The Lord in the next verse said, “Ye shall bind yourselves to act in all holiness before me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> This willingness to take action on what we have learned opens the doors for marvelous blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p14" pid="IAR49lNo-U-KB2t-CjfJ8Q" hash="LrRIqg">A year ago in the priesthood session of conference President Hinckley spoke about the dangers of pornography. I don’t think I’ve heard a more direct prophetic warning to members of the priesthood. You young brothers who listened and heeded his words have already been blessed and will be blessed more than you can now understand. Your future family will reap great blessings because of your obedience. Imagine how the world would be impacted if every priesthood holder blocked pornography from his life in response to the prophet’s counsel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p15" pid="qL7cF1F0DEKPQ7GWjgw5CA" hash="6slTwg">Every time we are obedient to the words of the prophets and apostles we reap great blessings. We receive more blessings than we can understand at the time, and we continue to receive blessings long after our initial decision to be obedient.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p16" pid="iUxBLVqB6UiImicuYp4Pvw" hash="bgPvAw">On the day the Church was organized, Joseph Smith received a revelation that included an important principle for all Church members. Speaking to the Church about Joseph Smith the Lord said, “Thou shalt give heed unto all his words and commandments which he shall give unto you … for his word ye shall receive, as if from mine own mouth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p17" pid="J5uhysNPVEqN96OcYNTJpQ" hash="sqzJig">Now listen to the blessings promised to those who heed: “For by doing these things the gates of hell shall not prevail against you; yea, and the Lord God will disperse the powers of darkness from before you, and cause the heavens to shake for your good.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p18" pid="xL_DWi0L0kCvMzz8Rw3O0w" hash="bQUMGQ">Those are powerful promises that can keep us safe in these treacherous times. We need them, and the Lord will give them to each of us if we are willing to follow the prophets, seers, and revelators.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p19" pid="kJ5GmoGfZEeKrT_TozMevA" hash="T67eNQ">Decide now to make general conference a priority in your life. Decide to listen carefully and follow the teachings that are given. Listen to or read the talks more than once to better understand and follow the counsel. By doing these things, the gates of hell will not prevail against you, the powers of darkness will be dispersed from before you, and the heavens will shake for your good.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference.p20" pid="RRQA8SqD-kuZsYUd8zXGwA" hash="S8wFwg">I know that our Heavenly Father loves us and has a perfect plan for His children. I know that Jesus is the Christ and that He lives. I testify that the gospel of Jesus Christ has been restored to the earth. We have true prophets, seers, and revelators on the earth today who have “the words of eternal life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> To this I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2005/10/the-blessings-of-general-conference</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2005-general-conference/2005-10-3030-elder-paul-v-johnson-64k-eng.mp3" length="4853491" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Than Conquerors through Him That Loved Us</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Trials are not just to test us. They are vitally important to the process of putting on the divine nature.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50028768_000_4020" doc-version="2" hash="Syv3zQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.head1">
    <h1 class="title" pid="BLsqpz-ir0uFUKdDj1twaA" hash="UwyFug">More Than Conquerors through Him That Loved Us</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="CSBXLrGNZ06BFxXWA565Dw" hash="AjMkLg">Paul V. Johnson</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="mIHH9MgE2067yYd0HyfKtg" hash="bkUIoQ">Trials are not just to test us. They are vitally important to the process of putting on the divine nature.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p1" pid="jZ2NIK-8sUqt8156WWc-sg" hash="ppPPKg">Earth life includes tests, trials, and tribulations, and some of the trials we face in life can be excruciating. Whether it be illness, betrayal, temptations, loss of a loved one, natural disasters, or some other ordeal, affliction is part of our mortal experience. Many have wondered why we must face difficult challenges. We know that one reason is to provide a trial of our faith to see if we will do all the Lord has commanded.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Fortunately this earth life is the perfect setting to face—and pass—these tests.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p2" pid="OYIiAKw7l0ePxAt5ICR0vg" hash="DrHVvA">But these trials are not just to test us. They are vitally important to the process of putting on the divine nature.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> If we handle these afflictions properly, they will be consecrated for our gain.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p3" pid="ipXY7lHLqk2b5gUPAb1o5w" hash="9dsxVQ">Elder Orson F. Whitney said: “No pain that we suffer, no trial that we experience is wasted. … All that we suffer and all that we endure, especially when we endure it patiently, builds up our characters, purifies our hearts, expands our souls, and makes us more tender and charitable. … It is through sorrow and suffering, toil and tribulation, that we gain the education that we come here to acquire.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p4" pid="qJMYXhtWwkydALxaDMqsCQ" hash="o775kw">Recently a nine-year-old boy was diagnosed with a rare bone cancer. The doctor explained the diagnosis and the treatment, which included months of chemotherapy and major surgery. He said it would be a very difficult time for the boy and his family but then added, “People ask me, ‘Will I be the same after this is over?’ I tell them, ‘No, you won’t be the same. You will be so much stronger. You will be awesome!’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p5" pid="ceNaPUN730qJt98SopNbUQ" hash="a4dEnQ">At times it may seem that our trials are focused on areas of our lives and parts of our souls with which we seem least able to cope. Since personal growth is an intended outcome of these challenges, it should come as no surprise that the trials can be very personal—almost laser guided to our particular needs or weaknesses. And no one is exempt, especially not Saints striving to do what’s right. Some obedient Saints may ask, “Why me? I’m trying to be good! Why is the Lord allowing this to happen?” The furnace of affliction helps purify even the very best of Saints by burning away the dross in their lives and leaving behind pure gold.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> Even very rich ore needs refining to remove impurities. Being good is not enough. We want to become like the Savior, who learned as He suffered “pains and afflictions and temptations of every kind.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p6" pid="rnWNbkwds02YOtJO78W2wA" hash="i8KCuQ">The Crimson Trail in Logan Canyon is one of my favorite hikes. The main part of the trail creeps along the top of tall limestone cliffs and offers beautiful vistas of the canyon and valley below. Getting to the top of the cliffs isn’t easy, however. The trail there is a constant climb; and just before reaching the top, the climber encounters the steepest part of the trail; and views of the canyon are hidden by the cliffs themselves. The final exertion is more than worth the effort because once the climber is on top, the views are breathtaking. The only way to see the views is to make the climb.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p7" pid="YkcPp47uT0SWtpjt7g9B3g" hash="vMjfVQ">A pattern in the scriptures and in life shows that many times the darkest, most dangerous tests immediately precede remarkable events and tremendous growth. “After much tribulation come the blessings.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> The children of Israel were trapped against the Red Sea before it was parted.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Nephi faced danger, anger from his brothers, and multiple failures before he was able to procure the brass plates.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Joseph Smith was overcome by an evil power so strong that it seemed he was doomed to utter destruction. When he was almost ready to sink into despair, he exerted himself to call upon God, and at that very moment he was visited by the Father and the Son.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> Often investigators face opposition and tribulation as they near baptism. Mothers know that the challenges of labor precede the miracle of birth. Time after time we see marvelous blessings on the heels of great trials.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p8" pid="aeX2qy1_8EKfswZEVVDEBg" hash="xYZ4eQ">When my grandmother was about 19 years old, she developed a disease that caused her to be very ill. She later said, “I couldn’t walk. My left foot was all out of shape after I had been in bed for several months. The bones were soft like a sponge, and when I touched my foot to the floor it felt like an electric shock.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> While she was confined to bed and at the height of her suffering, she obtained and studied pamphlets from The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. She was converted and later baptized. Many times a particular challenge helps prepare us for something vitally important.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p9" pid="M2v1_w-V3EWqwQzgGiisMQ" hash="_sLvBw">In the midst of problems, it is nearly impossible to see that the coming blessings far outweigh the pain, humiliation, or heartbreak we may be experiencing at the time. “No chastening for the present seemeth to be joyous, but grievous: nevertheless afterward it yieldeth the peaceable fruit of righteousness unto them which are exercised thereby.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> The Apostle Paul taught, “For our light affliction, which is but for a moment, worketh for us a far more exceeding and eternal weight of glory.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> It is interesting that Paul uses the term “light affliction.” This comes from a person who was beaten, stoned, shipwrecked, imprisoned, and who experienced many other trials.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> I doubt many of us would label our afflictions light. Yet in comparison to the blessings and growth we ultimately receive, both in this life and in eternity, our afflictions truly are light.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p10" pid="cBwDcPeACkePLeBm0QvhFw" hash="m8vPeQ">We don’t seek out tests, trials, and tribulations. Our personal journey through life will provide just the right amount for our needs. Many trials are just a natural part of our mortal existence, but they play such an important role in our progress.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p11" pid="POfFLrjQp0q88PoGSEsdTg" hash="eBspfg">As the Savior’s mortal ministry came to a close, He experienced the most difficult trial of all time—the incredible suffering in Gethsemane and on Golgotha. This preceded the glorious Resurrection and the promise that all our suffering will someday be done away. His suffering was a prerequisite to the empty tomb that Easter morning and to our future immortality and eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p12" pid="ilOghiyyBEax2CKVTJOO0w" hash="ePpTrA">Sometimes we want to have growth without challenges and to develop strength without any struggle. But growth cannot come by taking the easy way. We clearly understand that an athlete who resists rigorous training will never become a world-class athlete. We must be careful that we don’t resent the very things that help us put on the divine nature.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p13" pid="JSHm0D7vO0WpTmq-giKZnw" hash="dYFKAQ">Not one of the trials and tribulations we face is beyond our limits, because we have access to help from the Lord. We can do all things through Christ, who strengthens us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p14" pid="bkA7bJbF80GqBSBgTF9xOQ" hash="KQx_9Q">After recovering from serious health challenges, Elder Robert D. Hales shared the following in general conference: “On a few occasions, I told the Lord that I had surely learned the lessons to be taught and that it wouldn’t be necessary for me to endure any more suffering. Such entreaties seemed to be of no avail, for it was made clear to me that this purifying process of testing was to be endured in the Lord’s time and in the Lord’s own way. … I … learned that I would not be left alone to meet these trials and tribulations but that guardian angels would attend me. There were some that were near angels in the form of doctors, nurses, and most of all my sweet companion, Mary. And on occasion, when the Lord so desired, I was to be comforted with visitations of heavenly hosts that brought comfort and eternal reassurances in my time of need.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p15" pid="N4Xd6RYAdEmDqK1-QVItXg" hash="KYd9vA">Our Heavenly Father loves us, and we “know that whosoever shall put their trust in God shall be supported in their trials, and their troubles, and their afflictions, and shall be lifted up at the last day.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> Someday when we get to the other side of the veil, we want more than for someone just to tell us, “Well, you’re done.” Instead, we want the Lord to say, “Well done, thou good and faithful servant.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p16" pid="LWZbezrEZUCIcoXXhIYn5Q" hash="bjImcA">I love the words of Paul:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p17" pid="4Eowi52LtEyliUr3hYPQjA" hash="UUV4fw">“Who shall separate us from the love of Christ? shall tribulation, or distress, or persecution, or famine, or nakedness, or peril, or sword? …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p18" pid="pPa-LoGPZE6FpujG8kGdaA" hash="Su0G-A">“Nay, in all these things we are more than conquerors through him that loved us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us.p19" pid="GJrMdsZA4ky6M-YlA8CIUA" hash="H3ID_A">I know that God lives and that His Son, Jesus Christ, lives. I also know that through Their help, we can be “more than conquerors” of the tribulations we face in this life. We can become like Them. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/04/more-than-conquerors-through-him-that-loved-us</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2011-general-conference/2011-04-4020-elder-paul-v-johnson-64k-eng.mp3" length="5493223" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>And There Shall Be No More Death</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13285_000_66johnson" doc-version="3" hash="su9YaQ"&gt;
	
	&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.head1"&gt;
		&lt;h1 class="title" pid="UR6Fv8P3dUaaJlwKD-QhmQ" hash="lJOhzA"&gt;And There Shall Be No More Death&lt;/h1&gt;
		&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p2" pid="C67O319d6UCGez_tjTO33g" hash="sf0zhw1"&gt;By Elder Paul V. Johnson&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p3" pid="UXwIcC8XIkOb7QS-pKPw1g" hash="sSmk3g"&gt;Of the Seventy&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=9ODwaKxgBEuR45vK3XXswQ"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" altText="Elder Paul V. Johnson" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255542/a8d9f9ce33e54a6584401c0fa4ef9502/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255542/a8d9f9ce33e54a6584401c0fa4ef9502/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255542/a8d9f9ce33e54a6584401c0fa4ef9502/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x278="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255542/a8d9f9ce33e54a6584401c0fa4ef9502/200x278.jpg" data-src-320x446="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255542/a8d9f9ce33e54a6584401c0fa4ef9502/320x446.jpg" data-src-460x641="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255542/a8d9f9ce33e54a6584401c0fa4ef9502/460x641.jpg" data-src-640x892="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255542/a8d9f9ce33e54a6584401c0fa4ef9502/640x892.jpg" data-src-1024x1428="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255542/a8d9f9ce33e54a6584401c0fa4ef9502/1024x1428.jpg" data-src-2048x2856="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255542/a8d9f9ce33e54a6584401c0fa4ef9502/2048x2856.jpg" data-src-3745x5224="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255542/a8d9f9ce33e54a6584401c0fa4ef9502/3745x5224.jpg" webURL="paul-johnson-first-quorum-seventy_1255542.jpg" pid="9ODwaKxgBEuR45vK3XXswQ" hash="AAAAAA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="kicker" pid="HbO27_y8c0SMt4EBsC6iIA" hash="hfWTiw"&gt;For all who have grieved over the death of someone they loved, the Resurrection is a source of great hope.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="authorName" pid="Ec3e2dlRxUCnnO1_rLJ5Kw" hash="sf0zhw"&gt;By Elder Paul V. Johnson&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class="bodyBlock"&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p5" pid="KM7hGtEJXUmqTvUG7GXfwg" hash="GatQOw"&gt;A week ago was Easter, and our thoughts were focused again on the atoning sacrifice and Resurrection of the Lord Jesus Christ. This past year I have been thinking and pondering about the Resurrection more than normal.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p6" pid="OarHSsa1Z0qBEp-TVShTjQ" hash="c8X-Bw"&gt;Nearly one year ago, our daughter Alisa died. She had struggled with cancer for almost eight years, with several surgeries, many different treatments, exciting miracles, and deep disappointments. We watched her physical condition deteriorate as she came to the close of her mortal life. It was excruciating to see that happen to our precious daughter—that bright-eyed little baby who had grown up to be a talented, wonderful woman, wife, and mother. I thought my heart would break.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=qKzLDZw6lUeDLaKWs4rYEg"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1711467/38fb205a9dcb4affa1f0be4721749dcc/100x149.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x74="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1711467/38fb205a9dcb4affa1f0be4721749dcc/50x74.jpg" data-src-100x149="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1711467/38fb205a9dcb4affa1f0be4721749dcc/100x149.jpg" data-src-200x298="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1711467/38fb205a9dcb4affa1f0be4721749dcc/200x298.jpg" data-src-320x478="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1711467/38fb205a9dcb4affa1f0be4721749dcc/320x478.jpg" data-src-460x687="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1711467/38fb205a9dcb4affa1f0be4721749dcc/460x687.jpg" data-src-640x956="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1711467/38fb205a9dcb4affa1f0be4721749dcc/640x956.jpg" data-src-1024x1529="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1711467/38fb205a9dcb4affa1f0be4721749dcc/1024x1529.jpg" data-src-1205x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1711467/38fb205a9dcb4affa1f0be4721749dcc/1205x1800.jpg" altText="Alisa Johnson Linton" pid="qKzLDZw6lUeDLaKWs4rYEg" hash="XVSxRw"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p7" pid="gq9wIISoeEmAsxzfGQRH3w" hash="XolPGw"&gt;Last year at Easter time, a little over a month before she passed away, Alisa wrote: “Easter is a reminder of all that I hope for myself. That someday I will be healed and someday I will be whole. Someday I won’t have any metal or plastic inside of me. Someday my heart will be free of fear and my mind free of anxieties. I am not praying that this happens soon, but I am so glad I truly believe in a beautiful afterlife.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p8" pid="IeUGvetUa0eIfdq7myQkIA" hash="ehnJKQ"&gt;The Resurrection of Jesus Christ ensures the very things Alisa hoped for and instills in each of us “a reason [for] the hope that is in [us].”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; President Gordon B. Hinckley referred to the Resurrection as “the greatest of all events in the history of mankind.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p9" pid="PMFue7ypPEC5E1mc87iFtg" hash="6MNhiQ"&gt;The Resurrection is brought to pass by the Atonement of Jesus Christ and is pivotal to the great plan of salvation.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; We are spirit children of heavenly parents.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; When we come to this earth life, our spirit is united with our body. We experience all the joys and challenges associated with mortal life. When a person dies, their spirit is separated from their body. Resurrection makes it possible for a person’s spirit and body to be united again, only this time that body will be immortal and perfect—not subject to pain, disease, or other problems.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p10" pid="siB_z7nmlUe7P0Yx2rMF4w" hash="TRSQqQ"&gt;After resurrection, the spirit will never again be separated from the body because the Savior’s Resurrection brought total victory over death. In order to obtain our eternal destiny, we need to have this immortal soul—a spirit and body—united forever. With spirit and immortal body inseparably connected, we can “receive a fulness of joy.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt; In fact, without the Resurrection we could never receive a fulness of joy but would be miserable forever.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8"&gt;8&lt;/span&gt; Even faithful, righteous people view the separation of their bodies from their spirits as captivity. We are released from this captivity through the Resurrection, which is redemption from the bands or chains of death.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9"&gt;9&lt;/span&gt; There is no salvation without both our spirit and our body.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p11" pid="4j6uX81PcEq6pCDqNKoFPw" hash="j46GMg"&gt;Each of us has physical, mental, and emotional limitations and weaknesses. These challenges, some of which seem so intractable now, will eventually be resolved. None of these problems will plague us after we are resurrected. Alisa researched survival rates for persons with the type of cancer she had, and the numbers were not encouraging. She wrote: “But there is a cure, so I’m not scared. Jesus has already cured my cancer, and yours. … I &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;will&lt;/span&gt; be better. I’m glad I know this.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p12" pid="QXEkMVqGBEWjrXcoqU0vcg" hash="xUV8Dw"&gt;We can replace the word &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;cancer&lt;/span&gt; with any of the other physical, mental, or emotional ailments we may face. Because of the Resurrection, they have already been cured too. The miracle of resurrection, the ultimate cure, is beyond the power of modern medicine. But it is not beyond the power of God. We know it can be done because the Savior is resurrected and will bring to pass the Resurrection of each of us too.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11"&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p13" pid="sz5_noglKUS7u3V33UJDlw" hash="-NLo_w"&gt;The Resurrection of the Savior proves that He is the Son of God and that what He taught is real. “He is risen, as he said.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12"&gt;12&lt;/span&gt; There could be no stronger proof of His divinity than Him coming forth from the grave with an immortal body.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p14" pid="ArUeQKahnkOkI1JjfP0kfA" hash="ozsmrg"&gt;We know of witnesses to the Resurrection in New Testament times. In addition to the women and men we read about in the Gospels, the New Testament assures us that hundreds actually saw the resurrected Lord.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt; And the Book of Mormon tells of many hundreds more: “The multitude went forth, and thrust their hands into his side, … and [they] did see with their eyes and did feel with their hands, and did know of a surety and did bear record, that it was he, of whom it was written by the prophets, that should come.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14"&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p15" pid="lMReZj4oE0ut4_KI2U4X0A" hash="PXhukw"&gt;To those ancient witnesses are added witnesses in the latter days. In fact, in the opening scene of this dispensation, Joseph Smith saw the resurrected Savior with the Father.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15"&gt;15&lt;/span&gt; Living prophets and apostles have testified of the reality of the resurrected, living Christ.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16"&gt;16&lt;/span&gt; So we may say, “We also are compassed about with so great a cloud of witnesses.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17"&gt;17&lt;/span&gt; And each of us can be part of a cloud of witnesses who know through the power of the Holy Ghost that what we celebrate on Easter actually happened—that the Resurrection is real.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p16" pid="e6M2kLa1S0KI88D4-QehDg" hash="THf8MQ"&gt;The reality of the Resurrection of the Savior overwhelms our heartbreak with hope because with it comes the assurance that all the other promises of the gospel are just as real—promises that are no less miraculous than the Resurrection. We know that He has the power to cleanse us from all our sins. We know that He has taken upon Himself all our infirmities, pains, and the injustices we have suffered.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18"&gt;18&lt;/span&gt; We know that He has “rise[n] from the dead, with healing in his wings.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19"&gt;19&lt;/span&gt; We know that He can make us whole no matter what is broken in us. We know that He “shall wipe away all tears from [our] eyes; and there shall be no more death, neither sorrow, nor crying, neither shall there be any more pain.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20"&gt;20&lt;/span&gt; We know that we can be “made perfect through Jesus … , who wrought out this perfect atonement,”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21"&gt;21&lt;/span&gt; if we will just have faith and follow Him.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p17" pid="SUqwb9Nzz0-FyKXxENeJIA" hash="KIxHmA"&gt;Toward the end of the inspiring oratorio &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;Messiah,&lt;/span&gt; Handel put to beautiful music the Apostle Paul’s words that rejoice over the Resurrection.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p18" pid="-wRvFeYDbU6O0mr2NKnt4g" hash="rBbPDg"&gt;“Behold, I [tell] you a mystery; We shall not all sleep, but we shall all be changed,&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p19" pid="DJhM2RTbIUq82otziH65gQ" hash="18Bm-w"&gt;“In a moment, in the twinkling of an eye, at the last trump: … the trumpet shall sound, and the dead shall be raised incorruptible, and we shall be changed.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p20" pid="1mZcUvAYY0-y5XYNMv2slw" hash="F8A-Ng"&gt;“For this corruptible must put on incorruption, and this mortal must put on immortality.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p21" pid="7ewJkYqIBkWdUSQq-37d5A" hash="lRAMIA"&gt;“… Then shall be brought to pass the saying that is written, Death is swallowed up in victory.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p22" pid="WY1o0FwSsU6SaaI2h4WfYg" hash="owFE1w"&gt;“O death, where is thy sting? O grave, where is thy victory? …&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p23" pid="qxj_HcGlpUmAqpdZloeuJQ" hash="nwPUiQ"&gt;“But thanks be to God, which giveth us the victory through our Lord Jesus Christ.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22"&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p24" pid="AXLaQAGlekymRAZQSH5bjQ" hash="QBynJQ"&gt;I am grateful for the blessings that are ours because of the Atonement and Resurrection of the Lord Jesus Christ. For all who have laid a child in a grave or wept over the casket of a spouse or grieved over the death of a parent or someone they loved, the Resurrection is a source of great hope. What a powerful experience it will be to see them again—not just as spirits but with resurrected bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p25" pid="z5eGLGglcU6O3FESWQ-a1Q" hash="23ApZA"&gt;I long to see my mother again and feel her gentle touch and look into her loving eyes. I want to see my father’s smile and hear his laugh and see him as a resurrected, perfect being. With an eye of faith, I picture Alisa completely beyond the reach of any earthly troubles or any sting of death—a resurrected, perfected Alisa, victorious and with a fulness of joy.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p26" pid="MLTeMHfWZU-RsejksU3b5g" hash="KMWxBQ"&gt;A few Easters ago, she wrote simply: “Life through His name. So much hope. Always. Through everything. I love Easter to remind me.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23"&gt;23&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death.p27" pid="U3qhy1wAp0-9APjhj30dhQ" hash="51wabg"&gt;I testify of the reality of the Resurrection. Jesus Christ lives, and because of Him, we will all live again. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/04/and-there-shall-be-no-more-death</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2016-general-conference/2016-04-5060-paul-v-johnson-64k-eng.mp3" length="4895825" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
