<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Randall K. Bennett</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Randall K. Bennett.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Randall%20K.%20Bennett.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Randall K. Bennett.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2011 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Choose Eternal Life</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Your eternal destiny will not be the result of chance but of choice. It is never too late to begin to choose eternal life!</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50029123_000_5050" doc-version="2" hash="grnF0Q"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="GRJxNdniu0-y6iz9PAna4g" hash="K2LsmA">Choose Eternal Life</h1><p class="authorName" guid="16f5e16c-67a1-450e-b324-13b6949bb525" pid="nsDgPRDSqEakHICp6mXy6g" hash="T2jccw">Randall K. Bennett</p><p class="kicker" pid="xIRzO7tL0Eqr4qAOKguQMw" hash="4CKGZg">Your eternal destiny will not be the result of chance but of choice. It is never too late to begin to choose eternal life!</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="79816538-c8bf-4f5a-936e-df0b2640a676">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p1" guid="490aa112-f9e7-43c3-b8ff-dc26dbb6c778" pid="Gz0pr2GXG02wFKF1T_F4Cw" hash="yPBIsw">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="98"></span>Years ago, while at the beach with my family, I noticed signs and flags warning us of a strong current flowing away from the shore into deep, turbulent water. Invisible to my untrained eyes but easily detected by lifeguards on a nearby watchtower, the powerful current posed a danger to all who left the safety of the shore and entered the water. I remember rationalizing, “I’m a strong swimmer. Swimming will be great exercise. I’ll be safe in the shallow water.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p2" guid="0c381ae2-e7c3-4c06-9011-7cecdec211c1" pid="eg5OR1Yf1UKdggK4hth0ig" hash="E5s-zQ">Ignoring the warnings and feeling confident in my own judgment, I entered the water to enjoy a “refreshing” swim. After a few minutes I looked up to locate my family on the nearby beach, but the beach was no longer nearby! The deceptive current I had been warned of had captured me and was quickly pulling me away from my family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p3" guid="ad5557af-5381-4d5e-9341-fceabb56ea2b" pid="E7sOQLAAjkyyX88jny-gAw" hash="84chGA">Confidently at first and then desperately, I tried to swim toward shore, but the unforgiving current dragged me farther and farther into deeper, rougher water. I became exhausted and began choking on inhaled water. Drowning became a real possibility. My energy gone, I frantically and finally called out for help.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p4" guid="09d6bca8-0913-46fa-873e-c2d0e4d2cd05" pid="bACeeet82kunzyu5enfA9A" hash="Z2N0lg">Miraculously, it seemed, a lifeguard was immediately at my side. I wasn’t aware that he had watched me go into the water. He knew the current would capture me, and he knew where it would take me. Avoiding the current, he swam around and just beyond where I was struggling; then he patiently waited for me to call for help. Too weak to swim to shore alone, I was and still am grateful for his rescue. Without his help I never could have made it back to my family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p5" guid="cdbbf72b-7320-4c8e-b81a-c134adeb43cd" pid="U_OodF7rYEyQGEW7XhX12Q" hash="mfReaA">That day I made a poor choice that produced potentially serious consequences for me and for my family. As we now consider together the gift of choice, I pray that the Holy Ghost will help each of us individually evaluate the choices we are making.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p6" guid="d3cf61be-0636-477b-860d-910a175de18a" pid="ozWlzIYJQ0yk3GU-2YNwtw" hash="f1rRNA">Our beloved prophet, President Thomas S. Monson, has taught: “I can’t stress too strongly that decisions determine destiny. You can’t make eternal decisions without eternal consequences.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p7" guid="1fb621c8-55d0-44ff-abdb-b80ebacf7577" pid="pCP2uAJUfUe8bl0ZEQyrKA" hash="-r5GXg">Each of you—as we have been taught this conference—is a beloved spirit son or daughter of heavenly parents. You do have a divine nature and destiny.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> During your premortal life you learned to love truth. You made correct eternal choices. You knew that here in mortality, there would be afflictions and adversity, sorrow and suffering, tests and trials to help you <span class="pageBreak" page-number="99"></span>grow and progress. You also knew that you could continue making correct choices, repent of incorrect choices, and through the Atonement of Jesus Christ inherit eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p8" guid="48d08f79-823f-4e62-bbf6-e855febe64c9" pid="VyrpmYu1R02UYw9d_FnQzA" hash="wZUkeA">What did the prophet Lehi teach about choice? He counseled that we are “free to <span class="emphasis">choose</span> liberty and <span class="emphasis">eternal life,</span> through the great Mediator of all men, or to choose captivity and death, according to the captivity and power of the devil.” He then instructed, “Ye should look to the great Mediator, and hearken unto his great commandments; and be faithful unto his words, and <span class="emphasis">choose eternal life.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p9" guid="1e5113f5-fb65-4f7c-b25c-449b390a04d4" pid="NhDSnUu6OU6gpa3YdAkmJw" hash="GSbezw">Brothers and sisters, in what we choose to think about, feel, and do, are you and I <span class="emphasis">choosing eternal life</span>?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p10" guid="16a69af5-bf78-4dbe-a7c4-9fc550d4c041" pid="8jFyqojN202JqTvIyZHO0A" hash="gKI42w">Our grandchildren are learning that when they make a choice, they also choose its consequences. Recently one of our three-year-old granddaughters refused to eat her dinner. Her mother explained, “It’s almost bedtime. If you choose to eat dinner, you are choosing ice cream for dessert. If you choose not to eat dinner, you are choosing to go to bed now, without ice cream.” Our granddaughter considered her two choices and then stated emphatically, “I want <span class="emphasis">this</span> choice—to play <span class="emphasis">and</span> eat only ice cream <span class="emphasis">and</span> not go to bed.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p11" guid="2610ac5f-81ad-4f6e-90ac-5c6c6b556752" pid="OjGI5gbQZkegzfDj2JgboQ" hash="d9Q7yg">Brothers and sisters, do we wish we could play, eat only ice cream, never go to bed, and somehow avoid consequences like malnutrition and exhaustion?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p12" guid="c84f7a87-eadc-4360-89d7-2874b5340430" pid="EH1xpYbjx0S2qVnvWCNv0Q" hash="7FriuA">In reality we have only two eternal choices, each with eternal consequences: choose to follow the Savior of the world and thus choose eternal life with our Heavenly Father or choose to follow the world and thus choose to separate ourselves from Heavenly Father eternally.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p13" guid="9ac4b6b0-ef98-4003-8900-3f0a47727873" pid="2hwxwosb-kOHqBAuZfidSA" hash="I1h3qA">We cannot successfully choose both the safety of righteousness and the dangers of worldliness. Wading or dabbling in worldliness may seem harmless, but so did my “refreshing” swim!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p14" guid="83361d0c-c2ed-4984-b12e-8ce723f1b54c" pid="FXLcDHcFeEOsx_yW3ftacQ" hash="7RQ1zw">Like the current that could have changed the course of my family’s lives, today’s currents of worldliness, deceptive philosophies, false teachings, and rampant immorality seek to drag us away and eternally separate us from our families and from our Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p15" guid="60d62165-8235-49dc-af8d-c135df03a322" pid="NQZW4g6ksEiHwlBhSu_MLg" hash="huVO9g">Our living prophets, seers, and revelators both see and seek to warn us of the often subtle but dangerous worldly currents that threaten us. They lovingly invite, encourage, teach, remind, and warn us. They know that our safety depends on choosing to follow (1) the insights we gain during daily scripture study, pondering, and prayer; (2) the guidance of the Holy Ghost; and (3) their prophetic counsel. They know that there is safety and ultimately joy only in and through our Savior, Jesus Christ, and living His gospel. As Elder Dallin H. Oaks just taught, our Savior declared, “I am the way, the truth, and the life: no man cometh unto the Father, but by me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p16" guid="534bbd92-73da-4fbd-88c1-1a586c5962da" pid="KxzVAagsZUSiP3Kxr4L7lQ" hash="SZfOcw">During adversity and suffering in post-Soviet Russia, Anatoly and Svetlana Reshetnikov chose righteousness over worldliness. After joining the <span class="pageBreak" page-number="100"></span>Church, they were persecuted. He was demoted from his position at work. Valiantly they thought, “Now we have more time to serve God!” They repeatedly received threats, yet they chose to live gospel-centered lives. Elder Anatoly Reshetnikov was called as the first Russian Area Seventy. Through their choices the Reshetnikovs continue to <span class="emphasis">choose eternal life.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p17" guid="6ce924e2-70dd-4fb9-9933-7f335ecc3d61" pid="mJXg_pc3wE-lWhbwc7oR6g" hash="GWUOqQ">We all face adversity. We all have temptations. We all have made mistakes. It is never too hard or too late to make correct choices. Repentance is one of those critical correct choices.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p18" guid="8abff269-0215-4072-bd6d-3367c80cce02" pid="DcsJDSGRRU2UZN20PuM4Fw" hash="LYK0ig">President Dieter F. Uchtdorf has taught:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p19" guid="a181ccf8-8245-41b4-a2e6-c610c7d8d39b" pid="7-31i3OOA0G1iLV2EhgcDQ" hash="2mdlOw">“Small errors and minor drifts away from the doctrine of the gospel of Jesus Christ can bring sorrowful consequences into our lives. It is therefore of critical importance that we become self-disciplined enough to make early and decisive corrections to get back on the right track and not wait or hope that errors will somehow correct themselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p20" guid="a1db0d43-02f6-4365-9331-058bc7ca60fa" pid="4EkpNeuzyU2NMU8KS8qlFw" hash="Uv_bvw">“The longer we delay corrective action, the larger the needed changes become, and the longer it takes to get back on the correct course—even to the point where a disaster might be looming.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p21" guid="b6699dbd-b825-426b-9179-dda0e2dbc62e" pid="vsF-chQXd0Wk4shygtKl-g" hash="XyOMmw">The Savior’s arms of mercy are always extended to each of us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> When we sincerely and fully repent, we can be completely forgiven of our mistakes and the Savior will remember our sins no more.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.f1"><p pid="diTk_UHsQUCn6pFYY3LceA" hash="UY3vqQ">In evaluating your choices and their consequences, you might ask yourself:</p><ul class="bullet" guid="ecfe6391-2dc4-4021-b295-b290d476d329"><li guid="b0847505-fc49-4706-a227-a7c3704055e5" pid="rd3k3sfudUeoCvTGCgoE6Q" hash="dpR_VA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p guid="0a620a98-8edb-45b8-b65c-ca8251457bc8" pid="A5iDUlGzVE2EJBW5H9cH3Q" hash="V90jnw">Am I seeking divine direction through daily scripture study, pondering, and prayer, or have I chosen to be so busy or apathetic that I don’t take time to study the words of Christ, ponder them, and converse with my Heavenly Father?</p>
        </li><li guid="ec187983-1b9d-4c98-9f54-325adea80f18" pid="MAY8WGnqNkick-ke4XYTQQ" hash="nUQu6A">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p guid="717142c4-22ca-45f2-a8af-b689c3ecd894" pid="DbZqi4PdLkmmp_fgzjwurA" hash="1B3w1w">Am I choosing to follow the counsel of living prophets of God, or am I following the worldly ways and the opposing opinions of others?</p>
        </li><li guid="2cbf621f-aa7c-4e8e-8ef7-f95ddab0f150" pid="og0hfVJ1lEWg1ek-Qv3whQ" hash="6OHl0Q">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p guid="4c7604aa-a91f-4521-b7eb-7b77a1549e96" pid="65K2sBdwrEqPV4nZvs28Gw" hash="RfHKoQ">Am I seeking the guidance of the Holy Ghost daily in what I choose to think about, feel, and do?</p>
        </li><li guid="84146e2f-841b-4edd-92c9-6cb7aaea3b59" pid="tz85DGaezkmBlFgReyDZoA" hash="2NS1rQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p guid="9b1fffdc-78c3-477a-9c19-c0b9cca4986d" pid="55o1E5C_1k-wN0cORKV2Nw" hash="JaXeYg">Am I consistently reaching out to assist, serve, or help rescue others?</p>
        </li></ul></div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p22" guid="e2d4ce8f-6330-47ad-813e-422b4a74c9c3" pid="hXt39RypwU-qnN4dUv3sHQ" hash="Hi0nsA">My dear brothers and sisters, your eternal destiny will not be the result of chance but of choice. It is never too late to begin to <span class="emphasis">choose eternal life</span>!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life.p23" guid="1d94d889-1dea-4969-81ea-e9ff3739a44e" pid="vF3iC4LrwEiZbsoeIGWy5Q" hash="SJDIsw">I bear my witness that because of Heavenly Father’s great plan of happiness, each of us can be perfected through the Atonement of Jesus Christ. With our families we can live with our Heavenly Father eternally and receive a fulness of joy. Of these things I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/10/choose-eternal-life</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2011-general-conference/2011-10-5050-elder-randall-k-bennett-64k-eng.mp3" length="4870020" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2011 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Next Step</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Randall K. Bennett describes principles that will help us take our next steps back to the loving embrace of our Heavenly Father and our Savior.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13768_000_47bennett" doc-version="2" hash="8Knz7g">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="ClWOdej3KkiKeHG1i06rrA" hash="_oXI3Q">Your Next Step</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p2" pid="KD-H_Xy87kGJWtmP0dFeBQ" hash="Nf2Xsw">By Elder Randall K. Bennett</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p3" pid="vlrH-SfFvUCLUZA6bHAjrQ" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=tn0DfXn7pEes1PDuWDIhKA"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" alt="Elder Randall K. Bennett" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255498/b1d01adfde9c4236b98b1165955fdd3f/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255498/b1d01adfde9c4236b98b1165955fdd3f/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255498/b1d01adfde9c4236b98b1165955fdd3f/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x278="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255498/b1d01adfde9c4236b98b1165955fdd3f/200x278.jpg" data-src-320x445="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255498/b1d01adfde9c4236b98b1165955fdd3f/320x445.jpg" data-src-460x640="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255498/b1d01adfde9c4236b98b1165955fdd3f/460x640.jpg" data-src-640x891="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255498/b1d01adfde9c4236b98b1165955fdd3f/640x891.jpg" data-src-1024x1426="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255498/b1d01adfde9c4236b98b1165955fdd3f/1024x1426.jpg" data-src-2048x2852="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255498/b1d01adfde9c4236b98b1165955fdd3f/2048x2852.jpg" data-src-3652x5086="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255498/b1d01adfde9c4236b98b1165955fdd3f/3652x5086.jpg" pid="tn0DfXn7pEes1PDuWDIhKA" hash="mfNu7g"></img></a></div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="QAwa8f3qnUWJ0uv3YpLZhA" hash="M105bg">Your loving Heavenly Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, invite you to take your next step toward Them. Don’t wait. Take it now.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="Y0rIk6-0MEy2mlQzGpmeow" hash="T2jccw">Randall K. Bennett</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p5" pid="kgztyuWCP06ccvkMtcxV4Q" hash="7iqHPw">My heart sank during a recent meeting with wonderful Latter-day Saints. The question was asked, “Who desires to live with Heavenly Father again?” Every hand went up. The next question was “Who has confidence you’ll succeed?” Sadly and surprisingly, most hands went down.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p6" pid="NimaIHKXZE6Wc2anF-Tm6Q" hash="ztUujQ">When we perceive a gap between who we are now and who we desire to become, many of us are tempted to choose to lose faith and hope.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p7" pid="EmYAJuagsUKXY0uKXu_P7g" hash="8g93lA">Because “no unclean thing can dwell with God,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> in order to live with Him again we will need to be cleansed of sin<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> and sanctified.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> If we had to do this <span class="emphasis">alone,</span> none of us would make it. But we are not alone. In fact, we are <span class="emphasis">never</span> alone.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p8" pid="K_2_BCRssEy9lKzznrlkAw" hash="Fd55Mw">We have heaven’s help because of Jesus Christ and His Atonement.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> The Savior said, “If ye will have faith in me ye shall have power to do whatsoever thing is expedient in me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> When faith is exercised, faith increases.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p9" pid="AmD-ScUznUu4eO-5CHHBoQ" hash="NCwJvA">Let’s consider together three principles that will help us on our journey back to our Father in Heaven.</p>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.t1">
			<h2 pid="HFHvmL1oGEakdXTMMtbcIg" hash="Q3hdOQ">Become as a Child</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p11" pid="_PgL4UMx-kuPg6KgZqiK7g" hash="8G9H9g">Our youngest grandson illustrates the first principle. After learning to crawl and then stand, he was ready to try walking. During his first few attempts, he fell, cried, and gave a look that said, “I will never—ever—try that again! I’m simply going to keep crawling.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p12" pid="A7nxLdGdGkiQIN4yjpEgOQ" hash="bSl0pQ">When he stumbled and fell, his loving parents did not feel that he was hopeless or that he would never walk. Instead they held out their arms while calling to him, and with his eyes on them, he tried again to move toward their loving embrace.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p13" pid="RxK5EYsmU0iFZg6RzqfaXA" hash="ncTtwg">Loving parents are always ready with outstretched arms to welcome even our smallest step in the right direction. They know that our willingness to try and try again will lead to progress and success.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p14" pid="jiYHiy53PEKWDUw8p466iw" hash="GJvsvQ">The Savior taught that to inherit the kingdom of God, we must become as a little child.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> So, spiritually speaking, the first principle is that we need to do what we did as children.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p15" pid="hsO6DF1x2EuV6_XkHWd2sA" hash="w8YfmA">With childlike humility and willingness to focus on our Father in Heaven and our Savior, we take steps toward Them, never giving up hope, even if we fall. Our loving Heavenly Father rejoices in each and every faithful step, and if we fall, He rejoices in each effort to get back up and try again.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.t2">
			<h2 pid="K3ZJhhi4AE6ZFgCpbaRpqg" hash="sIcK4Q">Act with Faith</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p17" pid="JK3LbCdXKE-pdn4mFMix8A" hash="lbl-4g">A second principle is illustrated by two faithful Saints, each deeply desirous of finding an eternal companion. Both prayerfully took faith-filled steps.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p18" pid="MVm0C4O0H0m23kwneTiefw" hash="RXQu-Q">Yuri, a Russian Latter-day Saint, sacrificed and saved to take a long trip to the temple. On the train he noticed a beautiful woman with a bright countenance, and he felt that he should share the gospel with her. Not knowing what else to do, he began reading from his Book of Mormon, hoping that she might notice.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p19" pid="SsCH-UVbyE-g0rGq8OpnjQ" hash="u91KnQ">Yuri didn’t realize that the woman, Mariya, was already a Latter-day Saint. Not knowing that Yuri too was a member, and following a prompting she had to share the gospel with him, Mariya began reading in her Book of Mormon as well, hoping that he might notice.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p20" pid="cKeT7PsnH0-ZZ4XmhxjzLg" hash="tqUoJQ">Well, when they simultaneously looked up, Yuri and Mariya were astonished to see the Book of Mormon in each other’s hands—and yes, after falling in love, they were sealed in the temple. Today, Yuri and Mariya Kutepov of Voronezh, Russia, as eternal companions, contribute significantly to the growth of the Church in Russia.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p21" pid="PDhKW6upd0udAWHygjloVA" hash="HiBorA">The emphasis here is not only on this couple’s willingness to act in faith. It’s also about a second principle—the Lord more than matches our willingness to act in faith. Our willingness to take a step is not just met; it is exceeded by the Lord’s promised blessings.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p22" pid="HP_AcJxESk-r5-Epbwi50w" hash="NdlTkw">Heavenly Father and our Savior are <span class="emphasis">eager</span> to bless us. After all, They ask only for one-tenth of what They bless us with and then promise that the windows of heaven will open!<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p23" pid="j1DSgvBCuUqGbQKWoED83g" hash="8BlzIA">Whenever we willingly act with faith in Jesus Christ and take another step, especially an uncomfortable step requiring change or repentance, we are blessed with strength.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p24" pid="6eMO70fkf0mDI6bpVD7egA" hash="efPbGg">I testify that the Lord will guide us to—and <span class="emphasis">through</span> —our next steps. He will more than match our efforts with His power if we are willing to keep trying, repenting, and moving forward with faith in our Heavenly Father and His Son, Jesus Christ.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p25" pid="zASe-QP-ZECJ9ZzVInUp4A" hash="j_Ss0w">Spiritual gifts are promised not only to those who love God and keep all of His commandments but also, gratefully, to those of us who “[seek] so to do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> Strength is given to those who keep seeking and trying.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p26" pid="s2rFBD4la0Oap4muaYLIsQ" hash="XYN0fQ">Two essential weekly signposts that mark our journey back to our Father in Heaven are the perpetual covenant of the ordinance of the sacrament and our Sabbath day observance. President Russell M. Nelson taught us last general conference that the Sabbath is the Lord’s gift to us. Our devoted weekly observance of the Sabbath is our sign to the Lord that we love Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p27" pid="LvRwmqnUJUavoZIF5D6ECQ" hash="MRpOxg">Each Sabbath day we witness that we are “willing to take upon [ourselves His name], and always remember him, and keep his commandments.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> In return for our repentant heart and our commitment, the Lord renews the promised remission of sin and enables us to “always have his Spirit to be with [us].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> The Holy Spirit’s influence improves, strengthens, teaches, and guides us.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p28" pid="psVnLu2idU6eFpVfZV9Ung" hash="q3eZNA">If, in remembering Him each Sabbath, we turn our hearts to the Savior through these two important signposts, our efforts are again more than matched by the Lord by His promised blessings. We are promised that, with devoted Sabbath day observance, the fulness of the earth will be ours.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p29" pid="NjErOL1wWkOtzEkoUe9Ypg" hash="ty6HYw">The path back to our Father in Heaven leads to the house of the Lord, where we are blessed to receive saving ordinances for ourselves and for our departed loved ones. President Boyd K. Packer taught that “ordinances and covenants become our credentials for admission into [God’s] presence.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> I pray that each of us will always be worthy of and use our temple recommends to serve regularly.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.t3">
			<h2 pid="qIrHVlgQe0uS572ExF79-Q" hash="uIrQVg">Overcome the Natural Man</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p31" pid="lGvQNESmmEeapaEhxOYPCQ" hash="OkiQEw">A third principle is this: we must counter the natural man’s tendency to procrastinate, to put off, or to give up.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p32" pid="Gw6YxYFNb0GL-Okm_QJr_A" hash="6ftMEQ">As we progress along the covenant path, we will make mistakes, some multiple times. Some of us struggle with behaviors or addictions we feel powerless to overcome. But faith in Heavenly Father and in Jesus Christ is a principle of action and power.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> If we are willing to act, we will be blessed with the strength to repent and with the strength to change.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p33" pid="_Zzg50jLAEa1ZH7aEYePMg" hash="xPYVvg">We fail only if we fail to take another faithful step forward. We will not, we cannot, fail if we are faithfully yoked to the Savior—He who has never failed and will never fail us!</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.t4">
			<h2 pid="IQz4EZ_xSkyVs2qcwEeYJg" hash="d_hGOA">Promised Blessings</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p35" pid="GFRG3I71h0KBYi923OMMsA" hash="B1GGGA">I promise that each faith-filled step will be met with help from heaven. Guidance will come as we pray to our Heavenly Father, rely on our Savior and follow Him, and listen to the Holy Spirit. Strength will come because of the atoning sacrifice of Jesus Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> Healing and forgiveness will come because of God’s grace.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> Wisdom and patience will come by trusting in the Lord’s timing for us. Protection will come by following God’s living prophet, President Thomas S. Monson.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p36" pid="QAGxqlOKjkCz0fu0rsJDWg" hash="SynXwg">You were created “that [you] might have joy,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> joy you will feel when you worthily return to your Heavenly Father and your Savior and step into Their warm embrace.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step.p37" pid="VsICy5Euq06-gdp2zCQ5yA" hash="hbnIBw">I bear witness of these absolute truths. Your loving Heavenly Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, live. They know you. They love you. They lovingly invite you to take your next step toward Them. Don’t wait. Take it now. In the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/10/your-next-step</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2015-general-conference/2015-10-3020-elder-randall-k-bennett-64k-eng.mp3" length="4713392" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
