<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Richard P. Lindsay</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Richard P. Lindsay.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Richard%20P.%20Lindsay.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Richard P. Lindsay.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Mar 1990 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 1990 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>“Ye Have Done It unto Me”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me?lang=eng</link>
      <description>This past year has given me a new vision of the Savior’s words as recorded in Matthew:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_90905_000_007" doc-version="2" hash="e6tWxQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="btd79_dZN0G23B3y7pgjhw" hash="OdCQDw">“Ye Have Done It unto Me”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="XRCxabeCg0WjMIRouJDobw" hash="B-Flxw">Richard P. Lindsay</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-21e6.jpg" alt="Elder Richard P. Lindsay" pid="kcE2gB37dkydCK5epPCjKg" hash="5Pkn5w" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p1" pid="L5vJ7jpTgUGqW7F-2FKh0w" hash="OaOYuQ">This past year has given me a new vision of the Savior’s words as recorded in Matthew:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p2" pid="GiSpxQarV0q4lbJ0hCJJXw" hash="GAP1IA">“Then shall the righteous answer him, saying, Lord, when saw we thee an hungred, and fed thee? or thirsty, and gave thee drink?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p3" pid="ybJfMEaQwEq5CRhz8G0Zog" hash="3nEFVQ">“When saw we thee a stranger, and took thee in? or naked, and clothed thee?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p4" pid="947OVUqKiESV1apLeUIA9g" hash="8EgWfQ">“Or when saw we thee sick, or in prison, and came unto thee?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p5" pid="NjmvqJQNw0itTYeEQEOfZg" hash="RZnVoQ">“And the King shall answer and say unto them, Verily I say unto you, Inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.37-40" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:37–40</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p6" pid="8L1brFOYaUWZ_4lVBc34_Q" hash="0oPM9Q">In visits to more than thirty stakes of Zion during the year past, my life has been blessed and my faith has been increased as I have observed and experienced the Christlike love and the quiet, unheralded service demonstrated in the lives of countless true Latter-day Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p7" pid="-4wDA8xQrUS8bg1yUJmxoA" hash="A6md1w">Such examples of charity, the pure love of Christ, are not restricted to geographic location, to age, or gender, or station in life. Such acts of kindness and love of fellowman seek no praise or reward and are often performed within the humble homes and from the loving hearts of the Lord’s devoted servants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p8" pid="9pPUzhMxMEmxIWnye23ayw" hash="QJf_kQ">Permit me to recount a few such examples from the lives of true followers of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p9" pid="cyh4fI01fkmMBra4FnjOag" hash="ggmStA">In an early stake conference assignment, Elder Paramore and I were blessed to visit the home of a dear brother who, in a tragic industrial accident on August 26, 1958, fell from a cooling tower into a hole thirty-five feet below, where he landed on his head and became paralyzed from the shoulders down. In the intervening thirty-one years he has survived as one of the longest-living quadriplegics in medical history. He was unable to attend the conference meetings, but a brief, thoughtfully prepared video of his life and testimony was presented in the Saturday evening session of conference. He lies not in a bed but suspended on a circular metal rack, where he has received devoted nursing care twenty-four hours a day, seven days a week, since this accident—more than thirty-one years ago.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p10" pid="WC1T4k_fBUCwSBCJxqds3Q" hash="B5R8Gw">This brother, whose home we visited following the conference, praised his nurses, his priesthood leaders, his home teachers, and many others who during those long years stood by his side and ministered to his spiritual and temporal needs. A wise stake president had called him to be the regular correspondent to the missionaries and the servicemen from his stake. I have been inspired many times as I have read his letters sent to bolster the faith of choice young missionaries across the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p11" pid="CYoFg3_kZkqvt3qK30usIA" hash="HSW55A">May I quote two lines from one of these missionary letters: “Christ is the only way to heaven. All other paths are detours to doom—commitment to Christ should go hand in hand with commitment to His Church.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p12" pid="-JzDr2UMz0OgCJdg4F7MgQ" hash="uTSk9w">In another stake, in a Sunday morning Primary meeting of that stake conference, I met two beautiful daughters of a faithful young Latter-day Saint physician and his devoted wife. The older child was in a wheelchair, and the younger child moved with great effort. Both of these children suffer from a degenerative disease of genetic origin thought to be progressive and incurable. According to medical wisdom, their time in this life is extremely limited. Their eyes were beautiful and clear—full of faith and love of their Savior, whose presence had been made real in their lives by loving parents and grandparents and devoted Church teachers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p13" pid="9D5lNkXr_E6ZT2h4rQzD4A" hash="67x2pA">To fulfill a deep desire for more children, their devoted parents have adopted two other beautiful daughters from another country. Instead of cursing God as Job was encouraged by his associates to do in the face of other faith-testing burdens, this couple has reached out to these two beautiful additional daughters, who now feel the blessing of being reared in a household of faith, with love from parents whose hearts and lives demonstrate the pure love of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p14" pid="300VjLuYSE-fBXJBzrcrGw" hash="R5R5jw">Following a recent stake conference, Sister Lindsay and I were blessed to visit another household of faith located in rural Idaho. The young father in this home was suffering from a critical illness. A picture forever etched in my memory is of a mother and five beautiful children, together with this dear brother’s priesthood quorum leaders, kneeling around his bedside pleading with Heavenly Father for the life of this good man. He was then administered to within this circle of faith. It was our blessing recently again to meet this young couple and to hear their beautiful witnessing, their humble outpouring of spirit, of the Lord’s blessing in the restoration of the husband’s health.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p15" pid="HpE-naOQ3EOtCcZbPaDiSw" hash="otoE9Q">In yet another stake conference, a dear sister confined to a wheelchair testified to the strength which she had received from feeling the Lord’s love through reading the Book of Mormon. Earlier her devoted husband had been able to help her to adjust to the crippling effects of her illness. Now he was bedridden, and she spoke of the gratitude that the Lord had empowered her with greater strength to be more self-reliant and better care for her own needs. She had even been given additional strength to minister to the many needs of her dear companion, who now tenderly cared for her and had done so for so many years. Loving family and Church associates had also been helpful so that they were able to remain in their own home with precious memories of early happy family associations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p16" pid="V4ko54czGUS0_zGxb4SqHg" hash="SFRTjA">It was President Kimball who said, “The Lord answers our prayers, but it is usually through another person that he meets our needs.” An incident in the latter part of President Kimball’s ministry helped me to better understand his message and the way his own life witnessed to the truthfulness of his inspired counsel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p17" pid="uXSZm6sV0UKBy521l1F7kA" hash="WrpHig">As a stake president during this period, I went to a local hospital to visit a dear sister suffering with a terminal illness. More than forty years earlier, I had attended school with both this sister and her husband who had been childhood sweethearts. But they had not been blessed with children of their own, and they had filled this void by his serving as a Scout leader—and his loving companion as the “Scout mother”—to scores of young boys over a generation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p18" pid="c_mdpgCZ0kWe5wwu5JDNag" hash="dXRyZQ">As I approached the hospital that day, my heart was heavy with foreboding for what lay ahead in the lives of this choice couple. For weeks this dear brother had stayed with his companion at the hospital day and night to give comfort and ease her burden and the pain of her suffering.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p19" pid="uzqYF1B8FUy-_o1d4K2FMQ" hash="rJY4Ww">As I reached the door of her hospital room that day, I met my friend emerging from his wife’s room into the hallway. Unlike my earlier visits, when his countenance reflected the weight of their ordeal, this time his face was radiant and his eyes were aglow. Before I could utter a word, he said, “You will never guess what just happened. As my wife and I were feeling so burdened, into our room came President Kimball”—himself a patient at the hospital, where he had recently undergone surgery. “He prayed with us and he blessed us, and it was as though the Savior himself had come to lift our burdens.” Many other patients in that hospital, I might add, experienced a similar blessing from one who knew so much of pain and suffering.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p20" pid="sdLm2B_WDUSOFOE3e9l5MA" hash="gjlfaQ">In my own life I have experienced much of the Savior’s love through the kindness and goodness of many of the Lord’s servants. With King Benjamin I acknowledge that if we were to serve the Savior with all our souls, yet we would be unprofitable servants. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.21" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2:21</a>.) And this because of His great love and atoning sacrifice for each of His children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p21" pid="JYomKguJ4U6WaQYBrJdlGQ" hash="1nkgXQ">Some months ago a ninety-year-old patriarch and dear friend of my own father was quietly laid to rest in this valley. My father passed away during the height of the Great Depression in 1932, and ten days later my oldest brother, age fourteen, died. During forty-seven years of my mother’s widowhood, this gentle soul frequently visited our fatherless family to give wise counsel and encouragement and priesthood blessings. His example and personal concern, coupled with the goodness of many other priesthood leaders and loving neighbors, helped my mother and her five remaining children face the problems of economic depression and wars and the many worldly influences and daily challenges with which each of us must cope. His life in many ways touched scores of others in similar circumstances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p22" pid="gM9zsRAM20u8Uo9s1Wodmw" hash="uyns9A">To me he was the epitome of the “pure religion” described in the epistle of James: “To visit the fatherless and widows in their affliction, and to keep himself unspotted from the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.27" class="scriptureRef">James 1:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p23" pid="ZWkcw_6PYkSXVu7OYHDZ6w" hash="TvcHJg">In these challenging times, dear brothers and sisters, the need to “minister unto the least of these” of our Father’s children is so great. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.40" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:40</a>.) How much we need the gifts of discernment and wisdom and charity to know how to really reach down and lift up our brothers and sisters to higher ground.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me.p24" pid="nTdD1fBtdkKmh64NerXbHw" hash="XU4v1w">I pray that day by day we will strive more diligently to be about our Father’s business (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/2.49" class="scriptureRef">Luke 2:49</a>), to love and to serve our fellowmen—to feed the hungry, and clothe the naked, and comfort those that mourn (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.37-39" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:37–39</a>), to hold up the hands that hang down, and strengthen the feeble knees (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/81.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 81:5</a>)—to believe and live the Savior’s doctrine; and to follow after Him and put first in our lives the things of His kingdom. And for this I humbly pray, in the holy name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1990/04/ye-have-done-it-unto-me</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1990-general-conference/1990-04-1050-elder-richard-p-lindsay-64k-eng.mp3" length="5398097" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 1990 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Feed My Sheep”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Wirthlin, I was at that football game and spent ten cents to watch that great run. But I forgive you for not tackling Whizzer White.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_94905_000_021" doc-version="2" hash="u6Czng">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="FSD5ZOalSECV1xwX3WQ8-g" hash="pjx3IA">“Feed My Sheep”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="AMCpj_Tz8Eyd-I9U6tAhqA" hash="B-Flxw">Richard P. Lindsay</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-21e6.jpg" alt="Elder Richard P. Lindsay" pid="8DLcEvZN3kuPUaSO7PpB3g" hash="5Pkn5w" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p1" pid="5DHSCmNY_UOU8AjkcInvqA" hash="XqDrsg">Elder Wirthlin, I was at that football game and spent ten cents to watch that great run. But I forgive you for not tackling Whizzer White.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p2" pid="jGW3MKfHdU6406kspavZmw" hash="ypvYIg">Along with Elder Wirthlin, I should like to speak tonight to the great army of young Aaronic Priesthood bearers and especially to those who are called in these challenging times by divine revelation to be their priesthood leaders. I have had a lifelong feeling of deep gratitude to the Aaronic Priesthood leaders who blessed my early life in ways I will never be able to repay. These good men helped fill the void in my life after my father, who had served nearly all his married life as our ward’s bishop, was taken by a sudden illness when I was five years old.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p3" pid="3gQdI1GNm0SWDjw_hArUPg" hash="8fcDrw">Some years later in 1940 as a ward deacons quorum president, I received a letter from the Presiding Bishopric of the Church, signed by LeGrand Richards, Marvin O. Ashton, and Joseph L. Wirthlin. This letter said in part, “The Presiding Bishopric of the Church extends to the Presidency of the Taylorsville Ward deacons quorum congratulations and best wishes on achieving more than 90% attendance in priesthood and sacrament meeting for the year 1939.” Can you imagine, brethren, the impact of this letter on the Aaronic Priesthood bearers of our rural ward and especially the three thirteen-year-old deacons who composed the quorum presidency? From that moment on, these men of the Presiding Bishopric became my instant heroes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p4" pid="A7mEKyPkJUqXu8gMI7WQ-Q" hash="XbD59w">In more mature reflection on that event, I realize that this letter was largely the result of a faithful, conscientious ward bishopric whose second counselor, assigned to the deacons quorum, frequently sat in council with us in our weekly quorum presidency planning meeting. He was <span class="emphasis">always</span> present for at least a portion of our weekly quorum meeting. Our quorum adviser was the kind of humble leader I envision the Savior trying to help Peter become as He admonished the soon-to-be prophet-leader of the Church, “Peter, when thou art converted, strengthen thy brethren” (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/22.32" class="scriptureRef">Luke 22:32</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p5" pid="mjp1dC3X5UWJ2btGtvFh1A" hash="wsu7Xw">As we sat each Sunday morning in the dimly lit basement room of a nineteenth-century-built chapel, this great deacons quorum adviser poured out his heart to his young flock of eager youth. With pure love and plain words he told us of the folly of using harmful substances revealed by the Lord in the Word of Wisdom. He emphasized the need for us to be clean in body and mind in our personal lives and to be worthy to serve the Lord in the mission field. I remember that at appropriate times, with tears in his eyes, he would bear his humble testimony to the members of the deacons quorum of the divinity of the Savior and the prophetic mission of Joseph Smith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p6" pid="jUwUfQWmbEKPuBC9ct1kYw" hash="4vMeAw">He taught us faithfully that we were our brothers’ keepers and that the purpose of the quorum was to bless each member’s life. He emphasized that when we passed the sacrament or collected fast offerings or cut wood for widows living in the ward, we were doing just what the Lord would have us do. When one member of our quorum from a less-active family suffered a prolonged illness and could not attend priesthood meetings, we would go to his home, and he would there receive the weekly priesthood lesson and the fellowship of quorum members. When another less-active member, whose single parent was not a member of the Church failed to attend, priesthood sessions were held in his home as well. Both of these young men in more recent years have blessed countless Church members as they have been called to positions of major responsibility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p7" pid="8DVyHwXGjEid-3-ICk8DdQ" hash="BDUPcg">Many years later I stood at the hospital bedside of this dear quorum adviser as he was about to exchange this life for eternity. Despite considerable personal suffering, he wanted to use that brief time to have me review with him the current circumstances of each of those deacons who had belonged to that favored quorum more than thirty years earlier.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p8" pid="h10B_xjQf0e1j8IMLV_8_A" hash="B0q-ng">His life literally fulfilled the instruction of the Savior to Peter on the shores of the Sea of Tiberias in his final admonition to the Apostles: “Feed my lambs. … Feed my sheep. … Feed my sheep” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/21.15-17" class="scriptureRef">John 21:15–17</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p9" pid="zZemxtmLaUGnkphwY2Rb5A" hash="ojS5Jg">The battle for the souls of our Heavenly Father’s precious sheep and lambs is raging in every corner of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p10" pid="Cns4aL8dqE6X3HMtizvCbw" hash="HWBvXw">An increasingly permissive culture, so heavily influenced by the media, especially television, has caused us all, and especially our youth, to be subjected to a moral wasteland of values. Television in America in most instances has almost single-handedly removed vulgarity from modern culture by making it the “norm.” The result is a mass culture driven by profiteers who exploit the hunger for vulgarity, pornography, and even barbarism. Such influences cannot help but have a demoralizing effect on the religious faith and belief of our great young people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p11" pid="airgNPuoKUaKrAqS0S-utA" hash="KvCGPQ">Such is the condition envisioned by Bible and Book of Mormon prophets. And such is the world in which the faithful bearers of the Aaronic Priesthood in our time must live and emerge valiant and victorious. Against this worldly backdrop, leaders of Aaronic Priesthood must reach out, with love, to help each young man to:</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.f2">
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="VmLtyNayU0aetRZKB9om3w" hash="dX59og">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="E9KIRMJT9k-O--I1-FM-0Q" hash="ZSZzNg">become truly converted to the gospel of Jesus Christ and live by its teachings;</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="8G3ed37hWkW1-zX38JWFOQ" hash="6JHENg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="nZ6bceUlsESPN64tn-bVtQ" hash="neG6Sg">magnify his priesthood callings;</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="2DrXi0EbGk6zms4t-AGGcQ" hash="pnnf2Q">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="q58j8Wsc7kSpGSylI0BUCw" hash="BAJcFA">give meaningful service;</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="Wz43p0QfaEewUxRkzaq_9g" hash="hO_ztA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="FPWvSZ3XqEudiExezc6PaA" hash="Dy8zxg">prepare to receive the Melchizedek Priesthood;</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="toCEGDvXVkyyPqQKAvYyew" hash="grUcpQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="lML7RRzkd0Gjebsk0lNZJg" hash="6M1O1w">commit to, worthily prepare for, and serve an honorable mission;</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="aI6Ic5YtFUeo9j9m_5lYXg" hash="D_S4OQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="YUusfydrukqNdWBh3m5Uzg" hash="FRkZ3A">live worthy to receive temple covenants and prepare to become a worthy husband and father.</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p12" pid="FuRFvApAJUivvXY4rlpKMQ" hash="DYHUGQ">Brethren, make sure that the love and fellowship of the priesthood reaches out to each young man in your quorum and that each one is included and friendshipped.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p13" pid="l0gWZqMiYUCJ6AUH0j1UcQ" hash="IFFBBw">Since recently returning from a three-year Church assignment in Africa and becoming reacquainted with our twenty-three grandchildren, Sister Lindsay and I have often been requested on such visits to tell these grandchildren a bedtime story that is, first, true; second, exciting; and third, one they have never heard before. All you grandpas here tonight can understand the challenge which such a request represents. One such true story did come to my mind, however, as we visited recently in the home of a son and his wife who live in a midwestern city with their five children, including three bearers of the Aaronic Priesthood, a priest, teacher, and a deacon. This story concerned their own father when he was a six-year-old boy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p14" pid="x1ipFl8LRUSTqkUbUdOGhQ" hash="UkD0CA">I grew up in rural Salt Lake County when it was an economic necessity to care for a variety of barnyard animals. My favorite animals were sheep—prompted perhaps by the fact that sheep do not require being milked twice a day, seven days a week.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p15" pid="0n6oExhQzkegaByaDJCDoQ" hash="JsA7lg">I wanted our own sons to have the blessing of being shepherds to such farm animals. Our older sons were each provided with a ewe to teach them the responsibility of caring for these sheep and the lambs that would hopefully follow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p16" pid="3rvx2GumxEiBsE94BxNJug" hash="9hLYZA">Our second son, newly turned six years of age, called me excitedly at my office one cold March morning on the phone and said, “Daddy, guess what? Esther [Esther was his mother ewe]—Esther has just had two baby lambs. Please come home and help me take care of them.” I instructed Gordon to watch the lambs carefully and make sure they received the mother’s milk and they would be fine. I was interrupted by a second phone call later in the morning with the same little voice on the other end saying, “Daddy, these lambs aren’t doing very well. They haven’t been able to get milk from the mother, and they are very cold. Please come home.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p17" pid="O0_TSF5jT0KcdcKURZiM1A" hash="FonH1A">My response likely reflected some of the distress I felt by being distracted from my busy work schedule. I responded, “Gordon, the lambs will be all right. You just watch them, and when Daddy comes home we will make sure they get mother’s milk and everything will be fine.” Again, later in the afternoon I received a third, more urgent call. Now the voice on the other end was pleading. “Daddy, you’ve got to come home now. Those lambs are lying down, and one of them looks very cold.” Despite work pressures, I now felt some real concern and tried to reassure the six-year-old owner of the mother sheep by saying, “Gordon, bring the lambs into the house. Rub them with a gunnysack to make them warm. When Daddy comes home in a little while, we will milk the mother, feed the lambs, and they will be fine.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p18" pid="oCiJd9xuoUmTL8Bpw9kTpg" hash="Z2xzpA">Two hours later I drove into the driveway of our home and was met by a boy with tear-stained eyes, carrying a dead lamb in his arms. His grief was overwhelming. Now I tried to make amends by quickly milking the mother sheep and trying to force the milk from a bottle down the throat of the now weak, surviving lamb. At this point, Gordon walked out of the room and came back with a hopeful look in his eyes. He said, “Daddy, I’ve prayed that we will be able to save this lamb, and I feel it will be all right.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p19" pid="YIbDGtQRxEqsoo652ZoFKA" hash="dGhFgA">The sad note to this story, brethren, is that within a few minutes the second lamb was dead. Then with a look that I will remember forever, this little six-year-old boy who had lost both of his lambs looked up into his father’s face and with tears running down his cheeks said, “Daddy, if you had come home when I first called you, we could have saved them both.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p20" pid="WLo14hlqPkiz-k0McluFZA" hash="darJMg">Dear brethren of the priesthood, those who are entrusted as keepers of the Lord’s precious flock—we must be there with the lambs when we are needed. We must teach with love, principles of faith, and goodness and be righteous examples to the lambs of our Heavenly Father. Each quorum member must be prepared for his future role as a bearer of the holy Melchizedek Priesthood in a world plagued with sin and desperate for decisive moral leadership.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep.p21" pid="TpsyEqhxTkixx7BXibB-IA" hash="pqvDBw">I leave my witness that this is God’s work. It is the most important work in all the world in which we can be engaged. That we will be instruments in His hands in saving the precious lambs for which He gave His life, I humbly pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1994/04/feed-my-sheep</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1994-general-conference/1994-04-3030-elder-richard-p-lindsay-64k-eng.mp3" length="5395172" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 1994 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
