<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Richard L. Evans</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Richard L. Evans.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Richard%20L.%20Evans.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Richard L. Evans.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1971 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1971 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Where Are You Really Going?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My beloved brethren and sisters—everywhere:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03006_000_4050" doc-version="2" hash="pitwkA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="BhxPeuvFYUiRtEKH6iepkQ" hash="uMKjkA">Where Are You Really Going?</h1><p class="authorName" guid="b1f38ce5-3984-4f6f-863e-2a3e7913d790" pid="4pHlk4IlCUi8Y0PBRLXoiw" hash="Gub1og">Richard L. Evans</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="444f97c0-33ea-4b25-8adf-a06c67b2881e">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3598.jpg" alt="Elder Richard L. Evans" guid="2f72a932-41ad-4a7e-953d-936440fb95aa" pid="pmFH5espu0GU0jufNXmndA" hash="xiDTsw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p1" guid="686a7759-28ac-4a51-aaae-11524ab74b95" pid="-EpIqi6lqUuunz_RE5dSMA" hash="NJcJJg">My beloved brethren and sisters—everywhere:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p2" guid="8aaf35eb-7260-44dc-8946-344772159c1e" pid="txGFT_oEFk6LO31FLBiI3Q" hash="bXl5yA">Some weeks ago some of us were considering what would attract the attention of people as they passed through a busy airport—moving to and from many places, intent on many purposes. The often-quoted questions came to mind: Where did we come from? Why are we here? Where are we going?—but a variation of one of these suggested itself: Where are you <span class="emphasis">really </span>going? And to this we might have added: What do you <span class="emphasis">really </span>want?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p3" guid="c6815cd0-cba0-4a09-884f-05f03019c767" pid="jctZi8KdAEeKQdvdrrparg" hash="QOC2Eg">We use much of our time in rushing around, not thinking always what we ought to be, nor what it is that matters most.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p4" guid="6b82e4ce-b2b5-4018-ac0e-3bafdbdac587" pid="DIZBaNsAK0K-afZ2lZavVw" hash="toadXA">Sometimes we set our hearts on things we feel we have to have, and when we get them find they don’t mean as much as once we thought they would.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p5" guid="23f18bb4-edbe-40e8-bc1e-efdb0ca08182" pid="cu1e_RurgkabuDxEbMxMbw" hash="E74YZA">And so the years move by—and even while yet young we become aware that we are older than we were.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p6" guid="0f03a5ad-faf1-437e-9d1d-0e3b4bdd2bdc" pid="dXT2vDeExk-7JtKuzeerug" hash="GgLpnw">Soberingly, more than one-fourth of this year already has passed—partly in pursuit perhaps of things that don’t matter very much—which reminds us of a dream that John Ruskin said he had:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p7" guid="2102ceca-711d-4ffa-aa7d-922687925c9b" pid="7VhoeHesNEi7BnotT7uunA" hash="-aTY8Q">“I dreamed,” he said, “that I was at a child’s … party, in which every means of entertainment had been provided … by a wise and kind host. … The children had been set free in the rooms and gardens, with no care whatever but how to pass the afternoon rejoicingly. … There was music … all manner of amusing books … a workshop … a table loaded with everything nice to eat … and whatever a child could fancy … but in the midst of all this it struck two or three of the more ‘practical’ children that they would like some of the brass-headed nails that studded the chairs, and so they set to work to pull them out. In a little while all the children, nearly, were spraining their fingers in pulling out brass-headed nails. With all that they could pull out they were not satisfied; and then everybody wanted some of somebody else’s. And at last the really ‘practical’ and ‘sensible’ ones declared that nothing was of any real consequence that afternoon except to get plenty of brass-headed nails. … And at last they began to fight for nail heads, … <span class="emphasis">even though they knew they would not be allowed to carry so much as one brass knob away with them. </span>But no! it was ‘Who has most nails? … I must have as many as you before I leave the house or I cannot possibly go home in peace.’ At last they made so much noise that I awoke, and thought to myself, ‘What a false dream that is of <span class="emphasis">children. </span> … Children never do such foolish things. Only men do.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p8" guid="ddfff298-2430-46b3-a347-b7b0cbd4f5af" pid="g5p-TIQpxkO5wVZpJSayKQ" hash="YY0E-Q">Well, I haven’t dreamed a dream as Ruskin said he did, but countless times I have searched and prayed and thought this through.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p9" guid="b3f63f3f-4b7d-46df-9c8f-d0fa1223e392" pid="uv3Baa2JtEuDaEZYAgK9QQ" hash="yK0z9w">Beloved young friends, beloved older friends, where are you <span class="emphasis">really </span>going? What do you <span class="emphasis">really </span>want?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p10" guid="bc2e3177-6307-4ae8-b99d-6253c8e4f30b" pid="SRKtaOVKzkGZNLmS3u0f8Q" hash="pD59Rg">Some months ago I spoke at the funeral service of a beloved old friend. He had, I would suppose, little of the <span class="emphasis">things </span>of this life, but I heard his grandson say, “Once a week Grandfather was with <span class="emphasis">all </span>his family—grandchildren and all. He taught the gospel to them. He was never negative. He always expressed faith and encouragement. There was no ‘generation gap.’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p11" guid="f65a9e61-042d-43a1-84ca-7928e27ce385" pid="Q4A-OAviHEGOxw3zhTJwVg" hash="VrlN1Q">And I thought how blessed and satisfied I would feel if a grandson of mine could sincerely say this of me when this life runs out its short, uncertain length.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p12" guid="a96d9e1a-0a61-44ec-a82e-8ba0fbc2026a" pid="w6LCSXydtUK-TsdZ-EcHfw" hash="Tr4NuQ">I thought of places where we’ve been, worldwide, where hundreds of millions have never had the privilege of learning to read and write. And then I thought of other places where young people drop out and ignore their opportunities. In a world that more and more demands training and competence and skill, where do they <span class="emphasis">really </span>think they are going?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p13" guid="5d9d1edd-fa79-4974-b068-b4e2beaf6c92" pid="X4JKRXKZM0CcviBNKdACTA" hash="BtCl0g">My beloved young friends, <span class="emphasis">every </span>day is part of eternity. What happens here and now is forever important.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p14" guid="4215bdaf-8886-4b75-9f58-da908e17a419" pid="pDmts1-lUE-T6T0hxQOToQ" hash="HCvM0A">And I would plead with you, wherever you are, to prepare yourselves for opportunities that await you here and now, as well as for a future that is forever. “What is opportunity,” asked George Eliot, “to the man who can’t use it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p15" guid="778d5d52-6025-4fac-b8f6-fd90caaea679" pid="RgBAmRZvAU6udKMXHvlUyA" hash="QiXFiA">The laws of nature, the laws of God, the laws of life, are one and the same and are always in full force. We live in a universe of law. Spring follows winter. This we can count on. The sun will show itself on time again tomorrow morning. This we can count on.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p16" guid="4d8b549f-012c-48b2-b30c-249413950eb4" pid="r1WWM9ulw06n0bI2e34HEQ" hash="zPYjyg">And the moral laws and spiritual laws are also in full force. This also we can count on. All of us will realize the results of how we live our lives. And don’t let anyone say that mere men have the right or power to repeal God’s commandments or ever set them aside—commandments that are so practical and essential, a part of life, dealing as they do with health and happiness and peace, with honesty and morality and cleanliness, and excellence, and all else that pertains to life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p17" guid="9ab187ae-1471-4a7d-8906-558834351279" pid="EXwNnUOnokqme5urY_5tBw" hash="IKQNew">If someone tells you, my beloved young friends, that you can set the commandments of God aside without realizing the results—if someone tells you <span class="emphasis">that, </span>then you may know that you are listening to someone who doesn’t know, or isn’t telling you the truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p18" guid="4a15123b-a113-4cde-a1d0-003dfa325e94" pid="PvuI1nQYjk2mgYQOAg8Bhg" hash="f8K81g">These minds, these bodies God has given, with their wondrous physical functioning, must last a mortal lifetime—and to impair or dull the senses, or damage their physical functioning, or abuse or fail to care for them—to indulge in body-destroying, mind-dulling, spirit-blighting substances is a foolish, wicked <span class="emphasis">un</span>wisdom. Whatever is not good for man should not be used by man—or done by man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p19" guid="4a9691cb-5585-445f-a2a0-d87d5514f39b" pid="VMwRedP9HUSl6VJsrR11mQ" hash="1rCkDQ">But it isn’t only physical punishment that comes from departing from the laws of life, but also mental and spiritual punishment, and the anguish of the soul inside. As Juvenal said: “The worst punishment of all is that in the court of his own conscience no guilty man is acquitted.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p20" guid="4d497af6-93e1-42ee-b91c-9ee2229f4ca1" pid="8kiUe_WCaEiWxLxA5CLrmA" hash="sg_Z6Q">Well, we ought to live as we ought to live, not only because it would please God, not only because it would please our parents, but as a favor for ourselves—for every commandment, every requirement God has given is for <span class="emphasis">our </span>happiness, for <span class="emphasis">our </span>health, and for <span class="emphasis">our </span>peace and progress. O my beloved young friends, even selfishly it is smart to keep the commandments God has given.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p21" guid="be64d377-58b8-439a-9967-d2f2d88db21d" pid="lEKLpCoD_EyacFqSRPsfVg" hash="XlV1iQ">Now along with the physical side there must be concern also with pollution of the mind and soul—concern for the purveyors and exploiters of pornography, those who for profit or for other purposes would fill people’s minds with vile, debasing pictures and impressions in print.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p22" guid="8ef25c06-f4e7-4541-95fc-a00f9069d4f4" pid="dUFPjlPPNUiTN6ZF-fkz8Q" hash="QNpAiw">O surely we should use such means as are available to roll back such evil—an evil that will never put limits on itself, but will become ever more pervasive and sinister as long as we let it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p23" guid="74c37058-8e97-4bb5-b090-b30fb3cdf8a2" pid="JcY1L5W3YEWen3-Nl1E43w" hash="VdDezQ">We have an obligation to safeguard children in their innocence and honesty. And besides the rising cry to clean up physical pollution, let there be like concern to clean up pollution of mind and manners and morals. Our concern for physical pollution is surely not more urgent than our concern for the pollution of the minds and souls of men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p24" guid="908309a3-7a8d-4809-842b-359caf500cdc" pid="oe8YDv5v3kKWJuodn10OlQ" hash="FKt24Q">Now, as we go along in life, two things should surely be considered: the power of prevention and the power of repentance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p25" guid="b40b989a-1a5c-4254-ad03-d53c5beffa66" pid="5sQ5tOEaOkiDhziTrFm1gQ" hash="SnsUig">Why run against the laws of life? Why run headlong into ill health and unhappiness? Why live contrary to conscience? Think of the heartbreak and waste and regret that could be prevented by living as we ought to live. No one can set aside consequences. As Cecil B. DeMille said: “We cannot break the … Commandments. We can only break ourselves against them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> O let us think and live and teach the power of prevention. “If it is not right,” said Marcus Aurelius, “do <span class="emphasis">not </span>do it; if it is not true, do <span class="emphasis">not </span>say it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p26" guid="0af91522-68f7-4b76-9665-d1dcdc2b2bc6" pid="RD5XHn-kK0a29mkiMxhAJA" hash="CGR_jw">But wherein we may have failed in this (and heaven help us not to fail), then let us turn with all our hearts to the power of repentance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p27" guid="75ae44a6-7d50-4da0-aca7-232a4f9a3068" pid="-OBJ_MGnO0y4Jqx4V-StEA" hash="v1XA5w">The heavy weight of wrongdoing is too big a burden. I have heard President Lee say that the heaviest burden in all the world is the burden of sin. It isn’t a happy sight to see those—young or old—in the anguish of carrying that weight around, wishing to heaven they had done differently.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p28" guid="2457e1af-93e7-44ad-938e-fc9c8647a6bf" pid="SOpnzBGgiEWCG96hy7C36Q" hash="qFyQPg">But thanks be to God for the principle of repentance, for a Father who understands us and who has assured us he will accept our repentance so long as it is sincere. This he has said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p29" guid="f9ad45b7-8a62-472f-8e9e-17a736917e7c" pid="5qFgWbvEEEei_df5rIztbQ" hash="xml-vQ">“By this ye may know if a man repenteth of his sins—behold, he will confess them <span class="emphasis">and forsake them.</span>”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p30" guid="539310cf-1c05-4ffe-b811-da80636c8c47" pid="S1iW3g1ZgkqpQbsMEHPH8w" hash="cIAYpg">“… he who has repented of his sins, the same is forgiven, and I, the Lord, remember them no more.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.43,42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:43, 42</a>. Italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p31" guid="a5ebcded-9c5a-4659-8131-e7d25d9fdcd7" pid="CIRT0fy6H0mBiUzxbNcogg" hash="DL1TkQ">This you can count on. O turn from those ways which will take you where no one really wants to go. Turn to that which will bring you peace and self-respect and cleanliness and a quiet conscience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p32" guid="74888772-8bec-4bb5-bde2-3b9f507b4ca7" pid="rewgqO_4KkyszEnBQ2BbrA" hash="a6RnsA">I don’t presume to know the timetable of our Father’s plans and purposes, but I do know that with each of us the time to turn and begin to go where we ought to go is not later than now.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p33" guid="00478be3-92d3-4674-8f31-651aee2163a2" pid="KDniPeiWhkO0bylaS42vYg" hash="g-4wTA">Where are we <span class="emphasis">really </span>going? As we come again to the season that celebrates the coming forth of our living Lord and Savior, we would well remember the divine plan and purpose that in due time would take us from this swift passing life to a real and personal everlastingness of life, with limitless eternal possibilities, and with our loved ones with us, always, and forever. This is our Father’s plan and purpose. This is why it really matters where we’re going and why we need his gospel to tell us how to get there.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p34" guid="7e85ddbe-4836-42f3-8245-cee2346c7c92" pid="uTX5BUVcyEeGS78d0d39Ew" hash="bwfOgQ">Thank God for his revelations to his prophets, past and present, and for not leaving us alone. He has told us more than we have ever lived up to, and he will tell us more as we serve him and keep his commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p35" guid="df537a71-f90e-4b75-b7e6-95eef31fc969" pid="DdkOcjBz00WNhqu7D5ZLPA" hash="G9KvGg">I leave you, my beloved friends everywhere, my witness that God does live, that same God and Father who made us in his own image; that he sent his divine Son, our Savior, to show us the way of life and redeem us from death; that the heavens have been opened and the fullness of the gospel brought again, to save and exalt us all, if we are willing, which is God’s purpose: to bring our immortality and eternal life to pass.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going.p36" guid="031b03c4-9c94-4ec3-a217-af466fa0bf28" pid="FcS0VDdCUECRGL2TWF7fMA" hash="wmiNWg">I know that my Redeemer lives, and pray his peace and blessings upon all men everywhere, in the name of our Lord and Savior, Jesus the Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/04/where-are-you-really-going</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1971-general-conference/1971-04-4050-elder-richard-l-evans-64k-eng.mp3" length="7498912" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1971 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should the Commandments Be Rewritten?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Perhaps I could begin with an interesting question posed recently and an equally interesting answer. The question was, “Don’t you think the commandments should be The answer was, “No, they should be ”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03012_000_2010" doc-version="2" hash="c1z1jw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="pNwJfrnxIUyUgdXyD9mDKA" hash="uFMyEw">Should the Commandments Be Rewritten?</h1><p class="authorName" guid="b1f38ce5-3984-4f6f-863e-2a3e7913d790" pid="cdlCsoS-Bk6BMBYOncqWOw" hash="Gub1og">Richard L. Evans</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="24184c2d-37a5-4548-a99b-b9d191cf3dbd">
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.t1">
			<img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3598.jpg" alt="Conference photo" guid="dc4dac44-8e55-4c3d-acee-bb052ded0542" pid="TzDKYCrsFkuEB_DVISCY9A" hash="xiDTsw" />
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p1" guid="1727a5e6-3c8f-4c34-bb1d-b9aaab0d4bcf" pid="IkvNyHzEaEKy-yKUlLh_FQ" hash="dmF2fQ">Perhaps I could begin with an interesting question posed recently and an equally interesting answer. The question was, “Don’t you think the commandments should be <span class="emphasis">rewritten?” </span>The answer was, “No, they should be <span class="emphasis">reread.</span>”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p2" guid="d71cd63f-7719-47c0-892b-c684ca40942c" pid="ZloVYoljpUakuyOKMMFyuw" hash="j_p6qw">This may be a good point from which to take off for consideration of some fundamental facts; namely, the commandments of God are there. They come from a divine source. The experience of the ages has proved the need for them, and has proved what happens if they are ignored.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p3" guid="cea6a47d-a9d5-40fe-84a8-9d7d485bb47c" pid="xsmRvzs_Uk6XPSno5Pf65A" hash="NdkIuQ">So why spend life in the frustration and unhappiness and sorrow and tragedy of trying to rationalize and wave them away?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p4" guid="abeb63c2-ff35-408c-8cab-ba2b1e21dc2d" pid="LFM6k0O890O2DkLLGu6UAw" hash="foOW7g">Beginning with the Ten Commandments may be as good a place as any. It would be well to read and reread them and not spend life trying to convince ourselves that they really don’t mean what they say.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p5" guid="02b014ee-bda7-40d6-a875-0ffb164f2604" pid="fnR988IaTkKd2QYci6h9vg" hash="cZhITA">Some things the commandments say thou shalt not do, and if that is what they say, that’s what they mean, and there’s a reason for it.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p6" guid="014f31d2-6e96-4343-9e78-0d1a894a229b" pid="x4MU_LjRWkKprrKgK4bEKg" hash="Jb-QAA">Some of them say this you should do, and there’s a reason for it.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p7" guid="4054c649-82a3-476d-b8ef-9329696b1b89" pid="nzdL1MiyEUqT28SzLTnLxA" hash="sCHNYw">It would be interesting sometime to make a list of what our Father in heaven tells us to do and what he tells us not to do. Any parent is faced with the same situation. Any doctor is faced with the same situation.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p8" guid="a908fdd4-9fce-4532-b880-32c15ce31288" pid="UZsasmAytkCnvNw9XrTx9A" hash="x5diwg">Essentially this is what the gospel is: counsel from a living Father who says to his children, “You have limitless, everlasting possibilities. You also have your freedom. It’s up to you how you use it. This is what you can become if you take my advice—and this is what will happen if you don’t. The choice is yours.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p9" guid="686d13bf-dd5e-4da7-a533-2366f6697278" pid="kbv_l4OJoEmi-mDDoWabHg" hash="DOpJuQ">We all make choices every day. We all have to live with the results of the choices we make.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p10" guid="f32f7692-97c5-44ee-a61b-341a5671efd0" pid="UJqNKr10X0mx8fF6qsBdiA" hash="RU-Hog">It’s just that plain. It isn’t a question of quibbling or hairsplitting or arguing about the mysteries or brooding about the things God hasn’t yet told us, while neglecting the things he has told us. Let’s stop quarreling with the commandments and the requirements and just face the facts.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p11" guid="9b99488c-d853-4a36-ad86-3211a57a8461" pid="2Mqin2rt0UKtEJo4vJooLQ" hash="VHmRLg">Who knows better than the Creator and Father of us all what is and isn’t essential?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p12" guid="a83bd7b6-af5f-4678-abc1-b71bcc03dad0" pid="kF5y7pQT30WoaRSt19eDLA" hash="dA7ZlA">Brilliant men, philosophers and others, have wrestled with these questions through the centuries, and haven’t arrived at any answers they can agree on among themselves.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p13" guid="55775ce4-2d6c-45c1-9d49-d20a2e314328" pid="Vcbts1SrLkGiCS21LSBlaw" hash="DrlSyQ">I have a great respect for scholarship, for education and research, for academic excellence, and for the magnificent accomplishments of sincere and searching men. But I also have great respect for the word of God, and his prophets, and life’s purpose; and it comes to a question of where to place our trust.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p14" guid="a4a34701-ca14-43d7-89c4-c325faceb019" pid="ak1JkWwf7k-VkRihrfQUnQ" hash="9vp5mw">I have been privileged to know some of the ablest men on earth—men of many faiths, many professions, many accomplishments, in nearly 150 countries. But I’ve never known a man who knew enough that I was willing to trust him with my everlasting life.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p15" guid="058c88ad-40c2-4a38-ad45-8b1ea6e69827" pid="k8VVmg8Gx0Sf4rza8znQ_g" hash="9Ur1-Q">Sometimes people quibble about the meaning of scripture and rationalize and justify themselves in doing things they well know they shouldn’t do. They sometimes say, for example, that “Thou shalt not commit adultery” doesn’t include all the other kinds and degrees of immoral sins and perversions, or that the Word of Wisdom, for example, doesn’t catalogue all the substances and brand names and all the products and dope and harmful things that have been discovered or concocted that are not good for men.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p16" guid="90ca6de6-e57a-4aa4-ad3a-41bec6e5e3fb" pid="JV1ZAE3XE0WvbAsnmqyezw" hash="MDIeRg">Obviously, all of them couldn’t be catalogued. In the words of King Benjamin: “And finally, I cannot tell you all the things whereby ye may commit sin; for there are divers ways and means, even so many that I cannot number them.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.29" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:29</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p17" guid="686f1235-5be6-4064-8848-bea0059aaec4" pid="p-CsRGRO3km0eP8nbouBQA" hash="1_MMKw">The Lord expects us to use wisdom and common sense and not quibble about what obviously isn’t good for the body or mind or spirit or morals of man. And before doing or partaking of anything, stop and ask honestly, “Does this contribute to health? Does it contribute to happiness? Would this please God? Will this bless and benefit me and others, or does it drag me down? Is it good or isn’t it?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p18" guid="e41bcd01-9008-4579-a13c-09282db9be81" pid="Omt1pdjoHEav1y1J1K8oQA" hash="f9wm4g">It doesn’t matter what people <span class="emphasis">call </span>things. It matters what they <span class="emphasis">are</span>—what they <span class="emphasis">do.</span> If I may modify Shakespeare considerably: Anything by any name will still be what it is and will still do what it does no matter what you call it.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p19" guid="32228d22-f8d2-4549-a625-4be520715ab9" pid="EkOmUAad-USHvJTulAHe3A" hash="tz6A8Q">And if anyone doubts that all forms of moral infraction and perversion are not condemned by scripture, may we assure you that there are scriptures that could be cited for you that prohibit all evils, all impurities and perversions, all uncleanness and excesses, all unwise habits and unbecoming conduct.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p20" guid="fd5d9698-9fac-4856-b230-f64dc2f522ec" pid="ya2CWfiecEKpNFWkJuoN4Q" hash="qnNTmA">Why quibble? Why not simply accept the facts and be honest with ourselves?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p21" guid="8747ddf1-a35b-4f82-979f-76dae905ab41" pid="PzvRKxspWk-ndcu0yF0Y1g" hash="w7d79A">“… fear God, and keep his commandments: for this is the whole duty of man.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/eccl/12.13" class="scriptureRef">Eccl. 12:13</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p22" guid="b3b69a16-e9d9-43bd-a51b-0b5f9fd241b1" pid="M9tbHND6_EGBqgLibCIvPQ" hash="X-pBOw">“If ye love me,” said our Savior, “keep my commandments.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.15" class="scriptureRef">John 14:15</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p23" guid="63f195ef-cb96-4f23-b1b2-64cb1d52fa29" pid="ti_ib8LovEycYtOilrh3QA" hash="h6eeWw">But we ought also to keep the commandments simply as a favor to ourselves.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p24" guid="d83c5acf-5a63-453d-8c90-a32ec1a0dd73" pid="_guzb-Xoe0iLkXEzveARvw" hash="PQlsFQ">Many years ago Emerson wrote an essay, “Compensation,” in which he said:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p25" guid="109be0d1-cb18-45a1-ab2f-b808028ed217" pid="6iXyc8_9LE6kJk9lKedUcw" hash="ObuK7A">“The world looks like a multiplication-table, or a mathematical equation, which, turn it how you will, balances itself. … Every secret is told, every crime is punished, every virtue rewarded, every wrong redressed, in silence and certainty. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p26" guid="9b2d01e4-bcf1-470f-be01-1b554ae4117c" pid="nDsBAI_yxEOCAhZGP1aRsw" hash="_7Ld8Q">“Cause and effect, means and ends, seed and fruit, cannot be severed; for the effect already blooms in the cause, … the fruit in the seed. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p27" guid="aaef773b-5d79-43bb-8b2e-acd2cd5bd3b4" pid="co5wRSH0KUiq53iqlAbyhA" hash="KZzV3w">“What will you have? quoth God; pay for it and take it. … Thou shalt be paid exactly for what thou hast done, no more, no less. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p28" guid="679c932f-65f3-4d9a-a196-4fa6990d24b8" pid="Cmu9LuqUSkCL2FVHn7HQlg" hash="ukyjnw">“A man cannot speak but he judges himself. … Every opinion reacts on him who utters it. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p29" guid="f850b0df-c939-49c7-a6f5-83fc14d23b8b" pid="WYZJAXQjr0Ge3F9kf42MVQ" hash="FkyhUw">“You cannot do wrong without suffering wrong. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p30" guid="cd203ae9-14c0-4bdf-afd3-1e73ad4ae3c6" pid="bFus08rwmkOVMPlEtaNvgw" hash="5KBZ_g">“The thief steals from himself. The swindler swindles himself. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p31" guid="098ed846-2c93-4898-8b50-d1d421785532" pid="mPe8InpHc06NmFUHFlJfOA" hash="XxSgUQ">“… it is impossible to get anything without its price. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p32" guid="83b4930e-1c10-4525-87aa-8a3fb7892458" pid="2r24gXxPXUa2z4uCCog-IQ" hash="6dn57Q">“Commit a crime, and it seems as if a coat of snow fell on the ground, such as reveals in the woods the track of every partridge and fox and squirrel and mole. You cannot recall the spoken word, you cannot wipe out the foot-track, you cannot draw up the ladder, so as to leave no inlet or clew.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p33" guid="6cd14391-7cf7-40f5-9b16-ae0207171955" pid="PGaswR-1gEaeWOQ4onhyGw" hash="M82wGg">“… we gain the strength of the temptation we resist. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p34" guid="714a7d38-d861-46eb-a8cb-200bac30e445" pid="lmYfIiKpy0GrGiXMqClWog" hash="022qFw">“Men suffer all their life long under the foolish superstition that they can be cheated. But it is … impossible for a man to be cheated by anyone but himself. …”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p35" guid="b9e7913c-573e-4116-a04e-447f9c330e21" pid="oWUr2R4tSECwJAjcJTaf-Q" hash="yT7G5w">I heard from President Lee a very short sentence that said essentially what Emerson said, that there are no successful sinners. It is a remarkable sentence to contemplate.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p36" guid="403c4713-644c-4906-aca3-ce88ea2c16f5" pid="jOUAqwX-Eki7QXVqbAKNQQ" hash="2Py8Lw">Since there is a law of compensation that is built into life, we ought always to take time to stop and look and consider what we do, and fail to do, and what we will wish we had done.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p37" guid="0ec0333b-77cb-463d-b189-f2616f80bb9e" pid="dNZkjxE76kKiuPx1eDvtig" hash="xCh9TA">Now this to our youth: There are persuasive people who will tell you that the commandments of God are not valid, that there are no serious consequences for breaking them.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p38" guid="3de37bb7-031b-4c26-82b8-293db89eb5a7" pid="LLG1WGEp8kqBq1Vke4-Bdw" hash="1dMy4A">But if you want a guideline to know whom to follow, who’s telling the truth, ask yourself always, “Is what this person is telling me or tempting me to do something that will bring me happiness and peace and lead me to my highest possibilities, or is it something that will lead me to the baser side?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p39" guid="3903182c-34f0-44d9-a65c-aaf978899509" pid="TbwT8EISeEKLLazkXc5dag" hash="UXAGEw">Don’t follow anyone who will endeavor to destroy ideals, reject the commandments, or lead you to lower levels.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p40" guid="8dbcc5ba-b1f8-45f8-bcd3-10ed6a62231e" pid="9yOkcDvRX0eILrvhFOqaoQ" hash="eM_c3w">I heard a question once asked by President [Hugh B.] Brown: “Do you want to repent or to rationalize?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p41" guid="fbe5b189-6fd0-4ed3-947e-f994ad282d2f" pid="8ky5sQOpEUKyc6MegxMd6A" hash="f2WGlg">To quote a sentence from Cromwell: “I beseech you, … Think it possible that you may be mistaken.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p42" guid="318e20a5-b772-4172-8f6c-ed410c6e6067" pid="PguTP-TNVkKrJJN5ugDa1Q" hash="ue48rw">Anyone is mistaken if what he is doing would lead him down physically, mentally, or morally, if it would destroy his peace, or estrange him from his Father in heaven, or impair his everlasting life.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p43" guid="b884c47f-44f4-4288-8f00-0c633cab0ff7" pid="2ce2MVkIaUySTCHJtLYFpQ" hash="g99F3g">“Pride,” said John Ruskin, “is at the bottom of all great mistakes.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p44" guid="69495a4f-db84-410b-b1d7-382714290177" pid="VkUlQjsT90ClQa8swLV5dg" hash="tlpx4Q">At least, pride is one of the principal barriers to repentance, because we can’t correct an error without first admitting a mistake.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p45" guid="f2ed6dc2-576a-40c8-a274-817826734044" pid="Mf8maibmME6eP6IqtmZY2g" hash="N6PJ3Q">God bless you, my beloved young friends, and be with you and give you the humility to overcome pride, to admit and correct mistakes.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p46" guid="b1d1b2a3-96ab-4597-b2f4-f23ce257168d" pid="-GGOJA1blUKpaLswEmp80g" hash="Lf0rgg">Respect parents. Confide in them. Respect yourselves. Respect God and the knowledge he has given. Don’t gamble with life. It is all we have.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p47" guid="fe512292-c343-4b54-9158-1fc988246172" pid="h5idc-33NE2cCvVvz4sKPw" hash="bVczbg">Don’t tempt temptation. Don’t foolishly see how close you can come to danger or evil, how close you can come to a precipice. Stay away from what you shouldn’t do or where you shouldn’t go, or what you shouldn’t partake of.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p48" guid="319510d2-ab1d-450d-8ef1-e40593e0ba22" pid="YnIInC21zkStI2MBZXz8Ew" hash="X4sa5A">And if you’ve turned toward some dead-end or down some wrong road, turn back as quickly as you can—not later than right now—and thank God for the principle of repentance.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p49" guid="e5293223-23e1-4443-b6c2-66fc9ab340e2" pid="2eYbT2yW8EaJuUGo7kEKxg" hash="6SKHhg">Don’t run aimlessly looking to and fro for what has already been found. Don’t live by the sophistries and temptations of these times.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p50" guid="c1637137-a827-4a3e-848e-fa57b82efbf4" pid="sq5af-O5EUSKkssLoX3JIQ" hash="Lxnr8w">Don’t tamper with the degrading soul- and body-destroying things of life. Don’t deliberately look less than your best, or grubby or unclean, physically or morally.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p51" guid="9dbde610-d2fb-402f-b3e5-90e11b465ea7" pid="LBxYauYaJUa4CyVTkVhojg" hash="oKGhPQ">Parents, set before your children an example of honesty and honor and cleanliness and righteousness and dedication to duty.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p52" guid="eb8ecb32-1c83-43d0-a381-d0c069ced17d" pid="b4I7IecuTEm5UY38P6NeUQ" hash="_zUKrw">Children, love and respect your parents. They’ve given you life. They’d die for you. Families, draw closer together, in love and kindness, preserving the home, building traditions that will make you proud of each other and grateful to belong and be what you are.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p53" guid="e7930cc8-7c54-4b0e-81f8-d96eb9c64691" pid="-Fm-EIK5nUer174wC-bvtA" hash="DBgu9Q">Should the commandments be rewritten? No, they should be reread and become the guide and standard of our lives, if we want health and happiness and peace and self-respect.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p54" guid="c9122645-0b5b-4db2-aa63-824767498649" pid="FKSFIzh2j0K_XP7flHP1bQ" hash="tiFWQA">I remember the words of a beloved stake president, and I thank him for the thought he left with me some months ago. He said, “I used to ride the range with my father, looking for lost sheep or cattle. And as we would mount a ridge we would look off into a distant hollow or a clump of trees, and my father would say, ‘There they are.’” But this stake president said, “My father could see farther than I could, and often I couldn’t see them. But I knew they were there because my father said so.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten.p55" guid="e0c92dc5-fb74-4633-8726-49cbb43cad9f" pid="nBw1G4gj8U2Gi5JLurzXRA" hash="6haARQ">There are many things, my beloved brethren and sisters, that I know and you know are there, because our Father said so. And I know that he lives, that he made us in his image, that he sent his divine Son, our Savior, to show us the way of life and redeem us from death. I know that he will enter into our lives as fully as we let him, and that his church and gospel and way of life are on earth and here with us, and that we will realize our highest possibilities if we accept the counsels God has given, and that we will fall somewhat, somewhere short of what we might have been, or might have had, if we run contrary to his commandments. God bless you and be with you always, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/10/should-the-commandments-be-rewritten</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1971-general-conference/1971-10-2010-elder-richard-l-evans-64k-eng.mp3" length="15750185" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 1971 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
