<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Richard J. Maynes</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Richard J. Maynes.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Richard%20J.%20Maynes.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Richard J. Maynes.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1997 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1997 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>A Celestial Connection to Your Teenage Years</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years?lang=eng</link>
      <description>If you want to become the person the Lord wants you to be, you had better work on it today, because it is a true principle that we become what we do.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_97911_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="Jk-pmw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="_mIw4swq60eZh_Q7FvmISQ" hash="JGV0vQ">A Celestial Connection to Your Teenage Years</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="u8ljopD6N0i_ULfJUXLHWA" hash="wBuf9g">Richard J. Maynes</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="ORuZT1w6yUeJ5vQB5Fr9fQ" hash="O6OqeQ">If you want to become the person the Lord wants you to be, you had better work on it today, because it is a true principle that we become what we do.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1e64.jpg" alt="Elder Richard J. Maynes" pid="M1mvfQyCNkybbjiCWyEGLA" hash="48fg3Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p1" pid="-vHprfmXnECCwBKAcGUB1g" hash="PMmJ8g">Brothers and sisters, this afternoon I would like to direct my message toward the young men and young women who are growing up in these troubled times. Many of you young people have established, at least in the back of your minds, lofty goals which probably include missions, education, temple marriage, successful careers, and, of course, the safe return to your Heavenly Father’s presence in the celestial kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p2" pid="PL8oGpdubUaEclwPXKOwhA" hash="mcioOA">One of the great challenges of being a teenager is successfully connecting these celestial goals with your everyday life. This is difficult because our lives are jammed so full of worldly stuff. You’re involved with schoolwork; dozens of activities which include music, dance, sports, various clubs; and, of course, many throughout the world work part-time jobs as well. Mixed in with this hectic schedule are weekend activities such as games, dances, Scouting activities, and parties. Everywhere you go you’re bombarded with temptation from peers, television, movies, and music. Wow! What an adventure!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p3" pid="LjJ42og-eEGtPID15gidHg" hash="ZyKC1A">The real trick is trying to balance the importance of what is happening next Friday night with what’s going to be happening 2, 5, or 10 years from now. You might be asking, “What does Friday night have to do with two years from now?” Well, it could have a lot to do with it, depending on where you are and what you are doing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p4" pid="dhtWf64cB0C5H7F_Ce_XFw" hash="AlTgNg">If you want to reach your potential in the future, if you want to become the person the Lord wants you to be, you had better work on it today, because it is a true principle that we become what we do. If we want to be a successful university student, we had better be successful in high school. If we want to live a celestial life in the hereafter, we had better live a celestial life here on earth. Our futures are truly connected to our past.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p5" pid="kN8eqBRsKEezu9JR9l_kcw" hash="uLJkUQ">One of the great purposes of the gospel of Jesus Christ is to teach us of our eternal potentials. The purpose of the organization of the Church of Jesus Christ is to help us reach that potential.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p6" pid="9fUbNSkRt02LlacoTGUzxg" hash="0YMktQ">It is important for you young people to recognize that the foundation of your future success, both temporally and spiritually, is being built while in your teenage years. If those years are fractured with sin and go unrepaired, then the structure of your life will be built upon a weakened foundation. Your future will be less secure and certainly more stressful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p7" pid="gDK4FlTI6kGhE8KZ21WO6w" hash="RwtLkA">We all realize that in today’s society, the family, and particularly our youth, is under assault throughout the entire world. The prophet Isaiah saw our day and that it would be a day turned upside down. This prophecy and warning is found in Isaiah 5:20–21 [<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/5.20-21" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 5:20–21</a>]:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p8" pid="VHjPEQ2sx0yQOqzuAWQojA" hash="QAR5Mg">“Woe unto them that call evil good, and good evil; that put darkness for light, and light for darkness; that put bitter for sweet, and sweet for bitter!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p9" pid="ECbFuodGjEiFiDMMjJZOtA" hash="g0_1Hg">“Woe unto them that are wise in their own eyes, and prudent in their own sight!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p10" pid="-jfGyqjTDUagO5v0aYubZA" hash="mYKBiw">As young people growing up in this upside-down world, you have quite a challenge confronting the various pressures of modern-day life. How will you make it through your teenage years spiritually prepared for your celestial future? How will you connect your celestial goals with your everyday life?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p11" pid="5cIRjdyyS0-OEjnqF05jrw" hash="UQsMag">I have yet to meet a businessman, educator, artist, or athlete who has attained a high level of excellence in their chosen field who has not successfully been able to connect the vision of their future to their everyday life. It is very likely that a goal or vision not connected to everyday life by specific action will become just another unrealized dream with nothing more than hope to support it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p12" pid="rmWxXIdZ5kac6DSVH1waCw" hash="FmTV1g">So how is it done? How do we connect our hectic daily life to these lofty celestial goals? The answer is simple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p13" pid="aEBoI7acA02xTiV2x8IWkA" hash="XSAPQg">Let’s take an example we can all relate to. Suppose you have a midterm test coming up in geometry in two weeks. One of your goals is to get an A in geometry. How do you go about reaching that goal? Do you wait until the last minute and cram the night before the test? This technique is filled with risk. Instead of truly understanding the material, the attempt is to learn enough that somehow you can make it through the test successfully. Unfortunately, instead of being totally prepared and confident about the subject, you walk into the classroom a little bit nervous, with a lot of hope that the teacher will ask you the questions which you happen to know. I have a feeling I’m not the only one here today who has experienced this uneasy feeling.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p14" pid="nRE2NMlrDU-tHKmvzTLE5w" hash="rA5l-A">Now let’s take another student who, with the same goal of attaining an A in geometry, realizes that he doesn’t want to count on the intangibles of luck and hope. So, instead of cramming, he or she sets aside a little time every day to calmly and in depth study the subject. This gives the necessary time to digest and properly understand the material. If confusion arises on any given topic, there’s plenty of time to ask the teacher for help. What’s the result from this second technique? A deeper understanding of the material? Increased self-confidence going into the test? Less reliance on hope? I think so.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p15" pid="r7B_7yRIHkyvVTo6HzT5oQ" hash="sW3B3w">Is it actually possible to go into the classroom knowing beforehand that you will get an A on the test because of your preparation? I know it is. I’ve seen it done.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p16" pid="90coZn4GAkqXTW-t-w_qzQ" hash="hvCfrQ">Therefore, if you want to get an A in the classroom, continual daily dedication is the answer. If you want to get an A in your celestial goals, the same daily technique needs to be applied.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p17" pid="xXvshTnAh0ia1uYZrL9wkw" hash="FMifmg">Young friends, it is very difficult to cram for a mission, and it is equally difficult to cram for a temple marriage. Don’t take the risk. Be wise. Prepare yourselves daily. Study the scriptures. Communicate with your Heavenly Father in prayer. Attend seminary. Keep yourselves clean and prepared. Understand that what happens on Friday night will ultimately impact your celestial future.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p18" pid="-V9apL0A9UG-hO_Fo_TReg" hash="631vag">If these seemingly little things seem tiresome, tedious, or time consuming, carry on! The little things that confound the wise also confound Satan. Remember, celestial blessings are on their way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p19" pid="eCqQHmpsxUip-2N7UAlqBA" hash="Cw6XbA">How else can you protect yourself against the pressures and evils of the world? Three hours of church on Sunday? Not likely. Just like in your studies, a concerted daily effort is the only sure way to come out victorious. The Lord wants you to succeed, and He will be with you. He will help you and support and sustain you in your time of need if you are true to His plan. If you stay close to Him on a daily basis, He will stay close to you, and you will reap untold blessings in every aspect of your life, especially the most important, the spiritual.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p20" pid="fJKnG8ANz0Ov9hOb8FIcMQ" hash="UvrJ5A">And when the day comes to enter the classroom door of the temple, you will be at peace, your conscience will be clean, your self-confidence high, and you will know in your heart that you will receive an A in the most important of all your subjects: your celestial future.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years.p21" pid="DSGJ7xwqBke-1rFMg_jGfw" hash="h4Xe1A">Young brothers and sisters, it will ultimately be your love of the Lord which will help you commit and then stay true to your celestial daily plan. I know the Lord lives and His desire and hope for us all is a celestial future. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1997/10/a-celestial-connection-to-your-teenage-years</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1997-general-conference/1997-10-2060-elder-richard-j-maynes-64k-eng.mp3" length="3759060" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1997 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Our Covenants</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The most important thing we can do in this life is to keep the promises or covenants we have made with the Lord.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030208_000_031" doc-version="2" hash="eSrIwg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="xEkYEUnzu0OmmTn8BTjkkA" hash="E06YRA">Keeping Our Covenants</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="lvIWAaaqKUKpKArQh74PmQ" hash="wBuf9g">Richard J. Maynes</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="PIwlqmfWNU6wkRio8m-JAA" hash="igj40Q">The most important thing we can do in this life is to keep the promises or covenants we have made with the Lord.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-649.jpg" alt="Elder Richard J. Maynes" pid="kOVyz1_ot0-lQ7TMnD-HBg" hash="68NiGQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p1" pid="6PuRAwvBp0uhRqxfM3E-yQ" hash="zv-zmQ">From ancient days to modern days, true disciples of Jesus Christ have understood the importance of making and keeping covenants with the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p2" pid="QYfLmvzBY0ykaC90JcJFHw" hash="adDw2g">In approximately 64 <small>B.C.</small>, the Nephite nation was living in extremely perilous times. Because of iniquity, dissensions, and intrigue, they found themselves in the most dangerous of circumstances (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/53.9" class="scriptureRef">Alma 53:9</a>). The government teetered on the brink of collapse. The war with the Lamanite nation had been ongoing for years. Nephite dissidents were leaving to join forces with the enemy. Many Nephite cities had been attacked and captured.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p3" pid="lEXfUXdoukGHgL89m9OW7w" hash="Yn-75A">In the midst of this dangerous and chaotic situation, righteous men were sought after to lead the Nephite armies—men like Moroni and Helaman. These Nephite leaders understood that their nation’s ability to defend itself was in direct proportion to their obedience to the Lord. They constantly struggled to motivate the population to remember the Lord and keep His commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p4" pid="ENGFAD34IkWpjEHBQasstw" hash="0mphLQ">At this very critical point in time, after many Nephite cities had been lost and the balance of power seemed to be shifting towards the Lamanites, a miraculous thing took place. A group of people, once Lamanites, now known as Ammonites because they were converted to the gospel of Jesus Christ through the teachings of Ammon, came forward desirous to take up arms in the defense of their newly inherited land, country, and way of life (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/53.13" class="scriptureRef">Alma 53:13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p5" pid="Rk94Ca4itEKJLte3aahimA" hash="wzjlFQ">The fathers of these Ammonite families had previously made an oath to the Lord never to take up arms again. Helaman, the Nephite prophet, counseled these men to keep their promise to the Lord (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/53.15" class="scriptureRef">Alma 53:15</a>). Helaman relates what transpired after he shared that counsel:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p6" pid="FDRyBKb-nU-DBbk9qjTZcw" hash="vkOywg">“But behold, it came to pass they had many sons, who had not entered into a covenant that they would not take their weapons of war to defend themselves against their enemies; therefore they did assemble themselves together at this time, as many as were able to take up arms, and they called themselves Nephites.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p7" pid="8hAk0VUkak-97di4yzHf0A" hash="mpsKDQ">“And they entered into a covenant to fight for the liberty of the Nephites, yea, to protect the land unto the laying down of their lives; yea, even they covenanted that they never would give up their liberty. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p8" pid="IqDGRtxPfkaTxtJGy35Big" hash="0V652Q">“Now behold, there were two thousand of those young men, who entered into this covenant and took their weapons of war to defend their country. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p9" pid="fLeeYqG6VUWoaWeiAH7gLQ" hash="74j1Xw">“And they were all young men, and they were exceedingly valiant for courage, and also for strength and activity; but behold, this was not all—they were men who were true at all times in whatsoever thing they were entrusted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p10" pid="L2Ntu7qpvkSkbFxuYWwqSw" hash="ATP2qA">“Yea, they were men of truth and soberness, for they had been taught to keep the commandments of God and to walk uprightly before him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p11" pid="Fg3yURS5AU2_cxULopxGOQ" hash="Ct2UGw">“And now it came to pass that Helaman did march at the head of his two thousand stripling soldiers, to the support of the people” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/53.16-18,20-22" class="scriptureRef">Alma 53:16–18, 20–22</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p12" pid="EegcogI3bUmMvmipahTXzQ" hash="w0untA">Helaman and his 2,000 stripling soldiers fought valiantly to protect their families and their liberty. Their entrance onto the field of battle changed the course of the war. Momentum swung back in favor of the Nephites.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p13" pid="npUXQuC8ZUmW12e2gMVCjg" hash="z-6NTQ">In a letter written to Moroni, Helaman describes the faith and courage these young men exhibited:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p14" pid="KdnIyY2Uh0CDaqjoxp1n1A" hash="25y2SA">“And now I say unto you, my beloved brother Moroni, that never had I seen so great courage, nay, not amongst all the Nephites. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p15" pid="yia0gfUrJ0C9LCR7gGP-RQ" hash="P5xWWg">“Now they never had fought, yet they did not fear death; and they did think more upon the liberty of their fathers than they did upon their lives; yea, they had been taught by their mothers, that if they did not doubt, God would deliver them” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/56.45,47" class="scriptureRef">Alma 56:45, 47</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p16" pid="6Owq27Jic02d7rEWc9je2g" hash="UQxvrA">Brothers and sisters, “they did not doubt, [and] God [did] deliver them.” In their first great battle, not one of the 2,000 was slain. After the battle, 60 more young Ammonite men joined the small army. Helaman tells us “they did obey and observe to perform every word of command with exactness; yea, and even according to their faith it was done unto them” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/57.21" class="scriptureRef">Alma 57:21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p17" pid="waXeozuzu0Sn8jSxIMv2ZA" hash="RYx3YA">The second battle in which this small army was engaged was more intense than the first. In its aftermath Helaman writes:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p18" pid="AU6xgDHLqkKoJj63XQZ2oA" hash="8taxpw">“And it came to pass that there were two hundred, out of my two thousand and sixty, who had fainted because of the loss of blood; nevertheless, according to the goodness of God, … there was not one soul of them who did perish. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p19" pid="TmdXmE6jaE2GUkjIdxtUQg" hash="LVNxpg">“And now, their preservation was astonishing to our whole army, yea, … And we do justly ascribe it to the miraculous power of God, because of their exceeding faith” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/57.25-26" class="scriptureRef">Alma 57:25–26</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p20" pid="yP7rFY_P-0CC_CzMuwvang" hash="Z7aElw">Helaman and his young stripling soldiers understood the importance of making covenants with the Lord. They were also recipients of the blessings that come to those who faithfully keep their covenants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p21" pid="HkAw7iQgbkiNEsy3gRtdLw" hash="nW0Teg">As members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, we have also taken upon ourselves sacred obligations. We have done this in the waters of baptism and in the temples of the Lord. We call these obligations <span class="emphasis">covenants.</span> Covenants are promises we make to the Lord. They are extremely sacred in nature. The most important thing we can do in this life is to keep the promises or covenants we have made with the Lord. When we keep our promises to the Lord, He allows us to progress spiritually.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p22" pid="X0jYrKKsGkG5VRmk_Ip0Jw" hash="ZMnjBA">During the past two years, Sister Maynes and I have been assigned to serve in the Philippines. We have come across many examples of Filipino families and individuals who understand and keep the covenants they have made with the Lord. Let me share with you an experience that we have had with one of these families.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p23" pid="Q7roa6EADUmLP9P3jHd1GA" hash="kW4Ehg">A few months ago I was assigned to preside at the Talisay Philippines Stake conference. During the Sunday general session, I began my talk by thanking the congregation for their reverence. While speaking, I looked down to my left and saw a very large family sitting a couple of rows back from the front of the chapel. I was impressed to point them out and use them as an example of a family who understood and lived the principle of reverence. The parents were sitting there surrounded by many, many reverent children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p24" pid="Os3LyaKOO0qnbZVjyavPFg" hash="5J8TGQ">Upon the completion of the meeting, we had the wonderful opportunity to meet the Abasanta family. The more I learned about them, the more I was impressed with the fact that they truly understood what it meant to keep covenants and live the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p25" pid="uYW_NCv2KEKSGQuIFTfIjQ" hash="xt2L_Q">Brother Lani and Sister Irenea Abasanta joined the Church 22 years ago. Together, they have had 17 children. Among the 17 children is one set of triplets. We all know that raising a family is not an easy task anywhere in the world, and the Philippines is no exception. The Abasanta family is a living example that it can be done, and it can be done in the right way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p26" pid="zo1YrAS-zEOqJjFLG0QKtA" hash="uv2BCA">The successes they have enjoyed raising their children in the Church are made manifest in many ways. A family of 19 sitting reverently through Church meetings is just one example.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p27" pid="s75FE5c5CUWs05VSD0IKkA" hash="qLBVtw">Another example is illustrated by how they work hard and how they work together to meet their everyday financial needs. Brother Abasanta works as an electrician. Sister Abasanta, with the help of her daughters, makes and sells jewelry out of their home. Together, they have succeeded in providing the necessities of life for their family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p28" pid="eQpmlomS5kiKLz3ZrtoxLA" hash="7w6x2w">Even more important than their example in supporting their large family financially is how they teach their children to live the gospel of Jesus Christ. Their regular family home evenings play an essential part in the teaching of their family. Referring to their family home evenings, Brother Abasanta explained, “First we discuss any problems we might have in the family and how we can become more united; then there is a spiritual thought or lesson; then we play games.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p29" pid="0Z2kKy-CkEWGzh9Bbua4Nw" hash="IUcFgA">At a recent family home evening, Brother Abasanta used the <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> magazine as a tool to help him teach his children not to spend so much time watching television but instead to use that time doing something of greater worth, like homework or reading the scriptures. Over the years during family home evenings the children have been taught to practice being reverent. Because their children have been taught to be reverent in their home, it is easier for them to demonstrate reverence at church on Sunday.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p30" pid="BiR4xqL5vku_4TBT8sucHQ" hash="qEOZiA">Another example of living the gospel and keeping their covenants is the priority they have given in teaching their children the importance of paying an honest and full tithing. Brother Abasanta stated: “We teach our children that the food we have is a direct result of paying tithing. When our kids have their own work, we make sure to tell them that they need to pay their tithing. It’s hard to provide for so many children, but when I pay my tithing faithfully and honestly, it’s not hard at all. We just trust in the Lord 100 percent that if we pay an honest tithing, we’ll be able to eat daily.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p31" pid="gmK730uy2UyDhUSooh9q6Q" hash="muq7sw">Remember that I mentioned that Brother and Sister Abasanta have 17 children. Now, let me tell you about the triplets. They happen to be all boys. They happen to be 19 years old. Their names are Ammon, Omni, and Omner. Yes, you guessed it. All three are serving the Lord as faithful and hard-working full-time missionaries. Ammon is serving in the Philippines Baguio Mission, Omni is serving in the Philippines Davao Mission, and Omner is serving in the Philippines Manila Mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p32" pid="b0N559F8r0-fBwbt2kcSUA" hash="poaTHA">Now I do not want you to get the impression that the Abasanta family is perfect. None of us are perfect. However, by trying their best to live the commandments and keep their covenants, the Abasanta family is able to enjoy the blessings of the Lord in their lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p33" pid="9rg-voULiUCpOH1CdZeIcg" hash="PPDDsg">Brothers and sisters, we are all looking forward to the day when we can return home to our Heavenly Father. In order to qualify for exaltation in the celestial kingdom, we must gain the trust of the Lord here on earth. We gain the trust of the Lord through earning it, and that is accomplished through our actual performance in living His gospel and keeping our covenants. In other words, we earn the trust of the Lord by doing His will.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p34" pid="mGS2C_jTVEKS4HaY7zQ5wQ" hash="p280tg">Remember when the Lord warned Joseph Smith regarding those who “draw near to me with their lips, but their hearts are far from me” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.19" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:19</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p35" pid="aRT2WvBRlkOGhaMP4faghg" hash="K4xlAg">Remember the admonition of James: “But be ye doers of the word, and not hearers only” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.22" class="scriptureRef">James 1:22</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p36" pid="a8S2t39sAkq30Jz2_UbSXw" hash="O6VWKA">Actions truly do speak louder than words. In fact, actions mean much more to the Lord than words. The Lord declared in the Doctrine and Covenants, “If thou lovest me thou shalt serve me and keep all my commandments” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.29" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:29</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p37" pid="b5dyUvVoPk22LWdbgVVeiQ" hash="jxJKrA">Helaman and his young stripling soldiers are an ancient illustration of the blessings that come to those who faithfully keep their promises to the Lord. The Abasanta family is a modern-day example of a family doing their best to keep their covenants and live the principles of the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p38" pid="WFN_hObzJkmsiRaomwdhUg" hash="czOFIg">All members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints have made promises to the Lord. We have promised to take upon ourselves the name of Jesus Christ, always remember Him, and keep His commandments (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.77" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:77</a>). Faithful members of the Church keep those promises.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants.p39" pid="Odgnx2R4yEyOez8EzjAzbg" hash="0QZ0HA">It is my prayer today that we might all recommit ourselves to do everything in our power to earn the trust of the Lord by doing His will, by living His gospel, and by keeping our covenants, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2004/10/keeping-our-covenants</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2004-general-conference/2004-10-5030-elder-richard-j-maynes-64k-eng.mp3" length="6323064" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2004 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Establishing a Christ-Centered Home</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We understand and believe in the eternal nature of the family. This understanding and belief should inspire us to do everything in our power to establish a Christ-centered home.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50028768_000_2060" doc-version="2" hash="MVvrlg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.head1">
    <h1 class="title" pid="6SzTEDcaFE22G3NPq_44Gw" hash="xxPfvA">Establishing a Christ-Centered Home</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="GetDRnrfzE-SDret3tAMYw" hash="wBuf9g">Richard J. Maynes</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="K1dFS1H78E-WQK13olQwRw" hash="1_9QFA">We understand and believe in the eternal nature of the family. This understanding and belief should inspire us to do everything in our power to establish a Christ-centered home.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p1" pid="UVtRaedB1kq11Dq0p7pDmQ" hash="pQ377A">Early on in my service as a young missionary in Uruguay and Paraguay, I realized one of the great attractions to those seeking to know more about The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints was their interest in our doctrine regarding the family. In fact, since the Restoration of the gospel of Jesus Christ, truth-seeking investigators have been drawn to the doctrine that families can be together forever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p2" pid="AX_pTM4nUkKEYZ2LwHd5UQ" hash="6TZF0w">The principle of eternal families is an essential element in Heavenly Father’s great plan for His children. Fundamental to that plan is the understanding that we have a <span class="emphasis">heavenly</span> family as well as an <span class="emphasis">earthly</span> family. The Apostle Paul teaches us that Heavenly Father is the father of our spirits:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p3" pid="fnJGuDOOtUixsGEGddDs8Q" hash="7WxaIQ">“That they should seek the Lord … and find him, …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p4" pid="xz5AmEMLM0qtoGLWTZ2kJQ" hash="ja8FXg">“For in him we live, and move, and have our being; … For we are also his offspring.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p5" pid="jc07DUzxF0eyiiFEynA-3A" hash="GAvGeA">Being offspring of a loving Heavenly Father is such a basic principle of the gospel of Jesus Christ that even our children proclaim its truth as they sing the Primary song “I Am a Child of God.” Remember the words?</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="x9citvikakKUcFaF0lz7ig" hash="Sxrctg">I am a child of God,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="jVJQHy_8K0-94p5TpLawBA" hash="A_i8KQ">And he has sent me here,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="cOKfudpFj0WzhGZWgxVCmg" hash="Iy8x2A">Has given me an earthly home</p>
          <p class="line" pid="LUnEtOiei0uqQe4BgL1nVg" hash="-jZOWw">With parents kind and dear.</p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="jsSeJFUyfEipjvAU-qaG9A" hash="-on1eA">Lead me, guide me, walk beside me,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="SMmZUOvybk6qhLfYpbY8Ow" hash="wkwinw">Help me find the way.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="C3KAtWxRBk-pxaHXeltblg" hash="bt_CJw">Teach me all that I must do</p>
          <p class="line" pid="0hxY97Iid02aKwHVONW1eQ" hash="IDVDkw">To live with him someday.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p6" pid="yBxexmmRYE6LsndHTQBNHA" hash="7fE8zg">Recognizing that we have a <span class="emphasis">heavenly</span> family helps us understand the eternal nature of our <span class="emphasis">earthly</span> families. The Doctrine and Covenants teaches us that the family is fundamental to the order of heaven: “And that same sociality which exists among us here will exist among us there, only it will be coupled with eternal glory.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p7" pid="SkApgPQzekmIAtEji0kEdw" hash="THYMIQ">Understanding the eternal nature of the family is a critical element in understanding Heavenly Father’s plan for His children. The adversary, on the other hand, wants to do everything in his power to destroy Heavenly Father’s plan. In his attempt to defeat God’s plan, he is leading an unprecedented attack on the institution of the family. Some of the more powerful weapons he uses in his attack are selfishness, greed, and pornography.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p8" pid="-pezU46EeUamvoaFcl4MKg" hash="bCxE5w">Our eternal happiness is <span class="emphasis">not</span> one of Satan’s objectives. He knows that an essential key to making men and women miserable like himself is to deprive them of family relationships which have <span class="emphasis">eternal</span> potential. Because Satan understands that true happiness in this life and in the eternities is found in the form of family, he does everything in his power to destroy it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p9" pid="fpbqMVPwHkuMGgVMoOMuUw" hash="pd3JSg">The ancient prophet Alma calls God’s plan for His children “the great plan of happiness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> The First Presidency and Quorum of the Twelve Apostles, whom we sustain as prophets, seers, and revelators, have offered us this inspired counsel with regard to happiness and family life: “The family is ordained of God. Marriage between man and woman is essential to His eternal plan. Children are entitled to birth within the bonds of matrimony, and to be reared by a father and a mother who honor marital vows with complete fidelity. Happiness in family life is most likely to be achieved when founded upon the teachings of the Lord Jesus Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p10" pid="hYIJpEi21kqe9eq5_e1puQ" hash="DH-4KQ">This happiness spoken of by Alma and more recently by the First Presidency and Quorum of the Twelve Apostles will most surely be found in the home with family. It will be found in abundance if we do everything in our power to establish a Christ-centered home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p11" pid="4bg7ogz9HkKwLWv7DKcUwQ" hash="8S27KA">Sister Maynes and I learned some important principles as we began the process of establishing a Christ-centered home early in our marriage. We started by following the counsel of our Church leaders. We brought our children together and held weekly family home evenings as well as daily prayer and scripture study. It was not always easy, convenient, or successful, but over time these simple gatherings became treasured family traditions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p12" pid="ADVd85MEuES_1kgrXWMI8g" hash="mlJa6Q">We learned that our children might not remember everything about the family home evening lesson later in the week, but they would remember that <span class="emphasis">we held it.</span> We learned that later in the day at school they would probably not remember the exact words of the scriptures or the prayer, but they would remember that we <span class="emphasis">did read</span> scriptures and we <span class="emphasis">did have</span> prayer. Brothers and sisters, there is great power and protection for us and our youth in establishing celestial traditions in the home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p13" pid="R0BqnB-JZ0-XC11nTdXE-w" hash="5dNJYA">Learning, teaching, and practicing the principles of the gospel of Jesus Christ in our homes helps create a culture where the Spirit can dwell. Through establishing these celestial traditions in our homes, we will be able to overcome the false traditions of the world and learn to put the needs and concerns of others first.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p14" pid="yVh-bBWw5keUff1lkJPiTQ" hash="KY1UUw">The responsibility for establishing a Christ-centered home lies with both parents and children. Parents are responsible to teach their children in love and righteousness. Parents will be held accountable before the Lord in how they perform their sacred responsibilities. Parents teach their children <span class="emphasis">with</span> words and <span class="emphasis">through</span> example. This poem by C. C. Miller titled “The Echo” illustrates the importance and impact parents have as they influence their children:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.f3">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="V8GeoxcYO0KCoD6fHorb0w" hash="G5HAkg">’Twas a sheep not a lamb</p>
          <p class="line" pid="8cUsPQ3BskSGzo6vzkfA1g" hash="zOicig">That strayed away in the parable Jesus told,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="2MN5HDO8lkSenTmqpItP2g" hash="Y2Lcsg">A grown-up sheep that strayed away</p>
          <p class="line" pid="gpMTouRNjkG9aeHY-1vrJA" hash="u8wjfw">From the ninety and nine in the fold.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="7hEbWWzXoUm749HUzHOSVA" hash="Ae5wTg">And why for the sheep should we seek</p>
          <p class="line" pid="0qEZ4wxCAUKrsotff7y0TQ" hash="0dLgaw">And earnestly hope and pray?</p>
          <p class="line" pid="qILuV_vfnUSZNblx9WK-_w" hash="aGVUiw">Because there is danger when sheep go wrong:</p>
          <p class="line" pid="fLwYeilbjUGKClyVVEwiJQ" hash="nCmKFA">They lead the lambs astray.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="-ttuc3sqjEqy50AuKq0HsQ" hash="jhF92Q">Lambs will follow the sheep, you know,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="ZBf_CKHbkkCl9b3J-bCZqg" hash="1RHe9A">Wherever the sheep may stray.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="kOfcRjXF80-kvUDcOJE3jw" hash="KIaSpA">When sheep go wrong,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="FcbkO2br5EqQndRg5rdnDA" hash="-6Pxcg">It won’t take long till the lambs are as wrong as they.</p>
          <p class="line" pid="07Du_RTw0k66aO8xS4uyIg" hash="YHAldg">And so with the sheep we earnestly plead</p>
          <p class="line" pid="4dhtj5MvM0-zWjfEkPJv3w" hash="xNMuaA">For the sake of the lambs today,</p>
          <p class="line" pid="vxiNcAveiU6AlkMNKtTcUg" hash="MiJFeg">For when the sheep are lost</p>
          <p class="line" pid="lH1nBDJ6rEe6D-6AS0E72g" hash="ZXSCow">What a terrible cost</p>
          <p class="line" pid="4szm209kxEuJLbJPno63yA" hash="UB8tLA">The lambs will have to pay.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p15" pid="wJJBF4aNSk2SyHQ9xYRStg" hash="Ih_Dmg">The consequences to parents who lead their children astray are laid before us by the Lord in the Doctrine and Covenants: “And again, inasmuch as parents have children in Zion … that teach them <span class="emphasis">not</span> to understand the doctrine of repentance, faith in Christ the Son of the living God, and of baptism and the gift of the Holy Ghost by the laying on of the hands, … the sin be upon the heads of the parents.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p16" pid="cqGXU87FaUisP4wh4MiZcA" hash="nTM1Mg">It is difficult to overstate the importance parents have in teaching their children celestial traditions through word and example. Children also play an important role in establishing a Christ-centered home. Let me share with you a short talk recently given by Will, my eight-year-old grandson, that illustrates this principle:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p17" pid="YRiCZ-UO_kWjE-mau2ui5Q" hash="iAuYQA">“I like to ride horses and go roping with my dad. A rope has different strands woven together to make it strong. If a rope had only one strand, it wouldn’t be able to get the job done. But because there are more strands that work together, we are able to use it in many different ways and it is strong.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p18" pid="vN_feXPy5Ua-GFL80yxSfA" hash="cn1dIA">“Families can be like ropes. When only one person is working hard and doing what is right, the family will not be as strong as when everyone is putting forth the effort to help each other.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p19" pid="sTXh5G4sUUW5cbTphlfu_Q" hash="80uiLw">“I know that when I do what is right, I am helping my family. When I am treating my sister, Isabelle, nicely, we both have fun and it makes my mom and dad happy. If my mom needs to do something, I can help her by playing with my little brother, Joey. I also can help my family by keeping my room clean and helping out whenever I can with a good attitude. Since I am the oldest child in my family, I know being a good example is important. I can try my best to choose the right and follow the commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p20" pid="-IPNaDhk9Em3sVK4Q4fRYQ" hash="tZh0nA">“I know that kids can help their families be strong like a strong rope. When everyone does their best and works together, families can be happy and strong.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p21" pid="dLqcKUWXP0u32aH1GsaHfw" hash="ct6XXQ">When parents preside over the family in love and righteousness and teach their children the gospel of Jesus Christ <span class="emphasis">by</span> word and <span class="emphasis">through</span> example, and when children love and support their parents by learning and practicing the principles their parents teach, the result will be the establishment of a Christ-centered home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home.p22" pid="pbKFfB5_HEuSHux3O3SbrA" hash="u4Gmtg">Brothers and sisters, as members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, we understand and believe in the eternal nature of the family. This understanding and belief should inspire us to do everything in our power to establish a Christ-centered home. I bear you my testimony that as we strive to do this, we will more fully practice the love and service that was exemplified through the life and Atonement of our Savior, Jesus Christ, and as a result, our homes can truly feel like heaven on earth. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/04/establishing-a-christ-centered-home</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2011-general-conference/2011-04-2060-elder-richard-j-maynes-64k-eng.mp3" length="5263253" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Strength to Endure</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Our ability to endure to the end in righteousness will be in direct proportion to the strength of our testimony and the depth of our conversion.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10791_000_44maynes" doc-version="6" hash="GKXf3g">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="zqgF7lK_I0KusZX57tOvVA" hash="yoj_7A">The Strength to Endure</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="gQIxpdNb2Eai_cOQ7DrIUw" hash="EyYbpg">By Elder Richard J. Maynes</p>
		<p class="kicker" pid="mtA_l7qRdE2W8JSCvc_uRQ" hash="6NkUqw">Our ability to endure to the end in righteousness will be in direct proportion to the strength of our testimony and the depth of our conversion.</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="Fa-Qli9rjk2cmmPEecIdlw" hash="B_mcgg">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p5" pid="Gp6Xgv4hLU61GV_flopC8Q" hash="geXmfQ"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="79"></span>Every morning when we wake up, we face a new day filled with the challenges of life. These challenges come in many forms: physical challenges, financial setbacks, difficulties with relationships, emotional trials, and even struggles with one’s faith.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p6" pid="gmnS2PThSkW2UN84WoWg5Q" hash="6FevCg">Many of the challenges we face in life can be solved and overcome; however, others may be difficult to understand and impossible to overcome and will be with us until we pass on to the next life. As we temporarily endure the challenges we can solve and as we continue to endure the challenges we cannot solve, it is important to remember that the spiritual strength we develop will help us successfully endure all the challenges we face in life.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p7" pid="Gx00MoC-hkO7ioZNoT3wFA" hash="yWE5lQ">Brothers and sisters, we have a loving Heavenly Father who has designed our earthly existence so that we can individually learn the lessons we need to learn to qualify for eternal life in His presence.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p8" pid="0JS6zDVDhUi9u5RhJFOqNg" hash="g84dCw">An episode in the life of the Prophet Joseph Smith illustrates this principle. The Prophet and several companions had been prisoners in Liberty, Missouri, for months. While suffering in jail, the Prophet Joseph pled with the Lord in humble prayer that the Saints might be relieved from their current suffering. The Lord responded by teaching the Prophet Joseph, and all of us, that the challenges we face, if successfully endured, will be for our ultimate good. This is the Lord’s response to Joseph’s petition:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p9" pid="mvqarIgYjUCcxrTCyATjWA" hash="j14rSQ">“My son, peace be unto thy soul; thine adversity and thine afflictions shall be but a small moment;</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p10" pid="GcnJnp5ct0G_xj-tHq1jfQ" hash="N8j8pw">“And then, if thou endure it well, God shall exalt thee on high.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p11" pid="omX6LFyOR0mZ8Vw4NQgR6g" hash="hss6Ww">Heavenly Father has organized our journey through life to be a test of our character. We are exposed to both good and evil influences and then given the moral agency to choose for ourselves which path we will take. As the ancient Book of Mormon prophet Samuel taught, “Ye are free; ye are permitted to act for yourselves; for behold, God hath given unto you a knowledge and he hath made you free.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p12" pid="N7YAeSx4FEyoxWCMPzWEuA" hash="_x7kaQ">Heavenly Father also understood that due to our mortality we would not always make the correct or righteous choice. Because we are not perfect and because we make mistakes, we need help in returning to His presence. The necessary help is provided through the teachings, example, and atoning sacrifice of Jesus Christ. The Savior’s atoning sacrifice makes possible our future salvation and exaltation through the principle of repentance. If we honestly and sincerely repent, the Atonement can help us become clean, change our nature, and successfully endure our challenges.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p13" pid="zALnlRoWQE-0Zw97pNjM9A" hash="RN5McA">Endurance is an important principle found within the doctrine of Jesus Christ. It is important because the quality of our eternal future is proportional to our ability to endure in righteousness.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p14" pid="DMr-R6b0GUG-bCsurKFynw" hash="az-jkg">In <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 31</a> the prophet Nephi teaches us that after we receive the same saving ordinance of baptism that Jesus Christ received and then receive the gift of the Holy Ghost, we must “press forward, feasting upon the word of Christ, and endure to the end, [and then] behold, thus saith the Father: [We] shall have eternal life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p15" pid="IDN8jGOBtEi31nUmYOw8Rw" hash="YbXqnw">Therefore, in order to receive the greatest of all the blessings of our Heavenly Father, which is eternal life, we must complete the appropriate ordinance work and then continue to keep the associated covenants. In other words, we must successfully endure.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p16" pid="qs8G4h2-vUaMbd6FIkHZVA" hash="mlifWw">Our ability to endure to the end in righteousness will be in direct proportion to the strength of our testimony and the depth of our conversion. When our testimonies are strong and we are truly converted to the gospel of Jesus Christ, our choices will be inspired by the Holy Ghost, they will be Christ-centered, and they will support our desire to endure in righteousness. If our testimonies are weak and our conversion superficial, the risk is much greater that we will be enticed by the false traditions of the world to make poor choices.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p17" pid="kpGIvcuaUEa1WSx8F2wRRg" hash="qzOJuA">I would like to share an experience that illustrates the effort required to endure physically and then compare it to the effort required to endure <span class="pageBreak" page-number="80"></span>spiritually. Upon returning from my mission, I had the opportunity to play basketball for a well-respected coach and author at a college in California. This coach was very serious about his players being in shape before the start of the basketball season. One of his training prerequisites before any of us could touch a basketball on the practice court was to run a cross-country course in the hills near the school in a specific and very aggressive time. I remember my very first attempt at running this cross-country course immediately upon my return from the mission field: I thought I was going to die.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p18" pid="O2I3TigvuEesUMxwms2gTg" hash="B8B9-g">It took weeks of serious training in order to finally beat the time that the coach set as a goal. It was a great feeling to not only be able to run the course but also to accelerate down the stretch to the finish line.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p19" pid="SOylWMatW06TTB2FHufLJQ" hash="DiMI6w">To play basketball successfully, you need to get into good shape. Being in good physical condition comes at a price, and that price is dedication, perseverance, and self-discipline. Spiritual endurance also comes at a price. It is the same price: dedication, perseverance, and self-discipline.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p20" pid="6MmFYEjHAUiNkSFAYrcsQQ" hash="RNf8sA">A testimony, like your body, needs to be in shape if you want it to endure. So how do we keep our testimonies in shape? We cannot get our bodies into good basketball shape by simply watching basketball on television. Similarly, we won’t be able to get our testimonies in shape by simply watching general conference on television. We need to study and learn the fundamental principles of the gospel of Jesus Christ, and then we must do our very best to live them. That is how we become disciples of Jesus Christ, and that is how we build an enduring testimony.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p21" pid="jW-jyncUO0uNiEhMscUiyQ" hash="Houleg">When we face adversity in life and our desire is to emulate the attributes of Jesus Christ, it is essential to be spiritually prepared. Being spiritually prepared means we have developed spiritual stamina or strength—we will be in good shape spiritually. We will be in such good shape spiritually that we will consistently choose the right. We will become immovable in our desire and ability to live the gospel. As an anonymous author once said, “You must become the rock the river cannot wash away.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p22" pid="y7TotrnbN0aWAHlQaXpOuQ" hash="C-Pg2w">Because we face challenges every day, it is important that we work on our spiritual stamina every day. When we develop spiritual stamina, the false traditions of the world, as well as our personal daily challenges, will have little negative impact on our ability to endure in righteousness.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p23" pid="fZpb3fq7TkKv7s96z7xKAw" hash="94n-nw">Great examples of spiritual stamina come from our own family histories. Among the many stories from our ancestors, we will be able to find examples that demonstrate the positive characteristics of endurance.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p24" pid="PCKRmzKSY0GKVndl2qwRZQ" hash="p9K-yw">A story from my own family history illustrates this principle. My great-grandfather Joseph Watson Maynes was born in 1856 in Hull, Yorkshire, England. His family joined the Church in England and then made their way to Salt Lake City. He married Emily Keep in 1883, and they became the parents of eight children. Joseph was called to serve a full-time mission in June of 1910, when he was 53 years old. With the support of his wife and eight children, he returned to his native England to serve his mission.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p25" pid="dTeyNbkRd0qGpzDZ41t4BQ" hash="B9nanQ"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="81"></span>After serving faithfully for approximately two years, he was riding his bicycle along with his companion to Sunday School services in Gloucester, England, when his tire burst. He got off his bicycle to assess the damage. When he saw that it was serious and would take a while to fix, he told his companion to go ahead and begin the Sunday service and he would be there shortly. Just as he finished saying this, he collapsed to the ground. He had died suddenly of a heart attack.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p26" pid="pOIxvs4eTkaMp0M3u3RhEA" hash="2wlFfQ">Joseph Watson Maynes never saw his wife and eight children again in this life. They were able to transport his body back to Salt Lake City and have his funeral service at the old Waterloo Assembly Hall. A statement made at his funeral service by Elder Anthony W. Ivins of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles teaches us an important lesson about life, death, and endurance: “This is what the gospel gives us—not immunity from death, but victory over it through the hope we have in a glorious resurrection. … It applies to [Joseph Maynes]. … It is a pleasure, and it is a satisfaction and joy to know that men lay down their lives in righteousness, in the faith, true to the faith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p27" pid="1D6fJSsCCkSEk8G33wBszg" hash="ZLGaEQ">This family story inspires me to try my very best to follow the example of endurance and spiritual stamina illustrated by my great-grandfather. I am equally inspired by the faith of his wife, Emily, whose life after Joseph’s death was certainly a heavy burden to bear. Her testimony was strong and her conversion complete as she spent the rest of her life true to the faith while supporting her eight children on her own.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p28" pid="yi96W79D0EWxvwG903zZ2Q" hash="eMqpww">The Apostle Paul stated, “Let us lay aside every weight, and the sin which doth so easily beset us, and let us run with patience the race that is set before us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> The race that is set before us on this earth is an endurance race filled with obstacles. The obstacles in this race are the challenges we wake up to each morning. We are here on earth to run the race, to exercise our moral agency, and to choose between right and wrong. In order to honorably and successfully finish the race and return to our Heavenly Father, we will need to pay the price of dedication, perseverance, and self-discipline. We need to get into spiritual shape. We need to develop spiritual stamina. We need strong testimonies that will lead to true conversion, and as a result we will find within ourselves the inner peace and strength needed to endure whatever challenges we may face.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p29" pid="VtbpHBhlSUekrIAp29gDWg" hash="LcCtgw">So whatever challenges you wake up to each morning, remember—with the spiritual strength you develop, coupled with the Lord’s help, at the end of the race you will be able to enjoy the confidence that the Apostle Paul expressed when he said:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p30" pid="m4mJgHB_zEmbwAkytcA9zQ" hash="IYlYNg">“For I am now ready to be offered, and the time of my departure is at hand.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p31" pid="Oot2y4LiDECMCOJOKmX6Bg" hash="PYl1-g">“I have fought a good fight, I have finished my course, I have kept the faith:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p32" pid="s_LcTMSOwEiA-hoEXSMIFA" hash="EZLi4g">“Henceforth there is laid up for me a crown of righteousness, which the Lord, the righteous judge, shall give me at that day.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure.p33" pid="Zl2GWYEq80uhmO52imgtrw" hash="onCwAg">I bear you my testimony and my witness of the reality of a loving Heavenly Father and His great and eternal plan of happiness, which has brought us to this earth at this time. May the Spirit of the Lord inspire us all to develop within ourselves the strength to endure. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2013/10/the-strength-to-endure</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2013-general-conference/2013-10-4040-elder-richard-j-maynes-64k-eng.mp3" length="6295079" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Joy of Living a Christ-Centered Life</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Maynes explains how living a Christ-centered life will help us have peace, happiness, and joy even when we face adversity.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13768_000_23maynes" doc-version="5" hash="RIEY-Q">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="jpPT_Wsjk0iG9CbFK7YYsA" hash="9bOCVw">The Joy of Living a Christ-Centered Life</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p2" pid="5lzwR8eUxEi0QyTn_Y3j8A" hash="EyYbpg">By Elder Richard J. Maynes</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p3" pid="xK2iA6Tp40KcGb-MKKEtDw" hash="hptprg">Of the Presidency of the Seventy</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=2Z0_Yvh9jU2k96JPZuW8AQ"><img xmlns="" alt="Elder Richard J. Maynes" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255552/d3db3d36f449412694def39d15f0bf04/100x125.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x62="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255552/d3db3d36f449412694def39d15f0bf04/50x62.jpg" data-src-100x125="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255552/d3db3d36f449412694def39d15f0bf04/100x125.jpg" data-src-200x251="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255552/d3db3d36f449412694def39d15f0bf04/200x251.jpg" data-src-320x401="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255552/d3db3d36f449412694def39d15f0bf04/320x401.jpg" data-src-460x577="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255552/d3db3d36f449412694def39d15f0bf04/460x577.jpg" data-src-640x803="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255552/d3db3d36f449412694def39d15f0bf04/640x803.jpg" data-src-1024x1285="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255552/d3db3d36f449412694def39d15f0bf04/1024x1285.jpg" data-src-2048x2571="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255552/d3db3d36f449412694def39d15f0bf04/2048x2571.jpg" data-src-3144x3948="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255552/d3db3d36f449412694def39d15f0bf04/3144x3948.jpg" pid="2Z0_Yvh9jU2k96JPZuW8AQ" hash="mcG1QQ"></img></a>
		</div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="Hbee115vl0qAs5sYfjHrBw" hash="9MXK-g">Our lives must be centered with exactness in Christ if we are to find true joy and peace in this life.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="F9Wh-NzWP066JN8GhmbS9g" hash="wBuf9g">Richard J. Maynes</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p5" pid="1uKd_rKOOUWYCtTRCwPypw" hash="y9aoZg">The world in which we live is putting great pressure on good people everywhere to lower or even abandon their standards of righteous living. However, despite the evils and temptations that surround us each day, we can and will find true joy today in living a Christ-centered life.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p6" pid="uFT03pbpk0itKqxT89sh_w" hash="iMnnzg">Centering our lives in Jesus Christ and His gospel will bring stability and happiness to our lives, as the following examples illustrate.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p7" pid="JVwzjA-PhUON1_O2zcgMpg" hash="sIyCqA">Elder Taiichi Aoba of the Seventy, who resides in a small mountain village in Shikoku, Japan, was asked to teach a class at a youth conference. “Stand Ye in Holy Places” was selected as the theme of the conference. After considering the theme and what to teach, Elder Aoba decided to use his vocation as a teaching tool. His work is making pottery.</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=VFhUgNittkeMCaZZBoxPTA"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579906/b9a1975fedea4caf98d0900a33d69e15/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579906/b9a1975fedea4caf98d0900a33d69e15/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579906/b9a1975fedea4caf98d0900a33d69e15/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579906/b9a1975fedea4caf98d0900a33d69e15/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579906/b9a1975fedea4caf98d0900a33d69e15/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579906/b9a1975fedea4caf98d0900a33d69e15/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579906/b9a1975fedea4caf98d0900a33d69e15/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579906/b9a1975fedea4caf98d0900a33d69e15/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579906/b9a1975fedea4caf98d0900a33d69e15/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579906/b9a1975fedea4caf98d0900a33d69e15/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Elder Aoba creating pottery with youth" pid="VFhUgNittkeMCaZZBoxPTA" hash="U8Vxgw"></img></a>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p8" pid="J_Aya4hFjUKZVc2-mt6okQ" hash="OnxYOQ">Elder Aoba relates that his classroom of youth really sprang to life when they saw how he was able to almost magically transform the shape of the clay in his hands to plates, bowls, and cups. After his demonstration, he asked them if any of them would like to give it a try. They all raised their hands.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p9" pid="KWWWaS1AXkqKt-YkC5WJqA" hash="499XbQ">Elder Aoba had several of the youth come forward to try out their new interest. They assumed, after watching him, that this would be quite simple. However, none of them were successful in their attempts to make even a simple bowl. They proclaimed: “I can’t do this!” “Why is this so hard?” “This is so difficult.” These comments took place as the clay flew all around the room.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p10" pid="50sV91vv3EO6vTu_EID91A" hash="uMHpRQ">He asked the youth why they were having such difficulty making pottery. They responded with various answers: “I don’t have any experience,” “I have never been trained,” or “I have no talent.” Based on the result, what they said was all true; however, the most important reason for their failure was due to the clay not being centered on the wheel. The youth thought that they had placed the clay in the center, but from a professional’s perspective, it wasn’t in the exact center. He then told them, “Let’s try this one more time.”</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=25Uyh-Y0EUSEziumZINyIQ"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579907/d53d4223f8a9441ca9a78f1ffcec3426/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579907/d53d4223f8a9441ca9a78f1ffcec3426/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579907/d53d4223f8a9441ca9a78f1ffcec3426/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579907/d53d4223f8a9441ca9a78f1ffcec3426/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579907/d53d4223f8a9441ca9a78f1ffcec3426/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579907/d53d4223f8a9441ca9a78f1ffcec3426/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579907/d53d4223f8a9441ca9a78f1ffcec3426/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579907/d53d4223f8a9441ca9a78f1ffcec3426/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579907/d53d4223f8a9441ca9a78f1ffcec3426/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1579907/d53d4223f8a9441ca9a78f1ffcec3426/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Elder Aoba creating pottery" pid="25Uyh-Y0EUSEziumZINyIQ" hash="zgIvfw"></img></a>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p11" pid="jdEbZgqX8k6JWaR9vvHreg" hash="pr7RKg">This time, Elder Aoba placed the clay in the exact center of the wheel and then started to turn the wheel, making a hole in the middle of the clay. Several of the youth tried again. This time everyone started clapping when they said: “Wow, it’s not shaking,” “I can do this,” or “I did it!” Of course, the shapes weren’t perfect, but the outcome was totally different from the first attempt. The reason for their success was because the clay was perfectly centered on the wheel.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p12" pid="lnHQAx3_qUWH322aYU4yJQ" hash="8pRFlA">The world in which we live is similar to the potter’s spinning wheel, and the speed of that wheel is increasing. Like the clay on the potter’s wheel, we must be centered as well. Our core, the center of our lives, must be Jesus Christ and His gospel. Living a Christ-centered life means we learn about Jesus Christ and His gospel and then we follow His example and keep His commandments with exactness.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p13" pid="IHUz1X8w7U2MOX6viB8_YA" hash="NhrCEg">The ancient prophet Isaiah stated, “But now, O Lord, thou art our father; we are the clay, and thou our potter; and we all are the work of thy hand.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p14" pid="ay-ESLMRDEuNnGNrWPVJdg" hash="K7wrFg">If our lives are centered in Jesus Christ, He can successfully mold us into who we need to be in order to return to His and Heavenly Father’s presence in the celestial kingdom. The joy we experience in this life will be in direct proportion to how well our lives are centered on the teachings, example, and atoning sacrifice of Jesus Christ.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p15" pid="Ta2sjJCfy0KE1f5ydXmu1A" hash="s0we1A">Brothers and sisters, I was born into a multigenerational Latter-day Saint family, so the blessings and joy of having the gospel of Jesus Christ as the basis of our family culture was woven into our everyday life. It wasn’t until my full-time mission as a young man that I realized the incredibly positive impact the fulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ has on those who have never previously experienced its blessings in their lives. This verse in Matthew reflects the process that people who are converted to the gospel of Jesus Christ experience: “The kingdom of heaven is like treasure hidden in a field, which a man found and covered up; then in his joy he goes and sells all that he has and buys that field.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p16" pid="IjGR_xxwRkyBV0lg_ijvOQ" hash="kj63lQ">Let me share with you an example from the Book of Mormon that illustrates what one convert was willing to pay in order to receive the joy associated with finding the treasure spoken of by Jesus in the parable of the treasure hidden in the field.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p17" pid="ZIMo6FNkcEyB122gqHMDsA" hash="ISz6zw">Remember in the book of <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/20.1-30" class="scriptureRef">Alma chapter 20</a>, Ammon and Lamoni were traveling to the city of Middoni for the purpose of finding and delivering Ammon’s brother Aaron out of prison. During their journey they encountered Lamoni’s father, who was the Lamanite king over all the land.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p18" pid="HWbtWkae3EOfF0V2wCViwg" hash="weGE-Q">The king was very upset that his son Lamoni was traveling with Ammon, a Nephite missionary, whom he considered an enemy. He felt that his son should have attended a great feast he had sponsored for his sons and his people. The Lamanite king was so upset that he commanded his son Lamoni to slay Ammon with his sword. When Lamoni refused, the king drew his own sword to slay his son for disobedience; however, Ammon interceded to save Lamoni’s life. He ultimately overpowered the king and could have killed him.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p19" pid="xyz_kFB7kE21Ka6ywkg4yQ" hash="7v7HpQ">This is what the king said to Ammon after finding himself in this life-and-death situation: “If thou wilt spare me I will grant unto thee whatsoever thou wilt ask, even to half of the kingdom.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p20" pid="yPH42gw_HEm-kXu8b7H-TA" hash="0goZJA">So the king was willing to pay the price of one-half his kingdom in order to spare his own life. The king must have been astonished when Ammon requested only that he release his brother Aaron and his associates from prison and that the king’s son Lamoni retain his kingdom.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p21" pid="JSlvTwenTUylEpfQoF9faQ" hash="iN4xHw">Later on, due to this encounter, Ammon’s brother Aaron was released from the Middoni prison. After his release he was inspired to travel to where the Lamanite king ruled over the land. Aaron was introduced to the king and had the privilege of teaching him the principles of the gospel of Jesus Christ, including the great plan of redemption. The teachings of Aaron inspired the king deeply.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p22" pid="06wKO7NtOU6aVpYMYCFEyA" hash="r-Uz8g">The king’s response to Aaron’s teachings is found in <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/22.15" class="scriptureRef">verse 15 of Alma chapter 22:</a> “And it came to pass that after Aaron had expounded these things unto him, the king said: What shall I do that I may have this eternal life of which thou hast spoken? Yea, what shall I do that I may be born of God, having this wicked spirit rooted out of my breast, and receive his Spirit, that I may be filled with joy, that I may not be cast off at the last day? Behold, said he, I will give up all that I possess, yea, I will forsake my kingdom, that I may receive this great joy.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p23" pid="AWUsLTkQGEaGgjhXpF8v1A" hash="WXON0g">Amazingly enough, in contrast to giving up one-half his kingdom to spare his life, the Lamanite king was now willing to give up his entire kingdom that he might receive the joy that comes from understanding, accepting, and living the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p24" pid="8K-i0YFDxEGRpBand0rawQ" hash="qq-c4g">My wife, Nancy, is also a convert to the Church. She has mentioned to me many times over the years the joy she has felt in her life since finding, accepting, and living the gospel of Jesus Christ. What follows is a reflection from Sister Maynes on her experience:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p25" pid="vF0dx81-iUSnZH_UxfcmZg" hash="qw18ig">“As a young adult in my early 20s, I was at a point in my life when I knew I needed to change something in order to be a happier person. I felt like I was adrift with no real purpose and direction, and I didn’t know where to go to find it. I had always known that Heavenly Father existed and occasionally throughout my life had said prayers, feeling that He listened.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p26" pid="XdHZuhcnv0aKWBzjoapn6Q" hash="JrZCKA">“As I began my search, I attended several different churches but would always fall back into the same feelings and discouragement. I feel very blessed because my prayer for direction and purpose in life was ultimately answered, and the fulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ was brought into my life. For the first time I felt like I had a purpose, and the plan of happiness brought real joy into my life.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p27" pid="3WQWfQsphEytpKXd-vqeNA" hash="Ec7_Vw">Another experience from the Book of Mormon clearly illustrates how living a Christ-centered life can fill us with great happiness even when we are surrounded with incredible hardships.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p28" pid="WMlmLckuzkeNn4X_LezYYg" hash="U4SSiw">After the prophet Lehi and his family left Jerusalem in 600 <span class="smallCaps">b.c.</span>, they wandered approximately eight years in the wilderness until they finally arrived in a land they called Bountiful, which was near the seashore. Nephi describes their life of tribulation in the wilderness this way: “We had suffered many afflictions and much difficulty, … even so much that we cannot write them all.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p29" pid="NwfYK4N3WUC2RxrjHki_ow" hash="VRXF-w">While living in Bountiful, Nephi was charged by the Lord with the responsibility to build the ship which would take them across the sea to the promised land. After they arrived in the promised land, great conflicts continued to arise between the people who centered their lives in Christ and the nonbelievers, who followed the examples of Laman and Lemuel. Ultimately, the risk of violence between the two groups was so great that Nephi and those who followed the teachings of the Lord separated themselves and fled into the wilderness for safety. At this point in time, some 30 years after Lehi and his family left Jerusalem, Nephi makes a well-documented and somewhat surprising statement, especially after recording in the scriptures the many afflictions and tribulations they had faced for so long. These are his words: “And it came to pass that we [did live] after the manner of happiness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Despite their hardships, they were able to live after the manner of happiness because they were centered in Christ and His gospel.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p30" pid="FX8todK4r0yHc1qBdKhNCg" hash="prfmBw">Brothers and sisters, like the clay on the potter’s wheel, our lives must be centered with exactness in Christ if we are to find true joy and peace in this life. The examples of the Lamanite king; my wife, Nancy; and the Nephite people all support this true principle.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life.p31" pid="oHxpe-uoREiqSSrsoI-v3w" hash="I1HkaQ">I bear you my witness today that we too can find that peace, that happiness, that true joy if we choose to live Christ-centered lives, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/10/the-joy-of-living-a-christ-centered-life</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2015-general-conference/2015-10-1030-elder-richard-j-maynes-64k-eng.mp3" length="5627291" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Earning the Trust of the Lord and Your Family</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Maynes teaches that earning the trust of the Lord requires us to first trust Him. Having “integrity of heart” will help us be true to our covenants.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60003502_000_43maynes" doc-version="1" hash="4-UGqA">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="rPAMLyOh90ORQq-Wc_gY_A" hash="ZaOY-Q">Earning the Trust of the Lord and Your Family</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p2" pid="vlWqvwJGnEuUiqtPhGwAHQ" hash="EyYbpg1">By Elder Richard J. Maynes</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p3" pid="5IKkylVnBUGeF_q2TN4N8Q" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="rBAxMOXjh0GUSZcVvDv0Tw" hash="iPoIkA">Men who have “integrity of heart” are men to be trusted—because trust is built on integrity.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="ej-jfQl1N0axYkWXy_Iwiw" hash="EyYbpg">By Elder Richard J. Maynes</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p5" pid="xlczZz0b80ar1DbX4OBkEg" hash="ehewkQ">Brethren, perhaps there is no greater compliment we could receive from the Lord than to know He trusts us to be worthy priesthood holders and great husbands and fathers.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p6" pid="J6r_ejtqWEOJYV_g08QKGg" hash="3p8ffQ">One thing is for certain: earning the Lord’s trust is a blessing that comes through great effort on our part. Trust is a blessing based on obedience to God’s laws. Earning the Lord’s trust comes as a result of being true to the covenants we have made in the waters of baptism and in the holy temple. When we keep our promises to the Lord, His trust in us grows.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p7" pid="G3gC4UXVxkKkB1d9gDu8pA" hash="0v-YMQ">I love both ancient and modern-day scriptures that use the phrase “integrity of heart” when describing a righteous person’s character.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Integrity or the lack of integrity is a fundamental element of one’s character. Men who have “integrity of heart” are men to be trusted—because trust is built on integrity.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p8" pid="pFV41hf78E2DjRMc2ByIkw" hash="jHysEw">Being a man of integrity simply means your intentions, as well as your actions, are pure and righteous in all aspects of your life, both in public and in private. With each decision we make, we either merit more of God’s trust or diminish His trust. This principle is perhaps most clearly manifest in our divinely appointed responsibilities as husbands and fathers.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p9" pid="sQuUsNAGn06-jv8jLwSs_Q" hash="tukVSA">As husbands and fathers, we have received a divine charge from modern-day prophets, seers, and revelators in the document “The Family: A Proclamation to the World.” This document teaches us that (1) “fathers are to preside over their families in love and righteousness,” (2) fathers “are responsible to provide the necessities of life,” and (3) fathers are responsible to protect their families.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p10" pid="B0cpm69XcE-Coo59SGV-cA" hash="4396tA">For us to earn God’s trust, we will need to accomplish these three divinely appointed responsibilities to our families in the Lord’s way. As further stated in the family proclamation, the Lord’s way is to fulfill these responsibilities together with our wives “as equal partners.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> To me, this means we do not move forward with any significant decision regarding these three responsibilities without total unity with our wives.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p11" pid="S2AwsaXnQkOkQ_NHuDEV0Q" hash="4GXkjw">The first step in our quest to earn the Lord’s trust is to place our trust in Him. The prophet Nephi exemplified this type of commitment when he prayed: “O Lord, I have trusted in thee, and I will trust in thee forever. I will not put my trust in the arm of flesh.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Nephi was fully committed to doing the Lord’s will. In addition to <span class="emphasis">saying</span> he would “do the things which the Lord hath commanded,” Nephi was unwavering in his commitment to <span class="emphasis">accomplishing</span> his assignments, as illustrated in this statement: “As the Lord liveth, and as we live, we will not go down unto our father in the wilderness until we have accomplished the thing which the Lord hath commanded us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p12" pid="I_NVB_RBPkmb59_SeOcpfg" hash="DF1MIg">Because Nephi first trusted in God, God put great trust in Nephi. The Lord blessed him with great outpourings of the Spirit that blessed his life, the lives of his family, and the lives of his people. Because Nephi presided in love and righteousness and provided for and protected his family and people, he records, “We lived after the manner of happiness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p13" pid="9IE3f2Z3CUuST2J4-ZJDIQ" hash="M9-FWQ">In order to represent a woman’s perspective on this subject, I asked my two married daughters to help me. I asked if they would provide a sentence or two on how they viewed the importance of trust as it affects their marriage and family life. Here are the thoughts of Lara Harris and Christina Hansen.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p14" pid="3qYJj17YKEi2bgdrPC2_YA" hash="lUGtNQ">First, Lara: “One of the most important things to me is knowing that as my husband goes about his day, he is making choices that show respect and love toward me. When we can trust each other in this way, it brings peace to our home, where we can enjoy raising our family together.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p15" pid="2-WoulTzyEmhIy0MqLhiww" hash="yPXBYw">Now Christina’s thoughts: “Having trust in someone is similar to having faith in someone. Without that trust and faith, there’s fear and doubt. For me, one of the greatest blessings that come from being able to fully trust my husband is peace—peace of mind knowing that he actually does what he says he will do. Trust brings peace, love, and an environment where that love can grow.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p16" pid="I7ggnXpZPkK4m8Wqav8KfQ" hash="vEFExQ">Lara and Christina never saw what the other had written. It is so interesting to me that both of them independently considered the blessing of peace in the home to be a direct consequence of having a husband they could trust. As illustrated by my daughters’ examples, the principle of trust plays an extremely important role in the development of a Christ-centered home.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p17" pid="GSfUD9Z5iEuvZ9sVYL175g" hash="-9GLwg">I was also able to enjoy that same Christ-centered culture growing up in a home where my father honored his priesthood and gained the trust of the entire family due to “the integrity of his heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> Let me share with you an experience from my youth that illustrates the lasting positive impact that a father who understands and lives the principle of trust built on integrity can have on his family.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p18" pid="vdMDJ5olGUK5XipXhH5KFg" hash="E6hXoQ">When I was very young, my father founded a company that specialized in factory automation. This business engineered, fabricated, and installed automated production lines worldwide.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p19" pid="NNUcYMMldU2jpVZHwPr9pg" hash="mmkhSQ">When I was in middle school, my father wanted me to learn how to work. He also wanted me to learn the business from the ground up. My first job included maintaining the grounds and painting areas of the facility not visible to the general public.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p20" pid="sSFx43VGnkGzywk1DM5UZA" hash="JJHgnQ">When I entered high school, I was promoted to work on the factory floor. I started to learn how to read blueprints and run heavy steel fabrication machinery. After high school graduation, I attended university and then entered the mission field. Returning home from my mission, I went straight back to work. I needed to earn money for the next year’s school expenses.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p21" pid="kSO8CUmDMUGkejTgti1zEQ" hash="oP_0gA">One day soon after my mission, I was working in the factory when my father called me into his office and asked if I would like to go with him on a business trip to Los Angeles. This was the first time my father invited me to accompany him on a business trip. He was actually letting me go out in public to help represent the company.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p22" pid="UbrBRIAP5U2yC1UZz1L_nw" hash="KD6a6A">Before we left on the trip, he prepared me with a few details about this potential new client. First, the client was a multinational corporation. Second, they were upgrading their production lines worldwide with the latest in automation technology. Third, our company had never previously supplied them with engineering services or technology. And finally, their top corporate officer in charge of purchasing had called this meeting to review our bid on a new project. This meeting represented a new and potentially important opportunity for our company.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p23" pid="qtFlVglrGkm4ipxvTVuDsQ" hash="mY80CA">After arriving in Los Angeles, my father and I went to the executive’s hotel for the meeting. The first order of business was to discuss and analyze the engineering design specifications of the project. The next discussion item concerned operational details, including logistics and delivery dates. The concluding agenda item focused on pricing, terms, and conditions. This is where things got interesting.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p24" pid="AhSAI3nNS0KJX5AgvJ80cg" hash="T--c-w">This corporate officer explained to us that our price proposal was the lowest of those who had submitted bids on the project. He then, curiously, told us the price of the second-lowest bid. He then asked us if we would be willing to take our proposal back and resubmit it. He stated that our new price should come in just below the next highest bid. He then explained that we would split the newly added dollars 50–50 with him. He rationalized this by saying that everyone would win. Our company would win because we would be making considerably more money than our original bid provided. His company would win because they would still be doing business with the lowest bidder. And, of course, he would win by taking his cut because he put this great deal together.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p25" pid="K84emu-NE0ujr5vZ1XJP9A" hash="ziw79g">He then gave us a post office box number where we could send the money he requested. After all of this, he looked at my father and asked, “So, do we have a deal?” Much to my surprise, my father stood up, shook his hand, and told him we would get back to him.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p26" pid="vN10Vb0iIkSwA0jLII78xQ" hash="XXPyEg">After leaving the meeting, we got into the rental car, and my father turned to me and asked, “Well, what do you think we should do?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p27" pid="eQ4ey4emYEuRcDEfMRhlvw" hash="4AQ_rw">I responded by saying I didn’t think we should accept this offer.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p28" pid="nZhgJIDs-0OE8NXpPHdwqg" hash="LUinVg">My father then asked, “Don’t you think we have a responsibility to all of our employees to maintain a good backlog of work?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p29" pid="VKu6ZLh3VkSgyRgMQYXP2w" hash="kuGigQ">While I was contemplating his question and before I could answer, he answered his own question. He said, “Listen, Rick, once you take a bribe or compromise your integrity, it is very difficult to ever get it back. Don’t ever do it, not even once.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p30" pid="cm7mMVRc1UeNpwdOw2-YYQ" hash="T9aGHw">The fact that I’m sharing this experience means that I have never forgotten what my father taught me on that first business trip with him. I share this experience to illustrate the lasting influence we have as fathers. You can imagine the trust I had in my father due to the integrity of his heart. He lived these same principles in his private life with my mother, his children, and all with whom he associated.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family.p31" pid="bg2yk69LO0uJV49d-uQb8g" hash="ATG_QA">Brethren, it is my prayer this evening that we might all first place our trust in the Lord, as Nephi exemplified, and then, through the integrity of our hearts, earn the trust of the Lord, as well as the trust of our wives and children. As we understand and apply this sacred principle of trust built on integrity, we will be true to our sacred covenants. We will also succeed in presiding in our families with love and righteousness, providing the necessities of life, and protecting our families from the evils of the world. Of these truths I humbly testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2017/10/earning-the-trust-of-the-lord-and-your-family</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2017-general-conference/2017-09-3030-richard-j-maynes-64k-eng.mp3" length="5484955" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
