<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Richard H. Winkel</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Richard H. Winkel.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Richard%20H.%20Winkel.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Richard H. Winkel.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Oct 1999 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 1999 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>“No Man Is an Island”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island?lang=eng</link>
      <description>New members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints cannot make it alone. … They need us and we need them.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_99265_000_032" doc-version="2" hash="4Xr6Cw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="37evuewOqUOzTyLQh2J55Q" hash="rYtsSw">“No Man Is an Island”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="s1Db_ka52Uye2mBywVAvkg" hash="qyi0gA">Richard H. Winkel</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="Je9_MC_Y-E2-N9r4gFMkJA" hash="EkHWKg">New members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints cannot make it alone. … They need us and we need them.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1b27.jpg" alt="Elder Richard H. Winkel" pid="JyrIxQCpvUWB-Ntt4nfM9w" hash="-FnGjw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.p1" pid="8lItCvBovUqZfYDxa-05kA" hash="20CCfA">Brothers and sisters, it’s so good to be here with you this afternoon. As I began preparing my talk, I pondered the thought that this is the first time I have been asked to speak in the Tabernacle—and that it would also be my last! But it is good to be here with you on this historic occasion in this historic building.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.p2" pid="cAjsjSlW0kiSFAjLqLWwHA" hash="xr7Jig">I’d like to change geographic locations now and talk to you about another beautiful place. The north coast of California is home to the world’s tallest trees. A walk through a virgin old-growth redwood forest can be one of the most awe-inspiring experiences you’ll ever have. These trees sometimes live to be over 2,000 years old and can reach heights of 300 feet and more. The tallest redwood tree ever recorded was 367 feet in height. That is taller than a football field and about one-third again as tall as the Salt Lake Temple. The gigantic redwoods dwarf their other softwood and hardwood neighbors, thus becoming “the Mount Everest of all living things.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.p3" pid="TWIsPSha4U-WcPej2ZUJZQ" hash="g1Q2zg">“Yea, all things which come of the earth, in the season thereof, are made for the benefit and the use of man, both to please the eye and to gladden the heart;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.p4" pid="50Xaxcb-AEKUC5-oeQqFMA" hash="wOAm6A">“Yea, for food and for raiment, for taste and for smell, to strengthen the body and to enliven the soul.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.p5" pid="O2i3nKRvoES2iBfg4VEM1A" hash="j_cZGw">“And it pleaseth God that he hath given all these things unto man; for unto this end were they made to be used, with judgment, not to excess, neither by extortion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.p6" pid="goyM68GKrkyDLgbVNELW8w" hash="KXEfRQ">“And in nothing doth man offend God, or against none is his wrath kindled, save those who confess not his hand in all things, and obey not his commandments” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.18-21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:18–21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.p7" pid="wqmGtQwXYEqdKn0QS2EbpA" hash="Uy-Jzw">The coastal redwoods are truly lords of their realm and a most exquisite creation of our Father in Heaven. They reign over associated trees because of their overwhelming height and majestic beauty. However, there is another feature of these towering giants that is truly remarkable and somewhat unknown to most of us. Even though they grow up to heights of 300 feet and can weigh more than one million pounds, these trees have a very shallow root system. Their roots only go down three to six feet but can spread out several hundred feet. As these roots extend out, they intertwine with their brother and sister redwoods and other trees as well. This intertwining of roots creates a webbing effect. Most engineers would tell you this shallow root system still would be impossible to keep the redwoods intact and protected against strong winds and floods. However, the interconnecting root systems are the secret of their strength and teach us a great lesson.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.p8" pid="mPGcO3nABk6A9KXIcaFPHw" hash="aw52JQ">First, let’s acknowledge that these magnificent giants simply could not make it alone. Without being connected to other family members and helpful neighbors, they would not survive.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.p9" pid="CBLENNwAkkWUcGYYeEb7_w" hash="wL6Iew">I would like you to contemplate the first two verses of the song adapted from a meditation by John Donne:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="gDPvooYQ8ku0LhNEng6wcg" hash="rYtsSw1">
            <span class="emphasis">No man is an island;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="_HRqfhk3iE2vqEEbH0jUBQ" hash="lcHEsQ">
            <span class="emphasis">No man stands alone.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="aofjsK72F0aJRl2Rqpl29g" hash="r_5gig">
            <span class="emphasis">Each man’s joy is a joy to me;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="PzkQcR1MZEGd_0Dr5kOolA" hash="JOx5Hg">
            <span class="emphasis">Each man’s grief is my own.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="sLe2tMfKo0WO96x8S75VXA" hash="0NpD6g">
            <span class="emphasis">We need one another,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="uVJv9VcYWkeU5oS9ct5MPw" hash="iuGqVw">
            <span class="emphasis">So I will defend</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="cFO-XF5TCEKxC91HWgvU9A" hash="WY_ckw">
            <span class="emphasis">Each man as my brother;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="1bbQeapDnE-qLhfd_M72Wg" hash="au8CAA">
            <span class="emphasis">Each man as my friend.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.p10" pid="UT9UZJPeJE2bPY23V-7b8A" hash="Z0I65w">New members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints cannot make it alone. They might appear to be as independently strong as the redwoods, but they need us and we need them. President Hinckley, in a satellite broadcast last February, shared the story of a woman who became a member last year. She wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.p11" pid="k3_BR_qZK067AyTVtRw7PQ" hash="U4hbNg">“‘My journey into the Church was unique and quite challenging. This past year has been the hardest year that I have ever lived in my life. It has also been the most rewarding. As a new member, I continue to be challenged every day.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.p12" pid="y7zZyaju7EanBToTOlZ0mQ" hash="Sal0VQ">“She goes on to say that when she joined the Church she did not feel support from the leadership in her ward. Her bishop seemed indifferent to her as a new member. Rebuffed, as she felt, she turned back to her mission president, who opened opportunities for her.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.p13" pid="L2vai8v1MkiNmiQm7TAH6g" hash="-fwMpg">“She states that ‘Church members don’t know what it is like to be a new member of the Church. Therefore, it’s almost impossible for them to know how to support us’” (“Find the Lambs, Feed the Sheep,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1999, 108).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.p14" pid="1w4cBkLlKk2iB-oJKKU_Ig" hash="Y7vbSA">They need our love and support. Whether we know it or not, they are reaching out to us as the roots of the redwood reach towards the Douglas fir, the Western hemlock, the Sitka spruce, and other species as well. We need to reach out to these new members and sustain them in their growth, for truly we are their brothers and sisters. Don’t we all do better when we are supported, sustained, and loved by our families and friends? Even trees do better when they grow close together in groves. They grow taller, straighter, stronger, and produce better lumber. When a tree is growing off by itself, it develops many branches. These branches generate knots, which can weaken the tree and downgrade its timber quality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.p15" pid="sz6CSruw4UaYcs0uSmGpgQ" hash="dEUgPA">You might recall when Christ organized His Church He called many to serve: apostles, prophets, patriarchs, bishops, deacons, teachers, priests, et cetera. Many were called to serve in His kingdom. These calls were given to strengthen the members, to organize the Church, and to bless the lives of God’s children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.p16" pid="aMLXKcwqGUulYF8SkOjEgw" hash="D6bO7A">When the Savior called Peter, James, John, and others, did they have experience? No, but He told them He would train them; He would make them fishers of men. Did His apostles and disciples make mistakes? Of course they did, but they were given opportunity, and they learned. So will our new brothers and sisters learn and grow as we befriend them, extend calls to them, and nourish them with the good word of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.p17" pid="o3NGMEHwmkGX9lXOvZxxxw" hash="WikuUQ">One of the other abundant species under the redwood canopy is a little-known hardwood tree called <span class="emphasis">Lithocarpus densiflorus.</span> It is also called tan oak. The tan oak fits into the same general family as the true oaks but is a little different. There are several billion board feet of this species growing amongst the popular redwoods, and it has many fine qualities, but it’s almost completely overlooked and unused. What a waste, what a tragedy when you consider the tan oak’s potential. The mind-set of many wood users is, <span class="emphasis">We’re doing just fine with the old standbys; why change?</span> We cannot overlook the potential of our new members or misjudge their talents. Remember, “he inviteth them all to come unto him and partake of his goodness; and he denieth none that come unto him, black and white, bond and free, male and female; and he remembereth the heathen; and all are alike unto God, both Jew and Gentile” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/26.33" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 26:33</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island.p18" pid="RwWZQezi8EGpdIKvVKpw9A" hash="Tu-yaw">I am thankful for the web of friendship that has nurtured me throughout my life, for having been born of goodly parents, for my brothers, sisters, and extended family. I am especially grateful for the love and support of my wonderful wife, Karen, and also our equally wonderful and loving children. I would like also to say that I feel very fortunate to have had many good friends through the years, both in and out of the Church. I am grateful to have recently been associated with outstanding missionaries in Spain and for the wonderful members of that country. Brothers and sisters, I know we have a kind and wise Heavenly Father and bear testimony of His Son, Jesus Christ, and of His atoning sacrifice, which touches each one of us. I also bear testimony that the Church is led by a great prophet today, even Gordon B. Hinckley. I ask the Lord to bless us all that we might feel more connected and caring of one another, especially as we move into this new era of growth in the Church and into this exciting new millennium, and I say this in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1999/10/no-man-is-an-island</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1999-general-conference/1999-10-5030-elder-richard-h-winkel-64k-eng.mp3" length="4332287" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 1999 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Temple Is about Families</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families?lang=eng</link>
      <description>When you come to the temple you will love your family with a deeper love than you have ever felt before.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006562_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="NT1Ieg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="779KOi0dDUOjqzhSBZwtPg" hash="clpBOQ">The Temple Is about Families</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="LN3bgItF-EWHycewi2gZrw" hash="qyi0gA">Richard H. Winkel</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="Jim3nSOCSEC8wBJENsXZWQ" hash="hPD5_A">When you come to the temple you will love your family with a deeper love than you have ever felt before.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.t1">
      <img src="WinkelRH_all.ob.jpg" alt="Elder Richard H. Winkel" pid="TBHT55bdDUmSdtKHcEpzoQ" hash="tdlINg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p1" pid="yuv_-E9rlEOfK-xcslPxGw" hash="aCOD8A">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="9"></span>As President Hinckley just mentioned, the 123rd temple of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints was recently dedicated by President Hinckley in Sacramento, California. This beautiful temple serves more than 80,000 wonderful and excited members of the Church in Sacramento and surrounding areas. Over 168,000 visitors toured the temple during the open house. They were told that members can draw closer to the Savior Jesus Christ in these magnificent edifices than anywhere else in the world. Our members know that through Him they can find the peace and hope that will sustain them and their families in today’s troubled world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p2" pid="CgcY2gKKt0SVrW6lG2W4jQ" hash="Nuu17w">When you come to the temple you will love your family with a deeper love than you have ever felt before. The temple is about families. As my wife, Karen, and I have increased our temple service, our love for each other and for our children has increased. And it doesn’t stop there. It extends to parents, brothers and sisters, aunts, uncles, cousins, forebears, and especially our grandchildren! This is the Spirit of Elijah, which is the spirit of family history work; and when inspired by the Holy Ghost, it prompts the turning of the hearts of the fathers to the children and the hearts of the children to the fathers. Because of the priesthood, husbands and wives are sealed together, children are sealed to their parents for eternity so the family is eternal and will not be separated at death.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p3" pid="YxaaaQbboUmGU6mMoD3_mg" hash="_LHZXg">When my wife and I were young parents with little children at home, we challenged our children to memorize the Articles of Faith. The prize, or reward, for completing them was a night out with Dad. We were pleased that our three oldest completed the challenge. When our seven-year-old son first memorized all 13 Articles of Faith, we sat down to pick out a night and activity that we could do together. I was so busy with work, <span class="pageBreak" page-number="10"></span>social activities, and Church responsibilities that I couldn’t give my son a night out for about two weeks. He was sorely disappointed. However, I found that in the city where we lived there was an all-night bowling alley. We immediately picked a date and chose to start our activity at 5:00 in the morning. Our plan was to get up at 4:00, have breakfast, and then go downtown.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p4" pid="7xzk28TslU2vyvwAQWPMyg" hash="A0ojgQ">When that day arrived, I felt someone shaking my shoulder very early in the morning. As I tried to open my eyes I heard my son say, “Is it time, Dad?” I looked at my alarm clock; it was only 2:00 a.m.!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p5" pid="Ofv6eNubuEKXztDrk0ImUQ" hash="v8sCSQ">“Go to sleep, Son,” I said. “It’s not time yet.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p6" pid="lYn1qDnfSkWkxonRYWMpRQ" hash="UXjZHA">An hour later the same thing happened. “Dad, Dad, is it time to go?” After sending him to bed for a second time, I couldn’t help but feel his excitement.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p7" pid="zyre-0S4eEKkmtw1ngea6g" hash="pbg93Q">Then at 4:00 a.m. we got up, had something to eat, and left for the bowling alley. We had a wonderful time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p8" pid="YOQmaUWmI06S8Zznbh7C8A" hash="XjTuig">I wish I could say I had regular and memorable activities like that with all my children, but I can’t. I’m one of those parents who ofttimes wishes he could go back and do some things over.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p9" pid="dqYVEM3S00OREKGyh31YDA" hash="evpSwg">Like you, I don’t want to lose any of my children. I want to be together forever with all of my family. The temple gives all of us extra hope of continuing and improving these relationships, even after this life. Sealings bestowed in the temple promise additional blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p10" pid="8g0H1nYawk-7ynpV0HnQcg" hash="3L5Qog">“The Prophet Joseph Smith declared—and he never taught more comforting doctrine—that the eternal sealings of faithful parents and the divine promises made to them for valiant service in the Cause of Truth, would save not only themselves, but likewise their posterity. Though some of the sheep may wander, the eye of the Shepherd is upon them, and sooner or later they will feel the tentacles of Divine Providence reaching out after them and drawing them back to the fold. Either in this life or the life to come, they will return. They will have to pay their debt to justice; they will suffer for their sins; and may tread a thorny path; but if it leads them at last, like the penitent Prodigal, to a loving and forgiving father’s heart and home, the painful experience will not have been in vain.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p11" pid="FRnOmp0e7UajbRzMax1eRA" hash="X43uvw">Isn’t this statement encouraging news for parents whose children are sealed to them?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p12" pid="tloBZ1K8B0uMqBj2XJIfqg" hash="SaPNlA">Let’s look at a few other blessings the temple brings. The house of the Lord is a refuge from the world. The Sacramento members shared the following comment with their open house guests: “Sometimes our minds are so beset with problems, and there are so many things clamoring for [our] attention at once that we just cannot think clearly. At the temple the dust of distraction seems to settle out, the fog and the haze seem to lift, and we can ‘see’ things that we were not able to see before.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p13" pid="nf0NtB0Qg0WQ-nap_vXXtg" hash="Nm-GcA">The celestial room in the temple is especially a place of peace, tranquility, and beauty. It is a quiet haven where one can reflect, ponder, pray, meditate, and feel the love of Heavenly Father and the Savior. As we ponder and meditate in the temple, our thoughts naturally <span class="pageBreak" page-number="11"></span>focus on members of our family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p14" pid="SU-8nsNs3UmjvSojBU59tA" hash="ZkW5VA">In <a href="/scriptures/ot/2-sam/22.7" class="scriptureRef">2 Samuel 22:7</a> we read the words of David: “In my distress I called upon the Lord, and cried to my God: and he did hear my voice out of his temple, and my cry did enter into his ears.” The temple is a place of personal revelation that will bless us in our stewardships.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p15" pid="K0BBjxontUqlB-Bgn8aIpA" hash="8xGjsQ">President Hinckley has told us that “just as our Redeemer gave His life as a vicarious sacrifice for all men, and in so doing became our Savior, even so we, in a small measure, when we engage in proxy work in the temple, become as saviors to those on the other side who have no means of advancing unless something is done in their behalf by those on earth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p16" pid="pDHK_sKtYk-25CnEMxmtlA" hash="z4BPKw">This is such meaningful service we give because our departed brothers and sisters literally become more connected to us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p17" pid="SPhjTw-Iy02Hdlzf64HylQ" hash="y7Xh_A">The temple is a place to know the Father and the Son. It is a place where we experience the divine presence. The Prophet Joseph Smith made this plea: “I advise all to … search deeper and deeper into the mysteries of Godliness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> And where shall we search? In the house of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p18" pid="mAkho7RFVkyRWpm7Va2icw" hash="PzRL6w">Let’s become a temple-attending and temple-loving people. I bear testimony that the temple is about families. I also testify that everything in the temple testifies of Jesus Christ. His example of love and service is felt there. The temple is His holy house. I know that He is the Son of God, our Savior, our Redeemer, our Mediator, and our Advocate with the Father. He loves us and wants our families to be happy and to be together forever. He wants all of us to be active in His temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families.p19" pid="pbYlvJkTdkSKQvetrR1lMA" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/10/the-temple-is-about-families</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2006-general-conference/2006-10-1030-elder-richard-h-winkel-64k-eng.mp3" length="4350447" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2006 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
